# Transcript
ID: ee6ab2c0-4c99-11ec-9486-e3922a6ab99f
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Eero CEO Nick Weaver on 5G, Thread, and the future of the smart home
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/1336462472/1227146598/s93290-US-2212s-1637698298.mp3
Description: Nilay Patel and Dieter Bohn interview CEO of Eero Nick Weaver live at On The Verge in New York City.
The discussion includes how the Ring Alarm Pro came together, Eero supporting Thread and Matter, integration of 5G, and what's next for the smart home.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Disabled
Speaker 1:  This episode of the Vergecast brought to you by click up. What would you
Speaker 1:  do with one extra day every week? Go ahead, close your eyes, picture it.
Speaker 1:  People lose a ton of time. Every day hours even toggling between
Speaker 1:  all of their work apps. Click up has a solution. They'll bring all of your
Speaker 1:  essential tools into one place. Prioritize tasks, collaborate on docs,
Speaker 1:  chat with your team and track goals. Listen, click up says
Speaker 1:  they will guarantee you save one day every week on
Speaker 1:  average, and it's completely customizable and free forever. So
Speaker 1:  try click up today at click up.com/vergecast
Speaker 2:  Support for this episode comes from Sephora. Beauty is a story.
Speaker 2:  That's why Sephora is shining a spotlight on the black creators and brand
Speaker 2:  founders whose contributions habits have shaped the industry. They help us
Speaker 2:  clean beauty for ourselves. Black beauty founders have been leading this
Speaker 2:  charge for decades. In fact, many today's beauty trends,
Speaker 2:  products and tools have deep roots in black culture. Learn more about
Speaker 2:  Sephora's commitment to supporting and celebrating black beauty at the
Speaker 2:  foreign.com/celebrate black beauty
Speaker 1:  Greetings mobile. Accomplishers welcome to the Vergecast. My name is Dieter
Speaker 1:  Bohn, and you are listening to our special series of topics
Speaker 1:  specific Tuesday episodes this week. The topic is
Speaker 1:  Eero and that's because we are bringing you an interview that Neil Patel
Speaker 1:  and I did with the CEO of Eero Nick Weaver. We have this interview back at
Speaker 1:  our 10 year anniversary party conference festival thing
Speaker 1:  called how the verge in New York city. It was a ton of fun. It was a huge
Speaker 1:  blast. And so we're happy to bring some of the things that happened at this
Speaker 1:  event to you, if you couldn't make it out to the party, but if you could
Speaker 1:  thanks so much for coming, it was great to see you anyway, with this interview
Speaker 1:  with Nick, I want you to pay special attention to the pieces where we began
Speaker 1:  to talk about thread and matter. So thread, if you're not
Speaker 1:  familiar with it is a kind of radio for smart home devices that Eero
Speaker 1:  in particular, but a lot of people in general have been hyping for several
Speaker 1:  years now, but never seems to amount anything, but it seems like it's actually
Speaker 1:  about to become super important. And it's about to become super important
Speaker 1:  because there is another smart home standard called matter, which is the
Speaker 1:  standard that used to be known as connected home over IP. Or you could have
Speaker 1:  called it the chip, or yeah, you could call it choice. If you wanted to be
Speaker 1:  a weirdo like me. Anyway, it's the standard that's supposed to make smart
Speaker 1:  home gadgets, all talk to each other, and arrow's whole jam is connecting
Speaker 1:  things in your home. They make wifi routers and they also now make a version
Speaker 1:  of arrow that connects up to a ring pro and can actually provide back up
Speaker 1:  internet over LTE for when your internet goes down. So we
Speaker 1:  discuss all of these things, but the reason I'm bringing up matter and thread
Speaker 1:  in particular is because in a couple of weeks after we get through the holiday
Speaker 1:  break, we're going to bring you one last topic specific episode on Tuesday.
Speaker 1:  That will be all about matter. We're going to get to the bottom of whether
Speaker 1:  or not the hype is real and what's going on with it. But in the meantime,
Speaker 1:  there's a lot of really interesting things here with Nick. And so I hope
Speaker 1:  you enjoy
Speaker 1:
Speaker 1:  I, this
Speaker 3:  Foreboding distance that I know you got you over there, what's going to
Speaker 3:  happen in Nash.
Speaker 4:  There's actually a bucket of water. You know, just if you answer a question.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, perfect. So I actually want to start with the
Speaker 4:  new product that you made Amazon made
Speaker 4:   yeah, there's a ring alarm pro, and
Speaker 4:  if you're not familiar, one of the cool things about it is it has IRO built
Speaker 4:  in. And how did that happen? Did you make it that they call you and
Speaker 4:  ask you, like what happened there?
Speaker 3:  We really just started with what are the problems that people are trying
Speaker 3:  to solve in their home. And when you have a camera,
Speaker 3:  wifi is really important. So the whole premise there was, how can we
Speaker 3:  make things as easy as possible for customers make it easy to set
Speaker 3:  up, make sure you've got super reliable wifi. So your cameras stay connected
Speaker 3:  and integrated all into one one device.
Speaker 4:  So it makes perfect sense to put wifi into a device like ring, but
Speaker 4:  again, like, did they ask you, did you, are you all in the room all the time?
Speaker 4:  Are you all just one big company now, or phone call, how does that work
Speaker 3:  Phone call meeting? We all know how to reach each other. And
Speaker 3:  just a lot of it starts with thinking about what problems we're hearing from
Speaker 3:  customers and deciding if we want to go work on a solution together or
Speaker 3:  independently, there's a lot of flexibility.
Speaker 4:  Well, I mean, I look at all the smart home gadgets now in my house and I
Speaker 4:  think, well, that should have wifi. That should be a router. That should
Speaker 4:  be a router. Like why ring and nod and echo. Okay.
Speaker 3:  I think there with echo devices, you've got them everywhere in the
Speaker 3:  house, and there's a lot of places where you want a voice assistant that
Speaker 3:  doesn't necessarily have the best wifi coverage. There's a lot of places
Speaker 3:  where you need great wifi coverage. It's not a great place for a voice
Speaker 3:  assistant. So, you know, for instance, there's a lot of routers
Speaker 3:  in people's closets. That's where the internet comes in, not a good place
Speaker 3:  for voice assistant. So a lot of the thinking is, Hey, where can we
Speaker 3:  converge devices where it makes sense for customers and putting it into a
Speaker 3:  fully comprehensive alarm base station makes a lot of sense,
Speaker 3:  but like an echo in your kitchen is a great place for a router. It could
Speaker 3:  be, will it be,
Speaker 3:  You know, we've looked at everything and
Speaker 3:  you know, in the future who knows it might, it might make sense to
Speaker 3:  converge more of those devices than we have
Speaker 4:  In the past. The other genius thing about the ring alarm pro is that it has
Speaker 4:  a backup LTE modem. So if your internet goes out, you can
Speaker 4:  have a backup internet. I forget the exact name. Once you get over
Speaker 4:  LTE for a little while, so that you're not just knocked offline,
Speaker 4:  Y Y LTE and non 5g.
Speaker 3:  And we're looking at, you know, what's required for, for an
Speaker 3:  alarm system, LTE provides just, you know,
Speaker 3:  just enough connectivity that you need. You know, this is not really supposed
Speaker 3:  to be your high-speed primary internet connection. We want you to be
Speaker 3:  able to stay online and then with, you know, 5g still
Speaker 3:  evolving and depending on what flavor of 5g,
Speaker 3:  sometimes it doesn't get through walls particularly well. And
Speaker 3:  so that was one of the considerations that went into that product decision.
Speaker 3:  Specifically,
Speaker 5:  There are some flavors of 5g that you're like, millimeter wave doesn't go
Speaker 5:  through walls. But also, like, I don't think a lot of people are setting
Speaker 5:  up ring camera system is under like one streetlight in New York
Speaker 5:  city. It's like, it's just like you holding your floodlight cam. I
Speaker 5:  get the, just enough arguing, but there's another argument that you would
Speaker 5:  want to fail over to 5g when you're in air. It goes down and that would be
Speaker 5:  really fast. There are the home internet services from their providers.
Speaker 5:  Is that, do you see that as a
Speaker 3:  Path? I think when we look at the performance and reliability of
Speaker 3:  Eero networks, just across the U S across the globe, there
Speaker 3:  is a subset of customers where fail-over could
Speaker 3:  and would be really valuable. So it's certainly something we've
Speaker 3:  been exploring. You know, a lot of it comes down to the amount of
Speaker 3:  data you're going to use. Cellular is fairly expensive.
Speaker 3:  And in particular with 5g, it's super fast speeds. You can consume a
Speaker 3:  lot of data really quickly, and the cost per gigabyte is still
Speaker 3:  fairly high.
Speaker 4:  Okay. So if we're talking about 5g, I think our audience knows that 5g is
Speaker 4:  a race and we're, we're winning. We've lost.
Speaker 4:  Do you feel like you're in a race with 5g? Cause like the claim has been,
Speaker 4:  well, we're not going to need wifi anymore. Everything's going to have 5g.
Speaker 4:  It'll be great.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I think 5g and wifi are really great.
Speaker 3:  Complimentary technologies, cost of cellular is
Speaker 3:  really expensive. Cost of 5g, very expensive. We're
Speaker 3:  talking not one, but frequently two orders of magnitude
Speaker 3:  more in terms of putting a wifi chip set into a
Speaker 3:  device versus a 5g modem. And so 5g is
Speaker 3:  great for coming into the home, but for getting it to all the devices around
Speaker 3:  your house, paying that cost on a per device basis just
Speaker 3:  doesn't make sense. You also, you miss out on having, you
Speaker 3:  know, your own local network. That's one of the great things about running
Speaker 3:  your own network. You get a firewall, you can set rules, you can keep your
Speaker 3:  devices safe and secure and you lose a lot of that control and
Speaker 3:  capability if it's all connecting directly to a cellular network,
Speaker 4:  Right? So you don't feel any competition at all from, from 5g.
Speaker 3:  I think again, it's a really great
Speaker 5:  Complimentary technology, anything at all from 5g. I
Speaker 4:  Mean, there's that,
Speaker 5:  I mean, that's like kind of the big question is yep, I get it. You need to
Speaker 5:  connect. You need a fast connection to your house. They needed to redistribute
Speaker 5:  it to all the things, your house. Are you seeing a higher attach rate of
Speaker 5:  like T-Mobile at home 5g or Verizon as a fixed
Speaker 5:  service and like Texas, are you seeing those numbers tick up
Speaker 5:  versus straight cable?
Speaker 3:  I think th th the biggest trend we are seeing, it's just, people are
Speaker 3:  upgrading to gigabit and droves. They want gigabit. They want faster than
Speaker 3:  gigabit. A lot of people are sitting at home doing everything, school
Speaker 3:  work entertainment, and they just want more speed,
Speaker 3:  more bandwidth to do all the things they need to do from home. So we've just
Speaker 3:  seen really, really significant adoption
Speaker 3:  of gigabit internet and not trend is not slowing down.
Speaker 4:  Here's a weird one. I have gigabit internet and it's sucks because
Speaker 5:  We fixed Dieter's network right here. Right
Speaker 4:  Now. My download speeds are okay. My upload speeds are garbage, and that's
Speaker 4:  very common in the U S especially with cable. When you're
Speaker 4:  designing routers, are you like, are you designing for an idealized world
Speaker 4:  where we all have actually good internet from good companies, or are you
Speaker 4:  designing it with the realities of what you think customers are actually
Speaker 4:  going to be able to do?
Speaker 3:  When we're designing our products, it's being designed independent
Speaker 3:  of your internet connection. We are just trying to make our
Speaker 3:  radios, our RF performance as high quality
Speaker 3:  as we possibly can. We want it to be as reliable as it can,
Speaker 3:  and we want to hit the highest bandwidth metrics that's
Speaker 3:  possible with that design. And so if you hook it up to a
Speaker 3:  symmetric gigabit connection, great, if you hook it up to a gigabit
Speaker 3:  connection with 10 megabits up, you know, you're not going to
Speaker 3:  see great upload speeds because you're limited by the pipe coming into
Speaker 3:  your home. But the Eero network is going to perform as well as
Speaker 3:  we possibly can make it
Speaker 5:  With gigabit. One of the right, we need wifi six to really take advantage
Speaker 5:  of gigabit. Now there's six E scrape. The names are great. We're
Speaker 5:  very proud of the whole industry. Constantly. It's improving. That's a
Speaker 5:  low floor and we've noticed the wifi
Speaker 5:  six products are still wildly expensive. It's been like a year and a half,
Speaker 5:  maybe more. There's just a cost penalty for this stuff. Is
Speaker 5:  that because there's not enough. They haven't had scale. Why, why that
Speaker 5:  cost penalty?
Speaker 3:  It's just a transition. And everybody has been hearing about this for
Speaker 3:  months and months and months. The supply chains also backed up
Speaker 3:  and things are a lot more expensive. It's chips are more
Speaker 3:  expensive. Labor's more expensive.
Speaker 3:  Shipping is more expensive.
Speaker 5:  There's just like full of arrows, just like floating around.
Speaker 3:  There's probably a few of them at this point.
Speaker 5:  Is that something that you pay attention to, is the CEO like, do you get
Speaker 5:  a report? That's like, we actually, can't, we're waiting for a container
Speaker 5:  to unload with product.
Speaker 3:  I've spent more time on the phone with our head of manufacturing operations
Speaker 3:  in the last year and a half than I think we had in the last three
Speaker 3:  years or four years before that it has consumed a lot of
Speaker 3:  time and energy. And our teams have been just
Speaker 3:  working around the clock. You know, you fix one problem. Another one pops
Speaker 3:  up. It's a huge, huge game of whack-a-mole. And in
Speaker 3:  particular getting product to customers like that is something
Speaker 3:  I'm really involved in.
Speaker 4:  It actually surprises me because I would assume if you guys don't know arrows
Speaker 4:  bought by Amazon, that you've got Amazon, who's pretty good at logistics.
Speaker 4:  I would think that you could let them handle that. So like w what is
Speaker 4:  Amazon doing in terms of, you know, working with customers? I'm sure they're
Speaker 4:  handling much like HR and corporate stuff for you, but like, what's your
Speaker 4:  relationship with Amazon? There's a ring over there. You work with them,
Speaker 4:  but what do they do? What do you still like? No, this is mine. I will always
Speaker 4:  control this part of the business.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. So we handle, you know, all the product development support,
Speaker 3:  and we've got our own dedicated teams for nearly every
Speaker 3:  function that runs the company in terms of how do we leverage
Speaker 3:  the greater Amazon? Well, there are a lot of it's relationships
Speaker 3:  pasty thinking about like long-term inventory
Speaker 3:  and really being able to make sure we have enough stock for
Speaker 3:  customers that has been places where we've leveraged the greater
Speaker 3:  team a lot. Then there's also strategic planning. You know, what sub
Speaker 3:  suppliers can we work to work with together
Speaker 3:  and really aggregate, you know, the demand of radios or
Speaker 3:  memory or other parts of the supply chain. So we
Speaker 3:  get, you know, better scale, better support and can
Speaker 3:  deliver better products for customers. So we've done a lot of that,
Speaker 3:  but yeah, we S Amazon's very much about single-threaded
Speaker 3:  ownership and, you know, that's my responsibility at eeros keep driving the
Speaker 3:  company, keep driving the product portfolio, keep building
Speaker 3:  great, great devices for customers.
Speaker 5:  We get on the phone with like the prime video team. And you're like, dude,
Speaker 5:  Ted lasso is just like constantly using an iPhone. Can we, can we
Speaker 5:  get the boys? Some Euro routers
Speaker 3:  Every station yet, but yeah,
Speaker 5:  That's my only suggestion. Okay. We're going to have more about thread, but
Speaker 5:  that,
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I guess I'll have to talk about getting stuff out to customers. Do
Speaker 4:  you have people who don't know, you don't just sell to like consumers on
Speaker 4:  Amazon, you've got like an ISP business. You're partnering with actual internet
Speaker 4:  service providers. How's that going?
Speaker 3:  Yeah, that's, that's been a huge part of our business. So over the last year,
Speaker 3:  our Eero networks that get deployed by our
Speaker 3:  ISP customers have increased over 75%.
Speaker 3:  And that's just because customers want faster speeds when they get
Speaker 3:  faster speeds, they want faster wifi and they want coverage everywhere.
Speaker 3:  So we've announced deals with TalkTalk in the
Speaker 3:  UK Mediacom here in, in New York. And
Speaker 3:  it's been really exciting taking, you know, really great internet connectivity
Speaker 3:  plans, bundling them with eeros and then delivering this
Speaker 3:  like great internet experience to customers like that is what we are
Speaker 3:  trying to do each and every day we want the internet and people's homes to
Speaker 3:  just work and, and working really closely with
Speaker 3:  internet service providers is, is a really big part of our business. Is that
Speaker 3:  going
Speaker 4:  To be a bigger part of your business than selling direct to consumers?
Speaker 3:  You know, over time, we'll see, you know, we, we sell a lot of
Speaker 3:  arrows on, you know, with retail partners, like best
Speaker 3:  buy Costco.
Speaker 5:  And then I mentioned the other ones before we really like an
Speaker 3:  Amazon on amazon.com, hulking Goliath
Speaker 5:  In the corner.
Speaker 3:  We also sell it on eero.com.
Speaker 5:  Actually. What do you think about, like, where is it growing? W I,
Speaker 5:  we are going to talk about threatened smart home, but when you can worse,
Speaker 5:  we've made you wait for the punishment. But when you think about, okay,
Speaker 5:  my cable company is going to put an ear on my house. Okay. Will companies
Speaker 5:  have historically weird ideas about configuration
Speaker 5:  and stuff like that? When you start to add the capabilities, are
Speaker 5:  they getting in your way? Will they get in my way, like, I want to turn on
Speaker 5:  thread, or I want to use some of the IRO features that you've deployed. Are
Speaker 5:  they leaving that stuff alone? Do you have to talk to them or you have to
Speaker 5:  negotiate? Like the classic example I would use is cell phones and carriers.
Speaker 5:  We have an entire exhibit to a cell phone that was destroyed by carriers.
Speaker 5:  The DDA made a documentary about like, is that something that's happening
Speaker 5:  to you too?
Speaker 3:  Eero devices across the globe, regardless of
Speaker 3:  where they were bought or where they're coming from, I'll run the exact same
Speaker 3:  software. They all talk to the same app. You have the same controls.
Speaker 3:  So for, for customers, if you get
Speaker 3:  your Eero from your local ISP, or you
Speaker 3:  buy it from eero.com, you're going to have the same, same
Speaker 3:  experience. And you're committed to that. You're never going to white label
Speaker 3:  it. You're never going to let ISP mess with it. We, we think
Speaker 3:  really tight integration between hardware software and delivering
Speaker 3:  that same experience works, works really well for customers. And
Speaker 3:  that that's how we've built the company, built the business,
Speaker 3:  and we're going to continue to do that.
Speaker 1:  Okay, we're going to take a quick break, but when we come back, we're going
Speaker 1:  to have a little bit more from the CEO of your own. Nick Weaver
Speaker 2:  Support for this episode comes from Sephora. Beauty is a story.
Speaker 2:  That's why support is shining a spotlight on the black creators and brand
Speaker 2:  founders whose contributions habits have shaped the industry. They help
Speaker 2:  us clean beauty for ourselves. Black beauty founders have been leading this
Speaker 2:  charge for decades. In fact, many of today's beauty trends,
Speaker 2:  products and tools have deep roots in black culture. Learn more about
Speaker 2:  Sephora's commitment to supporting and celebrating black beauty at the
Speaker 2:  foreign.com/celebrate black beauty.
Speaker 7:  When it comes to your finances, wouldn't it be nice to have a little extra
Speaker 7:  help, like an intelligent assistant to point out when a free trial is about
Speaker 7:  to end or alert you to suspicious charges, capital
Speaker 7:  one does this and more for its customers. They have
Speaker 7:  teams of engineers building software, like a tech company. That means
Speaker 7:  using leading edge tech, like artificial intelligence to make sure their
Speaker 7:  products are the best they can be. And building these machine
Speaker 7:  learning capabilities all on the cloud. Their work is at the forefront
Speaker 7:  of what's possible in banking today. In fact, a lot of capital one's
Speaker 7:  AI and machine learning tech innovations are leading the industry,
Speaker 7:  taking out as an example, capital one's intelligent assistant helps
Speaker 7:  millions of customers have confidence and control over their financial
Speaker 7:  lives and their apps and products have won awards for offering some of the
Speaker 7:  best real time. Personalized customer experiences.
Speaker 7:  We're in a golden age of machine learning right now. And capital one is on
Speaker 7:  front lines, leading the charge using human centered design and
Speaker 7:  leading edge tech to serve customers better. Learn
Speaker 7:  more@capitalone.com slash tech
Speaker 8:  Support for this episode comes from Tillamook, the clatter of
Speaker 8:  cutlery, warm conversation, over a lingering meal. The finest
Speaker 8:  flavors of each season food brings us together and creates community.
Speaker 8:  But where does that great food actually come from? It comes from farmland.
Speaker 8:  That's under threat. The U S lost 11 million acres of
Speaker 8:  farmland to development in the last 20 years. That's 2000
Speaker 8:  acres of fertile farmland, disappearing to development every single day.
Speaker 8:  And today's farmers are facing unprecedented challenges, the loss of life,
Speaker 9:  And is a big issue for farmers, but it's more than that. It's a
Speaker 9:  rapidly changing marketplace and trying to grow food
Speaker 9:  facing severe weather associated with climate change. It is hard and
Speaker 9:  risky being a farmer.
Speaker 8:  That's David Haidt, VP of programs with American farmland, trust an
Speaker 8:  organization, working to save farmland and support farmers. It's more
Speaker 8:  important than ever to protect the future of farming. The offer farmers
Speaker 8:  coalition, a partnership between Tillamook and American farmland trust is
Speaker 8:  working to help farmers find out more and what you can do to help at all.
Speaker 8:  For farmers.com.
Speaker 10:  It used to be hard to stay close to family until Facebook portal. We
Speaker 10:  went from rarely video chatting to seeing each other on portal. Almost every
Speaker 10:  day. Portal has cool features like smart camera that keeps up with the kids.
Speaker 10:  So they don't have to sit still, which is its own challenge.
Speaker 10:  Plus, the new portal go is portable so we can take it to the playroom or
Speaker 10:  the kitchen. The best feature is how close we all feel,
Speaker 10:  even though we're far apart,
Speaker 11:  Give the gift of a deeper connection. Facebook portal
Speaker 8:  Share something real.
Speaker 4:  All right. We're back with more of our interview from the, on the verge event
Speaker 4:  with the CEO of Eero Nick Weaver.
Speaker 4:  So I promised we were going to fix the smart home and it was not going to
Speaker 4:  be confusing anymore, but before we do, I want you to pull out your phone.
Speaker 4:  Sure. And we're going to look at our Aero networks. I want you to
Speaker 4:  avoid, and we are all going to find the most embarrassing
Speaker 4:  thing currently connected to our smart home. And we're going to cop to it
Speaker 4:  and explain why we have it. So this is
Speaker 4:  here. I knew this was coming. So I'll just tell you the most embarrassing
Speaker 4:  thing on my network is Lisa. That's my spouse mega, I don't know what mega
Speaker 4:  means. Smart plug question, mark. Question mark.
Speaker 4:  I don't know what it is. Neither does she, but we are too afraid to turn
Speaker 4:  it off because we think it controls something important. That's good.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. That's a, it's a 2.4 and it's made by a company
Speaker 4:  called expressive. That's
Speaker 4:  Maybe, maybe someone's someone's spying on me. Yeah, he got mine is
Speaker 4:  extremely dumb. It is also a plug. Okay. I know what it does.
Speaker 4:  It's turns the
Speaker 5:  Subwoofer and our living room off because often when we
Speaker 5:  are verge casting, my daughter max is watching pop
Speaker 5:  patrol and there are at least two episodes of our show
Speaker 5:  where you can hear the thump of the pop patrol themes
Speaker 5:  coming from right above us. So I put the subwoofer on a plug and I turn
Speaker 5:  it off before he podcasts. And I don't know why I turn it back
Speaker 5:  on it's cause like, she's not like, I don't know the base response to that.
Speaker 3:  I think for me, it's just like the long list of devices in the home category.
Speaker 3:  We have air quality sensors. We have air purifiers. Cause
Speaker 3:  we're in Northern California. I have
Speaker 3:  ceiling fans. I have the ceiling fan controller. We have
Speaker 3:  an oven and then we have a bunch of hubs I've been
Speaker 3:  trying out to see if they do anything. It's been,
Speaker 3:  it's been, been a lot, like a very long project. Do you
Speaker 5:  Have a, do you have a HomeKit bridge?
Speaker 3:  I do have a hoops.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. We have three of them. Three of them on stage. I feel like, but it's
Speaker 5:  weird. Like, you know, we're outside the system, you admitting that you have
Speaker 5:  a hoops box. It's like, all right, it's not
Speaker 3:  Maybe experimenting. It's it. It's, it's an interesting
Speaker 3:  experience. Very hard to configure
Speaker 5:  The hubs is it's a thing you can buy, but the actual software is called HomeBridge
Speaker 5:  and it is, it just bridges everything into home
Speaker 5:  kit. So you're like your ring cameras show up in home kit Dieter, and I have
Speaker 5:  very different experiences with it. I'm like, it's great. And was like, why
Speaker 5:  did you make me do this? You're a horrible monster to bad friend.
Speaker 5:  I think it's great. But I've like, we've heard like lots of apple engineers
Speaker 5:  have this thing running. And like, to me, that, that brings us right to where
Speaker 5:  we're going, which is that it's crazy that like a bunch of
Speaker 5:  Europeans like ship everybody raspberry pies to make their smart homes
Speaker 5:  work. But that is the current state of things you're working on. Fixing it.
Speaker 5:  How's it, how's it going?
Speaker 3:  Well, you know, our whole thesis bureau, why we started the
Speaker 3:  company, everything in our homes is going to be connected to the internet
Speaker 3:  and ultimately, or our homes are going to run on a computer.
Speaker 3:  And so our vision has always been, you need to have a network to
Speaker 3:  enable that and that computer and that network are probably going to
Speaker 3:  converge into the same thing, but there's a first really
Speaker 3:  important step. And that is having super fast, reliable
Speaker 3:  connectivity everywhere today. That's primarily wifi over
Speaker 3:  time. It's to continue to be, you know, you need low
Speaker 3:  power. You need long range. There's a bunch of different flavors of
Speaker 3:  connectivity that this home of the future needs. And actually the home
Speaker 3:  of today needs to, to get all these devices connected. And
Speaker 3:  once they're connected and it's as reliable as our running water and our
Speaker 3:  power, then you can start layering on control
Speaker 3:  intelligence and you know, all the other things that we are
Speaker 3:  trying to make happen today.
Speaker 5:  There's two big things happening. One there's this industry group
Speaker 4:  Called matter, which is apple, Google, Amazon, and
Speaker 4:  formerly choice.
Speaker 5:  My, my t-shirt that says we matter raises a lot of questions,
Speaker 5:  right? It's a great,
Speaker 4:  It's a connected home over IP. The idea is that gadget should have like simpler,
Speaker 4:  easier networking. There works more like, like over IP. So that's like
Speaker 4:  one thing that's happening and you're involved in that. But then the other
Speaker 4:  thing is there's like the radio called thread,
Speaker 4:  which you have been promising is going to matter
Speaker 4:  and, and be a big deal for quite a while.
Speaker 5:  The first day I met you like next, he was like a startup founder and he's
Speaker 5:  like, I made this great router. And like, we had great conversations like
Speaker 5:  early on, like we love startups and we're like, what is this
Speaker 5:  radio? And he was like, this is going to be a big deal. And that was in
Speaker 5:  2017. Yes.
Speaker 3:  June of 2017.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. You're like, you're got it. And like the, it was apples and the support
Speaker 5:  it and Google's, and they kind of are now, but it's still in its infancy.
Speaker 5:  So why did it, why that dip and is it going to happen?
Speaker 3:  You know, what's interesting about thread, so it's a 15 dot four radio.
Speaker 3:  And what it does is it acts very much like
Speaker 3:  wifi just says, Hey, I'm going to let, I'm going to create a
Speaker 3:  network. I'm going to let devices connect to it. We're going to talk IP what
Speaker 3:  you send packets. And I'm just going to get out of the way. It's
Speaker 3:  really simple, like wifi, but it's built for low power
Speaker 3:  devices. It's got great range. Great on in
Speaker 3:  terms of reliability. And then, you know, it can, it can mesh so you can
Speaker 3:  easily extend coverage throughout the network.
Speaker 4:  It's wonderful. It's great. Are there any gadgets that I could connect to
Speaker 4:  this wonderful network?
Speaker 5:  No, I think, I think
Speaker 5:  my lights come on
Speaker 3:  With, with matter. There's a shot that all of this comes together.
Speaker 3:  There's just, there's so many different ecosystems. There's Z-Wave wave there's.
Speaker 5:  Have you ever been to the Z-Wave Alliance building? I haven't. Okay. If
Speaker 5:  anyone knows what that building is shaped like a Z, please let me know. Like,
Speaker 5:  if your organization is called the Z-Wave Alliance and you don't find a Z
Speaker 5:  shaped building to be in, like, you're not going to succeed. Okay.
Speaker 4:  Generally the question is like what what's taking so long for thread. If
Speaker 4:  it's such a great technology, what's taken so long. We, we, we are living
Speaker 4:  in this incredibly fragmented smart home world thread seems like a good one,
Speaker 4:  potentially good solution, but there's too many standards. We've gotta make
Speaker 4:  a new standard. Why isn't,
Speaker 3:  It's just these things just take off. They take a long time. All right. Imagine
Speaker 3:  for us, for a lot of people in this room, like we've been doing connected
Speaker 3:  home things for a very long time. When you look at
Speaker 3:  just the average customer, that stuff is
Speaker 3:  still, it's just starting. And now that there's,
Speaker 3:  you know, voice control layers that make things easier to
Speaker 3:  control, you don't have to do a bunch of custom programming on a home
Speaker 3:  automation system. We're just, we're, we're starting to get there. And
Speaker 3:  then it's the chicken or the egg problem. Like you have to have
Speaker 3:  enough base station support for it so that devices can connect.
Speaker 3:  And then you also need enough devices to move everything together.
Speaker 3:  And that,
Speaker 5:  I love it. Let me, I'll push you there. Like I've got a bunch of heroes in
Speaker 5:  my house. Yep. They support thread. I can turn them on. Apple is in
Speaker 5:  the thread. The home pod mini is a thread router,
Speaker 5:  but they won't talk to each other yet. Right? Like the arrows are not
Speaker 5:  HomeKit compatible. And then if I want to add a handful of
Speaker 5:  thread devices, they actually still need a home pod mini or an apple TV.
Speaker 5:  And they won't talk to the like, how are you solving that? Are you going
Speaker 5:  to talk to apple or give me home kit? Was that something apple needs to do?
Speaker 3:  I think that that's where matter starts to become interesting. You're going
Speaker 3:  to have these profiles for all the different devices. It's independent of
Speaker 3:  how the devices are connecting. We have the Eero pro six, the
Speaker 3:  six, the Eero pro and the Eero beacon are all thread, border routers. You
Speaker 3:  can turn that on today. I've got nano leaf bulbs that connect
Speaker 3:  via threat.
Speaker 5:  I love it. Like network. What's the first nerd product we
Speaker 5:  should do. It's like gamer lights. Yes. And like everybody has them.
Speaker 3:  So I, I think it, it, it is, it's been slower
Speaker 3:  than I certainly would have liked, but it feels like it is gaining
Speaker 3:  momentum and starting to finally move in the right dress.
Speaker 5:  So you're kind of in the middle of it. Do you see the, and I recognize that
Speaker 5:  this is what matters is supposed to solve, but I see apple saying, we
Speaker 5:  still kind of want our system to win. And Google wants
Speaker 5:  that. And Amazon obviously wants that and the incentives are
Speaker 5:  not aligned, right? Like if you buy everything, that's Alexa
Speaker 5:  compatible. That's probably better for Amazon that if everything works with
Speaker 5:  all three systems and you can mix and match, how, how do you align those
Speaker 5:  incentives and how do you manage it in the middle?
Speaker 3:  So, so era devices, they're going to support matter of her threat, that
Speaker 3:  that is something we are doing. And we're really, we're excited about
Speaker 3:  that. And personally, I think customers, when, when the devices
Speaker 3:  work with however they want to control them. And so
Speaker 3:  that's what we are trying to enable, trying to make sure any device can connect
Speaker 3:  to our network and communicate wherever it needs to just talks
Speaker 3:  IP, just like all their wifi devices do today. Okay. A few
Speaker 3:  more questions,
Speaker 4:  But if y'all have questions about how to configure your network, please don't
Speaker 4:  come to the mix because
Speaker 4:  there's Mike's side of the room. And so you can symbolize
Speaker 5:  And plug it right back in. That is,
Speaker 5:  well, actually the first time we talked, Nick told me that he got the idea
Speaker 5:  for Eero because he'd put his parents a wifi
Speaker 5:  set up on a power strip and he had like a fix it button that just
Speaker 5:  turned the powers trip.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Internet reset, button, power, strip, big red button.
Speaker 3:  And you could hit that. And then a V1 of automation was
Speaker 3:  you got one of those old school rotary timers. And then just once a
Speaker 3:  day, you know, it hits like 2:02 AM and just
Speaker 3:  power cycles. The whole thing
Speaker 5:  There is, remember the Cabo. I always know that an
Speaker 5:  Android based product is like gonna run into some troubles when
Speaker 5:  it has like a built-in restart feature. That's like, just, I'm gonna reset
Speaker 5:  up right now. It's that good? All right.
Speaker 4:  So what's next for thread with hero? Like you say, you're gonna support matter.
Speaker 4:  Is there anything else you're doing anything else you're gonna put
Speaker 3:  For us right now? It's just, how do we get as much coverage thread
Speaker 3:  coverage out there as possible? You know, our devices support
Speaker 3:  ZigBee thread, Bluetooth, and obviously wifi. And
Speaker 3:  we're, we're just trying to add as many arrows out there
Speaker 3:  as possible so that we can have that low power coverage
Speaker 3:  that customers are going to need. They don't need already. So next year
Speaker 3:  matter is going to matter. You think, I think it's, everything is
Speaker 3:  trending in the right direction. We were a little early in 2017. I don't
Speaker 3:  want to be that early again, but it, it does. It
Speaker 3:  does feel different this time. It feels like, you know, there's, there's
Speaker 3:  just a lot of momentum device manufacturers are starting to
Speaker 3:  really reevaluate their roadmaps. And also the, the Silicon out
Speaker 3:  there supports all this stuff natively. So it can support
Speaker 3:  ZigBee or can support thread or can support Bluetooth. Right. All on the
Speaker 3:  same chip. So people aren't going to need. So it's just a, you know, a software
Speaker 3:  setting. So we finally are starting to get the infrastructure down to the
Speaker 3:  Silicon level to make all this stuff happen. Right.
Speaker 5:  Told me you read the subreddit, you admitted this to me backstage, the band
Speaker 5:  wakes up the CEO and then reads the subreddit, which is just
Speaker 3:  Masochistic. But I appreciate your section is real. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I know that subreddit wants to know if you're going to support home kitten
Speaker 5:  thread. Are you going to do it?
Speaker 3:  We are doing everything we can to support thread
Speaker 3:  how HomeKit fits into it. Like we're just going to have to
Speaker 3:  see how that evolves here over the next little bit. Not correct.
Speaker 12:  Hey, so huge fan. I went from an airport
Speaker 12:  to an IRO and I feel like that's probably a pretty common path for a lot
Speaker 12:  of people in this room. Your first generation of products is now
Speaker 12:  probably about five years old. And as other companies have had to
Speaker 12:  deal with recently life cycling and supporting them over the over
Speaker 12:  time of computers, living in your home that are really, really critical
Speaker 12:  to your experience. There is going to be a real
Speaker 12:  challenge. What is your strategy for, you know, keeping
Speaker 12:  those things useful for as long as possible?
Speaker 3:  Well, that is our strategy. We are, we are trying to keep the
Speaker 3:  products as a safe, secure, and
Speaker 3:  reliable as possible for as long as we feasibly can. And
Speaker 3:  so that means continuing to, you know, run regression
Speaker 3:  tests on, on all of our first-generation, eeros
Speaker 3:  standing behind them. If customers are having problems, part of that
Speaker 3:  too, like we do want to encourage customers to upgrade over
Speaker 3:  the, over the years to get faster speeds, more
Speaker 3:  reliability, frankly, we've gotten a lot better at
Speaker 3:  building these products as we've learned over the last
Speaker 3:  seven, almost eight years. But you know, again, our, our
Speaker 3:  primary goal is just keep delivering great internet experience
Speaker 3:  to our earliest supporters. And, and, and
Speaker 3:  most importantly, keeping the devices secure because
Speaker 3:  running the network is it's a lot of responsibility. We take that really
Speaker 3:  seriously.
Speaker 4:  You have a number in mind in terms of years, we're like, okay, no more. We
Speaker 4:  can't support this anymore.
Speaker 3:  We're going to try to support them as long as we, as long as we possibly
Speaker 3:  can. You know, we do run into practical limits. If a wifi
Speaker 3:  router is running more than five to seven years, it's not going to
Speaker 3:  perform the same way a new device will. You're going to
Speaker 3:  just, it'll slowly start degrading just because
Speaker 3:  the duty cycle on these things is they're on 24 hours a day,
Speaker 3:  seven days a week, and they're always sending packets. So it
Speaker 3:  is something you should, you don't need to upgrade your network every year
Speaker 3:  or even every two years, but it is something you should think about upgrading
Speaker 3:  every three to five to six years,
Speaker 3:  because it's one of the most important devices in our home.
Speaker 4:  We've got time for one, maybe two more of a please keep it quick.
Speaker 13:  Let's see. All right. So I got a smart home question for you. So we have
Speaker 13:  Z-Wave, which has obviously been around for quite a while, and it has that
Speaker 13:  standardized protocol and radio layer. So where
Speaker 13:  does thread and matter succeed where Z-Wave does it, like what
Speaker 13:  went wrong with Z-Wave because it is ubiquitous, there's lots of
Speaker 13:  devices, but we don't really see it dominating the smart home will I spend
Speaker 4:  And a building shaped like a Z? Yeah, that might be it. So
Speaker 3:  I think part of it is really separating the profile,
Speaker 3:  the device and the connectivity layer. So it's removing like
Speaker 3:  profiles and not having specific profiles for each
Speaker 3:  device. So what threads really trying to do is separate
Speaker 3:  that out where any device can connect to the network, send packets,
Speaker 3:  it can then use a matter profile if it wants to, it can extend
Speaker 3:  a matter profile or it can, you know, use whatever
Speaker 3:  application layer makes sense for that device. So it's really about
Speaker 3:  separating things and making it easier for device manufacturers
Speaker 3:  to build devices, deploy them and leverage,
Speaker 3:  you know, that means of connectivity. Another thing is it's
Speaker 3:  about the like RF usage within the device. And so what's
Speaker 3:  great about 15 four is it's running and 2.4
Speaker 3:  gigahertz. So it just, it reduces the amount of RF you have to deal
Speaker 3:  with in the, you know, in the router, you know, for us so that,
Speaker 3:  you know, you're not having to deal with all these different frequencies
Speaker 3:  and paying that like per chip cost in three or four
Speaker 3:  or five units or however many units you have on your Eero
Speaker 3:  network.
Speaker 4:  Well, I think on that incredibly nerdy answer, that's a perfect place to
Speaker 4:  end talking about routers. So everybody Nick Weaver. Yeah. Thanks. That's
Speaker 4:  great.
Speaker 1:  All right. My thanks to Nick Weaver for coming on the verge cast, talking
Speaker 1:  to us about Eero and thread in the future of the smart home and my thanks
Speaker 1:  to you for listening to this episode. And you know what, it's been an instance
Speaker 1:  we've asked her this, if you could head over to, you know, it's apple podcasts,
Speaker 1:  that's the place to do reviews, go over there and give us a review and rating
Speaker 1:  really appreciate that. It really does help to show out this week search
Speaker 1:  cash was produced by myself, Andrew Marino and Liam James. We are going to
Speaker 1:  be taking the rest of the week off for the Thanksgiving holiday. We'll be
Speaker 1:  back next week with an extra special episode that I think you're going to
Speaker 1:  like. And then the following week we'll have that matter episode on the chat
Speaker 1:  show and so on and so on. If you got any feedback about these Tuesday episodes,
Speaker 1:  I'd really appreciate to hear that as well. You can find me on Twitter, I'm
Speaker 1:  at back lawn, or, you know, you can email me. It's not a hard email to guests.
Speaker 1:  It's just dieter@theverge.com. All right, have a good holiday for celebrating
Speaker 1:  and stay safe
Speaker 2:  Support for this episode comes from Sephora. Beauty is a story.
Speaker 2:  That's why Sephora is shining a spotlight on the black creators and brand
Speaker 2:  founders whose contributions habits have shaped the industry. They help
Speaker 2:  us clean beauty for ourselves. Like beauty founders have been leading this
Speaker 2:  charge for decades. In fact, many today's beauty trends,
Speaker 2:  products and tools have deep roots in black culture. Learn more about
Speaker 2:   commitment to supporting and celebrating black beauty at the
Speaker 2:  fora.com/celebrate black beauty.