# Transcript
ID: 61ae7870-59a6-11ec-8593-8349b5919c2c
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Matrix Awakens Unreal Engine 5 demo / Snap’s first AR Spectacles /  Android games come to Windows in 2022
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-4701140849490103990/3946575658230698949/s93290-US-4841s-1639130270.mp3
Description: Nilay Patel, Dieter Bohn, and Alex Heath discuss Epic Games' Matrix experience in Unreal Engine 5, Snap’s first AR Spectacles, streaming news, and more.
Speaker 1:  This week on the webcast Alex seat, during the show, we talk about his interview
Speaker 1:  with Ken or using Kerrianne Moss. What else is going on in the metaverse
Speaker 1:  a bunch of streaming news and then the lightning round to end a lightning
Speaker 1:  round. So it's coming up on the webcast. Now,
Speaker 1:  Hello. Welcome to Vergecast the flagship podcast of
Speaker 1:  reality. See, you got to sit in that for a
Speaker 1:  minute. Yeah, really just pull the car over
Speaker 1:  now and just thinking about what the flagship podcasts of reality would
Speaker 1:  be. And it's this. That's what I listen to. Then you can keep growing. Hi,
Speaker 1:  I'm Neil I'm your friend Deidre brown is here. I'm the glitch in the matrix.
Speaker 1:  Ooh, that's good, Alex.
Speaker 3:  I am a cyber punk mod.
Speaker 1:  Okay, good. You'll understand why that's funny. And a little bit, Heath is
Speaker 1:  going to be with us for the whole show. There's lots of talk about you, but
Speaker 1:  we will, we'll just start with, you know, one of the more exciting things
Speaker 1:  that has happened@theoldverge.com in our 10
Speaker 1:  years of running around, you hung out with counter Reeves and carry on last
Speaker 1:  this week.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. We talked about a lot of things. It was a very
Speaker 3:  interesting interview. And the reason that we talk to
Speaker 3:  them is because they are doing this new interactive
Speaker 3:  playable tech demo by epic games showing off
Speaker 3:  unreal engine five. And it's a tie in with kind of teasing the
Speaker 3:  next matrix movie, which comes out later this month. So we talked about all
Speaker 3:  that kind of, what is real, what is fake, the kind of blending of
Speaker 3:  the virtual and the real and how that's changing storytelling.
Speaker 3:  And a lot of other random things Kiana was very
Speaker 3:  classic.
Speaker 1:  You mean the video's up by the time you're listening to this, it's up. You
Speaker 1:  should go watch it. It is very much like a key on a Reeves
Speaker 1:  experience. Carry on loss is great too. Like, she's great, but
Speaker 1:  like, Kiano like literally you can just see him, like
Speaker 1:  he lights up over time. It's it's, it's just very, the whole thing
Speaker 1:  is very, at one point he was like, we do this so that we can sell
Speaker 1:  things. I mean, make art, I mean, sell things and he just starts
Speaker 1:  grinning. Like it's
Speaker 1:  very cool.
Speaker 3:  And the hand gestures are wonderful as well. And yeah, Carrie Ann Moss, not
Speaker 3:  really a fan of technology at all, even a all, which was
Speaker 3:  interesting. But yeah, we talked about kind of digital likeness, you know,
Speaker 3:  Kiana was one of the first actors ever. I found out in the process of doing
Speaker 3:  this to be, have to have himself digitally rendered
Speaker 3:  in the original matrix trilogy. And so Warner bros actually found that
Speaker 3:  footage in like a vault buried in the ground and like Idaho or
Speaker 3:  something like that and gave it to epic and epic re
Speaker 3:  rendered it with Youi for this matrix demo. And
Speaker 3:  it's, it is fairly trippy. There's a couple of times where they told me
Speaker 3:  after, like, when it's real him versus fake him. And it, it actually, it
Speaker 3:  got me like at least once and yeah, the, the intro to
Speaker 3:  this as written by Llano Chomsky, the main writer of the matrix
Speaker 3:  franchise, and then it's kind of an open world sandbox
Speaker 3:  experience that kind of showcases how Youi
Speaker 3:  five is basically just super scaling the ability to make like
Speaker 3:  actual metaverse stuff. So, yeah, it was, it was really
Speaker 3:  interesting.
Speaker 4:  And Canada was like, I'm almost ready to have a coherent thought about like
Speaker 4:  the nature of reality and unreality and how that interacts with
Speaker 4:  video games and cinema. I'm like, I'm like, I'm working my way towards it
Speaker 4:  and carry on Moss was like, yeah, no reality is cool. Everything. Like, why
Speaker 4:  would you, like, how about reality? How about I'm sitting at a table with
Speaker 4:  my family and he's like, it, it could be a virtual table. She's like, yeah,
Speaker 4:  but, but what about the real table? It was great.
Speaker 3:  Actually the most shocking takeaway from this counter
Speaker 3:  Reeves does not play video games. I thought that was really interesting
Speaker 3:  vegans. I
Speaker 1:  Can see that.
Speaker 3:  Well, he's, he's a character on cyberpunk. And I did ask him
Speaker 3:  about, you know, in cyberpunk 2077, we covered this when this was
Speaker 3:  happening, people were modding. One of the characters that you have
Speaker 3:  sex with in the game to be Canada Reeve's character. And it got
Speaker 3:  so bad that the game developer actually said, you can't do this. If we
Speaker 3:  find out you're doing this, we will ban your account. And I asked Keanu
Speaker 3:  about it and he loved it. He was like, you know, that's he was like, hell
Speaker 3:  yeah. And clearly was not
Speaker 3:  consulted on that decision. Another thing that I think fans of the
Speaker 3:  matrix will love is that counter really wants there to be a modern day
Speaker 3:  matrix video game. And basically told me point blank that Warner
Speaker 3:  bros dropped the ball 15 years ago and he would do
Speaker 3:  it. So there you go.
Speaker 1:  Well, the matrix franchise is, I don't know. I, I think I
Speaker 1:  watched it like my first week of college in 1999, it was like a field trip
Speaker 1:  that like my dorm took, you know, like it was just like one of those
Speaker 1:  eye-opening moments. I hadn't really heard about it. And then it was
Speaker 1:  like twisted and turned itself into all manner of things
Speaker 1:  in memes. So it's wild that they actually never made. The
Speaker 1:  game is like the rest of the tech and
Speaker 1:  gaming industry has done nothing, but try to make the matrix.
Speaker 1:  Yep, Nope.
Speaker 3:  They did make a game. They made two and there was only one where
Speaker 3:  you could play Neo. It was called path of Neo. It was on the chest
Speaker 3:  too. It was actually pretty good. The
Speaker 3:  gameplay was like, I watched some YouTube videos of it. It looks fun for
Speaker 3:  a PSU game and they could just remake that they could just like,
Speaker 3:  literally just do like, you're fighting as Neo as a game. Like you don't
Speaker 3:  even need to really do a story.
Speaker 1:  They would do it. And you would end up, you would end up in that dojo with
Speaker 1:  Morpheus and you would have to either grind for 60 hours to
Speaker 1:  level up two points or like pay micro
Speaker 1:  transaction fees to get a loot box that one of them would
Speaker 1:  maybe have Kung Fu in it, like, you know exactly how that game would be designed
Speaker 1:  now. Yeah. That's
Speaker 3:  Another highlight of this interview. Keanu seems very interested in being
Speaker 3:  the chief creative officer of a VR porn tech company.
Speaker 3:  So if you are listening to this show and that's what you
Speaker 3:  do, you should definitely reach out to his team. It's like, you don't
Speaker 1:  Want to admit who the audience of your show is. And sometimes you just know
Speaker 3:  It's like the Venn diagram, you know, it's like extremely verge
Speaker 3:  shitted in one corner, Keanu, Reeves, VR porn, and then it all just kind
Speaker 3:  of meets in the middle because
Speaker 1:  He has to see any of the movie at all. Do they preview the
Speaker 3:  Movie? No, I just, I've only seen the trailers. They were very cagey about
Speaker 3:  it. Something surprising Carrie Ann said is that it's funny, which I
Speaker 3:  wouldn't expect from a matrix movie, but, well, the first
Speaker 1:  Action movie was kind of
Speaker 3:  Funny, I guess it had funny moments, but I think the tone of this is going
Speaker 3:  to be a lot more funny than the, than the previous ones.
Speaker 3:  Okay.
Speaker 1:  I could see, I mean the whole like red pill, like cultural
Speaker 1:  association is such that I know what you sisters like want to break
Speaker 1:  it. Yeah. Because it is now associated with the alt-right and all that. Like
Speaker 1:  I get why they'd want to change the tone about red pill blue. We'll
Speaker 1:  see, I'm excited to see this movie, but I'm burnt on the previous two.
Speaker 1:  Like yeah. We're so disappointed. Anyhow is
Speaker 1:  the unreal stuff better than Gemini man. The movie in which will Smith
Speaker 1:  was famously.
Speaker 3:  Oh my God. Yeah. I mean, as a story
Speaker 3:  objective. Yes. But like literally anything
Speaker 3:  the tech is, I think the thing that impressed me the most is that, so you're
Speaker 3:  in this giant kind of sandbox city that they built, that they're going to
Speaker 3:  give to unreal developers to build like their own grand theft auto in, for
Speaker 3:  example, and everything is rendered in real
Speaker 3:  time, everywhere persistently. So like
Speaker 3:  anywhere you move, it's already there. It's already rendered down to the
Speaker 3:  detail and like a chain link fence. So like we flew up and then we shot down
Speaker 3:  into an Allan. He was like that didn't render as we moved down there that
Speaker 3:  was already there in full detail. And I've never seen that at that scale
Speaker 3:  in a game. So it's showing just kind of the power of the world building there.
Speaker 3:  And then also the ability for this is a little more geeky, but the
Speaker 3:  lighting is actually pretty cool. You don't need to know really
Speaker 3:  apparently placing lights in games as a super expensive tedious
Speaker 3:  process that really hinders the ability for it to look real and a big
Speaker 3:  breakthrough in  is this kind of automatically AI
Speaker 3:  powered lighting system that reflects naturally. And like, you
Speaker 3:  can, you can change the sunlight, you know, with a dial in the game as you
Speaker 3:  play and watch all the reflections against the skyscrapers change. I think
Speaker 3:  it's the cars and it's pretty cool, honestly. I mean, it's the idea
Speaker 3:  is that you'll be able to take, like, you know, a car maker will make a car
Speaker 3:  for a work, you know, simulation thing and , and that
Speaker 3:  same hyper-realistic looking car could then be used in a racing
Speaker 3:  game. It could then be used in the next fast and furious movie all as the
Speaker 3:  same asset in , which has signed well, it hasn't existed before.
Speaker 1:  That's really cool. I've been playing the grand theft auto remasters, which
Speaker 1:  are very fun. And I was like reading about them and how they did them. And
Speaker 1:  they, one of the biggest pieces of that puzzle was
Speaker 1:  lighting. So the original, they were just lit like the game
Speaker 1:  designers, like the scenes were just lit, like it made no sense where the
Speaker 1:  lights are coming from. We didn't have the technology, we updated the
Speaker 1:  lighting design and we try to naturally light the game. And we
Speaker 1:  had to go through and like add streetlights to
Speaker 1:  places because there wasn't, they made no sense where the light was coming
Speaker 1:  from before. And that was like, the work of remastering. This game was just
Speaker 1:  re rejiggering all the lighting, that all that stuff is
Speaker 1:  like the confluence of game engines,
Speaker 1:  movie special effects. And then the metaverse stuff. It does feel
Speaker 1:  like it will all just kind of be the same software at the end.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. And it's, this is honestly like epic is the perfect company to, to
Speaker 3:  make all this because their CTO, Kim, who I also interviewed for the
Speaker 3:  story worked on the original matrix trilogy. He has a film background and
Speaker 3:  he did all the, he was an effects supervisor on kind of bullet time and like
Speaker 3:  all new kind of iconic matrix stuff and knows the Chelsea's, that's kind
Speaker 3:  of how this whole project came together. And he was talking a
Speaker 3:  lot about how he thinks it's going to change Hollywood and epic has already.
Speaker 3:  So like in the Mandalorian, in camera visual effects where there's a
Speaker 3:  giant led wall behind you, instead of CGI and post with a green
Speaker 3:  screen, that's being powered by unreal. And that
Speaker 3:  technology he thinks is going to really just change how Hollywood runs or
Speaker 3:  I think he hopes it will. So, yeah, they're a very interesting company. Unreal
Speaker 3:  is like this really fascinating, powerful thing that touches a lot of
Speaker 3:  things, but consumers don't really see. So it's a little wonky, but I mean,
Speaker 3:  if you're talking about like, metaverse like, this is actually like the toolkit,
Speaker 3:  right? This is actually the thing like Metta, the company does not have
Speaker 3:  anything remotely like this. I just, so I think it's interesting.
Speaker 1:  Did we, do we, I don't know if we talked about this last week, unity, the
Speaker 1:  other big game studio just bought what a digital, which was
Speaker 1:  Peter Jackson's special effects house for $1.6
Speaker 1:  billion. And like that's Lord of the rings and avatar and
Speaker 1:  Shang sheet. Like you can just see where it's going, that the, the game
Speaker 1:  engines are now getting good enough to do the special effects
Speaker 1:  everywhere.
Speaker 3:  And that's why there was a story about epic hiring a head
Speaker 3:  of film and like scripted entertainment. And I kind of got at this
Speaker 3:  with the CTO that they're going to start doing games that are also
Speaker 3:  movies using Fortnite using other things, because
Speaker 3:  allows them to just use these assets across mediums, which it's pretty cool.
Speaker 3:  It's a, it's a new thing for
Speaker 1:  Sure. Now I feel like a genius for telling people to watch red versus blue.
Speaker 1:  When I was looking through the early two thousands, right? This, this is
Speaker 1:  dumb sitcom that takes place in halo is the future of
Speaker 1:  entertainment. I said to no effect at the
Speaker 1:  bar, but I was right. It always comes out.
Speaker 4:  I'm just excited that all of this means that within the next,
Speaker 4:  well, let's be, let's be realistic within the next 10 years. We'll get rid
Speaker 4:  of quick time events that are just, you know, pre-rendered cut scenes where
Speaker 4:  you hit the button at the right time.
Speaker 3:  I didn't know this, but apparently all the Fortnite commercials are shot
Speaker 3:  in fortnight, like in real time. And so like, they're already doing
Speaker 3:  this. He's like, we just stage it in the game and we shoot it. And like,
Speaker 3:  we may like touch up things and make the characters look a little shiny or,
Speaker 3:  but like, they're already doing this. And like part of this matrix thing
Speaker 3:  is like, there's a car chase scene where the camera's like going under the
Speaker 3:  car and around the car. And like, that was all done in the engine. Right.
Speaker 3:  They didn't like have cars out on the street that they then tracked and brought
Speaker 3:  into . So it's, we're getting into a weird uncharted
Speaker 3:  territory.
Speaker 1:  So one of the reasons I asked about Gemini man, which is so
Speaker 1:  horrible,
Speaker 4:  It's not even an
Speaker 1:  Airplane movie. It's like, it's not even an F it's like, unwatchably bad.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. There are these really
Speaker 1:  hilarious, like YouTube clips where
Speaker 1:  people, I think Gemini man was actually like shot in
Speaker 1:  120 frames per second. And we're like released that way. But there are these
Speaker 1:  YouTube channels that like oppressed things into higher frame rates.
Speaker 1:  So you can go watch Gemini man at like 120 frames per
Speaker 1:  second on YouTube. And it looks, I mean, it looks like a bad video game.
Speaker 1:  It's like, there's no way to describe it. Just go watch it. It's like horrifying,
Speaker 1:  but a big piece of that puzzle that the big piece, that story of that movie
Speaker 1:  came out was there is now a model of young will Smith and like
Speaker 1:  who was going to own the digital character model of young will
Speaker 1:  Smith and what could that model be made to do and
Speaker 1:  who owned it? And like if the young will Smith model
Speaker 1:  acts in the new movie, will Smith get paid? Did you get into any of
Speaker 1:  that with, with Kiana? And
Speaker 3:  Yes, we did. And apparently Keanu saw this coming
Speaker 3:  like decades ago and has for ever had in his
Speaker 3:  contract where he has to approve any use or edits to his digital
Speaker 3:  likeness in any format. And he's like, this is happening.
Speaker 3:  Like we're having these conversations in Hollywood about like, it's almost
Speaker 3:  like estate planning is like, what are you going to do with your digital
Speaker 3:  likeness? And he's like in like Marilyn, Monroe's in a Coke commercial. And
Speaker 3:  you know, he was talking about how Marlon Brando's with Superman was talking
Speaker 3:  about this already, like decades ago. And so, yeah,
Speaker 3:  I, I do think it's something that's like on celebrity's
Speaker 3:  minds is like, how do I license my likeness?
Speaker 3:  And you know, like I asked him, so the matrix did this NFT thing for the
Speaker 3:  new movie and at the site like crashed after the first like
Speaker 3:  hour. And there were 300,000 people in the queue for like a hundred thousand
Speaker 3:  in FTS, at 50 bucks, a pop and Kiana and Kerianne were not in
Speaker 3:  FTS for that side. They obviously did not approve the use of them. But yeah,
Speaker 3:  they thought that was interesting. And Canada was like, do we get a cut of
Speaker 3:  that? I was like, oh, probably, probably not. But he was like, it's all
Speaker 3:  capitalism, man. You know, like, it's a,
Speaker 1:  That's all I want. If that's, if that's what you got out of your time within
Speaker 1:  then mission accomplished. One of my favorite copyright cases I ever
Speaker 1:  had in law school was a Vanna white V Samsung
Speaker 1:  electronics. I think that's the case. Caption, Samsung had an
Speaker 1:  ad for like washing machines where a robot
Speaker 1:  like turned letters like wheel of fortune.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. And Vanna white was like, that robotics is too much like me, you're
Speaker 1:  using my likeness and that's an unauthorized use of me and it's like a
Speaker 1:  robot. And she was like, it's amazing. And my law professor
Speaker 1:  was like, yeah, it's a California case like California, like the California
Speaker 1:  courts are always inside with Hollywood. Like it was like open in his mind.
Speaker 1:  It was open and shut. Like the corrupt California courts have
Speaker 1:  once again taken the side of big Hollywood, but it's like,
Speaker 1:  that was ages ago. And now we're all the way to, there's a digital Keanu
Speaker 1:  Reeves that is contractually obligated to only do what the owner use wants.
Speaker 1:  It's pretty good. You did some other, I mean your senior metaverse reporter
Speaker 1:  Alex, that's your, that's your title? Do you all see it? I mean, he had a
Speaker 1:  big week. He's also saw snaps, AR spectacles. You got to try them
Speaker 1:  on they're there. They seem very prototype to me.
Speaker 3:  Oh, very prototyping. I mean, the battery lasts for 30 minutes. The first
Speaker 3:  pair they gave me overheated, after less than 10, they
Speaker 3:  had like four onsite that they tried to like seamlessly swap out. As I
Speaker 3:  tried different lenses, you know, which are snaps, AR effects
Speaker 3:  so that I never noticed the battery. Definitely the best software on any
Speaker 3:  air, air glasses I've used. You can tell, they've thought a lot about the
Speaker 3:  interface. There's like this carousel you see through your eyes and it's
Speaker 3:  a touch thing and there's voice the thing that is the most promising on these
Speaker 3:  that I think probably won't be cool for several more years is a scan
Speaker 3:  button. I did another video thing on our site about a month or two ago
Speaker 3:  about this and the Snapchat app. It's like visual search, right? Google lens.
Speaker 3:  It's their stab at this. And they're working with a lot of other developers
Speaker 3:  right now, but I scanned a plant, you know, with my glasses and it
Speaker 3:  recommended some plant-based lenses. And like, you expand that
Speaker 3:  out a few years and you're walking around and you can just search
Speaker 3:  anything. I mean, it's, it's going to be wild. And they also like, they're
Speaker 3:  doing like club mapping to your clothing where like a
Speaker 3:  AR jacket will drape. Like it would naturally imagine putting
Speaker 3:  that on someone, you know, three years glasses or making them they're your
Speaker 3:  Bitmoji. Right? Like there's just so many ways that this is going to get
Speaker 3:  trippy, but yeah, definitely a prototype, but they're being like oddly humble
Speaker 3:  about it. Especially considering like the way that the first spectacles were
Speaker 3:  hyped beyond belief. And they ended up sitting
Speaker 3:  on 40 million and unsold inventory that they had right off. They're
Speaker 3:  just not selling these. They're giving them to hundreds of AR
Speaker 3:  creators just to try and play with. And it's, it's really a learning thing
Speaker 3:  for them. And I think that's really smart because if these things were sold
Speaker 3:  to the public, they probably cost thousands of dollars and everyone would
Speaker 3:  be like, what the hell? This thing dies after 30 minutes, what's the field
Speaker 3:  of view. Like it's so narrow, that's the thing like they optimized
Speaker 3:  for brightness and for color. And so, you know,
Speaker 3:  maybe half of the frame is the wave guide is what you can actually see. And
Speaker 3:  so I found that the lenses looked better in post, on my
Speaker 3:  phone, seeing what I was seeing through the glasses than they did in the
Speaker 3:  glasses, because I had Y wide field of view. So once that gets
Speaker 3:  there, once it fills that full kind of this thing looks like a cyber truck
Speaker 3:  on your face. So like once it fuels that wide kind of
Speaker 3:  lens, it's going to be wild. I mean, it's, it's going to take years
Speaker 3:  though, to get there. This really showed that battery and display are the
Speaker 3:  two things that I don't know are going to be cracked for a while.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. That the let's talk about this play for just a couple more minutes.
Speaker 4:  I mean, I know the field of view is narrow, but was it good? I mean,
Speaker 4:  the Dem doing this outdoors is kind of a flex, like I've done hollowlens
Speaker 4:  stuff. Disclosure. My wife works for
Speaker 4:  meta. What's the division that is maybe called
Speaker 4:  Oculus. Maybe not, I don't know over
Speaker 4:  there, but like, what was it
Speaker 4:  good? Like if, if you were to just take the display that you had at give
Speaker 4:  it a proper field of you, would you have been like, this? Is it
Speaker 4:  it's there? Or is it still feel like weirded, pixelated and
Speaker 4:  whatever?
Speaker 3:  No, it wasn't pixelated. It was, they have 2000 nits of brightness in this
Speaker 3:  thing. So it works a lot sunlight, which is why the battery
Speaker 3:  dies and it over needs after 10 minutes, but they're optimizing for
Speaker 3:  visual richness so that people can make compelling AR experiences
Speaker 3:  so that when the tech catches up the software kind of pipelines already
Speaker 3:  there, which is another piece of this they're being, I think very smart about
Speaker 3:  kind of seeding the developer ecosystem very early Metta is not doing
Speaker 3:  this, which I think is curious. But yeah, no, the display was
Speaker 3:  probably the most impressive I've used on a standalone device. Again, this
Speaker 3:  thing isn't tethered to anything for, for complainant and the glasses were
Speaker 3:  light. Like, I didn't feel like they were heavy on my face
Speaker 3:  or like I wanted to take them off after a few minutes. Like you could theoretically
Speaker 3:  wear these all day and be fine. You'd look really weird.
Speaker 3:  But so yeah, I think there's a lot of promise there.
Speaker 3:  And, you know, snap is this kind of silent, dark horse in these AR glasses
Speaker 3:  metaverse wars where they were actually kind of the first to like, think
Speaker 3:  about this in a serious way. And they're just kind of quietly iterating
Speaker 3:  now a little bit in public, which I think is interesting because they'd been
Speaker 3:  so secretive, but yeah, I mean the display apparently is so good that they
Speaker 3:  bought the supplier. That was one of our first
Speaker 3:  scooch that I did a wave optics. They're our largest deal ever for
Speaker 3:  half a billion dollars just to get the kind of display tech lock for
Speaker 3:  them. So, yeah, man, this is all, it's all starting to come
Speaker 3:  together. I mean, it's definitely not compelling for consumers,
Speaker 3:  but this was the first time doing one of these demos where I was like in
Speaker 3:  a few years, I can see this being really compelling. And it's going to kind
Speaker 3:  of flip how we think about computing. I think I have a big,
Speaker 1:  I agree with you like the, the part where you can see the software
Speaker 1:  applications are way ahead of the hardware is utterly
Speaker 1:  fascinating. That hasn't really happened in many other
Speaker 1:  places. Like you just like throw a dart at the board and think
Speaker 1:  about some other hyped, future hardware,
Speaker 1:  like 3d TVs, or like interactive
Speaker 1:  TVs as a whole, right? Like you're going to be shopping on your TV or you're
Speaker 1:  gonna be watching all the live cameras from a foot. Like none of that has
Speaker 1:  come to pass. It's all just streams. Like the software, even
Speaker 1:  of the hardware and the service ecosystems are there. The software
Speaker 1:  is kind of where it always was. In this case, a hardware is nowhere near
Speaker 1:  close, but everyone already has a pretty clear picture
Speaker 1:  of what it should be. And the
Speaker 1:  basics of like, we're going to point a camera at a thing and then do some
Speaker 1:  computer stuff and then layer some information or experiences
Speaker 1:  over that thing. That picture is really clear. So you can already like, apple
Speaker 1:  is already doing it. Snap is already doing it. Sam started doing it on Apple's
Speaker 1:  phones. Like you can see, but the hardware is really far
Speaker 1:  away.
Speaker 3:  And these lenses though beat these lenses are getting smart. So you can
Speaker 3:  have links and lenses now for the first time that kick out to like a store.
Speaker 3:  So if a creator makes like a something for their shoe, you can just go buy
Speaker 3:  it in the lens. There's music from all the labels in there, they're
Speaker 3:  bringing in outside apps for the first time. So you can have like FTX, crypto
Speaker 3:  trading in a lens or AQI whether you can pump in like the
Speaker 3:  temperature into a lens. So they're starting to become
Speaker 3:  interactive in real time where, before they were these static kind of more
Speaker 3:  artsy things. Yeah. It's like they were saying someone has spent two years
Speaker 3:  making a lens that can measure anything like, and there's another one that
Speaker 3:  can tell you if your surfboard is a good surf board based on its contours.
Speaker 3:  And so they're just coming up with all these wild things that once we have
Speaker 3:  these glasses, like it's, it's gonna be
Speaker 1:  Cool. I won't give too much away because it won't be out by the time you
Speaker 1:  listen to this. But my antic CEO, John hankie is on decoder next week
Speaker 1:  nine and tech makes Pokemon go. They have a big partnership with Qualcomm
Speaker 1:  to make smart glasses. I've got a references on floating around. I fell
Speaker 1:  down an absolute research rabbit hole of how these
Speaker 1:  displays work before I talked to him, they're all kind of the same, right?
Speaker 1:  You get like, there's two tiny LCD displays and the stems of the
Speaker 1:  glasses. And then there's a reflector and there's a bunch of
Speaker 1:  mirrors are not mirrors. There's a bunch of codings or
Speaker 1:  etchings on layers, wave guides. Yeah. Yeah. It's a bounce
Speaker 1:  that display onto your eyes. And so I, you know, I just pushed him. I was
Speaker 1:  like, is this it is like, can I go, am I going to go from here to here? I
Speaker 1:  see the first ever LCD display
Speaker 1:  on a primitive smartphone. And I know in my mind,
Speaker 1:  this technology is really important. Soon. LCDs will take over every
Speaker 1:  display in the world with some OLEDs on the side, right? Like, is
Speaker 1:  this the technology bet? Or is it, this is the best we
Speaker 1:  got and maybe something else will come up. And he was like, this is it like
Speaker 1:  this, this wave guy technology will, it will get to where we want it
Speaker 1:  to go. Which I guess if you're like in the partnership with Qualcomm or shipping
Speaker 1:  wave guide, like maybe that's what you say, but snap made that big investment
Speaker 1:  and bought that company. It makes wave guides. There are Hollins
Speaker 1:  is wave, like magic leap was supposed to make something else. And
Speaker 1:  they ended up at wave guides. It's what we got.
Speaker 4:  I don't know, because again, HoloLens has been around
Speaker 4:  and like it's wacky wave guides with an LCD. You're like,
Speaker 4:  okay, get better at the manufacturing process, the LCD gets
Speaker 4:  bigger and more responsive. Like there's like a hardware improvement
Speaker 4:  arc there. And I don't, I am not smart enough to know.
Speaker 4:  Is that what the hardware improvement arc for a wave guide is? Is it just
Speaker 4:  like we get better and better at etching until we can finally make them be?
Speaker 3:  My understanding is these things are constrained by size and battery and
Speaker 3:  like thermodynamics more than anything like these wave guides can power.
Speaker 3:  There's a reason magic leap raised $2 billion. It's because they had
Speaker 3:  people look into a thing called the beast. That was the size of the
Speaker 3:  closet that had all the computing, it needed to power this thing
Speaker 3:  appropriately. So when they have that, they can do incredible things
Speaker 3:  already. It's just getting it into a form factor. This is what Zuckerberg
Speaker 3:  is talking about with me. And Casey, like getting that form factor is, is
Speaker 3:  the hard part, right?
Speaker 1:  Yeah. But, but the beast, it's just like the best quote
Speaker 1:  ever. The CEO of magic leap was like, we're hacking the GPU of your
Speaker 1:  brain. And what, what he meant was they're going to send light into your
Speaker 1:  eyes in a way that mimics reality, that isn't just an emissive
Speaker 1:  flat plane wave guys, or just a flat plane of light,
Speaker 1:  right. It just, all the electronics are in the stems of the glasses. And
Speaker 1:  it's bouncing the light through that. So Dieter your question. Like if you
Speaker 1:  watch, there's like lots of like trade
Speaker 1:  industry presentations from wave guide suppliers. I need, I'm telling you,
Speaker 1:  I fell deep into it. And like all their presentations are like,
Speaker 1:  here's our process. Here's where the cost is. Here's where the cost is coming
Speaker 1:  down. And they're trying to convince you basically that they're using
Speaker 1:  standard glass, making screen, making techniques to
Speaker 1:  make this next generation of wave guide pieces of glass. The actual
Speaker 1:  display is still just like a tiny little LCD and the stems
Speaker 1:  of the glasses. Right. They're just bouncing it in front of your eyes with
Speaker 1:  these wave guides that they're still expensive. So like they're trying to
Speaker 1:  make that cheaper, but they haven't, I don't know. I don't know that it's
Speaker 1:  the bet. Like it feels like it's the resistive touch screen of the
Speaker 1:  AR world, you know, that can get you there. And then someday Steve jobs is
Speaker 1:  going to show up with like the capacitive touch screen iPhone. Everyone's
Speaker 1:  going to be like, oh, that's what we should have.
Speaker 3:  This is a good segue to apple because there is a continuum here where the
Speaker 3:  wave guys in the air glasses are happening on one side of this. That's definitely
Speaker 3:  several years out at minimum till we have that at scale what's
Speaker 3:  happening in the near term. And I think 20, 22 will be the year of is
Speaker 3:  pass through mixed reality, proper LCD, whatever it's
Speaker 3:  going to be, no wave guides, but basically tricking you
Speaker 3:  by piping and video of the outside world and mixing it with the
Speaker 3:  graphics. And that's what Apple's going to do. It's what med has got with
Speaker 3:  Cambridge, which is this headset they're working on for next
Speaker 3:  year. And I think that's going to really show people that
Speaker 3:  there is something there's like a stop gap before we get to AR glasses. And
Speaker 3:  it's that mixed reality pass through.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. And I think that's like the reason that apple is doing
Speaker 1:  pastor video in a VR headset and potentially why Matt is doing it
Speaker 1:  too, is because apple cannot ship glasses with a teeny tiny field of view.
Speaker 1:  They get really hot. They they've got to ship a, it like their brand is
Speaker 1:  finished consumer products. And that core technology of a piece
Speaker 1:  of a display that you can look through is just like, what we got
Speaker 1:  is wave guide. I'm like, I encourage everyone. Like if you're a huge nerd,
Speaker 1:  you'll see in the shot, like, go look at how you guys were. It's neat. It's
Speaker 1:  super cool. But at the end of the day, it's like, you're wearing the entire
Speaker 1:  hollow lens in your head and you've got like a post-it stamp in the middle
Speaker 1:  of your field of vision. It's like put the spark plug in the
Speaker 1:  ATV, you know, like this is not that
Speaker 1:  great. I think it's really neat. Like we're
Speaker 1:  just in a place now. I think it's fascinating that every software developer
Speaker 1:  is like ready for this. And the hardware is just like years, like
Speaker 1:  five, at least out from what I can tell the other thing, the little
Speaker 1:  decoder preview, I'll give you, you were talking about how snap has filters.
Speaker 1:  Like everyone could be wearing different clothes. So I was like, how are
Speaker 1:  you going to govern reality? Like in, and he was like, everyone can just
Speaker 1:  pick and choose. Like, what if we all just like, it's like, I don't govern
Speaker 1:  what song you listened to and you walked down the street. Why should I, why
Speaker 1:  should I govern what you're looking at? And he was just like, there's only
Speaker 1:  a marketplace of realities. This is my new phrase. It's going to be terrifying.
Speaker 1:  Put that on a
Speaker 3:  Shirt.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, this is gonna be great. All right, we should take a break and we should
Speaker 1:  come back. There's a, there's like a lot of streaming he's talking about.
Speaker 1:  We'll wrap
Speaker 1:  back.
Speaker 1:  All right. We're back there is like a lot of, how would you describe this
Speaker 1:  low stakes streaming drama,
Speaker 4:  Low stakes streaming drama, and like news. That seems unimportant, but
Speaker 4:  actually could be massively important.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. It's like, it's, it's that? It's like, we're going to have to convince
Speaker 1:  you that a lot of these things are important. So buckle
Speaker 1:  up, let's start the Keanu Reeves, Karen Ross video app,
Speaker 1:  because of the game awards. They're announcing the unreal stuff there, but
Speaker 1:  Google is announcing specific game wards to it, which is by the way, we are
Speaker 1:  recording this before the game awards happen, but you're listening to
Speaker 1:  it after they've happened.
Speaker 4:  Right. So imagine there, we're just assuming there's like huge game streaming
Speaker 4:  news and we're reacting to that. It's amazing. It's going to change everything.
Speaker 4:  We don't know,
Speaker 1:  But there's some like Google news coming. Yeah. Well,
Speaker 4:  This isn't streaming, but apparently Google play games is going to be available
Speaker 4:  on windows. So it's like Android up some windows. Here we
Speaker 4:  go. And it's interesting instead of just bringing
Speaker 4:  the whole of Google play Android apps, they're bringing Google play
Speaker 4:  games, which is a fascinating decision.
Speaker 1:  Are they bringing that into Microsoft's weird Android
Speaker 1:  app universe?
Speaker 4:  Unclear. What do you mean by that?
Speaker 1:  Like Microsoft signed a deal with Amazon. They use the Amazon app store to
Speaker 1:  get Android apps on windows. Right. But then they were also like, you can
Speaker 1:  use any app store you want, so are they building like a special windows?
Speaker 1:  Google play games. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. They're making Google play games, a Google play games store where you
Speaker 4:  can download and install Android games for when
Speaker 1:  And that's running inside of the windows, Android app compatibility. Not
Speaker 1:  some weird new Google layer.
Speaker 4:  So that is a little bit unclear because it's
Speaker 4:  like Google. Isn't like partnering with Microsoft to make this happen. They're
Speaker 4:  just doing it.
Speaker 1:  This is going to go great. Yeah. Okay. So that's one thing. We'll see how
Speaker 1:  that goes. You can see how Google just needs to diversify its revenue base
Speaker 1:  has all the app store drama continues to go like
Speaker 1:  getting more of its game stuff out in the world is I think good for
Speaker 1:  Google. Like apple would love this to be happening on the Mac. I just don't
Speaker 1:  think they're ever going to convince any game developer to take the Mac seriously.
Speaker 1:  Even the game developers on the iPhone are like why maybe with like, as M
Speaker 1:  one chips become more widespread game, developers will make the easy jump
Speaker 1:  to games on the Mac, but it just kind of hasn't happened yet.
Speaker 4:  I mean, the whole question with games right now is like, what is the
Speaker 4:  future of like the platforms that you're going to be thinking about? Like
Speaker 4:  what the games run on because they keep making Android
Speaker 4:  games. That seems to like, you know, I, I now believe
Speaker 4:  that Android gaming phones exist and have a purpose. I've been
Speaker 4:  convinced by who just looking at the world, looking at the
Speaker 4:  market, looking at the Chinese market. Like they don't, they they're not
Speaker 4:  making them for no reason. Yeah. So there's that there's of course the
Speaker 4:  various streaming platforms. There's windows,
Speaker 4:  there's Xbox there's PlayStation. There's like the
Speaker 4:  various inner versions of Xbox and it's streaming
Speaker 1:  Stadia now runs on LG TVs.
Speaker 4:  Yes. So the thing that's interesting about that to me
Speaker 4:  is, well, of course it does. It's just like, it's just a video
Speaker 4:  stream. Yeah. Like the it's potentially a big deal.
Speaker 4:  It's like the, the rules of how you think about what your screen
Speaker 4:  can do are changing. Like they were changing slowly
Speaker 4:  and now they're changing really quickly. So whether or not you can just
Speaker 4:  play console quality games on your LGTV was just a matter of
Speaker 4:  when did they get around to creating the, you know,
Speaker 4:  casting and points app for web alas. It's actually
Speaker 4:  not that difficult. And I just, I don't know, like
Speaker 4:  where that's going to shake out. Are you going to care where your game comes
Speaker 4:  from? Are you going to care if it's local or streaming? And the, the
Speaker 4:  fact that it's, it's just a question of like, who's gotten around to building
Speaker 4:  a client for the thing this even applies to like Google play games on
Speaker 4:  windows is really interesting. So like, honestly,
Speaker 4:  this kind of leads us up to talking about the
Speaker 4:  Roku YouTube drama a little bit, I think. Yeah. Other than
Speaker 1:  It's settle it this week. So Roku and Google
Speaker 1:  were about to Sue each other. Like they had switched.
Speaker 1:  It hadn't gotten very far. They were, who was going to kick YouTube off
Speaker 1:  its platform. Google had done some shady stuff on other platforms. They built
Speaker 1:  YouTube TV into the YouTube app. Cause he can't get rid of the YouTube app,
Speaker 1:  but they were at the kind of the brinksmanship point. They're going to
Speaker 1:  walk,
Speaker 4:  They're going to pull YouTube from Roku,
Speaker 1:  Which I pull YouTube from Roku. And I gotta say the arguments were
Speaker 1:  dumb. Like if you read like Roku put all of these blog
Speaker 1:  posts and like whatever, like the arguments they were having were when you
Speaker 1:  push the Roku voice search button and the YouTube app is
Speaker 1:  open, what voice search should you go to?
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Okay. Google was like Google, like ours and record was
Speaker 1:  like, no, the operating systems. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  By the way, they won that front. Like Samsung, unlike my Samsung frame TV,
Speaker 4:  the microphone button, like it's a Google button, it's a Google assistant
Speaker 4:  button. But when you're in the YouTube app, it ceases to be a Google assistant
Speaker 4:  button and it becomes a YouTube search button. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. These arguments are like, they're very Vergecast arguments.
Speaker 1:  Like what do you think then should the native control
Speaker 1:  supersede the applications control. Right? And like, there are
Speaker 1:  other ones where if you had the YouTube app
Speaker 1:  open and you search for a movie using Roku voice
Speaker 1:  search, the native Roku voice search
Speaker 1:  would pull movies from the applications that supported its
Speaker 1:  library. Right. And so at Google's big complaint was like, this movie is
Speaker 1:  available for free on YouTube. You should be showing users,
Speaker 1:  which sounds great. But also if you're in the YouTube app, like you
Speaker 1:  should like it. None of it made sense. We were like how actual
Speaker 1:  people use their software, but
Speaker 1:  it all just seemed like little corner cases of what the buttons on your route
Speaker 1:  did. If the YouTube app was open and the, like, it just seems like Google
Speaker 1:  believes that people open the YouTube app and live in at 24 hours a day when
Speaker 1:  they watch TV, which maybe people do, but does not seem that
Speaker 1:  likely when you're searching for like a Disney
Speaker 1:  movie.
Speaker 3:  I gotta say, hearing you guys talk about all this makes me think there should
Speaker 3:  just be some good old fashioned consolidation in this
Speaker 3:  industry.
Speaker 4:  Has there been enough?
Speaker 1:  And then there's like, there's like ad money in the background. Right. Right.
Speaker 4:  Well, and so this is like, there's this like great inversion where you, you
Speaker 4:  tweet about this new, I I'm selling your idea, but like, it used to be that
Speaker 4:  like what you could play on your screen, whether it's a game or a video
Speaker 4:  or whatever was like really dependent on who your service provider
Speaker 4:  was, what the screens capabilities was, you know, what platform
Speaker 4:  you picked, et cetera. And now it's completely dependent on have
Speaker 4:  some deals been made. And as someone like done some engineering work to make
Speaker 4:  an app, your app or not.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, it is utterly. No one knows what the terms of this new deal are.
Speaker 1:  It is a multi-year deal. YouTube and YouTube TV will like
Speaker 1:  stay on the Roku platform. It's funny, Rick Roku is calling Google and
Speaker 1:  uncheck monopolous throughout all this. Because when, when they like
Speaker 1:  threatened to kick YouTube TV off the whole like money
Speaker 1:  dispute, is it Roku? Hardware is extraordinarily
Speaker 1:  cheap, right? It's like 30 bucks, 20 bucks. They don't, they're not making
Speaker 1:  any money in a hardware. All they make money on is when you sign up, just
Speaker 1:  like in any other app store, when you sign up for Disney, plus they get a
Speaker 1:  cut, right? They get a bounty of that signup. When Hulu
Speaker 1:  runs an ad on the Roku, like either those ads are served by Roku
Speaker 1:  ad services or Roku gets a cut. Like those that's just
Speaker 1:  like the app store itself. When, when any commerce happens in an
Speaker 1:  app, apple wants a cut. When any advertising or subscription happens on
Speaker 1:  a Roku, Roku gets a cut. And that's how they subsidize all the hardware.
Speaker 1:  This is the economics of every TV, by the way, like the
Speaker 1:  LG, the reason the TVs are cheap is because all of the money is made
Speaker 1:  through ongoing transactions. Like this story of adding a chip to things
Speaker 1:  and then making them connected so that they can just like charge you for
Speaker 1:  the rest of your life. That's that's where that was happening. But that's
Speaker 1:  totally backwards. Right? You used to pay your cable company and then the
Speaker 1:  cable company would pay ESPN. Yeah. Now you're paying Disney and Disney
Speaker 1:  is hang Roku. Right? And like, I don't know if that's good or bad, but it's,
Speaker 1:  it's clear. Lo Roku sees itself as like, you're not going to get another
Speaker 1:  TV box or have 50 TV boxes. They're going to have one and that one
Speaker 1:  should have all the apps you want. And if you want to be on that one, you
Speaker 1:  have to meet their terms, show up in the interface in front of other people.
Speaker 1:  And the one thing they can't get rid of is YouTube. So when they kick YouTube
Speaker 1:  TV off, like screw it, you're gone. But then Google can add YouTube
Speaker 1:  TV to YouTube because they can't think YouTube like
Speaker 1:  are, are aren't. They they're like both monopolists in that way. Like
Speaker 1:  Roku controls. Most of the streaming platform business in the
Speaker 1:  country. I don't know. Anyway, it's over. We have no idea what this deal
Speaker 1:  is. A bunch of people on a smoke cigars on
Speaker 1:  zoom and came to terms
Speaker 1:  it's shady. We'll see. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  But they're back. But so in theory, a couple of years from now, all
Speaker 4:  this is going to get shaken up again. So Jennifer Patterson Tuohy on her
Speaker 4:  site basically broke the news that there is a part of a standard
Speaker 4:  for matter. So matter is the connected home over IP standard. We're going
Speaker 4:  to have a whole Vergecast about this on Tuesday. So buckle up for that. We're
Speaker 4:  going to talk about this, but because Jennifer published a story today, I
Speaker 4:  want to talk about it briefly. So there's a part of the spec called matter
Speaker 4:  TV. I don't think most people realize what's going to be part of this smart
Speaker 4:  home standard. And it's basically just universal
Speaker 4:  casting either from app to app or app to TVs. Once they're there,
Speaker 4:  that all of these big companies have agreed. Oh yeah. If you want to tell
Speaker 4:  your screen to play a video, this standard will be
Speaker 4:  supported so it can replace airplay. It could replace Google cast.
Speaker 4:  It can replace whatever weird stuff Samsung
Speaker 4:  does. Amazon is like written the spec cause they really need it because
Speaker 4:  people have echo devices, but they don't necessarily have fire TVs,
Speaker 4:  but it's like part of the spec. And so like
Speaker 4:  casting might actually not suck next year or beginning of next
Speaker 4:  year.
Speaker 1:  Oh, I don't think doubt apple or Google or walking away from their
Speaker 1:  standards.
Speaker 4:  Well, no, but they're not walking away from their standards, but this standard
Speaker 4:  will also be supported and they are part, they like signed off on the
Speaker 4:  spec. So if you have a TV that supports
Speaker 4:  matter, it will support having this casting
Speaker 4:  standard hit it.
Speaker 1:  I mean, that's fair. I just don't think, I don't think this casting center
Speaker 1:  run up in iOS for years to come. No,
Speaker 3:  This is going to fail for sure.
Speaker 4:  I mean, it probably will. Why do you think it will fail? Because,
Speaker 3:  Because no, like we are everything you all were just saying like this entire
Speaker 3:  there's so much infighting right now in this space, everyone wants to
Speaker 3:  own their layer and their, their system and their
Speaker 3:  substrate of the TV experience and some
Speaker 3:  startup or whatever's there. There's no way. There's no way.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. So, but we're going to get to this next week. But like they have walked
Speaker 4:  away from that walled garden fight in the smart home. Everyone's like
Speaker 4:  we have hit the ceiling. We can't make any more money. We can't grow this
Speaker 4:  pie, but I'm telling you the matter shit, just it, everything
Speaker 4:  is like inter-operating and it's going to work locally. And it's based
Speaker 4:  on like equal parts from all of these big tech companies. And they're
Speaker 4:  all, you know, it'll fall, it's a standard. It'll probably fall apart. But
Speaker 4:  like, it seems like your, like your doorbell is just
Speaker 4:  going to work and it's not going to be locked into a walled garden anymore.
Speaker 4:  If it supports matter and you're gonna want it support matter. Cause then,
Speaker 4:  you know, it's easier to buy stuff. And if the matter TV
Speaker 4:  thing gets like brought in with that spec as like a Trojan horse, that
Speaker 4:  could be interesting.
Speaker 3:  All I want to do is go to a hotel and be able to cast my phone to
Speaker 3:  the TV and not have to worry about, is it a
Speaker 3:  Chrome cast? Is it an apple TV? Usually I can't stream my
Speaker 3:  iPhone because it's like a Chrome cast. And it just something that fixes
Speaker 3:  all that. Yeah. That's, that's going to be a trillion dollar company.
Speaker 4:  That's the, I mean, that's the matter spec is they, if, if the thing supports
Speaker 4:  it and it will see it locally and it will
Speaker 4:  either cast it locally from your phone or it'll like, just tell it the
Speaker 4:  URL that it needs to go grab from the internet. Yeah. Promises that it'll
Speaker 4:  all work. We'll see what it actually turns out to be. But I am very
Speaker 4:  optimistic about the smart home side of it. And the fact that there's like
Speaker 4:  a TV side being like brought in alongside that is
Speaker 4:  fascinating.
Speaker 1:  Well, you know, it's interesting. So apple didn't make a TV, which they should
Speaker 1:  instead of a car, it's put that out there. Continue to put that energy out
Speaker 1:  in the world, make a TV in our car. It seemed as soon as Warner lane, you
Speaker 1:  get it. No,
Speaker 4:  That's terrible. But that's my line. Come on.
Speaker 1:  I apologize everyone. But when I put the apple TV app everywhere, they gave
Speaker 1:  everybody airplay. It came along for the ride. So now every TV has
Speaker 1:  airplane Chromecast. So now you've got a third one if they don't
Speaker 1:  get like Samsung and LG, which are like
Speaker 1:  Vizio, right? Like I don't think Vizio is part of matter, but
Speaker 1:  Samsung, TCL, Panasonic and LG are all in matter.
Speaker 1:  That's a lot of TVs that might support this thing. Yeah. We'll see.
Speaker 1:  I have high hopes. What, I didn't see here anywhere. It was like, we're going
Speaker 1:  to make remote controls better.
Speaker 1:  No one seems at all like interested in doing
Speaker 4:  There's only so many problems technology can solve lie. That's true.
Speaker 1:  Okay. Can I, can I, can I go to my rabbit hole of my
Speaker 1:  streaming revenue rabbit hole?
Speaker 4:  Oh, is this a Spotify comedian thing?
Speaker 1:  Yeah. So there's this, there's this group that represents a bunch of comedians
Speaker 1:  called spoken giants, which is a great name. Yeah. And so they have this
Speaker 1:  new theory that they're arguing in Spotify about that resulted in
Speaker 1:  Spotify, removing a bunch of tracks from comedians
Speaker 1:  like Kevin Hart, Tiffany Haddish, Sean Laney, Jim Gaffigan, all off
Speaker 1:  Spotify. So they've got this idea that the written
Speaker 1:  jokes now constitute one work and the performance of the jokes
Speaker 1:  are another work and issue, right? So it's like
Speaker 1:  songwriters get one royalty stream and performers get another
Speaker 1:  often the songwriters and the performers and the same person they get paid
Speaker 1:  twice. This is like, there's like inventing a new, a new
Speaker 1:  revenue stream. Cause streaming revenue is so low that everyone's like trying
Speaker 1:  to find new money. So comedians have like come up with this new
Speaker 1:  lobbying groups, spoken giants to say that they're not
Speaker 1:  only just like telling jokes, but they're writing jokes
Speaker 1:  and then performing the jokes. And so the issue of the streaming revenue
Speaker 1:  for the audio recording and the publishing revenue for the jokes themselves,
Speaker 1:  which is just a wild way of thinking about comedians telling jokes. Because
Speaker 1:  for example, songwriters assume multiple people will
Speaker 1:  perform their songs over time. Comedians do not, no one
Speaker 1:  does a cover joke. Albums. It's just like not a thing.
Speaker 1:  That's pretty good. I'm doing
Speaker 1:  like an entire John Malaney cover album.
Speaker 4:  Like Tik TOK is full of cover jokes of just
Speaker 4:  people, lip sinking comedy routines. They're
Speaker 1:  Doing it to the audio. Sure.
Speaker 4:  But like it's a performance. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  I don't know. I don't actually have any idea how the Tech-Talk licensing
Speaker 1:  works. Yeah. I've always been fascinated by that. I just think it's the
Speaker 1:  pressure on the people who make the content for Spotify. The revenue
Speaker 1:  pressure on everybody is so high because the pay rates are so
Speaker 1:  low that like they're inventing this new concept, which would imply that
Speaker 1:  you should be able to like do an album of joke covers, put it on the
Speaker 1:  blockchain. Yeah. I think it's
Speaker 1:  fascinating. Ashley who writes Hotpod she and I are just
Speaker 1:  like staring at this being like, is this gonna work? Like Spotify
Speaker 1:  just was like, no. And she's like kicked him off. Yeah. Because Spotify doesn't
Speaker 1:  need a bunch of joke, albums. Like they're
Speaker 1:  fine. But it's like fascinating to me to see like
Speaker 1:  all of these ways, because the money has gotten so
Speaker 1:  bad that artists are creating new, lets NFTs. That's why every
Speaker 1:  artist is doing NFCS. But it's also like we're going to create a
Speaker 1:  new royalty structure for comedy out of
Speaker 1:  nothing.
Speaker 4:  We should do this for the Vergecast. We should get paid once for performing
Speaker 4:  it and paid an oh wait, we don't write it. Nevermind. We were writing it.
Speaker 1:  We're not going to prayers ago. We're contemporaneously writing this. What
Speaker 1:  does IP? But what is IP? What is IP? But what we
Speaker 1:  say, if someone wants to do a full cover of this episode of the verge
Speaker 1:  cast, you have to call us, I'll write you a
Speaker 1:  contract. It'll be cheap.
Speaker 1:  It won't cost a lot of money, but it will be ironclad that you have to perform
Speaker 1:  this Vergecast word for word, it'd be like 10
Speaker 1:  bucks. If you want to figure it out
Speaker 1:  like a screenplay of this verge cast. Look at that last little things. Apple
Speaker 1:  music is they got that weird voice plan for the home pods.
Speaker 4:  This is what I mean that like the capabilities of your device are dictated
Speaker 4:  by weird ass backroom contracts. Not by what the
Speaker 4:  capabilities of the device are. This voice plan is dominant knowing. And
Speaker 4:  I hate it.
Speaker 1:  And it's just because the record labels gave the same plan to Amazon. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Well it's like what enables your smart speaker, right? You, you want to say
Speaker 1:  play some music to a smart speaker that can't be that you don't want to do
Speaker 1:  a deal with Spotify. Right? So you like make your own deal for
Speaker 1:  like cheap streaming just for the smart speaker. It's like
Speaker 1:  five bucks a month, right? Four bucks a month. Yeah. It's super cheap. It's
Speaker 1:  weird. And then Sonos is not supporting Amazon music, ultra
Speaker 1:  HD and Dolby Atmos on the new beam that supports Atmos
Speaker 1:  and the arc. I got,
Speaker 3:  I wanna say I got a piece of physical mail from Amazon asking me if I want
Speaker 3:  to try Amazon music
Speaker 1:  Amazing the other day. And I was
Speaker 3:  Like, that says a lot about Amazon music.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. That's my only thought there we're quickly getting to a place by the
Speaker 1:  way, where the combination of the service
Speaker 1:  you subscribe to and the headphones you have has
Speaker 1:  meaningful implications for what music you listen to.
Speaker 1:  Like you've got to have an Atmos service and Sonos speakers to listen to
Speaker 1:  Atlas music from Amazon, but
Speaker 1:  your apple AirPods, which supports spatial
Speaker 1:  audio. There's no way to listen to Amazon music from Amazon. And he's just
Speaker 1:  like, it's nuts. Like it happened. The bad thing
Speaker 1:  happened. I don't know what to tell you. It could be a lot worse. We could
Speaker 1:  be paying gas fees every time we listened to a song. I mean, don't put that
Speaker 1:  energy into the world, man. What are you it's going to be happening. There's
Speaker 1:  a New York times article this week, like a choice the New York times is
Speaker 1:  on it. Article about how wired had funds are trendy again.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Do you see it as like I did it, this was me like the number of
Speaker 1:  people who were like, you got your wish. And I was like, there's still lightening
Speaker 1:  headphones.
Speaker 1:  All right, we gotta take a break. And we got the lightning round to end all
Speaker 1:  lightening rounds come up. We'll be right
Speaker 1:  back
Speaker 1:  Okay. We're back. We got there's like a chunk of Android lightning round
Speaker 1:  news. You're going to go through a tutor.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. So Google has a big update for
Speaker 4:  pixel, for Android 12. It's got a bug fix
Speaker 4:  list that is just three miles long, just
Speaker 4:  super, super. And like, you know, there's always like
Speaker 4:  the patch after the release where it's kind of big, but this one in particular
Speaker 4:  is like, oh, the pixel as reviewed is
Speaker 4:  not the one that they were hoping to get out the door. Like there's so many
Speaker 4:  fixes in this thing. And it also includes the launch feature where you're
Speaker 4:  going to be able to tap to snap, or you can double tap the thing and use
Speaker 4:  the snap camera, even though you're still on the lock screen. And then
Speaker 4:  immediately on the heels of that, there's an Android 12
Speaker 4:  L beta L large screens. I guess you
Speaker 4:  can install it on a pixel if you want to. For some reason you can.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It's just because, but it's meant for emulators. There's
Speaker 4:  like an Lenovo tablet that you can install it
Speaker 4:  on. If you want to see what it looks like, but it's clearly designed for
Speaker 4:  folding phones, right. And maybe they'll make another go at
Speaker 4:  tablets because they did the thing that should have done, which is like put
Speaker 4:  a proper dock on it, make rearranging windows via drag and drop part of
Speaker 4:  the system level thing and not a hack that Microsoft and Samsung have to
Speaker 4:  create, you know, like fix the notification dropdown
Speaker 4:  control panel drop thing. So it actually fills a screen instead of being
Speaker 4:  ridiculous, like the phone they've made Android, not terrible on big
Speaker 4:  screens or at least there's taking a couple of steps in that direction,
Speaker 4:  but there's just, there's no big screens to put it on.
Speaker 4:  Like, like there's the Kindles, there's like some random Samsung
Speaker 4:  tablets while we make some stuff, but like it's not here. And then there's
Speaker 4:  like the one Lenovo tablet that is, I think really only selling like
Speaker 4:  the UK. So I think it's interesting. I'm glad they're doing the
Speaker 4:  thing that they should've done a while ago to normalize the UI
Speaker 4:  on Microsoft two screen thing and Samsung folding and whatever else is
Speaker 4:  coming. But it's also like a pretty clear sign that yeah, they're, they're
Speaker 4:  still working on a pixel fold.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I mean, isn't everybody, I feel like we talked about like wave
Speaker 1:  guides in AR, but like also in the background, everybody is trying to make
Speaker 1:  a folding foam work. Right. I'm sure I was like dozens of folding phone
Speaker 1:  prototypes.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Literally who wants this? Because it's awesome. I want this. It's
Speaker 4:  great. It's the best I've been carrying around. And I've had many
Speaker 4:  at home lately instead of just my phone, like a tiny phone, an iPad mini,
Speaker 4:  and it's lovely to have a little, a little device with a big screen.
Speaker 4:  And I, you know, I bought a full Butterfield to have and use
Speaker 4:  that for awhile. I'm telling you, man, like big screens are
Speaker 4:  great. Like big screens are great. You get a big screen
Speaker 4:  in your pocket. Great. I
Speaker 1:  Love the pro max. And I guess you're saying folding makes that also
Speaker 1:  compact. Right? That's
Speaker 4:  The promise of it makes it a little bit smaller. Yeah, yeah. Yeah. I mean,
Speaker 1:  I also just think everybody knows that new form factors sell
Speaker 1:  in sack. You can deliver an actual folding phone that works without any of
Speaker 1:  the compromises that, you know, Samsung's already iterated its way through
Speaker 1:  some of the compromises. A lot
Speaker 4:  Of the compromises just
Speaker 1:  Get to like make that ad and be like, look, this iPhone folds in half. And
Speaker 1:  like, people will just instinctively. But yeah, I don't think they're, they're
Speaker 1:  trying to solve a huge problem. I think they can just see a, they can just
Speaker 1:  see a product that people instinctively understand.
Speaker 4:  The other pixel news is apparently the mail-in repair warehouse that they
Speaker 4:  were using. What was crazy was like people were mailing their
Speaker 4:  pixels in to get repaired and then the like their nudes
Speaker 4:  leaked. So that's horrible. And I want to tell
Speaker 4:  you that like PSA never send your phone in for repair without
Speaker 4:  wiping at first. But like if the thing is broken and you can't like use the
Speaker 4:  screen to wipe it, then like you're, you kind of have
Speaker 4:  no choice to send it in before you wipe your data in a lot of cases.
Speaker 4:  So yeah, not cool. That's all. It's
Speaker 4:  like what other advice can there be except to say not cool.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I mean, this is, I mean, we talk about the pixel. I'm like what
Speaker 1:  it, what Google needs to do. Like they need to market it. They need to sell
Speaker 1:  a lot of them. The back half of the story building these devices is like
Speaker 1:  service and support.
Speaker 4:  Right. And this is why we always recommended Samsung phones over pixels for
Speaker 4:  many years, even though we tend to prefer using pixels more ourselves,
Speaker 4:  because for the average person, you can walk to a
Speaker 4:  sprint store. If you use sprint and be like, fix my Samsung and they'd be
Speaker 4:  like, okay, yeah,
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Or more likely, there'll be like, your contract is up in three months.
Speaker 1:  Would you like a new Samsung? But like
Speaker 4:  Also what is, how, how sad is it that I still in my, in my, in
Speaker 4:  my world sprint still exists, just occurred to
Speaker 4:  me.
Speaker 1:  It's human was running those ads for free phones and they keep mentioning
Speaker 1:  sprint customers too. I don't know if you've seen these ads. They're like
Speaker 1:  everyone gets a free phone, including sprint customers. I'm like you own
Speaker 1:  sprint. Like you shut it down. Who are you talking
Speaker 1:  to? It's gone. It went away. Did you see this
Speaker 1:  Microsoft bug on? I can't tell you. I don't know if it's a Microsoft
Speaker 1:  bug, but if she had teams installed an Android phone, it
Speaker 1:  would occasionally prevent you from calling nine.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Well, so the, the phone app lets other apps plug into it. The iPhone
Speaker 4:  does this too. Right? And so there must be something where the teams
Speaker 4:  app wants to show up in your call log and that messed with that.
Speaker 4:  But this should never happen like that. That needs to be like
Speaker 4:  the phone app. There should be like an iron clad, you know, secure enclave
Speaker 4:  around that sort of functionality. It's ridiculous.
Speaker 1:  You wait, you, you think that they were trying to call 9 1 1 and it was routing
Speaker 1:  it through teams. And so like the nine 11 dispatcher was like getting a message.
Speaker 1:  It was like please in salt lake stuff,
Speaker 4:  Teams, all I'm saying is
Speaker 1:  That growth hacking at its finest.
Speaker 4:  The Microsoft software could have touched Google software. So
Speaker 4:  like something there went wrong. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Other phone stuff. This 5g story with the
Speaker 1:  FAA is getting more and more complicated by the day.
Speaker 1:  So now the FAA, the FAA was unhappy with the
Speaker 1:  FCC and with the telecom companies. So at and
Speaker 1:  T and Verizon agreed to delay some of their 5g rollout on
Speaker 1:  certain bands to solve these FAA problems. And now the
Speaker 1:  FAA is saying some flights
Speaker 1:  in some weather conditions should not land using instruments
Speaker 1:  alone. If the pilots can see the runway because a
Speaker 1:  5g interference,
Speaker 4:  But then at and T and rice had also promised I think the lower power on airports
Speaker 4:  or something, and these slides, these rules only apply to like certain
Speaker 4:  equipment that a lot of people want replaced. Anyway, it's like
Speaker 4:  the,
Speaker 1:  I will just say this. The, this is, I mean, it's you
Speaker 1:  usually see this for like the FTC and the DOJ, like fighting over. Who's
Speaker 1:  going to Sue a big company, the FCC and the FAF, like clearly not
Speaker 1:  talked like the FCC, his entire job is
Speaker 1:  to manage spectrum in this country. Yeah. And yes, like they only just
Speaker 1:  got into heroin dresser, Rosen or Saul was officially confirmed by the Senate
Speaker 1:  like two days ago, but
Speaker 4:  There's still, they're still deadlocked. They don't, there's not the fifth,
Speaker 1:  But they don't need a vote for the stuff. Like the votes that we care about
Speaker 1:  that we pay attention to her, like neutral, like a big policy stuff. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Like mostly the FCC is full of engineers and lawyers whose job it is to just
Speaker 1:  figure this stuff out. Right. And it's nuts that it's, we're this far into
Speaker 1:  the 5g cycle and the FAA is like, oh, there's going to be a
Speaker 1:  problem with planes. So like maybe thousands of flights can't
Speaker 1:  land
Speaker 4:  Sometimes when you're in a race, some people get left
Speaker 4:  behind.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Anyway, the telecom lobbyists are out of control, mad
Speaker 1:  about this and sort of like the FCC people are, are like, why don't you tell
Speaker 1:  us about this earlier? So we'll see what happens, but it's, I don't know.
Speaker 1:  There's something wacky here where like, maybe it was just the race,
Speaker 1:  but in effect, what is happening is the big at and T and
Speaker 1:  Verizon mid band roll-outs are being affected by the FAA.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. And we'll just see where that goes. Did you see this horizon
Speaker 1:  story?
Speaker 4:  Yes. And it's like this, this is my PSA
Speaker 4:  moment. So there's this thing where Verizon has Verizon already
Speaker 4:  had this program called like Verizon, like up or something where it was really
Speaker 4:  obvious that signing up for this to get a deal is definitely going to sign
Speaker 4:  you up to have them collect more data, but they're doing it. And even skeezy
Speaker 4:  your way now with Verizon custom experience and custom experience
Speaker 4:  plus, and it seems
Speaker 1:  Rational shaking his head.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It's like, come on. I mean, Verizon, you know, famous
Speaker 4:  adventure of the super cookie, right? Yeah. What I believe is happening
Speaker 4:  here is Verizon and a bunch of other companies are
Speaker 4:  tr there's a story about the secretary, or they're turning the knob up on
Speaker 4:  all of their, like customer loyalty programs and of their like, you
Speaker 4:  know, sign up and give us some piece of information program to
Speaker 4:  as high as they can go right now, in
Speaker 4:  case the stuff with app tracking on iPhones
Speaker 4:  and, you know, Chrome decides it's going to finally do something with flock.
Speaker 4:  Although my money is on, they're going to waffle for an extra two Mo two
Speaker 4:  years. You know, if the cookie apocalypse happens
Speaker 4:  or if you know something with app tracking gets shut down, there was a weird
Speaker 4:  story where like apple was maybe letting people collect data on, you know,
Speaker 4:  iPhone apps, blah, blah, blah. All of this stuff is really frothy right
Speaker 4:  now, but like just don't sign up for anything. That's that's
Speaker 4:  my advice to you.
Speaker 1:  So the specific thing Dieter was talking about was for the Verizon super
Speaker 1:  cookie ages ago was for Verizon at the network
Speaker 1:  level would just track everything you did on the web, using something called
Speaker 1:  the super cookie and you couldn't get rid of it. And if you had a Verizon
Speaker 1:  phone, they were just building this profile of you. Everyone got mad, they
Speaker 1:  turned off. I'm telling you that this is evidence that they're bringing it
Speaker 1:  back. Yeah, no for sure. Like Verizon's entire media strategy. Remember
Speaker 1:  they bought AOL and Yahoo and they merged them into a company
Speaker 1:  called I spun out and now
Speaker 1:  yeah, the Yahoo got spun off again. And they just renamed
Speaker 1:  Verizon media. The company that was known as Verizon media
Speaker 1:  is now just known is Yahoo ad tech. Like
Speaker 1:  no, no hiding the ball. Like the corporate entity
Speaker 1:  that owns like tech crunch and gadget, which are great sites and run by great
Speaker 1:  people. But like that corporate entity is now just known as Yahoo ad tech,
Speaker 1:  like zero hiding the ball, what they're doing. So now,
Speaker 1:  because apps can't track their data on the phone for
Speaker 1:  Isen can track your data on the network. Correct.
Speaker 3:  And you've opted in because it's your
Speaker 3:  carrier,
Speaker 1:  Right? You've just signed whatever contracts you got a free phone. So Ryzen
Speaker 1:  has all this data about where you are, what your traffic is doing, what your
Speaker 1:  interests are with websites are going to, and then they can then flip
Speaker 1:  that into ad tracking profiles. Yep. And bypass
Speaker 1:  all of that.
Speaker 3:  The thing that throws a wrench in this is private relay is, is
Speaker 3:  iClouds, VPN type thing. It's not a VPN, but we'll
Speaker 3:  call it that. And it's almost like apple saw this coming. This is like
Speaker 3:  fighting at what, how low in the stack of like the ability
Speaker 3:  to block out a tracking, can you get apples pretty down there, but then there's
Speaker 3:  Verizon. It's like, well actually we can just sniff all your packets. And
Speaker 3:  then Apple's like, well, hold on, we're going to put a wall up. So you can't.
Speaker 3:  So I have a feeling this won't work is around about way of
Speaker 3:  saying that,
Speaker 1:  Oh, I mean carrier software ideas. That's a good bet. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  But like both, this is what H and T wanted to do with Warner
Speaker 1:  media. Like their stated purpose for buying Warner
Speaker 1:  brothers, which is just
Speaker 3:  Ridiculous to think
Speaker 1:  About ad tracking in advertising. There is just a
Speaker 1:  study like where there is a bunch of STC noise lately because of Rosenworcel.
Speaker 1:  And then Judy Stone is up for the other commissioner spots, a break, the
Speaker 1:  two to tie. And I think we talked about this
Speaker 1:  with Russell last week. I don't know. I'll just recapitulate it. So GG
Speaker 1:  sound is up for the last spot in the FCC. Yup. And
Speaker 1:  Fox news in the wall street journal don't want her to be on the FCC, but
Speaker 1:  OANN Newsmax do because she supports
Speaker 1:  competition just like as a principal. And they're the competitors, which
Speaker 1:  is very funny. But so there's all this noise where the sec, but if you look
Speaker 1:  at investment in networks, themselves, capital expenditure
Speaker 1:  networks, when they got rid of net neutrality, the actual net
Speaker 1:  investment in networks went down because all of the broadband companies started
Speaker 1:  buying media. They went and bought Warner media and they went and
Speaker 1:  bought AOL. They did all this stuff because
Speaker 1:  they were like, we're going to monetize what happens on the networks as we
Speaker 1:  can see the networks. And then all of a sudden he is we're inevitably
Speaker 1:  bad. So I would just say like this, you can
Speaker 1:  see what's happening. Like apple turned off the cookie stuff. They turned
Speaker 1:  off tracking. And now everyone else who has the ability to track is like
Speaker 1:  lit this idea back up, Alex, you cover like a bunch of, you know, like snap
Speaker 1:  had like bad earnings, but this is like hitting these companies in serious
Speaker 1:  ways.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I mean, what's effectively happening is it's it's a lot of it is
Speaker 3:  apple in the private sector. A lot of is actually coming from the
Speaker 3:  EU in the public sector. So between apple and the EU and
Speaker 3:  then Google, whatever the hell they're going to do, you effectively, you
Speaker 3:  could think of the internet today. It is like a, a big series of
Speaker 3:  interlocking webs, right? Where it was pretty easy for X company
Speaker 3:  to sell it, sell data to another, or even just tell them,
Speaker 3:  Hey, like we think this person is this and they corroborate what's happening
Speaker 3:  is apple in the U with this digital market service act, that's coming
Speaker 3:  out sometime or just taking scissors and cutting all those webs. And so
Speaker 3:  everything is becoming siloed and we're in this
Speaker 3:  like kind of adjustment, painful adjustment period, mostly brought on
Speaker 3:  by apple right now. But like the things that Facebook is doing where it's,
Speaker 3:  you know, getting rid of ad targeting options, you know, where you can't,
Speaker 3:  you no longer can target somebody by based on their sexual orientation. That's
Speaker 3:  actually motivated by laws that are coming in the EU that are just
Speaker 3:  clamping down on targeting from a legal perspective. And
Speaker 3:  so, yeah, everyone's building these, there's a guy named Eric Sue for it
Speaker 3:  is like a super smart ad tech guy who calls them content fortresses. But
Speaker 3:  every app and I wrote this in a 10 year kind of package,
Speaker 3:  like every app is going to become a super app where like, instead of you
Speaker 3:  going off app to purchase something, Facebook wants you to do
Speaker 3:  shopping on Instagram because when you shop on Instagram, they know you
Speaker 3:  bought it. Whereas if they kick you off to a website, there's no more cookie
Speaker 3:  for them to say, oh, they came from our ad. Therefore our ad worked. And
Speaker 3:  so this is going to reshape big parts of the internet for
Speaker 3:  sure. And it already is starting to do that. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I'm just going to put an idea out there if you're, I'm sure an apple
Speaker 4:  engineer just wants you to pull over in your car, think about this
Speaker 4:  problem of these super apps and everyone trying to keep people inside their
Speaker 4:  apps, take a deep breath and realize in your heart
Speaker 4:  that allowing at browsers was a mistake and you should
Speaker 4:  turn them off on your platform. And that browsers are the
Speaker 4:  worst. Give me my tabs. Give me my
Speaker 4:  browser. Give me my extensions. Give
Speaker 4:  me my own space where I'm a control away visit on the
Speaker 4:  web. And don't make me bounce from the Twitter
Speaker 4:  browser to safari. Don't make me relogging
Speaker 4:  in to the New York times. So I can read an article 15
Speaker 4:  times and every single app that happens to link to the New York times,
Speaker 1:  Just send them all to
Speaker 4:  Safari. This isn't a problem on, on Chrome because they share cookies with
Speaker 4:  the enterprisers, but still I'm just saying ban in at
Speaker 4:  browsers and you will go a long way towards solving this super app tracking
Speaker 4:  problem. Just do it.
Speaker 1:  We'll end up back in court tomorrow.
Speaker 1:  It's like, it's like the death now. Okay. Other letting around
Speaker 1:  stuff Adam Maseri had of Instagram was in front of
Speaker 1:  Congress. Facebook's or just set up shop in DC at this point
Speaker 1:  and move all their executives. There are Mehta, I'm sorry, Metta, but it's
Speaker 1:  first time for Adam in front of Congress. He said, they're bringing back
Speaker 1:  the chronological feed. What'd you think of the,
Speaker 3:  Oh my God. I mean, how many more of these are we going to have? It's like,
Speaker 3:  you know, forever Casey had a great tweet about how, you know, it's like
Speaker 3:  they just legislate through hearings, right? Like nothing actually happens.
Speaker 3:  And it's all just a bunch of grand standing. I mean, I think I
Speaker 3:  tuned out of this hearing after like half of it, because it was
Speaker 3:  just, it's just incomprehensible. And it's like, you can just tell that
Speaker 3:  this is all, it's all politically motivated. Like all of a sudden, all the
Speaker 3:  senators care about our kids. And it's like, you know,
Speaker 3:  it's all Metis fault. And obviously there are problems here. I'm not trying
Speaker 3:  to absolve them of all responsibility, but I just wish there was actual
Speaker 3:  more. I come back to like the fact that like the
Speaker 3:  honest ads act, which is a response to
Speaker 3:  2016, like literally never happened. And it was like
Speaker 3:  the only thing that managed to even like get some
Speaker 3:  kind of interest in Congress. And yeah, I
Speaker 3:  just, I don't know. I don't think the American public really thinks these
Speaker 3:  hearings are interesting or working. Like I would be shocked.
Speaker 3:  I just don't really know who they're for except for donors and the
Speaker 3:  media. And then when most serious says we're bringing chronological
Speaker 3:  feedback. That's the actual news out of the entire, whatever, two or three
Speaker 3:  hour hearing, it was like Instagram bringing back this thing they killed
Speaker 3:  for no reason. I mean, it, wasn't no reason, but that people hated that they
Speaker 3:  killed years ago. So
Speaker 4:  It's next year it comes, sorry. Twitter moved faster than
Speaker 4:  Twitter. If you can't move as fast as Twitter, what are you
Speaker 4:  doing?
Speaker 3:  Well, you know, they're going through a lot over there. Okay. You know, they've
Speaker 3:  got a lot of people in the metaverse
Speaker 3:  it's funny because like that's Francis Haugen, you know, if the Facebook
Speaker 3:  whistleblower, that was her whole thing, that her, her stump speech, when
Speaker 3:  she came out and was like ban algorithms, like the chronological feed will
Speaker 3:  fix integrity on the internet. And we're going to see if that
Speaker 3:  works. And I would not be shocked if like,
Speaker 3:  most people don't even use this when it comes out. I don't think Twitter's
Speaker 3:  chronological feed is heavily used and that's what I use.
Speaker 1:  So it
Speaker 3:  Is. Wow. Yeah, of course, man, I used to be a Twitter completion as two.
Speaker 1:  So I mean, my entire thing is at Twitter, poisons your brain and then we
Speaker 1:  should all quit. So if I intentionally make my Twitter
Speaker 1:  experience as broken as possible,
Speaker 3:  That's fair. I mean, I remember being a tweet bot stand and like having to
Speaker 3:  read every single tweet in my feed, because it would show you the counter
Speaker 3:  before you can refresh. And I'm really glad those days are behind
Speaker 3:  me. But yeah, I don't know this whole, like, should we all be
Speaker 3:  chronological feeds or should we be algorithms? And I
Speaker 3:  just, I don't know, they're doing this to appease the, the, the angry
Speaker 3:  senators who, who care about our children. So
Speaker 1:  I think that the angry senators you're correct about donors, but I think
Speaker 1:  it does get them voters yelling at Metta or Facebook or
Speaker 1:  Instagram is like, it works for both
Speaker 1:  parties
Speaker 3:  Because the Republicans need like suburban women or what's, what's the,
Speaker 1:  Yeah, I, I think there's that. I like, I think this next year, you
Speaker 1:  know how it is testifying, there's assuming
Speaker 1:  this next chunk of the Biden plan passes, which who knows if it, well, the
Speaker 1:  next set of attention is gonna be back on. So two 30 in social media regulation,
Speaker 1:  like we've heard both parties say they want to do it and there there's going
Speaker 1:  to be some meaningful, oh shit. The first amendments in
Speaker 1:  our way. It's just coming for them till we say this
Speaker 3:  Every year though, that it's coming. Like, again, I come back to
Speaker 3:  like the honest ads act, which was like a smart piece of like
Speaker 3:  detailed niche focus legislation about like political
Speaker 3:  ads. Like that went nowhere. So, I mean, you really think
Speaker 3:  we're going to get to like meaningful section two 30 reform in a divided
Speaker 3:  Congress.
Speaker 1:  I think what's going to happen is the, the Florida social media
Speaker 1:  bill will work its way through the courts. Right? It got stayed. The Texas
Speaker 1:  social media bill got stayed. Like as those things move
Speaker 1:  their way through the courts are gonna, and Congress like
Speaker 1:  turns as in selection year, they're all going to start yelling about it.
Speaker 1:  Like it's just easy money for a politician to be like Facebook as
Speaker 1:  bad. Sure. It's it's just like, it's easy to be like, YouTube is poisoning
Speaker 1:  our kids. We got to do something about it. If you reelect me to the United
Speaker 1:  States, Congress, my bill will make YouTube, not sensor conservatives.
Speaker 1:  Like I could probably win a seat in upstate New York
Speaker 1:  right tomorrow. If I just like ran around saying that like it's
Speaker 1:  convincing to a lot of people, for reasons that make sense,
Speaker 1:  like people do not have great relationships with these platforms.
Speaker 3:  The nurse did in our survey say that, say that a little differently.
Speaker 1:  They said they like the utility platforms. So
Speaker 1:  Google, Facebook, YouTube, which is a not
Speaker 1:  Facebook. So Google and Amazon really, really highly rated whether they provide
Speaker 1:  an ongoing utility. I was like 98% approval in our
Speaker 1:  survey. YouTube way up there, because look, my
Speaker 1:  refrigerator's broke. I watched a lot of yesterday trying to fix it. I failed.
Speaker 1:  So now my opinion of YouTube is very
Speaker 1:  low. As you break it
Speaker 1:  further, my father-in-law's here and he has spent the entire day just like
Speaker 1:  tearing this thing to shreds. Oh boy, is it something to do? It's 15 years
Speaker 1:  old. The thing is that it's, it's not going to happen. Supply chain crunches
Speaker 1:  real though, buy a new refrigerator right now. It's a real problem. Anyhow,
Speaker 1:  those are all the top. And then you get to Facebook and Instagram and Twitter.
Speaker 1:  And there are people like I'm way less. And I, I just think that's like
Speaker 1:  easy money for politicians. I think it's coming. Something is the, some
Speaker 1:  conversation is coming and right at the center of it
Speaker 1:  is a theme park, a theme park. Either
Speaker 1:  our government is going to tell, tell itself that the first
Speaker 1:  amendment keeps it from regulating social networks, which is what
Speaker 1:  the judicial branch has currently telling legislative branches,
Speaker 1:  or that's going to change. Like those are the only two options we're going
Speaker 1:  to change the constitution.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I think that conversation is
Speaker 1:  coming in a serious way next year. I do. And not in the they'll pass a
Speaker 1:  law, but in the two states have now made a run at it and run
Speaker 1:  directly into the first amendment. And they're going to the, those lawsuits
Speaker 1:  are going to wind their way through the courts. Next year, last few things.
Speaker 1:  Speaking of lawsuits, epic V apple, the deadline
Speaker 1:  for apple to allow links to external payments.
Speaker 1:  And
Speaker 4:  What about, what about meta buttons?
Speaker 1:  The deadline for apple to metaverse buttons to two other
Speaker 1:  payments. It was going to come, but the appeals court, which is
Speaker 1:  unusual, the appeals court, granted a stay saying
Speaker 1:  apple had raised serious issues about the ruling in the district court. That's
Speaker 1:  on hold. What I will remind you is that skipping to the
Speaker 1:  end of a legal process is not
Speaker 1:  correct. Like, like they issued the stay.
Speaker 1:  That doesn't mean apple one. It means I have to appeal. And it means when
Speaker 1:  that's done the, you know, there's an epic V Google
Speaker 1:  exists too. So then are going to be two cases that get
Speaker 1:  appealed, which usually means you
Speaker 1:  get another appeal. And that might mean you get a Supreme court
Speaker 1:  case, right? And ethics law firm
Speaker 1:  famously represented Amex against a bunch of retailers
Speaker 1:  lost at every level until they got to assume Supreme court in
Speaker 1:  one, in an antitrust case about merchant payments.
Speaker 1:  So I'm not saying apple is gonna win. I'm not saying Amex and lose. I'm just
Speaker 1:  saying don't skip to the end.
Speaker 4:  The one important thing, the state does not appear to apply to
Speaker 4:  apps, being allowed to admit that payment systems outside the app store
Speaker 4:  exist. So they can't link to it. But like,
Speaker 1:  And apple, I think Apple's already bent on this. Right. They bent on it in
Speaker 1:  Japan. They're not interested in fighting that. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. So like that to me was always one of the most egregious things.
Speaker 4:  So I hope that goes away with a quickness.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Samsung, I didn't realize this had already
Speaker 1:  happened. They've merged their mobile and consumer electronics businesses.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I
Speaker 4:  Mean, I see this as a function of the mobile businesses, a hurting unit,
Speaker 4:  like, like literally the business units is hurting
Speaker 1:  It's finally, which is like, is an Android phone.
Speaker 1:  Like what's a, what's a, what's the T what's a TV. It's a giant Android phone.
Speaker 4:  But like the TV people are in charge. Yeah. So like, this is either
Speaker 4:  just not a big deal or it's like, I don't know. The Sony
Speaker 4:  reification of the voice Samsung makes phones, which is like a scary thought
Speaker 4:  because Sony has not been great at phones. Anyway. I don't think we can read
Speaker 4:  too much into it yet. It might just be crazy Samsung
Speaker 4:  company politics. But I do think that it may mean
Speaker 4:  some like changes to the way that like they've been cranking out
Speaker 4:  phones. I think that there might be in theory,
Speaker 4:  maybe if we're lucky, some more coherency there, but who knows?
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 1:  As the person who in the market for a refrigerator, I'll say that I played
Speaker 1:  with the Samsung smart fridge. Yeah. At the store
Speaker 1:  yesterday, man, putting a slow mid range. Android tablet on the front of
Speaker 1:  the refrigerator is not the compelling idea. You thought it was
Speaker 1:  new.
Speaker 3:  I'd be like, you need a high-tech refrigerator. So you are going to come
Speaker 3:  to see us.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I'm pretty sad that I won't be doing the refrigerator tour at
Speaker 1:  CS
Speaker 4:  One with like a curved screen of what the Android tablet. So you can get
Speaker 4:  a curved TV refrigerator in your house
Speaker 1:  House. Do you want to do an hour on refrigerator since I'm in it right now,
Speaker 1:  deep in the game, do you know where you're on? The antitrust regulators in
Speaker 1:  this country need to turn their attention? There's like three appliance
Speaker 1:  manufacturers. They all are
Speaker 4:  Samsung, LG
Speaker 1:  There's Samsung and LG. And then there is a higher which on this GE and
Speaker 1:  there's Whirlpool, which owns everything else. Gotcha. Okay. That's a
Speaker 1:  real throw mess. Also a appliance forums, just a
Speaker 1:  hotbed of internet activity. There's a whole world here. We're not paying
Speaker 1:  attention to
Speaker 4:  Running on
Speaker 1:  Vivo. Yeah, man. You want to, you want to see misinformation at work. You
Speaker 1:  ask people about LGS refrigerator compressors and whether they're
Speaker 1:  reliable. All
Speaker 1:  right. Last few things. There was a really dumb story
Speaker 1:  about the vice president and her wired headphones.
Speaker 1:  Just Corrine. Fave is our new senior security reporter. He wrote a very
Speaker 1:  pessimistic. I read that, but long story short it's okay. If
Speaker 1:  the most powerful people in the government don't have wireless radios that
Speaker 1:  intrinsically serve as location beacons turned on, we gotta read that
Speaker 1:  and then send a sense, a plan to make its products more repairable, which
Speaker 1:  is interesting. That that is becoming a thing. Microsoft announced the
Speaker 1:  plan in a sense, a plan like apple just did that big right to repair
Speaker 1:  stuff. That movement is regardless of the legislation, there's proposed
Speaker 1:  legislation. Alex, I know it might not ever happen. Regardless of that,
Speaker 1:  the market is demanding repairability and the companies are starting to realize
Speaker 1:  they can sell it.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Well, especially if you're apple and you already made your products
Speaker 3:  on repairable, why not just give someone a fix it kit and say,
Speaker 3:  go for a kid.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. So I was spiky about this on Twitter. I said it was a right to repair
Speaker 4:  equivalent of greenwashing because they didn't have any details about repair
Speaker 4:  manuals or offering to sell replacement parts or
Speaker 4:  whatever Sonos has emailed me. And they're, they're not happy with my
Speaker 4:  spiky tweet even a little. So I just, for the record, want to
Speaker 4:  say that a spokesperson, Tom lodged lets me know that I
Speaker 4:  want to assure you, this is a real plan with significant work already
Speaker 4:  undertaken on products we will release. And
Speaker 4:  that we continue to work through the details of how we're going to manage
Speaker 4:  the software aspect. And as we move closer to launch, we're committed to
Speaker 4:  consulting with organizations active in this space. For example, I fix
Speaker 4:  it in Fairphone to ensure our offering is as meaningful as
Speaker 4:  possible. He admits the proof will only come when they release the
Speaker 4:  products. But Sonos pinky swears
Speaker 4:  is my new phrase. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Okay. I feel like this is a second time sentences and a big
Speaker 1:  thing. And then everyone misinterpreted it and they're like, no, we should
Speaker 1:  have said more. Just a lesson for all of us finished your plan, then release
Speaker 1:  the plan. All right. That's it. That's a very fast, you can
Speaker 1:  tweet at us. Alex is Alex . I'm at reckless theaters at
Speaker 1:  Baclofen Tuesday dealer. Which one was it?
Speaker 1:  Matter? Yeah, that's a good one. The spec, the holiday
Speaker 1:  spectacular is continue with matter. By the way, Jen, our new
Speaker 1:  smart home reviewer has been working on that matter piece for a long time.
Speaker 4:  They're coming out together like the, the, the matter podcast which
Speaker 4:  features Jennifer quite a lot is put into her big matter explainer. It's
Speaker 4:  a, it's a huge, huge splash that you will understand
Speaker 4:  what's coming and what's coming is actually a lot. It's a
Speaker 4:  spectacular.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I think Tony Fidel makes an appearance in the Jones matter piece.
Speaker 1:  It's good.
Speaker 4:  We talked about thread just a little. Okay. Actually a hell of a
Speaker 4:  lot.
Speaker 1:  That's good. And then as I mentioned earlier, John hanky CEO of Niantic
Speaker 1:  on decoder next Tuesday, these last two decoders, by
Speaker 1:  the way, they're not CS, right? It was miss Excel,
Speaker 1:  which is on track to be our most popular episode of, to go to
Speaker 1:  forever. People love Excel influencer as a
Speaker 1:  concept, which I should have expected because when I heard about it, I was
Speaker 1:  like, oh, we gotta do that. And then Jonah Ehrlich from constitution
Speaker 1:  Dow talks about blockchain. That was a good one. And I will say the
Speaker 1:  response to it is like people being like, this is all the
Speaker 1:  problems with blockchain or people being like, look at how awesome blockchains
Speaker 1:  are. And there's no in-between, which is, I think a
Speaker 1:  sign of a good episode together. That's it we'll be back next week.
Speaker 1:  That's where Chester and get a
Speaker 1:  boost.