# Transcript
ID: 7871fac0-4144-11ec-9a57-b1270c2eb232
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: What’s next for USB-C
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/1336462472/2992842698/s93290-US-3837s-1636451663.mp3
Description: The Verge's Dieter Bohn dedicates this week's Tuesday episode to the fractious history and fraught future of USB-C.
Speaker 2:  Here at the verge. One of our hardest weeks every year comes in
Speaker 2:  January, it's CES, the consumer electronic
Speaker 2:  show. And it's such an intense tech conference that we spend just
Speaker 2:  a ridiculous amount of time planning out what gear we're going to
Speaker 2:  bring. It's vital that we have tools that we can
Speaker 2:  rely on our cameras, our phones, and our laptops. They all have
Speaker 2:  to work. And if there's any way we can make the stuff that we stuff into
Speaker 2:  our bags simpler, or more importantly, way less, we're going to
Speaker 2:  take it. So in 2016, I was
Speaker 2:  very excited to have a tiny 12 inch Mac book and
Speaker 2:  a Google nexus, six P the laptop weighed next to
Speaker 2:  nothing. And the phone had a massive screen,
Speaker 2:  both my phone and my laptop charged with the exact same
Speaker 2:  cable, which was perfect. I was super ready for
Speaker 2:  CES until suddenly in the middle of that
Speaker 2:  hectic week, the single solitary USBC port
Speaker 2:  on the Mac book stopped working. I couldn't plug my
Speaker 2:  camera in, I couldn't sync files. I could barely get the laptop to
Speaker 2:  charge. And it was all because of a faulty cable.
Speaker 2:  My next six P did what it was designed to do what I plugged into the Mac
Speaker 2:  book. It asked for all the power that it could get to fast charge.
Speaker 2:  And so then the cable provided it and that ended up frying the
Speaker 2:  laptop's USB controller. When USBC first
Speaker 2:  started, the only way to know for sure that you were buying a safe and
Speaker 2:  reliable cable was to follow a Google
Speaker 2:  plus group and hope that you could come across the reviews of
Speaker 2:  a single Google engineer who was running tests on
Speaker 2:  everything that was available. According to the USB implementers
Speaker 2:  forum, the official group that defines USB, there were only
Speaker 2:  61 certified USBC cables. At the
Speaker 2:  time, the rest were just unlabeled junk. It was
Speaker 2:  like playing Russian roulette with your laptop.
Speaker 2:  It's five years later now, and you're not likely to fry your computer with
Speaker 2:  a cable, but USB-C is still complicated. We
Speaker 2:  have one plug that now does multiple things from low power
Speaker 2:  charging and slow data to ridiculously high, 240
Speaker 2:  watt power. You can also get super high speed data. There's Thunderbolt,
Speaker 2:  there's monitors, there's audio. The dream of a single cable and
Speaker 2:  plug is great, but it's also a little
Speaker 2:  confusing. I'm Dieter Bohn, the executive editor of the verge.
Speaker 2:  And I'm really excited to talk through what's going on today with
Speaker 2:  USB-C we're doing a special run of more focused Vergecast
Speaker 2:  episodes on Tuesdays. And this week, as you can obviously tell it's
Speaker 2:  time to really talk about
Speaker 2:  USB-C.
Speaker 2:  So before we get into the variety of complications that USB-C created,
Speaker 2:  let's talk about what it actually is because there's even some confusion
Speaker 2:  right there. Let's just get down to the very,
Speaker 2:  very basics. USB-C is a 24 pin
Speaker 2:  universal serial bus connector system, universal because it works
Speaker 2:  with everything in theory cereal, because that's the technical term for
Speaker 2:  communication and computers for this kind of port and bus, which is short
Speaker 2:  for omnibus switches, a kind of transport. It's another computer
Speaker 2:  term for communication. Anyway, one of USB C's big
Speaker 2:  innovations is that it has a rotationally symmetrical connector, which
Speaker 2:  means that you can plug it in upside down or right side up. You don't get
Speaker 2:  it wrong every time you try to plug it in, like you do with older flavors
Speaker 2:  of USB, like USPA or micro USB USBC was
Speaker 2:  designed to replace data transfer connectors like USBA, and also offer
Speaker 2:  faster speeds, which these days could be as fast as 40 gigabits per
Speaker 2:  second. USB-C is also meant to provide power to replace your
Speaker 2:  power cable. The name for the main standard is USB PD or
Speaker 2:  USB power delivery, which is a much higher power delivery
Speaker 2:  standard than past USB connectors. It can range from standard phone wattage
Speaker 2:  like five or 20 or 30 Watts up to a hundred Watts for laptops, or now
Speaker 2:  with the newest versions, 240 Watts. This standard
Speaker 2:  allows the cable to power devices like gaming laptops and smart speakers.
Speaker 2:  You're in a Tendo switch, headphones, whatever, and communicate the
Speaker 2:  appropriate amount of wattage and the current levels that are being
Speaker 2:  delivered to the device. USBC cables also have the
Speaker 2:  ability to transfer both video and audio signals, replacing cables like
Speaker 2:  HTMI or the old 3.5 TRS headphone
Speaker 2:  Jack. It can also send video signals for monitors, like say over display
Speaker 2:  port, add all that up. And the dream is really simple, a
Speaker 2:  single cable and plug that does anything and
Speaker 2:  everything. You don't need multiple different cables. You can get everything
Speaker 2:  you need onto your laptop or your phone with just a single
Speaker 2:  one. Okay. So that all sounds simple enough, right? Transfers
Speaker 2:  data transfers. Power can be used for video or audio, but the
Speaker 2:  problems pop up pretty quickly. We're used to the shape of the
Speaker 2:  cable telling us what the cable does. Only your power cable fits
Speaker 2:  into the power plug or the HTMI fits into the HTMI. But with
Speaker 2:  USB-C the physical shape, doesn't tell you what the thing does
Speaker 2:  anymore. And it turns out not every USB-C cable can actually
Speaker 2:  support doing everything that you might want it to.
Speaker 3:  The issue, I guess, is that the physical plug, the USBC plug
Speaker 3:  is the same, regardless of whether it just carries power or power and
Speaker 3:  low speed data or power and high-speed data or power and high-speed data.
Speaker 3:  And high-speed video
Speaker 2:  Rod would be he's the CTO of a company called a S C the
Speaker 2:  Australian semiconductor technology company.
Speaker 3:  So I've been involved with USB-C and USB PD, I guess for eight years
Speaker 3:  now worked with a number of Silicon vendors, a number of
Speaker 3:  OEMs, and I've attended a number of USB drop
Speaker 3:  building workshops during the early days of USB-C when everyone was just
Speaker 3:  working out how things worked with each other, or didn't work with each other
Speaker 3:  as the case may be. So
Speaker 2:  It's a bit about the intricacies of the standard and where the confusion
Speaker 2:  comes from
Speaker 3:  When you start to have a single cable for all those different things, power,
Speaker 3:  video, and data. Then clearly, if you want to
Speaker 3:  have cheap cables, they're going to be different cables that
Speaker 3:  just carry power and nothing else versus cables that can carry four to
Speaker 3:  gigabits per second of video and dark.
Speaker 2:  Since there are different types of USB-C cables being made, you
Speaker 2:  may own a cable that charges your phone, but doesn't really support anything
Speaker 2:  else. You may own another USB-C cable that charges your
Speaker 2:  phone faster. And then another that's only able to transfer data
Speaker 2:  and they all look the same at the heart of it. The
Speaker 2:  universal USBC connector, which is designed to simplify things, created a
Speaker 2:  problem of cheap cables that don't do what you want and confusing tech
Speaker 2:  standards USB-C is on the way to making tech faster and
Speaker 2:  smarter. Don't get me wrong. But right now my cable drawer is still as
Speaker 2:  messy as it's always been. Now. Technically there is a
Speaker 2:  process for clarifying all of these different cables, as you could probably
Speaker 2:  guess, it's by labeling them on the packaging or ideally
Speaker 2:  on the cable itself, but there's a problem there too. There's
Speaker 2:  weird naming conventions and different branding from different manufacturers.
Speaker 2:  So it's not easy enough to know whether or not you've bought the right
Speaker 2:  cable. There is
Speaker 3:  Branding that's meant to be put on the plug to tell you what's what, but
Speaker 3:  of course, you know, some manufacturers put their own logo on instead of
Speaker 3:  the branding. And so that doesn't help with people. And then on the side
Speaker 3:  of laptop, you know, there's limited space there to write what that
Speaker 3:  receptive go on the laptop can handle. I guess it's a combination of
Speaker 3:  humans making assumptions about what things can do, which are reasonable
Speaker 3:  assumptions to make, you know, if it plugs in, you expect it to work. But
Speaker 3:  of course all the cables look the same unless you know what the logo
Speaker 3:  means. It's rifle confusion.
Speaker 2:  All right, let's talk about the logos because the USB implementers
Speaker 2:  forum, which is the organization that maintains the USB standard and its
Speaker 2:  specifications are really great at keeping a clear message for
Speaker 2:  consumers on what the cables they buy can actually do. But my colleague
Speaker 2:  at the verge Haim Gardberg is great at deciphering and explaining what
Speaker 2:  all of these USB specs are and what the logos mean and what they're
Speaker 2:  used for. So let's bring them in to talk. I'm
Speaker 2:  Gartenberg you are senior reporter at the verge. Also the
Speaker 2:  only person I personally know who is more obsessed with USBC than I am
Speaker 2:  welcome,
Speaker 4:  Good to be here. So
Speaker 2:  We have talked a bit about the USB spec and how it
Speaker 2:  works, but fundamentally, what we're really talking about here is lots of
Speaker 2:  cables that theoretically can do different things, even though they look
Speaker 2:  the same. So what kind of specs can actually be
Speaker 2:  labeled on a USB-C cable?
Speaker 4:  So broadly speaking, there's two types of things that
Speaker 4:  USB C cable can do. There is data and there
Speaker 4:  is charging. Now most cables do both, but
Speaker 4:  up until USB four, which is new, you didn't have
Speaker 4:  to actually do either of these things. You could make a charging cable
Speaker 4:  that didn't do data. You could do a data cable that, you know, didn't meet
Speaker 4:  certain charging specs. So USBC describes the
Speaker 4:  port, but there's a lot of things you can do with it,
Speaker 2:  Right? So let's stick with power to start. So what are the different labels?
Speaker 2:  We should look for the different types of power that USBC can
Speaker 2:  do. So
Speaker 4:  When USBC first started, there were a lot of different specs. There are
Speaker 4:  still a lot of weird, different, little proprietary, fast charging
Speaker 4:  specs. There are bigger, fast charging things, but the most important one
Speaker 4:  and the one that's become the main one that virtually everyone uses in some
Speaker 4:  capacity is USB power delivery or USB PD. Now
Speaker 4:  there are several versions of that. Newest is USB PD,
Speaker 4:  three.one, which was announced in may. They started rolling out new logos,
Speaker 4:  new documentation for it in September. And there are actually products shipping
Speaker 4:  with it today. The new MacBook pros that apple just released
Speaker 4:  do use USB PD, three.one for the mag safe ports, not the
Speaker 4:  regular ports, just the max eight ports.
Speaker 2:  Sure. And what is USB PD? three.one, get us
Speaker 4:   gets you all the benefits of USB PD,
Speaker 4:  which is the different tiers of charging. It is designed
Speaker 4:  that the two devices can kind of handshake and go, I need 10 Watts
Speaker 4:  and your charger will go, okay. I can give you 10 Watts. So it does all that,
Speaker 4:  but it ups the wattage considerably. So USB
Speaker 4:  PD three a which the one that came before this was up to a hundred
Speaker 4:  Watts and was sort of the bottleneck for adding
Speaker 4:  USBC to laptops, higher powered laptops for
Speaker 4:  charging, because the most of you got, if it was a hundred Watts, the bigger
Speaker 4:  laptops you have apples old 16 inch literally was a 97
Speaker 4:  watt USBC charger, but you can go pass that. So this
Speaker 4:  goes all the way up to two 40, assuming you have a device cable on a
Speaker 4:  brick, that can go that
Speaker 2:  Right. And so I looking for USB PD,
Speaker 2:  three.one on the box or the cable. Am I looking for like a
Speaker 2:  color code? How do I know that my device,
Speaker 2:  my cable and my brick are all capable of getting to
Speaker 2:  40 Watts through that entire chain,
Speaker 4:  The USB implementers forum, which is the group that comes up with all these
Speaker 4:  standards is not the best at naming and not the best at
Speaker 4:  branding. They are trying a different tack with this
Speaker 4:  generation of stuff, which is, they now have bespoke
Speaker 4:  logos that are supposed to appear on certified PD, three.one
Speaker 4:  devices, and also certified USB four devices, which is not the same thing
Speaker 4:  as PD three.one, which we'll get to in a minute. And it's
Speaker 4:  literally either a two 40 watt. It'll be like a little sticker on your
Speaker 4:  thing that this is a cable that is capable of going up to two 40. It's
Speaker 4:  like a little USB. It has a thing. You can see it on our site. And they also
Speaker 4:  have one for up to 60 Watts. So you'll know this is either,
Speaker 4:  you know, a quote unquote, low power cable that's designed to
Speaker 4:  charge, you know, lower power things. Or this is a high powered cable that
Speaker 4:  can charge your theoretical, you know, 240 watt gaming laptop.
Speaker 2:  And for me like the big thing with USB PD, and this was a
Speaker 2:  problem early, early on with USB-C is there, like you mentioned that
Speaker 2:  proprietary charging Samsung Qualcomm had one that was super weird. A bunch
Speaker 2:  of Android phones were using wackadoo fast charging systems and
Speaker 2:  not using standard USB PD, but by and large, it
Speaker 2:  seems like we are at a place where most stuff is using the non-proprietary
Speaker 2:  standards-based USB power delivery system. And it's just a matter of
Speaker 2:  making sure that you look for the correct label on the box to
Speaker 2:  make sure that your cable is capable of providing the power that your device
Speaker 2:  is asking for. Exactly. Okay. So power could be
Speaker 2:  worse, but it's, it's definitely like, okay,
Speaker 2:  for the most part, as long as you're keeping an eye on things, what about
Speaker 2:  data? Because we also have new standards for transferring data.
Speaker 4:  So data is where things get a little complicated
Speaker 4:  because just because you have USB-C cable does not
Speaker 4:  necessarily mean you're using the USB data
Speaker 4:  transfer spec. And even if you are using the USB data transfer
Speaker 4:  spec, it doesn't guarantee that you're using any particular version
Speaker 4:  except for us before, which in part was largely designed to fix a lot of
Speaker 4:  these issues. There are many different USB
Speaker 4:  specs. There are many different names. They have gone through various attempts
Speaker 4:  to rebrand them. So we have all the way going through you have
Speaker 4:  USB three.one gen one, USB three.one, J two USB three.one,
Speaker 4:  two den, one USB through to two gen two USB, three dot two gen one by
Speaker 4:  two used to be three to dot three dot two gen two by
Speaker 4:  two a and USB four. Wonderful part of this is
Speaker 4:  not as bad as it sounds because a lot of it is whenever they come up with
Speaker 4:  a new standard. So when we have, you know, USB three,
Speaker 4:  two USB three, one gen one gets renamed to USB
Speaker 4:  three to gen one, and same with gen one by two and gen two by
Speaker 4:  two. A lot of this is just backporting because the new
Speaker 4:  standard has to include all the previous standards so that if I get a
Speaker 4:  USB three dot two gen two by two supporting cable, and I
Speaker 4:  plug it into, you know, my old headphones or, or my old computer that only
Speaker 4:  supports the lower data transfer speed, everything still needs to work.
Speaker 2:  And to a certain extent, you know, we're running through all the different
Speaker 2:  names of all the specs over the years, but this is a probably
Speaker 2:  actually kind of want to have, I mean, you want to have clear branding for
Speaker 2:  sure, but you want your cables to get faster over time.
Speaker 2:  Right? You want it, you want this to,
Speaker 4:  Yes. The perfect opposite example is lightning, which is the same cable,
Speaker 4:  the same port, and hasn't updated its data transfer speed, and, you
Speaker 4:  know, half a decade at least, and transfers much, much, much slower
Speaker 4:  than USBC does. Right. So this is a good kind of problem. It
Speaker 4:  does lead to some confusion. And that in part is sort of what USB
Speaker 4:  four is sort of trying to solve.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. So why don't you talk about USB for what it's trying to solve and what's
Speaker 2:  good and maybe bad about it.
Speaker 4:  Okay. So you asked before is the newest USB spec. And it does a
Speaker 4:  couple things differently than like the four versions of
Speaker 4:  USB three dot two that existed before, which
Speaker 4:  is, it is technically a super set of USB three dot
Speaker 4:  two and Thunderbolt three, which went open source in 2017. So it was
Speaker 4:  previously Intel's own standard. Now it's open source.
Speaker 4:  And a lot of that is what the foundation of USB four is. Okay. A
Speaker 4:  couple of things that make you as before different is you're no longer allowed
Speaker 4:  to make USB type a cables or USB BB cables. If it is
Speaker 4:  us before it has to be USBC. Got it. Second, if you
Speaker 4:  are doing charging, the charging has to support PD. Got it.
Speaker 4:  So in theory, if you buy USB for cable, you know, that it will
Speaker 4:  have certain minimums for charging and certain minimums or data
Speaker 4:  transfer, and those will be consistent across anything that is
Speaker 4:  USB four compatible. Got it, which is good,
Speaker 4:  except it's not perfect. Because when we
Speaker 4:  mentioned before that, you don't have to do both at the same time, so
Speaker 4:  you don't have to do everything. So there's two different levels of USB
Speaker 4:  for data transfer a USB for, it goes all the way up
Speaker 4:  to 40 gigabits per second, but there are actually two
Speaker 4:  substandards there's USB for 20 gigabits per second, which as the name implies
Speaker 4:  only goes up to 20 gigabits per second. And then there's USB for
Speaker 4:  40 gigabits per second, which goes all the way to 40 gigabytes per second.
Speaker 4:  And there are also separate logos for those two things. So in
Speaker 4:  theory, when you're looking at a USB for cable or
Speaker 4:  charger, well USB for cable, for data transfer, you're going to look at the
Speaker 4:  cable and it'll say on the box, you'll look for 20 or 40. And you'll have
Speaker 4:  an idea of whether you have the slower or faster cable and then
Speaker 4:  60 or two 40, which will give you an idea of whether you have the
Speaker 4:  slower, faster charging.
Speaker 2:  And part of the thinking here, isn't just, oh, let's confuse people. It's
Speaker 2:  that like making a full USB for 40
Speaker 2:  gigabit, two 40 watt cable. It's just, it costs
Speaker 2:  more, right? And so you could theoretically go buy something that only does
Speaker 2:  20, cause you don't need the 40 cause that's a lot. Or you could buy something
Speaker 2:  that doesn't support all the way up to two 40. You only need a hundred or
Speaker 2:  15 or whatever, because you can save a ton of money buying
Speaker 2:  a full spec top of the line, USB for cable supports
Speaker 2:  everything. It's like buying an old Thunderbolt three cable it's, you know,
Speaker 2:  there's limits on its length. And it's also costs a lot of money, right?
Speaker 4:  Yes. Before also does fix a couple of the other problems with the older USBC
Speaker 4:  standards because it is built on Thunderbolt three. So USB four by
Speaker 4:  default will support things like audio and display port, which you did
Speaker 4:  not necessarily have to bundle in before on USB three.
Speaker 4:  But it's also a slow rollout. Like to my knowledge, there are no two
Speaker 4:  40 watt USB four cables that you can just buy today. Except
Speaker 2:  Technically, I guess you could say maybe the mag safe, although it's not
Speaker 2:  for a gigabyte MagSafe has just power
Speaker 4:  By two MagSafe cables and cut the ends off and splice them
Speaker 4:  together. You might have one, but please, actually,
Speaker 4:  please do. If you spend $160 on this and on this med science
Speaker 4:  experiment and you don't electrocute yourself, let me know if it works.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, please, please be safe. We don't recommend trying this at home, but
Speaker 2:  if you wanted to, so you briefly mentioned display part alt mode and audio.
Speaker 2:  So there's like standard data transfer, but USB C cables have also been used
Speaker 2:  just for straight audio or for straight providing display via the display
Speaker 2:  port standard that was not necessarily included before. But part of
Speaker 2:  the point of view as before is that all gets, that all has to be part of
Speaker 2:  the spec now. Exactly.
Speaker 4:  That's sort of a trickle down effect from thunderbolts, right? Because you
Speaker 4:  have all these alt modes and these optional protocols that you can build
Speaker 4:  in that you don't need to necessarily, or you didn't need to. If
Speaker 4:  the logic sort of was, if I was building a pair of headphones or a battery
Speaker 4:  pack, the battery pack doesn't need data transfer. Right. For the most part,
Speaker 4:  there are one or two battery packs that have firmware that you can update.
Speaker 4:  But for the most part, most battery packs don't need data. Yeah. My battery
Speaker 4:  pack doesn't need a headphone Jack. Right.
Speaker 2:  Right. Okay. So you roll up to amazon.com or best buy or Walmart or
Speaker 2:  whatever. And you see there's a USB 3.2 cable and USB for cable.
Speaker 2:  Is it, is it reasonable that you might just want to spend less money and
Speaker 2:  get the 3.2 cable? Is it, is that a totally normal thing to do? Or should
Speaker 2:  everybody be thinking, oh, I only want to buy USB for, from now on if possible.
Speaker 4:  I mean, as someone who likes to future proof their stuff, I always try and
Speaker 4:  buy the most, which is funny because now all my a hundred watt cables are
Speaker 4:  going to be worthless. If I ever get a device that needs more than that.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I mean, it depends a lot on what you're using it for. If you're looking
Speaker 4:  for, you know, a one, a one job fits all cable to hook your computer up to
Speaker 4:  your monitor, that'll do, you know, audio and the whole USB hub, this built
Speaker 4:  into your monitor and display port and charging and everything, make sure
Speaker 4:  that you're getting the cable that you need for that. And it can
Speaker 4:  be easier just to get a USB for cable. Cause you're pretty much guaranteed
Speaker 4:  that that will work, right. If you want to avoid the hassle, that's probably
Speaker 4:  your best solution. If you know what you're doing, if you just need something
Speaker 4:  to charge your cell phone at night, you know, we just want a long cable to
Speaker 4:  stretch across the living room to, you know, charge your phone while you're
Speaker 4:  watching Netflix. You're probably good with anything so long as it, you know,
Speaker 4:  supports PD and the thing to really keep an eye on. And this is the thing
Speaker 4:  that, you know, you'll see on sellers on Amazon and in stores, look at what
Speaker 4:  the wattage that it supports is because not all PD cables support a hundred
Speaker 4:  Watts, even some are 30 Watts. Some are 60 Watts. I have personally run
Speaker 4:  into when I've been charging with cables and realized like my laptop wasn't
Speaker 4:  charging. Cause it was only a 30 watt cable cause it was really old.
Speaker 2:  Right? So this all sounds great. We've landed at USB four is the one that
Speaker 2:  you can safely buy, but you brought up Thunderbolt a couple of
Speaker 2:  times and now Thunderbolt is Intel standard and it
Speaker 2:  has, it's using the same USB-C plug at least with Thunderbolt three,
Speaker 2:  they opened source Thunderbolt three. So that's now part of USB four,
Speaker 2:  but there's a new version of Thunderbolt. Can you tell me a little bit about
Speaker 2:  that?
Speaker 4:  So that's thunderbolts for, and the difference between Thunderbolt
Speaker 4:  for, in us before is thunderbolts is proprietary to
Speaker 4:  Intel. Not that other device and other manufacturers can't use it. They show
Speaker 4:  up on devices all the time. Again, Apple's new MacBook pros are Thunderbolt
Speaker 4:  for ports, but if you want to make a thunderbolts for device or a
Speaker 4:  cable, you need to go to Intel and Intel has to approve it and test
Speaker 4:  it and make sure that everything works. And thunderbolts is
Speaker 4:  sort of the idea that the USB for standard was
Speaker 4:  sort of promising before, which is that it's just
Speaker 4:  one cable. You don't need to worry about what you're getting or what you're
Speaker 4:  doing or anything. If it has the thunderbolts and a four on it, you can plug
Speaker 4:  it into your Thunderbolt thing with four on it and you will be guaranteed.
Speaker 4:  It'll support, you know, the 40 gigabits right off the bat, it'll support
Speaker 4:  the multiple displays, it'll support, you know, PCA data transfer speeds
Speaker 4:  up to a certain thing. It'll work with thunderbolts for docs socially, you
Speaker 4:  have more ports. The flip side is that Thunderbolt for cables and Thunderbolt
Speaker 4:  for accessories are really expensive. So
Speaker 4:  it's sort of your one shot fits all thing except you you're paying for that
Speaker 4:  privilege. Right? The other weird quirk is thunderbolts four was built
Speaker 4:  on the original batch of USPS before.
Speaker 4:  So it's cross compatible with that in a lot of ways. So it supports, you
Speaker 4:  know, the USB for 40 gigabit per second data transfer rate, which is the
Speaker 4:  Thunderbolt three one, but used before has a weird quirk actually where
Speaker 4:  it is slightly better in theory, in charging than
Speaker 4:  thunderbolts because Thunderbolt right now only does a hundred watt
Speaker 4:  charging because it has the old PD spec because Thunderbolt
Speaker 4:  four came out in July, 2020, a
Speaker 4:  full year before the USP actually introduced
Speaker 4:  three.one with this two 40 spec goddess. So if you are
Speaker 4:  buying a new and at this point,
Speaker 4:  non-existent, if you're buying, you know, a laptop somewhere in the
Speaker 4:  future and it charges it to 40 Watts, or right now we Thunderbolt for
Speaker 4:  cable, theoretically does not charge that, which is actually a quirk. You
Speaker 4:  can see just to bring it up again. Cause it's the only device that's even
Speaker 4:  a little bit using three.one PD, three.one, right on the 16 inch Mac
Speaker 4:  book. The reason that you can only fast charge the 16 inch Mac book through
Speaker 4:  that mag safe port is because that's the only one that uses
Speaker 4:  USB PD, three.one, the other three are Thunderbolt ports. And those
Speaker 4:  can still only charge at a hundred Watts, which isn't the full one 40 that,
Speaker 4:  that 16 inch laptop needs to fast charge. Right?
Speaker 2:  So in theory, we could say that that MagSafe port is a USB
Speaker 2:  for port, but it's not USBC. It's not really even USB cause it's just power.
Speaker 2:  It's a sort of a,
Speaker 4:  Yeah. So the max safe port doesn't do data like you can't plug your Mac safe
Speaker 4:  cable into a USB C hard drive. And that's the perfect
Speaker 4:  example of how you can use PD as a spec without necessarily
Speaker 4:  using the USB for transfer and everything. Okay.
Speaker 2:  Okay. Lightning round lightning round. If I have a Thunderbolt for
Speaker 2:  cable, does it support everything that USB four does?
Speaker 4:  Yes. Except for the 240 watt charging. Got it.
Speaker 2:  If I have a USB for cable, does it support everything? Thunderbolt
Speaker 2:  three does.
Speaker 4:  Yes, but they are not entirely cross
Speaker 4:  compatible. All Thunderbolt three stuff should work with us
Speaker 4:  before, but it's not necessarily backwards compatible because Thunderbolt
Speaker 4:  three came first. So like if you have an older hub, it might not necessarily
Speaker 4:  play well, unless it's been updated, et cetera. Got it.
Speaker 2:  If I see a USB-C cable sitting on my desk, what can I
Speaker 2:  trust that it will do
Speaker 4:  No label audit? You can't trust that it will do anything in
Speaker 4:  theory. It is probably a good bet that it will do data
Speaker 4:  transfer at at least five gigabits per second. And that it will charge at,
Speaker 4:  you know, at least five Watts, which is the minimum data
Speaker 4:  transfer rate of USB three.one gen one, which is
Speaker 4:  the slowest and worst USB-C cable that
Speaker 4:  exists anything past that. There's no real way to know,
Speaker 4:  unless it physically says on the cable has, you know, the
Speaker 4:  USPI branding that they've been encouraging people to use or some other
Speaker 4:  markings, you know, on the physical cable itself.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Which nobody's doing, I've never seen this mark on, on the cable itself
Speaker 2:  in my life, except maybe I'll say like the thunderbolts
Speaker 4:  I'll occasionally see the, the display port one. Like I have a cable on my
Speaker 4:  desk that has a display port one. There is in theory, like a USB
Speaker 4:  for 20 and 41. Like I have a nice picture of it from USB I
Speaker 4:  F of what it could look like on a cable, but I've never seen it in person,
Speaker 4:  but I also haven't seen it two 40 watt cable yet. So maybe, maybe that's
Speaker 4:  a new
Speaker 2:  Final lightening round question. Are you happier with this
Speaker 2:  system than with having every single cable does something different?
Speaker 2:  It has a different port and looks different and you don't know if it, you
Speaker 2:  know, you plugged it in the wrong way and whatever are you, do you think
Speaker 2:  we're better off with this USBC plug and these like
Speaker 2:  progressing standards on top of this same cable year after year?
Speaker 4:  I actually do think we're better off because at the end of the day, a lot
Speaker 4:  of this does suck and is really confusing, but
Speaker 2:  I think we're better off. Cause a lot of this sucks. It was really confusing.
Speaker 2:  The verge,
Speaker 4:  I have a BA I have like a good, a good second half of the sentence. All right.
Speaker 4:  If you are willing to, you know, play not entirely play by the rules and
Speaker 4:  play to the higher end and always assume the worst out of
Speaker 4:  USB-C. If you charge everything with an a hundred watt
Speaker 4:  PD charger, then I know that I can confidently travel with one
Speaker 4:  brick and two cables and I can charge my laptop and my
Speaker 4:  headphones and my Kindle and my switch and my battery
Speaker 4:  pack. And I don't need to bring a separate charger for this
Speaker 4:  and a separate charger for that. I don't need to worry about, you know, oh,
Speaker 4:  did I bring the right USB cable? Did I bring the right thing? Everything
Speaker 4:  works. And if I need to plug this into that, I have one cable.
Speaker 4:  That'll do that. If I need to, you know, sync an ebook that I bought, I can
Speaker 4:  do that. So the benefits do still outweigh
Speaker 4:  the negatives, especially because, and this has
Speaker 4:  been true for awhile and hopefully continue to be true. Things are
Speaker 4:  slowly getting better, that things are getting more consolidated. When I
Speaker 4:  first bought a Nintendo switch, like I couldn't figure out how to
Speaker 4:  charge it with anything other than the charger it came in because the PD
Speaker 4:  standard was very new and things were out. Battery
Speaker 4:  packs were out. Cables were out that didn't support PD on PD chargers were
Speaker 4:  actually pretty expensive at the time. Now every charger in my house is a
Speaker 4:  PD charger and I can charge my switch with my laptop charger and vice
Speaker 4:  versa. So things have been getting better. It's just been a slow
Speaker 4:  March. There's a Kindle with USB-C now, like that did not exist
Speaker 4:  for a very long time. So it is a slow thing forward,
Speaker 4:  but it is better. It's just still not great.
Speaker 2:  And it's never going to have it on the iPhone.
Speaker 4:  It's never going to happen on the iPhone.
Speaker 2:  All right. Well, here we go. Hi. Thank you so much for coming on the verge
Speaker 2:  cast and explaining all of this to us. We will have more
Speaker 2:  to explain about USB-C I'm sure in the near future,
Speaker 4:  I look forward to arguing about it
Speaker 4:  then.
Speaker 2:  Okay. So you've actually got the right cable. You're transferring
Speaker 2:  data at 40 gigabits per second. You're ready to charge a 240
Speaker 2:  Watts. That's great. Congratulations. You bought a cable,
Speaker 2:  unfortunately that's still just the beginning. You
Speaker 2:  still need the right ports on your actual devices
Speaker 2:  and you still need a charging brick that could support all the wattage that
Speaker 2:  you want. And there are still a lot of devices that
Speaker 2:  just haven't adopted USBC at their laptops
Speaker 2:  with barrel plugs gadgets with micro USB. And of
Speaker 2:  course the iPhone still uses Apple's lightning
Speaker 2:  connector C for a lot of companies. It doesn't make
Speaker 2:  sense to change over to the newest tech standard for a
Speaker 2:  variety of reasons. If you have a hardware design that's been built around
Speaker 2:  like micro USB, it costs a lot of money to change that. And if you
Speaker 2:  don't need to redesign your product or it wouldn't necessarily benefit
Speaker 2:  from what USBC has to offer, it doesn't really make sense to
Speaker 2:  spend all that development money to remake your product, just to put a new
Speaker 2:  port on it. Now, rod wippy who we spoke to earlier has seen
Speaker 2:  USB-C from its infancy. He was there at the very start
Speaker 2:  of making new kinds of data speeds and power standards work. So I
Speaker 2:  asked him is the adoption rate for USBC, just taking
Speaker 2:  way too long.
Speaker 3:  The question I think it has taken longer than I
Speaker 3:  expected, but I'm not surprised pecan doing
Speaker 3:  USB C properly and supporting
Speaker 3:  these hundred Watts charging or 240 Watts charging in the future.
Speaker 3:  You need to put a chip in their fridge for a start, right, just to do a hundred
Speaker 3:  Watts instead of 60 Watts. You need to have a chip in the cable and you need
Speaker 3:  to have chips at either end that can do this negotiation
Speaker 3:  to do high-speed data. You know, the 40 gigabits per second. Well, these
Speaker 3:  days, even inside a new laptop, just to get from the
Speaker 3:  processor, which is sitting in the middle of the laptop to the ports on either
Speaker 3:  side, you need extra chips to really drive the 40 gigabit
Speaker 3:  signal. I mean, if you remember the first Mac book that came out with
Speaker 3:  USBC, it had USBC on one side only, right?
Speaker 3:  There's a reason for that.
Speaker 2:  And it wasn't that they, they hate having ports on both sides.
Speaker 3:  If you want to have bots on both sides and you need to put extra chips in
Speaker 3:  there to really drive the signal, the further distance to the other side,
Speaker 2:  That's amazing. That's like less than a foot, but still when you're going
Speaker 3:  At 40 gigabits per second, then 10 centimeters
Speaker 3:  matters.
Speaker 2:  So you can see that this is way more complicated than you assumed. It's not
Speaker 2:  just say Microsoft resisting, putting USBC on the surface. Cause they're
Speaker 2:  worried. People will get confused about whether or not they should use their
Speaker 2:  phone charger to charge their laptop. It gets down to centimeters
Speaker 2:  within the device itself. Even apple who led the charge for
Speaker 2:  USB-C on laptops had this problem where they didn't want to spend
Speaker 2:  the extra money to put extra ports all the way. On the other side of the
Speaker 2:  laptop, there are still technical limitations to this technology,
Speaker 2:  which have hindered adoption. Rod says that once you start going past two
Speaker 2:  meter cables, for example, you start to stretch the boundaries of the
Speaker 2:  technology and you start thinking about putting repeaters him to the cable,
Speaker 2:  but Hey, you know, we've got USB-C ports on both sides of the Mac book now.
Speaker 2:  So progress. Anyway, speaking of apple, as we mentioned
Speaker 2:  before, Mac books have fully incorporated the Thunderbolt three standard
Speaker 2:  into USB-C and newer iPads have USBC
Speaker 2:  on them. And that's great, but again, the iPhone doesn't
Speaker 2:  and it seems more likely that the iPhone is going to end up with no
Speaker 2:  ports before it ends up with a USB C
Speaker 2:  port, but that hasn't stopped our next
Speaker 2:  guest from adding USB-C to the iPhone
Speaker 2:  himself.
Speaker 5:  And I could see like how that could possibly be done. And I saw that nobody
Speaker 5:  was doing it. And so just one day I thought, well, maybe I'm the guy who's
Speaker 5:  going to do that.
Speaker 2:  We're going to take a quick break for some ads. But when we come back, I
Speaker 2:  talked to Ken PO PNL, a hardware hacker in Switzerland about how he
Speaker 2:  opened up an iPhone 10 and figured out how to replace the lightning
Speaker 2:  port with
Speaker 2:  USB-C.
Speaker 2:  Okay, we're back with the Vergecast USBC special. I'm about to talk
Speaker 2:  to Ken PNL who cleverly built USB-C directly
Speaker 2:  into his iPhone. So I guess
Speaker 2:  if we could start with, can you tell me why you
Speaker 2:  decided to pursue this project of getting USBC
Speaker 2:  working on an iPhone?
Speaker 5:  I think there's a lot of reasons like the first one that's maybe the most
Speaker 5:  relatable one is that like as a consumer, you know, I
Speaker 5:  think it was in 2015, apple came out with like the Mac book and
Speaker 5:  they really sold it as having courage and like
Speaker 5:  going all in with this type Seaport that is going to be deported to the future.
Speaker 5:  And that we only have this one connector to rule them all.
Speaker 5:  And I was really like sold by that idea, you know? And then the
Speaker 5:  years went by and for some reason, this lightning four, it
Speaker 5:  just stuck around and it didn't want to go and
Speaker 5:  don't get me wrong. I am a super fan of apple. Like I like what they do,
Speaker 5:  but I never could be like full on into the ecosystem
Speaker 5:  because there was always this thing that was bothering me. So I always had
Speaker 5:  like an Android phone and after a while, like I started
Speaker 5:  to gain more skills and I could see like how that could possibly
Speaker 5:  be done. And I saw that nobody was doing it. And so just one day I
Speaker 5:  felt, oh, maybe I'm the guy who's going to do that. And I just, I
Speaker 5:  just went for it. So
Speaker 2:  I built a sort of an outboard, you know, thing for it so that you could just
Speaker 2:  test to see that it worked and you were, you know, tracing all the leads
Speaker 2:  and whatnot. And you were pulling off little chips from Apple's own board
Speaker 2:  and transferring it over. What was that process like? Did you sort
Speaker 2:  of have a hunch? It would work or was it, was that part of the process of,
Speaker 2:  well, let's see if this thing will even work even with a, you know, big,
Speaker 2:  giant Frankenstein thing attached to the side of the phone.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So I thought if it works with the big Frankenstein thing,
Speaker 5:  then there's no reason that it won't
Speaker 5:  work. If I redo it myself smaller, it's just so matter of
Speaker 5:  time and dedication and like fixing the problems.
Speaker 5:  But in theory, if you see it work here with you on eyes and it's
Speaker 5:  big, I know for a fact that there's a lot of stuff in here that are not
Speaker 5:  useful, like, like the lightning connector, I can remove it, I can replace
Speaker 5:  it before wires and things like that. So I knew then that I
Speaker 5:  could get it done. Eventually. I just didn't know how long it would take.
Speaker 2:  And one of the really surprising things to me, I mean, maybe not surprising,
Speaker 2:  but just something I haven't thought about is that you, without
Speaker 2:  working at a big company or whatever, you can, you can go out and design
Speaker 2:  a board and design a PCB and like, have it
Speaker 2:  manufactured for you. Can you tell us a little bit more about that process?
Speaker 2:  Because you know, I was like, how do you fit the electronics in there? And
Speaker 2:  like, I would, I would have wires everywhere. I would never have occurred
Speaker 2:  to me. Like, oh wait, I could just go into CAD. I can actually make a thing
Speaker 2:  and have somebody manufacture it for me.
Speaker 5:  So it's not too complicated. Like you said, you're going to a cat
Speaker 5:  software, a thing here. The most difficult part was
Speaker 5:  choosing the shape of the board because like my board
Speaker 5:  bends 90 degrees two times. And so you really need to have some kind
Speaker 5:  of like spatial awareness of like where it's going to
Speaker 5:  go inside the phone and, and really imagine it. And
Speaker 5:  once that's done, it's really like a flat surface. And then you place the
Speaker 5:  components where they are, and then you like run little
Speaker 5:  like traces. It's like little wires on them. And then you get
Speaker 5:  like a file that you send to hear it. It was a company in
Speaker 5:  China and they manufacture it for you and then they send it to you and then
Speaker 5:  you can sort their things on it. And yeah, it's, it's pretty amazing.
Speaker 5:  What, like before you, you couldn't do that. But now for the
Speaker 5:  last few years, there's really a lot of companies like low-cost companies
Speaker 5:  that came into the market and that proposal services
Speaker 5:  and like for the, do it yourself community, it's really like
Speaker 5:  awesome. Can, you can do things you couldn't do before.
Speaker 2:  And it really is incredible. Oh, I'm sorry. I meant to ask, why did you pick
Speaker 2:  the iPhone 10? Was it, it, was it just that it was like not too expensive
Speaker 2:  or was, do you think that there was stuff on newer I-phones that would've
Speaker 2:  made this project more complicated?
Speaker 5:  So first I started like more than a year and a half ago, almost
Speaker 5:  two years ago. So I think back then it was like the iPhone 11, the
Speaker 5:  latest iPhone. And it was just, I didn't want to pick the latest
Speaker 5:  one because there was the most expensive and I went with the iPhone X
Speaker 5:  and also now looking back because I was thinking maybe I could forward it
Speaker 5:  to another iPhone, like the iPhone 12 and I from 13 or something like
Speaker 5:  that, I'm not sure I'll be the person to do that because
Speaker 5:  there's a, with like the repair community, they have kind of like
Speaker 5:  a, a war with apple on authorized
Speaker 5:  repairman and unauthorized. And now they're really like
Speaker 5:  putting serial numbers on parts. So you can't just like you, it
Speaker 5:  could be for bias screen and swap it up yourself. And so that
Speaker 5:  kind of annoys me. I thought if I, if I break something which I
Speaker 5:  did in phonetics, I broke the screen. I broke, I broke a few things that
Speaker 5:  I had to change multiple times. If I need to have those specialized
Speaker 5:  tools just to change my screen, once it doesn't make sense. Right.
Speaker 5:  And GI for next didn't have those problems. So
Speaker 5:  also it made a great fit for this.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. That makes a lot of sense. When you managed to get USB in and
Speaker 2:  working and got everything working, do you know if you were able to get,
Speaker 2:  I don't know, faster data speeds. One of the problems with lightning is it's
Speaker 2:  it's data speeds are slower. I'm assuming that it's just, you know, it's
Speaker 2:  the same interface and internally with the board you made. So it, it basically
Speaker 2:  still had USB two or whatever lightening speeds are, but I'm wondering, were
Speaker 2:  there any other functional differences that you noticed once you switched?
Speaker 5:  So that's the question I get a lot. I think so first about data,
Speaker 5:  there's a limitation inside the iPhone where the
Speaker 5:  connection to the main board only has, you could say two
Speaker 5:  wires, two data wires, and that's the limiting
Speaker 5:  factor. Like I don't see myself being able to change that that would
Speaker 5:  take care. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  You'd have to replace the whole main board. You're taking the whole thing.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  So if you want to get into faster data transfers, USB
Speaker 5:  three, for example, then you need multiple pairs of
Speaker 5:  wires and use be true. Only had one. So they're called deep
Speaker 5:  loss and D minus data plus data minus signals. And so
Speaker 5:  in the iPhone, all the I-phones until the latest ones, all we'll
Speaker 5:  have this one pair. And so that's the limiting factor. You can't, you
Speaker 5:  can't change that. So yeah, the project is stuck at USB to
Speaker 5:  then about accessories. Can you plug in a
Speaker 5:  USB-C hub and then put HTMI sadly
Speaker 5:  nuts. You can't do that in this mud simply because the
Speaker 5:  accessories up use all have a different chip inside the
Speaker 5:  accessory. So the way I see it at least is if I
Speaker 5:  wanted to include all accessories, I would have to
Speaker 5:  include like a, this little chip inside my special
Speaker 5:  board and then have some kind of logic. Like, I'm not saying it's a
Speaker 5:  possible, I'm just saying it would take me maybe an extra two
Speaker 5:  years to add either by their accessories.
Speaker 5:  So then I fought charging and data is already
Speaker 5:  pretty good. Then if I have more time, I'll do something. I'll probably
Speaker 5:  add something else.
Speaker 2:  I wondered if it'd be possible to take, say the USB connection off an
Speaker 2:  iPad, like the new iPad mini and take those parts and plug them into an
Speaker 2:  iPhone. If it would just, you know, somehow work. But it sounds like it probably
Speaker 2:  wouldn't, it'd be a lot more complicated than that.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I've thought about this in the beginning. So in the iPad, I think what
Speaker 5:  changes is that there is a software change. So iPad always
Speaker 5:  knows it's directly talking a USB language. And so
Speaker 5:  what's useful in inside the iPhone, like the hardware,
Speaker 5:  which has be the little connector, but the little connector I can order
Speaker 5:  it for $2 of any website. It's, it's no different
Speaker 5:  than the others. So the thing in the iPad is that it's the
Speaker 5:  software already knows it's talking USB and then goes through the USB
Speaker 5:  connector. Whereas here, if I would want to do something like that, I
Speaker 5:  would have to change the software on the iPhone so that it
Speaker 5:  knows it talks to you is B and not lightning,
Speaker 5:  but that would change completely the scope of the project. It would be
Speaker 5:  like jailbreaking GA phone or something like that whole thing. And
Speaker 5:  so here, it was only a hardware rack where we took the
Speaker 5:  chip that does the conversion in the cable, and we
Speaker 5:  integrated it inside the iPhone so that it does the job for
Speaker 5:  us without having to worry about software or anything else.
Speaker 2:  Were you surprised at your ability to, I don't know, fit the
Speaker 2:  larger USB-C plug at the bottom of the phone? I, you know, you did a really
Speaker 2:  clever thing to, to mill out the space, finding the space inside
Speaker 2:  for your adapter, where you concerned early on like, oh, wait, apple goes
Speaker 2:  with lightening. They must have to cause it's thinner. There's no way this
Speaker 2:  could work. Or just from taking apart. I-phones did you know, like, come
Speaker 2:  on, this is, this is actually possible.
Speaker 5:  So it worried me a little bit at the beginning because it
Speaker 5:  does look bigger when, well it lays bigger cause I had to drill out the
Speaker 5:  hole. But when I went to choose actually the connector
Speaker 5:  that I was telling you about, like actually order it on a website, just that
Speaker 5:  little connect, her metallic piece, every time you ordered those
Speaker 5:  components, there is like 2d drawings with the
Speaker 5:  dimensions. And so I went through maybe like 50 of them or
Speaker 5:  something like that to look at their dimensions and compare them
Speaker 5:  with the lightning connector. And I was trying to find one
Speaker 5:  that could actually maybe be smaller than the lightning
Speaker 5:  connector. And I did in the end. I did find one that was
Speaker 5:  smaller. So the connector where you plug in the cable is
Speaker 5:  bigger, but from the outside, like the volume that the
Speaker 5:  connector takes, the one I chose is actually smaller than the lightning
Speaker 5:  connector. And so that gave me some extra room to then
Speaker 5:  do a little 3d printed bracket that holds the connector. So it
Speaker 5:  doesn't when you plug in the cable, it, it feels strong. So yeah, I
Speaker 5:  think that's a, that's pretty funny to know about that in the end is that
Speaker 5:  micro negative is actually smaller than the lightning connector.
Speaker 2:  And so you, you put all this on get hub and there was a step where you had
Speaker 2:  to get, like you had to order some extra parts. Can you talk about the process
Speaker 2:  of sort of putting your, your process out there, the worlds so that anybody
Speaker 2:  might theoretically be able to, to redo what you did?
Speaker 5:  So when I was trying to reverse engineer this little
Speaker 5:  connector that apple builds for their cables,
Speaker 5:  right. I saw that there was kind of, it wasn't impossible
Speaker 5:  to do, but it was kind of hard to do because they make it. So it's hard.
Speaker 5:  They make it. So people don't go put their nose in that cable and see how
Speaker 5:  it works, because then maybe someone in China will make a fake connector
Speaker 5:  and then sell it on their website. And then they lose revenue for those
Speaker 5:  accessory sales. And then I thought, if I
Speaker 5:  continue pursuing this connector, then it's first. I
Speaker 5:  don't think I'll be able to make it open source because if I do, then I'm
Speaker 5:  basically putting out the layout of what apple builds.
Speaker 5:  It's kind of like, I put the plans out there, how to
Speaker 5:  remake what they do. Right. And then here I would definitely
Speaker 5:  get in trouble.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Regardless of whether or not you are right for the various
Speaker 2:  DMTA style rules, apple would not be afraid to go after you and you don't
Speaker 2:  want to deal with that hassle, even if you were in the right.
Speaker 5:  So I knew, I knew from the beginning, if I did, that would get in
Speaker 5:  trouble. And then I, I started, I was doing some research on the
Speaker 5:  connector and then one day I stumbled across an article that was
Speaker 5:  saying, actually, someone did what you want to do already.
Speaker 5:  Someone hacked that cable and they're selling fake cables on the internet
Speaker 5:  for cheaper so that you can charge your iPhone or your, your
Speaker 5:  airports with that cable. And it won't give you an error message
Speaker 5:  saying this cable is not the original. Then I, it like clicked in my
Speaker 5:  mind, Hey, maybe I can hack them. I can hack the
Speaker 5:  hackers. And so then when I posted my plans
Speaker 5:  online, I'm not posting the plans of what apple did.
Speaker 5:  I'm posting the plans of the people who hacked apple. So it's not, I'm not
Speaker 5:  really doing anything wrong. Right.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. That's great. And why did you post the plans? I mean, you know, you
Speaker 2:  could have been like, look, look what I did, but like, was it important to
Speaker 2:  you to put this up on, on GitHub instead of, you know, just like a blog post
Speaker 2:  or something?
Speaker 5:  Well, here, you know, there's files, right? There's the schematics for the
Speaker 5:  electronics. And I thought probably some people who want to contribute to
Speaker 5:  that and then they can actually add their own files to it. Of course,
Speaker 5:  that I need to look into it, see if it's good and then I can add it. But
Speaker 5:  then if it's like a hub, well, it's got the get hub, but if it's like a
Speaker 5:  hub for this project, then people can go on it and maybe they
Speaker 5:  can download their own files and then make their own version of it,
Speaker 5:  modify it however they want. I think that's very interesting
Speaker 2:  Using the iPhone that you modded as your phone,
Speaker 5:  I've used it for a few days just to see that it wouldn't burn in my
Speaker 5:  hand, but no, I'm, I'm using outside of some
Speaker 5:  phone as a, as a daily driver. If you could
Speaker 2:  Speak briefly, what do you think of USB-C itself as
Speaker 2:  a spec, as a standard? Do you really like it? I know
Speaker 2:  apple was evangelizing it early on, but do you think it's a good
Speaker 2:  plug? Do you think it's a good standard or is it just that, it's the thing
Speaker 2:  that everyone's using and that's why you wanted to get it going on the,
Speaker 5:  But I think it's an aspect that some sometimes not talked about too much
Speaker 5:  on why it's, it would be interesting to have only one connector. Like
Speaker 5:  you can't save things only when they go your way. Like you can't
Speaker 5:  stop including a charger in your iPhone in the box and say it's
Speaker 5:  to reduce waste. And then for other things like the connector, you
Speaker 5:  act the complete opposite, you know what I mean? So I've, yeah. I think it's
Speaker 5:  important to be consistent with what you say and with
Speaker 5:  what you think. And I think that's an important aspect to talk about.
Speaker 2:  Do you think it's worth the trade off of having the same plug,
Speaker 2:  given all these extra complications and things you need to know about? Because
Speaker 2:  in the old world, every plug was a different shape. And so you knew what
Speaker 2:  the plug would do based on its shape. Do you think that we're better off
Speaker 2:  having all the plugs have that same USB shape it, but you need to
Speaker 2:  understand what the cable or the, you know, devices are capable of,
Speaker 5:  I think we're better off if it's safe. So I mean, if the worst
Speaker 5:  that can happen is that you're charged your Mac book very slowly
Speaker 5:  instead of at the normal speed. I think, I think it's worth it, but I
Speaker 5:  do think that in the mid to long-term, there needs
Speaker 5:  to be solutions to that. And I think that's things that I will
Speaker 5:  explore in my channel if I, if, if, if it's something that is of
Speaker 5:  interest to people, and I know it's of interest to me, because I'm here talking
Speaker 5:  to you about this right now, I'll definitely do some more research
Speaker 5:  about that and maybe propose ideas that are mine are not mine
Speaker 5:  and get people talking about the subject.
Speaker 2:  Well, cool, man. It's a, it's a really fun project. I'm really glad you did
Speaker 2:  it. It's it's really nice. If nothing else, to be able to point to it and
Speaker 2:  be like, yep. See, like nothing, nothing exploded. The world didn't come
Speaker 2:  to an end. The phone still works fine. Nobody, nobody got hurt. It still
Speaker 2:  fits. So if nothing else congrats for showing everybody that it's,
Speaker 2:  it's absolutely possible.
Speaker 5:  Thank you. Thank you so
Speaker 5:  much.
Speaker 2:  So now Ken probably has the only iPhone of the world that has
Speaker 2:  a proper USBC port on it outside of Apple's labs. And I
Speaker 2:  am, I have to admit insanely jealous. So look, we know that
Speaker 2:  apple doesn't want to put USBC on an iPhone,
Speaker 2:  but if they want to keep ports on it in general, they might actually be
Speaker 2:  ordered to make the switch
Speaker 10:  Commissioners proposing common USB-C charging ports for
Speaker 10:  all new smartphones, iPads, tablets, cameras, and
Speaker 10:  headphones
Speaker 11:  In terms of waste. This is significant because this measure will allow us
Speaker 11:  to save one tons of electronic waste and
Speaker 11:  2,600 tons of raw materials per year. There is also the
Speaker 11:  impact on CO2 emissions. It will save 180,000
Speaker 11:  tons of CO2 equivalent per year.
Speaker 2:  So the European union may speed up the process of forcing companies to adopt
Speaker 2:  USB-C. But speed up is a relative term because the
Speaker 2:  European union has been talking about charging standards for devices for
Speaker 2:  around a decade or so. In fact, one of the reasons that a bunch of phones
Speaker 2:  switched over to micro USB from all of the proprietary charging standards
Speaker 2:  was the European union, tried to force that as the standard, and
Speaker 2:  now we're moving onto USB-C. So now they're pressuring apple
Speaker 2:  to switch the iPhone over to USB-C and in
Speaker 2:  theory, that could happen, but the reality could turn out to be much, much
Speaker 2:  different. And actually, I also talked to him Gartenberg a little bit about
Speaker 2:  all this.
Speaker 4:  So the proposal is mandatory USBC
Speaker 4:  on all devices for smartphones and other electronics, common charging
Speaker 4:  port. The goal here is to cut down on e-waste, by letting people
Speaker 4:  reuse their existing chargers and cables that you don't have to get a new
Speaker 4:  charger. Every time devices won't have to include charges in the box anymore,
Speaker 4:  which is a trend we've already started to see with companies like apple and
Speaker 4:  Samsung. And it notably would only apply to wired
Speaker 4:  ports, not wireless ones. So this is, as you said, it's really the
Speaker 4:  culmination of like a decades long process. The EU
Speaker 4:  actually did have a similar thing where they had required
Speaker 4:  micro USB, but that original voluntary thing
Speaker 4:  was less strict and also allowed,
Speaker 4:  you know, the loophole of you could include an adapter in the box,
Speaker 4:  right? Which apple did for a while, when you bought an iPhone in the
Speaker 4:  EU, it would come in addition to a lightening cable, it would include in
Speaker 4:  the box like a $15 low freebie of lightning to micro
Speaker 4:  USB cable so that you could use your existing
Speaker 4:  chargers and plugs with that device, which is really the thing that the EU
Speaker 4:  is looking to try and cut down on under this proposed rule,
Speaker 4:  you would not be allowed to sell a device. You know,
Speaker 4:  if it has a form of wireless charging, it has to have USBC.
Speaker 4:  So for example, apple in theory could make, you know, an iPhone
Speaker 4:  EU edition that had a USB-C port and a lightening port,
Speaker 4:  but in theory, under the rules, it would not be allowed to just offer a
Speaker 4:  lightening port.
Speaker 2:  Would they be allowed to offer a phone that has only wireless
Speaker 4:  Charging, only wireless charging would be allowed? Okay. The exception here
Speaker 4:  includes the fact that it only applies to it common wired
Speaker 4:  port. If the device doesn't offer wired charging, it is not required
Speaker 4:  to fall in. It doesn't have to abide by that rule. I see the proposal
Speaker 4:  is right now, also just a proposal it's still needs to pass a vote in the
Speaker 4:  European parliament. And then if it is actually adopted as
Speaker 4:  law device manufacturers, like apple will then have
Speaker 4:  two years to comply with the new rules. So there could still be
Speaker 4:  a fair amount of time before this actually impacts don't necessarily
Speaker 4:  expect the iPhone 13 to suddenly have a USBC port.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  So how do you think it's going to shake out? I mean, we, it took us this
Speaker 2:  long to get to the proposal that apple is strenuously fighting. I know you're
Speaker 2:  not an expert in European law, but do you foresee apple like
Speaker 2:  saying sure. You know what, you're right. We're working on.
Speaker 4:  On the one hand, there's not a lot of wiggle room in this proposal, which
Speaker 4:  would require either apple will have to ship a USBC iPhone.
Speaker 4:  It could limit it. Geographically could only sell them in the EU. It could
Speaker 4:  take an approach similar to the bundled in adapters that it offered at the
Speaker 4:  time. I assume apple as a company will be doing everything it can, you
Speaker 4:  know, from a lobbying and legal side, to make sure that this doesn't actually
Speaker 4:  become law. It also could try and jump to a
Speaker 4:  proprietary wirelessly charging, iPhone. The issue there is sort
Speaker 4:  of getting the genie back in the bottle because apple can sell a
Speaker 4:  wireless charging iPhone or a wireless protocol iPhone, but it
Speaker 4:  already supports Chyanne it's stuff, which is a universal charging
Speaker 4:  standard. It's actually the first and really only, you know,
Speaker 4:  cross apple universal charging standard that you can use to charge an iPhone
Speaker 4:  and something else. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  I mean, there are ways to transfer data wirelessly right next to each other.
Speaker 2:  Like there, there have been phones, the failed essential phone that actually
Speaker 2:  literally had a little near field wireless USB thing. So you
Speaker 2:  could attach things to, and who can communicate over a relatively slow, but
Speaker 2:  it was there like wireless USB. So these things are possible. We just have
Speaker 2:  no idea how aggressively apple is pursuing them.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. But the other issue is, is that there's no real wireless solution that
Speaker 4:  exists yet. That's better than wire charging. There's a reason we use wired
Speaker 4:  charging for things which is transferring data. Wirelessly is not as fast
Speaker 4:  as transferring at wired transferring power. Wirelessly is not as efficient.
Speaker 4:  And even if apple can circumvent those two issues and come up
Speaker 4:  with a super fast, super power efficient way of doing power and data
Speaker 4:  transfer it also then has the trap of its own argument, which
Speaker 4:  is switching away from lightening to something else will generate a huge
Speaker 4:  amount of e-waste. And it'll inconvenience customers switching from
Speaker 4:  lightening to a new proprietary magnetic wired thing with a dock
Speaker 4:  and a cable and everything will generate a huge amount of e-waste and
Speaker 4:  generate more waste than just switching to USBC
Speaker 4:  would.
Speaker 2:  Okay. We have learned a lot here about USB-C its
Speaker 2:  advantages disadvantages and the wacky things
Speaker 2:  that makes us do in a confusing tech market. So here we are,
Speaker 2:  but where are we going? What's next for USBC?
Speaker 2:  How will the technology advance I asked rod with be,
Speaker 3:  I think the next thing will be higher data rates. As we've seen the power
Speaker 3:  go from a hundred Watts to 240 Watts, the data rates go from five to
Speaker 3:  10 to 20 to 40. I expect, you'll see, 60 gigabits a second
Speaker 3:  with a Thunderbolt five or something. I've got no internal information, of
Speaker 3:  course. And even if I did, I wouldn't be able to disclose it, but that's,
Speaker 3:  but that's just what you expect. People always want faster data, always want
Speaker 3:  bigger video screens, which means more data being transferred across the
Speaker 3:  table. So I think at the moment, the research is there
Speaker 3:  to be able to send more data across the same cable. And the
Speaker 3:  spec is now there to be able to send a higher power across the
Speaker 3:  same cable. So I think we'll see a two hundred and forty one
Speaker 3:  sixty gigabits per second data cable is the next step.
Speaker 2:  This is why I keep bringing in rod because he's got me excited for the
Speaker 2:  near future, but he also makes me take a step back and realize how
Speaker 2:  we actually got here with USB-C.
Speaker 3:  The emphasis, I guess, is there is a lot of work that happens
Speaker 3:  through a lot of engineers and a lot of different companies to make sure
Speaker 3:  that when you plug a USB cable into a computer that actually
Speaker 3:  does something and it's incredible the number of ways that it could
Speaker 3:  possibly not work, but somehow through all this hard work,
Speaker 3:  usually, you know, 98% of the time just does
Speaker 3:  work.
Speaker 2:  Here's how I deal with all of this confusion. I just make sure that
Speaker 2:  I know which of my USBC cables are good and can do the
Speaker 2:  things that I need. And I e-waste the bad ones for
Speaker 2:  me. I know that the cables that I get from apple and Google tend to work
Speaker 2:  better and they also happen to be white cables. So I keep
Speaker 2:  those cables around for when I need a good USB-C cable,
Speaker 2:  but for the cheap stuff like charging earbuds or cameras or
Speaker 2:  whatever, I have a bunch of cheap cables that happen to be
Speaker 2:  black. And if I need something truly
Speaker 2:  reliable, like the main cable I plug in my laptop with
Speaker 2:  Thunderbolt cables usually have a little lightning bolt on them. So I keep
Speaker 2:  an eye out for that. Is that a perfect solution? No, not
Speaker 2:  even a little, but is it better to have fewer
Speaker 2:  cables? Yes, actually it really
Speaker 2:  is. And as we're going to see in this series of special
Speaker 2:  Tuesday, Vergecast episodes do standards and technologies do
Speaker 2:  solve real problems, but they don't solve them quickly.
Speaker 2:  And they do bring up new problems of their own in the
Speaker 2:  meantime. And the truth is we live in the
Speaker 2:  meantime. It's always the
Speaker 2:  meantime. Thank you for listening to this.
Speaker 2:  USB-C spectacular. We brought the term back.
Speaker 2:  See what I did there. You're welcome. I'm sorry. This episode of the verge
Speaker 2:  cast was made by Andrew Moreno, Liam, James and B Dieter
Speaker 2:  Bohn special, thanks to Haim. Gartenberg Ken PNL and rod would
Speaker 2:  be who gets a second extra. Thanks for working on web iOS
Speaker 2:  internals back of the day. Thank you to all of them for lighting us along
Speaker 2:  this journey. The Vergecast we'll be back on Friday and my Tuesday
Speaker 2:  episodes will return. Next
Speaker 2:  week.
Speaker 13:  Hi there it's Peter Kafka. And I wanted to tell you that we've wrapped our
Speaker 13:  latest season of land of the giants, the podcast that
Speaker 13:  explores the biggest, most important tech companies of our time. This time
Speaker 13:  we looked at apple company that changed what a computer is and then change
Speaker 13:  what a phone is. The iPhone has given apple tremendous
Speaker 13:  power, but it's forced the company to make compromises that didn't expect.
Speaker 13:  Apple says
Speaker 14:  Privacy as a fundamental human, right? But it also conflicts with its need
Speaker 14:  to follow the laws of every country. It operates in, especially in
Speaker 13:  And it's app store generates billions in profit, but that doesn't work for
Speaker 13:  everyone.
Speaker 15:  Apple basically is preventing me small business owner and
Speaker 15:  servicing my customers the way I've serviced them for many, many years for
Speaker 15:  decades. And they're saying, no, you can't do it now.
Speaker 13:  I mean, well, what exactly is going on with apple TV
Speaker 13:  plus
Speaker 16:  Apple doesn't want to win this trimming wars. They want to be extremely
Speaker 16:  highly regarded for their tastes
Speaker 13:  Land of the giants, the apple revolution Recode and the box media podcast
Speaker 13:  network. This season is sponsored by web flow and you can catch up on the
Speaker 13:  entire series. Now, wherever you get your podcasts.