# Transcript
ID: b495be10-494b-11ec-90a7-c371242af330
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Apple will make repair manuals and parts available to public / Russia blows up a satellite / Biden signs infrastructure package
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/1336462472/1118624148/s93290-US-5452s-1637333860.mp3
Description: Nilay Patel and Dieter Bohn chat with policy reporter Makena Kelly about Pres. Biden's $1 trillion infrastructure package and what it will do to improve broadband access in the US.
Senior science reporter Loren Grush joins the show to talk about Russia destroying one of its own satellites with a ground-based missile.
Managing editor Alex Cranz stops by to chat about Apple opening up iPhones and Macs to DIY repairs.
Speaker 1:  This week on the verge cast mechanic, Kelly joins the show. You talk about
Speaker 1:  the new $1 trillion infrastructure package, what it means for broadband
Speaker 1:  EVs, all kinds of other things. Lauren Gruss joins the show. We talk about
Speaker 1:  Russia, blown up a satellite in space. What's going on with space X and trans.
Speaker 1:  During the show we talk about Apple's new repair system and lots of other
Speaker 1:  things that's come up on the Rochester. Now
Speaker 2:  The future is here and that's as true in banking as it is. In fact,
Speaker 2:  in fact, capital one is building software like a tech company using
Speaker 2:  machine learning and real-time data in the cloud to solve unique, challenging
Speaker 2:  problems to benefit millions of customers like an industry, leading
Speaker 2:  AI powered, intelligent assistant Eno, or their fraud detection and
Speaker 2:  prevention capabilities or improving the customer service experience
Speaker 2:  capital one's AI and machine learning capabilities are at the forefront of
Speaker 2:  what's possible in banking today. Learn more about how capital one
Speaker 2:  is building cutting edge experiences for its
Speaker 2:  customers@capitalone.com slash tech.
Speaker 3:  You probably know that smartphones really got started with the iPhone, but
Speaker 3:  did you know there was an innovative app driven smartphone six years
Speaker 3:  before it
Speaker 4:  Took off like a rocket. Everybody wanted this product
Speaker 3:  And act in a new documentary from the verge called springboard the secret
Speaker 3:  history of the first real smartphone. We look at a tiny startup called
Speaker 3:  handspring that tried to create the modern phone before anybody was ready
Speaker 3:  for it. You can watch springboard now for free on the verge TV app
Speaker 3:  and learn more at the verge.com/springboard. That's the
Speaker 3:  verge.com/springboard.
Speaker 1:  Hello, and welcome to the broadcast, the flagship program with
Speaker 1:  infrastructure roads, bridges, ports. We've been talking about them for
Speaker 1:  10 years on this podcast. And today we're going to do it again. I'm your
Speaker 1:  friend Nila. Dear brown is here. I
Speaker 3:  Am a week cause it's
Speaker 1:  Infrastructure week. Oh, there you go. Well done mechanic. Kelly's here.
Speaker 1:  Hi McKenna. Hey, McKenna is not amused, but my
Speaker 1:  infrastructure jokes, I am just laughing.
Speaker 2:  No, it's great. It's finally
Speaker 1:  Infrastructure week. It didn't. I mean your policy reporter, I feel like
Speaker 1:  you've been living in the moment of it's infrastructure week
Speaker 1:  four or five years. So I'm happy that you got this
Speaker 1:  when there's a lot going on this week, McKenna is going to talk to us about
Speaker 1:  the infrastructure package, what it means for broadband electric vehicle
Speaker 1:  chargers. There's another bill coming with tax credits, three bites. There's
Speaker 1:  FCC drama. A little later in the show. Loren Grush is going to join us. There's
Speaker 1:  drama in space as well. Satellite explosions for real, it's like a real thing.
Speaker 1:  And then Alex, Cranz gonna join us at the end of the show. That's some apple
Speaker 1:  stuff in somebody around, but let's start with the infrastructure package.
Speaker 1:  It is a long time coming. President Trump famously promised an
Speaker 1:  infrastructure package. A hijack for many reasons, never came to pass
Speaker 1:  Biden obviously came into office promising a huge program called
Speaker 1:  build back better, which was then broken up into two bills. The first trunk
Speaker 1:  passed. There's a second potentially more controversial bill coming.
Speaker 1:  That's coming to a vote as well. What passed now? It's a trillion dollar
Speaker 1:  package. What's in there for, for people who are interested in tech.
Speaker 6:  So Monday Biden actually signed the bill at the Congress
Speaker 6:  and the house and the Senate approved it finally a couple of weeks ago and
Speaker 6:  they held this like gigantic signing ceremony at the white house. There was
Speaker 6:  like a whole band. It was like kind of cool to actually see an accomplishment
Speaker 6:  like that under like some administration where there's actually
Speaker 6:  like a speech in a white house and like all of this kind of stuff in the
Speaker 6:  background of a signing. So that was cool. But essentially it's a $1 trillion
Speaker 6:  deal that includes a lot of money to fix bridges and roads
Speaker 6:  and the things that we drive and walk over every day. But then also there's
Speaker 6:  a lot of stuff in there that touches on tech and a lot of things that the
Speaker 6:  verge covers primarily broadband expansion. Of
Speaker 6:  course, a lot of people in the country do not have access to high-speed broadband.
Speaker 6:  This is an issue we have been trying to solve for how many decades now all
Speaker 6:  of them, exactly. All of the decades,
Speaker 1:  George Washington was like, here's my platform. He was
Speaker 6:  Like, why can't I download apps fast enough? But anyways,
Speaker 6:  so the bill got approved and that means that there's $65 billion
Speaker 6:  now headed to states to get infrastructure
Speaker 6:  built so people can have those in-home connections. And what the administration
Speaker 6:  is saying is that this money is going to make sure every household in America
Speaker 6:  is connected to high-speed broadband by the end of the decade, which, you
Speaker 6:  know, we don't know, we can't really predict the future, but that's a really
Speaker 6:  cool goal. If they're able to move that,
Speaker 1:  I put that in the context of like, you know, historic programs to electrify
Speaker 1:  every home or to get every house on the phone network.
Speaker 1:  $65 billion does not seem like a lot of money, right. In the context of a
Speaker 1:  trillion dollar package. Even in the context of that number, it's not a big
Speaker 1:  number. I guess my two questions are, is it enough? And it's going to the
Speaker 1:  states, like, how is it going to be administered? Like, how does it work?
Speaker 1:  Do like, do I just get a check? Are you just gonna write me a check? And
Speaker 1:  I can go find a broadband provider? Like, how's it, how's it gonna happen?
Speaker 6:  Unfortunately, that's not really the case. That would be kind of sick if
Speaker 6:  it was. But basically the $65 billion is a smaller number.
Speaker 6:  At first, the Biden administration this year promised a hundred billion,
Speaker 6:  but the 65 is kind of what was reconciled between
Speaker 6:  Republicans and Democrats. Many Republicans who were like
Speaker 6:  broadband is not infrastructure, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah. Right. And
Speaker 6:  we came to agreement with broadband is infrastructure enough for 65 billion,
Speaker 6:  I guess, was the logic. I don't know. But basically it comes down to
Speaker 6:  subsidizing right? And giving the whole problem with
Speaker 6:  broadband expansion is that you look at Verizon, you'll get 18 T you look
Speaker 6:  at all your ISP, right? And they just don't have the
Speaker 6:  incentive to connect one family living in the
Speaker 6:  middle of nowhere, Nebraska. I can say that cause I'm from Nebraska.
Speaker 6:  Right? So they just don't get the right return on investment. So these costs
Speaker 6:  need to be subsidized in order for the infrastructure to be built.
Speaker 6:  Now, the interesting thing that we need to talk about here, especially is
Speaker 6:  like this, isn't going to be fiber to every home. And that's
Speaker 6:  something that was a little sad for Democrats and more progressive. This
Speaker 6:  is, this is going to be a process that has to do with some fiber, with
Speaker 6:  some other cables, you know, co-ax and then also like wireless
Speaker 6:  5g services, I guess, is here.
Speaker 6:  So it's going to be a mix of all of these things in order to get people connected.
Speaker 6:  Sure.
Speaker 1:  Or the state's in charge is the FCC in charge like
Speaker 6:  Notably the FCC was left out of the
Speaker 6:  infrastructure package pretty broadly, which I think we can kind of get into
Speaker 6:  when we talked about the FCC later, but the FCC has been unable to really
Speaker 6:  do anything this year. They have had like a two to
Speaker 6:  stalemate with net neutrality being rolled back. There's a lot of questions
Speaker 6:  about the extent to which the FCC has any authority over
Speaker 6:  broadband. So the money is being sent to the commerce department
Speaker 6:  essentially to offer, you know, kind of like grant programs to states
Speaker 6:  who basically say, Hey, we have this really cool plan. We need
Speaker 6:  this much money. Can you give it to us? And that's kind of how it's going
Speaker 6:  to be solved so far
Speaker 3:  Broadband, you mentioned it could be 5g. It could be co-ax. Are we
Speaker 3:  still working with the definition of broadband that we've been working with
Speaker 3:  here in the U S which is like somewhat 25 down three up something insane
Speaker 3:  like that? Yeah.
Speaker 6:  It's twenty-five three still. And now this year there was some senators who
Speaker 6:  saw, you know, an opportunity in the infrastructure build to be like, Hey,
Speaker 6:  we need 100 over 100 or at least, you know, 100 over
Speaker 6:  something that, you know, is still much faster than three megabytes
Speaker 6:  upload. And there were some letters, there were some discussions, right.
Speaker 6:  But that did not end up making it in the final infrastructure package that,
Speaker 6:  and then, so I guess this leads into the FCC kind of having to make this
Speaker 6:  decision later and maybe with a democratic majority fingers crossed, I
Speaker 6:  guess if that's what you want, they can change that definition
Speaker 6:  later once they're able to do anything.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. We'll get to that. That is a whole swirl of drama, which is kind of
Speaker 1:  interesting, but just on broadband just to lay it out. So the commerce
Speaker 1:  department gets $65 billion and then the state's going to the commerce department
Speaker 1:  and say, we've got a cool plan to pay at and T to
Speaker 1:  wire every house in Wisconsin, which I can say, cause I'm from Wisconsin.
Speaker 1:  And then the Congresswoman is like, okay, here's the money who makes sure
Speaker 1:  that they don't just waste it. That 18 T decision is blow it because the
Speaker 1:  immediate reaction from a lot of people, like in my mentions and I was like,
Speaker 1:  I'm excited about this was I've heard these lies from Verizon before.
Speaker 1:  Right, right. Cause it's true. Like I think the state of New Jersey has
Speaker 1:  paid Verizon like $10 billion to give one house fires
Speaker 1:  and they just hit like there's lawsuits and it's deeply corrupt. And I think
Speaker 1:  there's a lot of skepticism here. There's also, I think in,
Speaker 1:  I noticed you get the same replies. I do. Sometimes there's a lot of people
Speaker 1:  that are like, just give the money to Starling. Right. Cause they'll do it.
Speaker 1:  And you know, there's like, there's a lot to unpack there, but I
Speaker 1:  think people are rightfully skeptical of the big broadband
Speaker 1:  providers who have not done the work they should have done even with some
Speaker 1:  subsidies already. And so like what makes this money? What, what
Speaker 1:  mechanism makes this money more effective this time? Do you think it's
Speaker 6:  Unfortunate because I really, I don't know. That's we always want to be able
Speaker 6:  to make these promises, right? The FCC Democrats want to be able to say,
Speaker 6:  well, this money is going to do what you want it to do, but the only effective
Speaker 6:  enforcement that we've had over the past, I don't even know if we can call
Speaker 6:  it an effective, but the only like working enforcement that we've really
Speaker 6:  had has been, you know, very thorough FCC investigations
Speaker 6:  that take a lot of time, but then also like state attorney general lawsuits.
Speaker 6:  So what
Speaker 1:  I can imagine is there might be something in some contract, a
Speaker 1:  state or a locality makes with a broadband provider
Speaker 1:  to maybe essentially it later, if they don't fulfill it to have like the
Speaker 1:  state ag go after them or something. But it is hard, you know, with
Speaker 1:  net neutrality the way it is. And with so much skepticism over title two
Speaker 1:  and authority, it's hard to say, you know what enforcement will look like
Speaker 1:  in the future. I just want to unwind that because you've said it a couple
Speaker 1:  of times, what you mean by net neutrality is not actual net neutrality. It's
Speaker 1:  when net neutrality was rolled back, the FCC actually gave up its
Speaker 1:  authority to regulate broadband at all, but they weren't just like, we're
Speaker 1:  not doing that neutrality. They're like, we now have prohibited ourselves
Speaker 1:  from doing anything. Right. So their ability to even like, look at this and
Speaker 1:  enforce, this is constraint.
Speaker 6:  It depends on the interpretation rank. The FCC is just a house full of
Speaker 6:  lawyers,
Speaker 1:  Furnished building in DC. It's so
Speaker 6:  Fun, Florida. We love it. But it's essentially like a, it's just like a house
Speaker 6:  full of lawyers who have like different interpretations of what they can
Speaker 6:  do. So like the FCC could do something and then, oh my God, you know,
Speaker 6:  some lawyer somewhere might Sue them and say it's illegal. So
Speaker 6:  essentially like they did give up like that. Sure. I
Speaker 6:  think a lot of people on the left and like Democrats and progressives will
Speaker 6:  say, well, when they did give up title to net neutrality rollback, they
Speaker 6:  did get rid of this authority. But it hasn't really been challenged in like
Speaker 6:  too many ways to really sort that out judiciously. So it
Speaker 6:  is kind of this weird, like haunting apparition above
Speaker 6:  the FCC. But you know, we're going to talk about this and then the
Speaker 6:  podcast is going to go up and then you're gonna have a ton of telecom lawyers.
Speaker 6:  And I mentioned being like, well, that's not actually what it is and blah,
Speaker 6:  blah, blah, but that's the world.
Speaker 1:  And then it's mentioned so like telecom lawyers and Starling
Speaker 1:  families. It's great when they get together.
Speaker 6:  I wish the guidance could have seen my visceral reaction when you mentioned
Speaker 6:  Starlink, because honestly I just wanted to scream. I could
Speaker 6:  feel it in my throat, all the mentions I get
Speaker 1:  Just to be clear for everyone, space X and Starlink have received
Speaker 1:  billions of dollars in subsidies already Starling
Speaker 1:  specifically and pretty controversially
Speaker 1:  Starlink applied for subsidies to provide service in like the parking lot
Speaker 1:  of Walmart stores and like other heavily populated
Speaker 1:  areas, which is maybe that maybe at the end of the day, Starlink is
Speaker 1:  just another ISP in the act like other ISP.
Speaker 1:  Like I appreciate that. People love them. I'm just saying if you're a broadband
Speaker 1:  company, my instinct is not to trust you. That's that's the way that
Speaker 1:  goes.
Speaker 6:  Speaking of Ilan too specifically, another interesting thing in the
Speaker 6:  infrastructure bill is that there's a couple of billion
Speaker 1:  Dollars in it to build out a nationwide Evie charging
Speaker 1:  system. That was a great segue.
Speaker 6:  But yeah, so there's a nationwide Evie charging plan in there to
Speaker 6:  basically over the next couple of years, make sure that you can just like,
Speaker 6:  you would like go get your big gulp or whatever. When you like go fill up
Speaker 6:  with gas, you can basically do that with your EBT card too, which is kind
Speaker 6:  of cool to see that coming into play.
Speaker 1:  I have the same question here. $7.5 billion is maybe not enough
Speaker 1:  billion dollars, but it's some it's meaningful. I've talked to a lot
Speaker 1:  of car company CEOs on decoder. They're like, we're waiting for the government
Speaker 1:  to help us with charging. How does this, how are they going to pay electrify
Speaker 1:  America or are they going to pay the states? How does this money get allocated?
Speaker 6:  That's a really interesting thing. It's something that I think Andy would
Speaker 6:  be better well-suited to talk about, but I have, I have a feeling it's probably
Speaker 6:  the same kind of grant program. There's a problem with like handing out money
Speaker 6:  to states. And like this argument over federalism is very wonky
Speaker 6:  things with Republicans that they like trying to do grant
Speaker 6:  programs and things, but that's it, the goal is, you know, to do it
Speaker 6:  over the next couple of years. And I think what we can actually say for real
Speaker 6:  is like with the government backing this, I think having a
Speaker 6:  plan to do this over so many years, we actually incentivize other,
Speaker 6:  you know, car companies or infrastructure companies to follow suit. Right.
Speaker 6:  Invest more money on their own, seeing that this is already starting. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  I think the E V charging thing, every time we bring up another
Speaker 1:  Evie on the show when Andy or Sean are on the show, Shawn was on last week,
Speaker 1:  the feedback is that car looks great, but it doesn't have a supercharger
Speaker 1:  network. Right, right. And so like, I should buy a Tesla instead of whatever
Speaker 1:  new Eve, if this even goes a little bit of the way to making that market
Speaker 1:  more competitive. I think that's a good thing. I just, I'm kind of at the,
Speaker 1:  a lot of these companies are gonna try to get this money and actually holding
Speaker 1:  them accountable to using it for what it's for. I'm very central wealth
Speaker 1:  brought in companies historically, maybe less so with the EAP companies.
Speaker 1:  So I think at the end of the day, like GM and Ford will
Speaker 1:  know when their customers can't charge their cars and they can't, that's
Speaker 1:  not an acceptable outcome. Like thousands of dead electric
Speaker 1:  F-150 is on the highways of America is not an acceptable outcome for Ford.
Speaker 1:  Like I think they're, they're motivated to solve the problem, but
Speaker 1:  I'm very curious before we get CFC, what else is in this bill that's worth
Speaker 1:  thinking about,
Speaker 6:  That's kind of where we are with tech on that bill. Mostly the interesting
Speaker 6:  thing now is like we have to wait and see what happens with the other half
Speaker 6:  of the bill back better plan, which is more trillions of dollars for more
Speaker 6:  tech related things. So it's at this point now where we really don't
Speaker 6:  know when votes will happen in Congress, but what's in the BBB package right
Speaker 6:  now is some really fun stuff that I think our audience specifically will
Speaker 6:  be interested in specifically there's e-bike tax credits in there.
Speaker 6:  So you get like 30% tax credit through the IRS when you buy
Speaker 6:  like a, an eBike worth, like $1,500 or something,
Speaker 6:  which incentivizes more people to buy. Those
Speaker 3:  Is shocking me that the is hung on to the bill for this long I was expecting,
Speaker 3:  it would be one of the first things to get cut when they started, started
Speaker 3:  slicing things down. But it's still there,
Speaker 6:  Right? Yeah, no, I was surprised too. Cause I IDM somebody in a
Speaker 6:  senator's office and I was like, this was y'all's thing. Like, is it still
Speaker 6:  in there? And they're like, we're really scared, but we'll see that it was
Speaker 6:  so every white everyone was like, oh my God, this is so cool. And then also
Speaker 6:  something that I think is really important to talk about is this free laptop
Speaker 6:  program. That's in the BBB program as well. The infrastructure bill, like
Speaker 6:  we just talked about 65 billion to make sure families have in-home access
Speaker 6:  to high speed broadband. But what does that mean for families who don't have
Speaker 6:  devices at all? Right? So this program essentially
Speaker 6:  gives states and housing authorities, public
Speaker 6:  libraries, all these kinds of organizations, the ability to ask for
Speaker 6:  grant funding from the commerce department in order to make either
Speaker 6:  laptops, desktops, or tablets free
Speaker 6:  for people of lower income, they could also partner with
Speaker 6:  Microsoft maybe or some other company in order to do like a refurbish
Speaker 6:  lower cost device program. So that's really, really cool. And really
Speaker 6:  it comes down to, you can put all the money out there for broadband access,
Speaker 6:  but people still don't have the devices to even connect. You're really not
Speaker 6:  helping people all that much. So that'll be cool to see if it gets past
Speaker 1:  At the beginning of the pandemic McKinney, you've actually done a bunch of
Speaker 1:  stories with us pre pandemic during the pandemic, right? There's like the
Speaker 1:  homework gap for a lot of kids where they don't have access. And then
Speaker 1:  they, all they have is their schools, devices, which may or may not be
Speaker 1:  useful. So you connect broadband and you give people devices. That's that's
Speaker 1:  good. What's the status of that. Second bill is kind
Speaker 1:  of up in the air, right?
Speaker 6:  It is. So this is an interesting thing that happened before the house
Speaker 6:  left a couple of weeks ago. They there's this fight between
Speaker 6:  progressives who had long been promised. We're going to get these social
Speaker 6:  services programs in the BB, in the in Biden's infrastructure plan. We've
Speaker 6:  been promised this, we want the Medicare. We want things like that. And then
Speaker 6:  the bill got severed into, so Progressive's were like, well, we can
Speaker 6:  vote on Biff, but we bipartisan infrastructure bill, sorry, I should've just
Speaker 6:  like layered Twitter dragon. We should. When we vote on the infrastructure
Speaker 6:  bill, we need to vote on the BBB as well, the social spending program.
Speaker 6:  And I think it was close to 20 house Democrats refuse
Speaker 6:  to, they voted no on the infrastructure package. And so that infrastructure
Speaker 6:  package was narrowly very narrowly approved. So that BBB bill
Speaker 6:  and needs to be brought up in both the house and the Senate for a new
Speaker 6:  vote in order for it to pass. So the politics in the house of
Speaker 6:  course are a little shaky, but the politics in the Senate on that
Speaker 6:  is also a little shaky with Joe Manchin. Of course, who held
Speaker 6:  up the infrastructure package for a while and then Kirsten cinema
Speaker 6:  noted, Democrat net neutrality, hater,
Speaker 6:  the only Democrat who really opposes net neutrality. And so their votes are
Speaker 6:  really such a razor-thin majority in the Senate. They need those votes in
Speaker 6:  order to improve the BBB. And they're hoping to do this
Speaker 6:  Thanksgiving before December before something the timeline's not
Speaker 6:  entirely sure, just so
Speaker 1:  Just yet. I don't think I want to get too deep into the intro
Speaker 1:  Democrat politics of it all. There are many podcasts available for you to
Speaker 1:  listen to, if you want to really get deep into the weeds on democratic
Speaker 1:  party politics, but fundamentally, how do they decide,
Speaker 1:  okay, broadband goes in this bill, but laptops, let kids
Speaker 1:  use that. Broadband goes in this bill. It was there any rhyme or reason to
Speaker 1:  that?
Speaker 6:  The second half of the bill is being done through a process in the Senate
Speaker 6:  called reconciliation. So that has kind of changed a little bit of the
Speaker 6:  language, especially because they have to do it through reconciliation because
Speaker 6:  they only need a small majority rather than a super majority to
Speaker 6:  pass it, which requires those two democratic senators.
Speaker 6:  Right. In order for it to get approved with Biff, Biff,
Speaker 6:  Biff is called Biff because it's bipartisan, right. They had that super
Speaker 6:  majority, it was passed a lot of Republican support. And
Speaker 6:  for a long time, a lot of Republican senators, not just Democrats have been
Speaker 6:  calling for a universal broadband access, right? So that was easy to
Speaker 6:  secure in there. Maybe it wasn't as much money as Democrats had hoped, but
Speaker 6:  they were able to get it in there and secure it, bipartisan win for the Biden
Speaker 6:  administration.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. And we have long noted that giving people a faster internet
Speaker 1:  access is like across the aisle. Everyone wants it. Sometimes it's
Speaker 1:  the, it comes down to how will you deliver it is the disagreement, but, and
Speaker 1:  every member of Congress wants to go back to their district and be like,
Speaker 1:  you're an ass faster. And I did that and it's a pretty easy
Speaker 1:  win to deliver to people. Okay. Let's talk about the FCC because it
Speaker 1:  has come up in the context of broadband. So many times the FCC is in a moment
Speaker 1:  of extended drama in like many different
Speaker 1:  dimensions. So let's start with the simplest one that they did have a vote.
Speaker 1:  They might have a new chairperson soon who we know well, it's Jessica Rosenworcel,
Speaker 1:  we've, I've talked to her, you've talked to her, she's been on the show,
Speaker 1:  but then there's Gigi sewn, who we've also talked to a lot at the verge who
Speaker 1:  seemed as much more controversial breakdown what's going on there.
Speaker 6:  Right? So since the beginning of the Biden administration, a Jeep PI, the
Speaker 6:  former chair stepped away. And right now we're sitting at a two
Speaker 6:  to stalemate with two Republicans and two Democrats.
Speaker 6:  So they can't really do anything too controversial. They can't really do
Speaker 6:  anything that Democrats really want to do, whether that's passing net neutrality
Speaker 6:  or putting more broadband regulations in place because they just don't
Speaker 6:  have the votes to do it. So that's the way it's been for 11 months
Speaker 6:  now where they've just been kind of doing essentially like
Speaker 6:  administrative work spectrum work, basically just kind of like cleaning the
Speaker 6:  floors of like things, easy cooperatively, like things that just
Speaker 6:  need to get done. So they've been able to do that. And if, if for
Speaker 6:  so long, even over the summer, we're hearing rumors about who the next
Speaker 6:  FCC chair is going to be. Who's the next person who's going to be appointed.
Speaker 6:  And eventually it ended up being Jessica Rosenworcel who is serving as chair
Speaker 6:  now. And now we have Gigi stone who noted progressive supports net
Speaker 6:  neutrality supports like broader regulations for broadband at the
Speaker 6:  FCC used to work for Tom Wheeler as a general counsel during like the net
Speaker 6:  neutrality fight. Of course, like Obama's chairperson who pushed that through
Speaker 6:  in the end, everyone seems a little excited about Jessica Rosenworcel her
Speaker 6:  vote will be pretty easy to get through, but with GG, there's been this weird
Speaker 6:  fight that's crept up from
Speaker 6:  Murdoch owned businesses kind of, but I don't want to, you know, you can't
Speaker 6:  really say anything specifically, but Lindsey Graham, the wall street journal
Speaker 6:  Fox news, they're all saying that Gigi will work as a censor against
Speaker 6:  Republican speech on law. On, on the broad on airwaves, sorry, I've been
Speaker 6:  saying Republican speech online for years now, and this is migrating to the
Speaker 6:  airwaves now as so, which is essentially
Speaker 6:  Gigi has had some comments about like fairness over the
Speaker 6:  airwaves for a while. But over the last couple of years, she said that there's
Speaker 6:  no way that anything like that could happen again. So there's this weird
Speaker 6:  kind of fight. And I think that's also like explained through the fact that
Speaker 6:  like Newsmax and OAN noted
Speaker 6:  pro-Trump news organizations support her nomination.
Speaker 6:  So it's kind of in this weird moment where we basically know that we're
Speaker 6:  still going to have to too, but it's, there is no hearing for
Speaker 6:  Gigi. We have no idea what's really happening there and it's
Speaker 6:  questioned whether or not Democrats can get anything done really in Biden's
Speaker 6:  first year, first two years.
Speaker 3:  Can you explain why Newsmax and Owen would
Speaker 3:  be supporting GG sound? Because if there's any group that I would
Speaker 3:  assume would say that, you know, center and are being censored and
Speaker 3:  we must stop it, it would be those outlets. So I'm confused.
Speaker 6:  So I think it's interesting to note that like Gigi has been doing this for
Speaker 6:  like 30 years. She is a well beloved
Speaker 6:  person in the telecom community, amongst Republicans and
Speaker 6:  Democrats, every source I ha I talked to is like Gigi rules. She
Speaker 6:  will listen to you. And she has, when she talks about free speech, she
Speaker 6:  really means it and all this kind of stuff. And the people who worked at
Speaker 6:  Newsmax and OAN who offered these op-eds, you know, last week have worked
Speaker 6:  with Gigi and know what she, you know, what she stands for.
Speaker 6:  So they, they know that Gigi will support them, maybe not support,
Speaker 6:  right. But give them the opportunity, right. To continue to work the way
Speaker 6:  that they do. It's the interesting thing where it's coming from more, it
Speaker 6:  was a wall street journal op ed page that, that had the first thing about
Speaker 6:  GG. And then of course, Fox news, and then more conservative
Speaker 6:  Republicans who are raising the question about the censorship thing, which
Speaker 6:  feels kind of like a made up argument because it's not something anyone has
Speaker 6:  really raised against Gigi in the past at
Speaker 6:  all.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. This is my favorite, like mini drama going on
Speaker 1:  right now because Fox news versus Newsmax, if
Speaker 1:  you abstract away the fact that they're both conservative cable networks,
Speaker 1:  where you have as a gigantic monopoly position and an upstart
Speaker 1:  competitor and Gigi is aligned with the competitors and then the
Speaker 1:  gigantic monopolies dislike that. And then the other thing you have,
Speaker 1:  which is like more broadly, you have the cable networks,
Speaker 1:  which have to like run Owen and Newsmax and all those other
Speaker 1:  channels. So they have worked with Gigi on the business side to get access
Speaker 1:  to Comcast and spectrum and whoever else, disclosure,
Speaker 1:  Comcast and investor me, the parent company. I assure you, this has not
Speaker 1:  influenced our coverage at all. So ages ago, Gigi organized a
Speaker 1:  coalition of like independent cable networks to demand
Speaker 1:  access to cable companies and Fox posts that she organized the
Speaker 1:  conservative outlets to oppose when Tribune was trying to buy
Speaker 1:  Sinclair, which was the huge, broad, conservative broadcast network. She
Speaker 1:  organized a concern like small conservative outlets to pose that merger.
Speaker 1:  So just like broadly, she's on the side of big things, shouldn't get bigger.
Speaker 1:  And so all these small networks have worked with her to oppose big things
Speaker 1:  that ain't bigger. So I agree. I think there's that. And then there's also
Speaker 1:  like 18 T in Comcast in variety. Like they spent a ton
Speaker 1:  of lobbying money for a lot, for just across the board,
Speaker 1:  like pick a Senator there's money flowing in from the telcos and
Speaker 1:  Gigi wants to regulate them harder. So like across the board, I think
Speaker 1:  there's just a lot of opposition here. But if you look at the breakdown,
Speaker 1:  Fox news versus OAN comes down to Owen's business is
Speaker 1:  threatened by monopolies, both in broadcasting, in cable,
Speaker 1:  and then eventually for access. And anytime you try to regulate those
Speaker 1:  monopolies, people say it's censorship. And I think this is just hilarious,
Speaker 1:  right? Like you live by at and T is lobbying money. You kind of like you
Speaker 1:  die by these love England. Like Owen runs on direct TV.
Speaker 1:  There's all those stories about how at and T is like funds. OEN T is
Speaker 1:  lobbying. Money is preventing the, the person that Owen wants from,
Speaker 1:  from getting on the STC. I think it's just like utterly fascinating to see
Speaker 1:  that split in inside of conservative media play out in the
Speaker 1:  face of it is a progressive FCC commissioner. And I, I
Speaker 1:  don't know. I just find this. I could talk to us all day. Like it's very,
Speaker 1:  it's a very small beltway politics, but it's, I think its
Speaker 1:  symptoms something much bigger. Do you think she's going to get through McKenna?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I do. I think there's always horse trading done.
Speaker 6:  That's kind of what everyone says on the hill. When it come to
Speaker 6:  nominations, they get voted on the same time that they do another
Speaker 6:  bill or, you know, senators make some deal to get one nomination
Speaker 6:  in for getting like something else. So I think something will break eventually.
Speaker 6:  It just depends on when,
Speaker 1:  But there's like a, there's like a deadline here. Right? If they don't get
Speaker 1:  Rosenworcel in his chair, they don't get sewn in, in time. This two to
Speaker 1:  deadlock persists for quite awhile.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And Rosenworcel would have to pick up her office and leave. They don't
Speaker 6:  vote on to reconfirm her by the end of the year, which would be a one, two
Speaker 6:  would, was Republicans in the majority.
Speaker 6:  So that's what wasting all of this time, as broad as
Speaker 6:  to the kind of intense over there at the house of
Speaker 6:  lawyers,
Speaker 1:  It's like just a bunch of gray suits yelling. No, that's honestly, the sec
Speaker 1:  has been like, I feel like the Trump administration was notable in
Speaker 1:  that. Right? Maybe they never got infrastructure done, but
Speaker 1:  they confirmed a lot of appointments. They confirmed a lot of judges. They
Speaker 1:  moved really fast on this stuff. Why is the Biden administration been so
Speaker 1:  slow?
Speaker 6:  It's a good question. I think it has a lot to do with how the Senate will
Speaker 6:  confirm them. Right? When you have more controversial people like this, the
Speaker 6:  fun thing to note is like, there's like three really progressive people
Speaker 6:  in Biden's cabinet. Right now there is Lena Khan who we've talked about a
Speaker 6:  lot and she had bipartisan support because we've seen this like bipartisan
Speaker 6:  outcry over like tech regulation and like enforcement over monopoly
Speaker 6:  power at the FTC. And then the same thing with Johnathan Cantor, Jonathan
Speaker 6:  Kantor was approved earlier this week to lead the
Speaker 6:  antitrust division at the DOJ. And so there's those two
Speaker 6:  Progressive's right. But when it comes to Telekom and Gigi, it's funny that
Speaker 6:  that's like the one progressive who's having like that much of an issue.
Speaker 6:  And I think it really does come down to write this like huge history
Speaker 6:  of telecom money and things like that. And of course like at the
Speaker 6:  Senate cursing cinema is one of the deciding votes when she
Speaker 6:  gets brought to a house floor, right. To see if she even gets confirmed so
Speaker 6:  that you either need like more Republicans on board or to ensure that these
Speaker 6:  two Democrats mansion cinema will vote to approve her.
Speaker 1:  And I'll do it. Put me in coach.
Speaker 1:  I'll do it. I'll just put me in I'll I'll run the FCC. That'd be, I don't
Speaker 1:  think I'd get better for it, but I'll do it, Joe, if you're listening, you
Speaker 1:  got my number. Yes. He doesn't have enough. He could probably get it last
Speaker 1:  one. Biden's pick somebody to run the FDA and
Speaker 6:  They work at Google.
Speaker 1:  This is a very, it's very funny for a million reasons. But first tell us
Speaker 1:  who this person is.
Speaker 6:  This is Robert Kayla. If I'm assuming, and he's going to run, you know, the
Speaker 6:  FDA that was announced earlier this week, right now, he's like a
Speaker 6:  senior advisor for verily health sciences, but
Speaker 6:  sciences, sorry. And then like Google health, which is kind of
Speaker 6:  interesting. But of course, like it's good to note that the Obama
Speaker 6:  administration, that Joe Biden was a part of had a lot of
Speaker 6:  like tech people and a lot of people who left the Obama administration to
Speaker 6:  go work in tech. There is this like big atmosphere of like tech people
Speaker 6:  in the Obama circle. So we've seen a lot of tech people kind of move
Speaker 6:  into the, you know, the Biden office as well. And so
Speaker 6:  it's kind of interesting to see it. There's been a lot of pushback on having
Speaker 6:  like tech people in the cabinet. So it's interesting that this one kind of
Speaker 6:  like cracked.
Speaker 1:  I just had to say this Google never made the website. Don't hire the person
Speaker 1:  from Google. They're supposed to make a website that was supposed to test.
Speaker 1:  They just never did it. All right. I put it, it was only out here so I can
Speaker 1:  make the website check, but kind of what should we be looking for next we're
Speaker 1:  cruising into Thanksgiving and then holidays. When do you, when should people
Speaker 1:  be on the lookout for this next set of votes around Rosenworcel and around
Speaker 1:  build by better?
Speaker 6:  Ah, man. So bill back better, who knows?
Speaker 6:  We've gotten to this point where it could be tomorrow. It could be a month
Speaker 6:  from now. Honestly, it just depends when this gets said, decided when it
Speaker 6:  comes to Rosenworcel, the Senate never does
Speaker 6:  anything like one at a time, they always have like one day
Speaker 6:  where they decide to take a vote on like literally everything. So I'm sure
Speaker 6:  like she'll get voted around the same time that they end up like funding
Speaker 6:  the government, which is still a thing that they have not done yet. And the
Speaker 6:  government could shut down next month. Again, everyone we
Speaker 6:  are in shambles. I don't know how the system continues to work, but yeah.
Speaker 6:  So hopefully by the end of the year more broadly and then look
Speaker 6:  at it when other big projects like the defense authorization and other big
Speaker 6:  funding bills get pushed through who the end of the year.
Speaker 1:  All right, man, it's always a pleasure to have you on we'll have you back
Speaker 1:  when all this stuff gets passed to figure out where all this money is going,
Speaker 1:  who's going to spend it.
Speaker 6:  Great. Talk to you later, guys.
Speaker 7:  We're all used to shopping around for the best prices on airfare, groceries,
Speaker 7:  gas, basically everything we buy really, but almost none of us do
Speaker 7:  that for our prescriptions. If you're ready to start saving money on your
Speaker 7:  meds, you should check out good RX, good RX lets you compare
Speaker 7:  prices for your prescription at all the pharmacies in your neighborhood,
Speaker 7:  including the big guys like CVS, Rite aid, Walgreens, Kroger,
Speaker 7:  and Walmart. There's no reason to just buy your prescription at whatever
Speaker 7:  pharmacy your doctor picks. Not when using good RX could save you up to
Speaker 7:  80%. Just check their app or site for free and find
Speaker 7:  discounts in a few seconds. So for simple, smart savings on your
Speaker 7:  prescriptions check, good RX go to good
Speaker 7:  rx.com/verge. That is good.
Speaker 7:  rx.com/verge. Good RX
Speaker 7:  is not insurance, but can be used instead of insurance in
Speaker 7:  2020 good RX users saved an average of 79% off
Speaker 7:  retail prices.
Speaker 2:  When it comes to your finances, wouldn't it be nice to have a little extra
Speaker 2:  help, like an intelligent assistant to point out when a free trial is about
Speaker 2:  to end or alert you to suspicious charges, capital
Speaker 2:  one does this and more for its customers. They have
Speaker 2:  teams of engineers building software like a tech company. That means
Speaker 2:  using leading edge tech, like artificial intelligence to make sure their
Speaker 2:  products are the best they can be. And building these machine
Speaker 2:  learning capabilities all on the cloud. Their work is at the forefront
Speaker 2:  of what's possible in banking today. In fact, a lot of capital one's
Speaker 2:  AI and machine learning tech innovations are leading the industry
Speaker 2:  take, you know, as an example, capital one's intelligent assistant helps
Speaker 2:  millions of customers have confidence and control over their financial
Speaker 2:  lives and their apps and products have won awards for offering some of the
Speaker 2:  best real time. Personalized customer experiences.
Speaker 2:  We're in a golden age of machine learning right now. And capital one is on
Speaker 2:  the front lines, leading the charge using human centered design
Speaker 2:  and leading edge tech to serve customers better, learn
Speaker 2:  more@capitalone.com slash tech.
Speaker 1:  Lauren Grosh welcome and very fast.
Speaker 8:  So excited to be back.
Speaker 1:  If you don't know, Lauren was off on book leave, we're excited to read Lawrenceburg
Speaker 1:  when it comes out. We can't plug it yet because it's not out. So we got to
Speaker 1:  wait, but it's been months since we've talked to Lauren and months and she's
Speaker 1:  been on the show. So welcome back. And it's a good day to come back because
Speaker 1:  the space wars have begun.
Speaker 8:  They haven't been done, but they are closer
Speaker 8:  and they are having, we were getting some issues. Yes.
Speaker 1:  All right. So I'm just reading this headline. Russia blows up a satellite
Speaker 1:  comma, creating dangerous debris cloud in space. Is this a James Bond movie?
Speaker 1:  I just want to take both parts of that headline interns.
Speaker 1:  Let's start with Russia blows up the satellite. Why did Russia blow up a
Speaker 1:  satellite?
Speaker 8:  What Russia did is known as an anti satellite test or
Speaker 8:  an ASAP test and what these are
Speaker 8:  our basic political shows of strength to say that,
Speaker 8:  Hey, I have this capability of blowing up a
Speaker 8:  satellite that's in orbit around earth. And it's
Speaker 8:  actually a pretty hard thing to do. Remember that satellites that are, or
Speaker 8:  earth orbit are moving at roughly 17,500
Speaker 8:  miles per hour. And so being able to pinpoint exactly where
Speaker 8:  it's going to be and then send a missile to that. Satellite is a
Speaker 8:  pretty complicated technical
Speaker 8:  capability. And so Russia was basically showing off saying, Hey,
Speaker 8:  look, we took out one of our satellites. We could potentially do that with
Speaker 8:  one of yours. If you, you know, down the line, they, they didn't say
Speaker 8:  that outright, but that is what they are implying by doing this.
Speaker 1:  So they fired myself from earth and hit one of their own satellites in space,
Speaker 1:  which is very complicated. And obviously right, the, the signal is
Speaker 1:  we could potentially do it to yours. Aren't there like rules that say we're
Speaker 1:  not supposed to do that.
Speaker 8:  So that has been a big point of discussion. After this
Speaker 8:  test happen, we do have a treaty it's called the outer space
Speaker 8:  treaty. It's my favorite treaty, basically
Speaker 8:  loose guidelines of how we're supposed to explore space.
Speaker 8:  And you know, it's, we want to explore space peacefully. Don't
Speaker 8:  put nukes in orbit, kind of basic things like that.
Speaker 8:  It's essentially it's written vague on purpose so
Speaker 8:  that we have options when it comes to exploring space. They
Speaker 8:  didn't, they didn't want it to be very restrictive and, and telling exact
Speaker 8:  countries exactly what they could do in orbit. Also there
Speaker 8:  hasn't been a desire to outright ban ASAP tests because you know,
Speaker 8:  the U S did an ASAP test itself back in
Speaker 8:  2008. So I'm sure that discussion will be
Speaker 8:  revived. And I mean, it's already being revived right now that the
Speaker 8:  Russians did this, but yeah, it's, it's not outright banned.
Speaker 8:  We do have guidelines for how we're supposed to behave in
Speaker 8:  space. They're all very much open to interpretation,
Speaker 8:  but it's yeah, there is no, there is no treaty that says, do
Speaker 8:  not perform anti-satellite tests in
Speaker 1:  That seems like a, an oversight, but there's a reason you'd want to
Speaker 1:  do it. Right. I mean, a large chunk of our communications infrastructure
Speaker 1:  runs through space. Like if you were to go to a war, you would
Speaker 1:  probably want to do this.
Speaker 8:  I mean, there are plenty of discussions about what a war in space
Speaker 8:  with look like and not necessarily destroying a
Speaker 8:  satellite with a kinetic missile because of the impact it has,
Speaker 8:  but you know, jamming satellites, you know, taking out a satellite
Speaker 8:  either physically or with software is definitely
Speaker 8:  what I think a future space battle would entail
Speaker 8:  because I think a lot of people don't realize just how reliant we are on
Speaker 8:  our satellite infrastructure. You know, we are a space
Speaker 8:  nation in a way. We, our phones rely on GPS. You know, we
Speaker 8:  take a lot of earth imagery with our satellites.
Speaker 8:  A lot of surveillance satellites are very much necessary for
Speaker 8:  our military apparatus. So yeah, I think
Speaker 8:  taking out satellites in some form would definitely be a
Speaker 8:  way that you would do battle in space.
Speaker 1:  And then the other thing before we get to the debris cloud, which seems like
Speaker 1:  its own complicated problem, I don't know, just for like a
Speaker 1:  while there, it seemed like the United States and Russia for all their other
Speaker 1:  problems were pretty agreeable with space, right? The
Speaker 1:  international space station exists. We needed their rockets to go there.
Speaker 1:  That appears to have changed. Is that me just over reading the fact that
Speaker 1:  they blew up a satellite
Speaker 8:  Very interesting position that we are in, because
Speaker 8:  what seems to be happening is a
Speaker 8:  delineation between the Russian military and rose
Speaker 8:  cosmos the space agency or
Speaker 8:  a space corporation. And what it is is we have a good
Speaker 8:  relationship with Roscosmos. Sometimes it can be a little
Speaker 8:  iffy, but overall we have a great foundation
Speaker 8:  to work with them. They are our biggest partners on the international space
Speaker 8:  station. And so NASA is working with them frequently.
Speaker 8:  The NASA administrator seems to, he indicated
Speaker 8:  that it's possible Roscosmos did not know about this
Speaker 8:  test so that the military did it not
Speaker 8:  knowing that it would potentially jeopardize
Speaker 8:  their cosmonauts on board, the international space station, which we can
Speaker 8:  get into shortly. We haven't had a lot of
Speaker 8:  details and the Russian military put out a very spicy
Speaker 8:  statement after it happened. That was like, oh, the U S
Speaker 8:  knows very well that this was not a danger, that this
Speaker 8:  was not a problem, which is just a wild statement to make, but
Speaker 8:  that is part of the Russia playbook. So it's not necessarily on surprising.
Speaker 1:  Okay. And then I have to ask you this question, I'm just going to tell the
Speaker 1:  audience, I'm going to ask this question and then you need to imagine Lauren's
Speaker 1:  her eyes as hard as she can. We have a space force.
Speaker 1:  There's patches, there's uniforms, they
Speaker 1:  got uniforms are called guardians. The whole situation is this
Speaker 1:  what our space force is designed to do. Okay. Just
Speaker 1:  checking.
Speaker 8:  I mean, okay. There is, we have something called the us
Speaker 8:  space command and that is responsible for
Speaker 8:  overseeing the tracking of debris and objects in
Speaker 8:  space. And so it was actually the responsibility of US-based command
Speaker 8:  to track the objects that were created from
Speaker 8:  this ASAP test, which they said it was about
Speaker 8:  1500 trackable objects and then
Speaker 8:  thousands of small objects that we cannot track. And that's the
Speaker 8:  scary part, right? Because we have great tracking capability, but we just
Speaker 8:  can't see everything, especially if it's small. So that's, what's so
Speaker 8:  scary about it. The space force is mostly
Speaker 8:  tasked with operating and deploying those
Speaker 8:  satellites that we talked about. They oversee our
Speaker 8:  space assets in orbit. There has been discussion
Speaker 8:  about, you know, sending people into space for space for us, but
Speaker 8:  for now,
Speaker 1:  Could you hear the eye roll? Because I saw the,
Speaker 8:  Well, you have to understand is the U S military has had
Speaker 8:  a large stake in space and satellites and the
Speaker 8:  satellite infrastructure for a very long time. And what space force has
Speaker 8:  done is essentially put all those people that operate those
Speaker 8:  assets into their own branch or
Speaker 8:  yeah. And so it's really a bureaucratic and boring
Speaker 8:  change, but it did get a lot of attention because you know, it was
Speaker 8:  Trump's pet project and it has a very
Speaker 8:  provocative name. If you will,
Speaker 1:  Outer space treaty space for us, it's a good name. Okay. Let's talk about
Speaker 1:  the debris clouds. So they blew out the satellite. You said, there's stuff.
Speaker 1:  We could track 1500 things. We tracked stuff. We can't track. It seems like
Speaker 1:  the astronauts and the ISS didn't know this was going to happen. How did
Speaker 1:  this all play out?
Speaker 8:  Let me walk you through my Monday, because for us,
Speaker 8:  it was very crazy. So we started the day
Speaker 8:  with reports that there had been this ASAP test from Russia.
Speaker 8:  Wasn't confirmed the state department hadn't confirmed it yet. No one
Speaker 8:  from the U S was confirming it yet. And then at the same time, we
Speaker 8:  had these other reports that the astronauts on board, the
Speaker 8:  international space station had to shelter in place that morning
Speaker 8:  because of a D a cloud of debris that kept passing by the space station
Speaker 8:  every 90 minutes, which is how long it takes the space station to
Speaker 8:  orbit the earth. And so obviously we try, we put two
Speaker 8:  and two together. Okay. It seems like this Faiza test
Speaker 8:  probably created this cloud of debris that caused the
Speaker 8:  astronauts to go into the safety mode. But we didn't know that for
Speaker 8:  sure. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  My question is like, you don't, you don't know that for sure. But like, do
Speaker 3:  you, you know, you just don't want to say it or is it like, actually there's
Speaker 3:  like clouds of debris often enough, or like this could be just a wacky
Speaker 3:  coinkydink.
Speaker 8:  Well, when it comes to space journalism, I
Speaker 8:  never want to assume
Speaker 3:  I'm an author now, Dieter, the standards are higher. She does, she doesn't
Speaker 3:  want a space force, the issue
Speaker 8:  I assume. And obviously in our minds it did make
Speaker 8:  sense. And then what helps was we have, I have this great
Speaker 8:  source, a satellite tracker named Jonathan McDowell. He's like the
Speaker 8:  go-to guy when it comes to tracking debris
Speaker 8:  or satellites of any kind in orbit. And so he came online and then
Speaker 8:  he did all of these calculations and he basically showed that
Speaker 8:  the suspected satellite that we thought Russia had
Speaker 8:  blown up tracked with the ISS, it was
Speaker 8:  coming like it cross paths with the ISS about the
Speaker 8:  same time, every like the mission control kept telling
Speaker 8:  the astronauts of debris cloud was passing. So at that point it was
Speaker 8:  like, okay, this is absolutely happening because of the A's
Speaker 8:  test, but we still needed, you know, the U S to confirm that we
Speaker 8:  needed NASA to confirm that and getting those statements was actually pretty
Speaker 8:  difficult throughout the day. And I get it. It's a matter of national security.
Speaker 8:  It has a big geopolitical ramifications. So I
Speaker 8:  understood why it took them a while, but it was kind of frustrating because
Speaker 8:  we knew that this was a direct correlation, but we couldn't say for
Speaker 8:  sure.
Speaker 3:  So when you say passing by, was it close? Was it dangerously
Speaker 3:  close? Was it NASA being overcautious?
Speaker 8:  As I understand it, the satellite that they shot down was
Speaker 8:  about roughly a hundred kilometers. I want to say above the international
Speaker 8:  space station. But what happens when you do these ASAP tests
Speaker 8:  is like I said, it creates these thousands of pieces of debris and they don't
Speaker 8:  just stay in one spot, right? It's an explosive event. So
Speaker 8:  they go to higher altitudes, they go to lower
Speaker 8:  altitudes. They span like miles
Speaker 8:  along the orbital track of where the original
Speaker 8:  satellite was. So the way I described as a, somebody I thought was a pretty
Speaker 8:  good analogy was, imagine if you crash into a
Speaker 8:  car and it created all these car pieces, but those
Speaker 8:  pieces continued to drive down the highway
Speaker 8:  and you couldn't move them. They were just speeding along and you couldn't
Speaker 8:  stop them or maneuver it. And you just have to maneuver around them forever
Speaker 8:  because they're going to be, they're going to stay on the highway for years
Speaker 3:  So that they're not going to decay and fall into orbit and burn up. It's
Speaker 3:  going to be a long time.
Speaker 8:  Well, but it takes years for that to happen for our, our
Speaker 8:  atmosphere and gravity to pull them down. So what you have
Speaker 8:  this situation where they're going to be kind of raining down,
Speaker 8:  crossing paths with the international space station for years to come. So
Speaker 8:  it's, it's a significant problem that I'm pretty sure NASA
Speaker 8:  is going to have to be monitoring for a very long time.
Speaker 3:  Now you mentioned space command and that they could track the larger objects,
Speaker 3:  but the smaller objects for the scarier ones. So if we've got smaller objects
Speaker 3:  that can't be tracked around for a long time, I mean,
Speaker 3:  you know, I think everyone knows like the nightmare scenario is like, there's
Speaker 3:  so much space junk up there. Anything that goes into orbit, just get smashed
Speaker 3:  to bits by random space junk. Like, is this like
Speaker 3:  the first step towards that path of like, well, I guess we don't get to put
Speaker 3:  stuff in order to anymore, like how, how nerve wracked are. Do people
Speaker 3:  seem about the fact that there's a bunch of, you know, new space junk. They
Speaker 3:  can't track,
Speaker 8:  Oh, everyone, everyone in the space community is outraged over it. They've
Speaker 8:  all condemned it, you know, and there's some debate over
Speaker 8:  whether or not that exact scenario you painted will happen.
Speaker 8:  It may not be this thing where if you, if you launch into orbit, something's
Speaker 8:  going to immediately like smack you in your face. You know, it's, it's
Speaker 8:  more of, there is so much congestion up there that
Speaker 8:  you don't necessarily have a clear path, or you don't
Speaker 8:  necessarily know where all this stuff is. That's, that's another
Speaker 8:  big point of concern is we have all these tracking devices to
Speaker 8:  determine where space junk is, but we have differences
Speaker 8:  of opinion over where those things are. And those differences of opinion
Speaker 8:  can be a few miles in, you know, not knowing where they are. So
Speaker 8:  you could have one satellite and the us military
Speaker 8:  will say, oh, it's here. And then you have Leo labs, which
Speaker 8:  is a private space company tracker. And they say, actually, we see it, you
Speaker 8:  know, two miles this way. And so when you have that uncertainty factor
Speaker 8:  combined with the fact that it's getting more congested, then
Speaker 8:  you don't necessarily know if you launching your
Speaker 8:  satellite is going to be safe. If, if you don't know exactly where
Speaker 8:  everything is and everything's kind of all, you know, crowding that
Speaker 8:  environment just becomes harder to actually put things into orbit.
Speaker 8:  So it's less of a scenario where you have like gravity or things are
Speaker 8:  just constantly like destroying all of your, your
Speaker 8:  infrastructure. It's more of just, is it safe to put my satellite
Speaker 8:  in orbit? That question becomes more and more of a concern.
Speaker 1:  What about Russia? I mean, it, Russia also operates the international space
Speaker 1:  station. They've got cosmonauts. They're like, don't, shouldn't this bother
Speaker 1:  them.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. That was the whole, that's the irony of the
Speaker 8:  situation. I mean, when we found out that they had done this and that they
Speaker 8:  had potentially jeopardize the safety, they have there's two cosmonauts on
Speaker 8:  the international space station right now. So it was definitely
Speaker 8:  very strange. But if you look at the
Speaker 8:  history of the Russian space program, you know, they, they were
Speaker 8:  never that concerned about putting their cosmonauts in
Speaker 8:  harm's way. So I guess it's not
Speaker 8:  surprising, but it does feel a bit
Speaker 8:  counterintuitive,
Speaker 8:  but then you have Ross cosmos that comes out and they say, you know, safety
Speaker 8:  is our number one priority. So like I said, it is possible
Speaker 8:  that there was a miscommunication between the space
Speaker 8:  program and the military side of things.
Speaker 8:  But it does seem very strange that they would potentially
Speaker 8:  cause them nuts at risk.
Speaker 1:  Let's talk about some other space stuff. NASA announced a bunch of
Speaker 1:  changes to the lunar program. A delay
Speaker 1:  blue origin is mad as usual. It seems to be their permanent state
Speaker 1:  of being what what's going on with the moon. Is it still there?
Speaker 1:  Is it the tide still being driven by it as well? I like having you on the
Speaker 1:  show because you get to toss out these questions like a blood moon
Speaker 1:  soon. Right? Is moon cool? What's up with the moon?
Speaker 8:  Yeah. There's a lunar eclipse coming up. Wait witnesses
Speaker 8:  there,
Speaker 1:  My feet
Speaker 8:  Tomorrow. Okay. So it'll happen by the time this aired. So hopefully you
Speaker 8:  went out last night and looked at. Yeah. So what
Speaker 8:  I think DLI is referring to is the fact that NASA wants to send
Speaker 8:  people back to the moon with its Artimus program.
Speaker 8:  And they recently announced that their ambitious
Speaker 8:  target date, which was 20, 24, is not going to happen as
Speaker 8:  we all suspected. And they've moved the target date
Speaker 8:  to 20, 25 instead, which doesn't seem
Speaker 8:  nearly, it doesn't seem any more,
Speaker 8:  but you know, what can you do? It's good to have a bold deadline,
Speaker 8:  right?
Speaker 8:  You have your aspirational deadline, and then you have your real deadline.
Speaker 8:  And so
Speaker 1:  What do you think the real deadline is? Oh,
Speaker 8:  Gosh, we've all placed our bets on this, but I will not reveal my cards on
Speaker 8:  this. Cause I have my internal date.
Speaker 1:  I bet you it's the same year that they put a touch screen on the Mac. They
Speaker 1:  see, oh no, I hate it. And then blue origin is
Speaker 1:  suing the government because they didn't get the contract to build the slander.
Speaker 1:  Right.
Speaker 8:  Actually that lawsuit has now come to an end. The
Speaker 8:  judge overseeing the case, ruled against them.
Speaker 8:  And so now their litigation has ended. And actually
Speaker 8:  the judge just released his opinion, which was very
Speaker 8:  spicy and very in the weeds. And we can definitely get
Speaker 8:  into it if you want. Essentially,
Speaker 8:  Jeff Bezos came out and said that they were going to accept the ruling.
Speaker 8:  And so it sounds like they won't be protesting or
Speaker 8:  appealing the results anymore. And so now space
Speaker 8:  X is the sole provider for NASA's
Speaker 8:  human lunar Lander. And they have a long road ahead of them, but
Speaker 8:  I am very eager to see how,
Speaker 1:  And then Ilan has just been like wild and on Twitter and all kinds of ways
Speaker 1:  lately. And he got it, but he got to dunk on Bezos, which is like
Speaker 1:  all he cares about in the world,
Speaker 8:  But you can have me on every verge cast and we could always have somebody,
Speaker 8:  it didn't, he
Speaker 1:  Just do a live stream where he said some, some strange things.
Speaker 8:  Oh yeah. He gave an update on Starship, which is the
Speaker 8:  next generation vehicle that they're building is the same one that they are
Speaker 8:  building for NASA to take humans to the surface of the moon. And he just
Speaker 8:  gave an overview of, you know, its capabilities, what they hope to use it
Speaker 8:  for. And he made a new prediction
Speaker 8:  that it will fly to orbit for the first time in
Speaker 8:  January, maybe February. He doesn't know if it'll work
Speaker 8:  the first time, which to be fair. That's a, that's a good
Speaker 8:  prediction. Well, look, it's a, it's a, it's a very
Speaker 8:  ambitious vehicle and there's always gonna be
Speaker 8:  some, you know, explosions when you do something for the first time
Speaker 8:  and that's, that's basics the strategy. They kind of, they explode,
Speaker 8:  rebuild and do it again. You know? So it's, it's definitely, it's been
Speaker 8:  working out for them in terms of actually getting to
Speaker 8:  reliable flight hardware.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Other space X news, right. They, they launched
Speaker 1:  four astronauts to the space station and brought them back, which is now
Speaker 1:  becoming a little bit of a, like a regular occurrence. It was
Speaker 1:  just like a big deal.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. I mean, it was just last year that we were all kind of like,
Speaker 8:  you know, watching an eager anticipation as
Speaker 8:  they launched their first two astronauts. And now since then they've had
Speaker 8:  five human space flight missions for, for
Speaker 8:  NASA and one that sent, you know, four private crew members
Speaker 8:  into orbit for three days. And I think it's, I was actually just thinking
Speaker 8:  of this before I came on. And I think it's good when these things come routine
Speaker 8:  become routine. It's, you know, a lot of companies get upset
Speaker 8:  after a while cause I'll stop covering their launches. And I'm
Speaker 8:  thinking it's good when I'm not covering your loss. I am
Speaker 8:  covering it. That means that something bad happened, you know? So it's good
Speaker 8:  when the stuff becomes boring because it means that we're doing it safely
Speaker 8:  and routinely. That's great.
Speaker 1:  And then lastly, I kinda was just on, we were talking a little bit about
Speaker 1:  Starlink Starlink has a new dish.
Speaker 1:  It's like a, it's like a little rectangle guy. I want you to
Speaker 8:  Get, I think it looks
Speaker 1:  Cool. So I'm the person with the Starling dish. I pay, I
Speaker 1:  pay for the service, the old one. It's what, 22 inches. This
Speaker 1:  one's like little, they said it's cheaper to make. They did not lower the
Speaker 1:  price.
Speaker 1:  Like a graded. Like when I say Starlink is a broadband company,
Speaker 1:  only broadband companies are like, we made the thing cheaper to make,
Speaker 1:  but we're going to keep charging you the same money. That is a very broadband
Speaker 1:  company attitude. The only real difference besides the
Speaker 1:  smaller size cheaper to make the up the wifi specs,
Speaker 1:  they still haven't opened the coverage areas. It still seems
Speaker 1:  delayed. Starlink space, X does not have a PR department.
Speaker 1:  We can't even ask. It's like hard to even ask questions about what's going
Speaker 1:  on.
Speaker 8:  Well, I have a PR department, they just don't respond to me.
Speaker 8:  And I'm curious if anyone has actually received this yet, because as I
Speaker 8:  understand it, they're very backlogged when it comes to new orders
Speaker 8:  because of the chip shortage. And then also, I guess we did a, we did a
Speaker 8:  story that if you change your address at all in the map
Speaker 8:  tool, it sends you to the back of the line. So
Speaker 3:  This is, this is the most amazing thing. So they have a tool where you can
Speaker 3:  like say what your service area is. And people were going to go
Speaker 3:  play with the map. I think there was like an email that you're supposed to
Speaker 3:  go like, look at it or something. And so people, the quotas, I moved
Speaker 3:  my location from my barn to my house, which is 13 feet. And now
Speaker 3:  my order has been moved back to late 20, 22. I was just like, don't
Speaker 3:  mess around with maps. You never know what will happen.
Speaker 1:  They've launched a lot more satellites since I did the review. So
Speaker 1:  I'm going to try it again. Like I said, I have the dish I've been paying
Speaker 1:  for it, but the key problem with startling is
Speaker 1:  even one utility pole in the, in your line of sight. And that whole arc
Speaker 1:  will interrupt your service and they it's just, they keep kind of just like
Speaker 1:  quietly not mentioning that.
Speaker 8:  I'm sure you got a lot of you did the review. Well,
Speaker 8:  yeah, I'm sure you get a lot of feedback on it. Can
Speaker 8:  I ask why you didn't put it on the roof?
Speaker 1:  Oh, on my house, she'll put it on a roof of my house. I'd have to go a hundred
Speaker 1:  feet in the air to clear the trees. So when I did drive
Speaker 1:  down, like, you know, the cells are pretty big. The honeycomb cells of service
Speaker 1:  are pretty big. So like just a little ways down the road,
Speaker 1:  there's a big overlook where it's totally clear. And I spent about a day
Speaker 1:  with it out there and the results were the same. The point I was trying to
Speaker 1:  make an interview was like, even this much. And even this little bit
Speaker 1:  at the sky is totally clear, but you've got like eight trees in the way.
Speaker 1:  You're basically looking into graded service. And so to get in my house to
Speaker 1:  get up over those trees, I'd have to put up a hundred foot pole.
Speaker 1:  Yeah.
Speaker 8:  I guess it would be good for like somebody in the desert or, you know, and
Speaker 8:  out and out in a very non wooded area.
Speaker 1:  Honestly, one of the most wholesome places on the entire, in this
Speaker 1:  entire subreddit is mad at me, but that's fine. But one of the most
Speaker 1:  wholesome places in the entire internet is the Starling subreddit, where
Speaker 1:  they're all just talking about how excited they are and like comparing their
Speaker 1:  test results and sharing. They're absolutely
Speaker 1:  bonkers installs, right? Like
Speaker 1:  just bonkers. Like somebody is like, I didn't want to wait for this poll
Speaker 1:  to come in. So I, I built a tower out of two by fours.
Speaker 1:  It's 60 feet in the air. Do you guys think this is good? And everyone's like,
Speaker 1:  you did such a good job. And it's like, it's all crazy. Like,
Speaker 1:  there's a lot of people being like, just cut down the trees. Like there's
Speaker 1:  like, there's a characters in the subreddit, you know? Like there's the
Speaker 1:  people who are like, just pay the money. Like it's worth it to spend
Speaker 1:  $40,000 on a utility pole at your house. And then there's the guys who are
Speaker 1:  like, just get a chainsaw, dude. It's worth it. And it's
Speaker 1:  like, all of this, it is legitimately just go to the Starling
Speaker 1:  subreddit and scroll it for awhile. Like there's hardcore nerds doing
Speaker 1:  satellite tracking. Like every time Starlink launches, new satellites,
Speaker 1:  they track when they come online, they measure the speeds and the latency.
Speaker 1:  And then there's like the chainsaw guys. And like, it's just like,
Speaker 1:  I read it consistently on Reddit. Cause it is just like the happiest little
Speaker 1:  community of nerds because Starling doesn't help them.
Speaker 8:  Right. It'd be really
Speaker 1:  Rough. So they've just built their own little community of support. I
Speaker 1:  know they're all mad at me, but I'm just telling I'm expressing to them.
Speaker 1:  I'm meeting your hatred with nothing but love because I love you
Speaker 8:  Put in your order for the new
Speaker 1:  It can't there's no, there's no option to upgrade your dish.
Speaker 8:  Oh, because you already bought yours. Cause
Speaker 1:  I already have one.
Speaker 8:  Oh, interesting. Okay. Well, I would, I would have loved to
Speaker 8:  see like the, the review part two where
Speaker 1:  I kept the new dish. If someone wants to come to my house and put up a hundred
Speaker 1:  foot pole, the doors open, it's just
Speaker 1:  also, you know, the cable, the other big improvement on the new dish is
Speaker 1:  that the cable detaches from the dish. So the one I have, the cable is
Speaker 1:  permanently attached to it. I see. So even if I did put up the a hundred
Speaker 1:  foot pole, I'd have to take a bunch of cable
Speaker 1:  with me. And then a route that brought that from the dish to the house instead
Speaker 1:  of the way that you'd normally do it. So they did make that big improvement
Speaker 3:  Looking at what are the installs of the new dish, which
Speaker 3:  apparently it's called squishy square pants. Oh good. This
Speaker 3:  predator, which is amazing and
Speaker 1:  Really startling subreddit.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. It's, it's down to like putting calipers on every single part
Speaker 3:  of the cable that you can now unplug, like to show you
Speaker 3:  exactly like down to the millimeter, how wide the different pieces of it
Speaker 3:  are like the plug itself.
Speaker 1:  So you can route it through your
Speaker 3:  House. You can route it to your house and you can like figure out, you know,
Speaker 3:  if you would need to make any kind of Jager or whatever, to make sure it,
Speaker 3:  you know, stays for you, plug it in.
Speaker 1:  I'm telling you it's the most wholesome places. Great. It's I just,
Speaker 1:  I promise you like it is just bros, helping bros all day long in
Speaker 1:  every which way that you can think about it. That's great.
Speaker 1:  Well, it's good to have you back. We've missed you. There's an always an
Speaker 1:  endless flood of space in the us. We'll have you back soon. Thanks for coming
Speaker 1:  on.
Speaker 8:  And every day it's something's popping off. So I'm sure I'll be back pretty
Speaker 8:  soon.
Speaker 9:  This is paid content presented by Volvo cars. If you've never driven a
Speaker 9:  fully electric vehicle, like the Volvo XC 40 recharge before you might
Speaker 9:  be wondering, what's it like? So we developed a course for electric
Speaker 9:  vehicle first-timers they had a lot of questions.
Speaker 10:  Ah, well I understand you're all here because somehow you've never driven
Speaker 10:  a fully electric car before. Don't worry. You must have questions, but I'm
Speaker 10:  here to answer them. Yes.
Speaker 9:  You in the front, does it have to be plugged in to drive?
Speaker 10:  What, how, how would that? No, no, no. Just plug it in when you get home
Speaker 10:  and charge it up overnight, like you charge your phone for example.
Speaker 10:  Okay. So who's ready. Take a look at Volvo XC 40
Speaker 10:  recharge.
Speaker 11:  What happens when there's traffic?
Speaker 10:  The XC 40 recharge has regenerative braking. What's that?
Speaker 10:  Okay. Think of it like this. You're going to be charging your car when you're
Speaker 10:  stuck in traffic. So traffic becomes something you look forward to because
Speaker 10:  it's charging your car and it's not just the engine that's helping the environment.
Speaker 10:  No, no, no, no. There's more. This carpet is made from a hundred percent
Speaker 10:  recycled pet water bottles. So it's not just premium. It's not just
Speaker 10:  luxurious. It's made with a better world in mind. Oh. And Google is
Speaker 10:  built into the  recharge. So Google maps is
Speaker 10:  always with you even if, and when you forget your phone,
Speaker 9:  I get ready for the next chapter in driving with Volvo's pure electric
Speaker 9:  recharge. The future starts now learn
Speaker 9:  more@volvocars.com slash us
Speaker 9:  support for this episode comes from single store, the single database for
Speaker 9:  all data intensive applications. Why make the switch scaling
Speaker 9:  modern? SAS is already hard. It's even harder when you're using databases
Speaker 9:  that were built back when all your friends had pet rocks and the most stressful
Speaker 9:  part of your day was connecting to the dial up modem. Single store is
Speaker 9:  built for the smart SAS generation and all the data intensive applications
Speaker 9:  that come with it. The single store cloud powers, the new wave of SAS
Speaker 9:  technologies, displacing legacy providers with insights, for apps, effortless
Speaker 9:  operation of models at scale and easy shifts to the cloud,
Speaker 9:  introduce simplicity and ease to your data structure and watch what happens
Speaker 9:  to your speed scale and SQL. Find out why industry
Speaker 9:  leaders trust a single store to modernize their data platforms. Learn how
Speaker 9:  single store can help
Speaker 9:  you@singlestoredotcomslashvergecastthatsinglestore.com
Speaker 9:  slash Vergecast.
Speaker 1:  Alex Cranz hello. You've returned to us, has a gun
Speaker 11:  In the lake. I'm here. I'm ready to record.
Speaker 1:  So big story this week. This was like the week before Thanksgiving.
Speaker 1:  It's not like a flood of news. Like black Friday is coming. Like the new
Speaker 1:  stuff is like kinda over, right? Like it's all holiday, like ship the stuff
Speaker 1:  out mode for all the companies. But apple starts the week with a bang
Speaker 1:  and they announced it kind of out of the blue, we're going to start letting
Speaker 1:  people prepare their own I-phones are going to sell parts. And soon we're
Speaker 1:  going to let you repair your M one. Max. It's interesting that
Speaker 1:  it's like a weird line. Alex, tell us what's going on there. What was this
Speaker 1:  announcement?
Speaker 11:  Yeah. So they, they announced that they're gonna sell you little
Speaker 11:  kits that we don't know how much those kits will cost or what
Speaker 11:  will be in the kits that you can take and then repair your devices. And
Speaker 11:  they're going to make all of the instruction manuals available online. So
Speaker 11:  it's like really good extensively, unless you're I fix it. In
Speaker 11:  which case it might not be great for your business model.
Speaker 3:  They did a reaction video, which I watched and yeah, they're, they're, they're
Speaker 3:  gung ho. Kyle's like, yep. Bring it on. I love competition. It's like all
Speaker 3:  I've ever wanted, they're like welcome, welcome IBM or whatever. But
Speaker 3:  they actually made a really good point, which is, you said, Alex, you know,
Speaker 3:  it'll cost. I'm sure it will be a lot, but the fact that there's going to
Speaker 3:  be the parts plus the manuals. So instead of trying
Speaker 3:  to reverse engineer, all of the procedures, the, that the fact that apple
Speaker 3:  is publishing repair manuals means that I fix it. We'll be able to like
Speaker 3:  get a jumpstart on like creating proper procedures for their open source
Speaker 3:  version of repair manuals. And instead of just like intuiting, what they
Speaker 3:  think is the right way to do it. And like guessing based on their tear
Speaker 3:  downs, they'll actually see what like the official procedure is. And then
Speaker 3:  they can base their version of that procedure if they, you know, get different
Speaker 3:  parts or whatever off of that. And then the third key part is the
Speaker 3:  software, like the configuration software so that you don't have to replace
Speaker 3:  like ridiculous, tiny micro solder chips. If you want
Speaker 3:  face ID or true tone or whatever, to continue to work,
Speaker 11:  There's like something to be optimistic about. But for me, it's hard to
Speaker 11:  be super excited until we know what it is like, are they going to be sending
Speaker 11:  you the screwdrivers with the very, the proprietary screw bits
Speaker 11:  or you're going to have to go still buy those somewhere else? Are they going
Speaker 11:  to sell you a heat gun? So you can crack open your iPhone
Speaker 11:  13, which currently requires heat to like break the S the
Speaker 11:  water proof seals. Like, there's just a lot of stuff we don't
Speaker 11:  know. So it's like, this seems really, really cool. And I think that, I
Speaker 11:  think you're bang on, like, it's the instruction manuals here. That's really
Speaker 11:  the successful part of this. And this is really the exciting part of it
Speaker 11:  is like the actual kits. I think there's just too many things up in the
Speaker 11:  air for us to be like, anything but optimistic about them.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I will say this, the steps here are first, you have to
Speaker 1:  review the online repair manual. Like, I just love the idea that Apple's
Speaker 1:  going to be like, are you sure? Like, look at how hard it is and you
Speaker 1:  click through that. And then you place an order. Apple says they will offer
Speaker 1:  more than 200 individual parts and tools. So
Speaker 1:  whether or not the Johnny ive heat gun is coming, you
Speaker 1:  never know fingers crossed, but it does seem like a Pental lobe. Screwdriver
Speaker 1:  is coming like the word tools. Like it's, you know,
Speaker 1:  they're going to make a hammer and a wrench and a screwdriver. So we'll see
Speaker 1:  what that means. But 200 individual parts and tools it's very often 12 and
Speaker 1:  13 currently, which are not like repairable phones.
Speaker 1:  No, not really. They are held together with glue and weird screws in
Speaker 1:  lots of ways. So it's interesting that they walk this back. I would say this
Speaker 1:  was met with like uniform excitement, right? Cause
Speaker 1:  even if all you're doing is you click through the thing, you order the parts
Speaker 1:  and then you go to a service provider who's good at this massive
Speaker 1:  win, right? Like I think this is like right now, if you go to get
Speaker 1:  your iPhone screen repaired, you have no idea. If you're getting an OEM
Speaker 1:  screen, you have no idea if face ID is going to work
Speaker 1:  anymore. Like there are lots of people who are good at taking the screens
Speaker 1:  off life. They've not had access to parts or been able to do this in a particularly
Speaker 1:  official way, or been able to preserve your warranty.
Speaker 3:  And in fact, this is a better win. Even if you live in a world where like
Speaker 3:  you think, well, go to one of the official independent repair shops that
Speaker 3:  are like blessed by apple because the forms and the NDAs and the
Speaker 3:  agreements you have to sign to become, one of those shops are actually relatively
Speaker 3:  onerous. And so even if all apple has done here is like change the
Speaker 3:  change that program for repair shops and just like made the website available
Speaker 3:  to the public, getting rid of those agreements and forms. So that,
Speaker 3:  like you said, you know, you could like go and buy the part and take it to
Speaker 3:  somebody else is a big one.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. And I don't think apple can NDA you out of like you, when the order,
Speaker 1:  the thing, they might be able to make you click a box and say, you have to
Speaker 1:  do it yourself. But like, we're not in the panopticon metaverse
Speaker 1:  yet Tim cook,
Speaker 1:  someone else can use that screwdriver. And you will never know. I
Speaker 3:  Don't know if you read the iTunes terms of service lately.
Speaker 1:  So that's all good. And I think universal praise and then kind of the
Speaker 1:  conversation immediately turned to, well, why would apple do this? And the
Speaker 1:  first cut was to satisfy regulators. And
Speaker 1:  this will mean nothing, which all deference to our friend, John Gruber is
Speaker 1:  kind of his take. You can go read and daring fireball. I would just argue
Speaker 1:  like, there's already a massive market for iPhone repair. Like you're not
Speaker 1:  inventing a market. You're just, legitimising an already huge market.
Speaker 1:  So I think this is going to get, take up because you can already, we don't
Speaker 1:  have to invent a demand. We don't have to invent a consumer who might want
Speaker 1:  this. They already exist. They're already being served. Now. They just have
Speaker 1:  better parts. Cool. But then there's like something else going on here, like
Speaker 1:  a shareholder lawsuit that might've actually pushed
Speaker 1:  apple. Yeah.
Speaker 11:  The, the shareholder that it was an, an activist
Speaker 11:  shareholders from the mutual fund green
Speaker 11:  century who has love and mutual funds. And
Speaker 11:  they had back in September, filed with the
Speaker 11:  sec saying, Hey, apple needs to serious we're we're
Speaker 11:  shareholders. And we as shareholders, demand that apple think
Speaker 11:  long and hard about its right to repair stance and change
Speaker 11:  things. And apparently this past Wednesday was
Speaker 11:  supposed to be the deadline for apple Blake do something. And
Speaker 11:  so apple did this and those shareholders were like, well,
Speaker 11:  okay, I guess we're withdrawing this because they did something. And they
Speaker 11:  still have to like, look at it. They said, it's not like off the table,
Speaker 11:  but, but yeah, it seemed, they are very much taking credit for
Speaker 11:  this move.
Speaker 1:  So what's interesting is they aren't taking credit. I mean, we have a story,
Speaker 1:  Maddie stone art or science editor read it. So apple told us on the
Speaker 1:  record, back on policy, coming through apple says the program has been in
Speaker 1:  development for well over a year, describing it as the next step in
Speaker 1:  increasing access to apple, genuine parts, tools and manuals, they would
Speaker 1:  not say whether the announcement is influenced by the shareholder lawsuit.
Speaker 11:  They would not say that people
Speaker 1:  Would not say in the shareholders, like the timing is no
Speaker 1:  coincidence. So it's not like a settlement, right. Where the
Speaker 1:  shareholders sued and apple said, we'll do this. And the shareholders agreed
Speaker 1:  to back off. Maybe it was. And they're all just
Speaker 1:  like agreed to not talk about it. Right. It's like the end of back to the
Speaker 1:  future where you're trying to connect the two things and like, oh, they're
Speaker 1:  so close. We're not quite connecting.
Speaker 11:  I think what was interesting with this was initially apple was like,
Speaker 11:  no, leave us alone. You're you're trying to change our business. And that's
Speaker 11:  outside the realm of shareholders. But then the sec had
Speaker 11:  issued new guidance between the filing. And
Speaker 11:  now that said, actually, we're going to carve it out. And
Speaker 11:  shareholders can protest. If it's something to do that res if it
Speaker 11:  shareholders can protest, if it raises significant social
Speaker 11:  policy issues, which theoretically the right to
Speaker 11:  repair factors into.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. So apple had asked CSCC, Hey, we've got a holders thing. Can we just
Speaker 3:  like, don't do anything about this. We got to like study it. And we got to
Speaker 3:  blah, blah, blah. And it seems like the way it usually goes is the STC is
Speaker 3:  like, okay, we'll like, go have fun. Well, we'll talk later.
Speaker 3:  But, but as Alex was saying, they issued new guidance saying that
Speaker 3:  like, if it's like, God, like societal impact, we're not gonna,
Speaker 3:  like, we're not going to just let you go have fun. Like, we're actually are,
Speaker 3:  are going to look into it when investors come to us. And so apple, like two
Speaker 3:  days before the deadline, when like this investor group, the mutual fund
Speaker 3:  was going to, like, it was going to happen. They're like, just kidding. We're
Speaker 3:  you can repair stuff. Now
Speaker 1:  I will say, and maybe it has been involved in it for over a year for something
Speaker 1:  that's been in development for over a year. Not a lot of information
Speaker 1:  on how it will work. Yeah. None like at the
Speaker 1:  end of the day, what we have from apple is
Speaker 1:  1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10
Speaker 1:  paragraphs, and a couple of cartoons.
Speaker 3:  Well, all of their copywriters are busy right now, writing the new
Speaker 3:  policy for an app payment links or links to
Speaker 3:  things because that deadline is coming very fast and that they, that appeal
Speaker 3:  is still like up in the air. So like they can't, they can't do both at the
Speaker 3:  same time. Obviously to me, what this is, is like
Speaker 3:  regulatory pressure can work. Even if there's not a law
Speaker 3:  passed or an action taken. Yeah. Like the, the overall
Speaker 3:  environment of legislatures and like regulatory bodies
Speaker 3:  looking at tech companies will spur them to action
Speaker 3:  sometimes in order to like fend off future action. But it
Speaker 3:  does stop.
Speaker 1:  This is the program that apple designed, right? Right. That's a win for
Speaker 1:  apple. This is their program. They have decided that it's the iPhone 12 and
Speaker 1:  13, they're picking the heat, guns and screwdrivers are
Speaker 1:  going to sell or whatever it is. They're deciding it's only M one
Speaker 1:  max. Right? They've, they've chosen. And by the way, the
Speaker 1:  iPhone 12 and 13, the newest I-phones. So if you think
Speaker 1:  about your batteries slowing down your phone, it's getting old, your phone's
Speaker 1:  starting to throttle itself. Well, that's not the iPhone 12 and 13 yet. And
Speaker 1:  by the way, apple, Tim cook himself on investor calls has
Speaker 1:  said, when they rolled out the battery replacement program, their upgrades
Speaker 1:  went down because people realize that could change their batteries over
Speaker 1:  and their phones would perform fast again. And I mean, remember, this was
Speaker 1:  a scandal. People believed in apple denied
Speaker 1:  for years, that iPhones automatically started slowing down. After two years
Speaker 1:  to force you to upgrade apple maintained. Nope. That's just your
Speaker 1:  battery getting older. And in order to prevent your phone from shutting off,
Speaker 1:  because it can't provide the voltage, we're throttling the processor to make
Speaker 1:  your phone, keep running. This is all very innocent. We just didn't tell
Speaker 1:  you about it. The cops,
Speaker 1:  they announced the battery replacement program. Now you can just replace
Speaker 1:  your battery. And they had to admit to their investors. Yep. Our upgrades
Speaker 1:  took a hit because people could just replace the batteries. Well,
Speaker 1:  I fund 12 and 13. They're not the phones in either batteries replaced right
Speaker 1:  now. Yeah. So like this, I would just say like,
Speaker 1:  you're right. It's the threat of regulation, lawsuits, all this stuff, this
Speaker 1:  cloud, that's hanging over tech companies right now. But the win for apple
Speaker 1:  is they're doing it on their terms. And then backing off the pressure. Why
Speaker 1:  M one max, not Intel mats, which they still sell.
Speaker 11:  Well, the, the M ones, they don't the batteries. And so you can actually
Speaker 11:  replace the battery now.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I mean, it may be that they, they knew that they were doing this. And
Speaker 3:  so they like, they made them slightly easier to repair question mark, not
Speaker 3:  the phones, not the phones. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  They designed the iPhone 13, three
Speaker 3:  Years ago. Here's my big question. What does an apple design heat gun look
Speaker 3:  like? And if they, if they commissioned Johnny ive to help make it from love
Speaker 3:  from like, do you plug it? Is it, is it charged? Does a charge of the lightning
Speaker 3:  cable does a lightning cable plug in like in the center of like where the
Speaker 3:  heat that actually has the exhaust. So it's like the apple mouse. Like you
Speaker 3:  can't have it, plug it in these at the same time. It's going to be
Speaker 1:  Great. You're going to have you say, I fixed it. Doesn't use a gun. They
Speaker 11:  Have like, what's essentially, it looks like a hot plate
Speaker 3:  And they place it. They have a giant TD pad and it's cause they can, they
Speaker 3:  can precisely control the temperature that way. I feel
Speaker 11:  Like that's expensive. I feel like most people are.
Speaker 1:  So all the old air power mats that didn't get sold that were overheating
Speaker 1:  had been repurposed to the repair
Speaker 1:  program.
Speaker 3:  So speaking of Briggs though, this is like the last thing, which is apple
Speaker 3:  might publish these documents and it might be the
Speaker 3:  instructions for taking apart. An iPhone 13 requires a
Speaker 3:  $14,000 rig. And we won't tell you how to do it without the rig,
Speaker 3:  but that's a real positive.
Speaker 1:  This is what I mean. If you're telling me that this has been in the works
Speaker 1:  for over a year and you're, you're announcing it today, time
Speaker 1:  do a shareholder lawsuit, expiration date, and you're not ready to
Speaker 1:  roll it out until next year. I dunno, man. Like maybe even talking about
Speaker 1:  it for a year. And like someone just pulled the ripcord. Yeah. That
Speaker 1:  timing with apple, apple historically famously announced
Speaker 1:  things. When they're ready to go very rarely
Speaker 1:  pre announces products that are not ready to ship like 3,200 parts. So we'll
Speaker 1:  see. But I am looking forward to an apple beautiful
Speaker 1:  aluminum heat gun. It's going to be gorgeous. Oh man, it'd be like that.
Speaker 1:  You know that, that they're going to do it because aluminum conducts so much
Speaker 1:  heat. They won't realize that humans have to hold it and then Belkin will
Speaker 1:  make a holder for it. Here's my question. If Illumina, if the heat gun has
Speaker 1:  a battery, we be able to replace the battery. That's
Speaker 1:  enough of this other little apple news. They delayed
Speaker 1:  Zoe Schiffer. Now NBC news broke the story. They're
Speaker 1:  delaying returned to work until February and changing the policies
Speaker 1:  continues to be a drama for apple. And we'll see how that
Speaker 1:  goes. And then mark Gurman at Bloomberg. I can't get enough apple
Speaker 1:  car story. It's my favorite. So apple now wants to
Speaker 1:  launch a self-driving Evie in 2025 with its own ship.
Speaker 1:  I have to say, and I always talk to Grumman. He gets great scripts. It's
Speaker 1:  just funny that apple thinks making a custom chip, which is the thing it's
Speaker 1:  good at. Yeah. Will be the thing that allows them to ship a car, which is
Speaker 1:  the thing that it's bad at. I love it. Like of course they're going to make
Speaker 1:  a customer. Like obviously that's the only thing they know how to do at this
Speaker 1:  point in terms of the car, right? Do they know how to make
Speaker 1:  wheels like unclean? They made the back pro
Speaker 1:  tiny wheels. So the story here is Kevin Lynch who
Speaker 1:  ran the watch by the way, resuscitated his career after Adobe and apple
Speaker 1:  amazing run with the Washington stuff is now in charge of the car project
Speaker 1:  they were, who knows what they've been doing in the past. There are now a
Speaker 1:  new focus on self-driving, right? The point of this car is that it can drive
Speaker 1:  it and it will have no steering wheel. And they're going to launch it in
Speaker 1:  four years.
Speaker 11:  Okay. I want to have that confidence in life. I want to
Speaker 11:  walk through the world with a confidence that the car design team at apple.
Speaker 1:  Well, that just means they're going to get fine.
Speaker 11:  Nevermind. Nevermind. I don't want that confidence.
Speaker 1:  I just saying like the, I talked to an awful lot of car
Speaker 1:  executives on decoder, right? It kind of every layer of the
Speaker 1:  industry from the CEO's to project, man, like we've just talked to an
Speaker 1:  awful lot of car folks. I've talked to the CEOs of LIDAR
Speaker 1:  companies and self-driving companies, none of them are
Speaker 1:  saying, we're going to have a product in four years,
Speaker 1:  not a one, right? Like your data collection problem is
Speaker 1:  insane. Your sensor problem is insane. Your
Speaker 1:  regulatory problem is insane. Like I just, it's
Speaker 1:  amazing that this is the target. And maybe it's just a bold target,
Speaker 1:  but like Waymo, which is the industry leader will not
Speaker 1:  commit to 40. Like, and they've already got
Speaker 1:  Chrysler Pacific as wandering the streets of San Francisco in
Speaker 1:  Phoenix, without drivers behind the wheel, like they're
Speaker 1:  operating a taxi service and they're not like we're ready to go. Here's a
Speaker 1:  huge problem for like Waymo's cars to Quadro Malecon
Speaker 1:  was on Dakota. We talked to code and she's on the cutter. You can go
Speaker 1:  listen to it. I was like, can you put a car in Denver and was like, no,
Speaker 1:  right? Like, they're like, snow's a problem for us. The cool that's
Speaker 1:  like pretty big problem. And like, she was like very
Speaker 1:  sincere. Like, she's like, that's the next challenge. I just don't see how
Speaker 1:  apple they're. There still are operating so far behind that curve.
Speaker 1:  They've never put a person in a car.
Speaker 3:  Here's my concern. You know, Apple's not saying anything about the car. They're
Speaker 3:  certainly not saying they're not certainly not giving to that. But someone
Speaker 3:  inside apple, must've given this deadline to someone. And so the concern
Speaker 3:  with the car is the same as a concern with like that health stuff. Right.
Speaker 3:  Is apple being honest with itself about its capabilities
Speaker 3:  and about what it's going to be able to ship? Like, are they giving themselves
Speaker 3:  like true deadlines and do they actually know what they are capable of and
Speaker 3:  not capable of internally? Or is there like, is there
Speaker 3:  a culture of, we can do anything in there that is going to end up burning
Speaker 3:  them?
Speaker 1:  Yes. I think it's both, right. I mean, either you have a car that can drive
Speaker 1:  itself or you don't.
Speaker 3:  No, no, no. There's a middle ground. It's called full self-driving on a model
Speaker 3:  three.
Speaker 1:  Right. But like even full self-driving, like give Tessa credit. Like they,
Speaker 1:  they keep putting that software out in the world. They keep selling the
Speaker 1:  sensor kits to people. When they buy the cars. They're not like this is ready.
Speaker 1:  Right? Like Elan's like next week self-track full self-driving will
Speaker 1:  be ready. And he will set the huge prediction.
Speaker 1:  And now every Tesla customer, no matter how much you love Ilan or not, you
Speaker 1:  know, in your heart, he's going to miss the deadline and Tesla to its credit
Speaker 1:  is not overclaiming. The name is bad and they should change the name
Speaker 1:  because I think it confuses everyone. But including the people
Speaker 1:  driving the cars, but like, Tesla's not saying it's ready
Speaker 1:  and they have as much data about actual human beings behind the wheel of
Speaker 1:  self-driving cars to anyone. I just, I see this stuff from apple. And it's
Speaker 1:  like at the end of the day, and we talked about this last week with Sean
Speaker 1:  at the end of the day, they have so much money that they
Speaker 1:  need to attack markets. We're spending that money is worth it
Speaker 1:  where they have a huge advantage because of their pile of cash. Yeah. And
Speaker 1:  the car industry is like one of those markets.
Speaker 3:  It's like, there's, there's the, there's a microfiber cloth industry.
Speaker 1:  It's the clock, the cloth industry. Yeah. Textiles. Apple's gonna be big
Speaker 1:  in the textiles. I mean, they give you a Samsung with it. They could start
Speaker 1:  making nuclear reactors, submarines boats.
Speaker 1:  Like if you just look at the like consumer products, making a
Speaker 1:  TV is like almost not worth the money and attention for apple. They could
Speaker 1:  buy an old led factory tomorrow in China. And like,
Speaker 1:  it wouldn't, it wouldn't hit the bank account. Like cut, like a couple of
Speaker 1:  zeros would go down or whatever. Like it's, there's just a piece of
Speaker 1:  the puzzle where they're like, yep. This is a place where we have a moat
Speaker 1:  in the moat is cashed and that might not be technology or focus or an idea
Speaker 1:  of what a car should do. And I think that's how you get to, we're gonna launch
Speaker 1:  it in four years ahead of every other player in the industry that
Speaker 1:  has been relentlessly focused and instead of like hiring teams and firing
Speaker 1:  teams. So we'll see. I just want to know what you think the apple car will
Speaker 1:  look like because we keep seeing new EVs and they all
Speaker 1:  look nuts, right? Like they either look like robot fish,
Speaker 1:  which is my favorite design trend of all time. Or like, like
Speaker 1:  Toyota lately is deep in the robot fish zone. Like go look at the new
Speaker 1:  Tundra. This is gigantic robot fish. Or they,
Speaker 1:  they look they're, they're all doing the, the light bars across
Speaker 1:  the face. And they look like that emoji with the line for the face,
Speaker 1:  which I, which Dieter I have to admit, I think it was the Dieter emoji.
Speaker 1:  Oh my God. You know the emojis, the smiley face, but it's just the line.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. That's me. Yeah. That's yeah. Cause you sent it to me a lot.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Well it's so it, it says so much like
Speaker 3:  it's the most expressive emoji, honestly. What if apple goes
Speaker 3:  like, like screw it and they just copy a Hyundai is
Speaker 3:  a grander. Did you seen the, this retro Evy
Speaker 3:  awesome car.
Speaker 1:  It's very good. It's very, do you ever seen the movie in time?
Speaker 1:  People, may people made this reference to this movie? So there's an old movie.
Speaker 1:  It's Justin Timberlake movie. I want to say. Yeah. Yeah,
Speaker 1:  yeah. And he's like, he's like a kid. And like, instead of
Speaker 1:  currency, the world uses time and you can run out of time. Lots of time.
Speaker 1:  And so all throughout this movie, in this like weird future,
Speaker 1:  they all drive crazy restaurant cars. Like he drives like a challenger, but
Speaker 1:  they're all EVs. And this concept reminds me of that movie. It's so
Speaker 1:  good. It looks like a 1980s Chrysler. Yeah. Yeah. Hyundai actually did have
Speaker 1:  a car that looked like this called the granddaughter, which has copy of a
Speaker 1:  19 days Chrysler, which is great. But yeah, I I'm, I'm confident that this
Speaker 1:  car has a 0.0 crash rating. Yeah. But I would buy it in
Speaker 1:  one heartbeat. If it was for sale,
Speaker 3:  You put this thing in a wind tunnel that would just flip over.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Car design right now is just a, it's a lot of weird ideas. I
Speaker 1:  would say like the fact that you don't need a grill anymore. I think it's
Speaker 1:  just confusing a lot of car designers. So they're like, like BMW is like,
Speaker 1:  but what if the grills were the whole car? Yeah. And as I just, I'm dying
Speaker 1:  to know like it's apple can make a mid-size crossover, but
Speaker 1:  yes, if you're gonna, are you gonna make a $60,000 mid-sized crossover?
Speaker 1:  Like, is that just like a boring pro product for apple?
Speaker 3:  It's going to be like $80,000. It's going to be $200,000.
Speaker 3:  It's going to be impeccable on those seats.
Speaker 1:  I there's just like there's. Yeah. There's the in and out of the car market.
Speaker 1:  There's the, it's a tech problem. It's an AI problem. There's a reasons then
Speaker 1:  you think about the actual product they have to deliver to people. Like,
Speaker 1:  are they going to have proprietary tires?
Speaker 3:  Will there be a right to repair, repair manual for it?
Speaker 3:  Can you get it fixed at
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Can you go to the Midas and have the fluids changed? Can I get
Speaker 3:  Change at Jiffy lube and we'll use premium fuel. It's
Speaker 3:  easy. Isn't it? That's like,
Speaker 1:  I think you're making a gas car. That would be the best. I
Speaker 1:  hope it's Tim cook was like, and we've uncovered a revolutionary power
Speaker 1:  source. It's been right under our noses the entire time. Yeah. It's called
Speaker 1:  diesel.
Speaker 1:  Alright. So lightning round things here. This bell muda phone. I don't, I
Speaker 1:  don't even know Dieter. Can you explain this toaster phone? To me? There's
Speaker 1:  a,
Speaker 3:  A high-end toaster company in Japan, a CAPA muda they make, they make lots
Speaker 3:  of cool stuff and they have made an Android phone. I just wanted to talk
Speaker 3:  about it. To encourage you to go to the website, pull over in your car, pull
Speaker 3:  in your car first. It does look cool. Go to the website. It's like a
Speaker 3:  half circle, like a wedge it's like wider and it's aspect ratio than
Speaker 3:  most phones. It's relatively small. I'm sure it's terrible.
Speaker 3:  But it looks so good. And it's like, yeah. You know what it
Speaker 3:  reminds me of, even though it's got perfectly flat screen, I was like for
Speaker 3:  the hot minute, when we had like concave screens,
Speaker 3:  like the galaxy nexus and you know that Samsung was, I miss
Speaker 3:  those. It reminds me of that a little bit. Anyway. Bring back weird phone
Speaker 3:  shapes. That's the only thing I wanted to say about this thing. It looks
Speaker 3:  sick.
Speaker 1:  I want to buy this toaster. The toaster is $300. It's gotta be a good toaster.
Speaker 1:  I went by the toaster. Okay. And then here's, this is like such a funny
Speaker 1:  Facebook story. They demoed a haptic glove. They're
Speaker 1:  very proud of it for the metaverse it's uses
Speaker 1:  like new micro fluids and pneumatics to like, feel pressure. So it feels
Speaker 1:  like you're like, it can resist your fingers. Cool. And then immediately
Speaker 1:  the next day, a company called haptics is like, dude, you just copied our
Speaker 1:  glove. Like that's our glove. Like it's the same technology. It looks just
Speaker 1:  like ours. So we don't know what's going on there. Here's my only question.
Speaker 1:  Phase Metta, Metta, Metta is buying everything
Speaker 1:  in VR. They just bought supernatural Peter Kafka, Recode reporter. That was
Speaker 1:  a $500 million deal. I have no idea if supernatural is worth
Speaker 1:  $500 million. I think Zuckerberg just wrote the check. Why didn't they just
Speaker 1:  buy this company? Like it's
Speaker 1:  such an unforced dumb error. Like who else are they going to solve a haptic
Speaker 1:  gloves to
Speaker 11:  It's like one exec was like, no, we can do those ourselves. But he got
Speaker 11:  slighted at a Bennigan's or something. It was like,
Speaker 1:  I've actually been working up on micro microfluid glove concept of my
Speaker 1:  very good Sonos at a DTS support to its
Speaker 1:  home theater stuff. I'm only calling this out because you, the
Speaker 1:  Vergecast listener, this is our community that cares about
Speaker 1:  DTS. Supports. People are very excited about it. Even the
Speaker 1:  play bars, getting it. Wow.
Speaker 3:  That's nuts. I've got to play bar. I'm very excited,
Speaker 3:  very excited.
Speaker 1:  You've got your blue rays and listen to some D B DTS stuff. I
Speaker 1:  almost said BTS are going to listen to some BTS Blu-rays
Speaker 3:  I think the last thing is, so the pixel six
Speaker 3:  Google never said what kind of
Speaker 3:  wattage it could take. They would only give you numbers. It'll charge from
Speaker 3:  to 80% in half an hour or something they would give you like charge times.
Speaker 3:  They wouldn't tell you how many Watts it could take to fast charge. They'd
Speaker 3:  also told you they will sell you a wireless charger. Eventually that will
Speaker 3:  charge as fast as plugging it in. That's pretty much it. And then
Speaker 3:  alongside the pixel six, they sold a 30 watt charger. If you want to buy
Speaker 3:  a charger because it doesn't come with the box, you can buy a 30 watt charger.
Speaker 3:  And I was like, cool, guess the charges at 30 Watts? Nope.
Speaker 3:  It turns out it, it charges like somewhere like at averages,
Speaker 3:  like way lower. It can do up to 20, 23 or something to
Speaker 3:  that in that zone. But like it bounces around depending on
Speaker 3:  heat and like how full it is and so on, which is what you want.
Speaker 3:  But it never hits the peak that people assumed was 30 Watts because that's
Speaker 3:  charter that they sell it peaks at 23 Watts. So Android authority
Speaker 3:  like did the testing to verify this. And then Google had to like
Speaker 3:  come out and say, yeah, by the way, this is like,
Speaker 3:  these are the waters. This is how it works. This is why. And they like, they
Speaker 3:  just kinda, they kind of tried to get away with something there and they
Speaker 3:  almost did, but good on Andrew entered authority for doing the testing. They
Speaker 3:  also put out a software update for the pixels that they said improved the
Speaker 3:  reliability and perhaps the speed of the fingerprint sensor, a bunch of us
Speaker 3:  have installed it. And I'm fully in the confirmation
Speaker 3:  bias on I'm like, yeah, sure. It's faster. Yeah. I'm sure it's failing
Speaker 3:  less. Yeah, no,
Speaker 3:  but like bottom line is, it's still not as good as like an S 20. It's still
Speaker 3:  not as good as other, other optical sensors
Speaker 1:  To read on, on pixel six at this moment. Right? This is their back in it.
Speaker 1:  This is our real flagship. Couple of weeks later. How do you think it's gone?
Speaker 3:  I mean, I wish I could say, you know, like it doesn't feel like
Speaker 3:  it's picking up any more momentum than any other pixel to
Speaker 3:  me in this moment. I think
Speaker 3:  every single year we're like, well, let's see what the hell, how hard the
Speaker 3:  carriers push it. And like we're coming into black Friday. Let's see how
Speaker 3:  the carriers are pushing the pixel six instead of the iPhone or,
Speaker 1:  And through the holidays. Right? If we see that big marketing push we'll
Speaker 1:  know, I want to call out two stories here. Katy Keck,
Speaker 1:  our new streaming reporter had an amazing inside look
Speaker 1:  at Netflix, open connect, which is their CDN where they like put
Speaker 1:  their own servers at your ISP. That's why Netflix doesn't go down. I'm
Speaker 1:  a, I'm torn on this. Like I wish the internet was better.
Speaker 1:  It'd be cool if it was, they did it because the internet like between
Speaker 1:  ISP and this country is not that reliable. So just a deep look at like
Speaker 1:  Netflix just solved. It's probably there's built there and infrastructure
Speaker 1:  great piece by Katie. And then Alex Heath, we were talking about meta after
Speaker 1:  all these leaks, the Facebook papers, that consortium that we
Speaker 1:  were in, all this stuff, Mehta has gone into lockdown and they've
Speaker 1:  started the culture of that company is changing. You have to ask for access
Speaker 1:  to things in a way that people didn't have to ask for access before.
Speaker 1:  And I think the changing culture of meta Facebook, Instagram, it will have
Speaker 1:  ripple effects, great piece by Alex, lots of inside info on how
Speaker 1:  that company is working in the face of all this pressure and leaks.
Speaker 1:  Okay. We have gone over. It's real.
Speaker 1:  So we're going to get out of here on Tuesday. Dieter did an
Speaker 1:  whole Vergecast on RCS. I did, which was pretty amazing. Yep. Very good.
Speaker 3:  Coming Tuesday. We're doing another, another episode, which well feature
Speaker 3:  knee-high we're going to, we're going to air the interview we did with Eero
Speaker 3:  CEO, Nick Weaver.
Speaker 1:  Oh, at the event. Yep. The spectaculars continue. Also go
Speaker 1:  watch springboard, teeters documentary about handspring.
Speaker 1:  It's available on our new app on TV streaming devices on Roku, Amazon fire,
Speaker 1:  TV, Android TV, and apple TV. It's got our videos. It's got our podcasts,
Speaker 1:  you know, put us on the big screen. That's where we belong. It looks great
Speaker 1:  in your living room. That was great. You can tweet at us. I'm at reckless
Speaker 1:  two years at backlog. Alex is Alex H Kranz. Lauren is Lauren
Speaker 1:  Grush. McKenna is Kelly McKenna. It's her name but backwards. We'll
Speaker 1:  see you next week. Get a shot.
Speaker 2:  The world is changing fast. And when it comes to online banking,
Speaker 2:  capital one and it's teams of engineers are working to keep customers safe
Speaker 2:  by developing, cutting edge technology at the forefront of what's possible
Speaker 2:  capital one, develops products like a tech company using machine learning
Speaker 2:  to lead the way like the way they fight fraud or their AI powered
Speaker 2:  intelligent assistant, you know, capital one's apps and products have
Speaker 2:  won awards for some of the best real time. Personalized customer
Speaker 2:  experiences learn more@capitalone.com
Speaker 2:  slash tech.