# Transcript
ID: 48ae43c0-57b5-11ec-8c22-7fdec605e3ed
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Behind the scenes of our Treo documentary, Springboard
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-2821149790439624718/2274619597870964666/s93290-US-3106s-1638917697.mp3
Description: Live at On The Verge in New York City, Nilay and Dieter discuss The Verge's documentary Springboard: the secret history of the first real smartphone and conduct at Q&amp;A with the audience.
Springboard is now streaming worldwide. You can watch it on The Verge’s new app on Android TV, Amazon Fire TV, Roku, or Apple TV. It is now also available to watch on our YouTube channel.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (6 ads detected)
Speaker 2:  Greetings mobile. Accomplishers welcome to the Vergecast. I am Dieter
Speaker 2:  Bohn and this is another entry in our special run of topic.
Speaker 2:  Specific Tuesday episodes. This week, we are bringing you another
Speaker 2:  conversation from our 10 year anniversary party. It was called on the
Speaker 2:  verge specifically. We're going to play a conversation that Nila Patel and
Speaker 2:  I had after the world, premier of our documentary, it's called
Speaker 2:  springboard the secret history of the first real
Speaker 2:  smartphone. And there weren't,
Speaker 4:  You can go buy you. Couldn't go to the market and say, build memory of these
Speaker 4:  tanks. We,
Speaker 5:  The cough like a rocket. Everybody wanted this
Speaker 5:  product.
Speaker 3:  The documentary is about a nearly forgotten company called handspring, which
Speaker 3:  made visor, PDAs and trio smartphones years
Speaker 3:  before the iPhone. You can watch it now on our smart TV
Speaker 3:  apps that are on Roku, fire, TV, apple TV, and Android
Speaker 3:  TV by searching for the verge. Or as of today, it's
Speaker 3:  also available on our YouTube channel, which is
Speaker 3:  youtube.com/the verge. I think that you're going to find a conversation to
Speaker 3:  just be a bit richer, more interesting if you've watched the documentary,
Speaker 3:  but I will play a couple of clips from it here on this podcast. Before we
Speaker 3:  get started with conversation, just to give you some context on a personal
Speaker 3:  note, I'm really proud of what the verge video team did here, but I'm
Speaker 3:  also personally happy to have put this thing out into the world. I
Speaker 3:  really do feel like the people behind handspring haven't gotten the credit
Speaker 3:  that they deserve. And my hope for springboard is that it goes some way towards
Speaker 3:  setting the record straight about who some of the early innovators were in
Speaker 3:  the smartphone space. If you've been following my
Speaker 3:  work for a long time, you might know that I got my start in
Speaker 3:  journalism by hanging out on the
Speaker 3:  forums@visorcentraldotcomandthenwritingfortriocentral.com.
Speaker 3:  In fact, my little intro here at the top of the podcast, greetings
Speaker 3:  mobile accomplishers is actually a reference to
Speaker 3:  Palm. See, back when Palm introduced the trio six 80,
Speaker 3:  just a few months before the iPhone was announced, they were trying to
Speaker 3:  describe who the target market was for the smartphone. And back in
Speaker 3:  2006, nobody really knew if smartphones are
Speaker 3:  actually going to take off blackberries or for email and
Speaker 3:  other smartphones are really not mass market yet. So palms idea
Speaker 3:  for the trio six 80 was that it was targeted towards quote mobile
Speaker 3:  accomplishers, which was something that was like not quite a regular consumer,
Speaker 3:  but not really business people either. You know, it's pretty common for companies
Speaker 3:  to come up with categories for their target demographic, but I just thought
Speaker 3:  the phrase mobile accomplishers was funny. So I started using it to
Speaker 3:  introduce the trio central trio cast. And I've been introducing
Speaker 3:  podcasts with that phrase kind of ever since greetings mobile
Speaker 3:  accomplishers here we are the sprint trio pro. We are readings mobile.
Speaker 3:  Accomplishers welcome to the verge mobile show. Anyway, this is
Speaker 3:  all just to point out that I have been reporting on smartphones since
Speaker 3:  forever, but more importantly, I want to put some of our
Speaker 3:  discussion about handspring into
Speaker 3:  context. Springboard is about a
Speaker 3:  period of time. That's roughly say 1998 to
Speaker 3:  2006, 2007. And back then the smartphone world
Speaker 3:  looked very different than it does today. Like I said, there was
Speaker 3:  Blackberry, but there was also Symbion there was pocket PC and
Speaker 3:  eventually windows mobile, Android didn't exist back then. And the iPhone
Speaker 3:  didn't exist back then. And nobody really knew how this market was going
Speaker 3:  to shake out except that a few people knew just how
Speaker 3:  big it was going to be a phrase that's been kicked around a lot in
Speaker 3:  Silicon valley, since it was originally introduced by John Sculley,
Speaker 3:  the former CEO of apple, when Steve jobs got sent away before he
Speaker 3:  came back, it was called the mother of all markets. And
Speaker 3:  at Palm, they actually had a little spinny sign and one sign pointed up to
Speaker 3:  mother of all markets. And the bottom of it was a pipe dream driven by greed
Speaker 3:  or something. And no one really knew where it was going to be with the PDA
Speaker 3:  market. And no one really knew where the smartphone market would land, but
Speaker 3:  everybody in the back of their mind, especially at handspring had a sense
Speaker 3:  that the smartphone market was going to be huge, that it was going to be
Speaker 3:  the mother of all markets. And they tried to make that happen,
Speaker 3:  but they were way too small. They were really scrappy and they faced
Speaker 3:  very long odds. There are lots of things working
Speaker 3:  against handspring, but the biggest thing working against handspring
Speaker 3:  was the carriers. The companies that actually sold the phones,
Speaker 3:  they had so much power back then. It was impossible to sell a
Speaker 3:  phone without them. And in many ways the I-phones biggest
Speaker 3:  innovation was taking some power away from those
Speaker 3:  carriers. So here's a brief clip from the springboard
Speaker 3:  documentary where some of the people from handspring talk about how
Speaker 3:  difficult it was to get anybody to just sell the
Speaker 3:  trio.
Speaker 6:  At times, these deals were so big. You're talking about the survival of the
Speaker 6:  company. The degree of gamesmanship could get
Speaker 6:  so intense. Your entire dream will fail
Speaker 6:  unless you agree to put this app on your launcher,
Speaker 4:  They were interested in adding features to their phones. They didn't view
Speaker 4:  it as a computer. They said, it's a phone everyone's going to fall on. And
Speaker 4:  phones are dominant. We were thinking, no, the future is going to be the
Speaker 4:  computers. And the phone is a,
Speaker 5:  I remember clearly going to sprint and saying, great
Speaker 5:  idea. Now, guess what? You can take a photo
Speaker 5:  right on this thing and send it to somebody. And they said, nah,
Speaker 5:  we don't want to do that. Our other devices can't do that. They
Speaker 5:  also were one of the principal resellers of the product. It went through
Speaker 5:  their stores. We made
Speaker 4:  The first products and they wouldn't sell them. They said, no, we can't.
Speaker 4:  We're not going to sell these things. You have to make the following changes.
Speaker 3:  Okay, one more clip. I want to play for you before we get started, it's a
Speaker 3:  very brief and abbreviated history of Palm and
Speaker 3:  handspring. Now, again, the springboard documentary only covers a portion
Speaker 3:  of this, but you can get a sense of just how complicated the corporate
Speaker 3:  history of Palm is by listening to this little clip. One of the big
Speaker 3:  reasons that Palm never really managed to take on the iPhone is it spent
Speaker 3:  all of the years leading up to the iPhone, just dealing with various
Speaker 3:  corporate shenanigans. They founded Palm, which was bought by us
Speaker 3:  robotics, which got bought by three com three comm refuse to spin
Speaker 3:  off Palm. So Donna and Jeff quit to start handspring.
Speaker 3:  Meanwhile, their old company, three com finally did spin off
Speaker 3:  Palm, but they split it into two divisions, one for
Speaker 3:  hardware and one to sell software. The Palm hardware
Speaker 3:  division screwed up the market with excess inventory and the Palm
Speaker 3:  software division. Well, it didn't accomplish very much at all. Handspring
Speaker 3:  then runs out of money. So the Palm hardware division buys them, but
Speaker 3:  they refused to buy back the Palm software division. So the family's back
Speaker 3:  together again, and they would continue to sell trios for years to come.
Speaker 3:  But the family trauma isn't over. Here's what was going to
Speaker 3:  happen next for Paul, Jeff and Donna would step away, but ed
Speaker 3:  collagen stayed on to give it another go at the new Palm,
Speaker 3:  but that separate Palm software company sold off and withered
Speaker 3:  away. So the new Palm had to sell windows, mobile trios, and then
Speaker 3:  start over again with new software called web iOS. Then they
Speaker 3:  ran out of money and had to sell the HP. And then
Speaker 3:  HP finally killed Paul. All right,
Speaker 3:  like I said, you can go watch the full springboard documentary on our
Speaker 3:  smart TV apps. Or you can go to our YouTube channel,
Speaker 3:  youtube.com/diverge to watch it there up next. My
Speaker 3:  conversation with Nila that followed the world, premier of the documentary
Speaker 3:  at our 10 year anniversary
Speaker 3:  party.
Speaker 8:  So I think Nila is coming up. I'm not sure where he is, but
Speaker 8:  actually I don't want you to plot for me. I didn't make
Speaker 8:  fish. I went on camera. The, the verge video team made this and there
Speaker 8:  stand up, please stand up. Come
Speaker 8:  on,
Speaker 9:  Buddy. Also to the Virginia team, I did a
Speaker 9:  lot. I'm so happy you saw my movie. All right.
Speaker 9:  Data. I have a number of questions. Okay. How do
Speaker 9:  we break the hold of the,
Speaker 8:  Well, what you need to do is be apple and read a
Speaker 8:  revolutionary new phone and just do the whole thing all
Speaker 8:  over again. It's really we're back in a lot of ways, right?
Speaker 9:  We do feel like we're backing a lot of ways. The carriers do have a lot of
Speaker 9:  control over products, but it does seem like the tide has
Speaker 9:  turned apple and Google do get to sort of do whatever they want. But there
Speaker 9:  are a lot of parallels to this moment, to that moment, like a new
Speaker 9:  company finds it very hard to make a phone.
Speaker 8:  Well, a new company can, it's easy to make a phone now just like to
Speaker 8:  build the phone. One of the, one of the stories here is when they wanted
Speaker 8:  to build the visor phone, like, okay, well let's go get a radio. Well
Speaker 8:  where they had to, like, they found like a company I think in France. And
Speaker 8:  that was the only place they could find a radio that would connect to a cellular
Speaker 8:  network. Now you can show up in Shenzen and be like, make me a
Speaker 8:  phone. And they're like, what? Which parts would you like? Here we go. Bang,
Speaker 8:  bang, bang, bang. So that part is easy, but getting a
Speaker 8:  phone that is actually something that will make it into the carrier stores,
Speaker 8:  get carrier marketing and be something that can be successful on a pretty
Speaker 8:  big scale is much more difficult. It's impossible to imagine a
Speaker 8:  tiny company, the size of what handspring was, would be able to
Speaker 8:  like believe that they could break into the smartphone market right now.
Speaker 8:  But
Speaker 9:  That's like, there's a myth in our industry, in our world that if you make
Speaker 9:  a great product, the market will find you
Speaker 9:  and you will be a success in the market is still under the control of like
Speaker 9:  a tiny handful. And if you sell your products to sprint, you'll
Speaker 8:  Die.
Speaker 9:  It's like how many times the sprint killed pawn separately. It's
Speaker 9:  actually you'll notice that we didn't get to web alas. I feel like I need
Speaker 9:  good left is,
Speaker 8:  Well, I mean like I was inspired by doing, you know, they just ended in the
Speaker 8:  middle.
Speaker 9:  Why'd you why'd you decide to start here. I feel like a lot of our audience
Speaker 9:  knows that you'd care a lot about Palm and web west. Why did you decide to
Speaker 9:  start? It's such a primitive zone
Speaker 8:  Because I don't think the story is well known. And I think that there's
Speaker 8:  a, there's a, I don't know if there's a hopeful element here. Like they came
Speaker 8:  up with these ideas. They were trying to make a
Speaker 8:  wonderful product and thinking really deeply about the user experience and
Speaker 8:  the customer experience and how apps should work and all of that. Like there's,
Speaker 8:  there's just, they don't get the credit that I think they deserve for it.
Speaker 8:  And I feel like, I mean, one, we, we started this six
Speaker 8:  months ago, so trying to tell the rest of that story would have
Speaker 8:  been a lot longer, but I felt like there was an arc
Speaker 8:  here to like this specific company and this thing that they try to do that
Speaker 8:  like starts with some drama. There's some, there was drama before this, by
Speaker 8:  the way. And then, you know, ends with, you know, it's, it's a
Speaker 8:  sad story, but like they were still trying, but the company of
Speaker 8:  handspring and the thing that they were trying to make, you know, it's not
Speaker 8:  a well-known enough story basically. What'd you leave out? Well, we left
Speaker 8:  out all of them. . I mean, if there's that, actually this was, you
Speaker 8:  know, post this, but there was a famous quote that ed
Speaker 8:  collagen gave it the Churchill club. They like do these breakfast talks or
Speaker 8:  whatever that if you read daring fireball and John Gruber, he loves to quote
Speaker 8:  this thing where he was talking to John Markoff I think.
Speaker 8:  And he said something to the effect of PC guys, aren't going to figure this
Speaker 8:  out PC guys. Aren't just going to walk in to the phone market to the phone
Speaker 8:  market was, was it, it was assumed that he was referring just to
Speaker 8:  apple saying that they're not going to figure this out. This is like, phones
Speaker 8:  are really complicated. If all you do is make PCs. You're not going to be
Speaker 8:  to figure this out. And you know, he has been lambasted for this
Speaker 8:  quite a bit. He, he contends, he's taken a little bit out of context. I didn't
Speaker 8:  put it in. Cause like I just
Speaker 3:  Gave you a long story that involves talking about during fireball. I don't
Speaker 3:  know if it fits in a documentary like this, but also the, the actual
Speaker 3:  archive of it is currently Mia. So I couldn't like
Speaker 3:  go verify that he believes he was talking. He was talking with the PC industry
Speaker 3:  at large. So funny story, since we recorded this live
Speaker 3:  show, back in October, we did manage to get a hold of the original
Speaker 3:  interview. So I'm going to play just a couple of clips from it. Now, for
Speaker 3:  context, I want to read how collagen was originally quoted in this interview
Speaker 3:  in print in the San Jose mercury news. And the quote goes like this
Speaker 3:  PC guys are not going to just figure this out. They're not going to
Speaker 3:  just walk in unquote. Now, as I mentioned on the live show, John
Speaker 3:  Gruber over it during fireball has quoted collagen on this very often
Speaker 3:  or the past 15 years, at least 20 times by my account. And so it's
Speaker 3:  become a bit of a meme. It's become a shorthand for how everybody
Speaker 3:  underestimated apple before the iPhone launched. But I don't think
Speaker 3:  that's an accurate reading exactly. Once you hear the full quote and the
Speaker 3:  context, see the context here is that they were speaking weeks before the
Speaker 3:  original iPhone was announced and nobody really knew what it would be. So
Speaker 3:  in the interview, mark Robin collagen speculate a bit on what apple might
Speaker 3:  be working on. And then mark off jumps into his next question where he not
Speaker 3:  only asks about future competition from apple, but also from
Speaker 3:  Google.
Speaker 10:  What will it look like? In 2007? You know, apple does get in, Eric's
Speaker 10:  wandering around talking about free phones. He's got Andy Rubin, who is
Speaker 10:  the founder of danger doing something inside. He bought Andy's
Speaker 10:  startup. The phone market could look, I mean, it looks crowded. Now it could
Speaker 10:  look intensely crowded. Nick.
Speaker 11:  Next year,
Speaker 3:  The Eric, there is Eric Schmidt who was then the CEO of Google and Andy
Speaker 3:  Rubin startup was what became Android. This was of course before Android
Speaker 3:  launched. Also, anyway, here's collagen reply.
Speaker 11:  It's intensely big. We just have to get our fair share of the pie. And let
Speaker 11:  me tell you, this is not as easy as it looks. Okay. You
Speaker 11:  know, you've seen Motorola one of the biggest phone companies in the
Speaker 11:  world and or with a device that was going to take over the world and it's
Speaker 11:  had enormous issue.
Speaker 10:  You're talking about queue. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  That Q would be the Motorola Q a very hyped up
Speaker 3:  windows, mobile smartphone that had a Cordy keyboard, but no touch screen,
Speaker 3:  terrible battery life, and really only so-so sales. So here's
Speaker 3:  collagen again. And I want you to pay attention to the tone of his voice
Speaker 3:  here, but also how the actual words he uses are not the
Speaker 3:  exact quote that I read earlier.
Speaker 11:  And so I just would caution people that think
Speaker 11:  they're going to walk in here and just, and do these. We've struggled for
Speaker 11:  a few years here, figuring out how to make a decent phone. The PC guys are
Speaker 11:  not gonna just, you know, knock this out. I guarantee
Speaker 11:  it. So look, you know, welcome,
Speaker 11:  you know, let's, let's go for it. I, I, we can't stop all that it's going
Speaker 11:  to happen, but it's going to be, yeah, I don't think it will be so easy
Speaker 11:  for everybody that everybody thinks to enter it. It's a tough space.
Speaker 3:  The difference between the old quote PC guys are not going to just figure
Speaker 3:  this out. They're not just going to walk in and what you heard Callie and
Speaker 3:  actually say here, I think is notable. There's a bit more humility
Speaker 3:  here than Coggins traditionally gotten credit for. And the topic is specifically
Speaker 3:  that making smartphones is hard. Anyway, Markoff also catches onto
Speaker 3:  this whole vibe that you get whenever a company has when there's a huge
Speaker 3:  competitor about to come in and eat their lunch. So he asked about that specifically
Speaker 3:  in the next question. ,
Speaker 10:  I've been around this industry long enough that you probably remember, maybe
Speaker 10:  you don't actually the famous wall street journal ad that apple took out
Speaker 10:  in 1981. Welcome. IBM, seriously. Yeah.
Speaker 10:  Right.
Speaker 11:  Well, look, I, you know, I'm not, I'm not trying to
Speaker 11:  be cocky about it. It is a tough, it's a tough business. We've
Speaker 11:  really struggled through that. You know, in the sense of making world-class
Speaker 11:  radios that perform on global networks consistently with all the
Speaker 11:  applications that we,
Speaker 3:  So that's the original interview. And well, I think it's fair to say that
Speaker 3:  collagen was putting on a brave face for apple jumped into his
Speaker 3:  market. I also think it's fair to say that really he was talking about the
Speaker 3:  rest of the industry that didn't have much experience with smartphones,
Speaker 3:  apple. Sure. But also Google and even Motorola. And when I asked
Speaker 3:  CogAT about it specifically during the interviews for the springboard
Speaker 3:  documentary, he said that his main point was that it was hard. And also
Speaker 3:  that he was a little bummed that this one section of an otherwise pretty
Speaker 3:  good hour long interview is the thing that gets quoted the most.
Speaker 9:  And he was right about that.
Speaker 8:  That's an excellent point.
Speaker 9:  Have any of you ever used a phone made by Dell? Yeah.
Speaker 9:  Right. I, I have it. Wasn't
Speaker 9:  great. Yeah. Right. Do any of you use a phone
Speaker 9:  made by a little company called
Speaker 9:  Microsoft? I'm actually, I was like,
Speaker 9:  assuming there'd be one person here. It's
Speaker 9:  just like given our audience, but like the PC guys did not
Speaker 8:  Figure it out. No, they did not.
Speaker 9:  What else? What were the other pieces? Cause when he puts this other, something
Speaker 9:  of this, you only got 30 minutes. There are some things you have to let go
Speaker 9:  of. And I know that you
Speaker 8:  There's more and more stories of carriers being dumb.
Speaker 8:  Japan, Taiwan,
Speaker 9:  30 minutes
Speaker 8:  Of donkey. Jeff Hawkins rolled into a meeting
Speaker 8:  in for a carrier in France. And the guy
Speaker 8:  refused to believe that Cordie keyboards were a thing. And at the time the
Speaker 8:  capacitive screens weren't really there yet. They were using resistance screen.
Speaker 8:  So a touch screen keyboard wasn't like viable. So Curry keyboards were the
Speaker 8:  shit. And like blackberries were doing it. They were doing it on the trio.
Speaker 8:  And so he rolls in and the carrier guys like, you know,
Speaker 8:  Courtney keyboards will never be as fast as T nine. And I challenge you to
Speaker 8:  erase, to type something and you have to put the phone
Speaker 8:  under the table. And so Jeff Hawkins had to race this guy with phones under
Speaker 8:  the table that he could type on accord to keyboard faster than T nine. And
Speaker 8:  he won. He won four. Of course he won. Come on.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. That makes sense. So yeah, we're going to take questions. So you
Speaker 9:  have lineup over there. The one thing that as I watched
Speaker 9:  this, you know, we have seen this documentary a lot, but watching it with
Speaker 9:  all of you, it seems like Donna Dubinsky does
Speaker 9:  not get the credit she deserves for being a pioneer in this industry.
Speaker 9:  Yeah.
Speaker 8:  She came on, she was, you know, the CEO, she used to work at
Speaker 8:  apple, like the, the number of like fights at these three executives. But
Speaker 8:  Donna and ed in particular who both were at apple had with, with
Speaker 8:  Steve jobs that like aren't in this cut, like there's a lot, they would,
Speaker 8:  they would call and yell at each other all the time. And you know, she talked
Speaker 8:  about how fast the company grew. It, there were there magazine articles of
Speaker 8:  like the Titans of, you know, Silicon valley at the time. And you like, look
Speaker 8:  at these pictures of these people. There's like, it's, it's 15 white
Speaker 8:  dudes and Donna in the middle. And like, she's so much shorter
Speaker 8:  than two. And you know, it's like the late nineties. So they're all wearing
Speaker 8:  pants that are like, you know, this wide, like what it was. But yeah, it
Speaker 8:  was remarkable. She was, she was successful and dynamic and you
Speaker 8:  know, doing really well, they just, they hit these dramas. I, the joke that
Speaker 8:  I make is that the history of Pullman handspring is every 18
Speaker 8:  months. If somebody would have just given them $300 million, they would have
Speaker 8:  won their own feet a
Speaker 8:  bunch. But
Speaker 9:  Yeah. What do you see now that reminds you of that, of that
Speaker 9:  excitement, not the excitement. Where are the small companies that if
Speaker 9:  only someone would just give them the money and the time. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  And they would break through, well, there's a website called the verge. We're
Speaker 8:  very good. You'd like to give us a 300 mil.
Speaker 9:  We're just 18 months away from defeating apple. She
Speaker 9:  could just help us out. That would be great. I think that, I see a lot of
Speaker 9:  those companies, it's a cliche now. Right? You
Speaker 9:  haven't made a product. You've made a feature where like somebody has a great
Speaker 9:  idea and we all love it. And the big company can just take it and like integrate
Speaker 9:  it in C operating system or they'll buy the nascent company and crush
Speaker 9:  it. And in many ways, buying the nascent company and
Speaker 9:  crushing it is a superior alternative to whatever happened upon me. Right?
Speaker 9:  Like that cycle of murders and deaths and spinoffs, and then HP kills
Speaker 9:  you is like, no, thanks. Right. Like I'd rather just like let Google
Speaker 9:  acqui-hire my company. Yeah. But I think I, I, I still feel
Speaker 9:  that right. Th the small companies don't get the
Speaker 9:  opportunity to take the market.
Speaker 8:  So the, I see excitement and dynamism all over the place. People making a
Speaker 8:  hardware and software tools for creators. There's just so much exciting stuff
Speaker 8:  going on there. The question is where do you see that excitement and that
Speaker 8:  possibility and the something the size of smartphones.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. And that is much more difficult to predict. And is there, is it possible
Speaker 8:  that there is a market that you could theoretically go after without the
Speaker 8:  resources of a tech giant? I'm not sure. I think that's one
Speaker 8:  of the reasons that maybe like crypto is so interesting to people is because
Speaker 8:  it seems like it's a potentially huge thing that you could get into
Speaker 8:  without being, you know, Google or apple or Microsoft.
Speaker 9:  For one second, I thought you were going to say the metaverse and I was going
Speaker 9:  to kick you
Speaker 9:  off.
Speaker 3:  We're gonna take a break. But when we come back, we'll have more of my conversation
Speaker 3:  with Neela about the history of smartphones. Plus some questions from the
Speaker 3:  audience.
Speaker 9:  All right. We're back. We've got some
Speaker 9:  questions. Let's start over here. Piney. Hi Dieter. Oh my God. The hype
Speaker 9:  desk is back. Hello, Sam, the
Speaker 9:  shadow. You know, that was really awesome to
Speaker 9:  watch. It's also crazy to think that so much happened in
Speaker 9:  20 years, 10 years, right? Like that iPhone came out in 2007. It's a long
Speaker 9:  time ago. Do you have a vision or
Speaker 9:  sort of like an idea or thoughts on what do things look like in 10
Speaker 9:  years with mobile computing, spacial computing, Aimee computing, and then
Speaker 9:  20 years. Cause that stuff was 2000 we're in 2021. Yeah. What
Speaker 9:  does, what does that future look like to you?
Speaker 8:  I'll give you 10 I'm too chicken to do 20 actually
Speaker 8:  I J Castroneves wonderful editor at the verge. I, I opened a final
Speaker 8:  draft on an article about this.
Speaker 9:  I stopped me for Jake, Jake, Jake, Jake, Jake,
Speaker 9:  Jake, Jake. It was like the third
Speaker 9:  time
Speaker 8:  Know. I think that that there's either going to be a radical,
Speaker 8:  like technological innovation that we can't see. Like screens will
Speaker 8:  go from folding to projecting into our, I familiar a little camera or
Speaker 8:  something. There'll be implanted some huge thing. And there's no way to predict,
Speaker 8:  or it will just be more relentless, incremental
Speaker 8:  innovation. And I say that in, it sounds like a bummer,
Speaker 8:  but from 2007 to now, it's arguably relentless
Speaker 8:  incremental innovation. And the cultural
Speaker 8:  changes that have been wrought by that those incremental
Speaker 8:  changes are massive. And so the smartphone 10
Speaker 8:  years from now may look very much like the smartphone that we have today,
Speaker 8:  just better cameras, better screens, better, you know, stuff. But that
Speaker 8:  doesn't mean that it doesn't still have the power to change.
Speaker 8:  Our culture changed the way we live our lives.
Speaker 9:  I have two answers. One of which is a relentless plug
Speaker 9:  one. I always look at display technologies,
Speaker 9:  right? That the thing that bounds the devices in our lives is the
Speaker 9:  display, right? So we CA we could not have smartphones with CRT
Speaker 9:  displays, although it would be
Speaker 9:  rad,
Speaker 9:  rad, we needed LCDs. And then we needed really thin LCDs. We
Speaker 9:  needed power efficient LCDs. We needed to touch
Speaker 9:  technology. That is the thing that makes technology
Speaker 9:  possible. We don't have a next display technology. We're really close in
Speaker 9:  some ways. I think Addie and Dieter corrected me on the verge cast a couple
Speaker 9:  of weeks ago. And I was like, it's all CDs. And like, no, there's a, there's
Speaker 9:  like hints of all their stuff, but there's not that turn. We might have folding.
Speaker 9:  So that's what I would look at because that is the thing that allows the
Speaker 9:  leap. The second thing is the restless plug, is we a
Speaker 9:  Nori, Donovan, RDP, and a bunch of other people diverge and I are. And a
Speaker 9:  bunch of other smart people I'm not doing anything might be working on a
Speaker 9:  show for a large streaming service about what life looks like 50 and a hundred
Speaker 9:  years in the future. Is that an exclusive,
Speaker 16:  So I'm
Speaker 9:  Pretty sure let's call it that. And I'm very, that's it's months away,
Speaker 9:  but we were spending a lot of time thinking about that. And I will tell you
Speaker 9:  not easy to predict the future, but we're doing our
Speaker 9:  best. So that'll come out later. Cool. Over here,
Speaker 16:  Hey, let us a proud owner of a Microsoft. So if you
Speaker 16:  ask about Microsoft phone owners is at least
Speaker 16:  one.
Speaker 16:  My question is, I think when you take any of these ideas, you can pursue
Speaker 16:  their origins down to, I mean like software keyboard, for example, you can
Speaker 16:  pursue them down from the iPhone to, to the handspring all the way down
Speaker 16:  to academia for a lot of these ideas. So when you try to tell the story
Speaker 16:  about the origin of ideas like this, where do you, how
Speaker 16:  do you think about where to start? Is it from the first product? Is it from
Speaker 16:  the origins of the ideas themselves and the people who wrote about them
Speaker 16:  thought about them? Or is it even earlier, where did you decide where to
Speaker 16:  start with, with the stories? Yeah,
Speaker 8:  I thought about that a lot. Cause it's like, am I, am I just wanting to tell
Speaker 8:  the story of spring? Cause that's how I got my start in reporting and I just
Speaker 8:  this whatever, and I, maybe this is rationalization, but I
Speaker 8:  feel like you start, I wanted to start with the products that
Speaker 8:  like had an audience and had a community and had like a real shot
Speaker 8:  at like hitting big numbers. I think that going
Speaker 8:  back to, before those products to academia, to there's again,
Speaker 8:  there's other Palmer Wes phones before this thing from Kyocera Wacom or
Speaker 8:  whoever, but the, these were the products
Speaker 8:  that like had more forward looking ideas
Speaker 8:  and also like had a commercial market and had a significant community around
Speaker 8:  them. Neil asked some of the stuff I left out the community
Speaker 8:  around visors and handspring and later Palm was
Speaker 8:  obviously very important to me, so.
Speaker 16:  Okay. Alright. Hi, my name is Scott. I have a question. I
Speaker 16:  don't know if I'm remembering this correctly, but I believe that Palm OOS
Speaker 16:  at one point was connecting to iTunes and apple killed
Speaker 16:  that. W so am I remembering that correctly? And if
Speaker 16:  so, where does that fit into this timeline of this company?
Speaker 8:  I do not know if there was ever a bridge from Paul. My
Speaker 9:  God. I know something about Palm OST. You don't know to
Speaker 8:  ITunes
Speaker 9:  Everybody. It was great. Seeing all of
Speaker 9:  you.
Speaker 8:  Is it the missing sink? No. Okay. Now Weber
Speaker 8:  less.
Speaker 9:  See this that's my God. I just feel my power grow right
Speaker 9:  now.
Speaker 8:  WebQuest did connect to iTunes and on the all things D
Speaker 8:  stage that's when they had a chat, they showed it off. They,
Speaker 8:  they did it by making the Palm pre, which comes after the story,
Speaker 8:  identify as an iPod by its USB
Speaker 8:  identification. So when you plug it a USB device, it says I'm a
Speaker 8:  BA. And so the Palm print, when it plugged into a max that I'm an iPod and
Speaker 8:  then iTunes was like, cool let's sync. Yeah. And then apple did not like
Speaker 8:  that. They did not like, and then there was a cat and mouse game for, I don't
Speaker 8:  know, three, six months where apple would find a way to block it.
Speaker 8:  And Palm would find a way to turn it back on. And then they finally stopped
Speaker 8:  and they stopped doing it.
Speaker 9:  But earlier, do you see that digital hub slide, that famous Steve jobs
Speaker 9:  thing? You net there's no iPod in that slide, there was a creative
Speaker 9:  Rio. Yeah. Central light, full product. I
Speaker 9:  had one, I had it in college, 2003. He
Speaker 9:  got me zero dates. No one was interested in, but
Speaker 9:  apple had a product called Eye-Sync and it could transfer to other players.
Speaker 9:  And then they released the iPod and they cut all that off. So there was like
Speaker 9:  one tiny moment. And I know more about pawn then Dieter I'm done. Okay.
Speaker 8:  No, actually, if, if we're talking about music stuff, I may have
Speaker 8:  noticed it. I talked about the sound's good springboard module. It was an
Speaker 8:  MP3 module. That company got started and
Speaker 8:  there was a young intern at that company. And then the springboard
Speaker 8:  market died. So they moved on to push email
Speaker 8:  services. And then that company got bought by Motorola. And then that young
Speaker 8:  intern,
Speaker 9:  You guys wonder why we are so angsty about mergers on our
Speaker 9:  show. Every time it's like there a good idea, then I company bought
Speaker 9:  it and then they died.
Speaker 8:  I don't know, but that young intern moved up the ranks and Motorola, and
Speaker 8:  it was like, Hey, Razor's not going to last forever. We should make an Android
Speaker 8:  phone. And he talked them into it and he'd launched the
Speaker 8:  droid. And the droid is one of the phones that killed poem.
Speaker 8:  And then Motorola got bought by Lenovo and Rick
Speaker 8:  Costello who currently is in charge of the
Speaker 8:  pixel.
Speaker 9:  So good.
Speaker 17:  Hi Dieter, huge trans since the trio central is I'm going to say three words
Speaker 17:  that might cause PTSD for you. Access Linux pro
Speaker 17:  platform.
Speaker 9:  So, oh God, he didn't even ask him. Why. So you mentioned
Speaker 17:  It. Dave mentioned it in there that the split between
Speaker 17:  Palm wine and Palm source happening, I personally think that schism was
Speaker 17:  one of the biggest cell phones in technology history. Do you think if
Speaker 17:  they hadn't split apart, they might've been able to execute a bit
Speaker 17:  better.
Speaker 8:  When handspring came back to Palm, the hardware
Speaker 8:  division, they were up to free up their license for Palm OLS
Speaker 8:  and, and collagen wanted to just buy them instead of
Speaker 8:  get a license. And the board said, no, just wrap the
Speaker 8:  license, there's it. But it's only like another, some so-and-so million dollars
Speaker 8:  more. And they're like, nah. And so they gave the Palm
Speaker 8:  OSPF company, Palm source, all of this money. And then the Palm source
Speaker 8:  company was like, look at all this money that we just got paid. We must be
Speaker 8:  worth a lot of money. Does anybody want to buy us? And so they sold to a
Speaker 8:  company in Japan access. They made access to Lennox,
Speaker 8:  Palm and this like, nobody else was licensing this
Speaker 8:  operating system except for Paloma obviously. And so it sort of didn't have
Speaker 8:  anywhere to go. And the team that was developing a
Speaker 8:  lot of very interesting, innovative ideas for Palm
Speaker 8:  source, that access Linux Palm, they like
Speaker 8:  started leaving the company and they all started going to a place where
Speaker 8:  they're like, you know, there might be something interesting and cool here
Speaker 8:  we can execute these ideas. One of the most important engineers was a Diane
Speaker 8:  heck thorn. And that company was Google and they made it Android along
Speaker 8:  with the folks from sidekick. So yes. Biggest cell phone in history.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. Sometimes you wonder why Dieter knows everybody. And it's like, because
Speaker 9:  you knew them when they were babies. It's like one of the
Speaker 9:  secrets of 10 years of doing this is like, oh, we know a lot of
Speaker 9:  important people now because we paid attention to them when they were not
Speaker 9:  very important. And like go at coming up with people is like one of the
Speaker 9:  secrets and it just,
Speaker 18:  Hey, so I'm thinking back to like the HTC touch pro too. If you remember
Speaker 18:  that, like the, the windows mobile stuff. And then I feel like after that,
Speaker 18:  the next big leap was Microsoft went all in on the Lumia
Speaker 18:  devices, tried to push that windows eight tile stuff did not work out on
Speaker 18:  desktop or mobile. Do you think if Microsoft would have switched to Android
Speaker 18:  a lot earlier on what we have, like a whole suite of Microsoft, like, could
Speaker 18:  they be the pixel or similar to that? Is that a
Speaker 9:  Victory?
Speaker 8:  Yeah. I dunno. Neela, would you like to discuss? Cause it's been a minute.
Speaker 8:  The burning platform memo
Speaker 9:  Like two days in a row, Steven Elop references on this day, he might
Speaker 9:  recall Steven Elop went to Nokia. He became the
Speaker 9:  CEO and he wrote this memo about saving Nokia. You don't
Speaker 9:  recall this because you're saying people with lives, this is a very important
Speaker 9:  to us. And the memo was an extended allegory about people who
Speaker 9:  lived on an oil Derrick in the middle of the ocean
Speaker 9:  and the oil Derrick catches fire.
Speaker 8:  The oil Derrick in this metaphor is Symbion another competing smartphone
Speaker 8:  operating system.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. It's been a long time since I've read it, but I believe the choices
Speaker 9:  were to burn to death or to dive into the frigid
Speaker 9:  ocean. And he's like, sometimes he got a dive and this
Speaker 9:  was his management philosophy for this
Speaker 9:  company. And he's like, we're diving
Speaker 9:  and the, oh, the frigid ocean was windows phone.
Speaker 9:  Right? So there's like this big thing. And he sends us a memo and I'm imagining
Speaker 9:  I'm, I'm not finished. As you may have noticed. Maybe, maybe
Speaker 9:  this has some like, meaning if any of you are finished, let me know. It's
Speaker 9:  like people just talk about the burning oil Derrick all the time. But like
Speaker 9:  maybe it has some residents, but I imagine the employees of Nokia are like,
Speaker 9:  well, this sucks, but they could have picked. And I think if
Speaker 9:  Nokia had picked Android, the whole market may have been
Speaker 9:  different. But instead the ex Microsoft employee who took
Speaker 9:  over his Nokia CEO surprisingly picked
Speaker 9:  Microsoft platform. So Nokia, Microsoft, Microsoft
Speaker 9:  losses, CEO, they got a new CEO. Who's
Speaker 8:  Like, yeah, the more, these are just some guys
Speaker 9:  Who make choices. I feel like we like elevate CEOs a lot, like many times
Speaker 9:  they're just guys. And like, you might make the same choices. And I think
Speaker 9:  this is like a pivotal choice, but everyone around that choice was like,
Speaker 9:  you should've picked Android.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. I mean the, when I said like the current iPhone,
Speaker 8:  Android world, we live in it, wasn't inevitable. This is one of the things
Speaker 8:  that maybe could have changed it. And so the big question I think that
Speaker 8:  we face now that tech companies are so massive. Is,
Speaker 8:  is there still the potential for that kind of disruptive change that will
Speaker 8:  like re shift things around? And I, you know, my heart
Speaker 8:  wants to say yes, but I think that it's harder than it used to
Speaker 8:  be.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. And I think the, another carrier
Speaker 9:  reference, the carriers saw the duopoly and
Speaker 9:  they wanted Microsoft to be a third competitive thing. So they could
Speaker 9:  get price, leverage. They needed to get leverage against apple and they still
Speaker 9:  do. And like that was their decision. And I think Eli
Speaker 9:  saw a business opportunity and not a product opportunity. And that's always
Speaker 9:  a mistake.
Speaker 19:  I, I love the documentary and it got me thinking about how history
Speaker 19:  always repeats itself. And so I was wondering, do you see a device category
Speaker 19:  like VR or AR or small board computing that is kind of going through a similar
Speaker 19:  cycle where it just hasn't found its form factor yet. That is like the real
Speaker 19:  hit of the iPhone disclosure. Oh
Speaker 9:  God,
Speaker 19:  We did
Speaker 19:  it.
Speaker 8:  You just wanted me to get the,
Speaker 9:  Yeah, that's all I wanted. Also, if we are taping that we need to send that
Speaker 9:  to like every journalism, ethics college course in American,
Speaker 9:  like our disclosures are brand, which is super
Speaker 9:  weird.
Speaker 8:  Nobody applauds for disclosures. Here's
Speaker 8:  amazing. My spouse works for
Speaker 8:  a Oculus Facebook reality labs, the division of Facebook that works on VR
Speaker 8:  and maybe AR I don't actually know. I do think your, that said, I
Speaker 8:  do think that AR is like an interesting possibility. VR is interesting possibility,
Speaker 8:  but the screen thing is real and the resource thing is real.
Speaker 8:  Can you do, can you break into that without having a
Speaker 8:  platform? That's a pretty tough, I think I mentioned tools for
Speaker 8:  creators a little bit earlier, and this is not a fully formed idea, but I
Speaker 8:  think that people that are making stuff that doesn't just feel like it's
Speaker 8:  an accessory for the iPhone, or it's an accessory for the iPhone or Android
Speaker 8:  phone, but it has its own like independent existence in some way that
Speaker 8:  lets you make stuff. That's the most exciting thing to me right now. Like
Speaker 8:  musical tools, you know, creative tools. Yeah.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. I'm with that. We talk about the AR stuff on the podcast all the
Speaker 9:  time, the number of problems to solve from
Speaker 9:  how will you make the battery last all day to who gets to
Speaker 9:  decide who augments reality? Like just, I mean like
Speaker 9:  know Senate rebrand itself, but imagine you're wearing the Facebook glasses
Speaker 9:  and you look at the United States Capitol building, like you don't want your
Speaker 9:  uncle augmenting that image in front of your eyes, right?
Speaker 9:  Like you don't want to literally live in a different reality than the person
Speaker 9:  sitting next to you wearing the glasses. And like, that is the big problem,
Speaker 9:  right? Like my dream, I said this yesterday, like if I could just know all
Speaker 9:  your names, I would be the most powerful person in America, but
Speaker 9:  I cannot, and I will not remember your names and I refuse to get better at
Speaker 9:  it, but just like, imagine what you need to solve for that problem. You need
Speaker 9:  to build a worldwide facial recognition
Speaker 9:  database that seems bad. Like I'm
Speaker 9:  just going to keep introducing myself to you. Like that's a bad, that's a
Speaker 9:  preferable outcome. So like, I think AR is really interesting, but that sack
Speaker 9:  of problems from like the battery won't last very long too, everyone lives
Speaker 9:  in a different dystopian. Hellscape in the same, like that sweet.
Speaker 9:  Let's calm down, let's breathe. But I do think AR and
Speaker 9:  VR to me are still the most interesting.
Speaker 20:  Hello gents, real quick. Any comments or where does danger
Speaker 20:  fit into this whole narrative?
Speaker 8:  Yeah. I mean, they're, they're here, they're around. And I think the one
Speaker 8:  could make a very similar documentary about, about danger and about the
Speaker 8:  sidekick and similar set
Speaker 8:  of, but I think
Speaker 8:  that their influence, like it went into
Speaker 8:  Android, but a little bit more indirectly, Larry and Sergei were big psychic
Speaker 8:  fans. So like there's, there's an influence line there, but I don't
Speaker 8:  think that there's as like, I don't know, frankly, as tragic a story of like
Speaker 8:  yep. Almost had it.
Speaker 20:  The reason I bring them up is because they had the carrier relationship.
Speaker 20:  And so it's, to me, it's very interesting. Right. They had that with T-Mobile
Speaker 20:  like there was an interesting opportunity. They got it
Speaker 20:  to
Speaker 8:  Yeah. Having the carrier relationship doesn't mean you win Blackberry had
Speaker 8:  to carry a relationship.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. Plus I remember Timo was very small or carriers, not all the same
Speaker 9:  size. So being the cool partner on the smallest carrier, doesn't make you
Speaker 9:  win.
Speaker 21:  Thanks guys. So, you know, the documentary obviously did not
Speaker 21:  realize this like many people here did make
Speaker 21:  me realize though it seems very similar to the wearables market, right?
Speaker 21:  The whole Kickstarter pebble right market. They
Speaker 21:  pioneered a lot of pebble fans.
Speaker 9:  There's somebody here wearing a pebble. Do we have like a windows phone pebble
Speaker 9:  combo and the audience?
Speaker 21:  I guess my question is, do you see some parallels in how the wearables market
Speaker 21:  is sort of, you know, last 10 years, example of this happening to that
Speaker 21:  market pebble gets acquired and they're, you know, killed by Fitbit basically.
Speaker 8:  So in this metaphor, the wearables are the smartphones and the carriers are
Speaker 8:  the people that own the smartphone platforms. Yep.
Speaker 9:  Like if, imagine that you could get a notification on a watch that isn't
Speaker 9:  an iPhone, which you cannot, you can get notifications. You can't do, they're
Speaker 9:  not smart. Right? You can't just like reply to them. That is a feature limitation
Speaker 9:  of the platform that prevents a competitor from keep competing with the apple
Speaker 9:  watch. Like there it is. If you could get a notification and actually reply
Speaker 9:  to it on the phone, I guarantee you, some people will pick not an apple watch
Speaker 9:  to use with their iPhones, but like they're the carrier dealer has written
Speaker 9:  an excellent editorial about this actually. And he was like, should I pitch
Speaker 9:  it as the iPhone? Like the smartphone companies or the new carriers, something
Speaker 9:  like that. Yeah. And we decided to use the word carrier, but
Speaker 9:  when we say carrier, we say it with like malice and hatred in our
Speaker 9:  hearts.
Speaker 22:  Hi. So we talk a lot about hardware and software, where they
Speaker 22:  come from, where they go to and people make terrible
Speaker 22:  choices in buying hardware and using software all the time,
Speaker 22:  which leaves marketing, advertising, how products are positioned in the
Speaker 22:  market. And I'm just kind of curious, how do you think this story
Speaker 22:  relates in that kind of sense, whether it's the failure
Speaker 22:  of Hannah spring, the ascent of the iPhone, but like that's an important
Speaker 22:  way that markets are shaped. I feel like give me an example. I
Speaker 22:  think that you could have a terribly
Speaker 22:  designed product that maybe has a terrible user interface, terrible
Speaker 22:  software. And if it's positioned really well in the
Speaker 22:  market, if it's advertised and given some of this is comes down to
Speaker 22:  carrier deals, it comes down to money. It comes down to all of those things,
Speaker 22:  but like things that are really terrible that are like
Speaker 22:  genuinely garbage, get really popular and sell a ton of
Speaker 22:  units. And that's just due to other forces in the market.
Speaker 22:  And I look at this and given, I don't know the full history of handspring,
Speaker 22:  but like would promotion would different positioning
Speaker 22:  would any of that have shaped this differently? And given apple
Speaker 22:  knocks, marketing out of the park, every chance they get. So it was almost
Speaker 22:  a surefire bet that the iPhone would do well. But like, I just wonder
Speaker 22:  how the market, if you think the market would have shaped differently,
Speaker 8:  A cynical is that I think that it's a good product can
Speaker 8:  fail because it didn't get proper marketing, but I think bad products
Speaker 8:  will out and the best marketing does, isn't
Speaker 8:  gonna keep a bad product. Like it's not going to have longevity,
Speaker 8:  you know, you'll get one or two rounds maybe, but you're not going to, you're
Speaker 8:  not going to become like an important iconic product if it sucks. And I think
Speaker 8:  that I'm actually, I don't think marketing saves at that point,
Speaker 9:  Unless you're ruthlessly locked into its ecosystem,
Speaker 9:  but I, I am unsurprisingly more cynical than
Speaker 9:  Dieter. And it is thinking about us like a thousand
Speaker 9:  people asked me about scissor vodka yesterday. The whole joke
Speaker 9:  there is very dumb, but underlying it is like my friends. And
Speaker 9:  I realized that bid range vodka is a commodity
Speaker 9:  product. And we could just like tell jokes about marketing it. And we would
Speaker 9:  just yell vodka taglines at each other. And that's, that's the whole
Speaker 9:  joke, right? Like if you think apple makes the same
Speaker 9:  product as everyone else, but Steve jobs is a better marketer. They'll
Speaker 9:  win. I think apple makes great products. And the
Speaker 9:  marketing is a bonus cause they're really good at marketing. But
Speaker 9:  at the end of that, you get the thing home and you turn it on in either
Speaker 9:  it is horrible. And in your Android TV crashes a
Speaker 9:  lot and you have to answer to your family or it's really good. Right. And
Speaker 9:  like that is as simple as it gets. And I think with some kinds of products,
Speaker 9:  the marketing is the whole story, right? Like that is the vodka job. And
Speaker 9:  with other kinds of products, your experience and how you feel about it
Speaker 9:  instantly transcends the marketer.
Speaker 22:  So I think just a one, one super quick followup to that is had
Speaker 22:  handspring Ben positions correctly in the market had, and again,
Speaker 22:  money carrier deals, all that could handspring have
Speaker 22:  succeeded just by virtue of having better
Speaker 22:  marketing, better positioning, better, whatever that
Speaker 22:  extra something is because everything else there was in the
Speaker 22:  right place.
Speaker 8:  But I'm not, I'm not going to say that they would have. I think that they
Speaker 8:  had really good ideas. I think that they executed them pretty badly in, in
Speaker 8:  these products. Cause they just didn't have the resources. They need to execute
Speaker 8:  them well, but that's not a guarantee that
Speaker 8:  they would have made it, but they would've had a better chance than they
Speaker 8:  ended up having. So, yeah.
Speaker 9:  Cool. Thanks. We've gone over scared, but we're gonna, we're gonna take these
Speaker 9:  last two. Let's start over here.
Speaker 23:  I had a question about what you guys think between apple and Samsung, because
Speaker 23:  apple makes everything like the software, the hardware,
Speaker 23:  and Samsung gets their software from Google for free, but their
Speaker 23:  phones are priced the same. How do you guys think that they can
Speaker 23:  justify charging the same when they get a major
Speaker 23:  investment that they don't even really have to pay for?
Speaker 8:  Yeah.
Speaker 9:  Is it, is it free? Like
Speaker 9:  yeah, it's free, but Google demands, like there's a reason every Samsung
Speaker 9:  phone has a two browsers and two email clients. Like at some point the tax
Speaker 9:  they're paying is that they have to ship half of Google's
Speaker 9:  product and a half of Samsung's product. Right. And then
Speaker 9:  we are like, Samsung's product sucks and like,
Speaker 9:  okay. But if they didn't, they weren't paying that tax and they didn't know
Speaker 9:  that they're going to release the phone and then we're going to like Bixby
Speaker 9:  is a dog with shoes and then no one's going to use it. Cause everyone's because
Speaker 9:  we are going to tell everyone the Google's doing a better job. Like I think
Speaker 9:  that tax, it might not be monetary. And I understand what you're saying,
Speaker 9:  that they charge the price of the phones the same. And that is like a whole,
Speaker 9:  like the hardware is still expensive, right? There's a reason Samsung has
Speaker 9:  a head on hardware features all the time. Maybe they're reinvesting that
Speaker 9:  money somewhere else. But I think there's a, there's a very
Speaker 9:  practical effect of the tax, which is that they've had to
Speaker 9:  compromise what might have been their user experience to a seed to
Speaker 9:  Google.
Speaker 8:  And I, I guess I would also add don't shed a tear for apple having to invest
Speaker 8:  in software development because they make more profits than anybody like
Speaker 8:  they're doing fine.
Speaker 9:  They're doing fine. Last one, mate, you had a lot of pressure on you.
Speaker 24:  Okay. Hi. I was wondering what you think of the
Speaker 24:  viability of Linux based phones. Yeah,
Speaker 24:  that's my question. Yeah.
Speaker 9:  It's like a perfect ender.
Speaker 8:  Th it has been tried. I think that even
Speaker 8:  Google was fuchsia maybe is thinking Linux isn't the best
Speaker 8:  Colonel. I mean, it's, it's not a question of the viability of
Speaker 8:  Linux as a technology and is it appropriate for a smartphone? Like there's,
Speaker 8:  there's lots of fascinating conversations to have there. And many of you
Speaker 8:  would be able to like beat me at that conversation really quickly.
Speaker 8:  It's a question of, can there be a third smartphone platform right now?
Speaker 8:  And that seems dubious that that's going to take a minute
Speaker 8:  if
Speaker 9:  Right. There's two parties involved. There's carriers
Speaker 9:  who will not allow anything good to happen. Can you tell, I feel if you're
Speaker 9:  a carrier partner and you're in the audience, please see our ad sales
Speaker 9:  people, they would love to talk to you. And then
Speaker 9:  there's customers like, are you going to buy a Linux phone that doesn't have
Speaker 9:  an Instagram app? Well, actually, maybe now you would some other good app
Speaker 9:  Snapchat. They're great. Thanks Rian station,
Speaker 9:  right? Like that, those developers aren't incentivized to build those
Speaker 9:  applications and bring up a new platform and say, well, not have all the
Speaker 9:  capabilities of the current mature platforms too. So between the
Speaker 9:  carriers and then knowing that you will not be able to
Speaker 9:  deliver any kind of tangible value except for freedom,
Speaker 9:  which is great. I like it. But I also just like, ha I like having a useful
Speaker 9:  phone. I think that just makes that investment very difficult to justify
Speaker 8:  We not in the duopoly down one more round of applause to the video team.
Speaker 9:
Speaker 9:  that's it. We didn't actually plan an ending. So no,
Speaker 9:  but thank you all for coming. I want to actually just say thank you to
Speaker 9:  Dieter. You might've noticed a weird theme of our
Speaker 9:  10 year birthday is like fragility. And we just did an entire documentary
Speaker 9:  about fragility and the verge was once very fragile. I think I
Speaker 9:  said this to almost everybody. You talk to me over the course past two
Speaker 9:  days, they're like, what did you learn in the past 10 years? And like, I
Speaker 9:  wish I had a time machine, so I could go back 10 years in time and tell myself
Speaker 9:  it was going to be okay. I really do like Dieter and I
Speaker 9:  at the very beginning, spent nights in the bar by my house.
Speaker 9:  This is Bosky is RP. It's closed, like literally in tears. Cause at the beginning
Speaker 9:  of this was so hard and it wasn't going to work and we were working too hard
Speaker 9:  and now it's here and we have a great video team. We have all these people
Speaker 9:  will work with us and all of you care for us. We do not take it for
Speaker 9:  granted. And Deidre is my brother. And I don't think I would have been able
Speaker 9:  to do with it. I
Speaker 9:  can't.
Speaker 8:  Thank you so
Speaker 8:  much.
Speaker 3:  Okay. My thanks to Nila for the chat to everybody who came to our ten-year
Speaker 3:  event. And of course, to the people who spoke with me in the documentary,
Speaker 3:  Donna Dubinsky, ed collagen, Jeff Hawkins, Peter Skillman and Rob hi
Speaker 3:  Tawny. And of course a huge thanks to the entire verge
Speaker 3:  video team for all the hard work they've put into making an excellent
Speaker 3:  documentary. We'll be back on Friday with the Vergecast chat show. And then
Speaker 3:  we're going to have one more topic specific episode next Tuesday,
Speaker 3:  when as promised, we're going to dig into the new smart home standard
Speaker 3:  that's called the matter this week's Vergecast is
Speaker 3:  produced by me, Andrew Marino and Liam James, if you want to hear more special
Speaker 3:  episodes like this, or if you have any other feedback about the Vergecast,
Speaker 3:  I am backlog on Twitter and my email remains very easy to
Speaker 3:  guess. dieter@theverge.com. Thanks so much for listening and we'll chat again.
Speaker 3:  Soon.