# Transcript
ID: 1b5544f0-d056-11eb-9954-05b0420ed050
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Google adds RCS encryption to Messages / Congress gearing up to fight big tech / Windows 11 leaks
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/1336462472/3891828128/s93290-US-4957s-1624030021.mp3
Description: Nilay Patel and Dieter Bohn talk to Verge senior editor Tom Warren about leaks of Microsoft's Windows 11 UI and announcements from E3 2021.
Verge politics reporter Makena Kelly explains how Republicans and Democrats are gearing up to fight tech monopolies.
Verge managing editor Alex Cranz joins the show to talk about Google's updates to Messages and a bunch of gadget news from this week.
Speaker 1:  This week on the verge cast, Tom Warren joins us talk all about the windows
Speaker 1:  11 leaks. What happened with Microsoft at  then McKenna Kelly
Speaker 1:  joins talking about all the antitrust action going on at tech companies right
Speaker 1:  now, then Alex Cranz joins the show. You talk about Google and a bunch of
Speaker 1:  gadgets that came out. That's coming up on the right chest. Now
Speaker 2:  Support for this episode comes from Octa. The leading
Speaker 2:  independent identity solution Octa provides best
Speaker 2:  in class authorization. So your customers and workforce can safely
Speaker 2:  access what they need from anywhere they're dedicated to building
Speaker 2:  the most reliable, neutral identity platform, because it means
Speaker 2:  protecting more than a login identity is protecting people,
Speaker 2:  their ideas, their work, their brilliance. It's protecting your
Speaker 2:  future with confidence. Learn more at okay. T
Speaker 2:  a.com support
Speaker 3:  For this episode comes from high sets. Let's get real buying a
Speaker 3:  TV. Shouldn't require learning a foreign language, but most TV companies
Speaker 3:  love to talk in confusing jargon, making overhyped and overpriced
Speaker 3:  promises. High sense gives it to you straight. That's why all we're going
Speaker 3:  to tell you about their new ULE D series is that it's got all the premium
Speaker 3:  features. You want a TV in a wide range of sizes to suit any room,
Speaker 3:  forget the jargon and get real. Get high sets, learn
Speaker 3:  more@highsense.com.
Speaker 1:  Hello and welcome to the roast cast. The flagship podcast of the
Speaker 1:  next generation of windows. The problem with that is that
Speaker 1:  sounds too much like how Microsoft would do its own
Speaker 1:  branded content. Anyways, what I got today, I'm Neil. I'm your friend Dieter
Speaker 1:  bonus here,
Speaker 2:  The Excel sheet embedded in the word document embedded in your Microsoft
Speaker 2:  teams. Chat.
Speaker 1:  If you're all fluid Dieter, Tom Warren is here.
Speaker 4:  Hello. I am here to give you all the latest and greatest song called Tana.
Speaker 1:  Oh man, it's a real winner of a show from the jump. And yet we've got an
Speaker 1:  all star lineup say, Tom's going to talk about windows and
Speaker 1:   and what's going on. X-Box with us mechanic. Kelly is going to
Speaker 1:  join what you're talking about. All the anti-trust stuff that's going on.
Speaker 1:  There's a lot of anti-trust stuff this week. And then Alex Cranz is going
Speaker 1:  to join us for the third segment to show and maybe go through all the other
Speaker 1:  gadget news that's going on. So a lot going on in the verge cast this week,
Speaker 1:  I want to start where we start with COVID is always one of the biggest stories
Speaker 1:  in the world. Lots of strange COVID news. This week,
Speaker 1:  Amazon had developed a COVID 19 test for their own
Speaker 1:  employees and the heart of the pandemic. They were going to release it to
Speaker 1:  consumers. It went up on the Amazon website where you just order a test from
Speaker 1:  Amazon, which would be a big deal. Now it's gone. We assume it'll come back,
Speaker 1:  but it would have been one of those big deals in the, in the sort of the
Speaker 1:  depths of pandemic, because testing was hard as for chess
Speaker 1:  listeners. Well, no access to testing was a big deal. I
Speaker 1:  think it will continue to be a big deal is a pandemic kind of abs.
Speaker 1:  And the virus becomes more of a seasonal thing. So Amazon having
Speaker 1:  a test it's widely available consumers at big deal. We got to follow up on
Speaker 1:  where went because it's disappeared. There's now a fourth vaccine, a company
Speaker 1:  called Novavax says its vaccine is 90% effective. It's
Speaker 1:  also two shots, but can be stored at room temperature, which big deal that's
Speaker 1:  good news. And then Nicole Weitzman wrote a pretty interesting story this
Speaker 1:  week, you know, before the pandemic, big pharma was one of the most
Speaker 1:  reviled industries in America. And after
Speaker 1:  all the vaccine development emphasis there, their popularity has
Speaker 1:  really skyrocketed. Pfizer was not as
Speaker 1:  popular as it is now several years ago.
Speaker 1:  So kind of a big shift in how we think about pharma, how we think about
Speaker 1:  pharma R and D, which is going to have ripple effects. There's always the
Speaker 1:  verge science team is doing just amazing work. So check out the virtual com
Speaker 1:  slash science. We've got all that. We've got other stuff, Nicole and I actually
Speaker 1:  had a long conversation the other day about what she's gonna cover as the
Speaker 1:  vaccine is, is what she's going to cover as the virus stops,
Speaker 1:  being the central story. And the answer is, oh man, tech companies have been
Speaker 1:  doing a lot of stuff. There's actually a lot of like health techs to cover.
Speaker 1:  So we're excited about that, but check out virtual Homme slash science, the
Speaker 1:  team doing incredible work is always okay.
Speaker 1:  Speaking of health windows, I'm open
Speaker 1:  Tom. I think my favorite story of the week was like, you're like
Speaker 1:  two sentence posts of Cortana on windows 11,
Speaker 1:  insisting that windows 11 doesn't exist. It's pretty good.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, that was short. I tweeted it, but Sean delivered the verge
Speaker 4:  goods. So windows 11 has leaked. Yeah, it has
Speaker 4:  leaked. It says windows 11, which is kind of the last time I was on, we
Speaker 4:  were basically saying it was going to be winners 11, right? Yeah, no surprise
Speaker 4:  there.
Speaker 2:  What do you think Microsoft's excuse is going to be for going to
Speaker 2:  windows 11 after they said for a couple years
Speaker 2:  now that windows 10 is the last version of windows and windows as a service.
Speaker 2:  Now we're never going to change the increment, the number again, I
Speaker 4:  Think the way that they framed it, when they first launched, it was like
Speaker 4:  windows as a service, like officially in all the marketing speak. But in
Speaker 4:  like one of their developer ramp Angeles kinda went off.
Speaker 4:  buildOn was like, this is our last version. And kind of everyone ran
Speaker 4:  with that. And I think that that's obviously created the
Speaker 4:  idea that they would never would be windows 11. And to be honest, Microsoft
Speaker 4:  never really came out and said that that was wrong. But I feel like they're
Speaker 4:  probably just gonna be like, that was something that someone said
Speaker 1:  Words
Speaker 2:  Don't have, meaning there's no consequence. We never
Speaker 4:  Really said, I didn't even know if they're going to fully
Speaker 4:  address it or whatever, because yeah. Like it
Speaker 4:  involves throwing someone under the bus essentially. But yeah, I think that's,
Speaker 4:  that's the kind of gist of it from the way I see it. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  It would be nice if they're honest and they're like PC sales have exploded,
Speaker 1:  which we weren't expecting. And so we just need to like juice the numbers.
Speaker 1:  Some like, I just wish some company would just be
Speaker 1:  honest.
Speaker 4:  I mean, like from what we've seen from the leak and everything, it's that
Speaker 4:  it's basically a windows 10 X. So they, they were happy to go with 10 X as
Speaker 4:  the branding, you know, a couple of years ago before the pandemic hit, like
Speaker 4:  it was October, then they announced a 10 X and then, you know, the
Speaker 4:  pandemic began
Speaker 1:  And there's the before time, there's the pandemic. And then there's like
Speaker 1:  last week and those are the only time periods I recognize. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Everything is March. Yeah. So yeah, like that, they obviously had an
Speaker 4:  idea to go 10 X at one point and they were happy with that branding, but
Speaker 4:  they will see for, you know, what, we're going to do some extra work
Speaker 4:  unless, you know, let's push the market. The marketing folks have been
Speaker 4:  like, Hmm, we could call this 11.
Speaker 4:  And then obviously all the teaser that's been happening over the past few
Speaker 4:  weeks and stuff. So, but yeah, it, it, it leaked and it looks like it's going
Speaker 4:  to be 11.
Speaker 1:  Okay. Let's just start with start. See what I did there. Oh, that's
Speaker 1:  good. I'm a professional podcaster. Why does the start menu come up
Speaker 1:  from the middle of the screen? This is the only thing that I've seen
Speaker 1:  in the, like I watched the little video you tweeted. I like
Speaker 1:  looked at some and I'm just focused on the fact that you
Speaker 1:  push the start button it's in the middle of the school.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I think because Macko S chromo S
Speaker 4:  I think like that, that general thing, I think more broadly is that like
Speaker 4:  people using windows are using ultra winds now, bigger,
Speaker 4:  wider monitors. And so having your like start menu on the left, doesn't actually
Speaker 4:  really make sense on those sorts of panels. What I'm curious about is
Speaker 4:  whether they move it for everyone, because there is an option to shift it
Speaker 4:  back to the left select. If you install it by default, it does actually move
Speaker 4:  everything to the middle. But this is, this is a leaked early
Speaker 4:  version. So who knows if, if you already have the menu on the left and are
Speaker 4:  they going to force you into the center? I don't know. I feel like they probably
Speaker 4:  will force you into the center, but there is an option to go back. But I
Speaker 4:  think, I think it's just, it's the evolution of
Speaker 4:  like chromo S has gotten that way. Obviously Macko list
Speaker 4:  has been that way for decades. It kind of makes
Speaker 4:  sense in, in a way. And I think it's more of a decluttering of
Speaker 4:  windows as well. Like just, I think they're trying to get away from
Speaker 4:  that the moment you can pin so much stuff to your task, but it can have all
Speaker 4:  your apps there because no one really wants to touch the start menu because
Speaker 4:  it's kind of, you know, all these live tiles and it's a bit, there's a lot
Speaker 4:  going on there. Whereas I think they're trying to bring that back. Like,
Speaker 4:  no, go to the start menu. You've got your recent documents. It's actually
Speaker 4:  useful, you know, like making it a bit more of a useful tool again.
Speaker 4:  So doing that, I think it's discouraged people from pinning stuff
Speaker 4:  on, onto the dock, essentially. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  It gravitates to it being in the center. I gravitate to, they have, they've
Speaker 2:  just given up on lifestyles. They've, they've taken that out of the start
Speaker 2:  menu. Now, Liz, like they're not lifestyles anymore or they're something
Speaker 2:  else and they live somewhere else. And so now it's file
Speaker 2:  recommended files and your apps, that whole
Speaker 2:  dream of mixing your personal information and glanceable
Speaker 2:  information and starting your apps and putting all that together. It started
Speaker 2:  windows phone is like, it's officially dead and gone.
Speaker 2:  Right? No, and that's fine. Like, no one really has liked it for the past
Speaker 2:  couple of years. Design trend trains, just design trends change or whatever.
Speaker 2:  But yeah, like the start menu is just, it's very, very
Speaker 2:  chromo se. Now it's sort of Mackey like the launch thing on Mac, but
Speaker 2:  nobody ever uses that. And that's kind of bad. I don't know how, how,
Speaker 2:  if I even think of this as a start menu anymore, if I gotta be honest with
Speaker 2:  you, like, I feel like the start menu was cool. Cause it had more it's the
Speaker 2:  launcher, right? Yeah. It's a launcher. Not a start menu. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I think, yeah. And I think that's, that's, that's obviously intentional.
Speaker 4:  Like you say, like the live tiles, they were, they were super useful for
Speaker 4:  like glance information, but then people soon realized how much
Speaker 4:  clients will information do actually want. Right. It's like the weather and
Speaker 4:  the news two obvious points. But beyond that,
Speaker 4:  it's like, no I'm going into the app and like digging through, I don't really
Speaker 4:  need the glanceable information. And they've put that like, glanceable sort
Speaker 4:  of weather new stuff in the taskbar on windows 10 currently. And then in
Speaker 4:  windows 11, they're actually moving into a separate widgets panel. So,
Speaker 4:  so they've obviously, there's still some of that elements of the stuff that
Speaker 4:  they wanted to do with live tiles. It's just, they're bringing back what
Speaker 4:  they were doing with widgets in Vista instead.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. So like, but it's definitely, it's going away. It's a launch now.
Speaker 4:  I, yeah, I agree. I don't really see it as like a start menu so much
Speaker 4:  anymore. It's definitely a launches. It's a portal for like quickly getting
Speaker 4:  access to documents, getting out to search and you're in your
Speaker 4:  apps and you know, your frequent amps and stuff. So yeah.
Speaker 1:  It's like, it's so funny to me to think about the
Speaker 1:  journey Microsoft has been on with this one button in windows
Speaker 1:  and then moving it again and making sure moving it around. Like it was the
Speaker 1:  revolution for windows 95. Like this was the thing they
Speaker 1:  licensed the rolling stones song because of the start button,
Speaker 1:  because literally people had no idea what to do when they sat down at a windows
Speaker 1:  PC and they're like, here's a button it's going to have stuff in it. And
Speaker 1:  it has so far expanded. Then they got rid of it in
Speaker 1:  eight. Then they realized that was the worst idea
Speaker 1:  that they've ever had. They brought it back in this other
Speaker 1:  conception. And it's just, it's kind of just going back to where it
Speaker 1:  started in like a pretty real way. Right?
Speaker 1:  Like here's a bunch of stuff that you might want to immediately do.
Speaker 4:  Obviously removed it in a, put it back in 8.1. But like they still had the
Speaker 4:  live tiles interface and then obviously windows 10 came and
Speaker 4:  just took things way back. But like kind of still kept those lifestyles.
Speaker 4:  It was like a really weird, like they didn't fully step back, but now they're
Speaker 4:  like, Hey, we're not even fully stepping back. We're just going to kind of
Speaker 4:  get rid of the start menu sort of interface that we've been, we've had a
Speaker 4:  flake years now and then just put it back to something really simple. And
Speaker 4:  I think that that simple or like concept is, is
Speaker 4:  broadly what this is, you know, like they're trying to simplify as windows
Speaker 4:  a little bit more, which is what 10 X was supposed to be. It's supposed to
Speaker 4:  be like cleaning up windows. Right. Simplifying it and make
Speaker 4:  it run on different hardware. But I think they they've obviously seen that,
Speaker 4:  that what, why, why should we do a separate sort of product
Speaker 4:  because they've done that before and it's never worked, has it. So it's like,
Speaker 4:  let's just do this two windows, but don't go too hard. Like
Speaker 4:  where you, you know, moving everything around, but doing it
Speaker 4:  in a way that it makes sense.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I mean, God forbid that they clean up the toolbar in the,
Speaker 2:  you know, the, the file Explorer. What is the story?
Speaker 2:  And there's so much crap there.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Yeah. The rib, the ribbon is still there. File Explorer still. It's
Speaker 4:  the same. I don't know whether that's fully going to change because so a
Speaker 4:  lot of the stuff that we do see, like if you look in the system tray, it
Speaker 4:  kind of looks a bit weird with the date, like triple stack and stuff
Speaker 4:  like that. Like that will all change. Like that's, that's definitely not
Speaker 4:  what it should look like. It's just this an early build, but stuff
Speaker 4:  like the file Explorer and everything, that's going to change radically.
Speaker 1:  Let's try some out followers for us. We have this conversation about the
Speaker 1:  iPad all the time, right? Like the iPad is like fully abstracted, the
Speaker 1:  file system away from you. There's this endless debate that they've
Speaker 1:  kind of re-engaged with iOS 15, like, is this a spatial
Speaker 1:  interface or is it chronological one? Like,
Speaker 1:  do you understand the core metaphor of this computer? And
Speaker 1:  like with the iPad we talk about every time, like the answer is no, like
Speaker 1:  apple needs to do a better job file Explorer to me is the most stubborn.
Speaker 1:  No. From any computer company ever,
Speaker 1:  right. It's like it's full of the computer trying to help you in
Speaker 1:  ways that are absolutely not helpful by
Speaker 1:  exposing all of the controls to you and
Speaker 1:  minimizing just the folder structure of the PC.
Speaker 1:  Like, what I really want is like, here's the root level of the hard drive.
Speaker 1:  And here are some quick links to where I might want to go. And instead it's
Speaker 1:  like, here's some recent things. Here's every command you might ever want
Speaker 1:  to do with a file. Here's a dynamically generated list
Speaker 1:  of like things we think you use frequently. Right. And then like
Speaker 1:  what human has ever looked at this and been like, I understand how to
Speaker 1:  use this computer. And every time I opened this window, my muscle memory
Speaker 1:  will like kick in and I'll do it well. And Microsoft has like looked at that
Speaker 1:  for 10 years and been like, that's
Speaker 2:  Cool. If you, the easy access button is in file Explorer and what it
Speaker 2:  does and what its function is, please tweet at Tom Warren and let him know.
Speaker 2:  Cause I, I do not.
Speaker 4:  The, the problem is once they start changing things, that's when people are
Speaker 4:  like, no, don't do that. Like, because there is, like you say that there's
Speaker 4:  a muscle memory, you build up, we've using this. And whether it's this, the
Speaker 4:  interface that it should be or not is a different question. But it's the
Speaker 4:  interface that people get used to using. That's that's the problem.
Speaker 1:  I think this is the thing that is always paralyzed Microsoft. Right? They
Speaker 1:  are so aware of the edge cases of all of their
Speaker 1:  software. And they're like, what if we lose one word
Speaker 1:  customer? Yeah. We can never change it. And I
Speaker 1:  just like Microsoft is like, their software design is almost defined
Speaker 1:  by how afraid they are irritating. Some people.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I mean, they've described it like in the past as like crane
Speaker 4:  pizza for a billion people, right. With different toppings like that, that's
Speaker 4:  kind of it like, there's so many different ways to do stuff in windows that
Speaker 4:  then if you change one of those ways to a certain path,
Speaker 4:  like people, people get upset.
Speaker 1:  So funny. Cause like, what are they going to do? Like we live in the age
Speaker 1:  of tech monopolies, like where are those customers going to go?
Speaker 1:  Like, that's how all of the other companies handle this problem. They're
Speaker 1:  like, yeah, that sucks. No meaningful choices.
Speaker 4:  It's true. Like there is, there is no competition to windows
Speaker 4:  really. Like, I mean, Android is probably the closest thing that
Speaker 4:  looked remotely like a fret, but obviously Macko is, is you have to buy the
Speaker 4:  hardware. So yeah, that's, that's not the same sort of competition,
Speaker 4:  but yeah, like from what we've seen in leak, I don't
Speaker 4:  feel like they've gone far enough,
Speaker 4:  but then I don't want to say that because I don't know how far they're going
Speaker 4:  to go next week and show early build and that sort of stuff. But
Speaker 4:  I think still, I don't feel like it's going to go far enough to be, you know,
Speaker 4:  I think to warrant the 11. Mm. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  I mean, that's my big question and like my easy dunk and it's like,
Speaker 2:  it's a hahaha, you know, thing, but it's also, I think really telling is
Speaker 2:  you, you tweeted out that you can still go in there and find like some
Speaker 2:  windows 95 shit. Like the control panel is still lurking
Speaker 2:  underneath all this pretty exterior. Right? Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And it's like, it's definitely beyond the point where they should get rid
Speaker 4:  of the control panel now. Yeah. You can surface those settings within the
Speaker 4:  main things that, but that is literally just there for legacy and
Speaker 4:  enterprise. So it's like the same reason that internet is still exists
Speaker 4:  and windows 10 right now, even though we've had two versions of edge. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Like that is, that's literally why control panel access. So it's just
Speaker 4:  because there's a bunch of CIS admins that use a particular tool or
Speaker 4:  control panel applet that plugs into it. And it's like,
Speaker 4:  unfortunately that's a lot of their customers. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  It's just, I'm just like, what do they, in the beginning saw Linux come on
Speaker 1:  like some off, like, are you
Speaker 4:  It's like the age old debate? Isn't it. It's like, they're great at like
Speaker 4:  supporting legacy stuff across windows, exports, back compatibility and all
Speaker 4:  that sort of stuff. Like that's one of Microsoft's great is things
Speaker 4:  that you can still run like apps from windows free, free
Speaker 4:  11 on here, you know, like that's, that's kind of insane that, that you can
Speaker 4:  do that, but it's also like just their worst enemy.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 1:  I mean, it's, it's, it is very much the character of Mike. There's no way
Speaker 1:  that, that care that DNA of Microsoft will not change. Right. Like
Speaker 1:  this is what they need windows to be it, everything
Speaker 1:  everywhere. They have a security model now that
Speaker 1:  kind of demands that you keep updating windows in this way. So they have
Speaker 1:  to keep the legacy stuff going, because I mean, like we
Speaker 1:  also live in the age of ransomware attacks, right? Like there's lots of reasons
Speaker 1:  to keep going the way they're going. I just think it's a very funny
Speaker 1:  that in the age of tech monopolies, Microsoft is like, what if we lose one
Speaker 1:  customer? And it's like, I don't, there's nowhere to go.
Speaker 1:  Like, if you want to play games in your PC, what are you going to do? If
Speaker 1:  you're mad at a setting as well? Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Like they dominate that they dominate it, but they don't like they dominate
Speaker 4:  gaming, but they don't really control it. This is totally out of their hands.
Speaker 4:  You know? Like it's steam is steam that really controls it, which is, it
Speaker 4:  was just kind of crazy to think about it as well. What else are you
Speaker 1:  Seeing in 11 and what are you hoping to see?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. So like obviously the start menus is the main thing. There's a bunch
Speaker 4:  of like out of box experience stuff. So like when you're setting up a new
Speaker 4:  laptop, that's like a lot nicer called Tana is no longer screaming at you
Speaker 4:  that you
Speaker 1:  High up your PSA or anything like that.
Speaker 4:  It it's the niceties of wrap around that. Some stuff's missing
Speaker 4:  that we weren't expecting. It's like the store, obviously the store has
Speaker 4:  been a bit of a pain point really, since it's existed, to be honest
Speaker 4:  and there's rumors that that's going to be totally overhauled. We don't see
Speaker 4:  any evidence of that in this leaked version, but I'm still definitely expecting
Speaker 4:  that to be revealed next week. And with it, like whatever changes
Speaker 4:  they do to let more apps into the store. So I think that will be a pretty
Speaker 4:  significant change to windows to be. So, cause even though you can get these
Speaker 4:  like, you know, rival browsers like Chrome, you can go to the web and download
Speaker 4:  them, having them in the store just makes it a lot easier to
Speaker 4:  set up your PC and restore and stuff. So
Speaker 1:  Windows event, June 24th, we'll obviously see more.
Speaker 1:  Yep. Lots of com other Microsoft news this
Speaker 1:  week, they announced that Sasha Andela is now the company's
Speaker 1:  chairman as well as the CEO, which is, it feels like a big deal.
Speaker 1:  He's now fully in charge of Microsoft in the way that gates was, which is
Speaker 1:  kind of interesting. Like they never get this done bomber, right?
Speaker 4:  No, they went like fully independent with
Speaker 4:  what was his name? John treneman bit surname. But anyway, they had an
Speaker 4:  independent chairman, John Thompson, John Thompson that's right now they
Speaker 4:  obviously have confidence in the delegator to be sort of fully in charge
Speaker 4:  of thing, which it does show you how much influence he's had on
Speaker 4:  the company since he became CEO. And so it's just how,
Speaker 4:  how much Microsoft changed really? Like I've, I've seen it in, in both their
Speaker 4:  products and people really, I think before their accessibility work was
Speaker 4:  impressive, but it was one of those sort of backstories. Like they didn't
Speaker 4:  really make it shine, but now they have like, you know, exports, adaptive
Speaker 4:  controller. They have like all these crazy accessibility options in windows.
Speaker 4:  Like they've really pulled that to the front because of Nadella. And that's
Speaker 4:  just a small example, but like there's obviously a bigger trust within there
Speaker 4:  to put him in the, in the chairman role.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. And it's funny that when he first got that job, he did a log interview
Speaker 1:  with him where I asked him, why does Microsoft exist? And he had some like
Speaker 1:  answers, but now he's like, he figured it out. Yeah. So that's
Speaker 1:  exciting. Anyway, a windows event, June 24th, but
Speaker 1:  this week was also,  lots of news on
Speaker 1:   no switch pro, which is like what we were all expecting, which
Speaker 1:  didn't happen. But I think some of the biggest news  is around
Speaker 1:  Xbox. They announced that they're going to make their own streaming
Speaker 1:  stick. They're going to start doing an X-Box app on other
Speaker 1:  smart TV platforms. Is it still called X cloud? X cloud
Speaker 1:  is like, it's in my head they're game streaming services called X cloud.
Speaker 1:  It's not called that, but they're going to do apps on smart TVs
Speaker 1:  that should work with their controllers to let you stream Xbox
Speaker 1:  games to TVs without any hardware. And then they're going to do their own
Speaker 1:  streaming stick clearly, which will have the Xbox interface and be
Speaker 1:  designed around that. But let you do all the media stuff too. If I had to
Speaker 1:  say there's a lot of obviously exciting games, news
Speaker 1:  83, I tried. But if I had to pick the one
Speaker 1:  gigantic thing that will reshape the industry, it's Metroid
Speaker 1:  shaped the industry.
Speaker 1:  It already has, what can it do? The Xbox series X mini fridge. It's not going
Speaker 1:  to reshape the industry. It was very cool. But I just think like Microsoft
Speaker 1:  decoupling as hardware and software is kind of a huge deal.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And it's kind of been like this, this stuff has obviously been super
Speaker 4:  obvious, like Phil Spencer's sort of hinted that they were going to do streaming
Speaker 4:  devices and on the, on the TV and all that sort of stuff. But like for them
Speaker 4:  to say it, and it's built upon what they've been doing the last sort of two,
Speaker 4:  three years, really, which is like this focus of like, we don't
Speaker 4:  care about sending consoles anymore or at least that's, you know, that's
Speaker 4:  how vision and it's said as they sold
Speaker 4:  and it's like, yeah, like they've had some serious competition against Sony
Speaker 4:  and it's amazing what competition does, right. Makes you do like
Speaker 4:  innovative things and different things to your competition. So they've
Speaker 4:  definitely gone a different, completely different route to Sony. Sony is
Speaker 4:  like, we're going to say 60, $70 games. Microsoft's like, we're going to
Speaker 4:  sell your subscription and you're going to get it everywhere. And I think
Speaker 4:  we spoke about this last time I was on, it was just like a lot of people
Speaker 4:  compare it to like the Netflix of gaming and all that sort of stuff.
Speaker 4:  And to get there, you do need to be everywhere. You do need to be on
Speaker 4:  TVs. You need to have your own streaming devices. You need to, you know,
Speaker 4:  you need to cut these deals to make sure you're everywhere. And they obviously
Speaker 4:  had problems trying to get to the iPhone that way, but they will
Speaker 4:  see not going to have too many problems with TV manufacturers. They already
Speaker 4:  have a crazy relationship with Samsung. So I can imagine Samsung is gonna
Speaker 4:  have some, maybe not exclusivity, but they'll definitely be there day one.
Speaker 1:  I'm sure. You know, it's just turning about the, the point with the iPhone
Speaker 1:  is they had to figure out how to make this work in the iPhone swept browser.
Speaker 1:  And almost all of the TV platforms
Speaker 1:  are based on HTML five. So I think that worked probably like paid
Speaker 1:  dividends across the board because if you look at writing native apps for
Speaker 1:  the TV platforms, almost nobody does it a because all they're really doing
Speaker 1:  is delivering video streams. Then B you have to write a Tizen app and an
Speaker 1:  Android app and a web ALS and like nobody wants to do that. So they've all
Speaker 1:  settled on HTML five apps as a way to cut across the board.
Speaker 1:  And I'm very curious if the work they had to do to figure this out on
Speaker 1:  the iPhone and bypass the app store has paid dividends for them in the TV
Speaker 1:  market.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I'm sure it has because they didn't actually do all the work themselves.
Speaker 4:  Like they've, they've actually outsourced a lot of it to, I can't remember
Speaker 4:  the exact name of the company, but they use it, someone else's stack to sort
Speaker 4:  of bring, bring it on board. So it makes it allows them to sort of focus
Speaker 4:  on the actual service side rather than the sort of platform of getting
Speaker 4:  it there. But yeah, like I can imagine this work was ongoing before
Speaker 4:  apple said, you know, we're not going to let you on the iPhone so that they
Speaker 4:  were ready for that scenario. He obviously just came a little bit later
Speaker 4:  than when it launched an Android, but it's definitely, yeah, that's definitely
Speaker 4:  a big part of it was to go to TVs. They've, they've spoken about going to
Speaker 4:  Facebook gaming because they obviously sold off mixer
Speaker 4:  to Facebook, but we haven't heard much more about that, but that was another
Speaker 4:  sort of area where they're supposed to be lighting up it's cloud. They've
Speaker 4:  obviously gone to the web, but the idea was that, you know, you'd
Speaker 4:  have it in these streams and you bid click a button kind of similar to stadia,
Speaker 4:  right? Like where the idea was you'd be on YouTube, see a person
Speaker 4:  streaming it, click play, and be playing with them or be playing at the point
Speaker 4:  they were playing it. And I think they were supposed to be doing some stuff
Speaker 4:  at Facebook there, but we haven't heard much more about that. But that's
Speaker 4:  all part of like this broader sort of X cloud, it's not called X cloud. It's
Speaker 4:  called, what is it called? I don't
Speaker 1:  Even
Speaker 1:  series X-Box live project. Just pick
Speaker 1:  some of those words. And you got exposed
Speaker 4:  Gaming. I think it's officially called . It is way
Speaker 4:  cooler. It's so much cooler. This, the shape thing is the underlying
Speaker 4:  technology is called project X cloud. And they still keep saying that.
Speaker 1:  Okay. So I'm just going to call it AXA.
Speaker 1:  Okay. So
Speaker 2:  Like in, in three years is the idea that you will
Speaker 2:  only buy an Xbox console if you have crappy bandwidth.
Speaker 2:  Is that like the vision here? Like you'll buy it if you want the very, very,
Speaker 2:  very best graphics and you care a lot about that. Or if you have really
Speaker 2:  shitty bandwidth, otherwise, why would you bother? You should just stream
Speaker 2:  all your games.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Like I don't, I don't think that's the vision for three years now.
Speaker 4:  I think it's like, it's an add on right? It's it's like, if
Speaker 4:  you don't own an X-Box and you don't want to own one, then go for it.
Speaker 4:  If you want to play on mobile, then yeah. Go, you know, get the subscription.
Speaker 4:  It, it really it's it's to really push game pals, isn't it like
Speaker 4:  it's any sort of entry point then for the next
Speaker 1:  Three months here, you want an X-Box. He can't get one.
Speaker 1:  Well, I mean, like we are hearing the truth, the shortage is going to last
Speaker 1:  another 12, 18 months. Like there's also just
Speaker 1:  very compelling solution to the Xbox series X
Speaker 1:  problem. Yeah. Right. Which is like, you can just stream your
Speaker 1:  games. Like he ain't got a PS five or an X-Box like just sign up for game,
Speaker 1:  pass and stream a bunch of next gen games. Maybe they'll look a little
Speaker 1:  bit worse, but you're still getting next gen games.
Speaker 2:  That sounds like a really good idea for like a game streaming service that
Speaker 2:  like Google could put together. Maybe
Speaker 2:  they should think about trying to make a game streaming service with that
Speaker 2:  sort of a goo well
Speaker 1:  Announced an at and T partnership with stadia. And I was like, what are you
Speaker 1:  doing? This is a kiss of death. It's like a, like
Speaker 1:  a Dementor from Harry Potter. It's sucks. Her life force
Speaker 1:  out of yo
Speaker 2:  Wait a minute, wait a minute, wait a minute. The world has shifted. It used
Speaker 2:  to be that if you had an exclusive sprit partnership, you were doomed now
Speaker 2:  it's at and T
Speaker 1:  It's amazing. He breathes on you. Like petrified, never
Speaker 1:  compete again. Horrible. All right. Any
Speaker 1:  other  news? You want to talk about Dieter?
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I said, I tried a few times, you know, I'm excited for some of the
Speaker 2:  other games, Nintendo Scott. I wasn't really expecting a switch pro, but
Speaker 2:  whatever I thought that I don't technically was this S3, like
Speaker 2:  the, the Starfield stuff, the halo, infinite stuff. Like
Speaker 2:  all that seems pretty good. Like Starfield looks
Speaker 4:  Really good. Yeah. Like I think that the thing that Starfield
Speaker 4:  was like kind of a teaser of what's to come, that's not till like late
Speaker 4:  next year, but it looks like an interesting concept. But the thing that really
Speaker 4:  stood out for me, it was false. The tech demo of that was, was pretty.
Speaker 4:  It was pretty interesting. I think overall, like just the exports eat
Speaker 4:  free. Like they did a really good job, which I was kind of
Speaker 4:  surprised at because I think they've for the past sort of, I dunno, since
Speaker 4:  the X-Box 360, really, they've been kind of flailing free and
Speaker 4:  behind these exclusive titles that Sony has just been
Speaker 4:  constantly delivering. And I think they finally answered and be like,
Speaker 4:  okay, it's custom, whatever it was 8 billion or whatever it was for preferred
Speaker 4:  stock. So it's customer a bunch of money.
Speaker 1:  I will say that I haven't wanted to buy a series X, like right.
Speaker 1:  It's hard. So I haven't been trying very hard, but I haven't even been trying
Speaker 1:  because that has what I need. But between flight
Speaker 1:  simulator coming next month and that fours it down, I'm like, all right.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. They got some interesting stuff coming. So I think it's, it's, it's
Speaker 4:  kind of coming like just constantly every month for the
Speaker 4:  next six months. So
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Yeah. If something is cross-platform, I default to buying it on Xbox
Speaker 2:  basically after this week, because like, it there'll be a better chance that'll
Speaker 2:  be on their streaming service. It'll just be a little bit more portable.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. It's weird. Like I, I, my PS five is going to become a PS five exclusive
Speaker 2:  machine and everything else I think is going to be on X-Box.
Speaker 1:  I think Sony is very happy about that scenario. Yeah. I don't think they
Speaker 1:  care if they are totally fine with that, but you're going to become the person
Speaker 1:  playing games on an Android phone. When you get you little Android game controller,
Speaker 1:  it'd be streaming. I've already got a Kishi. It's great. I love it. All right.
Speaker 1:  We got to take a break. We're going to come back with mechanic alley and
Speaker 1:  talk about what's going on with antitrust. Thank you so much time. I'll speak
Speaker 1:  to you guys. Soon.
Speaker 1:  This episode of rush gas brought to you by E Cornell. If he wants to advance
Speaker 1:  your career without stepping out of your job, look no further than today's
Speaker 1:  sponsor E Cornell with over 120 online certificates in today's
Speaker 1:  most in demand skills, taking a program with the Cornell is a great way to
Speaker 1:  better your professional self. So he wants to further your career work on
Speaker 1:  your professional expertise and preserve the strides you've already made.
Speaker 1:  Try Equinox visit E cornell.com and use code
Speaker 1:  Vergecast for 20% off certificate programs. When you enroll
Speaker 1:  more and more of these days, we are conducting our everyday business remotely.
Speaker 1:  And while there will always be a place for doing things the old way, the
Speaker 1:  convenience that comes with online, learning changes, everything it's even
Speaker 1:  changing. The way we learn with Equinox, you can gain skills in your field
Speaker 1:  without interrupting your career. Equinox offers over 120
Speaker 1:  online certificate programs to choose from. And they're flexible. So while
Speaker 1:  you're learning about data science, project management or web design, your
Speaker 1:  career doesn't get put on hold equals 100% online classes,
Speaker 1:  feature coursework that can be done anywhere. Anytime and most certificate
Speaker 1:  programs can be completed in two to four months. And while some other online
Speaker 1:  programs might lack that personal interaction and feedback from instructors,
Speaker 1:  Equinox, doesn't sacrifice it courses are developed by Cornell university
Speaker 1:  faculty, and you'll enjoy meaningful conversations about coursework with
Speaker 1:  instructors who have a wealth of knowledge in their field. Plus you get worthwhile
Speaker 1:  discussion with peers, from industry, from all over the world. Take the next
Speaker 1:  step with a professional certificate from Cornell university, visit
Speaker 1:  cornell.com today and use code of Vergecast for 20% off
Speaker 1:  certificate programs. When you enroll
Speaker 3:  It's good real the tech world. Doesn't always like to keep it simple from
Speaker 3:  over-hyped products to constant sales pitches and endless jargon shopping
Speaker 3:  for quality electronics can be overwhelming, but it doesn't have to be
Speaker 3:  cut through the usual BS with high sense, high census, the straight talking
Speaker 3:  electronics brand that offers clarity and quality over confusion because
Speaker 3:  let's get real. The most important thing about a great TV is that it's actually
Speaker 3:  a great TV with all the features you love, like their new ULE D
Speaker 3:  series. Whether you're watching movies with the kids, enjoying a date night
Speaker 3:  or comfort, watching that show for the million time, high sense brings you
Speaker 3:  an unmatched 4k TV experience and with a range of sizes there
Speaker 3:  you led series is bringing premium products to the masses. We
Speaker 3:  can sit here and tell you all about the awesome features that come with high
Speaker 3:  sense TVs features like quantum dot color HDR, 10 plus, and Dolby
Speaker 3:  Atmos, but all you really need to know is that high sense offers
Speaker 3:  unbeatable quality at unbelievable prices. Forget the
Speaker 3:  jargon and get real to learn more, visit high sense.com
Speaker 3:  today. That's high sense.com high sense. Let's get
Speaker 3:  real.
Speaker 3:  Okay. McKenna Kelly, how are you doing? I'm doing good. It's good to be back.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. It's going to have you a lot of anti-trust news this week, including
Speaker 1:  like a secret switcher Ru from the Biden administration with Lina
Speaker 1:  Khan, which is very exciting for five minutes, a bunch of bills from the
Speaker 1:  house. Let's start with Lina Khan, who
Speaker 1:  was just appointed confirmed to the federal trade commission.
Speaker 1:  That's a big deal.
Speaker 5:  It's a really big deal. So this week she finally received a floor
Speaker 5:  vote. It was a bipartisan vote, Republicans and Democrats, not going to say
Speaker 5:  all Republicans, but enough to get her confirmed voted for her. And
Speaker 5:  that was early in the morning, about 1130 ish. And then
Speaker 5:  a couple hours later, I was watching this
Speaker 5:  hearing on smart home check and competition and Amy
Speaker 5:  Klobuchar, friend of the pod
Speaker 5:  she leaked. And she basically scooped everyone that Lena was going to
Speaker 5:  be the chairwoman of the FTC and lead the agency.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. And then there was like a mad scramble to be like, what'd she say?
Speaker 5:  Right. And it was like, she misspeak speak. And then all of a sudden Reuters
Speaker 5:  is reporting. This is confirmed. And everyone was like, oh, dang. Okay,
Speaker 5:  cool. So she took her oath of office on Tuesday, I
Speaker 5:  believe. And she is currently leading the FTC.
Speaker 1:  That's amazing. So Lena is somebody also a friend of the bod she
Speaker 1:  has been on the verge has before probably listeners know this, but quickly.
Speaker 1:  She was a law student at Columbia. She wrote a really influential
Speaker 1:  lottery paper about Amazon called Amazon's antitrust paradox,
Speaker 1:  remarkable for a law students law review article to be that influential.
Speaker 1:  She ended up advising agencies advising the
Speaker 1:  FTC. Then she was on David Sicily's
Speaker 1:  antitrust subcommittee wrote a lot of the investigation then
Speaker 1:  was nominated for that. And now she's the chair of the MTC. Like she's in
Speaker 1:  charge of overseeing mergers and acquisitions of
Speaker 1:  making sure the markets are competitive, just a real rocket ship of her
Speaker 1:  career from law school to leading the MTC. And she has not
Speaker 1:  been shy about how she perceives the power of these become
Speaker 5:  Right. It's really remarkable too. So when she was first nominated, everyone
Speaker 5:  had assumed that she was just going to be another democratic vote on the
Speaker 5:  commission. And it's still really, you know, great for, you
Speaker 5:  know, people who are critics of big tech to have someone on that on the
Speaker 5:  commission, like point, you know, just as on its own. But it, the,
Speaker 5:  the power that now she has to basically lead these
Speaker 5:  investigations on these companies. And
Speaker 5:  basically she has the power to instruct staff to do specific
Speaker 5:  rulemakings. She can do these extensive six B
Speaker 5:  studies that the FTC can't necessarily subpoena companies, but they
Speaker 5:  are able to compel these companies to reveal certain documents and
Speaker 5:  things. So it really is the Biden administration saying by
Speaker 5:  appointing her chair, that they are going to take antitrust and
Speaker 5:  tech extremely seriously over the next four years.
Speaker 1:  Why do you think they weren't clear that she was going to be the chair?
Speaker 5:  Because I don't think everyone would have voted for
Speaker 5:  her if that was the case
Speaker 5:  during her confirmation hearing in the Senate, if she got a lot
Speaker 5:  of bipartisan applause from Republicans and Democrats, right? They were both
Speaker 5:  very excited for her. And it, it makes sense because over
Speaker 5:  the past couple of years, Republicans have their gripes with big tech
Speaker 5:  Democrats have theirs and Lena, both of them, both of the
Speaker 5:  parties are really leading towards competition as a way of remediating those
Speaker 5:  concerns. And so having someone so progressive and having
Speaker 5:  someone so aggressive on this front was good for both of them.
Speaker 5:  Now, of course, the aggressive nature of this may
Speaker 5:  be more than put both parties might have won it. So it was really
Speaker 5:  interesting to see such a overwhelming bipartisan vote on Tuesday.
Speaker 5:  And I think I'm thinking specifically like the chairwoman of the
Speaker 5:  FTC before Lina Khan was Rebecca slaughter and slaughter used to work
Speaker 5:  in Schumer's office. So maybe Schumer may not have even voted for con
Speaker 5:  and then maybe some Republicans wouldn't have either.
Speaker 1:  Wow. So she's in place, the vitamin assertion, hasn't filled a
Speaker 1:  bunch of these roles, but she's in place. That's a big piece of the
Speaker 1:  puzzle. And that is connected to the five bills that were introduced in the
Speaker 1:  house. One of which would really give more resources to the FTC,
Speaker 1:  but let's go through the five, what were the five? Right?
Speaker 5:  So they basically address
Speaker 5:  everything that was uncovered in these 16 months
Speaker 5:  long investigation that the house judiciary committee had last year and the
Speaker 5:  year before it. And they vary from something that
Speaker 5:  is, you know, very bipartisan, something that I could see more
Speaker 5:  center left center, right. Folks voting for. And then also
Speaker 5:  something, some things that are a little bit more controversial, right.
Speaker 5:  But when they were introduced earlier last Friday, they
Speaker 5:  all had bipartisan co-sponsors, which was
Speaker 5:  really interesting, a Republican and a Democrat introduced
Speaker 5:  each of these bills. So we can start going through what a lot of them do.
Speaker 5:  I'm looking at it. Now you'd mentioned the one that would give it's called
Speaker 5:  a merger filing seatbelt, and basically a large tech company, for
Speaker 5:  example, or any large company would have to pay more filing fee in
Speaker 5:  order for the FTC to really investigate whether or not the acquisition or
Speaker 5:  merger as you had to competitive that has already been passed in the
Speaker 5:  Senate by part of certainly under Amy Klobuchar and Chuck
Speaker 5:  Grassley. And so that seems like a bill that could really
Speaker 5:  get bipartisan support and really make it into law over the next
Speaker 5:  four years. But then we get into other things, another less controversial.
Speaker 5:  One is one on interoperability, right? And the ability for
Speaker 5:  me and you to go to Facebook, ask for our data.
Speaker 5:  And if we don't like Facebook, we can take it and go to Google plus, right.
Speaker 5:  Something like that. I don't know the type of person who would do that,
Speaker 5:  but it makes, you know, it gets the opportunities there for folks to do
Speaker 5:  that. This is,
Speaker 2:  This is like data portability. It's not, they're going to force iMessage
Speaker 2:  and WhatsApp to talk to each other. Right.
Speaker 5:  So that I'm not entirely sure it's still a
Speaker 5:  little people are still trying to read the language and figure out
Speaker 5:  exactly what all of these do, but
Speaker 5:  let me get into the others. There's another
Speaker 5:  bill that would basically empower the justice department
Speaker 5:  and the federal trade commission to break up big tech companies and force
Speaker 5:  them to sell off parts of their business that create conflicts of
Speaker 5:  interest. So I'm thinking of Amazon carving off it's
Speaker 5:  house brands like Amazon basics or something like that. But th
Speaker 5:  th the bills go through just basically everything for
Speaker 5:  all of these individual companies.
Speaker 1:  That one to me, I think of these five bills as being kind of like a
Speaker 1:  negotiating tactic, right? If you had one big bill with all the
Speaker 1:  stuff in it, then people would latch on to the worst
Speaker 1:  parts they didn't like, and maybe you wouldn't get the easy stuff. So you
Speaker 1:  break them into five, you pass the filing fees, you
Speaker 1:  pass this data, portability interrupting that the company is already kind
Speaker 1:  of working on, right. Like not very controversial,
Speaker 1:  kind of, kind of SOPs, you know, like, okay, we're increasing the filing
Speaker 1:  fees. These are the five richest companies in the world. They're going to
Speaker 1:  be fine. Then you like move up the spectrum and you
Speaker 1:  get to the one that's like, you can't have a conflict of interest,
Speaker 1:  which just as I've read it. And I have read that
Speaker 1:  the unfortunate Twitter discourse around
Speaker 2:  It, and the
Speaker 1:  Immediate response from the tech companies and their lobbyists are like,
Speaker 1:  wait, people like this stuff like this bill might just die on the
Speaker 1:  vine, right? Like there's enough of an attack against it already where it's
Speaker 1:  like, people actually perceive AmazonBasics to be good.
Speaker 1:  The tech companies, a lobbying organization, the chamber for progress
Speaker 1:  made this incredible Twitter thread. And like, this would prevent Microsoft
Speaker 1:  from putting LinkedIn in word. And I was like, wait, hold up. Like, that's
Speaker 1:  good Redfin lock immediately. But there's this like long,
Speaker 1:  there's just like a long list of things that you might have to
Speaker 1:  sell or otherwise get rid of. Right? Like default apps on the iPhone.
Speaker 1:  Apple might have to change the way that works. And I think the second you
Speaker 1:  kind of step into the law will change the way the phone works.
Speaker 1:  The controversy will get higher and higher. And the rest of the bills, I
Speaker 1:  think had the same price.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And David, miscellany the chairman of the committee who helped with
Speaker 5:  all of these bills. It confirmed in a press conference this week that
Speaker 5:  apple iPhones would not have iMessage on them. By default, if
Speaker 5:  these bills go through, they would not have, you know, calendar or
Speaker 5:  all of the services that we're used to. You know, when you turn on the iPhone
Speaker 5:  and it has all of the apple services that we use every day, or, you
Speaker 5:  know, that also have competitors on the app store too.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. And I just, I mean, God bless him. He went hard. He
Speaker 1:  told us he would. And he did. I just don't know if that's going to be a winning
Speaker 1:  argument. And so that's when I say like, this feels like a negotiation and
Speaker 1:  they put five chips on the table. Like I wonder, you know, you've
Speaker 1:  reported, these are going to go into markup soon. They're going to change
Speaker 1:  a little bit. I'm wondering if you see, if you see these bills as
Speaker 1:  being written, such that when they get walked back, they're still
Speaker 5:  Right. So of course they had to come out swinging on something like this
Speaker 5:  after such a long investigation. And then after like
Speaker 5:  that huge hearing last year, you know, where they brought in
Speaker 5:  Jeff Bezos and mark Zuckerberg and everyone, they really had to go hard on
Speaker 5:  this. And so it's anticipated that these bills will go
Speaker 5:  to markup next week, right. That is incredibly fast.
Speaker 5:  That is ridiculous momentum for Congress on something like this,
Speaker 5:  especially something that is, that would in theory, if all these go through
Speaker 5:  enact like such radical change to the tech
Speaker 5:  industry. And of course, I mean, a lot of these bills, a
Speaker 5:  lot of these bills like introduced are just to kind of spook companies a
Speaker 5:  little bit, but I, I do see there's already come out.
Speaker 5:  People have already come out in Congress saying that these bills
Speaker 5:  support big tech companies rather than do anything
Speaker 5:  to dampen competition or help, you
Speaker 5:  know, benefit competition. And the house GOP leader
Speaker 5:  leader, McCarthy already said, like, we're not going to let these go
Speaker 5:  anywhere. So I think in order to get them through the
Speaker 5:  house and, you know, caucus leaders will either have to
Speaker 5:  rewrite some of the language, really take a step back and see how this affects
Speaker 5:  the real world, how this affects devices and users before any of them can
Speaker 5:  really move to the floor for a final vote. Okay.
Speaker 1:  We, we, we stopped it three of the five bills. What are the last two days?
Speaker 1:  Right.
Speaker 5:  So I mean like another one is just blocking companies like Facebook from
Speaker 5:  buying nascent competitors. We've talked about this all the time, like the
Speaker 5:  2012 acquisition of Instagram. So basically companies would be
Speaker 5:  forbidden from buying companies like that. And how, how do you,
Speaker 5:  you know, understand what is initially, you know, what could be a competitor,
Speaker 5:  but could be not, that's kind of up for grabs. So that's the second to last
Speaker 5:  one. And then the other one is
Speaker 5:  barring companies from giving their own surfaces preference over
Speaker 5:  rivals. So I think the classic example of that is in
Speaker 5:  Google search, Google having its own products at the top of
Speaker 5:  the page, rather than other companies like Yelp or things like
Speaker 5:  that. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  And again, I think all of those sound great, all of them are going to get
Speaker 1:  significant pushback, but your point that
Speaker 1:  you've brought up several times now, there is a pretty huge set of
Speaker 1:  Republicans and Democrats who are like, this is what we need to
Speaker 1:  do. We need to push it really hard. And I,
Speaker 1:  you know, the, the last set of
Speaker 1:  tech regulation proposals that we talked about was two 30.
Speaker 1:  We've talked about it endlessly. And we're kind of like both sides want different
Speaker 1:  things. They're just mad. And like, here's a place where they can be mad
Speaker 1:  together, but they actually have different goals here they're upset. And
Speaker 1:  it seems like their goals are aligned and they're moving forward to achieve
Speaker 1:  the same results in a way that I think the poisonous
Speaker 1:  two 30 conversation has made people think nothing will ever happen.
Speaker 5:  Right. And I think if you talk to policy, think tank people in DC, you talk
Speaker 5:  to lawmakers, you talk to Republicans and Democrats, folks are really more
Speaker 5:  aligned when it comes to antitrust because they do believe, I mean, for
Speaker 5:  Republicans, they're still mad. They're still tweeting about parlor being
Speaker 5:  kicked off the app store partners back, but they're still really mad about
Speaker 5:  it. Right? And they want to make sure that there's more competition in
Speaker 5:  the market that Facebook can't, you know, dominate everything that we can
Speaker 5:  have these more conservative entrance in the market and competition reform
Speaker 5:  helps that in theory. And then when you think about other
Speaker 5:  concerns that, you know, company Democrats have
Speaker 5:  having to do with pricing, or just like
Speaker 5:  small business concerns or all these kinds of things, they really do align
Speaker 5:  on competition is this is something where Republicans and Democrats can really
Speaker 5:  move forward together. And we saw that this week at the press conference,
Speaker 5:  it is, it was just ridiculous to see somebody like 10 bucks, the
Speaker 5:  ranking member of the house. And she trusts committee at this press conference
Speaker 5:  supporting all of these bills. After when the investigation
Speaker 5:  ended last year, he authored his own report. He did not agree with a
Speaker 5:  single thing. The Democrats came up with an offer a date third
Speaker 5:  way report. Right? So just looking at Ken
Speaker 5:  Buck's specifically in his evolution on this and his, you know, his thinking
Speaker 5:  on this changing, I think it really makes the case
Speaker 5:  that these could move forward and more Republicans could probably be swayed
Speaker 5:  to vote for these bills, kind
Speaker 1:  Of the, the wonky thing at the heart of this, and, you know,
Speaker 1:  connected to Lina Khan in her lottery
Speaker 1:  paper was the idea of the consumer welfare standard that we shouldn't look
Speaker 1:  at things unless we can prove that prices go up. These companies
Speaker 1:  all controlled prices to the cents they can make or not make
Speaker 1:  profits as they wish. So it was very difficult to use that standard.
Speaker 1:  That's not in here, right. They're not changing that. It was the thing that
Speaker 1:  Ken buck really didn't want to do. And it seems like they just set that
Speaker 1:  aside and they went with much more direct approaches to
Speaker 1:  regulating the companies, which is really interesting to me.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, definitely. And I think even some Democrats have strayed away
Speaker 5:  from, you know, changing the consumer welfare standard. I think Amy Klobuchar
Speaker 5:  was on the coder talking about it too. And I think you asked her about it
Speaker 5:  and she didn't have a very straightforward answer.
Speaker 5:  It's a very testy subject. And that's one that I see having
Speaker 5:  more problems on both parties, you know, than what was proposed in the bills
Speaker 5:  this week.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. It's just, it's, it's interesting to me is we talk about, you know,
Speaker 1:  bipartisan solutions, something like let's change. The legal
Speaker 1:  standard is like up in the clouds, right? Like
Speaker 1:  it's, well, let's change the law. And they're like, we'll try a new enforcement
Speaker 1:  way and way of thinking. And you would almost expect that to
Speaker 1:  work better than this set of bills, which is
Speaker 1:  like, I'm reaching into your iPhone and taking the calendar app
Speaker 1:  off of it. Right. Which is much as there's a much more direct
Speaker 1:  government intervention products and services. And yet
Speaker 1:  it has just been really surprising to me. That's where everyone has gone.
Speaker 1:  They're like, we're just going to reach into the products. And we're going
Speaker 1:  to D rank Google Google's own products and put Yelp at the top.
Speaker 1:  And that's what we want to have happen. So the government is going to basically
Speaker 1:  say this has to happen. Whereas at least with the consumer, it was like,
Speaker 1:  it was just so much more airy. Like we're going to change the way we
Speaker 1:  think about the market, which is like, you can
Speaker 1:  just glue any emotion you want onto that. And that's how you bring people
Speaker 1:  together. And that's just not what happened here at all.
Speaker 2:  I think deep down, every single congressional representative wants
Speaker 2:  to be a product manager. So this is what they want. You know, they, they
Speaker 2:  they've used the calendar app. They're annoyed by the button placement. They
Speaker 2:  think the round wrecks are a little bit off there. Just do it better themselves.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 1:  And none of them know how to fix content moderation. So we're going to do
Speaker 1:  to father
Speaker 1:  McKenna what's next in his, in this complicated process.
Speaker 5:  Great. So next week is the markup. And I think that is when we're
Speaker 5:  really going to hear the problems that other lawmakers have with these bills.
Speaker 5:  I mean, this organization called the internet accountability project, came
Speaker 5:  out with a list this morning of Republicans asking people to call
Speaker 5:  them and tell them to vote for these. They were like, Jim Jordan, there are
Speaker 5:  these very, you know, right. Populous leaning folks
Speaker 5:  who would rather change all this stuff through to 30. So there's some activism
Speaker 5:  building now, even within the parties to get people to vote for
Speaker 5:  these. But next week we will see all the gripes people have. We will see
Speaker 5:  amendments send to these bills to change the language. And
Speaker 5:  then hopefully in the next couple of weeks, we'll see the finalized
Speaker 5:  language. It'll get a vote out and
Speaker 5:  maybe we'll see what the Senate comes up with because Clover charts that
Speaker 5:  she was going to try and introduce companion bills to these in the Senate.
Speaker 5:  So they can have momentum on both sides of Congress. Amazing.
Speaker 1:  I really do think kind of the tech industry's response to this has been well,
Speaker 1:  nothing ever happens, but like things are going to happen. Everyone
Speaker 1:  was spooked. They all
Speaker 5:  Had these. They all had these statements and all these examples ready for
Speaker 5:  how the world was going to change with these. It's, it's an, it's an unusual
Speaker 5:  amount of momentum for something this radical from Congress, for sure.
Speaker 1:  And maybe one day it will be illegal to put LinkedIn in Microsoft word.
Speaker 1:  I was like, read that tweet. I was like, is this really the best he got?
Speaker 1:  Like, everyone's happy about that. They kind of, well, it sounds like we're
Speaker 1:  going to have you back on several times as this keeps going. Thank you for
Speaker 1:  coming on. It was great talking to you. Yeah, no, it's great to be here.
Speaker 3:  This episode is brought to you by masterworks.io. The total value of
Speaker 3:  the art market is massive. Deloitte estimates it to be
Speaker 3:  $1.7 trillion. That's trillion with a T,
Speaker 3:  but you don't have to go to a stuffy auction house to get involved. It might
Speaker 3:  be a little known asset class, but the super wealthy have been putting their
Speaker 3:  money into it for a while. Fine art. And I don't mean
Speaker 3:  buying the art itself. masterworks.io is a premier membership
Speaker 3:  platform for investing in finance. In fact, masterworks has seen contemporary
Speaker 3:  art prices beat the S and P by 174%. Since
Speaker 3:  1995, you can invest in multi-million dollar works by artists like
Speaker 3:  Banksy, Warhol, and Basquiat. It's a great way for everyday
Speaker 3:  investors to diversify into fine art without breaking the big masterworks
Speaker 3:  thinks maybe there's a reason why 86% of wealth managers recommend investing
Speaker 3:  in art. Their waitlist has exploded, but listeners to this show can hop the
Speaker 3:  line by using the code verge@masterworks.io today. See
Speaker 3:  disclaimer at masterworks.io/display.
Speaker 6:  If you picture a skinny teenager with a short dark Bob
Speaker 6:  knock knees and oh, a massive four blade kin. She
Speaker 6:  uses as a boomerang weapon. You're picturing UV from final fantasy
Speaker 6:  seven remake intergrade, where she's featured in a whole new
Speaker 6:  episode as the main character UFOs, a skilled hunter
Speaker 6:  Hinz cunning to in her FF seven episode intermission,
Speaker 6:  the rebellious Wu tight ninja infiltrates the capital city of mid
Speaker 6:  Gar and conspires with the eco terrorist group avalanche, the steal,
Speaker 6:  the ultimate materia from the Shinra electric power company. If none
Speaker 6:  of this means anything to you, you're missing out. Remake integrated
Speaker 6:  features a leap in the quality of the graphics. There's better lighting and
Speaker 6:  background environments that make the visuals oh, much better. You can switch
Speaker 6:  between graphics mode to play in 4k or performance mode for
Speaker 6:  super smooth action at 60 frames per second. And that
Speaker 6:  should make for fantastic photos by the way, with the fully customizable
Speaker 6:  photo mode, a great option for capturing photos of your
Speaker 6:  battles, to share with friends who missed the action. Final fantasy
Speaker 6:  seven remake integrate is available for P S five. If you have
Speaker 6:  the original remake on PS4, you can download a free, enhanced update
Speaker 6:  that will have the next gen visuals. FF seven episode intermission
Speaker 6:  is available as a separate purchase. Looks like this'll be a fun ride,
Speaker 6:  Alex. Cranz welcome. Hey, glad to be here.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, you're, you've been a real hit these past basket weeks. All the tweets
Speaker 1:  are coming in.
Speaker 7:  I feel so loved. Like I love getting all these tweets. Not many
Speaker 7:  people slid into my DMS to complain about
Speaker 7:  putting their, their task bars stuff on the right side of their screen though,
Speaker 7:  which was very surprising.
Speaker 1:  We really did ignite kind of a long, a long running
Speaker 1:  Twitter battle. I think we can list one person
Speaker 2:  To move their doc from the side to the bottom. I saw that if you can, if
Speaker 2:  you can improve one person's life, it's all worth it. Amazing.
Speaker 7:  I felt so good about it. It just really felt helpful.
Speaker 1:  All right. Well, no pressure. Your goal here is to improve one person's life.
Speaker 1:  Don't stress. Alright, Dieter, lots of
Speaker 1:  gadget news, lots of stuff to go through, but feel like we're just going
Speaker 1:  to spend most of this segment with you explaining to me what on
Speaker 1:  earth is going on with RCS encryption in Google?
Speaker 2:  It's actually very simple. What happened with RCS encryption
Speaker 2:  is if you use Android messages and you've got, you know, Google
Speaker 2:  providing, if you're using edited messages, basically you can get encryption
Speaker 2:  for one-to-one messages. If you're using the beta and starting this
Speaker 2:  week, they started rolling that out to a
Speaker 2:  regular people that aren't on the beta. So in the near future,
Speaker 2:  once the rollout is finished, if you are having a one-to-one RCS message,
Speaker 2:  you will be encrypted. You have the option to have those messages be end
Speaker 2:  to end encrypted. That's kind of it, they rolled it out kind of quietly,
Speaker 2:  like surprisingly quietly, like stupidly
Speaker 2:  annoying.
Speaker 1:  He in real time Hiroshi Lockheimer it's like
Speaker 1:  tweeting out. We've added RCS. We've got an encryption RCS
Speaker 1:  he's tweeting like retweeting photos of his sticky notes
Speaker 1:  from the last time he was on the verge cast. Yeah. Well it's like, oh, this
Speaker 1:  is all happening at once. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  There was a bunch of like minor Android updates that came out alongside this
Speaker 2:  emoji mashups and some other earthquake detection in more countries and whatever.
Speaker 2:  Here's my thing. I do not want to be known as the world's
Speaker 2:  foremost, RCS, Stan. I think RCS is fundamentally a
Speaker 2:  compromise
Speaker 1:  Product. I'm so sorry. He did hurt many, many problems.
Speaker 2:  I think that it's broken in so many ways.
Speaker 2:  However, I also think that we live in a fallen
Speaker 2:  universe and it's the best we're going to get
Speaker 2:  for cross-device encrypted communication that isn't
Speaker 2:  controlled by a single company, right? That's just bleak.
Speaker 2:  It's technically Google runs a bunch of stuff, but like technically RCS doesn't
Speaker 2:  need to be controlled by a single company. You know, you can have servers
Speaker 2:  run by any number of carriers. I wish that it could be more independent like
Speaker 2:  signal, but for default on device communication, that is
Speaker 2:  encrypted. RCS is the thing that will work across all devices
Speaker 2:  except I-phones within the next year. And so I am like official. I
Speaker 2:  like tweeted, like it's time apple it's time for you to support RCS.
Speaker 2:  That's actually the thing that you could do that would protect your own customer's
Speaker 2:  privacy because of an iPhone customer tries to use their default messaging
Speaker 2:  app to text an Android customer. They have less privacy than if
Speaker 2:  they had an Android phone and they were texting that Android customer. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  And so I tweeted this, not quite that vociferously. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Tim cook like it, no, it was the product
Speaker 2:  lead for Android messages, Sonata, Hari from Google. And she
Speaker 2:  said she welcomes everyone to participate in RCS. Oh, that's nice. If
Speaker 2:  you're
Speaker 1:  A high profile, Google product manager, that's as spicy as you can get.
Speaker 1:  That's it? I welcome everyone
Speaker 1:  specifically one company that I will not name, but they are
Speaker 1:  welcomed here.
Speaker 1:  All right. So that's RCS and then there's other Google messaging. This is
Speaker 1:  what I mean when I say there's, there's a lot on the list.
Speaker 2:  So if you have RCS available to you, you know that RCS is available to you
Speaker 2:  because it says that you could enable chat. Google has
Speaker 2:  another product called Google chat, which is not RCS, which is Google
Speaker 2:  chat. That's built into Google workspace
Speaker 2:  Cibele
Speaker 2:  and it is now available to everybody. So if you have a Gmail account, you
Speaker 2:  can go into settings and like flip on the new experience of all the new cool
Speaker 2:  Google workspace stuff, the smart campus chips and Google chat
Speaker 2:  conversations and Google chat rooms and Google
Speaker 2:  meet in your toolbar at the bottom, you can have all the new stuff it's available
Speaker 2:  to everybody. And that's the news. It was very difficult
Speaker 2:  for me to understand that was a news based on Google's blog post about, about
Speaker 2:  all this, but it's there and hurry. You can go turn it on.
Speaker 2:  Everything is that's, that's the whole story. There's nothing more complicated
Speaker 2:  about that. Oh, except they're going to change the names of rooms to
Speaker 2:  spaces. Don't know why they're going to evolve rooms into spaces. And they're
Speaker 2:  going to, they're going to start doing new stuff. And like spaces are going
Speaker 2:  to compete with everything from like old email list serves to
Speaker 2:  discord to slack is my understanding. Why
Speaker 1:  Don't they just make one product called G chat?
Speaker 2:  Well, there is a product called Google chat. Now finally, no G chat O
Speaker 2:  U N G chat. There was never a product called G chat. It never existed.
Speaker 1:  I know. I understand. Yeah. It's like that movie, but I
Speaker 1:  have fond memories of it. Right. It is the best. Why don't they
Speaker 1:  just make that product and put it on phones and
Speaker 1:  inside of these services and then like use their
Speaker 1:  dominance to win
Speaker 2:  Because they're afraid of antitrust even that's it? Yeah, no, I absolutely
Speaker 2:  think that's it. I think that's the whole reason they went with this weird
Speaker 2:  federated RCS thing on Android. You could, you could install, chat on your
Speaker 2:  Android phone. It'll probably be on deck. And like, what are the default
Speaker 2:  apps? It's just not the default texting experience
Speaker 1:  Doing it's antitrust or carriers. Yes. Okay.
Speaker 1:  I would offer this criticism of Google and I'm curious what you both think
Speaker 1:  of this right now. We just came out of IO and they, you know, they had their,
Speaker 1:  their usual big ideas that IO and machine learning is going to
Speaker 1:  drive a car and draw a picture and do all this stuff it's going to do. But
Speaker 1:  Google from a product perspective has been in slow motion for a long
Speaker 1:  time. Right? Like they rename a bunch of stuff. They move stuff
Speaker 1:  around. They like welcome partners. Some
Speaker 1:  partners don't show up in like, Google makes a sad, that's the true
Speaker 1:  flock to their, their ad thing. You know, their
Speaker 1:  hardware division, total slow motion. Oh, but
Speaker 1:  they got a store now and Eli in New York. Yeah. They got it. But I was like,
Speaker 1:  that's actually what made me think of this? Like they opened their first
Speaker 1:  retail store and it's like a bunch of stuff that has been out for over a
Speaker 1:  year that all fundamentally works the same as the stuff that was out the
Speaker 1:  year before it. And I was just like, is it antitrust? Is Google
Speaker 1:  just afraid of doing stuff? Because someone will yell at them. It's just
Speaker 1:  weird that they're kind of like treading water. Am I the only one who like
Speaker 1:  perceives this?
Speaker 7:  No, I think you're, you're totally right. They, they just sorta sit
Speaker 7:  there with
Speaker 1:  Just raking in cash, controlling the internet
Speaker 7:  And they control everything. But then there's all these tools that we use
Speaker 7:  that people use. And they're like, no, but don't use that or like
Speaker 7:  use it, but don't use it like the way we want you to you, you would normally
Speaker 7:  use something. We're not going to let you do that. You're you're going to
Speaker 7:  have to like work for it. And it's like, but that's antithetical to what
Speaker 7:  Google is, which is I never have to work for it. I just get it for free.
Speaker 7:  And I give you all of my data. So it's just like, they're,
Speaker 7:  they're just kinda shrugging. It feels like
Speaker 7:  just a big shrug emoji and like all of their, all of the stuff that I would
Speaker 7:  normally find very interesting and be excited about. They kind of like
Speaker 7:  it when they announce it, like every single announcement, it's just
Speaker 7:  like, sort of like, oh yeah. And we also did this and we're going to announce
Speaker 7:  it like three weeks later, it'd be really confusing about it. And
Speaker 7:  also, I didn't know, like, I didn't know, for six months that Google
Speaker 7:  Hangouts have become Google meets, like I saw the press
Speaker 7:  release and I understood it, but I didn't understand it until one
Speaker 7:  day when I was like, I can't find the app on my phone anymore.
Speaker 7:   you out
Speaker 7:  now? Well, it looks exact Sam. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  No, everything is a phased rollout. Right? So you kind of never know when
Speaker 1:  things are happening. I don't know. You pay more attention to Google than
Speaker 1:  almost anybody. I know you haven't, your status is the only person who understands
Speaker 1:  RCS, which you have, if you want it or not.
Speaker 1:  Is that perception accurate or are they just like doing a lot of things that
Speaker 1:  we don't see? I think
Speaker 2:  The perception is accurate for a bunch of their consumer stuff. I think that
Speaker 2:  one of the things that's going on with this Google workspace stuff is they
Speaker 2:  actually have started making stuff and doing stuff. And
Speaker 2:  that is feels weird. And I think it feels weird for Google to, and so they
Speaker 2:  don't know how to talk about it because when
Speaker 1:  They start making something like here's some new thing, words,
Speaker 2:  Words about the thing.
Speaker 2:  But yeah. I mean hardware, especially, I don't want to have existential
Speaker 2:  feelings about the pixel for the thousandth time right now, but I
Speaker 2:  don't know, like this is the year where they're going to have their own processor
Speaker 2:  and hopefully they'll do something with the camera and it's going to have
Speaker 2:  this wacky new design. This is the year where like they really
Speaker 2:  need, they they've got a store, a store. I think that they're getting close
Speaker 2:  to put up or shut up time for their hardware efforts. They bought Fitbit.
Speaker 2:  They're going to have a watch. The watch has got a whole new operating system
Speaker 2:  that is, you know, merged with ties in, in some way. So there's a
Speaker 2:  bunch of consumer stuff where they really need to show
Speaker 2:  that they can be directly relevant. And if they can't, they
Speaker 2:  should just like stop and let Samsung just own everything.
Speaker 2:  While I was in there for a second where they maybe they were going to try
Speaker 2:  and like Google is going to like have an ecosystem of multiple hardware vendors
Speaker 2:  making great stuff. But they got banned honor is back now, which
Speaker 2:  used to be Hawaii division or whatever, they seem fine.
Speaker 2:  But yeah, in general, I think that Google has not told a compelling
Speaker 2:  regular user story for a while now.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. You know, you said antitrust and I would actually, I would, to me,
Speaker 1:  it's the flip side of antitrust. Google makes so much
Speaker 1:  money doing exactly what it did yesterday. Did it
Speaker 1:  hasn't really had any existential pressure to figure out what it's going
Speaker 1:  to do tomorrow. Right. Right. Like they can do
Speaker 1:  nothing in print money from the advertising business.
Speaker 1:  And every time they kind of like stray away from that, like
Speaker 1:  eventually the grownups come by and they're like, no, no, no, hold on, go
Speaker 1:  back to collecting the money. Right? Like what are we doing? Why are we
Speaker 1:  spending money when we could just make money for no. And I know this is like
Speaker 1:  very reductive and I know a lot of Google people listen to this and like,
Speaker 1:  yeah, I'm being a little unfair, but where's the new stuff.
Speaker 1:  Like where's the big, the next big idea from Google that isn't an
Speaker 1:  AI demo that I just keep thinking about
Speaker 1:  two, three hours ago, they had that, we're going to take the fence out of
Speaker 1:  the photo demo and it never shipped. We haven't seen it
Speaker 1:  last year. They had Google assistant is going to make you a dry cleaning
Speaker 1:  appointment. That's sort
Speaker 2:  Of half shipping a little bit here and there. Like it happens. It
Speaker 2:  pops up in the assistant. It's just like, like Alex, you had a pop-up for
Speaker 2:  you once recently. Didn't you? I think so. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  But that's even better. But by, by that phased rollout, like, I don't know
Speaker 1:  if that's out or not. Right? Yeah. You
Speaker 7:  Can't get hyped about it because it's like, well, I'll get it four years
Speaker 7:  from now. And I will have forgotten that it was happening. You'd be like,
Speaker 7:  oh, this is a nice pleasant change of pace. You guys mentioned the
Speaker 7:  antitrust and I've put on like my little tinfoil hat. Like you've completely
Speaker 7:  like convinced me it's primary colored. Right? Like it's in Google colors,
Speaker 7:  but it's tin underneath. But like, it really
Speaker 7:  does feel like they almost don't want us
Speaker 7:  because this stuff is successful. Like as much as we all complain about,
Speaker 7:  like these rollouts are slow and boring and all this other stuff, like the
Speaker 7:  pixel phone is, is, is still, it's not Samsung, but it still
Speaker 7:  sells a lot of phones. It sells a lot more phones than a lot of other companies
Speaker 7:  we talk about.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. But that's like a low there's like Samsung. And then like,
Speaker 1:  you know, the bar, the bottom of the bar chart is just like a blend of colors
Speaker 1:  that adds up to brown or whatever. And like Google has the biggest slice
Speaker 1:  of the brown mess at the bottom of the bar chart.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I don't think they're outselling, LG and LG. It was like, this isn't
Speaker 2:  worth it anymore.
Speaker 1:  There was reports say the LG exited the smartphone business so hard that
Speaker 1:  apple is talking about selling I-phones and LGS stores in Korea. Oh my
Speaker 1:  God. That's how hard I was. She was out there like there's literally a
Speaker 1:  vacuum in the store. Would you like to fill it?
Speaker 2:  So we started the podcast talking about windows and how windows is sort of
Speaker 2:  trapped by needing to be backwards compatible even now, even still.
Speaker 2:  And Google is trapped by its size. It needs it. Android is like
Speaker 2:  the most used operating system, the planet 3 billion plus people. Right?
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Everybody uses Google. Everybody uses Chrome. Anything that
Speaker 2:  Google does as bigger repercussions. And they just get
Speaker 2:  spooked by that. And sometimes that's for good reason. But other
Speaker 2:  times it's it's I think it's maybe slowing him down.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I just think it's we just came off talking to McKenna with all these,
Speaker 1:  this antitrust action happening and you can see it in two ways. One, they
Speaker 1:  don't want to do anything cause they'll get yelled at and two, they don't
Speaker 1:  have to do anything. Cause they're already printing money is
Speaker 1:  the foremost member of the advertising duopoly on the internet.
Speaker 1:  And so like, why would you do anything if you're going to get yelled at and
Speaker 1:  it won't make you as much money as the money, you can just collect by waking
Speaker 1:  up every day and like, yep. That's why competition is good. Like
Speaker 1:  something has to break that open. Yeah. I don't know. I don't know if these
Speaker 1:  bills are going to do it, but it's just it's I don't know. Google used to
Speaker 1:  do a lot of things all the time. They used to have gigantic
Speaker 1:  ideas and then like ship them at like big scale.
Speaker 1:  And like, I don't know,
Speaker 7:  Like yeah, but they also like failed at all of them, right? Like
Speaker 7:  wave.
Speaker 2:  Yes. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  In
Speaker 1:  Platform where this week Casey wrote about how Facebook is making, making
Speaker 1:  a bunch of VR acquisitions and kind of the thesis. He was riffing off some
Speaker 1:  tweets from our own out teeth. Facebook is like buying VR
Speaker 1:  game studios. So they're going to have this commanding lead by the time this
Speaker 1:  becomes a real market. And I was like, well, yeah, but there's they have
Speaker 1:  no competition. Like who are they preventing those game studios from working
Speaker 1:  with no one, like, there's not
Speaker 1:  like it's, it's no one. And it's just funny. Cause it could have
Speaker 1:  been Google. They were like headed in that direction and they just kind of
Speaker 1:  pulled the plug. And like, I dunno, I didn't mean to get that all
Speaker 1:  is essential, like Google, but it's, it just, it was just looking at pictures
Speaker 1:  of this store. And I was like, well, I already have all this stuff.
Speaker 7:  You can go and sit in the store in one of the chairs in
Speaker 7:  place stadia, which like maybe the Internet's
Speaker 7:  really good there. Right. That's that's my only reason to think to go with
Speaker 1:  That source itself as Google fiber, then everyone would go to that store.
Speaker 7:  Yep. Yeah. I would live there. Just get like a little coffee in the background.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Okay.
Speaker 1:  All right. Dinner. There's a lot of just like little Ghazni he's going to
Speaker 1:  go through it. Yeah. I
Speaker 2:  Dunno. Like there's a bunch of stuff. I think the one that caught captured
Speaker 2:  the most attention in the verge was probably Ikea finally shipped their picture
Speaker 2:  frame
Speaker 1:  Speaker, but it's like, it's a, it's a big
Speaker 2:  Fabric thing. You can put different fabrics on the top of it. It's a flat
Speaker 2:  speaker. It seems good. I don't know. Flat speaker
Speaker 7:  If I had a home that was not a New York
Speaker 7:  apartment where I think you guys can actually see my entire apartment
Speaker 7:  from, from the camera view, I would a hundred percent get that. Like you
Speaker 7:  put that on a wall on like your second, you know, the landing for your second
Speaker 7:  floor. That'd be great.
Speaker 1:  This is my theory of, of, of this Sonos market expansion. They're just counting
Speaker 1:  and people buying bigger homes over time. Yeah. And with every home you gotta
Speaker 1:  buy one more speaker
Speaker 7:  Long to buy these speakers and have a place to put them
Speaker 1:  As a company that is just betting on the American dream. More than any other
Speaker 1:  company. It's like, everyone will buy a slightly bigger house over time.
Speaker 1:  I love them. You know, it's really interesting that center's for now. Is
Speaker 1:  it almost impossible to buy their products? Yeah. If you want to buy a Sonos
Speaker 1:  one, you're like September.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I waited almost two months for a Sonos five. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  I think a people are typing at home. They have bought a lot of the
Speaker 1:  products and then the chip shortage is like real. So it's funny that they're
Speaker 1:  like, well, you can't have the one you want picture frame
Speaker 7:  Two picture frames, stereo sound.
Speaker 1:  You can use them as surrounds or do you have a center,
Speaker 1:  a soundbar, which is amazing. I cannot wait for us to get these intestinal
Speaker 1:  mandalas plaid.
Speaker 2:  So, so I'm curious what you all think about this? I think it's great. I think
Speaker 2:  that, you know, they improved a bunch of stuff. I think that the yoke
Speaker 2:  steering wheel is the biggest misstep that I've
Speaker 2:  seen Tesla make in a hot minute. It is,
Speaker 2:  it just seems really bad. And really like when the, when the, when there
Speaker 2:  was like the center screen on the three and you're like, I don't know, I
Speaker 2:  kind of want something run right in front of the steering wheel, but eventually,
Speaker 2:  you know, I think they got away with that. I do not think they're going to
Speaker 2:  get away with this yoke steering wheel.
Speaker 7:  This feels like eighties concept, car bad.
Speaker 1:  It's the, it's a stereo from Knight rider. We should just be honest about
Speaker 1:  what this is. They watched a bunch of episodes, a night rider. And they're
Speaker 1:  like, what if kit's steering wheel was in our car? Yeah. And I,
Speaker 1:  I, I appreciate and support that method of product development. I
Speaker 1:  think they should have done the whoosh thing in the front of the car. We'll
Speaker 1:  get there. We'll get there slowly, slowly
Speaker 1:  over time they put that light
Speaker 7:  On there. I will buy it immediately. We're going,
Speaker 1:  Gonna make this car self-driving without the red Bush thing. I don't know
Speaker 1:  what it's actually called. I think it's technically called the scanner. You
Speaker 1:  remember Knight rider, like all of kit's sensor ability
Speaker 1:  was in the red thing
Speaker 2:  That went back and forth. Yeah. Yeah. That's the future
Speaker 2:  under the verge cast, are we talking about 80 TV shows that we remember?
Speaker 2:  Cause we are super old.
Speaker 1:  The same time Illumina. We had the CEO of Lumina Austin Russell he's
Speaker 1:  25. He is, makes me feel very old and
Speaker 1:  unsuccessful. See of Luminar LIDAR company. He was on decoder a few months
Speaker 1:  ago. They had an event this week in New York where they were showing off
Speaker 1:  their LIDAR tech and their self-driving stack and how to not set any audience
Speaker 1:  driving in the car. And their dream is that you will be able to identify
Speaker 1:  a self-driving car with Lumina tech because it will have like a piece of
Speaker 1:  hardware on it that isn't a big, silly spinning dome. Right. Right.
Speaker 1:  And they had some like prototypes of what this might look like on various
Speaker 1:  cars. What if it was the night rider thing you see? I'm
Speaker 1:  trying to bring all the threads together. Like
Speaker 7:  If he was a little older. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  If only Austin was a little bit older, he would know what I was talking it.
Speaker 7:  Oh my God. None on the top. We've got to put it under
Speaker 1:  The bumper. You got to make a Trans-Am. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  And yeah, this yoke thing, I think the reason they're going to get away with
Speaker 1:  it is because this car is so expensive. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Right. Like if that's fair,
Speaker 1:  What I think they're not going to get away with is a gear shift on this,
Speaker 1:  on the screen
Speaker 1:  and turn signals on the wheel. Yeah. That's very video game,
Speaker 2:  But no, but the didn't I think that they get like a pass from the national
Speaker 2:  transportation safety board.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. But I mean, Tesla gets a lot of passes for being Tesla all the time.
Speaker 1:  Like I think people are going to buy this car and be like, these buttons
Speaker 1:  are hard. And I, when I want to go in reverse, I actually just like want
Speaker 1:  to put the car in reverse. Yeah. Not have the car. Try to guess when I want
Speaker 1:  to be in reverse and maybe get it wrong. And like Tesla's
Speaker 1:  autopilot experiences suggest that it is not as
Speaker 1:  good at guessing what you want is it wants to be. And so like I just,
Speaker 1:  very few people are gonna buy a model as plaid. Some large number of people
Speaker 1:  are gonna buy a new model. S and I think that's when we're going to see.
Speaker 1:  Cause if you spend like $150,000 on a car, how much the plan costs, like
Speaker 1:  you're motivated to be like, this is good. Yeah. Does he come down? I
Speaker 1:  think it'll be, it'll be different.
Speaker 2:  I think the last thing I want to talk about is there's a bunch of BBK stuff
Speaker 2:  happening. BBK you may not know, or you may know is the like
Speaker 2:  umbrella company of a bunch of smartphone companies. So
Speaker 2:  oppo, vivo reel me one plus. So
Speaker 2:  the real me GT standby, forgot to look at it. It is
Speaker 2:  really cool looking and it's, you know, it's like maybe it could have taken
Speaker 2:  up the mantle of flagship killer from one plus APO made a rollable phone.
Speaker 2:  So like it stretches out, just rolls out
Speaker 1:  The thing it does on a screen when it rolls out is like, so chick.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. So if you're happy, you're looking at the phone, you've got like,
Speaker 1:  I don't know. I think we have a gift with like a webpage.
Speaker 2:  It looks like we're just stretching the image.
Speaker 1:  It stretches the image and then it fades out and it pops back up as normal.
Speaker 1:  And it's like, yeah, that's not what you want.
Speaker 2:  They're not going to ship it because it will only be good for a hundred thousand
Speaker 2:  cycles, a hundred thousand opens, which is enough. Oh, that's well,
Speaker 2:  they're aiming for 200,000, which is, I dunno, 50 opens a day for five
Speaker 2:  years or something. I dunno. Anyway, the last thing and the saddest thing
Speaker 2:  is one plus is apparently gonna like start working more closely
Speaker 2:  with APO or BBK or just its parent
Speaker 2:  company APO. Yeah. It's going to work more closely with APOE. One plus phones
Speaker 2:  have been like basically redesigned apple phones and vice versa. Nobody ever
Speaker 2:  wanted to admit it. And we kind of just accepted it
Speaker 2:  and thought of it in terms of like GM had a bunch of different brands and
Speaker 2:  technically at Pontiac and a Chevy were different, but you know, kind of,
Speaker 2:  they weren't, that's how I I've always felt about one plus. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  And now that's just sort of going back to the mothership a little bit.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I mean, I think we're seeing the phone market in
Speaker 1:  general consolidate and shrink. Like, it just didn't
Speaker 1:  happen the way people thought it would happen. That there'd be lots of products
Speaker 1:  and brands, different price points and segments. And so it's like natural,
Speaker 1:  this is happening, but it's also a, we, we were always like, isn't this aren't
Speaker 1:  you just part of it. And they insisted it wasn't true, but B it's like sad.
Speaker 1:  Cause it was, they were the Renegade that gots a push.
Speaker 7:  They were cool. Yeah. They were fun. And I mean, I I've maybe
Speaker 7:  one of the weird people that actually has fond memories of APO, because
Speaker 7:  like in 2006, if you wanted to watch
Speaker 7:  some anime or something you bought from China, you
Speaker 7:  needed a region free player and APO had the best
Speaker 1:  One. Oh yeah. Oh wow.
Speaker 7:  Like APO did the best region, free DVD players. So when I was
Speaker 7:  like, oh, they're getting into phones. I mean, I don't need a region free
Speaker 7:  flow.
Speaker 1:  So I totally forgot that they had dominated the region
Speaker 1:  free. I mean, what else is really saying is that she was a DVD buyer.
Speaker 7:  I had way too many like
Speaker 7:  eBay purchases. I don't know, half of which were legal.
Speaker 1:  Just great. I mean, we've just seen the FA we're assigning to
Speaker 1:  LG. Like the phone market is just, it's kind of done and people gotta find
Speaker 1:  the next big thing and slop and find the next big thing. Okay. My two
Speaker 1:  things that I want to end on one, so you can have apple and Chris Walsh
Speaker 1:  reviewed the beats studio buds, which are fascinating to me. He thinks they're
Speaker 1:  pretty good. They do not have an H one ship in them. They do
Speaker 1:  not support things like iCloud sinking between devices. Correct. And
Speaker 1:  he's theorizing is beats knows that Android has
Speaker 1:  big market for them. And they made a product that worked well with Android
Speaker 1:  phones and they didn't need all the H one stuff, which is,
Speaker 1:  I just think whatever, like apple spent all that money on beads. They bought
Speaker 1:  a streaming service, a pile of executives who no longer work there.
Speaker 1:  They completely retooled the streaming service. And they've got this
Speaker 1:  headphones company and it's still successful and throws off money that they
Speaker 1:  treat like
Speaker 1:  they do not care about beats at all. It is so funny to me,
Speaker 1:  but good on apple in this roundabout way for making
Speaker 1:  a product for Android people. It's the thing they rarely do. That was really
Speaker 1:  nice of them.
Speaker 2:  I wonder why not both though. Why is it? Does it just then become too much
Speaker 2:  of an AirPods pro killer? Like it's too close in AirPods pro feature set.
Speaker 2:  And so they needed to hold something back. I dunno. When
Speaker 1:  One company controls the entire market, then we weird synthetic decisions
Speaker 1:  about that. Like, I don't know, man, like it
Speaker 1:  just wacky. Okay. So that's one. You can either be a Krista did
Speaker 1:  like them. They seem great. And then lastly, you can sign up.
Speaker 1:  There's a webpage to sign up for dish networks, forthcoming
Speaker 1:  5g wireless service. So you will recall when T-Mobile
Speaker 1:  sprint, the Trump administration engineered this complicated
Speaker 1:  deal because they knew taking the market from four national
Speaker 1:  wireless carriers to three was bad. Every ounce of evidence in the
Speaker 1:  world says, this is bad for consumers. Once again, competition the real
Speaker 1:  theme of the rush chest. So they were like, we have to still get a fourth
Speaker 1:  one. We can't rely on sprint to not suck. So we're going to let you buy
Speaker 1:  sprint, but you got to help dish stand up a new
Speaker 1:  fourth carrier, which no one has ever believed will
Speaker 1:  happen. But today we got a webpage. Hell
Speaker 1:  yeah. That's all you can do. You can just put your email address on a webpage.
Speaker 1:  The network is called project Genesis and the
Speaker 1:  first S is a five. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  It's just a very good the website, by the way,
Speaker 2:  you have to, it's like a concert and a whole bunch of people are holding
Speaker 2:  their fists and hands in the air. And the tagline is help us
Speaker 2:  democratize wireless access and create the 5g network of the future,
Speaker 2:  which is what you're going to do by giving them your email address.
Speaker 1:  Very good. Like what does that mean? What does
Speaker 1:  democratize wireless access mean? I don't know.
Speaker 1:  I just think it's, it's very good. And also hilarious
Speaker 1:  because when we inevitably moved to 6g networks,
Speaker 1:  none of this will be valid anymore.
Speaker 7:  Jenna six Jenna's six. That's so good. Oh
Speaker 1:  My God. It's so good. Okay. So here's my theory.
Speaker 1:  My theory. So we're like, you know, the Virgin is turning 10 this year
Speaker 1:  and we're like talking a lot about rethinking and redesigning all this up.
Speaker 1:  And like a thing that constantly happens to me is our design team. As like
Speaker 1:  the one they like, and they make sure to show me a bunch of stuff. They don't
Speaker 1:  like apple executive. Did you see this Steve jobs all the time?
Speaker 1:  Like steer him towards the one they wanted by making the other ones really
Speaker 1:  bad. My theory with this is the branding consultancy had one they
Speaker 1:  really liked and they put a Shen five SIS,
Speaker 1:  right. Is like the bad one to knock out, to make it seem like they'd
Speaker 1:  explored a lot of things. And then dish network. I was like, Ooh, 5g
Speaker 1:  and had to pivot and take it seriously, which is why this website is
Speaker 1:  just, just to field for an email address.
Speaker 7:  Dish also do like the hopper and it was just like a
Speaker 7:  kangaroo.
Speaker 1:  It was a hopper and the Joey, somebody
Speaker 7:  There is just like, you know what, it's Charlie
Speaker 1:  Irrigate. He's just a whimsical man.
Speaker 1:  When I think of ruthless satellite CEO, Charlie Ergen, I'm like
Speaker 1:  Wednesday guy likes kangaroos, kangaroos, and fives. You know that
Speaker 1:  the underlying hopper story, do you remember this scene
Speaker 1:  that gave hopper the CES best of show,
Speaker 1:  but CNN is owned by CBS and
Speaker 1:  CBS was suing dish network over the hopper. And so
Speaker 1:  CBS made CNET team take away the award
Speaker 1:  over time, shifting on the hopper. And like, I don't think
Speaker 1:   still mad about that. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  But look, I hope project Jen, Jenna six goes, well,
Speaker 1:  it's going to be so good. We'll see. I, we, we were talking and I was like,
Speaker 1:  we cannot over cover the launch of a ground up wireless network in the
Speaker 1:  United States. Like it's a big deal. But the idea that it's actually going
Speaker 1:  to happen is also going to like ship people, their own towers. Now they've
Speaker 1:  got this. It's like we were, they thought we were going to wrap up.
Speaker 1:  No you did. You got 15 minutes on cotton baby.
Speaker 1:  This idea right now, cell networks run on proprietary software
Speaker 1:  stacks called radio access networks. There's a handful of suppliers. The
Speaker 1:  biggest one, which is Walway the reason they're like democratize it. American
Speaker 1:  5g, all this marketing is they're trying to build something called
Speaker 1:  open radio access networks that are interoperable. There are no suppliers
Speaker 1:  for this. The pliers they have chosen are still based in
Speaker 1:  Asia in various ways. Like they haven't actually accomplished their goal,
Speaker 1:  but they think that like Erickson, all these companies can build new kinds
Speaker 1:  of radio hardware for them they'll they operate cheaper. And then they just
Speaker 1:  keep saying, AWS will be involved in some mysterious way that they've failed
Speaker 1:  to explain. So like there's a lot going on with this
Speaker 1:  dish network, wireless idea, a lot of buzz words, just a lot of
Speaker 1:  words.
Speaker 7:  I love it. Yeah. Not even buzzwords. Just words.
Speaker 1:  Just throwing words at us in the hopes were distracted, but they're like
Speaker 1:  Amazon. And then like the regulators, like there's a fourth wireless network
Speaker 1:  and it's like, no, actually what's going to happen is T-Mobile's going to
Speaker 1:  turn off it's 3g network and a bunch of dish mobile customers are not
Speaker 1:  going to have surface. All right. That was it. That
Speaker 1:  was Vergecast. Thank you to Alex.
Speaker 1:  She pretended to care about Iran today. McKenna
Speaker 1:  and Tom, thank you both very much. That was great. We will be back
Speaker 1:  next week. There's a windows event. So lots going on next week.
Speaker 1:  Also, as McKenna said, markup on these entrust bells. I know there's a lot
Speaker 1:  of news decoder this past week,
Speaker 1:  Jamie Hyman CTO, John Deere. I would say the response to the
Speaker 1:  John Deere episode of decoder is unlike anything that I ever expected. People
Speaker 1:  really care about trackers. It turns out next week, Jack
Speaker 1:  Conti CEO of Patrion. That was like a deep
Speaker 1:  creator economy conversation. So that's coming up. You can tweet at us. I'm
Speaker 1:  at reckless. Dieter's at Baclofen. Tom is at Tom Warren.
Speaker 1:  McKenna is at Kelly McKenna. I name the backwards. Alex is
Speaker 1:  Alex H yeah, that was incredible. That's it? Rock and roll.
Speaker 1:  Snip. Snip.