# Transcript
ID: a9726970-bbe3-11eb-bc74-9b7a07d0fa13
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Google I/O announcements and iPad Pro M1 review
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/1336462472/4136819179/s93290-US-6182s-1621586137.mp3
Description: In part 1 of this week’s episode, Nilay and Dieter talk with deputy editor Dan Seifert about Google I/O and reviews for the M1 iMac and iPad Pro.
Speaker 1:  Two-part Vergecast this week here in part one, Dan Seaver is going to join
Speaker 1:  the show. We're going to do Google IO, including Andrew 12, Android where
Speaker 1:  merging the Tizen plus our M one reviews. That's the new iMac with an M
Speaker 1:  one ship, the iPad pro with an M one ship, whatever apple is doing. Lossless
Speaker 1:  music. Then we got part two coming later today, Addie Robertson and I are
Speaker 1:  going to talk about everything epic versus apple, including Tim cook on the
Speaker 1:  stand. That's the verge cast coming up now. And later.
Speaker ?:  This episode is virtuous brought to you by Okta, the leading independent
Speaker ?:  identity solution. Octa provides the best in class authorization. So your
Speaker ?:  customers and workforce can safely access what they need from anywhere they're
Speaker ?:  dedicated to building the most reliable, neutral identity platform, because
Speaker ?:  it means protecting more than a login identity is protecting people, their
Speaker ?:  ideas, their work, and their brilliance. It's protecting your future with
Speaker ?:  confidence. Learn more at okay. ta.com. This
Speaker ?:  episode is brought to you by NerdWallet, got money goals. NerdWallet's got
Speaker ?:  your back looking for a credit card with better cash back. NerdWallet's got
Speaker ?:  tons of tools and tips to help you find the cards you're looking for. Finally,
Speaker ?:  ready to buy your first home. NerdWallet has calculators to help you find
Speaker ?:  a mortgage that works for you. And if you want your money to work as hard
Speaker ?:  as you do NerdWallet Scott side-by-side comparisons to help you find the
Speaker ?:  smartest investing account, whatever your money goals may be. NerdWallet
Speaker ?:  helps you compare and find the smartest financial products for
Speaker ?:  you.
Speaker 1:  Hello and welcome to broadcast the flagship podcast of natural
Speaker 1:  language interpretation. It's very
Speaker 1:  topic. I'm your friend, Nila, Dieter brown this year. I'm
Speaker 1:  your mum. Wow. It's like talking to a paper. Airplane
Speaker 1:  Dieter. Let me tell you, Dan Seaford is here.
Speaker 1:  Hello. So here's what we're gonna do. The apple epic trial is
Speaker 1:  ongoing as we're recording in on Friday,
Speaker 1:  Tim cook is going to take the stand. So we're going to split this
Speaker 1:  episode into two parts, Dan and Dieter, and I are going to go through
Speaker 1:  Google IO, Android news, where news big,
Speaker 1:  massive where news, where ROS news. We got
Speaker 1:  reviews of the new iMac with M one ship Dieter review, the iPad
Speaker 1:  pro there's apple lawsuit. We got all the stuff. We got all kinds of stuff
Speaker 1:  talking about. Then Addie and I, after Tim cook is done on the
Speaker 1:  stand on Friday, we're going to record a bonus
Speaker 1:  episode to cover that because what is the point of talking
Speaker 1:  about the epic apple trial? If we don't talk about Tim cook on the stand
Speaker 1:  and I don't want to wait a whole week until
Speaker 2:  Next time, the real reason that that we're not doing epic right now is as
Speaker 2:  we're recording, we're doing this on Wednesday a little bit, early credit
Speaker 2:  crank fighter. He just referred to the Mac as a car, not a
Speaker 2:  truck or a bicycle, and he doesn't want to lose the entire episode to me,
Speaker 2:  just losing my mind over computer metaphors. I will
Speaker 1:  Say this Craig Federighi basically implied. The iPhone is for
Speaker 1:  babies
Speaker 2:  And using the Mac is very dangerous.
Speaker 1:  This is like a really, he was like, the Mac has an unacceptable amount of
Speaker 1:  malware. The iPhone, even an infant can use it.
Speaker 1:  We're trying to make them act like they are in the,
Speaker 1:  of what makes them act different from a phone. And Craig's answer is basically
Speaker 1:  the neck is too dangerous. It's it's real.
Speaker 1:  So that's going on now? And then Tim cook on Friday. I just didn't want
Speaker 1:  to, I didn't want to talk about it before Tim cook. And
Speaker 1:  then if we did our normal show, I didn't want to wait a week.
Speaker 1:  So Addie and I are going to do a whole trial focused episode later
Speaker 1:  on Friday. So this episode is just about IO and apple reviews,
Speaker 1:  but I want to start where we always start with, COVID a lots of COVID
Speaker 1:  news this week, actually as vaccination
Speaker 1:  ramps up, there's a lot of interest in tracking vaccination and continuing
Speaker 1:  to test and continuing to contact trace. I've got a whole story about those
Speaker 1:  tools and why people are uncomfortable using them to control the spread of
Speaker 1:  COVID. I completely understand why people are uncomfortable with digital
Speaker 1:  tracking technology, but there's a lot of conversation about how to use those
Speaker 1:  tools to the countries that they're being used in and how effective they
Speaker 1:  are. So that's a great story. I should read that COVID is running rampant
Speaker 1:  in India. It is a disaster. It is, people are
Speaker 1:  dying. People are getting sick at unacceptable rates. It has
Speaker 1:  happened in my own family that people have gotten sick and died. And there's
Speaker 1:  a lot of conversation about patent waivers and vaccine manufacturing
Speaker 1:  waivers in India. We've got a long story from a reporter in India who freelanced
Speaker 1:  with us about the Indian COVID crisis and specifically
Speaker 1:  why just like wide opening manufacturing will definitely help. It should
Speaker 1:  help. Patent waivers are important. And I think the Vita administration should
Speaker 1:  grant them, but there are, there's a laundry list of issues that created
Speaker 1:  that problem. And so we wanted to dive into that and then Nicole wrote a
Speaker 1:  great piece. And I think this is just as we go through it. And as we
Speaker 1:  get vaccinated, we come out of it. There's a lot of focus on what you as
Speaker 1:  a person should do to manage your COVID risk and like your individual
Speaker 1:  choices. And Nicole has a great piece about how focusing on what
Speaker 1:  individuals can do does not solve public health problems. And like, we've
Speaker 1:  really learned that a lot through COVID. So that's all on the site. If
Speaker 1:  you're not vaccinated, go get vaccinated. The CDC says you can ditch your
Speaker 1:  mask. Obviously that's controversial too. We've got a story about that,
Speaker 1:  but if you're not vaccine, please go get vaccinated. It would be
Speaker 1:  great to have this all over with. And that brings me to IO, which I
Speaker 1:  would note I always held on Google's campus. And if you watch the
Speaker 1:  stream, you notice people were socially distanced. They were outside and
Speaker 1:  they were wearing masks. No chances taken during this, but lots of
Speaker 1:  announcements at IO theater take, take us through
Speaker 2:  The biggest stuff is sort of the, the traditional stuff that you expect.
Speaker 2:  It's Android 12, it's a Google showing off a bunch
Speaker 2:  of futuristic AI demos.
Speaker 2:  It is, you know, that stuff, but some of the do stuff, they they've got a
Speaker 2:  big iteration of workspace. They
Speaker 2:  surprised a bunch of us by actually doing something with
Speaker 2:  where Android, where, where ROS, whatever you want to call it, I guess we're
Speaker 2:  calling it where, but it's unclear. They remembered it exists and they're
Speaker 2:  doing something with it. And then a bunch of Google photos updates to
Speaker 2:  distract you from the fact that unlimited photo storage is going away
Speaker 2:  in a little less than two weeks. Bunch of
Speaker 2:  maps updates, a big, big one, which I
Speaker 2:  imagine, I don't know. We're not probably not talking about too much, but
Speaker 2:  it's, I think it's a big deal. Google shopping is
Speaker 2:  basically now going to be attached to everything. Google makes you are
Speaker 2:  going to have Google shopping, retail things pop up
Speaker 2:  in all sorts of new places. Now like lens is going to be more directly
Speaker 2:  pointing to it, a whole bunch of other stuff. And they're also partnering
Speaker 2:  with Shopify, which, you know, I recently talked to somebody from
Speaker 2:
Speaker 1:  The president. Yes. And
Speaker 2:  Now if you are, if you're a retailer on Shopify, you can like click three
Speaker 2:  buttons and show up now on Google shop. So it's a big
Speaker 2:  shot across the bow at Amazon potentially. And it's
Speaker 2:  also, I don't know how often do we worry about
Speaker 2:  the incentives for SEO for websites? How do we worry about the
Speaker 2:  incentives that Google has for where it ranks things like, I don't know,
Speaker 2:  flights and whatever else. Now, Google has an entirely new set of
Speaker 2:  incentives for selling stuff on the internet and they're going to be attaching
Speaker 2:  it to way more of their products. So that'll be fun. So that's like the
Speaker 2:  top level overview, I think. But I think the big, big
Speaker 2:  news for us to really get into is probably Android and where,
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I want to talk about some of the AI stuff in these big ideas
Speaker 1:  around multimodal search. Well, we'll get to all of that. How could we not
Speaker 1:  spend an hour talking about Google docs, but let's start with
Speaker 1:  Android. Android 12 was in public beta. Now I think YouTube already installed
Speaker 1:  it. I did not have time yesterday. It looks very
Speaker 1:  different. So I mean, that's like the first thing Google can do.
Speaker 1:  There's a part of me that says the pixel not
Speaker 1:  selling well is actually like, it's a good thing
Speaker 1:  in some ways, because if you look at the, like the iOS user
Speaker 1:  experience or even Samsung user experience, they have such a huge install
Speaker 1:  base. They sell so many phones that radical changes to the
Speaker 1:  interface patterns. They have to do a lot of work to get you
Speaker 1:  there. Whereas Google is like, well, 10 of you have this
Speaker 1:  phone. Now it works entirely differently. And you can just
Speaker 1:  deal with it.
Speaker 3:  I mean, they've been doing that for years, right? They changed the, how you
Speaker 3:  access multitasking and stuff on the app or in the phone
Speaker 3:  three years in a row, they changed it. And then they settled down at this
Speaker 3:  time. They didn't change it, the sign, they just changed everything else.
Speaker 3:  And so it's a lot more colorful and it's bubbly and it's, I Dieter. I know
Speaker 3:  you like it. Cause you, you feel like it's a lot easier to use a lot of the
Speaker 3:  settings buttons and the dials and what have you.
Speaker 2:  So the here's the thing it's big and bubbly. We should
Speaker 2:  talk about material you while you
Speaker 2:  heavy side on that one. But like the big change, like functional
Speaker 2:  change of the design is everything is just really
Speaker 2:  big. And everything is a little bit smoother because they've optimized the
Speaker 2:  way animations work as a sub system, those fewer interrupts and they're using
Speaker 2:  the big, less offense. So battery life should be better and it's more efficient,
Speaker 2:  blah, blah, blah, blah. But everything is big. I think that's more
Speaker 2:  accessible. But if you like information density, you're probably going to
Speaker 2:  hate it. And there's a, there's a pretty even mix of responses in the
Speaker 2:  YouTube comments on Twitter, on it. Also a lot of people saying it looks
Speaker 2:  like the iPhone, which I don't understand actually very much.
Speaker 1:  How does it look like the iPhone? I don't
Speaker 2:  Know. I like control panel has big round buttons. I
Speaker 2:  guess
Speaker 1:  There's only so many shapes. Y'all I
Speaker 1:  know
Speaker 2:  You can have a square or you can have a circle and then you can do something
Speaker 2:  with the corners. Like, what do you want stars? They've got them. They've
Speaker 2:  gotten weird. Starting to got like badges. The new, the new widget system
Speaker 2:  is just like, you can have any shape you want, it looks away. I could
Speaker 2:  do. But
Speaker 2:  anyway, I'm fine with them taking up more
Speaker 2:  space and like having the buttons just be easier to hit and like
Speaker 2:  less cognitive load and be like, where's the wifi button because now it's
Speaker 2:  like twice as big and now you can just have it. So that's an interesting
Speaker 2:  idea, but I'm always interested in like new, interesting ideas
Speaker 2:  in, in UI. The big kerfuffle that I've seen is people trying
Speaker 2:  to decide if what they want the power button to do. Cause Google tried to
Speaker 2:  do a new thing with Android 11 and they've already ditched it. It used to
Speaker 2:  be that it would bring up like some power buttons and then the Google wallet
Speaker 2:  and then home controls. But now it just brings up the assistant, which is
Speaker 2:  what it does on the iPhone, which is what it does on a galaxy phone. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  So they just had to like, copy everybody else there. But it was like,
Speaker 2:  if you have a smart home stuff, it is a little bit more convenient to like
Speaker 2:  get to it from a power button. But whatever.
Speaker 1:  I mean, I think the thing for me about material, you and I thoroughly enjoyed
Speaker 1:  Mathias is presentation because it, yeah,
Speaker 1:  in many ways it was ominous. I dunno how to
Speaker 2:  Describe it any other way. Like,
Speaker 1:  Like his he's just, he's a big personality. He was wearing an insane
Speaker 1:  shirt, big, big shirt. Well, he definitely looked like he was, he had been
Speaker 1:  DM-ing with the mayor of Miami. You know what I'm saying? Like huge personality,
Speaker 1:  big floral shirt. And he kept saying things like now there is a color for
Speaker 1:  every mood and it's like, dude, why aren't you
Speaker 1:  in my brain? Like, but the operating
Speaker 2:  System, my favorite was what if instead of form following
Speaker 2:  function, form followed feeling
Speaker 1:  You think was the line. Yeah. I mean, there's just, there was all these little
Speaker 1:  lines in there that they were delivered with such
Speaker 1:  intensity that I was like, are you going to Ash feel like the
Speaker 1:  last line could have been like in now we will control your feelings.
Speaker 1:  Like just make the turn. But I look at
Speaker 1:  this, I look at the design across Google's products is this
Speaker 1:  is the whole point of material. You, it's not just Android 12. It's how the
Speaker 1:  apps are going to work. It's connected to their hardware design that they're
Speaker 1:  trying to unify all the sustetic. And it is definitely less
Speaker 1:  silly than Google used to be. It's far more
Speaker 1:  refined. It feels more careful,
Speaker 1:  right? Like there's a sense of, okay, we're actually
Speaker 1:  going to do the thing where the shapes of our hardware map to
Speaker 1:  shapes in our software design, like a very apple thing to do, but Google
Speaker 1:  hasn't really done it. And now they've got a big plan to do it. I think Dieter,
Speaker 1:  you said everything is really big. Google's confidence that it
Speaker 1:  knows what the most important information is, is like at a DNA
Speaker 1:  level across the company. I think that's what Google does. And you see how
Speaker 1:  big things are. And they're like, what you really want is a big ass clock.
Speaker 1:  So here's a big ass clock and it's a very, well-designed integrated with
Speaker 1:  everything and it kind of looks like your nest hub. And I think that's, that
Speaker 1:  is a big turn for Google. And I, I, you reacted when I said it doesn't look,
Speaker 1:  it's not as silly as Google used to be. I think it's still friendly, but
Speaker 1:  Google it's like outrageously silly.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. So what's funny about it is it's like, this is the, the
Speaker 2:  last nail in the coffin of the droid aesthetic, right? This is so far from
Speaker 2:  like even a honeycomb that Matea, Storytape worked on.
Speaker 2:  There's this whole, like, I dunno, cool computer nerd vibe, right?
Speaker 2:  Like the game revive or whatever to Andrei Tony stark back. Yeah. Tony
Speaker 2:  stark. Yeah. And like that's all gone. And so when compared
Speaker 2:  to some of the old stuff at Android, I think it's more
Speaker 2:  playful, but you're right. That it is refined in a way that oh, gee,
Speaker 2:  Google playfulness was never refined. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  I mean, that's just like not primary colors and big silly shapes.
Speaker 1:  Like I think it looks really good. I think one of the big
Speaker 1:  problems Google has is that nobody buys these phones.
Speaker 1:  So it's a, it's like an opportunity for them to experiment way
Speaker 1:  faster than anybody else can. And
Speaker 1:  like the hardware design and the app design and you know, the
Speaker 1:  Chromecast TV or the, what is the Google TV with Chromecast or whatever it's
Speaker 1:  called now, the Chromecast ultra with Google
Speaker 1:  TV, Android name, guys, search
Speaker 1:  docs, TV, good job ever. It's
Speaker 1:  called. You can see that that little piece of
Speaker 1:  hardware like connects to this aesthetic, they're building a remote app.
Speaker 1:  Like they're starting to do all the connections, but so many of
Speaker 1:  their apps and services run on other people's operating systems. So
Speaker 1:  they're disconnected from like the iOS aesthetic. They're disconnected from
Speaker 1:  the windows aesthetic. And I think the big question for Google is always,
Speaker 1:  how do you they're disconnected from the Samsung
Speaker 1:  aesthetic? So how do you, how do you like put
Speaker 1:  your, your company's interface identity into the world when it's always
Speaker 1:  sitting next to something else that is the primary UI design
Speaker 1:  of, of that hardware.
Speaker 2:  Well, and how much of this is going to get on Samsung or, you know,
Speaker 2:  Shami or whatever. They're going to encourage everybody to adopt material
Speaker 2:  you in their own, like, you know, personal, beautiful way, but is Samsung
Speaker 2:  going to do that? If Google is actually successful at getting app
Speaker 2:  developers to update their widgets? Cause I haven't done it since 2012, which,
Speaker 2:  sorry I have developers, but chances are you haven't updated your widget,
Speaker 2:  your Android widget since 2012. Well that now look weird on a Samsung phone
Speaker 2:  because it's like designed for a pixel. Like cause no one, no people are
Speaker 2:  gonna want to design to have it look good on a phone. So the only
Speaker 2:  question that really matters is what does it look like on a pixel is what
Speaker 2:  does it look like on a Samsung? Yeah. We won't know for six
Speaker 2:  months.
Speaker 1:  Well, are we expecting a new pixel at this? There were some rumors. Right?
Speaker 1:  And then they didn't do it.
Speaker 3:  I mean, they've announced the Google pixel,
Speaker 3:  like they said, Hey, we're doing this phone and you know,
Speaker 3:  a logical person might have said, oh, you've got this big event. A lot of
Speaker 3:  press is paying attention to it. Maybe you want to slip a hardware announcement
Speaker 3:  into there. They
Speaker 2:  Did not do that. Yeah. They announced the phone. If you don't recall, by
Speaker 2:  denying that it was canceled. That was how they,
Speaker 3:  There was rumors that, oh, this phone that everyone expects Google to probably
Speaker 3:  make it's not going to happen. And then Google was like, no, no, no, wait,
Speaker 3:  wait, wait, wait, we're doing it. We're releasing it in two markets. We'll
Speaker 3:  talk to you later. And then, you know, we haven't heard anything since.
Speaker 3:  So the pixel five a is still TBD. You would assume that it's going to be
Speaker 3:  soon. It's almost June. It is a different generation
Speaker 3:  than what we expect them to do with the fall, with the pixel six and the
Speaker 3:  rumor du processor and everything like that. So you would assume that it's
Speaker 3:  gotta be soon. The other piece of hardware that's long been rumored now is
Speaker 3:  new pixel buds that are called some kind of pixel buds a. So there was, are
Speaker 3:  two pieces of hardware that you maybe could have seen here didn't
Speaker 3:  happen. It was an entirely software services show.
Speaker 2:  I believe Google might have Telegraph that they want to do announce the five-day
Speaker 2:  at the usual time, which may mean that they are in fact waiting for the fall.
Speaker 2:  And so we'll have another one of these wacky situations where there's a pixel
Speaker 2:  six and a pixel five eight at the same time, which will
Speaker 2:  be exhausting. The third piece of rumored
Speaker 2:  hardware, which there's much less information about is the, the pixel
Speaker 2:  watch. But that is, we should probably get through the rest of Android before
Speaker 2:  we started having emotions about wearables.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Do was like adding little features to Android. I'm always
Speaker 1:  interested, like what makes it in the system and what
Speaker 1:  makes it into Samson's version of Android or Jeremy's or whoever. So
Speaker 1:  what are the, the system level features they've added to Android 12th,
Speaker 2:  Other than moving the stuff around, which nobody adopted, they have added
Speaker 2:  new privacy permissions. So there's a little indicator for
Speaker 2:  camera and a microphone. There is a
Speaker 2:  new approximate location thing. So instead of giving someone your pinpoint
Speaker 2:  location, you can give your neighborhood, there's a new privacy dashboard
Speaker 2:  that tells you how often your stuff has been accessed. I don't know if that'll
Speaker 2:  make it. And there is a new Android TV remote, which
Speaker 2:  may or may not make it to other phones, but it will be built in at an O S
Speaker 2:  level. And there's also buttons in quick settings to
Speaker 2:  just turn off like their switches, your camera, your microphone. I think
Speaker 2:  that's actually pretty cool. Yeah. Just the apps think they have camera
Speaker 2:  access, but they don't, which is kind of clever.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I think that's really smart. I mean, I, I like the idea that these
Speaker 1:  two companies are now racing each other for privacy features. And I really
Speaker 1:  like the we're going to let the apps think they have it. And every
Speaker 1:  time they call it, we're going to ask you again. Cause it, a lot of people
Speaker 1:  say no and forget, and then they have no idea why things are broken.
Speaker 1:  So I think this is really
Speaker 2:  The other privacy thing. I was expecting a non-answer from Google,
Speaker 2:  but they gave me, we'll tell you later this year answer, which is some kind
Speaker 2:  of app tracking for ads in the same way apple has ATT and
Speaker 2:  Chrome is doing
Speaker 1:  Flock, oh my God, privacy
Speaker 2:  Sandbox. There's going to be some answer for Android later this year, but
Speaker 2:  they don't have it today. So that's, that's something to watch out
Speaker 2:  for
Speaker 1:  Before I, oh, there was some reporting times journal, et
Speaker 1:  cetera, that Google doesn't really know how to
Speaker 1:  handle the cookies, flock tracking debate because
Speaker 1:  their entire business is selling ads. Yep.
Speaker 1:  And I think this is just a very unique dynamic for Google. They're also under
Speaker 1:  an enormous amount of antitrust pressure. So if they
Speaker 1:  do the thing, everyone wants them to do, which is turn off most tracking
Speaker 1:  and just use this first party data set. They have anti
Speaker 1:  competitively foreclosed other people from running advertising
Speaker 1:  networks in their browser and on their phone. Right. Do you think
Speaker 1:  this is a problem? You probably don't do. I think it's a problem.
Speaker 1:  I don't think it's a problem to the ad. Tech vendors think it is a
Speaker 1:  problem. They definitely think it's a problem. And they're like, get me on
Speaker 1:  the phone with Europe. We're going to shut Google down. And that is just
Speaker 1:  the weirdest situation for Google to be in. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  You know, if you're worried that Google won't be able to figure out how to
Speaker 2:  target ads to you, if they don't have third-party cookies and ad app tracking,
Speaker 2:  I'll just say to you, the thing that Casey Newton said to me, which
Speaker 2:  is they can talk to Pluto. They're going to be fine.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. They're going to figure it out. The question
Speaker 2:  Is, will they figured out for everybody else or not? And who knows? Yeah.
Speaker 2:  The last thing I guess for Android is we should talk about the Android
Speaker 2:  private compute core. Yeah. It's a
Speaker 1:  Core. Yeah, that's right. It's a real clock, not hardware,
Speaker 1:  hardware.
Speaker 2:  It is a special sandbox for running machine learning. Things that Google
Speaker 2:  thinks you will think is creepy. So it's smart chips that
Speaker 2:  analyze how you talk to give you smart replies. It's what
Speaker 2:  music is playing. And I get the impression, it's more stuff there.
Speaker 2:  Like they made this thing so they could do more machine learning stuff in
Speaker 2:  the future that they know would, you know, creep you out a little bit. So
Speaker 2:  everything in the box has no network access and apps can only communicate
Speaker 2:  via very limited API APIs. Speaking of stuff that I
Speaker 2:  expect from them in the future, they implied that that was one of the reasons
Speaker 2:  they moved the Google assistant button to the power button so that I could
Speaker 2:  do more contextually, aware stuff based on whatever screen you're on. Cause
Speaker 2:  it's easier to just hit the power button and ask about the screen that you're
Speaker 2:  looking at than it is to swipe up from the corner actually swiping
Speaker 2:  up from the corner was always a terrible idea. And I'm glad that nobody bothered
Speaker 2:  doing it except for Google because what a fiasco, that gesture was
Speaker 1:  Okay. I did it by accident a lot. And I know this
Speaker 1:  isn't you have nothing to say to me about this Twitter
Speaker 1:  feed.
Speaker 3:  I will say, you know, first beta,
Speaker 3:  very early, you can do
Speaker 3:  both. Currently you can have the power button
Speaker 3:  launch assistant. You can also do the corner gesture.
Speaker 2:  If you, if you have a power button launch assistant, Dan, how do you turn
Speaker 2:  the phone off?
Speaker 3:  Ah, that's a good question. Let's find out. All right.
Speaker 3:  I, I don't know. I'm holding the phone. It's like,
Speaker 1:  Oh no, there's gotta be. There's
Speaker 3:  Gotta be the volume thing. Nope. That's a screenshot. Nope. I know how to
Speaker 3:  use phones. Well,
Speaker 2:  It's my understanding is that you have to turn it off again. If you
Speaker 2:  want to turn the phone off, eventually, if you look closely at the screenshots
Speaker 2:  in my article, there is going to be a power menu in the bottom of the quick
Speaker 2:  settings. So there'll be like edit quick settings, go to all settings. And
Speaker 2:  then there's a tiny little power button there to go to power settings. The
Speaker 2:  Samsung way. I hate that way. It's funny. He's the power button. Well,
Speaker 2:  I liked the death grip way that that apple does, although I hit the screenshot
Speaker 2:  accidentally, but yeah.
Speaker 2:  Whatever who wants to turn their phone off anyway.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I mean, this is like, it's like kind of, you only want to turn off
Speaker 1:  when it's like crashing in most, most of these funds, like will eventually
Speaker 1:  recognize they're in some sort of death loop and just like restart themselves.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. So maybe the way is actually no buttons. Here's my Steve jobs approach
Speaker 1:  to this problem. No buttons at all. It's for
Speaker 1:  babies. It's for me actually.
Speaker 2:  Can I, can I tell you a story, Paul Moez, when
Speaker 2:  it crashed, they would, unless they knew unless they knew what it was
Speaker 2:  and that you needed to do something about it, they would just let it crash
Speaker 2:  and restart it and never tell you, including rebuilding the entire phone.
Speaker 2:  In some cases it's like they would just, they would ne they just, they chose
Speaker 2:  not to show error messages because nobody knows to do to their messages.
Speaker 2:  So they just crash in the background. But
Speaker 1:  This is like, like echo devices do this, right? Like
Speaker 1:  Amazon echo devices are like constantly restarting themselves. And no one
Speaker 1:  ever knows
Speaker 3:  That. That's also how a certain folding device that recently came into my
Speaker 3:  life behavior.
Speaker 1:  It just reboots it. But it's just like a motor is like flaps, open and shut.
Speaker 1:  It's a goodbye.
Speaker 3:  It's you close it and you open it. And it's just like,
Speaker 1:  All right. So that's Andrew 12, a bunch of stuff. We'll see. There's like
Speaker 1:  other little stuff like Google photos adding this like locked folder for
Speaker 1:  pictures. Yeah. Which is great. So
Speaker 2:  Like, yeah, if you're, if you're like taking pictures of a puppy to give
Speaker 2:  to your child. Yeah. That's what it's called. That.
Speaker 2:  That's great.
Speaker 1:  No, that's a good feature. Like I think that stuff is neat. There's other
Speaker 1:  stuff that's kind of like more, I don't know, it's less tangibly part of
Speaker 1:  Android 12, like they're updating their camera algorithms to handle dark
Speaker 1:  skin better to do it. There's stuff that's coming that will
Speaker 1:  affect in particular, the pixel experience and
Speaker 1:  hopefully spread out to the rest of Android. I think that's
Speaker 1:  great. But the real news theater, the real
Speaker 1:  news. Yeah. Samsung and Google are
Speaker 1:  bringing their smartwatch platforms together. Yeah. I put in the live blog
Speaker 1:  that there are 60 people who care about this and the tree got like, I retweeted,
Speaker 1:  somebody took a screenshot, I got 95 likes.
Speaker 1:  That was up 30%, but it was still 95
Speaker 1:  likes, but this is sort of a big
Speaker 1:  deal. Like Tyson was invented is like a hedge against
Speaker 1:  Google. Remember there was that whole, there was like a year where people
Speaker 1:  thought Samsung was split off from Google where Google was mad at launched
Speaker 1:  a couple of phones where Google was mad about
Speaker 1:  Samsung, just like skinning, Android so hard and trying to pull them back.
Speaker 1:  And now they're like, yeah, it was just emergencies operating. It's if
Speaker 1:  you old old-school Vergecast heads will know when I say this is Migo,
Speaker 1:  this is Migo. You
Speaker 2:  Actually, can you explain that? Cause like it, it takes, it's a long walk
Speaker 2:  to get to this as beco.
Speaker 1:  All right. What were the constituent operating systems? Amigo?
Speaker 2:  And there was memo memo, Nokia hadn't memo, which
Speaker 1:  Was their new smart fund platform. Intel had like
Speaker 1:  Bob Moblin
Speaker 1:  Dan, remember, as Dan did, Dan is trying to pretend it's not on the tip of
Speaker 1:  this time. Anyway, there was a
Speaker 1:  vision of a new Linux-based smartphone operating system from like
Speaker 1:  two or three companies that they jammed together to make
Speaker 1:  Maemo M a E M O and
Speaker 1:  then it still was like, not as good as iOS. And then Android shut
Speaker 1:  up. That is my understanding at the time, I
Speaker 3:  Don't know if MIMO ever made it to a shipping phone. There was
Speaker 3:  one like Intel was threatening to release a phone for years and it, it
Speaker 3:  all fell apart and they never could get their chips in order. And
Speaker 3:  Nokia became windows phone, like
Speaker 3:  yeah.
Speaker 1:  900 was a default name of Wego
Speaker 2:  They made, they made some, they made some stuff with either maybe army or
Speaker 2:  I forget Nokia and 900.
Speaker 1:  Definitely. Yeah. Okay.
Speaker 3:  I, I stand corrected. The end 900 was the memo phone. And then it
Speaker 3:  died designed
Speaker 2:  By Peter Skillman who helped design Paulo, Wes and web boss.
Speaker 1:  We're so far down this road anyway, when they announced this thing.
Speaker 1:  So I want to, I know what is actually happening, but so they
Speaker 1:  announced this thing and it brought me back to like straight
Speaker 1:  up my old head gadget playing days. Like what happens when two companies
Speaker 1:  announced a partnership to merge their operating systems? Well,
Speaker 1:  random executives you've never heard of from before show up on stage to
Speaker 1:  be like working with partner company X has been a
Speaker 1:  dream with their innovations and ability to
Speaker 1:  do fitness and our innovations and ability to make
Speaker 1:  hardware. The future is bright for smartwatch customers. And that is
Speaker 1:  exactly what happened here. It was like a 2008 CS cleanup,
Speaker 1:  so, okay.
Speaker 2:  Where O S slow, not a lot of
Speaker 2:  support, nobody's using it, whatever.
Speaker 2:  A Tizen fast, terrible non-existent app
Speaker 2:  support. That's got Samsung behind it. And so it's good. And
Speaker 2:  also by the way, Google bought Fitbit. And so Fitbit's over in the corner
Speaker 2:  and Google insisted, they didn't buy Fitbit for the software or the data.
Speaker 2:  They wanted to buy it for hardware. But there's a, that's a little bit weird
Speaker 2:  this there, because Fitbit is also part of the story. It's not two things
Speaker 2:  coming together. It's three.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. So kind of right.
Speaker 2:  Kind of. So from what I can see the basis, basically still
Speaker 2:  warehouse, I watched the IO presentation on it and like, it's very wearable
Speaker 2:  se it's not very tiny Samsung contributed screen
Speaker 2:  stuff. They contributed how to make it more battery efficient and they contributed
Speaker 2:  how to make it work with processors better. So maybe it's
Speaker 2:  like some low level merging of the two, but like you
Speaker 2:  write apps with Kotlin and a jet pack, which is the Android way to
Speaker 2:  do good fast apps. Now it's like, it's basically where with a bunch of Samsung
Speaker 2:  stuff put in, like how to make, watch faces.
Speaker 3:  Well, I had already kind of adopted a lot of the UI that Samsung had
Speaker 3:  with Tyson in later versions where RS already. So they were already kind
Speaker 3:  of on the same path in terms of like interactions. And then
Speaker 2:  Fitbit is going to be the fitness health stuff
Speaker 2:  on the watch, but apparently Google fit isn't going away, which is the
Speaker 2:  dumbest decision. Really?
Speaker 3:  Fortunately S health Samsung S health is going
Speaker 3:  away.
Speaker 2:  That one will not be there. Okay, great. Yeah, they did confirm it.
Speaker 2:   so several one is promising that there's new
Speaker 2:  stuff. Yeah. Everyone's
Speaker 2:  promising to make stuff. Samsung has said we're doing it soon. Samsung has
Speaker 2:  done making ties and watches apparently, which is great
Speaker 2:  news. All I care about is that there be a decent
Speaker 2:  smartwatch option for Android users. Like this thing is gonna, you'll
Speaker 2:  have a cellular option. It's going to work a with more cellular networks,
Speaker 2:  quote unquote. So like it's going to be supported. We are assuming Google
Speaker 2:  is going to make its own thing too. Maybe some company not called fossil.
Speaker 2:  We'll start making these watches too.
Speaker 1:  Who knows? Well, so this isn't, this is kind of the big question for me,
Speaker 1:  right? So why do you bring these two things together?
Speaker 1:  Because where, where oh, S has supported the
Speaker 1:  Android system level. So you can theoretically use it with any Android
Speaker 1:  phone, but the products are bad.
Speaker 1:  Sorry. I know some people like some of the products, but like as a sweeping
Speaker 1:  generalization, I'm comfortable saying the products are bad. Ties and
Speaker 1:  watches are slightly better, but really only work with Samsung
Speaker 1:  phones.
Speaker 3:  Well, I think the difference is, is what this is bringing together in that
Speaker 3:  I think the 90 people that are excited about it are excited because the
Speaker 3:  ties and watches, the Samsung watches generally have the best hardware in
Speaker 3:  the Android option ecosystem. They have the best battery life. They have
Speaker 3:  the best screens. They've got reliable clicky vessels to
Speaker 3:  control them. And they are noticeably faster than the was
Speaker 3:  counterparts, but they don't have, they have Bixby instead of the Google
Speaker 3:  assistant, they don't have access to any of Google services and things like
Speaker 3:  that. So if they, the dream is take Google services, stick them on a
Speaker 3:  Samsung Tizen watch, and you've got like a compelling
Speaker 3:  interesting.
Speaker 1:  I'm just like, let's take a step back from that. If you think about, if you
Speaker 1:  are fully in the big ecosystem, you know, I'm cutting this down to like
Speaker 1:  four people and please call me, I just want to talk to you for
Speaker 1:  hours. You're a full dog with shoes, right? Big speeds. Just wandering
Speaker 1:  around your house. Ties in, is great for you. And the ties and wash will
Speaker 1:  complete the experience. And you're using S health in the Samsung
Speaker 1:  email app. And like, and all that stuff kind of works for you, but you're
Speaker 1:  living a very lonely life. He has, no one else is using those
Speaker 1:  things. And that's fine. I mean, maybe you're just happy alone with
Speaker 1:  Bixby. That means like Samsung's total addressable market for their
Speaker 1:  better hardware is just like small in
Speaker 1:  Google's market is like all of Android, but the products are bad.
Speaker 3:  But, but I mean, when you think about it, what is Android? Especially in
Speaker 3:  the U S sure. What is Android, but Samsung, right? And so like
Speaker 3:  wearables, as we know them in smartwatch sense, the apple
Speaker 3:  watch the ties and watches, things like that. Those are expensive. Add-ons
Speaker 3:  that people buy with expensive phones. Low-cost
Speaker 3:  fitness trackers are a different story, but that's not what we're talking
Speaker 3:  about here. So like, this is like
Speaker 3:  Samsung sells the most Android compatible
Speaker 3:  smartwatches, right? Maybe Fitbit is up there as well, but the, where it
Speaker 3:  Wes wants just don't don't sell it all. And so like,
Speaker 3:  this is Google's opportunity here is to bring where or
Speaker 3:  where, whatever it wants to call it today, to that market of people who are
Speaker 3:  buying Samsung watches, which is a real market, it's not an apple watch market,
Speaker 3:  but it is a real market and bring those Google services and
Speaker 3:  hooks and all that stuff in to it. And then maybe the trickle on
Speaker 3:  effect is if they're not buying a Samsung phone and they have a different
Speaker 3:  Android phone, they can buy this watch. It's got Google's name on it. It's
Speaker 3:  got Google software. They don't need six helper apps. Like if, if you have
Speaker 3:  a pixel right now and pair up a Samsung watch to it, you need to download
Speaker 3:  no lessons, six apps to get every service working on it, which is just
Speaker 3:  like, kind of a wild thing. So you get a better experience on that. But really,
Speaker 3:  I think it is, Google's getting access to this larger market of people who
Speaker 3:  are actually buying these smartwatches.
Speaker 1:  But this brings me to my last kind of big question about this. You've got
Speaker 1:  Samsung making watches that work better across Android. You've got Google
Speaker 1:  making launches using this new operating system that worked
Speaker 1:  better. How much room is left,
Speaker 1:  right? Like we'll fossil compete and like show up and like
Speaker 1:  continue to make these washes. Like, I would like there to be a vibrant
Speaker 1:  ecosystem of competitive smartwatches that run on and are compatible.
Speaker 1:  It has Google services across all these phones, but
Speaker 2:  Right. I think that, that they're walking away from that. They tried that
Speaker 2:  with where ROS and it bombed LG, like couldn't make it only other
Speaker 2:  fossil brands managed to participate. You know, like
Speaker 2:  the, the thing to think about here, isn't the smartwatch market in the U
Speaker 2:  S it's like the 80% of all phones on worldwide are
Speaker 2:  Android based on Android. And their smartwatch
Speaker 2:  options are like the, like the weird low-end stuff that you
Speaker 2:  can get from, you know, OnePlus or what's the other one, like a
Speaker 2:  ma or you get a Fitbit
Speaker 2:  or you're, you know, you deal with the, of the Samsung stuff. And
Speaker 2:  so there needs to be a high-end option.
Speaker 2:  And, you know, I would love there to be a big, you know,
Speaker 2:  competing ecosystem of a bunch of different
Speaker 2:  manufacturers fighting to make the best thing. But I would
Speaker 2:  like that for phones too. I would like to have HTC and LG, you
Speaker 2:  know, still in the game, but right now it's like, it's Samsung. And then
Speaker 2:  if you are like, really nerdy, sorry, you get a OnePlus. So you look at the
Speaker 2:  market shares. What plus is just like, especially in the
Speaker 2:  U S
Speaker 2:  so
Speaker 3:  What are most interesting things with this shift is, and I don't
Speaker 3:  remember Sina and wired had some articles where they got to
Speaker 3:  talk to some of the people that were building it. And I don't remember which
Speaker 3:  one said this, but apparently watchmakers will now be able to customize the
Speaker 3:  UI. That's on top of ware, which is a huge departure from
Speaker 3:  how Android were and where ROS were, were basically Google dictated
Speaker 3:  that UI. You could not change it. You could not customize it at all. And
Speaker 3:  every single watch basically looked the same as a result. They could have
Speaker 3:  different watch faces and a couple of different apps, but DUI itself is the
Speaker 3:  same. So now Samsung, who definitely muck with it because they're
Speaker 3:  gonna make it look exactly like their ties and watches. I'm sure fossil,
Speaker 3:  if it wanted to these other manufacturers that maybe they play ball could,
Speaker 3:  you know, customize it and make it a different experience, kind of like what
Speaker 3:  we're seeing with Android phones. And then it begs the question or begins
Speaker 3:  to ask, like, what is the goal in terms of like, what Google wants
Speaker 3:  a smartwatch experience to be, because now hardware partners can dictate
Speaker 3:  a lot of that. So be kind of interesting to see how this shakes out, see
Speaker 3:  what is different between how, where ROS has been, that we've known for a
Speaker 3:  few years now and how this new, where when I suspect we'll see
Speaker 3:  devices in the fall running it.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Diener, is there a timeline? No,
Speaker 2:  I don't know. Honestly, I think fall is pretty good. I mean,
Speaker 2:  Samsung announced hardware that they're going to have watches. There's rumors
Speaker 2:  that Google's going to do a watch this fall. We've seen
Speaker 2:  renders that, you know, whether or not you believe them is dicey, but they
Speaker 2:  could be accurate. So I do think that it's like, this is the year. And I
Speaker 2:  think that because it's basically where with Samsung, GE
Speaker 2:  being given permission to put whatever Samsung stuff they want to top of
Speaker 2:  it, actually, it's not going to be that hard to get the watch out. Like,
Speaker 2:  I don't think they're making a whole new operating system here. I think it's
Speaker 2:  just where, but faster and less crappy, you know, you can wear
Speaker 2:  on a modern Qualcomm chip. It's like, okay, it's
Speaker 2:  better than its reputation, but there's just not enough to do on it. And
Speaker 2:  it still just feels a little bit incomplete. This feels like more of a complete
Speaker 2:  thought.
Speaker 1:  I think making it feel like more of a complete thought is great. But
Speaker 1:  like, as a person who wears an apple watch everyday, like what do I
Speaker 1:  use it for notifications? The walkie-talkie
Speaker 1:  feature, which is just a real hit in this house. And
Speaker 1:  like, it is the best RSA two factor dongle
Speaker 1:  that you could ever hope for it in your life. Right. Right. That's it
Speaker 1:  like, and like, I keep trying to make it do more things, but
Speaker 1:  those things, and obviously that like the fitness tracking, right?
Speaker 1:  Like it just happens to you. And then you're like, I got to close. These
Speaker 1:  rings like great. Yup. That's all stuff that
Speaker 1:  Google and Samsung can compete with in and rebuild. But that
Speaker 1:  like first it needs to be a complete thought that we're iterating on. And
Speaker 1:  like people want to use the features. It doesn't ha I don't think any of
Speaker 1:  these smartwatches need to do much more than that to be
Speaker 1:  compelling, but I just don't think where has gotten anywhere close to it.
Speaker 1:  So we'll see. I just can't get over the leg with our
Speaker 1:  excellent partnership in innovation, in our long track record of
Speaker 1:  partnership. Like I've heard it before, so
Speaker 1:  now they got to actually do it. I know. I mean, I,
Speaker 3:  You know, the cynical end game of this is where
Speaker 3:  becomes Samsung smartwatches. And like, it's
Speaker 3:  just like, that's it. It's just it. No, it's just
Speaker 3:  Samsung, like other partners don't sign on board or they give it a college
Speaker 3:  try with one model and then a year later they're gone and it's just, this
Speaker 3:  is what Samsung watches now run. I mean, that, that's, that's an end game
Speaker 3:  that I could very see happening with us.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Well, I hope it said, okay, we gotta to take a break. That's
Speaker 1:  so, well, I hope it's good. We
Speaker 1:  gotta take a break. Maybe we come back, we'll go through the rest of IO.
Speaker 1:  We'll be right back.
Speaker ?:  This episode of Vergecast brought to you by eCornell. If he wants to advance
Speaker ?:  your career without stepping out of your job, look no further than today's
Speaker ?:  sponsor eCornell with over 120 online certificates in
Speaker ?:  today's most in demand skills, taking a program with Cornell is a great way
Speaker ?:  to better your professional self. So he wants to further your career work
Speaker ?:  on your professional expertise and preserve the strides you've already made.
Speaker ?:  Try eCornell visit E cornell.com and use code
Speaker ?:  Vergecast for 20% off certificate programs. When you enroll
Speaker ?:  more and more of these days, we are conducting our everyday business remotely.
Speaker ?:  And while there will always be a place for doing things the old way, the
Speaker ?:  convenience that comes with online, learning changes, everything it's even
Speaker ?:  changing. The way we learn with Equinox, you can gain skills in your field
Speaker ?:  without interrupting your career. Equinox offers over 120
Speaker ?:  online certificate programs to choose from. And they're flexible. So while
Speaker ?:  you're learning about data science, project management, or web design, your
Speaker ?:  career doesn't get put on hold equals 100% online classes,
Speaker ?:  feature coursework that can be done anywhere. Anytime and most certificate
Speaker ?:  programs can be completed in two to four months. And while some other online
Speaker ?:  programs might lack that personal interaction and feedback from instructors,
Speaker ?:  Equinox, doesn't sacrifice it courses are developed by Cornell university
Speaker ?:  faculty, and you'll enjoy meaningful conversations about coursework with
Speaker ?:  instructors who have a wealth of knowledge in their field. Plus you get worthwhile
Speaker ?:  discussion with peers, from industry, from all over the world. Take the next
Speaker ?:  step with a professional certificate from Cornell university, visit III
Speaker ?:  cornell.com today, and use code of Vergecast for 20% off
Speaker ?:  certificate programs. When you enroll Let's get real
Speaker ?:  the tech world, doesn't always like to keep it simple from over-hype products
Speaker ?:  to constant sales pitches and endless jargon shopping for quality electronics
Speaker ?:  can be overwhelming, but it doesn't have to be cut through the usual BS
Speaker ?:  with high sense high census, the straight talking brand that offers
Speaker ?:  clarity and quality over confusion because let's get real. The most important
Speaker ?:  thing about a great TV is that it's actually a great TV with all the features
Speaker ?:  you love, like their new ULE D series, whether you're watching movies with
Speaker ?:  the kids, enjoying a date night or comfort, watching that show for the million
Speaker ?:  time, high sense brings you an unmatched 4k TV
Speaker ?:  experience and with a range of sizes, their you led series is bringing
Speaker ?:  premium products to the masses. We could sit here and tell you all about
Speaker ?:  the awesome features that come with high sense TV features like quantum dot
Speaker ?:  color HDR, 10 plus, and Dolby Atmos, but all you really need to
Speaker ?:  know is that high sense offers unbeatable quality at
Speaker ?:  unbelievable prices. Forget the jargon and get real to learn
Speaker ?:  more, visit high sense.com today. That's high
Speaker ?:  sense.com high sense. Let's get
Speaker ?:  real.
Speaker 1:  Okay. Lots of other IO stuff, including like a
Speaker 1:  huge change to Google docs, which are, I mean, our
Speaker 1:  entire business runs on Google docs. So we can talk about this forever, but
Speaker 1:  a big change in how it works. I will say they're adding Google, meet buttons
Speaker 1:  to everything like it's going out of style, which makes me sad, but some
Speaker 1:  cool stuff in docs what's going on there.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. So Google wants to do the thing that Microsoft says is
Speaker 2:  doing with fluid. They want to have all this stuff connect to each other,
Speaker 2:  right? And so their method of doing that is called the smart canvas.
Speaker 2:  And then there are these smart chips. So instead of mentioning somebody in
Speaker 2:  a doc, you can at mention them, you can mention them and add a Google task
Speaker 2:  to them, right in the doc, you can hit the app button and it'll pop up a
Speaker 2:  menu that will fill out a template. That's like ready for meeting notes.
Speaker 2:  You can add, mention other documents in your drive. And that could be
Speaker 2:  either a Google doc or like Microsoft word doc or whatever. And when you
Speaker 2:  hover over it, you can get a little preview of it right there in the thing.
Speaker 2:  So they're basically trying to get you to not have to switch
Speaker 2:  tabs and just like, just get rid of
Speaker 2:  tab overload. And this they're doing this with Google chat too, right? Like
Speaker 2:  a bunch of these things you can do inside chat. And now they're gonna let
Speaker 2:  you have chat for you inside the Google doc, or you could do it inside meats
Speaker 2:  or in the Google doc, you can click the meat button to share the, your doc
Speaker 2:  directly to the meeting. So you don't have to worry about screen-sharing
Speaker 2:  and showing the wrong tab or whatever. So they're just basically
Speaker 2:  making everything, do everything, which if they
Speaker 2:  can keep it feeling coherent and understandable is kind of
Speaker 2:  cool, but it's also Casey wrote a good
Speaker 2:  piece. I kind of gestured to this idea. It's a lot like what,
Speaker 2:  like the cooler new office suite site notion or code or whatever
Speaker 2:  we're doing, but Google can't go that fast because they have such a huge
Speaker 2:  user base just like the iPhone, right. They can't change it, bang and do
Speaker 2:  something completely wild. They can't bring back Google wave. So they're
Speaker 2:  doing these sort of baby steps. So that's the feature
Speaker 2:  set. But the, the thing for the first cast to
Speaker 2:  discuss is in order to enable that feature set, they have to
Speaker 2:  use this feature called canvas, which is basically a
Speaker 2:  thing in HTML. You say, there's a canvas here. And
Speaker 2:  then, you know, your web browser like stops paying attention. And then the
Speaker 2:  thing that's inside the canvas is an app. Or like, it's like JavaScript.
Speaker 2:  It's not flash. I mean, maybe it could be who knows, but it basically takes
Speaker 2:  the idea of like using the web technologies. We're used to thinking of as
Speaker 2:  the web HTML CSS, some JavaScript, blah, blah,
Speaker 2:  blah. And that like is not used to build this. And so it's no
Speaker 2:  longer in the document object model. It's not in the Dom anymore. And lots
Speaker 2:  of people have emotions about that because if there's any
Speaker 2:  company that could have figured out how to make a kick-ass futuristic web
Speaker 2:  app that interconnects everything together and makes you feel like everything
Speaker 2:  is all, you know, magically jumping from one thing to the next
Speaker 2:  inside web technologies, you'd want it to be Google. And if Google is bailing
Speaker 2:  on it, then that kind of bodes ill for, you
Speaker 2:  know, future of like web stuff. That's like more accessible where you can
Speaker 2:  like inspect source and see what's going on.
Speaker 1:  Wait, so you can't bring it down that simply. So with the
Speaker 1:  new Google docs, you can't just like inspect source and see how the thing
Speaker 1:  works, what you can do with some, but not all like most, but not all
Speaker 1:  web pages right now.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I mean, basically it's more of a black box. I don't know for sure if
Speaker 2:  like, if you really start pushing out it, if you can like find the link to
Speaker 2:  the web app, that is a, that the canvas is pointing to, and then like, you
Speaker 2:  know, go down the line and Google will tell you everything is open-source
Speaker 2:  all the time. So like, I'm not saying it's unexpectable, but I am saying
Speaker 2:  it's a lot less accessible if that makes sense. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  And, and Google said that a lot of like extensions that are built to modify
Speaker 3:  docs. So like a common one might be like a dark mode extension to flip
Speaker 3:  your Google docs into a dark mode. It's probably going to break until they
Speaker 3:  updated to work with this canvas or whatever,
Speaker 1:  Which gives them ultimately more control. Right?
Speaker 2:  Google is going to make this thing extensible so that other, you could like,
Speaker 2:  we could make a verge Google doc thing. So if you type at something in the
Speaker 2:  name of an article, it would auto fill the link. Right. That would be cool.
Speaker 2:  That would make making shadows way easier for
Speaker 1:  Me. But
Speaker 2:  For now, the way that most extensions and most like Google doc plugins
Speaker 2:  from third-parties work is they basically inspect source. They go through
Speaker 2:  the Dom and they're like, oh, like change this thing, change it. And then
Speaker 2:  changes it just like you can inspect source yourself to change a headline
Speaker 2:  for a joke screenshot or whatever. And that's going to be harder to do a
Speaker 2:  lot of that stuff might break, but it's not gonna break instantly. A bunch
Speaker 2:  of stuff is still gonna work. It's just like the stuff inside the canvas.
Speaker 2:  It's gonna take awhile to shake out, but it's potentially
Speaker 2:  more centralized, you know, control inside Google for API stuff
Speaker 2:  inside their apps.
Speaker 1:  So a lot of their demos were to me, things that
Speaker 1:  seem like great ideas, like they seem like great demos. And then I think
Speaker 1:  about how I actually work. And I, I wonder, right?
Speaker 1:  Like one of their demos was you are writing in a doc
Speaker 1:  or you're working on a spreadsheet and you push a button in the video call
Speaker 1:  starts right in the doc and everyone's already looking at it and the screens
Speaker 1:  are really small and it's all just happening in one place.
Speaker 1:  Right. And you don't have to like switch tasks. You don't have to switch
Speaker 1:  tabs. Yeah. He it, and then you go back to your doc
Speaker 1:  or, I mean, I think you brought this up in your piece,
Speaker 1:  Cedar, like these are kind of like ancient ideas about how to
Speaker 1:  work in docs like documents. Yeah. Like apple had
Speaker 1:  open doc. Microsoft had Ole
Speaker 1:  LA can I just say them?
Speaker 2:  This is a, Vergecast where we have brought up Maemo amigo and open doc. This
Speaker 2:  is just the class it's,
Speaker 2:  what's
Speaker 1:  In our feelings. And that technology ideas this time, it's just wild to me.
Speaker 1:  Like these are dreams that have persisted for you years and years and
Speaker 1:  years. And like finally, they can come into
Speaker 1:  reality. I think the pandemic and working from home has made people
Speaker 1:  be like, I want to figure out different ways to work with a bunch of
Speaker 1:  people remotely. So there's appetite for
Speaker 1:  change in a way that has not existed before. But really what
Speaker 1:  you're talking about is I want to make a document. I want to embed a table
Speaker 1:  from a spreadsheet. And if somebody else updates that spreadsheet, it all
Speaker 1:  happens. Live in one place. Also that's like wildly accessible to other
Speaker 1:  kinds of apps and services. And I'm just logging into like my work
Speaker 1:  dashboard and stuff is happening all the time. And I think that stuff is
Speaker 1:  great. And then I think about how I actually work, which
Speaker 1:  is I need to focus on a single thread and
Speaker 1:  just get through it without being distracted. And then I need to
Speaker 1:  like give that to Dan and be like, edit this review. I'm
Speaker 1:  leaving. And I, and I know that's not how everybody works on there's
Speaker 1:  lots and lots of different ways to work. But like these ideas are like somewhat
Speaker 1:  in conflict. Right. But you want, you perceive a way of
Speaker 1:  working. That is not actually the best,
Speaker 1:  like what most people would call the best way of working, which is like
Speaker 1:  extreme focus.
Speaker 2:  Well, well, I mean, the big question to me is like how
Speaker 2:  much of this is driven by like metrics. I'm not accusing Google of being
Speaker 2:  driven by metrics and like the old joke about, you know, how many thousands
Speaker 2:  of blues they tested, blah, blah, blah, blah. But like if you're
Speaker 2:  making an app and you see more use of your app, then that must be
Speaker 2:  good. And so all of this stuff is designed for like real-time interaction
Speaker 2:  and let's say synchronous communication, and like just more, more use the
Speaker 2:  apps more because there's more stuff going on. You're getting more notifications,
Speaker 2:  there's video calls, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah. But maybe that's not,
Speaker 2:  maybe you should make an app that doesn't need to be used so much because
Speaker 2:  the idea of work is to get it done and move on to the next.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. That's what I mean. It's like, and I recognize that we have very
Speaker 1:  strange jobs, right? Like we deliver things that need to be
Speaker 1:  finished and then published. And then if we have to change them after published,
Speaker 1:  like there's a process we have to like, yeah, that's all very different
Speaker 1:  for us than other folks in different kinds of industries. But
Speaker 1:  I do think that notion, I mean, this is why when I was doing virtual
Speaker 1:  interviews for song, I'd asked every guest, when do you work? Right. And
Speaker 1:  the answers were like, almost always some executive. Like I work in
Speaker 1:  business class flying across the country because the wifi is bad and no one
Speaker 1:  can bother me, which is always my favorite flux of an
Speaker 1:  answer. But I look at this stuff and it's like, oh, this is just allowing
Speaker 1:  more people to interrupt you and get in your way. But it looks really
Speaker 1:  cool. It sounds really cool. And I, I'm just, I think
Speaker 1:  Google like, yep, they've got a big user base. They got it is slow. But I
Speaker 1:  think some of that slowness is going to be helpful to figure out what
Speaker 1:  is useful and what is not. But I don't know, even
Speaker 1:  within our
Speaker 3:  Weird way of working, if you pull the staff
Speaker 3:  of writers who work with editors all day long, some of them will be writing
Speaker 3:  in Google docs, but a lot of them will be writing outside of Google docs
Speaker 3:  because they want a thing that does not distract them and they can write
Speaker 3:  it down. And then they literally copy their texts into Google docs, which
Speaker 3:  then gets collaboratively, edited, and then gets copied into our CMS. And
Speaker 3:  there's like this, this process that we have. So it's like,
Speaker 3:  these things that Google's coming out with are all
Speaker 3:  focused around immediate collaboration and like
Speaker 3:  real-time collaboration, which is like, like you said, looks really cool
Speaker 3:  in a demo. And it has this like neat idea of all of us. We're all in different
Speaker 3:  places of the world that we're all working on the same thing in the same
Speaker 3:  goal. But how much of that is going to reflect in the reality of how something
Speaker 3:  is put together? I mean, like, I don't know how we integrate this into our
Speaker 3:  workflow. Maybe there's other workflows where it's more obvious.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. And I, I don't want to be like too, narrow-minded lots of people
Speaker 1:  work in all kinds of fields. They do need more real-time collaboration. I'm
Speaker 1:  excited for the innovation. I just keep thinking about the fact that I own
Speaker 1:  an apple pencil and like all that is
Speaker 1:  easiest for us. My daughter draws on the tablet, like in
Speaker 1:  any demo, no one knows what to do, except circle things on a screen. And
Speaker 1:  like, it just feels like that. Like, man, this is cool. I finally have this
Speaker 1:  thing. I want, boy, it's usefulness to me is extremely
Speaker 1:  limited. We'll see,
Speaker 2:  We shouldn't get off workspace before pointing out that they finally added
Speaker 2:  a page list mode that is responsive. And so the, the document
Speaker 2:  will change its width to the width of your window. And not as soon as you're
Speaker 2:  printing it, which is a little bit overdue. And I
Speaker 2:  just want to reiterate that if you are a Google tasks, user
Speaker 2:  a, they haven't given you a website, you can go to, it's still only in a
Speaker 2:  sidebar. And B somebody in your team can add a Google
Speaker 2:  task to your Google tasks from a Google doc. So I am
Speaker 2:  intending on using that in all sorts of terrible ways.
Speaker 5:  That's super fun. I'm
Speaker 3:  Intending on continuing to ignore Google tasks, but they
Speaker 2:  Are normalizing a bunch of stuff. So like the little hover thing for a
Speaker 2:  contact Gmail is going to stop being so broken because they made it, they
Speaker 2:  fixed it for Google docs and they're going to bring that back to Gmail. So
Speaker 2:  the thing that strike struck me at the end of all of this was, oh my
Speaker 2:  God, they're doing stuff like they're actually, they have a roadmap and they
Speaker 2:  have a plan and they have a vision for what Google workspace is going to
Speaker 2:  be. And they're actually making products on the path to that
Speaker 2:  roadmap. That's a bad metaphor, but they're doing a thing and they
Speaker 2:  have a plan which at Google is
Speaker 2:  common.
Speaker 1:  I feel like Google's going to start shipping stuff in docs is
Speaker 1:  actually like the whole story here. But we'll see. Cause it has
Speaker 1:  remained remarkably unchanged for a long time. Okay. Let's round
Speaker 1:  out. I there's a bunch of other stuff. And I, it kind
Speaker 1:  of like falls into two categories. One is like Google doing a
Speaker 1:  bunch of demo stuff and then Google doing
Speaker 1:  AI stuff that is associated with controversy. And they're all kind of
Speaker 1:  like demo demo stuff. So just
Speaker 1:  like we could talk about classic. Vergecast like Google photos
Speaker 1:  is dying. We'll take two photos taken around the same
Speaker 1:  time and animate them. So like the question of what is a photo
Speaker 1:  is about to get extremely wild. So you take, let's
Speaker 1:  say you're, I mean their demos, like two, two photos,
Speaker 2:  But Nila, if you take two photos at different times where those photos photos
Speaker 2:  in the first place, weren't they also composites
Speaker 1:  Apparently in the photos are already HDR composites. So they are not single
Speaker 1:  moments in time. But then if you think about an animation, animation is frames
Speaker 1:  that when stitched together indicate the passage of time, but now the first
Speaker 1:  photo is actually a slice of time. That is
Speaker 1:  interpreted to create the impression of a single moment in time. So
Speaker 1:  as the last frame, and now it is generated multiple frames in
Speaker 1:  between. Yeah. That are moments in time that never
Speaker 1:  existed.
Speaker 2:  Right? Well, they may, they assume that it existed. They're there, they're
Speaker 2:  taking a guest that you, you know, you moved your head this way in between
Speaker 2:  those two frames, but they don't know. They're just figuring it out.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. But it's so like, that's crazy. Yeah. This is
Speaker 1:  crazy. I don't know what to say about that. That's an hour of
Speaker 1:  Vergecast asked, like, what is a phone like
Speaker 1:  is one of those middle frames, statistically, it could
Speaker 1:  be an accurate representation of that moment in time. Yeah. Maybe at a
Speaker 1:  high level, like a high rate of accuracy or
Speaker 1:  could not be. So now you have a computer photo.
Speaker 1:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  The whole concept of reality is just a, it's just statistics. Anyway.
Speaker 2:  Statistically, nothing made there or it's not, and it's not actually
Speaker 2:  odd off. Yes, no, it's statistics. It's a percentage chance that you exist.
Speaker 2:  And luckily it's a, you know, you're, you're hitting, you're hitting jackpot.
Speaker 2:  Every, every millisecond,
Speaker 1:  Which brings me to quantum
Speaker 1:  computing
Speaker 1:  Googled it a whizzbang. And this was like, I didn't think this was a great
Speaker 1:  interstitial nephritis, Michael Pena. They had like walked through their
Speaker 1:  quantum computing facility. It was very jokey. It's very hard to explain
Speaker 1:  quantum computing. I made this joke in the live blog with this is true. If
Speaker 1:  you ever in your life like encounter a quantum computing
Speaker 1:  person or like go to their facility within minutes,
Speaker 1:  there'll be like, this is the coldest place in the
Speaker 1:  universe because it is the single most relatable
Speaker 1:  thing they can say to you. And it is still insane. Cause
Speaker 1:  otherwise like cubits, here's the deal you're like off to the
Speaker 1:  races. So they're trying to build a quantum computer by 2029. They're actually
Speaker 1:  going to race with Microsoft. They're in a race with IBM. All these companies
Speaker 1:  have different approaches to how to do this thing that they're doing. That
Speaker 1:  they demo this thing called Starline. Yeah, this was wild, which
Speaker 1:  I kind of like don't understand why it's so
Speaker 1:  complicated. So
Speaker 2:  I don't think it's necessarily complicated. I just, that it's a smart thing
Speaker 2:  they made.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, it's fine. It's a video conferencing
Speaker 1:  booth. So you sit in it there's cameras, there's a 3d display
Speaker 1:  in front of you. But then instead of just like shooting you in sending that
Speaker 1:  video signal directly to the other line, booth it constructs a real-time
Speaker 1:  3d model of you and then re animates that model on the other
Speaker 1:  side, that's the part where I'm like, why is it so
Speaker 1:  complicated? Because they could just shoot the video of you
Speaker 1:  in 3d and send it over there. But they make a volumetric 3d model of
Speaker 1:  you.
Speaker 2:  Right. Maybe it gives you more ability to like move your
Speaker 2:  head around a little bit. Maybe it just looks less video, easy to do it that
Speaker 2:  way. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  I'm like bursting with questions cause they showed it off and it looked
Speaker 1:  cool. Lauren, good read a great piece of wired about it. She got to experience
Speaker 1:  it. But then they kept saying things like this takes so much
Speaker 1:  data. Yeah. Like gigabytes of data, we had to invent
Speaker 1:  a new compression technology and it's like, why don't you just shoot the
Speaker 1:  video? Like they never made that turn for me. Did you hear that? Because
Speaker 1:  I never figured out why they need to do all this like volumetric 3d
Speaker 1:  rendering instead of just showing 3d video
Speaker 1:  across.
Speaker 2:  Well, because what's, you're looking at on the, in the booth, you're looking
Speaker 2:  at a hologram, right? And th th the reason you can make eye contact is because
Speaker 2:  of the, one of the cameras is behind the hologram. And so you're actually
Speaker 2:  looking at a full person, like in
Speaker 2:  3d presented with, you know, hologram technology, not it. And so it's not
Speaker 2:  just a video, it's, it's a real person with like
Speaker 2:  volume right in front of you that, and so
Speaker 2:  could that have been done with a bunch of 3d cameras or did they actually
Speaker 2:  need to do like a full bunch of like motion capture, volume metric stuff
Speaker 2:  to like, get that, to have that presence on the other side, I'm
Speaker 2:  guessing they did. Maybe they didn't, but I'm guessing they did. And that's
Speaker 2:  also a lot of data, but that's weird. Cause they, they said like it just
Speaker 2:  worked on like a standard office. They didn't have to run a special fiber
Speaker 2:  over. So there is a lot of compression happening there as well. So
Speaker 2:  to me, the real question is like, how does it actually look in
Speaker 2:  person Lauren? I think it was one of the few people outside of Google to
Speaker 2:  like, be able to describe it. And she said it was very real, but as soon
Speaker 2:  as he like moved a little bit to the left or the right, it started to, to
Speaker 2:  break the illusion. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  And another one for the, what is a photo files, right? Like you're looking
Speaker 1:  at a person that is not there. That is a
Speaker 1:  reconstructed volumetric 3d model of a person. But
Speaker 1:  that is reacting in real time to that person's
Speaker 1:  actions. I don't know, man. I got to go lay
Speaker 1:  down. I think Ben
Speaker 1:  Thompson and Stackery referred to it as Google creates new realities. And
Speaker 1:  like here it is. Okay. And then lastly, and this
Speaker 1:  is Google just charged into this. And I, I
Speaker 1:  haven't kind of made a mistake. So they announced a bunch of AI stuff that
Speaker 1:  is at a high level. Very cool. So they announced mom and Lambda
Speaker 1:  was her new, natural language processing systems. We were
Speaker 1:  joking before about, I was saying, talking to Dieter, I was like talking
Speaker 1:  to a paper airplane or talking to Pluto. Those were there demos so
Speaker 1:  that the system can take on the character of
Speaker 1:  a paper airplane, and then sort of converse with you about what
Speaker 1:  it's like to be a paper airplane, or you can converse with
Speaker 1:  Pluto, which by the way, Sundar and Google just
Speaker 1:  directly call the planet like 10 times. What was Google
Speaker 1:  put Google being a planet. I thought that was great. Yeah. I hear me go
Speaker 1:  Pluto. I'm on team Pluto. Okay. So that's cool. And then they can do
Speaker 1:  searches with it. They have this thing called multimodal search where
Speaker 1:  they can understand photos where you can take a picture of your hiking
Speaker 1:  boots and say, are these boots good for hiking up whatever mountain I'm going
Speaker 1:  to hike up? And that system will understand all of these
Speaker 1:  things. Okay. Oh, that's in like provide you a
Speaker 1:  conversational answer. All that's great. All of this is in context
Speaker 1:  of Google had a team called the ethical AI
Speaker 1:  team led by a researcher named Tim , who
Speaker 1:  was writing about how Google's language models
Speaker 1:  had profound racial implications, that there was bias
Speaker 1:  built into the models because how they collect natural language data to
Speaker 1:  create the models. She tried to publish this paper. She got into a fight
Speaker 1:  with Google, she and a bunch of our team word summarily
Speaker 1:  fired that has led to Zoe's uncovering this rest lesson, right?
Speaker 1:  James Vincent has been covering. He has actually got a great piece about
Speaker 1:  how, like Google said it IO connects to the controversy and like Google
Speaker 1:  just papered over it. There's no mention of the fact that this is an
Speaker 1:  internal controversy in Google about whether the
Speaker 1:  AI teams are acting using correct data sets. The
Speaker 1:  only mention of it was they announced this image processing initiative where
Speaker 1:  they're going to change some of the camera filters and they've hired a bunch
Speaker 1:  of experts across fields to make sure the
Speaker 1:  image data sets are more inclusive. They're literally going to go out and
Speaker 1:  take photos. But that was it. I didn't catch anything else that you, I
Speaker 1:  think
Speaker 2:  There was a little bit with Landa about needing to be careful with the data
Speaker 2:  sets needed to be responsible with it. But again,
Speaker 2:  it's like, obviously they've been working on this stuff for forever. It's
Speaker 2:  unclear how much of the ethical AI team
Speaker 2:  contributed to it. If that controversy hadn't happened, I guarantee you,
Speaker 2:  they would have been like, they would have talked about the fact that they
Speaker 2:  have an ethical AI team and he has a  team. They could advise
Speaker 2:  them on this. It's pretty wild, how they just went for it
Speaker 2:  with this stuff. And they, they are basically daring
Speaker 2:  everybody to be like, well, wait a minute. And that's
Speaker 2:  kind of been the reaction. Remember, well they a duplex a few years ago,
Speaker 2:  whatever it was, we were like, this is amazing. And everyone went, but wait
Speaker 2:  a minute. Yeah. They just walked right into that again. But in a way that
Speaker 2:  is, I dunno, much more pointed because there's just much more,
Speaker 2:  you know, Google did a lot worse things here than a
Speaker 2:  duplex. It was just like, oh, you didn't think of it. What the hell with
Speaker 2:  here? It's like, oh, you fired somebody. What the hell?
Speaker 1:  Yeah. So James Vincent, who wrote about this for us, he's got a quote
Speaker 1:  from Emily Bender who coauthored that this paper
Speaker 1:  in the center of the controversy with Tim Nibiru and Margaret Mitchell, one
Speaker 1:  of the other Google researchers who's fired her quote is from the blog post
Speaker 1:  discussing Lambda. And given the history, I do not have confidence. Google
Speaker 1:  has actually been careful about any of the risks we raised in the paper.
Speaker 1:  For one thing, they fired two of the authors of that paper, nominally over
Speaker 1:  the paper. So like, there's, there's a
Speaker 1:  big sticky problem for Google here where they've
Speaker 1:  trashed the reputation. They know they have James Dean who runs AI.
Speaker 1:  Google has said it we've reported it. And now they're watching the
Speaker 1:  product or they're talking to the product in a way that is of high
Speaker 1:  strategic importance to them. I honestly do not know how they're going
Speaker 1:  to, how they're going to make that turn. I mean, they're just going to do
Speaker 1:  it, which is the problem
Speaker 2:  I was going to say, yeah, I'm just going to power through it. I mean, the
Speaker 2:  team is still there. It's got a new person in charge. Maybe they can come
Speaker 2:  back from it. But like how hard is hiring over on that
Speaker 2:  team right now, right? It's not a huge community. And they
Speaker 2:  have trashed the reputation in that community in a way that like isn't, isn't
Speaker 2:  like has they haven't figured out how to,
Speaker 1:  I mean, not even a little bit. And we also don't know how much that ethical
Speaker 1:  AI team gets to make calls about what Google's
Speaker 1:  products are. So what I, when I think about Dieter is something you have
Speaker 1:  mentioned in the context of voice search a million times, right? You ask
Speaker 1:  a Google home hub or an Alexa, a question you only get one
Speaker 1:  answer and you get no contextual information about where that
Speaker 1:  answer came from. You don't get other potential answers or
Speaker 1:  links. You just kind of get told information in Google.
Speaker 1:  If you look at their presentation across IO, all of their search results
Speaker 1:  are geared towards giving you the one answer. And they announced some stuff
Speaker 1:  in search about contextual search results and why we're showing this to you.
Speaker 1:  And they're going to disclose whether things are ads or not more clearly,
Speaker 1:  which is hilarious because that is totally a problem of their own
Speaker 1:  making, right? Like they've stuffed so many ads in search results. Now they
Speaker 1:  have to tell you when things aren't ads, but as you go down these AI
Speaker 1:  roads and you start to say the computer's going to tell you more things,
Speaker 1:  you're gonna take a picture of your shoes and ask the computer. If the
Speaker 1:  shoes are appropriate to wear, and the computer's gonna tell you an answer,
Speaker 1:  it's usually a generate an answer and tell it to you like a
Speaker 1:  person.
Speaker 2:  And it might, it might involve no, they're not, but you could go buy these
Speaker 2:  shoes. And when you do
Speaker 1:  Right. I mean, like, there's just like all of these moments now for Google,
Speaker 1:  where instead of showing you where information might be, they're going to
Speaker 1:  become the provider of it and are obviously trying to automate it. And
Speaker 1:  like, yeah, if you Google has mostly
Speaker 1:  escaped the Facebook dynamic, right? Like the algorithm is
Speaker 1:  bad. Facebook dynamic. They definitely, yeah. With YouTube, it's like
Speaker 1:  absolutely there, but as they start to turn search and maps and all this
Speaker 1:  other stuff into natural language, single result,
Speaker 1:  AI systems like, woo. Yeah, man, do you need an ethical AI
Speaker 1:  team showing like showing people the work more than
Speaker 1:  ever, because Google is a utility. The way that I think Facebook isn't
Speaker 2:  Well, and Google is also when you, when it gives you these answers, they're
Speaker 2:  coming from Google, they might tell you what the source was. But when you
Speaker 2:  get just one answer the person, the entity, the
Speaker 2:  responsibility for the accuracy of that answer is going to end up falling
Speaker 2:  on Google in a way, or it has a lot on Facebook, but Facebook can kind
Speaker 2:  of slide around it and say, well, it's our algorithm. It's other people are
Speaker 2:  other people are posting the misinformation, blah, blah, blah, blah disclosure.
Speaker 2:  My wife works for Facebook. Reality labs used to be called Oculus, et
Speaker 2:  cetera. Yeah. It's going to be a tougher problem in the future for both
Speaker 2:  companies.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I just, it, this, the demos are cool. You should watch them. It's fun
Speaker 1:  to watch Sundar talking to a planet. It was even, I thought when he
Speaker 1:  showed it braking, that's hilarious where he was like, Pluto's
Speaker 1:  answer was sometimes I play with the moon and it's like, oh, this is how
Speaker 1:  the world ends. Like the computers get feelings.
Speaker 1:  They, they, they blow up the moon. But I
Speaker 1:  just, I want to end the IO section on this because it is a huge
Speaker 1:  issue for Google and like, you know, Addie
Speaker 1:  and I are going to do a whole episode on an apple and epic and competition.
Speaker 1:  Antitrust. Where is the competition for Google in these
Speaker 1:  spaces? If Google screws us up, where are you going to go
Speaker 1:  to search for things on the web, a, in a meaningful and realistic way,
Speaker 1:  especially like, it's like, Apple's going to take, it's like stop taking
Speaker 1:  the Google money. So like, I think the pressure on Google to get this
Speaker 1:  right is high. It needs to maybe get even
Speaker 1:  higher. Okay. We're gonna take a break. We're gonna come back. We've
Speaker 1:  got some, we got some gadget reviews to talk about. This is a really like
Speaker 1:  a classic for a chest while we were at
Speaker 1:  back.
Speaker ?:  When it comes to tech, you want the latest and greatest, but there's definitely
Speaker ?:  something to be said for time-tested design that works with everything. And
Speaker ?:  it will last for years, Baird, Winthrop, CEO, and founder of American
Speaker ?:  giant grew up with a sweatshirt from the fifties that his father gave him
Speaker ?:  today. It's still in his closet and it looks better than ever. So he set
Speaker ?:  out to recreate a timeless classic. That's the thinking behind the American
Speaker ?:  giant classic full zip hoodie. They obsessed over every detail, both functional
Speaker ?:  and aesthetic. So you'll be obsessed with it too, but even brought in a formal
Speaker ?:  apple, industrial designer to help perfect. The design American shine hoodies
Speaker ?:  are built with a custom design heavyweight cut and fleece locally grown in
Speaker ?:  sown in North Carolina. And they're made to last with a durable, double lined
Speaker ?:  hood and reinforced elbow patches. Plus they added side panels for increased
Speaker ?:  mobility and a slim body skimming fit. Most importantly, it's
Speaker ?:  comfortable. American giant is committed to reviving local manufacturing
Speaker ?:  and they believe that all it takes is one quality piece to set any standard.
Speaker ?:  If your capsule wardrobe has room only one hoodie make it one you'll love
Speaker ?:  for a long time to come get your classic full zip hoodie at American desk,
Speaker ?:  giant.com today, and use promo code verge for 15%
Speaker ?:  off your first order. That's 15% off when you use code
Speaker ?:  verge@american-giant.com. What secrets do
Speaker ?:  matchmakers have up their sleeves to find the perfect match, some consult
Speaker ?:  with the stars. Others will listen to what you say you want and read between
Speaker ?:  the lines. When you're talking about finding the right candidate to fill
Speaker ?:  a job, indeed has their own set of tools to help you find the perfect fit,
Speaker ?:  take their skills test feature. You can use it to measure more than 130 different
Speaker ?:  skills and prospective hires, including hard skills, personality tests, and
Speaker ?:  work samples. Indeed says these tests reduce hiring times by
Speaker ?:  27% or their instant match feature, which delivers
Speaker ?:  quality matches over 80% of the time for your sponsored job post
Speaker ?:  with indeed, you can get a shortlist of quality candidates whose resumes
Speaker ?:  match your job description. Then you can schedule video interviews to see
Speaker ?:  if a natural work and you only pay for the ones who meet your must have
Speaker ?:  qualities. Indeed helps you match the right candidate to the job fast and
Speaker ?:  easy. Get a $75 credit at
Speaker ?:  indeed.com/vergecast offer valid through June
Speaker ?:  30th terms and conditions apply.
Speaker 1:  Okay, we're back. Gotta end. Monica reviewed the
Speaker 1:  M one iMac, which is beautiful Dieter year viewed the M
Speaker 1:  one iPad pro. And then I don't even
Speaker 1:  understand this lossless audio thing. Let's start with the
Speaker 1:  tan. Let's start with the iMac. Yeah. The
Speaker 3:  IMac is finally that redesigned that everyone's
Speaker 1:  Been waiting for a decade. I love it so much. It is very pretty
Speaker 3:  Comes in a bunch of fun colors. We were able to review and see
Speaker 3:  the purple one and the orange one, which have dumb marketing names
Speaker 3:  that I can not remember. So you can remind them as purple and orange
Speaker 3:  sales comes in green and blue and silver and yellow. So if you want a
Speaker 3:  yellow computer, you can now buy one. But the point is it's basically, if
Speaker 3:  you took a Mac book pro and one and put it into a desktop
Speaker 3:  chassis with a 24 inch screen, really great speakers, that's what this
Speaker 3:  is. And that's exactly how it functions. It performs. It's got great performance
Speaker 3:  for everyday work. It's very quiet. It's very quick. It's very responsive.
Speaker 3:  The webcams. Great speaker sound great. The it's got three microphone sound
Speaker 3:  great. So Monica tested it out a bunch with the, for video calling
Speaker 3:  because that's what we're all doing now. And it's a really great video calling
Speaker 3:  machine, but it's not like the iMac that people who
Speaker 3:  have bought IMAX for the past few years have probably been waiting for it
Speaker 3:  because the iMac for obviously, since its beginning was like
Speaker 3:  the family computer, it was a way to get online. Initially it was all in
Speaker 3:  one, very simple, but as time has gone on and things like the
Speaker 3:  MacBook air have kind of replaced the default computer from
Speaker 3:  desktops, the iMac became more of a focused professional
Speaker 3:  tools. Our video team use design Mac all the time. Lots of creative professionals
Speaker 3:  uses IMAX all the time. This new iMac is not probably the
Speaker 3:  computer for them. They're going to want to wait for something more powerful,
Speaker 3:  bigger screen, more ports. There's only four ports on this that you can get.
Speaker 3:  So, but it is kind of the return of the classic Bondi
Speaker 3:  blue iMac that came out in 1998. So actually,
Speaker 2:  I, I think you're wrong that this isn't something that people are waiting
Speaker 2:  for. My parents bought an iMac in the pandemic cause they just want, they
Speaker 2:  needed a desktop. They needed a bigger screen and they wanted to make video
Speaker 2:  calls a bit easier in a format they're familiar with because figuring
Speaker 2:  out the Facebook portal is a nightmare. And
Speaker 2:  so like I'm a little bit bummed that like they don't have this
Speaker 2:  computer because it would be so much happier with it. It's lighter. They
Speaker 2:  could like they could move it around, stick it on the kitchen table if they
Speaker 2:  wanted to. I think the computer is great.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. It's a great computer. Yeah, for sure. But like for the audience that's
Speaker 3:  listening to the Vergecast for the audience that reads the verge reviews.
Speaker 3:  They probably, it's probably not the computer for them. It's not the right
Speaker 3:  computer for me. I like a 24 inch screen. It's like, hi
Speaker 3:  Lauren.
Speaker 2:  I would, the first,
Speaker 3:  If I had this computer on my desk, the first thing I would do is stick a
Speaker 3:  Thunderbolt dock into the back of it. So I could actually have functional
Speaker 3:  and do what I want to do. So like, it's, it's the computer for someone who
Speaker 3:  cares about that stuff. But for some people like your parents, Cedar, or
Speaker 3:  like for people who are not, you know, that, you know, you care about it.
Speaker 3:  It's, it's, it's a great functional computer that they can literally put
Speaker 3:  down on a desk and not worry about it for like five to 10 years, which was
Speaker 3:  like the dream of the iMac. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  I mean, I dunno, we kind of, when these were announced, we kind of poked
Speaker 1:  around to the idea of like, did you know everybody was going to work from
Speaker 1:  home and then you had an M one ship. So you made like a fun, colorful, good
Speaker 1:  work from home. And like, the response was like, man, we wish we were that
Speaker 1:  good. Right? Like, yeah. But they have hit a
Speaker 1:  moment where a lot of people are reconsidering. How,
Speaker 1:  when they're going to work, a lot of people are like, oh, I, I want to have
Speaker 1:  like a nice home office situation. I'm not going to go in the office that
Speaker 1:  this computer is perfect for that. Like, they're going to sell so many of
Speaker 1:  these. So, so, so many of these, and it's also like a brand new
Speaker 1:  five nanometer chip. The  on a new process at apple
Speaker 1:  controls all the supply too. So there'll be no chip shortage
Speaker 1:  whatsoever. It's like, well, there might be some
Speaker 1:  actually apple. It might be, they might be running. But like
Speaker 1:  just in terms of media, like your plan meeting a
Speaker 1:  moment and like having that moment kind of be perfect. I
Speaker 1:  think they've, they've nailed it for a huge class of
Speaker 1:  people that is reconsidering. Whether they're going to go back to an
Speaker 1:  office. And like, I think if you, if you're not like I
Speaker 1:  cannot recommend enough. If you have a laptop, get an external display
Speaker 1:  and a keyboard and just tilt your head up, like, don't look down at
Speaker 1:  your laptop all day, just like sit up and look straight. And if you are in
Speaker 1:  the market for a new computer, like maybe you don't want your laptop to
Speaker 1:  follow you around the house and make you work all of the time. Maybe like
Speaker 1:  work should stay in a room. And like, I don't know. I think the
Speaker 1:   power thing, like how powerful is this computer
Speaker 1:  really? I mean, I want to, I want to wait for a bigger screen and a
Speaker 1:  faster computer, but most people are looking at 13 inch laptop screens. There's
Speaker 1:  just a part of me. It's like apple nail it. So completely this computer that
Speaker 1:  I want to get one, just to have it, even though I don't need it. You and
Speaker 3:  Your kitchen, that's where apple wants you to put it in the kitchen. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Cause your work will follow
Speaker 1:  You into it. I do. Why don't they do that? Why
Speaker 1:  didn't they, this goes into the iPad, but why didn't they do the CenterStage
Speaker 1:  video calling thing with this? It's very odd. Honestly.
Speaker 3:  I have no idea. It's got a great image sensor in there. It's 10
Speaker 3:  ADP from seven 20. Now Monica did like, if you watch the video, she
Speaker 3:  compares it directly to the camera. That's in the M one Mac book pro and
Speaker 1:  It is night and day. You know,
Speaker 1:  obviously
Speaker 3:  It's not going to compare it to like setting up your own rig with a mirrorless
Speaker 3:  camera and all this other stuff that people have done over the past year.
Speaker 3:  But just compared to like what it was before, it is much better experience
Speaker 3:  in terms of video. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  I think the answer to center stage is the same reason. It's the same answer
Speaker 2:  is why they didn't put a face ID on the iMac. It's just, it's a lot of work
Speaker 2:  to recreate that stuff on the Mac. And I don't know if they can run iPad
Speaker 2:  out. So apparently I can't run that yet and they just don't
Speaker 2:  want to do it. Mac
Speaker 3:  Is scary and dangerous. That's why, oh
Speaker 3:  yeah.
Speaker 1:  Monica says speakers are good. This is probably as good a place as any to
Speaker 1:  talk about Atmos and
Speaker 1:  lossless,
Speaker 2:  I don't know, like it supports
Speaker 1:  Dolby Atmos with spatial audio, apple music just rolled
Speaker 1:  out like just this extremely
Speaker 1:  complicated lossless audio plan. Yeah. Yeah. So there
Speaker 1:  you can get, it's not gonna cost anyone anymore. So the complexity is like,
Speaker 1:  whatever, but there's two different things happening at
Speaker 1:  once. One is what should
Speaker 1:  be the more straightforward thing is the quality
Speaker 1:  levels of apple music are rising. So now
Speaker 1:  instead of wherever they were at compressed AAC,
Speaker 1:  you can now get lossless apple
Speaker 1:  music that comes in two different quality tiers. Dan,
Speaker 1:  am I correct about this?
Speaker 3:  So there's a lossless and then there's high Def lossless
Speaker 3:  okay.
Speaker 1:  So there's two tracks here. One is like
Speaker 1:  existing apple music is going to be higher quality. And that
Speaker 1:  is very complicated. It involves a
Speaker 1:  lot of Apple's own hardware, not supporting anything.
Speaker 1:  So at the base level,
Speaker 1:  apple is going to support CD quality audio, which is hilarious to
Speaker 1:  me because everyone is always talking about CD quality audio, but
Speaker 1:  like CDs came out 30 years ago. That was, we got, we gotta be able to
Speaker 1:  do better than like one obstacle disc format, but CD quality audio is
Speaker 1:  16 bit at 44.1, kilo Hertz. Those are the numbers that you can fall
Speaker 1:  down the rabbit hole, those numbers if you want. But those are the numbers
Speaker 1:  that indicate CD quality audio then on apple devices,
Speaker 1:  but by apple devices, we mean Macs and iOS
Speaker 1:  devices. Not anything else. That's a big point on
Speaker 1:  apple devices. You can get 24 bit at 48 kilo
Speaker 1:  Hertz, which is a good and meaningful step up. Then
Speaker 1:  you can also further go to 24 bit at 192 kilo
Speaker 1:  Hertz. If you have an external USB digital audio
Speaker 1:  converter, which is like another box you have to buy. And he plugs fancy
Speaker 1:  headphones into that. So like at the top level of apple
Speaker 1:  music, you need to buy a piece of non-Apple hardware at the
Speaker 1:  middle level of apple music. You can use your
Speaker 1:  phone or your Mac to listen to
Speaker 1:  it probably over the built-in speakers because the phones
Speaker 1:  don't have had fun jacks. Yeah. And you can't
Speaker 1:  listen to any of this. If you have
Speaker 1:  Apple's headphones, if you have AirPods or AirPods max or AirPods
Speaker 1:  pro
Speaker 3:  It gets more complicated than that. Because the thing that apple says is
Speaker 3:  they that, so the, that highest tier where you need that external
Speaker 3:  hardware, you cannot listen to that with AirPods max or home
Speaker 3:  pods full stop, right? That lossless tier before you get to that
Speaker 3:  highest tier is not called lossless. When you are
Speaker 3:  listening through AirPods max, whether you're doing it wired or
Speaker 3:  wireless, and apple says, this is because what happens is the
Speaker 3:  audio is converted into analog. Then it's re
Speaker 3:  digitized for the AirPods max, because they do not
Speaker 3:  have an analog to digital converter. And so it's, it's,
Speaker 3:  it's digital goes to analog, becomes digital again, when it
Speaker 3:  hits your ear, before it goes to your ears where it comes out of the speakers
Speaker 3:  or whatever that can last conversion means that apple can't
Speaker 3:  call it lossless because it is not the,
Speaker 2:  Because the AirPods are themselves. Ear pods are shaping the music themselves,
Speaker 2:  right. They got their own algorithms for shaping music,
Speaker 3:  Right. But the 24 bit 48 kilohertz signal comes
Speaker 3:  in, gets converted. And then it gets reconverted back into
Speaker 3:  24 bit 48 kilohertz. So it's like, that level is still
Speaker 3:  maintained, but it can't be called lossless because of the number of times
Speaker 3:  the conversion. So it is like kind of this wonky thing that the
Speaker 3:  gist of it all is it'll probably sound great. It's
Speaker 3:  going to sound great in your AirPods, max. But like you can't
Speaker 3:  say I've got lossless in my ears.
Speaker 1:  I will save apple for years, said nobody could hear this stuff and it wasn't
Speaker 1:  worth it. And now they're like, they're in it.
Speaker 1:  Right. And I think that's because we expect Spotify is going to do it app
Speaker 1:  Amazon music the same day announced they're dropping the price of Amazon
Speaker 1:  music HD something happened. Yeah. Right? Like there was a smoke
Speaker 1:  filled zoom with the music industry
Speaker 2:  And they're like, we're doing it. There was like a bug in the app where you
Speaker 2:  could like see a Hi-Fi option, appear Criswell, found it on Reddit and found
Speaker 2:  it and like confirmed it on his own phone. Here's the thing. I mean,
Speaker 2:  one, the let's just talk about the fact that apple and
Speaker 2:  Amazon giant tech behemoths with piles of cash to
Speaker 2:  burn are offering this for free. When we think Amazon or
Speaker 2:  Spotify is going to have to charge more that's that's thing. One thing
Speaker 2:  too. I know there's a lot of people
Speaker 2:  defending or explaining why the AirPods max can't do it. And
Speaker 2:  like, you know, you don't understand audio and this is why they can't do
Speaker 2:  it, whatever. But I don't know apple chose to make the AirPods
Speaker 2:  max. They, they released them. Not that long ago. Presumably
Speaker 2:  somebody in the AirPods max team could have wandered over to the apple
Speaker 2:  music team and said, Hey, what are you working on? I know that apple is very
Speaker 2:  silent.
Speaker 1:  Come on. Dan is describing, is the wired
Speaker 1:  mode, right? Where to get audio to your computer, you got
Speaker 1:  to do a da, a digital to analog
Speaker 1:  conversion with a phone that happens in the lightning adapter, right?
Speaker 1:  That's why you get an analog audio Jack. And then you plug it in and the
Speaker 1:  AirPods convert it wirelessly the AirPods,
Speaker 1:  max that's Bluetooth and apple doesn't support any
Speaker 1:  lossless protocol over Bluetooth. Like it is necessarily
Speaker 1:  compressed. So when you're like the AirPods max team knew not only did they
Speaker 1:  probably know it was happening down the line with apple music, they
Speaker 1:  knew right from the start that the only Bluetooth Kodak
Speaker 1:  that they were supporting was like limited. And they didn't build it headroom
Speaker 1:  into the system. Could all this change
Speaker 1:  WWDC, could they add a Bluetooth codec to
Speaker 1:  iOS, to the iPhone? Could they update the w one?
Speaker 1:  Like maybe,
Speaker 2:  But then why? Why, why announced it? Why not for now? Yeah,
Speaker 1:  Because the music industry all got together and like you're doing it tomorrow.
Speaker 1:  My face
Speaker 2:  Favorite reaction to all of this is for years and years, Apple's like, this
Speaker 2:  doesn't matter. Nobody can hear it. A bunch of audit. People are like, no,
Speaker 2:  it matters. And now apple announced it at a bunch of audio. People are like,
Speaker 2:  it doesn't matter. Nobody can hear this. It's like completely
Speaker 2:  flipped.
Speaker 1:  So we still have a lot of questions on Sono
Speaker 1:  support, airplay support, like many, many questions to be
Speaker 1:  answered. None of Apple's pages make any of this particularly clear. We got
Speaker 1:  to figure that out. That is just one track of the apple
Speaker 1:  music chaos. And that I promise you is the
Speaker 1:  simpler set of problems to solve because all you're
Speaker 1:  doing is taking, you're taking the existing music library and
Speaker 1:  that you're compressing it. Or in some cases you're encoding it differently.
Speaker 1:  Right? You're you've got stereo audio, two channels. You've
Speaker 1:  got a master version of it somewhere that's uncompressed. And you're going
Speaker 1:  to encode it into one of the many formats and like ship it out over the
Speaker 1:  internet. It, some complicated scheme
Speaker 1:  will eventually make sense. They're also announcing
Speaker 1:  support for Dolby, Atmos and spatial audio, which
Speaker 1:  requires a new library of music that has been
Speaker 1:  re mixed for. Yes. And there is even
Speaker 1:  less information about that. And the only thing I ever think about when
Speaker 1:  I, and it's a different format than Amazon and Sony, which are using
Speaker 1:  like, what's it called Dan some Sony, well,
Speaker 3:  Sony 360 reality. Amazon's actually the one in-between
Speaker 3:  who supports both Atmos and
Speaker 1:  Threats. I think Amazon music is do is 360 reality and not
Speaker 1:  Atmos. I
Speaker 3:  Think it's, I think it's actually both. I mean, I, I could be
Speaker 3:  wrong, but if I remember correctly, the studio it's both, but you,
Speaker 3:  you won't know really which one it is when it, when you're playing it. Like
Speaker 3:  it's just one.
Speaker 1:  Anyhow. All I remember is when you reviewed the echo
Speaker 1:  studio, you discovered the tracks had had
Speaker 1:  instruments added onto them to make them sound more
Speaker 1:  3d. And literally no one tell the story. I don't think
Speaker 1:  anyone has ever explained to us what exactly happened. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  So I'm, I'm testing out. This was a couple of years ago at the echo studio
Speaker 3:  came out, Amazon rolled out its 3d music support with the echo
Speaker 3:  studio that was like their product to showcase it on. And there were like,
Speaker 3:  I don't know, 10 tracks that I could test it with. One of them happened to
Speaker 3:  be Cameron's oh boy. From 2002. So of
Speaker 3:  course I'm listening to that a bunch and I'm listening to it in stereo mode
Speaker 3:  and I'm listening to in a 3d mode. And I realized that when I'm in 3d mode,
Speaker 3:  there's this whole orchestra of strings in the song
Speaker 3:  that don't exist in stereo mode. And like
Speaker 3:  this just, just out of nowhere. And so we get comment on it
Speaker 3:  from Amazon. Amazon's like, you know, studios can choose to
Speaker 3:  add things to the songs. However they feel fit or
Speaker 3:  whatever we tweet about this. It goes out on Twitter, Jonathan, from
Speaker 3:  boy genius who worked in the music industry for a long time, has a lot of
Speaker 3:  connections. There happens to know just blaze. It's
Speaker 3:  like, look what they did to your song.
Speaker 3:  And just places like
Speaker 1:  She's on and paid for this. I don't know. Oh, by the way, the,
Speaker 1:  you are correct. The echo studio supports both and Amazon, Amazon music
Speaker 1:  HD is Atmos, not 360 reality audio. I don't know
Speaker 1:  all these are bad names. My point is, if you think the chaos and
Speaker 1:  confusion of lossless format support is not
Speaker 1:  just wait until artists are like, I remade this in
Speaker 1:  Atmos and you're like, great. I'm going to turn my head and listen for
Speaker 1:  stuff. Then they realize there's nothing to hear back there
Speaker 1:  because they recorded in stereo. And they're like, what if we put some strings
Speaker 1:  in this? Because that's what they're gonna do.
Speaker 1:  I just don't know why I, this is the one
Speaker 1:  where the music industry for
Speaker 1:  years, like their entire revenue model was format
Speaker 1:  shifting. Yeah. You know, like Google it. So they would sell you for years,
Speaker 1:  dark side of the moon by pink. Floyd was like the best selling album in the
Speaker 1:  world. And it's because every couple of years you would go from eight tracks
Speaker 1:  to cassettes, to vinyl, to CDs. And everybody would just ribeye dark
Speaker 1:  side of the moon because you could hear it, you know, like
Speaker 1:  yeah. Like smoke weed and what it was, it was the
Speaker 1:  wizard of Oz. Yeah. So everyone is like, everyone's like hitting play on
Speaker 1:  the eight track player and watching the wizard of Oz. And you're like, oh,
Speaker 1:  I got to buy this on the CD. When they have some real, they don't have shifting
Speaker 1:  anymore. It's just streaming. So this is like an obvious attempt to do a
Speaker 1:  format shift, but they didn't raise the prices. So I've
Speaker 1:  no idea what the point of this is. And then on the other side, the music
Speaker 1:  industry, everybody, all the new artists are just trying to make Tik TOK
Speaker 1:  beats. Yeah. Like half of the music industry is like, the songs need to
Speaker 1:  be one minute long and have a clear hook that you can dance to. And we're
Speaker 1:  going to master it for phones. And the other half the music industry, it's
Speaker 1:  like, we're adding strings to Cameron. So people will buy new
Speaker 1:  speakers. And it just doesn't seem like a
Speaker 1:  strategy to me
Speaker 3:  Anyhow, but will there be strings the tick-tock beats
Speaker 1:  There's always strings than tech sock beats. You got to get the woes man,
Speaker 1:  look, read our record desktop interview. I think my favorite thing that we
Speaker 1:  published last year, I talk about our Ricky desktop profile so
Speaker 1:  much. Okay. Speaking of speakers, the
Speaker 1:  iPad pro has four of them. Hi. Yeah. It was really
Speaker 1:  good. It was great, right? Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. So I reviewed the iPad pro the, the, the 12.9
Speaker 2:  and 11. I did not deeply test spatial audio
Speaker 2:  because it's the same as before. In fact, a lot of this stuff on these iPads
Speaker 2:  at the same as before, the things that are new are center stage, which we
Speaker 2:  discussed, you can follow you around and M one ship. And the
Speaker 2:  12.9 has a mini led display that is called the
Speaker 2:  liquid retina. XDR I believe
Speaker 2:  is the name of that display. And when you want it
Speaker 2:  liquid liquid right next year,
Speaker 1:  Well, we got to talk about display. So in the review,
Speaker 1:  you, I mean, the interview pointed out how it works. It's got
Speaker 1:  this huge grid of micro led. Backlights 10,000 as we
Speaker 1:  were talking about it, I was like, you got to run a blooming test because
Speaker 1:  I'm a gigantic display nerd. Yeah. And that is the first thing I thought
Speaker 1:  of. It seemed like it did pretty okay. On those tests.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I think it did fine. Like you could see it, you can see a little blooming
Speaker 2:  around the little, you know, square dot, moving around the screen. But I
Speaker 2:  haven't personally reviewed a bunch of all the TVs. I've obviously looked
Speaker 2:  at all the TVs. I don't currently own one, but blooming is
Speaker 2:  unavoidable. They've got 2,500 local dimming zones, blah, blah, blah, blah.
Speaker 2:  But that's just there. But when you're actually watching a movie or looking
Speaker 2:  at an HDR photo, you just don't see it. And to be clear, you should know
Speaker 2:  that the brightness on the screen is specifically for full screen
Speaker 2:  application. So you need to go full screen in a video or in a photo
Speaker 2:  for it to kick in the extreme HDR that can
Speaker 2:  peak at 1600 nets and have an overall screen brightness of a thousand minutes.
Speaker 3:  Does it do the thing that the iPhone does when you're watching HDR where
Speaker 3:  it like actually visibly shifts over into HDR mode? Yeah.
Speaker 3:  And
Speaker 2:  It's great. I'm sorry. It's fricking great. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  The, the, the blacks are black. Everything looks amazing. Colors feel more
Speaker 2:  accurate because there's actually detailed the texture that is lost in a
Speaker 2:  traditional backlight system. The screen, when you're like
Speaker 2:  watching movies is incredible. It's so
Speaker 2:  good. Is that worth the extra money? That is, that is between you
Speaker 2:  and bank account to
Speaker 2:  me
Speaker 3:  Because the extra money is it's, it's a hundred dollars more than it was
Speaker 3:  last year. Right? Like that's the
Speaker 2:  Extra one. If they had this thing on the 11 inch out of I'd have bought it
Speaker 2:  by now, I prefer the 11 inch size on the iPad pro. But yeah, I,
Speaker 2:  I wanna like, just, just cause I have no idea why they
Speaker 2:  didn't is it too expensive? Do they want to keep the iPad pro but cheaper,
Speaker 2:  not ha not able to make enough components to fit into both unclear,
Speaker 2:  unknown. So let's the screen. I did run into one weird thing
Speaker 2:  where in dark mode in ebook apps, there's like more than
Speaker 2:  blooming behind it. It's like kind of lit up like big gray
Speaker 2:  squares. You will not see it unless you're in like a pitchback room reading
Speaker 2:  at night, you just won't. But when you see it, you're like, what the hell
Speaker 2:  is that? And it's actually distracting enough to like, have put me off, wanting
Speaker 2:  to use it, to read at night with it,
Speaker 2:  but eating any amount of light at all in the room. And it basically disappears.
Speaker 1:  It's. I mean, I'm assuming there's like a very complicated backlight controller
Speaker 1:  that is just being confused by big blocks of text.
Speaker 2:  Well, I will tell you though, it's like, it's not just blocks of texts. Like
Speaker 2:  in, in, in I books, there's like a page
Speaker 2:  number, page two, just all by itself, down in the
Speaker 2:  bottom of the less left-hand page and nothing else near it. And
Speaker 2:  it had a, like two by two inch square of gray around it for that
Speaker 2:  for one digit.
Speaker 1:  Huh? Apple saying anything about this
Speaker 2:  That they, they, they did
Speaker 2:  not.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Sometimes I'll need to review things. I find vice and they're like,
Speaker 1:  yeah, well we'll get back to you.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I think they're, they're still investigating.
Speaker 1:  Okay. Well, I think if you think about that 10,000 micro led
Speaker 1:  grid, it is basically just a second lower resolution
Speaker 1:  display, like a lower resolution, black and white display
Speaker 1:  behind the, the main color display. Yeah. And
Speaker 1:  so, I mean, we've seen this demo at CS however many times,
Speaker 1:  but like the TV demo, when they show you local dinning,
Speaker 1:  LCDs is they show you each layer of the TV
Speaker 1:  operating. Yep. And so the local dimming one is like, they show you the person
Speaker 1:  walking across the screen. And then there's like a blockier led person walking
Speaker 1:  across the street. Right. And like, it like that display controller and
Speaker 1:  how fast it works and how responsible is like, it's a significant
Speaker 1:  engineering project. And it feels like there's probably a display controller
Speaker 1:  software update that needs to come. Yeah. By the way, I was
Speaker 1:  thinking about this, cause you said the yellow color thing and it occurred
Speaker 1:  to me. I just Googled this. This is probably wrong. But a
Speaker 1:  lot of the way you perceive brightness is based on the green
Speaker 1:  channel, which is why PenTile screens have more green pixels
Speaker 1:  because they can look brighter. Right. I think yellow is like one of the
Speaker 1:  weird ones. So now that you've got like a better backlight, you can actually
Speaker 1:  perceive different. Cause you call that yellow specifically. I've been thinking
Speaker 1:  about it ever since they're like yellow is one of the weirder like harder
Speaker 1:  ones. So you've got a backlight technology that can make the yellows brighter
Speaker 1:  so you can perceive the difference in the yellows is crazy. Me. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  See my obsession with PenTile displays finally paid off. I'm
Speaker 2:  Only going to watch movies with, I don't know, Lee pace at him so I can look
Speaker 2:  at his blonde hair. Very excited.
Speaker 1:  Do you think they're going to do something big at WWDC with this on one ship?
Speaker 1:  I mean, that's like every, every review you call it out, like don't wait.
Speaker 1:  Like nothing indicates that apple is going to make this thing more of a
Speaker 1:  Mac WWE.
Speaker 2:  Right. But like apple has certainly not indicated that they're going to make
Speaker 2:  the same. Well, iOS is for babies as we've learned today. Oh my God. So we
Speaker 2:  should just say the one. If you use very specific apps, you will
Speaker 2:  perceive a speed difference in like rendering or doing stuff. But if you
Speaker 2:  don't know exactly what app is slowed down by the 80 series chip, then you
Speaker 2:  will not notice it is fat is just as fast. It feels fast,
Speaker 2:  whatever it supports Thunderbolt. But again, the
Speaker 2:  way that apple supports third-party accessories on the iPad continues to
Speaker 2:  be frustrating. The one that I specifically called out is
Speaker 2:  audio stuff. So if you have a thing plugged into it that like has a
Speaker 2:  speaker like to my dock, there's no controls to tell the
Speaker 2:  iPad. No, don't use that. Play audio on the iPad. If you can find the
Speaker 2:  setting to like get audio back to the iPad piece, tell me, cause it's not
Speaker 2:  the little airplane looking thing in control center that didn't do it for
Speaker 2:  me. And that's it. Like the iPad is great.
Speaker 2:  And it's like the most enjoyable computer to use until you can't do
Speaker 2:  anything until you like hit a wall. And then it's
Speaker 2:  frustrating. So I have no idea
Speaker 2:  what they're gonna do at WWDC. They are do. Cause like they kind of like
Speaker 2:  if they're, if they're doing like the Tik TOK, small update, big update strategy,
Speaker 2:  last year's iPad update was pretty minimal. They didn't
Speaker 2:  do much. So maybe they're due to do a lot this year, but
Speaker 2:  we will, we will see
Speaker 1:  One of the challenges apple now has is Craig. Federighi just
Speaker 1:  said the entire software model of the pad over IOS's keeping you
Speaker 1:  safe, but Mac is like a car and you have to learn how to drive it and it's
Speaker 1:  not dangerous. And the iPad is like right in the middle of those
Speaker 1:  two approaches. Yup. And what they need to do is make it more open and extensible
Speaker 1:  and flexible and easier to use. But then they're going to have to
Speaker 1:  give up the things in iOS, right?
Speaker 1:  Like if you want to make the iPad truly extensible, you have
Speaker 1:  to de abstract the file system. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  They're just talking to do it. Right. And like, I just wonder like the
Speaker 1:  things people want iPads to do, like you can do most of them, I worked from
Speaker 1:  an iPad for most of today. Actually it was fine. But the second I'm
Speaker 1:  like, I gotta add something like we've had this color. How many times we
Speaker 1:  had this conversation. I can, I just think they're, they're
Speaker 1:  challenged now that they want to keep the iPhones. So locked down in the
Speaker 1:  face of all this antitrust pressure is going to land squarely on the iPad.
Speaker 1:  Not moving. Yeah. Because if they make any concessions on the iPad, people
Speaker 1:  are gonna say, why don't you make the same concessions on the phone? Right.
Speaker 2:  Well, it's got a different name. It's iPad iOS. It's not,
Speaker 1:  I mean, that's why they did it.
Speaker 2:  I mean, honestly, maybe that's why they did it, man. I
Speaker 2:  don't, I could complain about what's computer with the iPad for another
Speaker 2:  three. And I'm sure I will be. What about the, just like
Speaker 2:  briefly, what about the fact that apple, I think we've seen what the
Speaker 2:  M one devices are going to be, right? Like the, the low end Mac book
Speaker 2:  pro the medical care, the iMac, and now surprisingly the
Speaker 2:  iPad, they've just like taken this, this thing and they slapped it in all
Speaker 2:  their consumer stuff. So we know there's another version of
Speaker 2:  the M S process of coming for the higher end Mac book pro and
Speaker 2:  presumably a higher end iMac. Is it weird that the, like,
Speaker 2:  this is just the same chip in the Mac and the iPad is an advisor. The only
Speaker 2:  one that has a hang up on that, I know that they're not going to run Mac
Speaker 2:  apps, but they just like, they like created this amazing board and they just
Speaker 2:  like put it all their computers. And it's like, this feels more plant seed
Speaker 2:  than ever to me.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I don't, I think it it's weird to us. It's probably weird to our listeners.
Speaker 1:  Like now we know it can just do all the things in a way
Speaker 1:  that apple used to have an argument that Intel chips were
Speaker 1:  different and the architectures were different and they had custom built
Speaker 1:  a series processors to do X, Y, and Z. Now it's like, they're just
Speaker 1:  openly saying it's the same chip. And then, you know, over
Speaker 1:  here on Macko S which is starting to inherit a lot of
Speaker 1:  Iowa iOS paradigms, that it can just do all the
Speaker 1:  things. So like, I think there's a weirdness if you know, but I
Speaker 1:  think apple is also very proud of the M one ship. They're very proud of the
Speaker 1:  fact that it can run every form factor from an 11
Speaker 1:  inch iPad up to an iMac and like it, and
Speaker 1:  that's just a huge range of thermal constraints. Did it kinda like do a good
Speaker 1:  job in all those thermal constraints? Give me an one apple
Speaker 1:  watch. I think they're like their
Speaker 1:  general pride at like leading the industry in ship design
Speaker 1:  far supersedes us being like, well, the operating systems are really
Speaker 1:  close and why don't you just let me either touch my Mac or
Speaker 1:  layer a window. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Right. That's the only thing that I need to do. I need to
Speaker 1:  layer some windows or you need to touch this screen. And I think apple just
Speaker 1:  doesn't care. And I really do think, and maybe I'm sure certainly
Speaker 1:  would strenuously deny it. They're in a position right now where to
Speaker 1:  move the iPad to closer to the Mac where a lot of people want it to
Speaker 1:  go. They would have to give up those concessions on the phone. And that is
Speaker 1:  just a dangerous, dangerous place for them to be right at the
Speaker 1:  second.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And I couldn't do it in conclusion. The summary of everything
Speaker 2:  here is they should add malteser to the iPad because it's punitive that they
Speaker 2:  don't. That is, I don't
Speaker 2:  understand why they don't do it because they want to make you buy
Speaker 2:  both. I, that was going to be the original way I was going to conclude the
Speaker 2:  video is like, the reason is because they're going to Ford, they want to
Speaker 2:  make you buy both. And that's like, mean and whatever, but it's
Speaker 2:  not, it's not like the right attitude to take towards the
Speaker 2:  iPad because it is such an amazing computer. But yeah.
Speaker 2:  I just think that they, they want everybody to have an
Speaker 2:  iPad. They think it's a device that it's a lot of work to make it multi-user
Speaker 2:  right. iOS is not architected to be that way from the
Speaker 2:  jump. And so like having to RET cut retcon that
Speaker 2:  in is like a ton of work. I don't know if it's
Speaker 3:  Worth it for them. They, they did that work on the
Speaker 3:  education
Speaker 2:  IPads or like the multi user there's like, okay. I think that they
Speaker 2:  probably don't think it's a good enough experience to like send out to everybody,
Speaker 2:  but I wish they would. They've already, they've already been willing to make
Speaker 2:  the iPad complicated, trying to figure out like mow the windowing experience
Speaker 2:  on the iPad is hard. It's not easy to figure it out. It's not intuitive at
Speaker 2:  all. So whatever, make a comp it's already complicated, make it more
Speaker 2:  complicated offer multi-user so that a family that can't afford four
Speaker 2:  iPads can like actually use one.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Especially with like remote schooling and all this other stuff that
Speaker 1:  we've lived through. Like it's sitting there for them. They just do
Speaker 1:  it. Okay. I want to end, I just want to say this
Speaker 1:  out loud. We did this Starlink review last week, we talked about it at
Speaker 1:  length. This is so dumb. Have you been
Speaker 1:  listening to this show for any amount of time, but for example,
Speaker 1:  over the past 10 years, I will happily disclose to you
Speaker 1:  as many times as you wish that NBC
Speaker 1:  universal a part of Comcast is a minority investor in
Speaker 1:  Vox media, which owns the verge. I promise you that
Speaker 1:  Comcast does not love me. Like I just, I
Speaker 1:  there's the number of experiences I have or I've been
Speaker 1:  told this company is not a fond of our coverage of them is,
Speaker 1:  is numerous. And I also promise you that
Speaker 1:  even if they owned us and controlled us, that would not
Speaker 1:  be what it takes to influence me into saying that wired connections are
Speaker 1:  better than wireless ones, which is
Speaker 1:  just, which is really the thing that people are mad at me for saying that
Speaker 1:  I think the telecom industry in this country
Speaker 1:  has utterly failed to connect people well. And if you look at other
Speaker 1:  countries around the world with different competition models, different policy
Speaker 1:  regimes, someone's treating me and say, I'm on a beach and I'm on a remote
Speaker 1:  beach in Sweden. I'm paying for my fiber providers, basic plan.
Speaker 1:  And I have 200 up and down like that.
Speaker 1:  I understand it's a big country. There's all these issues. Most people in
Speaker 1:  this country have electricity. We can probably do a better job of
Speaker 1:  running broadband cables to way more places and making the market more
Speaker 1:  competitive, which was the heart of my Starlink review. If
Speaker 1:  you look at, if you just look at what the most like the
Speaker 1:  harshest lines in that review are, they are dedicated to the telecom
Speaker 1:  industry in this country. Not Starling, even though I think
Speaker 1:  Starlink for a lot of people might be a good solution in the
Speaker 1:  end. That's all I'm going to say. I don't want to like engage it too much.
Speaker 1:  I just think it's very funny to accuse me in particular of
Speaker 1:  being in the pocket of Comcast. In order to say that wired
Speaker 1:  connections are better than wireless ones. If anything, I'm in the pocket
Speaker 1:  of big HTMI in big. I think people know that.
Speaker 1:  So I just want to put that out there. That's this closure, we
Speaker 1:  disclose it all over the site. We disclose it on a show all the time. I
Speaker 1:  think it is a very funny to I'm sympathetic to it. I understand
Speaker 1:  it. I, some of the criticisms are valid. I got the name of the dish wrong.
Speaker 1:  It's dishy. Make flat face that dish you make takes place. We did correct
Speaker 1:  that in the piece. I think people are so desperate for
Speaker 1:  conductivity. They're missing. They're angry. They're angry at the wrong
Speaker 1:  things. There's like a helplessness about broadband in this
Speaker 1:  country that is utterly devastating to see in person.
Speaker 1:  And so I'm not upset or mad about this. I'm just pointing
Speaker 1:  out how upset other people are
Speaker 1:  that Teeter lives in San Francisco. Yeah. San Francisco
Speaker 1:  is
Speaker 2:  Everyone's upset that I live here.
Speaker 1:  I mean, I used to live in New York city. Like even if you want to make the
Speaker 1:  big land, you know, America's big and population like in
Speaker 1:  San Francisco, in New York city, two of the most densely populated and
Speaker 1:  expensive places to live in this country. It is hard to get good
Speaker 1:  broadband like Dieter your broadband connection. It's not
Speaker 1:  like you don't have like gigabit.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, no, it's not available to me. The best I can get is DOCSIS
Speaker 2:  from Xfinity. And I hate it. There you
Speaker 2:  go. I'm paying for their max to their max plan. And it's like, you know,
Speaker 2:  a gig down, but not usually doesn't hit that. And it's a 25
Speaker 2:  up. And why is it only 25 up? Who knows? And
Speaker 2:  I think if I moved, if I, if I happened to have moved like six blocks, I
Speaker 2:  would have access to Sonic, which is an independent
Speaker 2:  ISP. I think it runs on top of anti ADTs
Speaker 2:  fiber. And I would love to give them my money. I would be so happy to get
Speaker 2:  my money to an independent ISP. There's another independent ISP here in San
Speaker 2:  Francisco called Monkeybrains, which is very good, but it's just like, it's
Speaker 2:  microwaves and it's, it's a little bit too slow for my needs. So
Speaker 2:  my plan here, living where I live is if I need to upload something, I
Speaker 2:  will get on my bike and ride to our office. That's 20 minutes away and go
Speaker 2:  through our COVID protocols. No, I'm serious. I go, I, I go through our COVID
Speaker 2:  protocols. I like fill out the survey. I get permission from the company
Speaker 2:  to go to the office so that I can upload a file that's or then,
Speaker 2:  you know, a bunch of gigabytes, like 20 gigabytes. Anytime I shoot video,
Speaker 2:  I have to go to the office because Comcast is the only
Speaker 2:  provider I have here. And they suck.
Speaker 1:  Anyway. I just think that's like, that's San Francisco. That's not the middle
Speaker 1:  of rural America, which is where I'm sitting. I only have one
Speaker 1:  choice. That's all I want to adjust. The Starlink review
Speaker 1:  was more about broadband in America than one thing. And it was in
Speaker 1:  particular about American telecom
Speaker 1:  policy. Always promising you a new connectivity technology instead
Speaker 1:  of investing into deploying the ones that work and
Speaker 1:  making sure those markets are competitive. I think that is a mistake. I think
Speaker 1:  you can look around the world and see other countries that have made different
Speaker 1:  policy choices and their citizens are connected and much faster
Speaker 1:  for much lower prices. That's it? Disclosure and
Speaker 1:  NBC universal, a division of Comcast. Isn't a minority investor in Vox
Speaker 1:  media, which owns the verge. And I, I
Speaker 1:  promise you, I absolutely promise you. They do not let
Speaker 1:  us okay. That's it. That's a very fast, I didn't mean for that to take too
Speaker 1:  long, but if you know me, you know that I'm very passionate about
Speaker 1:  property palsy. It routinely bores the staff
Speaker 1:  of the verge to tears. That's my real problem is the constant low-grade
Speaker 1:  mutiny. If I talk about broadband policy anymore, all right, that's it, that's
Speaker 1:  very fast. We've got another episode. We went for an hour
Speaker 1:  and another episode coming
Speaker 1:  later, or more than
Speaker 1:  that, we went for an hour and we went
Speaker 1:  over is what I'm really trying to say. But Addie and I are going to do
Speaker 1:  another episode of the verge hassle later today, after Tim cook wraps
Speaker 1:  up his epic versus apple testimony. So look out
Speaker 1:  for that. You can tweet at us. Dieter is at backline.
Speaker 1:  Dan is at DCC Siefert I'm at
Speaker 1:  reckless. By the time this comes out, I'm going to tell you, episode of
Speaker 1:  Dakota with Ford CEO, Jim Farley, talking about the new F-150 50
Speaker 1:  lightening, we'll be up in the world. That was a wild hunt.
Speaker 1:  He basically told me that you'd be able to upgrade the computers in cars,
Speaker 1:  the same way you can upgrade like the shocks and the seats.
Speaker 1:  Ooh, I would love to see that happen. He did not
Speaker 1:  have an answer when I said, will I be able to upgrade my current cards here,
Speaker 1:  new Android operating system. Just didn't answer that here.
Speaker 1:  I think I know the answer. I think that means I know the
Speaker 1:  answer to that question, but that is good. Yeah, that it's, that was a really
Speaker 1:  fun episode to do. Like I said, we'll be back later, later on Friday
Speaker 1:  with apple versus epic and we'll be back again next week. That's it.
Speaker 1:  Rock and roll. Encourage your family to get back.
Speaker 1:  .