# Transcript
ID: 29e4a4a0-46c3-11ec-9563-1df25c4c3794
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Let's Chat about RCS
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/1336462472/19991034/s93290-US-2221s-1637055267.mp3
Description: The Verge's Dieter Bohn dives into the messy past and uncertain future of Rich Communication Services, or RCS, a new texting standard that Google had been pushing for Android users.
Speaker 1:  Sorry to interrupt. I'm going to go because there's breaking
Speaker 1:  RCS news. The carriers have basically formed a consortium to hijack
Speaker 1:  it and steal it away from Google. And I am the only person that can write
Speaker 1:  this story. So I got to go. Okay. I'll just tell people that you had to drop
Speaker 1:  for breaking RC. I'm going to just tell them exactly what happened.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I got to go make some calls. Bye bye.
Speaker 1:  That's hilarious. Back in October, 2019,
Speaker 1:  I was out in some rented podcast studio doing the Vergecast.
Speaker 1:  I couldn't get back to the office in time. And even though it's really not
Speaker 1:  a great idea to do during a podcast recording, I happened to check my
Speaker 1:  email and I saw something nuts. The big four
Speaker 1:  us cell phone carriers had agreed to form a new coalition to
Speaker 1:  support a new texting standard.
Speaker 1:  I immediately bailed on the verge cast, sorry, Nila. I ran
Speaker 1:  out to my car that was parked in this random street. And I started making
Speaker 1:  calls. I was trying to get to the bottom of the so-called
Speaker 1:  new cross carrier messaging initiative. The
Speaker 1:  CCMI it was a consortium that could mean that we might finally
Speaker 1:  get rid of SMS texting and move on to a new
Speaker 1:  standard that Google had been pushing for Android users. It was called rich
Speaker 1:  communication services or
Speaker 1:  RCS. As I sat in my car
Speaker 1:  reporting and making calls, I learned that the carriers were promising to
Speaker 1:  create their own texting app, which sounded
Speaker 1:  horrible. So we all waited for a long time
Speaker 1:  for this bad plan to go into effect. And it never did that.
Speaker 1:  Blockbuster announcement was pretty much the last thing we heard about
Speaker 1:  CCMI T-Mobile eventually bought sprint and it took until
Speaker 1:  April of 2021 for the carriers to admit, and
Speaker 1:  only under lots of reporting pressure that they had given up on the
Speaker 1:  CCMI. Here's the thing about this
Speaker 1:  new texting standard RCS, almost every story about
Speaker 1:  it ends up feeling like this. There's a big splash makes you
Speaker 1:  think. Maybe, maybe we're going to finally be able to replace SMS
Speaker 1:  with something that's not limited to 160 characters of text.
Speaker 1:  Then time goes by and not much happens. And we wait some
Speaker 1:  more I'm Dieter Bohn. And this week on the verge
Speaker 1:  cast, special run of topic specific Tuesday episodes. I think it's
Speaker 1:  finally time that we really dig into RCS, where it came from, why
Speaker 1:  it matters, where it's going, and of course,
Speaker 1:  whether or not apple will ever support it on the
Speaker 1:  iPhone.
Speaker 1:  You probably know that smartphones really got started with the iPhone, but
Speaker 1:  did you know there was an innovative app driven smartphone six years
Speaker 1:  before it, I took off like a rocket. Everybody
Speaker 1:  wanted this product In a new documentary from the verge called
Speaker 1:  springboard, the secret history of the first real smartphone. We look at
Speaker 1:  a tiny startup called handspring that tried to create the modern phone
Speaker 1:  before anybody was ready for it. You can watch springboard now for
Speaker 1:  free on the verge TV app and learn more at the
Speaker 1:  verge.com/springboard. That's the
Speaker 1:  verge.com/springboard.
Speaker 1:  If you've heard of RCS, it's probably because you heard that it's supposed
Speaker 1:  to be Google solution for texting on Android phones. It is
Speaker 1:  better than SMS because it's internet based. Instead of using a weird
Speaker 1:  network hack, it offers features like better group chats, read
Speaker 1:  receipts, typing indicators and bigger image and video
Speaker 1:  attachments. RCS is not controlled by any single company, but
Speaker 1:  instead it's handled by the carriers to route messages or if they don't want
Speaker 1:  to Google can do it. There are a lot of details to get into, but
Speaker 1:  that's the basic gist of what RCS is, but to really
Speaker 1:  understand why Google has gone all in on RCS, you need to understand
Speaker 1:  that there's a rich and complicated history of messaging apps at
Speaker 1:  Google, and that RCS has its own history. That's
Speaker 1:  actually entirely separate from Google. So let's start with the history
Speaker 1:  of RCS and actually look back at SMS and what it meant, but
Speaker 1:  I promise this isn't going to go for like three plus hours, like Dan Carlin's
Speaker 1:  hardcore history podcast, but it is gonna take a minute. It's just, there
Speaker 1:  are some foundational concepts in this history that we're going to need to
Speaker 1:  know to understand what's happening with RCS.
Speaker 1:  So SMS stands for short messaging service, and it's been the way that
Speaker 1:  phones can text each other. Since phone started texting each other in the
Speaker 1:  nineties, in fact, phone carriers back then didn't realize that texting
Speaker 1:  would be a thing that people wanted to do. So it came later than
Speaker 1:  regular phone calls and worked by taking advantage of some of the parts of
Speaker 1:  the phone networks that carriers used for other technical things.
Speaker 1:  That's why SMS is text only and why it's limited to
Speaker 1:  160 characters because that's all that will fit. It's difficult
Speaker 1:  to imagine now, but for a long time, SMS messaging was a
Speaker 1:  big business for carriers. They literally charged by the
Speaker 1:  text and it took a long time for so-called unlimited messaging to
Speaker 1:  be included in most plans, who are you
Speaker 3:  Texting 50 times a day,
Speaker 1:  And then MMS multimedia messaging was a hack on top of the SMS
Speaker 1:  hack. And it costs even more money per message. That high price is
Speaker 1:  actually super important to our story here because that high price was a
Speaker 1:  big mistake from the carriers because SMS cost so much and
Speaker 1:  provided so little. When smartphones came around, there was a rush to
Speaker 1:  make texting apps that costs less or were free. They sprouted
Speaker 1:  up everywhere and they jockeyed for market share. There was Blackberry messaging
Speaker 1:  and WhatsApp and KakaoTalk and line and MSN messenger. I message
Speaker 1:  him Facebook messenger and so on. And so on. All of them either had, or some
Speaker 1:  of them still have lots of users depending on what part of the world you
Speaker 1:  lived in. In fact, if you're not in the United States, all of this trauma
Speaker 1:  around RCS, or I message seems really silly because the chances are
Speaker 1:  better that you and all of your friends and family have already all agreed
Speaker 1:  to use one single app to talk to each other. So when it comes to making
Speaker 1:  money off of texting, the carriers eventually lost out boo hoo.
Speaker 1:  Right? But even though a lot of those apps were placed SMS for a lot of
Speaker 1:  people, they didn't kill SMS entirely because SMS is the
Speaker 1:  default. It's the basic fallback that you can pretty much trust will work
Speaker 1:  with any mobile phone. You might not know if I can receive a group message,
Speaker 1:  but you definitely know that I can receive an SMS text anyway, because of
Speaker 1:  all of that free competition, the carriers were forced to eventually stop
Speaker 1:  charging extra for texting on most of their plans. But, and this
Speaker 1:  is the key part that meant that texting was almost never going to
Speaker 1:  be a moneymaker for carriers. Again, not really. So in
Speaker 1:  2007 way before you thought a bunch of carriers got
Speaker 1:  together and said, Hey, this SMS tech is old and dumb and we should
Speaker 1:  replace it. And a bunch of them said, sure, but there was no
Speaker 1:  incentive for them to actually do the work to change it. That was the
Speaker 1:  beginning of RCS, but it would continue to be a total, nothing
Speaker 1:  burger for over a decade. So that's the
Speaker 1:  history of SMS and the very beginning of RCS. Now what about the history
Speaker 1:  of messaging at Google? Look, I don't
Speaker 1:  have time to get into everything that Google tried and I definitely don't
Speaker 1:  have the emotional energy, but there is a short version that I already
Speaker 1:  did in a YouTube video when Google first announced RCS. So let's
Speaker 1:  listen to that. So in 2005, Google launched Google
Speaker 1:  talks, you might notice Google chat. It was really popular. It was really
Speaker 1:  good. So when Android launched in 2008, they included
Speaker 1:  alongside SMS because that's what you do in 2009, the iPhone
Speaker 1:  got push notifications, which made apps like WhatsApp gets super popular.
Speaker 1:  And then when they came to Android, also it got popular there. So Google
Speaker 1:  had a problem to solve. So in 2011, they didn't
Speaker 1:  solve it. They saw Facebook and they're like, we want some of that. So they
Speaker 1:  launched a Google plus, which had yet more chat apps in it. It has huddle
Speaker 1:  for texts and Hangouts, a video for video chat, not the same Hangouts.
Speaker 1:  It's, you know, though it was just confusing. Anyway, in late
Speaker 1:  2011, I message. And Facebook messenger launched and they were way
Speaker 1:  simpler than Google, what Google had. And so Google had to fix it again.
Speaker 1:  And so a couple of years later, in 2013, they launched Hangouts, which took
Speaker 1:  all those other apps and combined them into a single app. And everything
Speaker 1:  was great for a couple of years. And then hang out, sit and get updated.
Speaker 1:  Google plus was like failing and they pulled texting out of it. And it was
Speaker 1:  just a big mess again. And so in 2016, Google's
Speaker 1:  like, we're going to fix it again. They launched aloe for text chat
Speaker 1:  and duo for video chat duo super-popular
Speaker 1:  Allo, not so much. Meanwhile, Hangouts turn into this
Speaker 1:  like enterprise slack competitor thing. I dunno, whatever. I haven't even
Speaker 1:  mentioned Google voice and Google wave and all the other crazy experiments
Speaker 1:  Google has been doing. It's been a rolling 10 year disaster, and
Speaker 1:  Google has to fix it. I mean, look at all this stuff,
Speaker 1:  what the Watts we made that video in 2018, that was
Speaker 1:  10 years after RCS was first proposed. And it was the moment that Google
Speaker 1:  made its big announcement that it was going all in on RCS as
Speaker 1:  the default texting solution for Android carriers around the world
Speaker 1:  said, oh, Hey, that's right. We had this RCS thing.
Speaker 1:  Okay, good luck with that. Google, when we made that video in April, 2018,
Speaker 1:  Google told me that it expected the switch over to RCS to take six to
Speaker 1:  12 months. It's now November of 2021.
Speaker 1:  And RCS is still not fully rolled
Speaker 1:  out.
Speaker 1:  Okay. With all of that history under our belt. Now it's time to
Speaker 1:  answer some questions. The most important one, I think gets to the
Speaker 1:  central tension of RCS as a standard. Is it a
Speaker 1:  carrier thing or is it a Google thing? So I spoke to
Speaker 1:  Sonata Hari, who is the senior director of communication products at
Speaker 1:  Google about precisely that question
Speaker 4:  And Google didn't create RCS. And like around
Speaker 4:  2015, where we got more involved, there were even like
Speaker 4:  different flavors of RCS. There was like a European
Speaker 4:  RCS, U S one. And so there was a
Speaker 4:  deviations before there was even any scale, the role that we played
Speaker 4:  in, you know, it was us as well as everyone else that was already engaged,
Speaker 4:  given that it is a telecom spec, was we really pushed for kind of
Speaker 4:  alignment on the set of capabilities, which ended up manifesting
Speaker 4:  itself as the universal profile, which is now the
Speaker 4:  GSM standard. You know, we were
Speaker 4:  participating along with the rest of the industry in terms of
Speaker 4:  aligning on one common definition of this and having one
Speaker 4:  common spec.
Speaker 1:  Now there are a lot and I mean, a lot of technical details behind
Speaker 1:  what Sonos is talking about here. For example, when she refers to different
Speaker 1:  flavors of RCS, what she means is that carriers literally used to have their
Speaker 1:  own proprietary versions of RCS that were incompatible with each other. So
Speaker 1:  like 80 and T and Verizon, for example, have their own custom texting
Speaker 1:  apps that you could install if you hated having good apps. And those
Speaker 1:  technically had RCS on the backend, but hopefully those days are going to
Speaker 1:  be behind a soon. Another thing is that when you send a text with
Speaker 1:  say WhatsApp, for example, there is one company that's in charge of making
Speaker 1:  sure it goes where it's supposed to the company that owns WhatsApp, Facebook,
Speaker 1:  or I guess Metta or whatever. But when you send an SMS or an
Speaker 1:  RCS, there are a lot of companies involved in routing that text
Speaker 1:  message and making sure that it gets to you so that universal profile that's
Speaker 1:  not as referred to is the standard way for that routing to happen so that
Speaker 1:  everybody can talk to everybody. So Google has been pushing for
Speaker 1:  a universal profile adoption, but a bunch of carriers haven't
Speaker 1:  updated to support it or even support RCS itself yet they just don't
Speaker 1:  seem to be interested. Lots of companies are also reticent to make deals
Speaker 1:  with Google. It turns out. So even though Google is pushing standards,
Speaker 1:  take a lot of time to get going. Obviously
Speaker 4:  The more people are involved in any problem that requires consensus that
Speaker 4:  you have, you know, it takes longer regardless of the problem.
Speaker 4:  However, you know, the benefits are, are pretty high because,
Speaker 4:  you know, especially in a world where we believe that communication is a
Speaker 4:  right, and everybody should be able to communicate with their phone in a
Speaker 4:  reliable and rich way. You know, the benefits are worth
Speaker 4:  the extra effort that's required to get into this. And you know, this is
Speaker 4:  my nature, you know, we're replacing something else that is a global standard
Speaker 4:  SMS, as old as it is. It has lasted the test of
Speaker 4:  time in the sense that it does have global adoption. And so I
Speaker 4:  do feel like it's a responsibility that we should not take lightly. And thus
Speaker 4:  the standard approaches is very, very important given that, you know, it
Speaker 4:  is replacing something that does meet the bar on that.
Speaker 4:  However, I do think, you know, obviously we have
Speaker 4:  exercise some flexibility on top of the standard in
Speaker 4:  terms of how we can advance our client to meet the end-user needs
Speaker 4:  of the modern user needs for messaging as well.
Speaker 1:  Just a little bit more technical detailed to understand some of the complication
Speaker 1:  here for messaging app to work. There's basically two parts, there's the
Speaker 1:  servers, but then there's also the client AKA the app on the
Speaker 1:  phone. And unlike SMS on Android, RCS only works with
Speaker 1:  specific approved client Habs. And so the features of
Speaker 1:  what RCS can do end up being a mix of what can be routed through all of those
Speaker 1:  servers, but more importantly, what features get added to the client
Speaker 1:  apps. So I started this whole section by asking if
Speaker 1:  RCS is a carrier thing or a Google thing. And now with all of these
Speaker 1:  technical details, we can answer that question. It's
Speaker 1:  yes, it's both. The carriers are in charge of the
Speaker 1:  standard and the servers and Google is in charge of
Speaker 1:  the app where the rubber hits the road or where the emoji
Speaker 1:  hits the chat box. And also technically Google can
Speaker 1:  also run some servers to route messages. The bottom line is that
Speaker 1:  it's messy and Google knows a thing or two about
Speaker 1:  messy, messy drama with messaging apps
Speaker 1:  recently, random audio reviews editor at ARS Technica wrote an amazing
Speaker 1:  overview of every single messaging app that Google has tried over the
Speaker 1:  years. We're going to link it in the show notes. I really encourage you to
Speaker 1:  read it because he brought up a bunch of apps that I had completely forgotten
Speaker 1:  about, but I wanted to talk to Ron because he is a person who can take
Speaker 1:  all this highfalutin open RCS, talked down a peg.
Speaker 1:  He's not,
Speaker 5:  I mean, RCS because it's a 12 or 13 year old standard
Speaker 5:  has ideas that we thought were a great idea, 12 or 13 years ago,
Speaker 5:  but it's missing a ton of things you would want from a modern messaging
Speaker 5:  standard like device support and encryption and a ton of other
Speaker 5:  features it's going to make SMS better, but you're going to go from the worst
Speaker 5:  messaging platform in the world to a slightly
Speaker 5:  worse messaging platform, but still the worst messaging platform in the world.
Speaker 1:  Wow. Yeah. So was the idea to replace SMS way back when they first were forming
Speaker 1:  it in the GSMs? Or was it some other random thing?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I mean, SMS has carrier messaging used to be
Speaker 5:  important. Like they, they used to charge us money for SMS, right. It was
Speaker 5:  a huge revenue stream. And so it made sense to kind of keep that going and
Speaker 5:  keep updating carrier messaging. But I think as messaging
Speaker 5:  became commoditized, you know, everybody has an unlimited texting plan now
Speaker 5:  there's really no reason for them to, to be interested in updating it anymore.
Speaker 5:  So it's been, it's just kind of been hanging out and nobody's really sure
Speaker 5:  what
Speaker 1:  I would assume that the carriers would want to get off of SMS. They can,
Speaker 1:  I don't know, do something more interesting or I don't wanna use that random,
Speaker 1:  weird channel that it uses for something else or whatever. Why do you think
Speaker 1:  it took Google to start saying, Hey, no, this is our thing. And everyone
Speaker 1:  should start doing it to, you know, get carriers to even think about bothering
Speaker 1:  with it in the first place.
Speaker 5:  Well, like I said, revenue, I don't think the carriers are that interested
Speaker 5:  in getting off of SMS. Like w why would they, there's no bottom line
Speaker 5:  opportunity for them.
Speaker 1:  So the carriers had this RCS thing, but they had no incentive
Speaker 1:  to do anything with it. Google on the other hand had year after year of
Speaker 1:  bungled messaging apps. So Google had a huge incentive to figure
Speaker 1:  out messaging for Android, but Google knew it. Couldn't just launch another
Speaker 1:  app again, because Google had tried that and it didn't work. It was just
Speaker 1:  too much of a fight to get anybody to use a brand new Google app, but
Speaker 1:  maybe they could get this RCS thing to work and that the carriers
Speaker 1:  would go along. If they did, you know, that old Winston Churchill quote about
Speaker 1:  how democracy is the worst form of government, except every other one has
Speaker 1:  already been tried. Yeah. RCS is kind of like that for Google,
Speaker 1:  but also as Ron points out, don't forget that Google is
Speaker 1:  massive. And one reason it's tried so many things is because it's
Speaker 1:  such a big chaotic company.
Speaker 5:  I don't like talking about the company is like a monolith. I think the motivations
Speaker 5:  are individual product managers trying to launch a product. And I think we've
Speaker 5:  seen, you know, some product manager will launch aloe and then it won't
Speaker 5:  work. And then they will leave and go join Facebook. And then a new
Speaker 5:  person will show up and launch a new messaging app. And I
Speaker 5:  think RCS, you can give the utopia sales pitch for it where, oh, it's going
Speaker 5:  to work on every smartphone. And I, I think that's why they started,
Speaker 5:  like, they've done every messaging idea in the world. And this is just the
Speaker 5:  next one that no one has tried yet.
Speaker 1:  So whether it's a genuine desire to fix SMS, an honest attempt to
Speaker 1:  spread a standard or just PTSD from all those failed
Speaker 1:  attempts, Google is committed. It is all in on
Speaker 1:  RCS going forward. Okay, we're going to take a break.
Speaker 1:  And when we come back, we've got another question to answer. How's it going
Speaker 1:  with RCS,
Speaker 1:  Google.
Speaker 1:  We're back for our special Vergecast episode, focusing on RCS as
Speaker 1:  the new way that Android phones are supposed to text. Now,
Speaker 1:  Google announced this RCS change for Android in April,
Speaker 1:  2018 and figured it would take a year or so for most carriers to switch
Speaker 1:  over. But by June, 2019, barely any had, it
Speaker 1:  was not going well. So Google took matters into its own
Speaker 1:  hands. Now, do you remember how RCS requires both a
Speaker 1:  server and an app? Well, Google just started offering
Speaker 1:  RCS services to people who are using its messages app on
Speaker 1:  Android, whether or not their carrier had turned it on. Google just
Speaker 1:  started connecting people to Google's own servers.
Speaker 4:  We have also really invested in ensuring that RCS is
Speaker 4:  accessible even in markets and where carriers don't
Speaker 4:  have any plans or haven't built RCS. Yet, we just
Speaker 4:  offer the availability for users to be able to have
Speaker 4:  RCS, even before their carriers. We're kind of offering
Speaker 4:  it within their markets. So in many ways, we've just accelerated the
Speaker 4:  adoption. And again, you know, we've, we've done this in partnership with
Speaker 4:  the ecosystem as a whole, but we do feel that it's a responsibility we
Speaker 4:  have in terms of having our users have a better messaging
Speaker 4:  experience. That's not 30 years old.
Speaker 1:  Here's how it works. If a carrier wants to connect you to its
Speaker 1:  servers via RCS, Google lets the carrier handle routing
Speaker 1:  for your messages. But if your carrier doesn't want to do
Speaker 1:  RCS or can't get around to it or whatever, Google will just do it
Speaker 1:  for them. Now the technical details of how that
Speaker 1:  happens and how RCS messages work are about as interesting as you might
Speaker 1:  guess, the technical details of routing messages through servers might
Speaker 1:  be, but there is one thing that might seem really
Speaker 1:  obvious, but we should explicitly talk about it. The way that you get
Speaker 1:  RCS messages is via your phone number. Just like
Speaker 1:  SMS. This is a carrier standard after all. Even if it's Google,
Speaker 1:  that seems to be the one, doing all the work to push it. Now this is a whole
Speaker 1:  other podcast, but phone numbers, they're a very annoying and
Speaker 1:  I would go so far as to say horrible identification technology. Here's
Speaker 1:  random audio. Again,
Speaker 5:  The problem I have with RCS is that because it's made by the GMA, it relies
Speaker 5:  on a phone number and a SIM card and a phone bill. And that means
Speaker 5:  anything. That's not a phone cannot like natively send an RCS
Speaker 5:  message. Google has cooked up a few like weird pairing
Speaker 5:  systems where like you compare a website, your phone with a QR code. And
Speaker 5:  then if you type a message into the web browser, it gets forwarded to your
Speaker 5:  phone, which gets forwarded to the internet. But that's still not a native
Speaker 5:  application. Like I want a messaging service to work on a tablet and
Speaker 5:  a laptop and a desktop and a smartwatch and you know,
Speaker 5:  a brain implant and whatever other weird devices we come up with. So
Speaker 5:  like you can't, you can't go jogging and leave your smartphone at home and
Speaker 5:  get a message because everything, your phone is the center of your,
Speaker 5:  it has to be the center of your messaging life. If you use Austria
Speaker 1:  And like picking the phone number, seems like that was definitely like a
Speaker 1:  carrier capture thing. I think that one of the, one of the points you made
Speaker 1:  in your piece was there's like an immoral aspect to making the phone
Speaker 1:  number, the source of identity, because it's the thing that fundamentally
Speaker 1:  you're leasing. You have to pay a monthly bill to
Speaker 5:  Keep it. Yeah. I mean, that's as opposed to like an email address,
Speaker 5:  nobody technically really owns their email address or their phone number.
Speaker 5:  But like I probably have an email from Yahoo that's been abandoned for like
Speaker 5:  15 years that it probably still works. Whereas a phone number, if you ever
Speaker 5:  stopped paying the bill, they like take your identity from you. If you're
Speaker 5:  using a phone number as identity and they will like give it to someone else,
Speaker 5:  like pretty quickly, which is, which is crazy. And if something
Speaker 5:  happens to you, you know, if you end up in the hospital or go to jail or
Speaker 5:  something to where you can't continually pay a phone bill, you just lose
Speaker 5:  your identity. And, and I think it causes a lot of problems for people that
Speaker 5:  want to borrow a phone. Also like if you can't afford a phone, it's pretty
Speaker 5:  easy to get on the internet. Like you can go to a library in New York city,
Speaker 5:  they replaced all the telephone boosts with like kiosks. You can just walk
Speaker 5:  up to and go on the internet. And if you use a phone number for
Speaker 5:  identity, you are locked out of all of these services
Speaker 1:  From Google's perspective, it really did want RCS to be
Speaker 1:  a universal standard, not a Google technology, even though
Speaker 1:  everybody associates it with Google right now. And since RCS started
Speaker 1:  as a telecom spec, well, what else were they going to use? But phone
Speaker 1:  numbers,
Speaker 4:  You know, a, we were looking at the RCS as a
Speaker 4:  telecom spec that was in place for numbers are, are a core part of
Speaker 4:  that. And also the lens that we ideally really want
Speaker 4:  as some nice to be upgraded. So in some ways it's really important that the
Speaker 4:  identity works for the global user base that uses
Speaker 4:  SMS today. And, you know, there are many Google users, but not the
Speaker 4:  whole world uses a Google accounts that may also have its own challenges
Speaker 4:  in terms of whether people want to use that as their identity or not.
Speaker 4:  And SMS for all of its problems. Like, you know, it is kind of a
Speaker 4:  known notion and it is a known identifier that from a global
Speaker 4:  perspective has a pretty broad reach and
Speaker 4:  understanding. And again, you know, we were very much kind of
Speaker 4:  aligned with us back overall and what the identifiers
Speaker 4:  should be. And so from that perspective, it's, it's global and it's
Speaker 4:  reachable. And I think that's really, really important when we think of this
Speaker 4:  bingo messaging protocol that works for anybody anywhere in the
Speaker 4:  world.
Speaker 1:  Okay, we're going to take one more quick break and then we're going to get
Speaker 1:  into what's next for RCS and Google's messages app.
Speaker 1:  And you know, we also need to talk about whether or not it's coming to the
Speaker 1:  iPhone.
Speaker 4:  We're back. And it's time to talk about what's next for
Speaker 4:  RCS. The good news is that after five years of
Speaker 4:  mucking about Google, just up and spent much of
Speaker 4:  2021 cutting deals with the big
Speaker 4:  three us carriers, there's only three now, sorry,
Speaker 4:  the deals were this in 2022 Google's messages app
Speaker 4:  will be the default texting app on every Android phone sold by
Speaker 4:  Verizon T-Mobile at, at and T.
Speaker 1:  That seems like not a big deal, but actually it's a huge deal.
Speaker 1:  Because again, remember that for RCS to work, you need both the server
Speaker 1:  and the app and in the world of Android, not
Speaker 1:  everybody uses the same texting app and a lot of those apps don't
Speaker 1:  support RCS. So if different people using different
Speaker 1:  texting apps, RCS doesn't happen. Having everybody on the
Speaker 1:  same app means that RCS can finally get going, but
Speaker 1:  also having everybody on the Google messages app means that Google can build
Speaker 1:  stuff on top of RCS. If both people are
Speaker 1:  using the Google messages, apps, then those apps end up talking directly
Speaker 1:  to each other and Google can turn on extra features like
Speaker 1:  end-to-end encryption for one-on-one chats. So now as a Hari
Speaker 1:  also hinted that maybe some other features might becoming like
Speaker 1:  encryption for group chats or better multi-device support. But you know,
Speaker 1:  first there are some baby steps we still have to take.
Speaker 4:  Let's just take the us as a market. We actually need to launch our
Speaker 4:  CS with the who S carriers. We need to make sure all of these
Speaker 4:  carriers can talk to each other and be able to talk to users in
Speaker 4:  Europe and India, et cetera. So the global vision needs to, in many ways,
Speaker 4:  the execution really, really needs to land. And then, you know, it's really
Speaker 4:  important that this happens multi-device so we need to make sure
Speaker 4:  that this works not just on, but on watch on, on
Speaker 4:  desktop, on all the different devices that users really expect their messaging
Speaker 4:  experience for. And then obviously we have started the journey on
Speaker 4:  antenna encryption. We still need to kind of fill that out. Obviously
Speaker 4:  we've started with one-on-one. We need to complete that picture
Speaker 4:  holistically. And then there's other things that I can think of. Like we
Speaker 4:  see so many communications move from email to
Speaker 4:  messaging. When I look at like the capabilities on messages versus
Speaker 4:  like Gmail, there's so many capabilities that we built in
Speaker 4:  Gmail for users to just be able to manage their inbox. A lot of those
Speaker 4:  things, I think also messaging clients as a whole need to evolve in
Speaker 4:  terms of we get personal messages, we get business messages. There's different
Speaker 4:  ways of managing important things, priority things, et
Speaker 4:  cetera, that I think those capabilities are going to evolve as more and more
Speaker 4:  communication kind of centers around messaging as a
Speaker 4:  whole,
Speaker 1:  By the way, there is one other confusing bit about RCS that I haven't mentioned
Speaker 1:  it's that in the app itself, Google calls it chat, but Google also
Speaker 1:  has another app that's called Google chat, but they're two different things.
Speaker 1:  It's very annoying. It's not my fault,
Speaker 1:  hopefully in a year, that might be the only confusing thing about
Speaker 1:  RCS that we have to worry about. I'm just kidding.
Speaker 1:  Obviously. There's another thing to worry about. There's an elephant in the
Speaker 1:  RCS room, or rather there's a missing elephant, a ghost
Speaker 1:  elephant. This is a bad metaphor. I'm talking about the
Speaker 1:  iPhone on
Speaker 1:  the iPhone. You've got iMessage. And then it falls back to
Speaker 1:  SMS on Android. You have RCS and it will
Speaker 1:  also fall back to SMS, but RCS, isn't supposed to be an
Speaker 1:  Android thing. It's supposed to be the thing that replaces SMS.
Speaker 1:  So will the iPhone ever support the thing that's supposed to
Speaker 1:  replace SMS? Will it ever support RCS? Because if
Speaker 1:  RCS becomes a standard and actually replaces SMS, Apple's
Speaker 1:  going to have to support it. Right? Right. I have
Speaker 1:  asked this question to apple many times and the
Speaker 1:  answer is always the same. No comment. I also asked
Speaker 1:  Sinaz over at Google, what her perspective is.
Speaker 4:  I don't work at apple. I do believe that, you know, the point
Speaker 4:  of an open spec is one that everyone can participate
Speaker 4:  in. I think they all it to their users as well. And
Speaker 4:  it's it's time that, you know, the industry as a whole, a lot of the people
Speaker 4:  that are still using SMS, they can have rich messaging. They can
Speaker 4:  have typing indicators, they can message over wifi. They can have
Speaker 4:  unbroken group chats and send high quality photos. And it's all
Speaker 4:  based on an open standard. And, you know, I think that the skin
Speaker 4:  benefit all of our users.
Speaker 1:  And if you think about it, that's actually kind of a strong statement that
Speaker 1:  apple would quote, owe it to their users. Unquote, want an
Speaker 1:  even stronger statement. Look no further than Google VP
Speaker 1:  Hiroshi Lockheimer who is in charge of Android and RCS and a whole
Speaker 1:  bunch of other stuff. Here's the tweet from him on October 7th, 2021,
Speaker 1:  where Hiroshi was commenting on how SMS breaks, I message group
Speaker 1:  chats. Here's a quote group chats don't need to break this way. There
Speaker 1:  exists a really clear solution. Here's an open
Speaker 1:  invitation to the folks who can make this right. We are here to
Speaker 1:  help by the way, really clear solution was in capital letters because
Speaker 1:  RCS, it was a acronym joke. They make dad jokes at Google
Speaker 1:  too. I'm just saying it's cute. Right? Well, if I've learned anything
Speaker 1:  from Twitter, tweeting is not the same thing as doing. So I actually asked
Speaker 1:  Sinaz about this tweet.
Speaker 4:  I honestly, I don't know. I don't have knowledge to that.
Speaker 4:  I do. Like, I don't know if she's doing stuff,
Speaker 1:  But you, you specifically, aren't calling up apple every day, asking them
Speaker 1:  if they're going to adopt RCS.
Speaker 4:  I don't have them on speed
Speaker 4:  dial.
Speaker 1:  We ended last week's Tuesday episode by pointing out that the
Speaker 1:  iPhone would probably never adopt USBC. And
Speaker 1:  now we're ending this episode with a big old question mark about the
Speaker 1:  iPhone and RCS. The fact that apple is
Speaker 1:  opting out of two messy and complicated standards with the
Speaker 1:  iPhone is not lost on me. It makes sense for the company,
Speaker 1:  even though I personally think that apple could go a long way towards
Speaker 1:  cleaning up both of these messages, if it would engage with them. But we
Speaker 1:  know that apple thinks I iMessage is a competitive advantage. We've seen
Speaker 1:  the emails where executives shot down the idea of bringing a message to
Speaker 1:  Android, because it would be bad for iPhone sales, which means
Speaker 1:  that well, eventually RCS could be a real true universal
Speaker 1:  standard, but in the meantime, it's messy. And we
Speaker 1:  live in the meantime, if you're an Android user talking to other
Speaker 1:  Android users in 2022, the default texting experience
Speaker 1:  might finally, finally, finally finally start to be
Speaker 1:  decent and relatively modern. And if that happens, maybe it'll be
Speaker 1:  the I-phones that start breaking group chats. And that could put some pressure
Speaker 1:  on apple, but here's my pressure. I think texting should be
Speaker 1:  private by default and SMS messages are not
Speaker 1:  encrypted. So if a government wants to force your carrier to
Speaker 1:  share those messages, the carrier is able to do it. Heck it doesn't actually
Speaker 1:  take that much force. Sometimes. Now there are lots of ways to encrypt
Speaker 1:  text messages. I use signal and I like it a lot, but none of
Speaker 1:  those ways are universal and none of them are the default across
Speaker 1:  different devices in the way that SMS and theoretically
Speaker 1:  RCS are. I know that apple cares about
Speaker 1:  privacy, especially the privacy of its customers. I
Speaker 1:  just wonder why it seems to stop caring about protecting that privacy.
Speaker 1:  When those customers happen to be texting Android
Speaker 1:  users, Hey, there's always
Speaker 1:  2023.
Speaker 1:  This episode of the Vergecast was made by Andrew Moreno, Liam, James and
Speaker 1:  me Dieter Bohn, special. Thanks to  for joining us this
Speaker 1:  week. The Vergecast we'll be back on Friday for the chat show. And my Tuesday
Speaker 1:  episode is going to return next week. Thanks for listening.