# Transcript
ID: 4d469720-5cc4-11ec-be3b-25a604acbfdf
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Can Matter save the smart home?
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-5776497365698012673/-7936515502276947638/s93290-US-2808s-1639474059.mp3
Description: In our final Vergecast Spec-tacular of the year, Dieter Bohn dives into Matter, the new tech standard that smart home gadgets will use to communicate with each other, making compatibility between gadgets significantly easier.
Guests include:
Verge smart home reviewer Jennifer Pattison Tuohy
Michelle Mindala-Freeman, Head of Marketing for the Connectivity Standards Alliance.
Tim Both, brand manager and product manager for Eve
Samantha Fein, VP of Marketing and Business Development at Samsung SmartThings
Speaker 1:  I would like to play a game with you playing a game on a podcast is a little
Speaker 1:  tricky. So we're going to keep it simple. I'm just going to list a bunch
Speaker 1:  of terms related to the smart home. And I want you to keep track of how
Speaker 1:  many you recognize then when we're done, we might have like a one question
Speaker 1:  bonus round. Okay. Are you ready? Here we go. ZigBee
Speaker 1:  Z-Wave 8 0 2 dot 15 dot four, six L
Speaker 1:  O w P a N. Thread weave, Bluetooth,
Speaker 1:  Bluetooth, low energy, wifi bridge, smart things. Alexa, home
Speaker 1:  assistant, Google home and home kit. Okay. Did you keep track
Speaker 1:  there? Did you got your score? Feel free to jump back and listen again, if
Speaker 1:  you need to. Now here's the bonus round question. Do you think
Speaker 1:  the number of smart home terms that you need to know is going to get
Speaker 1:  bigger or smaller in the future?
Speaker 1:  If there's any single category of technology that has been absolutely a
Speaker 1:  wash in too many different standards, protocols, radios,
Speaker 1:  and software stacks. It is the smart home 10
Speaker 1:  years ago, having smart switches or bulbs in your house was the domain of
Speaker 1:  the very rich or the very nerdy, the kind of people who would get
Speaker 1:  Crestron systems installed in their house by professionals. But now
Speaker 1:  thanks in large part to the echo and the smart speakers that followed
Speaker 1:  there has been a huge explosion in smart home gadgets, and it's gotten
Speaker 1:  way easier to install and use them, but all that smart home
Speaker 1:  pass brought a lot of baggage into our smart home present. And so
Speaker 1:  the question is how much of that are we going to have to carry into our smart
Speaker 1:  home future? Weirdly enough, there might be an actual answer
Speaker 1:  to that question. It's another standard to add to that list of terms,
Speaker 1:  but this time it might mean that you can forget about all of the
Speaker 1:  rest of them instead of your number, getting bigger. It could get smaller,
Speaker 1:  maybe even down to just one term that you need to know when you buy
Speaker 1:  a smart home gadget. I am Dieter Bohn, and this week on our
Speaker 1:  special run of Tuesday, Vergecast topic specific episodes.
Speaker 1:  It's time to talk about matter the new smart home standard that may
Speaker 1:  finally make this whole ecosystem less complicated.
Speaker 3:  This podcast is brought to you by Twilio for businesses around the
Speaker 3:  world, unlocking and unifying real-time customer data is critical,
Speaker 3:  especially for delivering truly personalized campaigns at scale.
Speaker 3:  That's why companies like Instacart into it. And IBM are turning to Twilio,
Speaker 3:  which was recently ranked number one for 2020 market share and customer data
Speaker 3:  platforms by IDC to learn how Twilio can help your business harness
Speaker 3:  real-time data and build customer engagement like no other visit
Speaker 3:  twilio.com
Speaker 1:  Ever wonder how the biggest international businesses in the world send payments,
Speaker 1:  get paid and generate market setting growth year in and year out. Well,
Speaker 1:  if they're Airbnb, Amazon, or Google, the payment platform Payoneer
Speaker 1:  has something to do with that success. Payoneer is the global
Speaker 1:  go-to for digital commerce. Their B2B payment platform spans
Speaker 1:  international borders with ease and makes an a to pay
Speaker 1:  contractors on the other side of the world while collecting payments from
Speaker 1:  international clients, pulling in earnings from online marketplaces and
Speaker 1:  so much more learn how to grow your business with Payoneer at
Speaker 1:  pioneer.com/verge that's P a Y O N
Speaker 1:  E r.com/verge, a universe of
Speaker 1:  opportunities open to you.
Speaker 1:  Okay. So what is matter? Well, we asked a bunch of
Speaker 1:  experts starting with the connective standards Alliance or
Speaker 1:  CSA, or you might know them as the standards, body formerly known as the
Speaker 1:  ZigBee Alliance, or, you know, all you really need to know is that
Speaker 1:  it is the group that's in charge of the new matter standard
Speaker 5:  Michelle Mandela Freeman. And I am the head of marketing for the
Speaker 5:  connectivity standards Alliance matter is a
Speaker 5:  breakthrough standard spaced protocol that
Speaker 5:  will transform the internet of things.
Speaker 1:  We also talked to Eve, a company that makes smart home gadgets with a
Speaker 1:  special focus on compatibility with Apple's home kit.
Speaker 6:  The from Eve brand manager and product manager matter is
Speaker 6:  basically the unifying standard that will really take
Speaker 6:  the SmartHome mainstream and get rid of all the
Speaker 6:  fragmentation and problems that have plagued the smartphone
Speaker 6:  industry for the past decades.
Speaker 1:  Okay. There's one more answer to go from Samsung smart things, but I
Speaker 1:  bet you're starting to see a theme here. I'm Samantha
Speaker 7:  And I'm VP of marketing and business development at Samsung SmartThings,
Speaker 7:  I would say matter is the open and universal connected home
Speaker 7:  protocol that makes life easier for developers and consumers.
Speaker 1:  That is a lot of positivity and hype isn't it, but I bet you're not
Speaker 1:  surprised to hear so much positivity and hype from the people that are in
Speaker 1:  charge of the new standard. What are the things that none of those answers
Speaker 1:  actually do though, is tell you what matter actually is. So let's
Speaker 1:  give that a shot
Speaker 1:  matter is the language that smart home gadgets are going to use to
Speaker 1:  communicate with each other. So you don't have to worry about whether or
Speaker 1:  not the thing that you buy will be compatible with the other stuff in your
Speaker 1:  house. See, when you have a smart home gadget, there's a few things
Speaker 1:  that need to happen. Here's how it used to work. You need the gadget itself.
Speaker 1:  It needs a radio to communicate like wifi or ZigBee. And
Speaker 1:  sometimes that means it also needs a custom bridge, like say for hue lights
Speaker 1:  or something. You need a language to communicate with like the home kit
Speaker 1:  SDK or the Alexa SDK. And you need to control it all with
Speaker 1:  something like Siri or Alexa or a Google home. Now, if you
Speaker 1:  look at that system of things that you need to make a smart home gadget
Speaker 1:  work, there are just too many places where things might not be
Speaker 1:  compatible. What matter does is standardize the language between
Speaker 1:  all of these different parts of the system. It's agnostic with regards to
Speaker 1:  the kinds of radios you're using. So it'll support wifi, Bluetooth, Bluetooth,
Speaker 1:  little energy, or thread. It means that no matter what kind of
Speaker 1:  controller you use, the steps are connecting and communicating with your
Speaker 1:  gadgets are the same. And eventually it might mean that you
Speaker 1:  won't need any more custom radio bridges plus matter helps
Speaker 1:  to find what things are. So the language knows the difference between a light
Speaker 1:  bulb and a smart lock matter is going to be released in the middle of
Speaker 1:  2022. If everything goes to plan and it'll include a spec that
Speaker 1:  developers can use, plus there should be a whole bunch of new devices that
Speaker 1:  officially support it released around the same time.
Speaker 1:  So that's hopefully not too inaccurate description of matter, but
Speaker 1:  to check my work, I wanted to check with our resident smart home guru. That
Speaker 1:  would be Jennifer Patterson to eat the smart home reviewer at the verge.
Speaker 1:  I figured that we should actually talk to somebody who can tell us just how
Speaker 1:  real this hype actually is
Speaker 8:  Going to get really short and sweet here. Matter means you can
Speaker 8:  buy what you want for your smart home. You can plug it in
Speaker 8:  and it will work with everything else in your home. Okay.
Speaker 8:  You don't believe me.
Speaker 1:  No, I don't. Well, so this is everyone. Everyone has basically the same.
Speaker 1:  Like everything's going to be wonderful and perfect in the future with matter
Speaker 1:  thing, like the hype is very real at this thing. So the second question I'm
Speaker 1:  asking everybody is like, what are the odds expressed as a percentage that
Speaker 1:  this will actually work?
Speaker 8:  Yes. Well, that's a good follow up question because the odds are still to
Speaker 8:  me up in the air. I'm not a betting girl. So can I say like
Speaker 8:  80% chance? I would say there's an 80%
Speaker 8:  chance. Now when I first started reporting on matter, I was thinking, this
Speaker 8:  is like a 40 to 50% chance, but I have been steadily
Speaker 8:  increasing my confidence as I've covered this space because you know, the
Speaker 8:  key here is we've got all the big players on board and as
Speaker 8:  one executive explained it to me, it's a lot like the beginning of the internet,
Speaker 8:  you know, when we had to choose between AOL and CompuServe and MindSpring,
Speaker 8:  I don't actually remember all of that, thankfully, but it's, it's like
Speaker 8:  that, but now we've got them all talking so we don't need to choose. We're
Speaker 8:  getting them to work together. And then that will provide us a strong
Speaker 8:  platform to move forward from
Speaker 1:  The thing that has struck me in talking to a bunch of people about batter
Speaker 1:  is just how hyped it is. Just how much everybody
Speaker 1:  seems to believe that's involved in it. Of course, normally when there's
Speaker 1:  a standards group, it's well, we'll see we're working together. We have high
Speaker 1:  hopes, whatever, but this one is like, we're going to fix it. It's going
Speaker 1:  to be great. And I'm wondering if you could just, you've been reporting on
Speaker 1:  smart home stuff for a very long time. You understand the fragmentation better
Speaker 1:  than anybody. Can you put in context how
Speaker 1:  bad the state of smart home is now and why we need
Speaker 1:  something like matter next year,
Speaker 8:  This is the key to why this could be successful because this isn't really
Speaker 8:  designed for the consumer matter is really
Speaker 8:  for the developer. Because I think all of the big
Speaker 8:  companies in the space who have platforms and ecosystems are getting
Speaker 8:  bombarded by developers and manufacturers saying we
Speaker 8:  can't develop seven different things, seven different
Speaker 8:  specs. It's really hard to develop for Alexa and to
Speaker 8:  develop for Siri and to develop for home kitten, to develop for Google and
Speaker 8:  develop for Samsung and, and choose whether we should do ZigBee and Z-Wave.
Speaker 8:  And whether we have a bridge or a herb. And this means we're spending all
Speaker 8:  our time on those things and not on actually developing our core
Speaker 8:  product and get making better features. And so I think that's why
Speaker 8:  these companies have really come together because they need products for
Speaker 8:  their platforms. Very few of them actually make a lot of products for
Speaker 8:  their platforms. They need developers and they need these products. That's
Speaker 8:  where I think the promise of matter is, is it's helping it, make it easier
Speaker 8:  for manufacturers to make these things as well as being
Speaker 8:  useful for the end user, to not having to choose between platforms.
Speaker 1:  What are those developers is Tim boot from Eve now Eve
Speaker 1:  makes smart home gadgets. And as I mentioned earlier, when I introduced them,
Speaker 1:  they mostly focused on working with home kit. But when matter launches,
Speaker 1:  suddenly Eve is going to have a lot more potential customers.
Speaker 1:  So you can see why Tim likes it,
Speaker 6:  Like initially with SmartHome, that there wasn't really any
Speaker 6:  standards to, to work on and any common platforms.
Speaker 6:  So what companies started to do is just build their own
Speaker 6:  ecosystem and built their own little island of
Speaker 6:  things. And then very quickly it became apparent that having
Speaker 6:  little islands everywhere didn't work out. So you would have this awesome
Speaker 6:  new startup with a new product, and it wouldn't work with your
Speaker 6:  specific islands. And all of that changed about five or
Speaker 6:  six years ago when, when the big players came into the fields. So
Speaker 6:  you now have a very dominant landscape of,
Speaker 6:  of a few big ecosystem providers, but still if as a, as a
Speaker 6:  normal customer, you walk into a store, you can't be certain, the
Speaker 6:  stuff works together in the fashion you wanted to. And if you're
Speaker 6:  invested in one ecosystem that maybe doesn't have a smart
Speaker 6:  display, but you really want to have a smart display in your kitchen. It's
Speaker 6:  a pain to get that working together. And what all of that led to is
Speaker 6:  that people just don't like buying these kinds of things because
Speaker 6:  they just don't want to have the pain. And I think the next big
Speaker 6:  step is just removing all of that pain. And then an average
Speaker 6:  consumer can actually go into the store and buy it and be confident.
Speaker 1:  That all sounds nice, doesn't it? But how does all of this actually work?
Speaker 1:  Let's get back to my conversation with Jennifer.
Speaker 1:  Here's a question that is harder to answer. Is it good? Will it
Speaker 1:  work? Is it a, is it like the right solution? Is it a good from a
Speaker 1:  technical perspective? Well,
Speaker 8:  Do you think wifi is good
Speaker 1:  Where I am in my house?
Speaker 8:  Yeah. So I mean, it is matter, works on wifi and thread. The
Speaker 8:  important thing to remember is this is a technology. This is not a platform
Speaker 8:  or an ecosystem, right? So how well it works on an
Speaker 8:  infrastructure level. I think we can feel quite confident that it is good
Speaker 8:  because it's been developed and tested over a long period of time. We're
Speaker 8:  using two very well-known protocols. Wi-Fi much more known
Speaker 8:  well-known and thread, which has actually been around for a very long time.
Speaker 8:  Even if it hasn't been out in the wild for that long or the broader
Speaker 8:  smart home. So, you know, these are tried and tested protocols. They're not
Speaker 8:  something brand new. They have reinvented the wheel here. So yes, I feel
Speaker 8:  like the actual underlying technology is going to be
Speaker 8:  reliable and work well. It is going to rely somewhat on
Speaker 8:  mesh and, you know, hence I mentioned, wifi mesh can be unstable
Speaker 8:  depending on how well you've got your setup. That's why you're going to need
Speaker 8:  these thread border routers, which will help extend
Speaker 8:  your mesh network if you have a larger home. But the great thing about thread
Speaker 8:  border routers is that they're not white boxes. You have to stick around
Speaker 8:  your house, the lighting, the
Speaker 8:  TVs, the smart speaker. So things you're probably already going to have in
Speaker 8:  your home, right? So you're not going to have a single point of failure for
Speaker 8:  your smart home, which often is the case. Now like someone unplugged your
Speaker 8:  apple TV by mistake, and none of your HomeKit automations work anymore. You
Speaker 8:  know, those types of things are frustrating and that should go away with
Speaker 8:  matter.
Speaker 1:  I want to zero in on the point, Jennifer just made there the potential end
Speaker 1:  of having to use extra hubs to connect up your smart home gadgets.
Speaker 1:  I am very excited to ditch my hubs and hopefully have
Speaker 1:  them be replaced with things that are more than just smart home hubs. So
Speaker 1:  my router or my echo, or my apple TV could work as a
Speaker 1:  matter hub, but it's actually going to be more than that. Jennifer mentioned
Speaker 1:  thread border routers. Basically every device on the network can be a
Speaker 1:  redundant node in the mesh network. That all sounds really
Speaker 1:  technical, but the result is that you shouldn't have to think about it because
Speaker 1:  just as you start to collect new things in your smart home, they're going
Speaker 1:  to quietly improve your smart home network without you having to do
Speaker 1:  anything. Samsung smart things seems to be invested in this idea.
Speaker 7:  18 months ago, we announced that smart things would no longer be making first
Speaker 7:  party hardware with a real vision of where could hardware be.
Speaker 7:  I think the life of a having simply the device itself as a hub,
Speaker 7:  and we've moved beyond that. We just announced it SDC a couple of weeks ago
Speaker 7:  that the smart things hub capability would be going in some of our televisions
Speaker 7:  and appliances as well. So you're starting to see that actualize.
Speaker 1:  Now, one reason that matter has the chance to obviate
Speaker 1:  hubs is that a lot of matter devices are going to use this radio standard
Speaker 1:  called thread, which you've heard come up a bunch already. Thread has a
Speaker 1:  long history. We actually talked about it on this podcast a couple of weeks
Speaker 1:  ago in our interview with Eero CEO, Nick Weaver now matter can work
Speaker 1:  over Bluetooth to set devices up and it can use wifi to communicate if they
Speaker 1:  need to. But both of those radios aren't as good for
Speaker 1:  smart home gadget communications as thread is
Speaker 1:  thread and matter are different, but they're complimentary parts of the whole
Speaker 1:  picture here. I asked Michelle at the connective standards Alliance, how
Speaker 1:  thread fits into this entire vision.
Speaker 5:  I do think that some of the reasons we've gone with the core radios
Speaker 5:  that we have for both for wifi and for thread and Bluetooth for
Speaker 5:  commissioning is because they are particularly common and prevalent.
Speaker 5:  I would say why first and foremost is dare I say, virtually
Speaker 5:  ubiquitous these days in terms of being able to, to support that
Speaker 5:  connectivity, Bluetooth through a commissioning and provisioning perspective
Speaker 5:  is something that's fairly ubiquitous. And I think what Fred
Speaker 5:  brings is that kind of in-home mesh networking technology,
Speaker 5:  IP based mesh networking. That really helps with
Speaker 5:  those types of connected in the home situations. So we
Speaker 5:  believe that this, I guess starter kit of physical layers is a good
Speaker 5:  package of physical layers for our members and consumers
Speaker 5:  to, to get the most out of what matters,
Speaker 1:  Right? Thread is one of those things that actually matter to where
Speaker 1:  I have this split in my brain of, it seems like it's taking too long,
Speaker 1:  that it's taken forever, especially with thread, but a little bit with matter.
Speaker 1:  I think the original promises from ship were a little bit sooner than what
Speaker 1:  we're going to be getting here. So I've got that side of my brain and why
Speaker 1:  is it taking so long? And then the other side of my brain understands how
Speaker 1:  standards processes usually go. And it seems like it's moving a
Speaker 1:  lightening quick, from your perspective, do you have that same split or do
Speaker 1:  you see it as on one side or the other?
Speaker 5:  I like that part of your brain
Speaker 5:  that's right. I mean, it is hard work, right? Let's not make bones
Speaker 5:  about that. It is difficult to bring together
Speaker 5:  hundreds of companies and thousands of engineers and cross more than one
Speaker 5:  standard site, by the way. Right? So the CSA is the home for matter.
Speaker 5:  And Fred group and the Wi-Fi Alliance, you know, are the
Speaker 5:  organizations who manage those kinds of physical networking areas. So
Speaker 5:  it is a complex solution to deliver. So
Speaker 5:  in one sense of the word, it's easy to see how a complex situation
Speaker 5:  like that can take a long time. The thing that I always come back to is the
Speaker 5:  fact that we are building something that's quite breakthrough. And I do
Speaker 5:  believe that in the grand scheme of things, we are moving at a very
Speaker 5:  rapid pace relative to what many other standards
Speaker 5:  organizations and standards of the past have done and even more.
Speaker 5:  So the thing to remember about whether you think we're going slow or
Speaker 5:  not, or going fast is we're not just delivering a paper
Speaker 5:  spec. And that I think is part of what makes
Speaker 5:  this work particularly different.
Speaker 1:  Let's get back to my conversation with Jennifer, the verge of smart home
Speaker 1:  reviewer, because she actually could tell us a little bit more about where
Speaker 1:  thread came from in the first place.
Speaker 8:  Okay. So thread came from nest thread came from nest.
Speaker 8:  pre-Google
Speaker 1:  The good nest, the nest one. It made stuff that worked everybody like.
Speaker 8:  So I spoke with Tony Fidel, I'm the founder of nest about this. And
Speaker 8:  he explained, you know, originally when they first put out the first nest
Speaker 8:  learning thermostat it, how does it be radio in because they, they envisioned
Speaker 8:  this future where thermostat would need to talk to more devices in the home.
Speaker 8:  And after a while, they started to realize that the ZigBee didn't
Speaker 8:  really have what they needed. And so they started to work with Silicon
Speaker 8:  labs, which is, who is very much involved in matter to
Speaker 8:  develop something more powerful on top of the ZigBee
Speaker 8:  radio. So it is a ZigBee radio, but it has their software layer
Speaker 8:  on top, which is thread and then matter,
Speaker 8:  which now matter is on top of that, when nest worked on it,
Speaker 8:  they actually had weave, which if you can recall way back
Speaker 8:  when we've was what nest came out with when they introduced
Speaker 8:  thread and they introduced thread and they introduced weave and the entire
Speaker 8:  smart home world went, ha
Speaker 1:  It's like too many metaphors, too many puns. Why would we trust
Speaker 1:  you? Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 8:  What is this even doing? Why do we care? Why do we need another
Speaker 8:  protocol? You know, we've already got 17 that don't work properly and why
Speaker 8:  we got one more. So I think it was an uphill climb. And
Speaker 8:  Tony mentioned that he had a lot of people pretty much laugh in his face
Speaker 8:  and say, this is ridiculous. You shouldn't even bother why are you doing
Speaker 8:  this? And I asked him, why is it now, why now has thread
Speaker 8:  taken off? And he said, his theory is because all of
Speaker 8:  the other smart home companies or ecosystems like Amazon and
Speaker 8:  apple went out and started to try and make products themselves or make systems
Speaker 8:  themselves for consumers. And they started to get all the feedback that nest
Speaker 8:  had been getting, that these things aren't working, we need this, we need
Speaker 8:  that. So they realized, oh, actually we do need something like
Speaker 8:  this. We need this universal protocol that is going to
Speaker 8:  work. Communication is the key in the smart home. Everything needs to talk
Speaker 8:  to everything else. And none of the existing protocols were specifically
Speaker 8:  designed for smart home devices to talk to each other. They all had failure
Speaker 8:  points that made it difficult. And thread fixes all of those.
Speaker 1:  The companies that make smart home gadgets are also excited about thread
Speaker 1:  because it makes their jobs simpler. They can just pick the radio that they
Speaker 1:  know works with everything. Instead of having to bet on an ecosystem like
Speaker 1:  ZigBee or Z-Wave or whatever, here's Tim from Eve
Speaker 6:  Threats, she removes like all of the problems you get
Speaker 6:  with using technologies that are not made for smart
Speaker 6:  devices. We, as a company, we are sort of the
Speaker 6:  minority with having lots of Bluetooth enabled products, because he
Speaker 6:  can't use wifi for like a door and windows
Speaker 6:  sensor that would just drain the battery much quicker than, than
Speaker 6:  anyone would like. So the alternative is to use some other
Speaker 6:  protocol and have a bridge, and we never wanted that. So for
Speaker 6:  us threads really is a no-brainer because you can just
Speaker 6:  use it for everything. It's, it's, it's low power. It creates a mesh
Speaker 6:  network, but, but a unified mesh network that works
Speaker 6:  across different manufacturers. So, so you can have an
Speaker 6:  Eve darned window sensor at your door, and very far away, a home
Speaker 6:  pod mini, and in-between, let's say a non-belief vault
Speaker 6:  and they just extend their network automatically and work together
Speaker 6:  to just create this seamless networking stuff. And I
Speaker 6:  think it aligns perfectly with the matter now, because with this IP
Speaker 6:  based world, you now really have the complete story on the transport
Speaker 6:  level, on the language level application layer that everything
Speaker 6:  just works and it's made with IOT in mind.
Speaker 1:  All right, stepping back a moment. I just have to tell you that right
Speaker 1:  now, I personally am feeling a little bit off
Speaker 1:  kilter. Usually when we talk about MSCI technologies and the
Speaker 1:  standards that are supposed to fix them, we end up talking about the
Speaker 1:  problems, but maybe because matter hasn't launched yet,
Speaker 1:  everybody still seems really excited. And there aren't a whole lot of
Speaker 1:  problems to talk about yet. Plus it is
Speaker 1:  very, very strange to think that apple and
Speaker 1:  Google and Samsung and Amazon are all working
Speaker 1:  together. I asked Michelle at the CSA about it.
Speaker 5:  It is a challenge, right? To get such a diverse group of
Speaker 5:  companies and players with perspective interests together to create this
Speaker 5:  kind of momentum and change. But I genuinely believe kind of the
Speaker 5:  impetus is one, a commitment to consumers and
Speaker 5:  creating consumer value. And to the notion that, you know, there
Speaker 5:  has to be some trade offs along the way, at a point each of these
Speaker 5:  small individual enclaves or each of these unique or individual
Speaker 5:  experiences are going to hit a bit of a market wall, the wall of the
Speaker 5:  walled garden as it were, right. You know, okay, I'm not going to grow
Speaker 5:  anymore. I'm not going to be able to expand beyond these walls. And it could
Speaker 5:  be an ecosystem provider who thinks about that. It could be a device manufacturer
Speaker 5:  who hide their reigns to one of the ecosystems and
Speaker 5:  realize, you know, if I really want to change the market, if I really want
Speaker 5:  to grow to the market, if I really want to get to that next step or that
Speaker 5:  next level, I have to look at places where I collaborate
Speaker 5:  in different ways. I have to find those places where collaboration
Speaker 5:  actually allows the market to grow or the pie
Speaker 5:  to expand or the walled garden to be knocked down. And
Speaker 5:  then everyone will benefit. So as a manufacturer or
Speaker 5:  an ecosystem provider or a chip set vendor, you have to look at the trade
Speaker 5:  off and say is growing the market and increasing value
Speaker 5:  more important than keeping my small piece of the pie hole.
Speaker 5:  And I think that's what enlightened companies are doing and why
Speaker 5:  they're participating in matter.
Speaker 1:  You really don't need to read between the lines much there. Do you, the walled
Speaker 1:  garden strategy of keeping everybody in separate ecosystems has
Speaker 1:  limited growth for each of these individual companies. I asked Jennifer
Speaker 1:  about this weird friendliness to
Speaker 8:  It's consumerism. I mean, they want to sell more products.
Speaker 8:  And the smart home has stagnated. There is a lot of early
Speaker 8:  adoption from early adopters us, but for the
Speaker 8:  masses, that larger consumer market, it's still just too
Speaker 8:  confusing and too complicated. And you know, we go into a
Speaker 8:  home Depot or Lowe's and you buy something and you bring it home and it doesn't
Speaker 8:  work with what you thought it was going to work with. And there was too much
Speaker 8:  confusion. And in order for the market to push forward, I think the big
Speaker 8:  players realized we have to fix this basic issue of what
Speaker 8:  talks to what in the home and how our home, you know, we
Speaker 8:  used to be able to go buy a light bulb and screw it in. And it worked. We
Speaker 8:  need to get back to that stage. We need to be able to buy a light
Speaker 8:  bulb, screw it in. And it should just work with a smart home because that's
Speaker 8:  the future of our homes. Everything is smart. Now our phones, our cars, our
Speaker 8:  TVs, our homes are going to be smart, whether you want them to be or not
Speaker 8:  honestly. So ultimately it's because they're going to sell more
Speaker 8:  products. If they fix this problem, right, there is still going to be plenty
Speaker 8:  of competition because matter is just the communication
Speaker 8:  level features on top of that and ecosystems and how
Speaker 8:  things work, not how they work together, but how they work are still
Speaker 8:  going to be differentiating factors in the smart home that are going to make
Speaker 8:  you choose to buy from one company over the other company.
Speaker 1:  Okay, we're going to take a break. But when we come back, we're going to
Speaker 1:  finish out the rest of our conversation with Jennifer to find out if matter
Speaker 1:  is really going to work and to find out what we can expect for matter. When
Speaker 1:  it comes to security and privacy,
Speaker 3:  This podcast is brought to you by Twilio, for businesses around the
Speaker 3:  world, unlocking and unifying real-time customer data is critical,
Speaker 3:  especially for delivering truly personalized campaigns at scale.
Speaker 3:  That's why companies like Instacart into it. And IBM are turning to Twilio,
Speaker 3:  which was recently ranked number one for 2020 market share and customer data
Speaker 3:  platforms by IDC to learn how Twilio can help your business
Speaker 3:  hardest real-time data and build customer engagement like no other visit
Speaker 3:  twilio.com.
Speaker 3:  If your snazzy new marketing campaign launches into an empty
Speaker 3:  forest and nobody is around to hear it, does it get any
Speaker 3:  clicks? Here's the thing about advertising. It's totally
Speaker 3:  useless. If you're not reaching people who are ready to engage with your
Speaker 3:  business, that's why more and more B2B marketers are turning to LinkedIn.
Speaker 3:  Advertising on LinkedIn is a great way to maximize every campaign dollar
Speaker 3:  you spend, but that's not all LinkedIn also offers advertisers
Speaker 3:  tools. They can use to focus their messaging, build their brand and generate
Speaker 3:  a ton of new leads. Dial in your campaign and fine tune your approach
Speaker 3:  by targeting customers based on their job, title, location, and
Speaker 3:  company name. You can even focus on people who have had past interactions
Speaker 3:  with your business. LinkedIn's customization options are effectively
Speaker 3:  limitless and offer a sure-fire way to hit your objectives. Do
Speaker 3:  business where business has done get a $100 advertising
Speaker 3:  credit toward your first LinkedIn visit
Speaker 3:  linkedin.com/vergecast
Speaker 3:  linkedin.com/vergecast terms and
Speaker 3:  conditions apply
Speaker 9:  Support for this episode comes from Andrea Andean is the payments platform
Speaker 9:  built to help your business grow with Andy? And you can accept payments in
Speaker 9:  app online in store touch-free and beyond. Think about it
Speaker 9:  more ways to get paid and more places. What could that do for you?
Speaker 9:  Higher sales and happier customers for starters, Adyen, payment platform,
Speaker 9:  technology adapts to any business store industry or shopper journey
Speaker 9:  for retail and marketplace to subscriptions and mobile payments. You can
Speaker 9:  do any of it or all of it. You'll get flexible features that
Speaker 9:  fit your business with a single integration. You can even get revenue
Speaker 9:  optimization and customer insights all in one solution Addie and
Speaker 9:  build their platform to help businesses like yours from day one, and yet
Speaker 9:  business not boundaries, visit Andy and.com to learn more.
Speaker 9:  That's a D Y E n.com
Speaker 10:  A perfect marriage, an almost perfect crime
Speaker 10:  inspired by real events. The new HBO limited
Speaker 10:  series, landscapers stars, Oscar, an Emmy winner,
Speaker 10:  Olivia Coleman and Emmy nominee. David Thewlis as
Speaker 10:  Susan and Christopher Edwards over the course of the shows.
Speaker 10:  Four episodes watches, Susan and Christopher, a seemingly
Speaker 10:  ordinary British couple become the focus of an extraordinary
Speaker 10:  investigation. When two dead bodies are discovered in the back
Speaker 10:  garden of a Nottingham home created and written by debut
Speaker 10:  screenwriter, ad Sinclair and directed by will. Sharp
Speaker 10:  comes this exhilarating exploration of love, nestled
Speaker 10:  somewhere between fact and fiction. What happens when
Speaker 10:  true love meets true crime, find out in the new
Speaker 10:  HBO original limited series landscapers. Now
Speaker 10:  streaming on HBO. Max.
Speaker 1:  We are back with our Vergecast Tuesday topic specific episode
Speaker 1:  focused on matter, the new smart home standard,
Speaker 1:  even though everything with matter seems great. There are still a bunch of
Speaker 1:  unanswered questions and technical details that could gum up the
Speaker 1:  works. So let's get to some of those with Jennifer Patterson, Tuohy, the
Speaker 1:  smart home reviewer at the verge.
Speaker 1:  So my understanding is that there's like a base layer of functionality that
Speaker 1:  matter sets it's like we define what the thing is that the light bulb it's
Speaker 1:  a door lock. It's a, you know, whatever it is. And there are certain features
Speaker 1:  that you have to standardize on turning it on and off knowing whether it's
Speaker 1:  on and off, knowing what I don't know, the temperature is or something there's
Speaker 1:  like a set of things like door lock has these components to it. And matter,
Speaker 1:  you have to do that the matter way, but then beyond those features, if you
Speaker 1:  want to do extra stuff, that will still be a thing where different
Speaker 1:  companies are going to be competing on like extra stuff that their ecosystems
Speaker 1:  or gadgets can do. Is that, is that right?
Speaker 8:  That's the plan right now? I mean, that could change, but
Speaker 8:  yes, the software level, like it that's really where companies are going
Speaker 8:  to be able to differentiate is in software because ultimately you're still
Speaker 8:  going to control your home using one or other of these ecosystems.
Speaker 8:  So you're going to pick home kit or Alexa or Google
Speaker 8:  home or Samsung smart things or another one.
Speaker 8:  So they're, they're, they're going to compete on that level from, from the
Speaker 8:  controlled side of things. But then also from the hardware side of things,
Speaker 8:  there are going to be different features, for example, with locks right now,
Speaker 8:  it's just lock and unlock in matter, right. But if you want like the
Speaker 8:  auto unlock, that's a big feature for some devices.
Speaker 8:  That's not part of matter. It may come, there is
Speaker 8:  something called an access control working group in matter, that is looking
Speaker 8:  at developing those types of things. But right now it's just going to be
Speaker 8:  a very simple lock and unlock with a master controller. So
Speaker 8:  there's still going to be different experiences. It's not like suddenly the
Speaker 8:  smart home is just going to be homogenous. It's just that things can communicate
Speaker 8:  with each other. That's really what this is all about.
Speaker 1:  I want another device type and you've actually broken some news on
Speaker 1:  this casting. So I did not realize that
Speaker 1:  the idea that you would be able to get contents playing on a television was
Speaker 1:  going to be part of the spec. So how does this work and can I never have
Speaker 1:  to try and make airplay work again?
Speaker 8:  Yeah. So this is kind of exciting. I, when they met, announced that televisions
Speaker 8:  were going to be in the first matter spec originally, I think everyone just
Speaker 8:  assumed they would be as a controller or a border router, which they
Speaker 8:  still can be. But also, and this is sort of spearheaded by
Speaker 8:  Amazon, most likely because they're the ones that don't have a handheld
Speaker 8:  device that you use every day, but also because fire TV and
Speaker 8:  Amazon Alexa is sort of prime video platform is, is such a
Speaker 8:  core part of their business. The concept here is that assuming you have a
Speaker 8:  matter controller, like your smartphone or a smart speaker, and you
Speaker 8:  have a matter enabled app on your TV, you'll be able to
Speaker 8:  cast. And that's a basic matter spec. So you will be able to
Speaker 8:  send any content from whatever controller you have to your
Speaker 8:  TV, right? You won't need any special casting
Speaker 8:  setup like Chromecast or apple TV airplay, or
Speaker 8:  I don't know what Samsung's is called, but yes, so you won't
Speaker 8:  have to worry about that anymore. Everything should just go from one space
Speaker 8:  to the other seamlessly. And that has been really an area of
Speaker 8:  friction. I think, in the home entertainment right now, it's been really
Speaker 8:  difficult to do, to do that. Well, I know my kids with that
Speaker 8:  Oculus is so upset that we can't watch them on TV cause we can never get
Speaker 8:  it to work properly. So yes, but it will depend on
Speaker 8:  individual apps and manufacturers allowing it and
Speaker 8:  being matter enabled.
Speaker 1:  So this sounds a lot more like the Google cast model, where instead of like,
Speaker 1:  you can do some direct stuff with cast now, but like airplay for a long time
Speaker 1:  up until I play too, was it takes the thing on your screen and directly like
Speaker 1:  sends it wirelessly to the local thing to play. But this is more like
Speaker 1:  you've got a controller you tell the matter app on the TV play this
Speaker 1:  URL. And so that's, that's much more how Google cast works. It's sort of
Speaker 1:  handing off the street URLs for streams than it is directly
Speaker 1:  streaming from the device to the thing.
Speaker 8:  Well, you know, I, I don't know the exact technical details. I do know that
Speaker 8:  you will be able to control more than just casting. So you'll be able to
Speaker 8:  control volume. You'll be able to control inputs and
Speaker 8:  you'll be able to control, you know, pausing and fast-forwarding, and it
Speaker 8:  will be based on your streaming device too. So it can either it can work
Speaker 8:  with a smart TV or a smart streaming device. So in
Speaker 8:  theory, you won't need to like use Google Chrome on your
Speaker 8:  phone to cast to a Chromecast if you're using an iPhone, which
Speaker 1:  Would be amazing.
Speaker 8:  Yes. It makes basically making everything easier. That's the
Speaker 8:  ultimate idea here.
Speaker 1:  This discussion is a perfect example of how I feel about matter is like
Speaker 1:  very exciting, very hyped. Everyone's like, yep, everything's just going
Speaker 1:  to work. It's going to be great, but then you stop. And you're like, but
Speaker 1:  hang on. There are some technical questions here that I don't know fully
Speaker 1:  know the answer to. And so I feel unsettled because I kind of
Speaker 1:  believe the hype right now. And that's not a normal thing for me to do with
Speaker 1:  tech. Like help me work through my emotions about like maybe actually
Speaker 1:  thinking that some of this stuff is actually gonna work.
Speaker 8:  I know, I know I'm kind, I'm right there with you. I want to be deeply skeptical,
Speaker 8:  but I also want my smart home to work. So I'm excited about
Speaker 8:  that. I think we should be confident and excited about the basic
Speaker 8:  technology. I don't think we should suddenly think everyone is going
Speaker 8:  to be, if there's all kumbaya and the whole smart home is, is this
Speaker 8:  great space. There's still a lot of big questions. The biggest questions
Speaker 8:  in my mind, a cameras, because that's such a big space in the smart home.
Speaker 8:  And that's still a ways off I'm smart security systems
Speaker 8:  too. We're not really seeing that space. Hasn't really come into the
Speaker 8:  inter matter. There's a lot of areas that are, that are key to our homes
Speaker 8:  that are not here yet. And I'm also a bit worried about companies hedging
Speaker 8:  their bets slightly here. Amazon's just released four or five new
Speaker 8:  products and didn't mention matter at all. Now their
Speaker 8:  argument here is, well, it's very hard to build a
Speaker 8:  product for a spec that does not exist, which is a fair
Speaker 8:  point.
Speaker 1:  Sure. But I mean, this working group has been around since
Speaker 1:  2019. They like they're deeply involved. They know what the spec is going
Speaker 1:  to be like, devices are getting tested right now for it.
Speaker 8:  Well, but this is the other problem. And this is something that, so Mitch
Speaker 8:  client of the Z-Wave Alliance and said, you know, protocol
Speaker 8:  politics have existed since the smart home began. And the
Speaker 8:  ZigBee Alliance, which is now CSA is all about making people talk to each
Speaker 8:  other. But just because you get people into a room to talk to each other
Speaker 8:  does not mean you end up with an agreement. So we've still got
Speaker 8:  that barrier to, to move through for each different
Speaker 8:  part of the smart home that goes through the matter specs. And right now
Speaker 8:  we've got like 10 different devices, but we've got many more that we have
Speaker 8:  to work through and it could take awhile. This is not something that's
Speaker 8:  going to happen overnight, as we can see, cause it's already been delayed
Speaker 8:  substantially.
Speaker 1:  So basically like the more complicated data privacy wise or politically
Speaker 1:  a product category is the longer it might take. So cameras are a perfect
Speaker 1:  example. You mentioned that like ring, it seems to be Mia
Speaker 1:  with regard to matter and the CSA. So I'm sure that ring
Speaker 1:  has a completely different philosophy on what to do with your video data
Speaker 1:  than apple does with HomeKit where they want everything local and they don't
Speaker 1:  even want to know it exists in the first place. Right. So should we just
Speaker 1:  like, we should be assuming that things that like are more complicated
Speaker 1:  are going to take longer or maybe like B become fragmented
Speaker 1:  again with matter.
Speaker 8:  I think things that involve revenue streams, I'm
Speaker 8:  going to go into be more complicated. It may not be that the
Speaker 8:  technology is an issue, but figuring out how all of the,
Speaker 8:  you know, how that's going to work in terms of the connection with the consumer
Speaker 8:  and the revenue model, you know, we saw it slightly with the HomeKit secure
Speaker 8:  video and some companies kind of half adopting it because they didn't
Speaker 8:  really want to give up back control. Like ALO you can have your
Speaker 8:  HomeKit videos, you can stream through home kit, but you can't have the home
Speaker 8:  kit secure video portion because Arlo still wants you to pay them.
Speaker 8:  I think when it comes to revenue streams, that's where we're going to start
Speaker 8:  seeing some hiccups and that, yes, we may still see some fragmentation there,
Speaker 8:  but hopefully they can figure it out.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. The other hype-y things that I might want to Pierce there's
Speaker 1:  security. So part of matter is like issuing security updates, but you
Speaker 1:  mentioned Z-Wave Alliance. It sounds like they're the one group that's like,
Speaker 1:  ah, I dunno. And they pointed out one possible
Speaker 1:  security concern here. Can you talk about that a little bit?
Speaker 8:  And I'm still, I've reached out to the matter for a little bit more clarification
Speaker 8:  on this or CSA group, but for more clarification on this, but
Speaker 8:  because matter is an IP based standard and the thread and
Speaker 8:  wifi are IP based protocols. In theory, each device can,
Speaker 8:  has an open connection to the internet, which gives you much more. I
Speaker 8:  mean, immediately you're like, oh, the hackers
Speaker 8:  malware.
Speaker 1:  Well, I'm thinking of my printer. And like, you know, like it it's like,
Speaker 1:  Nope, doom that's bad. Okay.
Speaker 8:  So, but they, you know, and with Z-Wave, it's the opposite. That's why you
Speaker 8:  have a hub because everything goes through this one hub and that hub is tightly
Speaker 8:  locked down and secure and that's how most security systems are built. And
Speaker 8:  that's why this, we may have an issue with porting that the
Speaker 8:  CSA said to me that actually, you know, we're, we're trying really hard
Speaker 8:  here to work with IP is the future IP based is going to give us so
Speaker 8:  much more flexibility. We can constantly update. We can constantly
Speaker 8:  provide patches, just like we have with our smartphone. You know, you get
Speaker 8:  a patch every week. I have a feeling that will be the case with a matter
Speaker 8:  smart home, you will be doing a lot of updates. Well, you won't have to do
Speaker 8:  it. It should automatically do it. But yes, security is a big concern.
Speaker 8:  Security is going to be a concern going forward. But if you want devices
Speaker 8:  to talk to each other, you have to open those channels. And if you lock
Speaker 8:  it down, you're going to lose the communication. So that's the sort of payoff
Speaker 8:  here, the security versus convenience.
Speaker 1:  And if they are genuinely like issuing security updates, that it is genuinely
Speaker 1:  part of the spec, maybe it'll be fine, but that's like definitely a thing
Speaker 1:  to keep an eye on. The other thing for me though, is that when I asked Michelle
Speaker 1:  from the CSA or Samantha from smart things about privacy, their
Speaker 1:  answers were about security. So here's Michelle's response.
Speaker 5:  This is as I'm building those incredibly strong security foundations,
Speaker 5:  making sure every device that tries to join the network can be
Speaker 5:  attested and authenticated. That every message that goes across that home
Speaker 5:  network, you know, using matter is encrypted. That we do support
Speaker 5:  the ability to continue to patch and upgrade. You know, as
Speaker 5:  vulnerabilities are found and resolved, which they will be, that is the world
Speaker 5:  of security that we're able to, to enable that through standards for
Speaker 5:  our
Speaker 1:  Members. And here's Samantha's response. One of the things
Speaker 7:  Fundamental charters of matter is privacy and security.
Speaker 7:  It is considered pinnacle. And one of the core charters of
Speaker 7:  the protocol, something that is not only discussed, but a commitment from
Speaker 7:  each of these leading companies to ensure that we fulfill that promise.
Speaker 1:  So you can see there, they're like security at the court. We do. And I'm
Speaker 1:  like, okay, but privacy in my data, they're like, yep, we're very
Speaker 1:  secure. And it's like, there's a, there's an Allision there that has me
Speaker 1:  trouble that they're like the matter has nothing to say about what happens
Speaker 1:  with the actual data, other than it can do local control. But that's not
Speaker 1:  a guarantee that it won't get out somehow.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, no. So because really it's privacy, isn't
Speaker 8:  there remit the privacy will still be up down to your
Speaker 8:  relationship with the vendor, right? The privacy is going to be, if you're
Speaker 8:  in an Alexa home, you know, with your relationship with Amazon, if
Speaker 8:  you're in a home kit, home, your relationship with apple, if you buy a
Speaker 8:  device from a no-name brand in China, your relationship with that
Speaker 8:  company, you know, it matter doesn't deal with the software level, which
Speaker 8:  is where the data and the privacy relationship really is going to sit in
Speaker 8:  the smart home. It just deals with the hardware level. Really great. Wonderful.
Speaker 8:  That's why they never answered the question.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Well, and it's also like, well, they don't know and that yeah.
Speaker 1:  There's no way they could ever get these companies to agree on something
Speaker 1:  like that. It's hard enough to get them to agree on just like basic networking.
Speaker 8:  Right. And also it depends where you live too. So there's going to be very
Speaker 8:  different rules and regulations based on which country you're in
Speaker 8:  or the matter is global. It's not just us. I mean, it is in every country
Speaker 8:  almost.
Speaker 1:  Okay. So this thing is supposed to launch next year, but next year is next
Speaker 1:  year. And this year is holiday season and I want to buy the, some
Speaker 1:  smart home gadgets, should I or should.
Speaker 8:  So Matt and CSA will say, go ahead and buy
Speaker 8:  everything. It's all going to fine. Everything's going to upgrade
Speaker 8:  because I don't want everyone to stop buying stuff right now. And
Speaker 8:  to an extent, I think they're right. I mean, enough of these companies
Speaker 8:  have gotten on board and said, we are going to upgrade these
Speaker 8:  things to matter. So, you know, Amazon said all, its Alexa speakers will
Speaker 8:  be matter enabled. We know that there are thread radios in the
Speaker 8:  HomePod minis and there are many devices you can feel comfortable with.
Speaker 8:  There are a few categories I would hold off on as we've already discussed.
Speaker 8:  If your thinking matters the way you want to go with your smart home cameras
Speaker 8:  and security systems for one, anything you already have, you know,
Speaker 8:  that you've had for a long time. And you're thinking about upgrading. I'd
Speaker 8:  wait because there's a chance what you have may still may be
Speaker 8:  upgradable. And if it's not, then wait and find the new one once, you know,
Speaker 8:  for sure what's going to work. It is a difficult time to be making
Speaker 8:  big decisions. But if you're talking like smart speakers, sensors, you
Speaker 8:  know, what's the things that are in the main, the first sort of rollout you
Speaker 8:  should feel pretty comfortable about buying new devices this Christmas.
Speaker 1:  Okay. I completely disagree. I think I said, no. I say it every,
Speaker 1:  every time it comes up, never buy hardware today based on the promise of
Speaker 1:  a software update tomorrow, if you want to buy something because you know
Speaker 1:  it works today and it does what you want today that probably won't break.
Speaker 1:  Once matter comes out, it might not work with the beautiful matter system
Speaker 1:  in the future, but don't, don't just only buy it if
Speaker 1:  it works today.
Speaker 8:  Oh yeah, definitely. Don't. I mean, if you want something, if you have a
Speaker 8:  need right now by what's going to work for you today, I totally agree
Speaker 8:  with that.
Speaker 1:  So this thing is launching sometime mid 20, 22. What do you think this launch
Speaker 1:  is going to look like? Is it going to be like a press release saying the
Speaker 1:  spec exists, developers can make stuff and there's a nano leaf you can,
Speaker 1:  or is it going to be, here are
Speaker 1:  6,000 smart home gadgets that all work together in a beautiful
Speaker 1:  Columbia future. Bam, go to best buy, get in line. Like what on that
Speaker 1:  spectrum? Where do you think we're going to get
Speaker 8:  Apple iPhone five sale day? Well, it it'll be queuing outside best buy
Speaker 1:  For smart light
Speaker 8:  Bulbs. I think it will be a slow rollout. I spoke with Eve you spoke
Speaker 8:  with, and they have, you know, they have a plan, like they already have thread
Speaker 8:  radios and all their devices and they're, you know, staggering the rollout.
Speaker 8:  So I think you'll see as the, the initial, the devices that are in the
Speaker 8:  initial spec, those will come out pretty quickly because they've already
Speaker 8:  got hundreds of devices that are being tested and going through the process,
Speaker 8:  even though they don't have a spec, which confuses me slightly.
Speaker 8:  But you know, they, I think it's, they just don't have the final spec that,
Speaker 8:  so they're still tweaking things, but yeah, I think it'll be a slow process
Speaker 8:  starting probably around summer sort of looking like early June will be
Speaker 8:  when we'll see the new, most of the new ones starting to
Speaker 8:  appear. And then, you know, every couple of months, I think we'll be seeing
Speaker 8:  new devices come onto the market. As the spec gets updated
Speaker 8:  next black Friday is going to be huge.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, for sure. I suspect that apple and Google in particular are
Speaker 1:  eager to have some sort of official launch around or
Speaker 1:  right before their standard developer conferences, because I guarantee you,
Speaker 1:  they both want at WWDC and Google IO to be like, and by the way, the smart
Speaker 1:  home doesn't suck now. So I'm sure that that's something to look forward
Speaker 1:  to.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. And you know, to your point, the smart home, isn't about it. Shouldn't
Speaker 8:  be about building one smart home, all in one go, I mean, as
Speaker 8:  things stop working in your home and you need something, you have to fill
Speaker 8:  a need. It's always worth considering the smart version. I know
Speaker 8:  you're deeply skeptical, but anything that you buy today from a
Speaker 8:  trusted brand who has committed to matter if matter goes forward.
Speaker 8:  I do think you're going to find that it will work in that.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Except for the Amazon division of ring at rest of Amazon. Cool. That
Speaker 1:  ring we don't know yet. This is
Speaker 8:  Basically
Speaker 1:  Okay. Well, the other thing to look forward to is
Speaker 1:  watching you have to review the hundreds of smart
Speaker 1:  catches that are coming out next year. Enjoy have fun. I
Speaker 1:  will I'll pitch in every night I'll pitch in on door locks. That's the one
Speaker 1:  thing that, where my life sucks right now.
Speaker 8:  So find you a good door. Look, I'm sure.
Speaker 8:  Now it's going to be fun. There's lots to look forward to.
Speaker 1:  All right. Cool. Well, thanks so much for chatting.
Speaker 8:  Great, thanks.
Speaker 1:  So that is matter. And next year we should see that big
Speaker 1:  splashy launch that I'm actually optimistic
Speaker 1:  about. Look at that a discussion about tech standards that ends with hope
Speaker 1:  also with a million things for Jennifer to review, sorry, Jennifer,
Speaker 1:  but thank you to her for coming on the verge cast and explaining it all to
Speaker 1:  us. Thanks also to Michelle Medalla Freeman from the CSA, Samantha
Speaker 1:  Fein from smart things and Tim boot from Eve for speaking with us,
Speaker 1:  the Vergecast is produced by myself, Andrew Moreno and Liam James.
Speaker 1:  This is the last of our run of Tuesday topic specific
Speaker 1:  episodes, but we'd really like to know what you think. And if you'd like
Speaker 1:  us to bring them back next year, you can tweet at me, I'm at backlog. And
Speaker 1:  my email is dieter@theverge.com. We'll be back on Friday with the
Speaker 1:  regular Vergecast chat show. And then after that, you know, I bet you can
Speaker 1:  expect to see a bunch more battered news at CES in January,
Speaker 1:  which is happening again to all of us together.