# Transcript
ID: 7d908d60-d5be-11eb-ba74-0b622f1deeb1
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Microsoft announces Windows 11, with a new design, Start menu, and more
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/1336462472/3463580661/s93290-US-4704s-1624610216.mp3
Description: Nilay Patel, Dieter Bohn, and Tom Warren discuss the official reveal of Windows 11 at Microsoft's event on Thursday.
Speaker 1:  This week on the verge has Tom Warren joins the show. We go through everything
Speaker 1:  that happened at the windows 11 event, including running Android apps on
Speaker 1:  windows. That's a big deal. Then we talk a little bit about what's going
Speaker 1:  on with the antitrust bills and Congress and there's lightning round
Speaker 1:  coming up on the broadcast. Now the support
Speaker ?:  For this episode comes from high sense. Let's get real buying a
Speaker ?:  TV. Shouldn't require learning a foreign language, but most TV companies
Speaker ?:  love to talk in confusing jargon, making overhyped and overpriced
Speaker ?:  promises. High sense gives it to you straight. That's why all we're going
Speaker ?:  to tell you about their new ULE D series is that it's got all the premium
Speaker ?:  features you want in the TV in a wide range of sizes to suit any
Speaker ?:  room, forget the jargon and get real. Get high
Speaker ?:  sets, learn
Speaker ?:  more@highsense.com.
Speaker 3:  If you love final fantasy seven, there's an enhanced version coming your
Speaker 3:  way. There's better lighting, textures and background environments that bring
Speaker 3:  the visuals to a whole new level. You can even play in 4k.
Speaker 3:  It's called final fantasy seven remake integrate, and it's available
Speaker 3:  only on PS five. You can grab photos of epic battles with a fully
Speaker 3:  customizable photo mode. And this is exciting for fans of
Speaker 3:  teenage ninja, with a pension, for hunting and theft. There's a brand new
Speaker 3:  episode featuring you fee as a main character. Sharpen your shirt
Speaker 3:  can blades and get ready. Visit S Q E
Speaker 3:  x.link/remake Vergecast for more
Speaker 3:  information,
Speaker 1:  Hello and welcome to the Vergecast. The flagship podcast,
Speaker 1:  multi application environments say it's my windows shut.
Speaker 1:  That's my windows 11 job. I got CA Dieter made a noise. I'm
Speaker 1:  Neil, I'm your friend. That's Dieter.
Speaker 4:  I'm here. 19th century continental philosophy
Speaker 4:  expert. That's actually true. Like,
Speaker 1:  I just want to be honest that in many ways, that's what you are for
Speaker 1:  me. Tom Warren is here. Hey Tom. Hi
Speaker 5:  There I run windows apps, Android apps, iOS apps,
Speaker 5:  web apps, everything.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, there was a lot of talk about web apps and Android apps at the same
Speaker 1:  time today. Anyway, Thomas here, cause it's windows 11 day,
Speaker 1:  we're coming off a sprint of windows, 11 news.
Speaker 1:  Tom literally just came from a meeting with Microsoft talking about windows
Speaker 1:  11. He's on the show. Now tons of news about
Speaker 1:  windows. We'll get to it all. Actually a lot to talk about windows is going
Speaker 1:  to run Android apps. This is a big, big situation, but as always, I want
Speaker 1:  to start at start the pandemic, which is really not quite over around the
Speaker 1:  world. Marybeth, Greg's wrote a great piece for us called the slow transitions
Speaker 1:  of a lingering pandemic. Go read that it lays out kind of where we
Speaker 1:  are, the stutter steps around the
Speaker 1:  world that are coming because it's not quite over yet.
Speaker 1:  So we're still really focused on that. But vaccination in United
Speaker 1:  States means that it feels over for us, but it's not quite over in many other
Speaker 1:  places around the world. And indeed many other places United States, we always
Speaker 1:  talked about second order effects of the pandemic. We have a great big feature
Speaker 1:  on the radio stations of the Navajo nation and how they were broadcasting
Speaker 1:  throughout the pandemic. And it became more important to the community. And
Speaker 1:  it's like, I always think of the verge is really just being off the movie,
Speaker 1:  pump up the volume. So anytime we do like how important radio station stories,
Speaker 1:  I love them that one's great. And then Indian healthcare workers
Speaker 1:  are trying to get a handle on misinformation about
Speaker 1:  COVID in WhatsApp, which is a big problem. We've got a great big story
Speaker 1:  about that. We're trying to do more coverage about just
Speaker 1:  technology in India. A lot of what we see there from a
Speaker 1:  regulatory standpoint, from how Facebook is user, how WhatsApp is used.
Speaker 1:  There feel like previews of what's happening here. We also
Speaker 1:  have a great big audience in India and we have a great big audience
Speaker 1:  of obviously the Indian diaspora in the United States that works in tech.
Speaker 1:  So we're working on it. There's, there's some things there. If you think
Speaker 1:  about how India regulates social media apps, real big
Speaker 1:  previews of some of the things that get talked about here. So we want to
Speaker 1:  explore it more. And so this story about WhatsApp and how healthcare workers
Speaker 1:  are using it to, to fight COVID misinformation are, is, is really interesting.
Speaker 1:  Check that. Okay. Windows 11,
Speaker 1:  Tom. Ooh.
Speaker 5:  It's a lot of love windows 11 today. Yeah. Yeah. Where do I
Speaker 5:  begin? So, I mean, we've talked about this on the verge cuts before,
Speaker 5:  but there was a lot today you start menu and you design
Speaker 5:  Android apps. So should we start from the design?
Speaker 1:  I think we should start with the fact that Microsoft tried to host a live
Speaker 1:  stream. Microsoft. One of the world's biggest cloud computing
Speaker 1:  providers was not able to execute a live stream for
Speaker 1:  windows. Was it Azure? Did that fail? I don't think we'll ever know. I
Speaker 1:  just know that eventually Microsoft executives were like
Speaker 1:  tweeting out YouTube links so people could watch this thing.
Speaker 5:  All I know is that I watched the majority of it through
Speaker 5:  Twitter. I don't typically watch Twitter videos cause
Speaker 5:  they crushed the compression of ink, but it worked fine
Speaker 5:  through there. But yeah, through Microsoft's own streaming, it was, yeah,
Speaker 5:  it was terrible.
Speaker 1:  So that was kind of the stutter start to the whole
Speaker 1:  thing started out with Penn has been a, has she product officer
Speaker 1:  Microsoft? One thing I was not expecting, and this was the
Speaker 1:  frame, they put her on the whole thing. They were like, oh shit, windows
Speaker 1:  is important.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  That seems to be like the, the thing they realized during the
Speaker 5:  pandemic, essentially
Speaker 1:  They were like explicit about it. Panels was like, damn, I used the windows.
Speaker 5:  I literally just finished speaking to panels. And he was kind of saying that
Speaker 5:  basically that they obviously went in, started this work on 10
Speaker 5:  X. So the last time they did a surface event in New York, it was this jewel
Speaker 5:  screen device is 10 X was the thing that they were going to do is it's new
Speaker 5:  version of windows, 10 CIOs screen devices. And then when
Speaker 5:  the pandemic comes, everyone's rushing out to get laptops and to
Speaker 5:  work from home. Like they, they obviously see way more into the metrics and
Speaker 5:  the telemetry and everything else than we would ever do. But I think their
Speaker 5:  argument is that people are using windows more and they're not picking up
Speaker 5:  their phones when they're at home, when stuck in doors, you know, like you,
Speaker 5:  you and I know that I'm not like I'm more glued to my laptop than I've ever
Speaker 5:  been at my desktop than I've ever been before. So I think they've obviously
Speaker 5:  realized that opportunity to then try and keep people glued to those
Speaker 5:  devices when we start venturing out into the world and have this
Speaker 5:  hybrid workplace. But it's also that they've had to like redesign and
Speaker 5:  re work windows during that pandemic to then
Speaker 5:  try and guess where people are going to be using it. Like when we start going,
Speaker 5:  trying to get feel back to the office and stuff, which is kind of happening
Speaker 5:  in a lot of locations now. So it's definitely an interesting time to launch
Speaker 5:  a new version of windows under that whole era of the pandemic. You
Speaker 1:  Just talked to pantos Sasha and Adela is on decoder. By the time you listened
Speaker 1:  to this, it'll be out there coming out at the same time. And he mentioned
Speaker 1:  to me, he said the same thing. He's like, I never had a home office. And
Speaker 1:  then I had one in my girls were at home and he got all the way
Speaker 1:  to, I'm really proud of windows update and how it works now. And I was like,
Speaker 1:  oh, you were annoyed too. Like it
Speaker 1:  happened, right? Like they all stopped using their managed computers at the
Speaker 1:  office in Redmond. All of their executives are at home and they're like,
Speaker 1:  oh, we can make windows easier and better to use. And there was just a lot
Speaker 1:  of that. Like throughout this event, they were just kind of
Speaker 1:  explicitly saying it to me,
Speaker 4:  The feature that like most clearly shows it is they
Speaker 4:  fixed your windows, flying all over creation. When you plug in a
Speaker 4:  monitor or unplug the monitor, they actually go where they're supposed to.
Speaker 4:  And then come back to where they were. And it's like, oh, they
Speaker 4:  actually like are using monitors at home. They're actually using their devices
Speaker 4:  in a multimodal way. They're not just leading them around their desk at the
Speaker 4:  office. Now they, they finally get it. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  It's a little dark.
Speaker 5:  It's slightly all turned into windows, laptop reviews
Speaker 5:  overnight. Like this one thing that never really
Speaker 5:  affected me. Oh man, does it affect me now?
Speaker 5:  So
Speaker 1:  Just a remarkable frame for an event that they were, they were honest
Speaker 1:  about it. I, I appreciated that, but then there's a lot of changes.
Speaker 1:  So the last time you were on, we were talking about a leak build. They went
Speaker 1:  farther than the leaks in many ways. What were the big, big changes to the
Speaker 1:  UI?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, because obviously the leak was kind of just scratching the surface.
Speaker 5:  I feel like there was a lot more than, than what we thought was
Speaker 5:  coming. The big sort of visual stuff, design stuff is a new
Speaker 5:  start menu. It's centered. They made a big deal about that. Obviously they
Speaker 5:  couldn't really avoid it and it can be put to the left-hand side. We know
Speaker 5:  that, but it's, it's centered. You start button, the actual
Speaker 5:  start menu itself. When you launch it is more like a launch.
Speaker 5:  Now I know we talked about this before, but like, is, it is almost like
Speaker 5:  you're an app launcher. Like you try and on Android, like it's
Speaker 5:  obviously heavily inspired by Android Chrome iOS, even macro S right.
Speaker 5:  Like it kind of matches up to everything now.
Speaker 5:  So it's going to be censored by default. You'll get like your
Speaker 5:  search on there. You get pinned apps, your recent, it feels just a
Speaker 5:  lot more usable than the current start menu. I know D likes
Speaker 5:  live tiles. I, I ha I read about it on the LifeLock
Speaker 5:  today.
Speaker 4:  I will like the new widget system that we'll talk about in a minute better,
Speaker 4:  but there is something useful about having like the
Speaker 4:  original, you know, windows, phone dream. Like here's this place you go.
Speaker 4:  And it has all the stuff you need to launch your apps. But it also like has
Speaker 4:  a little bit information that it's just nice to see real quick while you're
Speaker 4:  doing the other thing. So like, oh, the weather's there. Okay, great. Oh,
Speaker 4:  this is what's playing right now. Okay, great. But that's all going away.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. That's all going away. But I feel like at
Speaker 4:  The same way, I feel about Android widgets where it's like, if everybody
Speaker 4:  tried really hard to make them and keep them updated, then it would be great.
Speaker 4:  But no one seems to be able to maintain that for more than like three months,
Speaker 4:  you know?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Like that's obviously going away from the start menu, that lifestyle
Speaker 5:  thing. And then that is actually been shifted into a separate sort of
Speaker 5:  section a panel of glass, I think is what they described as in the,
Speaker 5:  in the event. Hi, I'm
Speaker 1:  Said it in chat during the event. There's a lot of Vista
Speaker 1:  vibes through windows holiness, right? Lots
Speaker 1:  of frosted transparency, lots of layers. A
Speaker 1:  lot of Vista vibes going on here and now maybe the hardware's fast
Speaker 1:  enough.
Speaker 5:  It's very glassy. Yeah. It's the way they call it. Yeah. And
Speaker 5:  like that, that fostered panel glass thing slides
Speaker 5:  in, and it's basically we, your widgets. So we don't, they didn't really
Speaker 5:  get into the detail of like how these are gonna, you know, like developers
Speaker 5:  are going to be able to plug into this stuff, but they showed up like newsfeeds,
Speaker 5:  some verge. Of course
Speaker 1:  There are two different verticals in there and their demos and PR all right,
Speaker 1:  I'll take it. The weather's in there. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Freaked me out was when they said that this was like, there there's like
Speaker 4:  going to be an AI. And it was like a feed. And I was like, oh God,
Speaker 4:  this is basically like the left of home, Google menu. This is going to
Speaker 4:  suck. But it looks like you, it's a combination of widgets that you
Speaker 4:  move around and place yourself. And then underneath that, all the news feed
Speaker 4:  stuff. And so they're not going to try and do the Google mouse thing where
Speaker 4:  they like show you what you think you need there. You know, when you need
Speaker 4:  it, you're actually going to be able to organize your own damn widgets the
Speaker 4:  way you want. And then underneath that, or next to it will be
Speaker 4:  the news feed stuff is my hunch. Oh, you harsher. Right? Like
Speaker 4:  they know
Speaker 1:  That everybody uses windows has a phone. And just like Tom was saying, the
Speaker 1:  start menu is starting to converge on what everything else looks like. This
Speaker 1:  left of home widget system is converging on what Android
Speaker 1:  looks like in some way, what iOS is doing in some way, what
Speaker 1:  Samsung is doing in some way, there are differences.
Speaker 1:  Yes. Like minor execution differences. Yeah. But the way
Speaker 1:  windows is organized now, just roughly
Speaker 1:  approximates the way everything else is organized. I think that's
Speaker 1:  smart. I don't, I don't think it's the wrong thing to do. I just the idea
Speaker 1:  that this is some sort of breakthrough pattern of user
Speaker 1:  behavior is like, nah, this, this is kinda what an iPad
Speaker 1:  looks like. And also kind of what Samsung phone looks like and kind of
Speaker 1:  what a Chromebook looks like. It means it's easier to switch between
Speaker 1:  devices, which I'm always banging on about making it easier to
Speaker 1:  switch. They actually feel some competition, but it's also like, like you
Speaker 1:  were saying neater, like this stuff only works with people like developers
Speaker 1:  participate in it. And if you're like a widget developer, you're like, where
Speaker 1:  do I go? What do I do? Like you just kind of like wanna make an app
Speaker 1:  that makes
Speaker 6:  Them money and stuff, which you don't need life. You think
Speaker 4:  About it this whole, like it's an entire other layer of the system on
Speaker 4:  top of it. It might as well be underneath the desktop full of
Speaker 4:  glanceable information wizards. It's almost like a, like a dashboard,
Speaker 4:  right. I'm
Speaker 1:  Still extremely salty for
Speaker 1:  years. I had a dashboard widget that just told me
Speaker 1:  what time, like it was called Kronos. I can't believe I'm talking about a
Speaker 1:  Chronos ladder. It would just tell me what time it was, where
Speaker 1:  everybody you could like sly, you would like slide a slider and
Speaker 1:  he'd be like, it's four. O'clock my time. And then it would tell me what
Speaker 1:  time it was everywhere that the verge team was. Yeah. And they took it away
Speaker 1:  from me. And now I'm just like, whatever. It's two in the morning for Tommy,
Speaker 1:  he's getting the slack anyway.
Speaker 6:  And it's all because of widget study. Cause it
Speaker 5:  Ruined everyone's life. That's the interesting part of this is that it all
Speaker 5:  comes under this panel. You can't like drop these widgets on a desktop.
Speaker 5:  You know, you obviously could in macro S and obviously in Vista as
Speaker 5:  well, they did these widgets. They did a similar thing in Vista
Speaker 5:  back in the day in like windows 98. I kind of remember active
Speaker 5:  desktop similar sort of thing, which is so that these things live in their
Speaker 5:  own slide out. So I'm curious about that. Like, are
Speaker 5:  people really going to slide out to get these widgets? Where are they putting
Speaker 1:  Notifications in all of this on the right same way they are now? Yeah.
Speaker 5:  The notification cation center is pretty much the same as it was in windows
Speaker 5:  10. It just looks better. They've changed a few things around that and obviously
Speaker 5:  the volume fly outs and stuff like that. Like the one in windows 10 right
Speaker 5:  now it's super annoying. The one in windows 11 is not as super annoying.
Speaker 5:  So
Speaker 1:  I'll just say between the leak and then this, with the transparency and seeing
Speaker 1:  some of these additional features, it looks a lot better than I expected
Speaker 1:  from the lakes. Like some of the stuff where there's
Speaker 1:  ancient parts of the elements or ancient parts of the interface and control
Speaker 1:  centers. Like yeah. There's like windows stuff going on in
Speaker 1:  here that everyone has always complained about, but just in
Speaker 1:  general it looks a lot tinier and more modern. And
Speaker 1:  this like ultra flat windows, 10 interface was starting to age out
Speaker 1:  and this looks a lot better.
Speaker 5:  And, and they did show some of the dark mode stuff and it's, it looks like
Speaker 5:  they're actually going to make sure dark mode is a bit more
Speaker 5:  universal because I have dark mode running on my windows 10 PC
Speaker 5:  right now, but I could do stuff like going to start and run. And
Speaker 5:  in immediately that dialog box it's, you know, it's is a white
Speaker 5:  mode element. So it's like, they're starting to think about those sort of
Speaker 5:  things that they kind missed or which are really glaringly obvious. And
Speaker 5:  just, I feel like they're getting all the touch points where you really interact
Speaker 5:  with windows where it really matters and yes, yes. There's going to be stuff
Speaker 5:  like control panels probably still there. Right? Like that's not going away.
Speaker 5:  Richard is still there, all this stuff buried underneath. But I think
Speaker 5:  as long as that, stuff's still there for people who need it, but like, you
Speaker 5:  don't stumble across it from just a, you know, just using your
Speaker 5:  computer for a zoom call or whatever. Then I don't think it's so
Speaker 5:  much of a big deal as long as they make it just way more usable. And this
Speaker 5:  does look a lot more usable. We have to play around with it. Obviously. I
Speaker 5:  also
Speaker 1:  Like just compared to what apple is doing in big Sur, which
Speaker 1:  is a nightmare of crap that happens on the right side of your
Speaker 1:  screen. This makes a lot more sense.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Like it does, it does look like they've gone down the simplification
Speaker 5:  route, which they were obviously going for windows 10 X and it feels like
Speaker 5:  they've got the right ideas. So it's just how it plays out. So
Speaker 1:  10 X was like going to happen and it feels like they took all of those ideas
Speaker 1:  and just made it windows 11. Is that more or less what happened here? Pretty
Speaker 1:  much.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Like they, they basically supercharged those ideas. I think like the,
Speaker 5:  even like down to the Android apps on windows stuff, I think that was probably
Speaker 5:  always going to come to Tenex at some point. It's just that stuff just being
Speaker 5:  accelerated for, you know, get that in windows and let it get out or all
Speaker 5:  machines. And it's, it's also interesting that this is obviously arriving
Speaker 5:  in like October time, roughly. And it's, it's an interesting
Speaker 5:  release of windows as well, because it's also, it's almost going to demand
Speaker 5:  like new hardware, which we haven't really seen for
Speaker 5:  windows since like windows eight, really? Because windows 10, wasn't really
Speaker 5:  a hardware thing. It was more of a like, yeah, we kind of
Speaker 5:  messed up windows eight, see these install this immediately, it's
Speaker 5:  a free upgrade. So that's, that's another sort of interesting
Speaker 5:  dimensions to see what sort of hardware comes in
Speaker 4:  Tom, since you brought it up. I mean, we've got to get into a bunch of other
Speaker 4:  stuff. I really want to talk about the, the new step guide stuff or snap
Speaker 4:  layout stuff. I knew that's what you were going to say.
Speaker 6:  It's coming, it's coming. I'm so excited about it. Requiring
Speaker 4:  New hardware comes with like, it's going to entice some people to upgrade.
Speaker 4:  There's this thing where like the stylist has haptics and that might entice
Speaker 4:  some people to upgrade, but can you talk about this, this issue that's been
Speaker 4:  flying around today with windows health check and you need a certain kind
Speaker 4:  of thing and your bios
Speaker 5:  And seminars. Yeah. That's, that's definitely been something that's been,
Speaker 5:  been flying around, so they have actually made it. So you need to have a
Speaker 5:  TPM 2.0 chip, which basically it sounds
Speaker 5:  complicated, but it, that should have shipped with any sort of modern CPU
Speaker 5:  in the last decade. Really. So, and I think it's been a requirement of like
Speaker 5:  windows PCs since like 2016. So like if you've got a
Speaker 5:  relatively new device in the last sort of five years, then you should be
Speaker 5:  fine. I think what people are seeing is that they they're
Speaker 5:  in, like, they have a device where they don't have a TPM chip maybe,
Speaker 5:  or they've got it, but it's not fully enabled in the bile. So I'd love to
Speaker 5:  see how Microsoft's going to solve that and tell people to dig into bile
Speaker 5:  screens, which are always different on every single
Speaker 5:  device. That's going to be like an interesting
Speaker 5:  one. They
Speaker 4:  Can just tell people to go visit a Microsoft store. Oh yeah.
Speaker 4:  Oh,
Speaker 5:  Microsoft experience center. There's only three of them in the world, but
Speaker 1:  That's why it's such an experience. I've got to get to one it's a
Speaker 1:  long, it's a long journey actually do. Let's talk about when snapping, cause
Speaker 1:  I think we're going to end up spending a lot of time on Android apps. Okay.
Speaker 1:  We talk a lot about windowing on this show. We mostly talk about it in the
Speaker 1:  context of the iPad because they've had is horrible at
Speaker 1:  it. Yeah. Microsoft is just leaning all the way into it. Like you're going
Speaker 1:  to have a bunch of windows and our system should arrange them for you. And
Speaker 1:  like in reality, there's only what is it? Six layouts that you might actually
Speaker 1:  want and here they are. And it seems so
Speaker 1:  simple and it is kind of genius.
Speaker 4:  Well, they're also, they and I I've had, I was 15 to doing the same thing
Speaker 4:  where they, they like, they know no one's going to ever remember the stupid
Speaker 4:  swipe gestures to like snap the window into the corner that you wanted or
Speaker 4:  whatever. So in the same way that iPad has, and Samsung have like the 3d
Speaker 4:  menus to show you the layout options. They're just doing that with the expando
Speaker 4:  button, the square button on a window and they show you the tile
Speaker 4:  options. And I think that's fine. I love that. They're just being way
Speaker 4:  smarter about maintaining your layouts. You can apparently save
Speaker 4:  layouts and there'll be like a whole mix of like, your desktop is over here
Speaker 4:  and then your snap layouts are here. And like, people might get confused
Speaker 4:  by that. But just looking at it, my hunch is that
Speaker 4:  people will like find one thing that they like it'll get saved in their doc
Speaker 4:  and all that extra complexity will be there for power users. But hopefully
Speaker 4:  won't get in the way of, you know, normal people that just want to have their
Speaker 4:  windows stay where they're supposed to.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And it's super interesting that they're surfacing basically what's
Speaker 5:  already existed in windows for years, these select snap areas. So
Speaker 5:  you can cascade windows, you can snap them side by side. Have you been able
Speaker 5:  to do this, but in with a bunch of windows shortcuts or just with your mouse,
Speaker 5:  but it's not, you know, most windows use it like regular windows users never
Speaker 5:  knew that you could even probably do that. So it's like, they're literally
Speaker 5:  surfacing on the maximize button, which is super interesting.
Speaker 1:  Keep coming back to this idea that all of their executives were working at
Speaker 1:  home and they were like doing the same thing that everyone else
Speaker 1:  does in like slack or teams or whatever. And someone's like, oh, there's
Speaker 1:  a keyboard command to snap your windows to the right. And Panis was like
Speaker 1:  really
Speaker 6:  Right. Like patos pedals do come on.
Speaker 1:  I don't know, man. Well, no, cause he's in flow. He definitely knew. Okay.
Speaker 1:  I'll, I'll give you an S like definitely he knows he's got a macro to get
Speaker 1:  himself to be some marketing exec for sure. But it's
Speaker 1:  true of the iPad too. Like what is the big theme across all these operating
Speaker 1:  systems? This year, they took a bunch of power user features and they
Speaker 1:  just made them obvious for people. And they stopped treating everybody like
Speaker 1:  idiots, right? Like for what a full decade,
Speaker 1:  the dominant design attitude was, most
Speaker 1:  people are stupid and can only do one thing at a time. And that's how our
Speaker 1:  operating systems work. And like just over the past year, they're like,
Speaker 1:  what if we're not stupid?
Speaker 6:  What if you'd like
Speaker 1:  To use your computer in a multiple different ways? And we, you can
Speaker 1:  handle the complexity of windows, not
Speaker 1:  windows. You understand what I'm saying? Yeah. It's just hilarious
Speaker 1:  to me that it, right. Like I talked about second order effects of the pandemic.
Speaker 1:  This is like the 50th order effect of the pandemic
Speaker 1:  is big tech companies are like, we think our users are not
Speaker 1:  complete idiots when it comes to organizing windows on a desktop. And it's
Speaker 1:  just like hilarious to me that it is true of Apple's operating systems and
Speaker 1:  it is natural windows that they're just showing you the complexity and trusting
Speaker 1:  you to solve it. And everyone's like, this is
Speaker 5:  Awesome. I'd also love to know like the stats from Microsoft
Speaker 5:  on how many people in the pandemic have suddenly gone from using one
Speaker 5:  screen, wherever it'd be big, regardless of the resolution to using
Speaker 5:  too. Because like, I just know, anecdotally people
Speaker 5:  who've been having to shift at work in the live room have had gone out and
Speaker 5:  bought a monitor, a 24 inch monitor and then used
Speaker 5:  both. But they're using their laptop screen. Whereas in, in the office they
Speaker 5:  would just be using the monitor they've got in their office and not, not
Speaker 5:  leave necessarily using both of them. I have a machine in the office. So
Speaker 5:  I'd love to know that because that like plays into this snap thing is that
Speaker 5:  these snack groups have the see, save where all your windows
Speaker 5:  are, which has been a real big problem. When you connect
Speaker 5:  up a windows, laptop to another monitoring, all your windows, just fly
Speaker 5:  around.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Yeah. That's what Deidre is saying. Yeah. They all had that experience
Speaker 1:  of on this call, but my kids are being loud. I got to unplug my laptop and
Speaker 1:  go somewhere else and then plug it back in and everything is messed
Speaker 1:  up. There's like, I don't know why. Maybe it's because they were
Speaker 1:  so honest about their rethinking windows because of the pandemic. I just
Speaker 1:  look at this stuff and I'm like, oh, a lot of people had to actually use
Speaker 1:  their products this past year across the companies. And they're doing
Speaker 1:  things that previously they insisted to us
Speaker 1:  that only some small percentage of people actually want it.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Yeah, exactly. All
Speaker 1:  Right. Well that obviously brings us to enter it apps and windows, which
Speaker 1:  I guarantee you only some small percentage. Sure. People, you know,
Speaker 4:  Another thing that every single Microsoft executive was forced to use during
Speaker 4:  the pandemic was teams. And now there's a big damn button for
Speaker 6:  The task bar.
Speaker 5:  If you're in windows 11, do you know? What's not everywhere in windows 11,
Speaker 5:  Skype op op, because teams as teams has taken over.
Speaker 5:  Right. Okay. It's just
Speaker 1:  About time. I mean that's years in the making. So here's, so they put teams
Speaker 1:  in a start button. They're giving a teams account to
Speaker 1:  everyone now. Yep. Which is one of those we're
Speaker 1:  making it great for you also, we're a giant dominant monopoly, not everybody
Speaker 1:  as a default teams account. Which one do you think it is? Got
Speaker 1:  this feature that Dieter, I'm just assuming you understand, maybe only
Speaker 1:  understand, so you can message anybody in
Speaker 1:  teams across a range of formats. Yep.
Speaker 1:  And then like if the person you're trying to message, doesn't have a teams
Speaker 1:  account it'll fall back to SMS using
Speaker 1:  correct. Your phone number, using your phone number. That's what they have
Speaker 1:  said. I
Speaker 4:  Have tweeted someone to please answer how this works to me.
Speaker 4:  I've hunted around a little bit, a Microsoft site can't find it. And I've
Speaker 4:  also emailed Microsoft PR and said, how does this work?
Speaker 4:  And I have yet to find an answer. Cause the
Speaker 1:  Other option is every windows machine gets a new phone
Speaker 1:  number that can use SMS. Right. Which seems even
Speaker 1:  more unworkable than, than using SMS.
Speaker 4:  It's unclear. Like how do they, how, if they're, if they're texting from
Speaker 4:  your phone number, there's like two ways to do that. Three ways to do it.
Speaker 4:  One, you like mirror to the Android phone. You can do that. Now on windows
Speaker 4:  10, you can like set up a web app that beers to your Android phone. You can
Speaker 4:  do that on any platform or you a text from the
Speaker 4:  phone. That's a way you just use the phone, but that's not obviously what
Speaker 4:  this is doing. Or you sort of a deal with every single carrier on the planet
Speaker 4:  and let them give you a backdoor into their SMS system, which seems unlikely
Speaker 4:  to me. So they must, I have no idea how this works,
Speaker 5:  Unless, because SMS is so sketchy
Speaker 5:  that you can just pretend you are that number
Speaker 5:  that's possible.
Speaker 1:  Okay. I'm just going to read you that this is in their blog post.
Speaker 1:  Now you can instantly connect through text, chat, voice, or video with all
Speaker 1:  of your personal contacts anywhere, no matter the platform or device they're
Speaker 1:  on across windows, Android or
Speaker 1:  iOS, if that's all about teams, right. That's what they're saying.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. If the person you're connecting to on the other end, hasn't
Speaker 1:  downloaded the teams app. You can still connect with them via
Speaker 1:  two way. SMS. Yeah. No further
Speaker 1:  information.
Speaker 4:  Here's my hunch. They get a text from a random number saying Nila
Speaker 4:  wants to chat. This is what he said. And then they could reply to that thing.
Speaker 4:  And it creates a relay that texts back to you until they finally give up
Speaker 4:  and install the teams. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  At the end of every message is download the teens up here with the short
Speaker 1:  link.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Yeah. Sent from Microsoft teams. Shortlink I will
Speaker 4:  Tell you that one of the only companies to sign on
Speaker 4:  to promise that they would someday adopt RCS
Speaker 4:  was Microsoft.
Speaker 1:  No, God. Oh no. This is a direct call out to
Speaker 1:  two-way SMS. Yeah. There's no, there's no RCS in here. I
Speaker 1:  just, yeah. They called it out. They're excited about it. No details on how
Speaker 1:  it works. If they've actually managed to figure out how to
Speaker 1:  let your windows computer, or just do SMS through teams using
Speaker 1:  your phone number, that's a huge deal. We just don't know.
Speaker 5:  I had to mention it's something to do with your phone.
Speaker 1:  Nobody. Cause I said iOS to you don't need it. You don't need an Android
Speaker 1:  phones do this. Yeah. And I have no deal with apple as far as I know.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Although in, in his interview with Joanna stern, Satya said that anything
Speaker 4:  apple wants to do with windows, whether it's iTunes or I iMessage or what
Speaker 4:  have you, we would welcome that. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  So hold your breath there. Satya. All right.
Speaker 4:  Well
Speaker 1:  That brings us to like the biggest thing and windows
Speaker 1:  11 in terms of architectural, which is there's
Speaker 1:  a new Microsoft store that store
Speaker 1:  will let you discover Android apps. And then when you go to download
Speaker 1:  one, from what we can tell, it will open Amazon
Speaker 1:  Android app store inside the windows store. We don't actually that's
Speaker 1:  unclear. Okay.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. They didn't actually really show it and they, they they're like, we're
Speaker 5:  not quite sure what it's going to look like. So
Speaker 1:  My guess is that there's a separate app, the Amazon Android
Speaker 1:  app. Yeah. That you have to install so that you'll discover the absence in
Speaker 1:  the windows store. And then when you go to download the Android app, you'll
Speaker 1:  open the Android app store and then that will download Android apps. And
Speaker 1:  then you will be able to just run Android apps on your windows PC.
Speaker 4:  Right? Oh, so it's discoverable in the ma in the Microsoft stores. Like you
Speaker 4:  can search for Tik TOK, it'll show you it. But then there's a button that
Speaker 4:  has a little arrow going away saying get from the Amazon store. So
Speaker 4:  is yeah. Yeah. And
Speaker 1:  Adela told me that if Google wants to participate, they would also support
Speaker 1:  the play store. What actions they've asked Google and
Speaker 1:  Google has declined to participate. Hence we have the Amazon app store,
Speaker 1:  which to be fair, has a bunch of stuff on it. It
Speaker 1:  does have TechTalk and Snapchat and all these things that people use on fire
Speaker 1:  tablets. For the most part, I think you can download the Amazon app
Speaker 1:  store on Google. You can like sideload it. No one uses it. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It has a bunch of outdated Android apps. It's probably the best way to describe.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Well, so my hope is that maybe this will be the thing
Speaker 4:  that incentivizes developers to keep their apps on the Amazon
Speaker 4:  app store updated, or even submit them to the Amazon app store. And then
Speaker 4:  we might have some better app store competition on Android. That could be
Speaker 4:  interesting.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. We'll get to there in a second. So you download the, the example they
Speaker 1:  kept using was tick tock, right? Tectonics, very popular app Panisse went
Speaker 1:  so far as to claim it was his favorite app, which is hilarious. Moda
Speaker 1:  love to see what Pennys Penny's tick tock algorithm serves him
Speaker 1:  weightlifting because he's pumped. It's just designed for, you know, it's
Speaker 1:  just like close-ups of like chamfers and
Speaker 1:  hinges. That's a great Tik TOK feed. And I'd love to look at it.
Speaker 1:  And yeah, so you download tech doc in some convoluted way. It
Speaker 1:  delivers, it gets full windowing support on windows.
Speaker 1:  So you can like pin it to the side. He can stretch it. Most windows
Speaker 1:  computers are touchscreen. Like the ad that is coming is
Speaker 1:  somebody scrolling Tech-Talk on their laptop while doing work over
Speaker 1:  here. And of course, apple has no recourse for that because
Speaker 1:  they refused to put a touch screen on their laptops. I think that alone,
Speaker 1:  even if all you did this and it's kind of janky, but you get to make that
Speaker 1:  ad super worth
Speaker 5:  It. Yep, yep. Right. It is also Android mobile games as
Speaker 5:  well. Like there's a surprising amount of people who do actually want to
Speaker 5:  run those on, on their PCs that like carry on their gaming
Speaker 5:  session that they had on their phone and they just have it running on their
Speaker 5:  windows PC through like blue stacks and all those sorts of connectors. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I could definitely see the value in it. And like, I think most people probably
Speaker 5:  don't really need Android apps on the PC, but there's some stuff
Speaker 5:  like home automation apps that just aren't available on
Speaker 5:  the web or on your desktop PC. So like there is, there's
Speaker 5:  some apps that you might, I'm sure everyone has one app that they would be
Speaker 5:  like, huh. Okay. That's kind of useful to have that on my
Speaker 5:  PC. It's just what is the app, but
Speaker 1:  Yeah. And is it available in the Amazon app store as opposed to Google
Speaker 1:  play? That's the big blocker, but again, a preview of the conversation with
Speaker 1:  on decoder, I was like, it's not great. Do you think he's good enough? He's
Speaker 1:  like, I hope that all gets better. Like if I go into it eyes
Speaker 1:  open, but they have this other avenue and he was like, it will be very interesting
Speaker 1:  to see if Google participates in there's competition between app stores.
Speaker 5:  So the big deal about this, not necessarily the Amazon app
Speaker 5:  store and all that sort of stuff. It's the pure fact that they've opened
Speaker 5:  up the app store to rival app stores essentially within their
Speaker 5:  store. So I spoke to panelists like moments ago about
Speaker 5:  this and he, he was basically open to like, you know, steam being their
Speaker 5:  epic games store being in there. It's like, they basically want the store
Speaker 5:  now to be the place where you get all of your apps, regardless of whether
Speaker 5:  you're getting them from the windows store or not. And like that's, that's
Speaker 5:  more of an interesting shift than even Android apps on windows, to be honest,
Speaker 5:  because that actually makes the store that much more interesting
Speaker 5:  and useful. And you know, the center, the center to get all your apps.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I want
Speaker 4:  To wrap up Android one last thing, which is why not side load. You can install
Speaker 4:  Android apps directly just like you can any other app on a windows PC. So
Speaker 4:  maybe that'll be open and that'll be a fun world of piracy to think about
Speaker 4:  on the app store. If they can succeed even a
Speaker 4:  little in getting other app stores to participate, even just a little flag
Speaker 4:  that says I have installed these things so that I can have one
Speaker 4:  place on windows where what I set up a new PC, it could be.
Speaker 4:  Yep. Re-install these things that would be so
Speaker 4:  nice. That's all I want. I don't want to have to keep a doc. I keep a
Speaker 4:  notepad document. That's like all the stuff that I installed on a windows
Speaker 4:  computer. And just like, when I set a new one up, I just like go down the
Speaker 4:  checkbox tick, tick, tick, tick, tick. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  I think the other, the other thing that Android apps in particular is
Speaker 1:  unclear how well they're going to run, right? I mean, some big question.
Speaker 1:  These things are designed for the most part for arm processors,
Speaker 1:  particularly Qualcomm arm processors. The vast majority of
Speaker 1:  windows PC is run x86 processors from
Speaker 1:  Intel and AMD. Microsoft has been talking about the fact
Speaker 1:  that Intel bridge is the reason they're using this. That led a lot of
Speaker 1:  people to wonder this was Intel. Only Microsoft has since
Speaker 1:  clarified. It we'll work on Intel AMD and arm
Speaker 1:  processors. And Intel is like, oh, it's just a technology, but it'll work
Speaker 1:  best with Intel processors. So we'll see, we don't really
Speaker 1:  know what the CPU requirements are. And
Speaker 1:  we've just been told that like the real big constraint here is Ram. It's
Speaker 1:  an interesting thing to have been told as directly as I was told it. So we'll
Speaker 1:  just see like iOS apps on M one max are
Speaker 1:  not the greatest in the world. And that's the same
Speaker 1:  processor architecture. Literally the same processor is as the iPad.
Speaker 1:  There's just a lot to sort out here and all these developers have to
Speaker 1:  participate. They have to be in the Amazon app store and they have to decide
Speaker 1:  that they want to distribute to windows. So, yep. They got ticked off to
Speaker 1:  do it. But to Tom's point that huge long tail of Android
Speaker 1:  apps, all of those developers have to want this distribution. I think Microsoft's
Speaker 1:  argument is why wouldn't you want to distribute to another billion
Speaker 1:  devices? Just go get them. That's a reasonably good argument.
Speaker 1:  But as with everything we have to get it, we have to try it to see how
Speaker 1:  it actually works.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And then there's obviously the benefits for Amazon partnering with
Speaker 5:  them here is that they're going to get probably more
Speaker 5:  developers put in their apps over, right? Like there's going to be some percentage
Speaker 5:  of, of developers that will do that now. Whereas they probably wouldn't have
Speaker 5:  before, but like, it really does depend on the apps. I think home
Speaker 5:  automation apps are the other key, last stuff like ring
Speaker 5:  and all this sort of apps. But like beyond
Speaker 5:  that, I don't know. Like it's not something that I'm
Speaker 5:  like dying from windows. Like I do most of my work in
Speaker 5:  the browser and I think that's the same for, for a lot of people now. So
Speaker 5:  that's
Speaker 1:  Why Microsoft, you know, even when they talked about app support, it was
Speaker 1:  never just about Android apps. It was universal windows apps, regular windows
Speaker 1:  apps, progressive web apps and Android apps. Like that was the list they
Speaker 1:  kept on saying, cause they're like, we kind of don't care. We just want you
Speaker 1:  to use windows.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And I think if you can get all of those into the store in, in a coherent
Speaker 5:  way that like makes sense. Like if I, if I go in search for, I don't
Speaker 5:  know, Fortnite, and then, and then I searched for it in the windows store,
Speaker 5:  I click a button and it pulls me into the epic games. Still great. Like,
Speaker 5:  yeah, yeah, that's fine. Like, it's like, it's a little bit of a janky experience,
Speaker 5:  but like, that's kind of fine. Like, you know, that is kind of
Speaker 5:  windows. I prefer that to like, having to
Speaker 5:  think where is fortnight installed or like w
Speaker 5:  what vulture have I got to use to get to that, to update it or to launch
Speaker 5:  it, whatever. So I think if they can pull it
Speaker 5:  off and be open in the process, which it seems like they
Speaker 5:  are like, yeah, that's, that's good news for people who use windows. For
Speaker 5:  sure,
Speaker 4:  Tom, how I'm going to hold myself back from talking about progressive web
Speaker 4:  apps. You're welcome. How big a deal is it? Do you think that they're opening
Speaker 4:  it up to like 1 32 and just like any app that runs on windows it's hap we're
Speaker 4:  happy to have it in her store. They're gonna, you know, I'm sure they're
Speaker 4:  going to have some requirements about, I dunno, some content stuff, no Nazis,
Speaker 4:  no porn or whatever, but other like, from a technical perspective, they're
Speaker 4:  like, yeah, come one, come all.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Like that's another big part of this. Right? Cause when he first launched
Speaker 5:  the store, you couldn't have Chrome in there. So everyone was like, okay,
Speaker 5:  number one, browser. I can't get it. And you're gonna force me to use edge,
Speaker 5:  which is obviously edge is better now, but it wasn't then there wasn't
Speaker 5:  iTunes, which obviously doesn't matter now, but it did then. And
Speaker 5:  it's just like opening it up to all these apps. Adobe creative suite is not
Speaker 5:  in the store slate. If you want to get Photoshop, you get like some touch
Speaker 5:  version or like some really lightweight version that let's be honest,
Speaker 5:  nobody really uses do they, they just go for the full, full version of
Speaker 5:  Photoshop or windows. So like having that stuff there is,
Speaker 5:  is, yeah, like that's, it, it goes to your point again, like you have
Speaker 5:  a list of apps, you used all on new windows device, right? Like,
Speaker 5:  and all of those apps, you have to go search out onto the web to like find
Speaker 5:  them and stuff. And it's just centralizing it in one location where it should
Speaker 5:  be.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Let's, let's take a break right there because there's some big
Speaker 1:  business side stuff to why Adobe chose to be in that
Speaker 1:  store that we need to talk about at length. But we got to take a break. We'll
Speaker 1:  be right
Speaker 1:  back.
Speaker ?:  Let's get real the tech world. Doesn't always like to keep it simple from
Speaker ?:  over-hype products to constant sales pitches and endless jargon shopping
Speaker ?:  for quality electronics can be overwhelming, but it doesn't have to be
Speaker ?:  cut through the usual BS with high sense, high census, the straight talking
Speaker ?:  electronics brand that offers clarity and quality over confusion because
Speaker ?:  let's get real. The most important thing about a great TV is that it's actually
Speaker ?:  a great TV with all the features you love, like their new ULE D
Speaker ?:  series. Whether you're watching movies with the kids, enjoying a date night
Speaker ?:  or comfort, watching that show for the million time, high sense brings you
Speaker ?:  an unmatched 4k TV experience and with a range of sizes there
Speaker ?:  you led series is bringing premium products to the masses. We
Speaker ?:  can sit here and tell you all about the awesome features that come with.
Speaker ?:  High sense TVs features like quantum dot color HDR, 10 plus, and Dolby
Speaker ?:  Atmos. But all you really need to know is that high sense offers
Speaker ?:  unbeatable quality at unbelievable prices. Forget the
Speaker ?:  jargon and get real to learn more, visit high sense.com
Speaker ?:  today. That's high sense.com high sense. Let's get
Speaker ?:  real. I can't wait to call customer
Speaker ?:  support is something no one has ever said bad. Customer support experience
Speaker ?:  has cost businesses over 75 billion. Every year. It's 70% of
Speaker ?:  customers prefer to use search on a company's website to resolve their support
Speaker ?:  issues swiftly and independently, but not if that means sorting through a
Speaker ?:  bunch of random blue hyperlinks that get them nowhere. That's the experience
Speaker ?:  you get when your business uses keyword search and outdated technology that
Speaker ?:  hasn't innovated since 1999, you need Yext a modern AI
Speaker ?:  powered search that delivers direct answers to customer short questions,
Speaker ?:  not links with the XD can deflect more customer service calls,
Speaker ?:  decrease support tickets, and save a lot in costs all while raising
Speaker ?:  CSA T to learn more, go to Y E X
Speaker ?:  t.com/support.
Speaker 1:  Okay, we're back. So Tom, you were just talking about creative
Speaker 1:  cloud in the windows store. Adobe is they're not
Speaker 1:  there wacky touch versions. You're talking about maybe the
Speaker 1:  epic store will be there. Kind of a huge point of emphasis
Speaker 1:  for Microsoft for Nadella around
Speaker 1:  windows is that it's a platform for other
Speaker 1:  platforms and a huge term in the store that they are
Speaker 1:  changing. Is there cut if you choose
Speaker 1:  to use their payment processing, all that stuff is 15% now.
Speaker 1:  So instead of the 70 30, that we've just heard about endlessly with apple
Speaker 1:  and Google and whoever else, Microsoft is going to fly 85 15,
Speaker 1:  and then you can just not use it. So you don't have to use their
Speaker 1:  payment systems or whatever. You can put your apps in the store, use your
Speaker 1:  own payment. And obviously the 0% you're responsible for whatever
Speaker 1:  costs of rolling your own payment solution, which is why
Speaker 1:  Adobe is putting creative cloud in the store.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So, so there's a, there's a few things to this. So the 85,
Speaker 5:  15 split for apps has always been there from the windows
Speaker 5:  store, but like apps like creative suite just wouldn't, wouldn't
Speaker 5:  go for it. And not necessarily for the revenue split, but also just because
Speaker 5:  they couldn't have their own updater in there. So they couldn't control how
Speaker 5:  all their apps updated. So like that's also a part of it, but it's also
Speaker 5:  like the split between apps and games is really like
Speaker 5:  apparent here. So, so it's 85, 15 for apps,
Speaker 5:  88, 12 for games, which is coming in August, which they've
Speaker 5:  already announced. So they're pulling it back a bit, but if you want to
Speaker 5:  use the in app purchase system, so if you're fortnight and you want to be
Speaker 5:  in the windows store that doesn't apply like that free
Speaker 5:  open approach doesn't apply to games. Right? So it's only
Speaker 5:  for apps CA works great for like creative suite,
Speaker 5:  whatever. I'm trying to think of other sort of subscription based apps on
Speaker 5:  windows. But like for those sorts of apps, it works fine. But for
Speaker 5:  games, which is really where revenues generated in these stores, no,
Speaker 5:  like you have to use Microsoft's payment processing platform
Speaker 4:  Draws a similar line on the play store actually have different rules for
Speaker 4:  games and they do for everything else.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Like that's, that's literally where people spend their money, right?
Speaker 5:  Like it's not many apps that people,
Speaker 1:  Another decade of asking what is a game
Speaker 1:  is right. But this is because
Speaker 1:  we know that the vast majority of the revenue for all these stores is in
Speaker 1:  app purchases in games like candy crush and whatever. They're not going to
Speaker 1:  turn away from that. And the game developers except for
Speaker 1:  epic are generally like, yeah, we're making a lot of money. Like let's just
Speaker 1:  pay some of it to the app store is because this is our whole business model
Speaker 1:  it's baked in. Whereas companies like Adobe and others, like,
Speaker 1:  what are you even doing for us? We don't want to pay you this money. We'd
Speaker 1:  rather just run our own, our own stack and be okay with it.
Speaker 4:  What do you make? Devil's advocate of the argument that what, the, another
Speaker 4:  reason that games have different rules is they're also like the place where
Speaker 4:  most of the like fraud and dark patterns to trick kids
Speaker 4:  into making purchases happens. And so forcing games to go through the
Speaker 4:  app store system means that they can provide a little bit more
Speaker 4:  protection to consumers. I'm like 50 50 on that at best.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Put on windows. It doesn't matter. Like, yeah, that's right. There's
Speaker 1:  just like, there's also the wild west and other games towards them, whatever
Speaker 1:  else have you, what you're really getting is again, I asked them like,
Speaker 1:  what do you got for your 15%? And he was like, you get discovery, you get
Speaker 1:  promotion, you get all this stuff. Microsoft will provide, which is the right
Speaker 1:  way to think about it. And I don't feel like that's kind of what apple
Speaker 1:  says, right? Like we bring the customers to you, but
Speaker 1:  they're also the only way that you can get customers for an iOS app. So it
Speaker 1:  just rings hollow. Whereas Microsoft is like, pay us the money. And then
Speaker 1:  over time you can evaluate whether you think that money is worth it and
Speaker 1:  leave if you don't think so, which I think is just a much healthier
Speaker 1:  dynamic for the stores. Like it'll put pressure on Microsoft to actually
Speaker 1:  deliver discovery and users and all that stuff in a way that apple
Speaker 1:  clearly doesn't feel any pressure to do. That's Dieter.
Speaker 1:  You wrote about this, like that's kind of where Nadella ended the whole event,
Speaker 1:  right? Just talking about how open windows is talking about being a
Speaker 1:  platform for platforms. I think you and I read it the same way or listened
Speaker 1:  or heard it the same way. Then he wrote about it that, well, that's a lot
Speaker 1:  of direct shots at apple.
Speaker 4:  It was a lot of direct shots at apple. This is the part where I get to talk
Speaker 4:  about Arthur Schopenhauer. I'm not actually going to do that, but he did
Speaker 4:  quote this like random philosopher who believes
Speaker 4:  that nothing is real and everything only exists. If you perceive it
Speaker 4:  yourself, I'm not going to go there. He caught him at the end. It's like,
Speaker 4:  you know, there are some creators that are meteors and they flame out on
Speaker 4:  there. Some creators that are stars that own a permanent place in the firmament
Speaker 4:  of the galaxy. And that's what we want to do is we want to make stars
Speaker 4:  very, very soaring. But leading up to that, he said some stuff
Speaker 4:  that like, here's a, here's the, here's a line that alludes to it. Ben
Speaker 4:  Thompson windows has always stood for sovereignty for
Speaker 4:  creators and agency for consumers. And
Speaker 4:  on both of those fronts, those are shots that apple agency for
Speaker 4:  consumers, she's got some stuff about like, you can build your own
Speaker 4:  PC. You can, it's your PC. You have agency over what happens
Speaker 4:  on it. You could choose what it does. It's yours not controlled by us. And
Speaker 4:  then on like sovereignty for creators, it's like creators are able to
Speaker 4:  like be in control of their own destiny and not have the money that they
Speaker 4:  make come through, you know, app store
Speaker 4:  fees. Although maybe if you use our direct tipping feature,
Speaker 4:  maybe cause you can get paid and Microsoft points in their new direct tipping
Speaker 4:  feature.
Speaker 1:  It's like amazing. If you're a local journalist and you get paid in Microsoft
Speaker 1:  YNC, I would be so mad. Oh man, I'd be so mad.
Speaker 5:  You could buy an export series X and then put it on.
Speaker 6:  I can't. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. He's got like lines, like windows recognizes. There is no personal
Speaker 4:  computing without personal agency. Personal computing
Speaker 4:  requires choice. Like tell me that's not a giant
Speaker 4:  shot at apple. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  And this thing about sovereign craters and owning your own business, like,
Speaker 1:  okay, here's the cynical read.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Oh yeah. I definitely share this. Yeah. The obvious
Speaker 1:  Cynical read, which is no one uses this app store. Yup. Until this
Speaker 1:  pandemic, we know it was an afterthought. Even for Microsoft, they've
Speaker 1:  got a big opportunity with soaring, laptop
Speaker 1:  sales and work from home. And everybody re
Speaker 1:  to attract developers to say, you're mad
Speaker 1:  at apple, come on home, come on home to windows. Here's a
Speaker 1:  billion users here into be the more open
Speaker 1:  platform because that's how you compete against the dominant closed
Speaker 1:  platform. Right. Which is exactly what apple did to
Speaker 1:  Microsoft in the early two thousands. Right?
Speaker 1:  Like Microsoft was the big dominant platform with all the antitrust scrutiny
Speaker 1:  and all the bullshit. And apple was like, our computer runs a Unix.
Speaker 1:  Our computer is good at the open web. It's so good at the open web that we
Speaker 1:  actually let Microsoft put internet Explorer on it. Cause that's what y'all
Speaker 1:  motherfuckers want to use. Apple, the Unix computer, that's
Speaker 1:  easy to use like straight up. That's what they said to developers and all
Speaker 1:  this web development moved to apple. Now Microsoft it's like Linux
Speaker 1:  runs on windows. First-class citizen, Android runs on windows, just
Speaker 1:  another Linux. Really also our store terms are easy. Like don't you want
Speaker 1:  to be here where everything works and everyone's happy. And also you definitely
Speaker 1:  have to have a Microsoft account to use windows. And we're definitely just
Speaker 1:  sort of doing telematics someone who's alive. Nevermind. Don't worry about
Speaker 1:  that. Right? Like that's the super cynical read of
Speaker 1:  this. I think the other read of it is, and
Speaker 1:  Nutella alluded this to, in his remarks and he said it on decoder, which
Speaker 1:  is, this is always what windows has been. Windows is where the
Speaker 1:  other biggest software businesses in the world have come up to some extent.
Speaker 1:  He even tried to take credit for the web on windows or some areas given all
Speaker 1:  the antitrust battles they faced. But he's like SAP was built in, born on
Speaker 1:  windows. That's a huge software company and we have no pardon. They just
Speaker 1:  run their apps on windows. There's a tension there. Like, I don't
Speaker 1:  know if the idealism versus the cynicism, like what the right ratio
Speaker 1:  is, but it's, it's both to some extent. Right?
Speaker 1:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And it's, it's, it's also windows was the default for so many years
Speaker 5:  right. On the desktop. So like of course SAP would have been built on that
Speaker 5:  and like PC gaming is built on top of that and it's
Speaker 5:  it. And I think the problem with windows is that yes, it's great. And it's
Speaker 5:  been open and like kinda Della can take credit for some of that if, if
Speaker 5:  he wants. But the problem with it now is that it's, it's escaped their
Speaker 5:  control in a way. And so they've tried all these different ways to
Speaker 5:  like bring the control of windows back and it hasn't really worked. So now
Speaker 5:  they've just been like, all right, we're open again. Yeah. So that
Speaker 1:  List is like, we know windows 10 S all the modes they've done, they
Speaker 4:  Went from windows S mode to windows, shrug, whatever, do what you
Speaker 4:  want
Speaker 5:  Love to have had the app model that apple has, right. Like that
Speaker 5:  control. Yeah. They tried and they failed. It's failed. And they've had,
Speaker 5:  they've had to be open. They've had to embrace this openness, which has been
Speaker 5:  great for them, like as a, as a company. And like for consumers is
Speaker 5:  great. Right. They've turned windows into an actual dev box that
Speaker 5:  developers aren't like laughing at. They're like, oh, well it does all this
Speaker 5:  stuff. Okay. Maybe I'll maybe I'll get one. And
Speaker 5:  it, yeah, just the open approaches is obviously for the best
Speaker 5:  bit it's differently because they've had to,
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I mean, I wrote that the underdogs always agitate for openness. That's
Speaker 4:  always how it works. Then when they become top dog, they close it up again.
Speaker 4:  But the other thing is like, it doesn't cost Microsoft anything to do this.
Speaker 4:  They get, they get the, have the easy shots at apple during the, all
Speaker 4:  this antitrust scrutiny. And it's not like their stores were successful in
Speaker 4:  the first place. So they're not losing anything by saying, come on, come
Speaker 4:  on. They're losing like potential future revenue. Maybe if they
Speaker 4:  figured out a way to turn it around, but they're probably not gonna. So they're
Speaker 4:  just going to stop trying take the easy, cheap wins now,
Speaker 4:  rhetorically against apple or whatever, and maybe build up some Goodwill
Speaker 4:  if people come to do it. And as far as the idealism versus cynicism
Speaker 4:  thing, I think the answer is yes, like in the same way
Speaker 4:  that Google is a, you know, their business
Speaker 4:  model is based on the web and based on advertising. And do they care about
Speaker 4:  privacy or they care about advertising? It's like, well, they're try to do
Speaker 4:  both. And when apple starts locking things down, it's like, why are they
Speaker 4:  locking things down? Cause they care about privacy. Are they locking things
Speaker 4:  down? Because you know, it's good for their business model that everybody
Speaker 4:  has to pay for stuff directly through their bottles. It's like, well, yes,
Speaker 4:  it's, it is possible for their philosophy and their business
Speaker 4:  model and the way they make their products to like all come together. And
Speaker 4:  I think that's kind of what's happening here. And there's definitely some
Speaker 4:  cynicism to think about with it, but you know, not so
Speaker 4:  much that like you should take advantage of the things that they're giving
Speaker 4:  you, you know, because they're cynical, you know what I mean? Yeah. I
Speaker 1:  Also said that on Dakota, he was like other companies do things for different
Speaker 1:  reasons and they're internally consistent for why they do them, but this
Speaker 1:  is our choice and we feel internally consistent about it. And I think part
Speaker 1:  of that is, you know, three years ago or whatever,
Speaker 1:  he, he was like, we could just rename windows Azure edge, but no
Speaker 1:  one's going to let me, and he's saying windows is not,
Speaker 1:  the operating system is not the most important layer for us. And I
Speaker 1:  think that's still true. He basically said, yeah, that's still basic. That's
Speaker 1:  still true for us. Right? Like Azure in our services,
Speaker 1:  businesses are the big businesses and they deploy to windows and the
Speaker 1:  windows team relies on the fact that we run a huge cloud platform to do a
Speaker 1:  bunch of stuff. And it's all one thing. And I don't have to make money on
Speaker 1:  windows, the way that we used to. And he's like other companies make money
Speaker 1:  in different ways and it leads them to different results. And I think that's,
Speaker 1:  you can feel about that a million different ways. Like at the same
Speaker 1:  time we're talking about anti-trust and browsers and defaults and other platforms
Speaker 1:  working on it. Microsoft is like, teams is in the start
Speaker 1:  button, right? Teams is everywhere now.
Speaker 1:  Like we're going to make teams, the default communication app for business
Speaker 1:  as aggressively as we can, because that's the future of Microsoft's
Speaker 1:  like workplace productivity business, and they're going to be aggressive
Speaker 1:  about it. But at the same time, if they are going to be idealistic, they
Speaker 1:  have to let you replace it. Right. And if it's not easy to get rid of all
Speaker 1:  the teams, buttons are in place, some of the slack buttons or whatever, but
Speaker 1:  I think they open themselves up to some criticism. So we'll see. But I think
Speaker 1:  you're right Teeter, like at the end of the day, there's one major
Speaker 1:  commercial operating system that lets you build your own
Speaker 1:  hardware that lets you run almost anything on it from a variety
Speaker 1:  of sources too. Once you touch the fucking
Speaker 1:  street, that's kind of
Speaker 1:  remarkable that Microsoft is positioning itself right there.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And it's Linux, right? It's
Speaker 1:  Linux, windows is Lennox now. Right? It's like Jamie
Speaker 1:  love to say, I
Speaker 5:  Absolutely think like everything they've done in windows 11,
Speaker 5:  everything they've showed today goes back to that thing. I'm sure it's
Speaker 5:  Nadella said it, that they wanted windows to be
Speaker 5:  loved. Like they want people to, and they've realized it during the
Speaker 5:  pandemic. Well, so they say like, you know, people using it more, but they
Speaker 5:  want to keep people hooked on windows because they know like where
Speaker 5:  computing is going. Like they know that they're building it, right? Like
Speaker 5:  cloud computing, everyone working in their browser is slowly
Speaker 5:  becoming it. We're not even slowly. It's just rapidly becoming
Speaker 5:  like a thing. And it's like, they want
Speaker 5:  people to move into the cloud, wanting
Speaker 5:  windows and wanting that flexibility so that if you
Speaker 5:  are going to work in a browser and they're going to stream that copy of windows
Speaker 5:  to that browser, you'll have all of your familiar controls, all the
Speaker 5:  stuff, you know, your apps are in the store, all that sort of stuff.
Speaker 5:  Like it's definitely about keeping people on windows now that they've got
Speaker 5:  a bit of a taste for it during the pandemic and also just, you know,
Speaker 5:  just getting them to rely on it more.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I think one interesting. You mentioned streaming windows. Like they're
Speaker 1:  streaming, Xbox. Yeah. Like Microsoft's bet on if
Speaker 1:  you can stream it, you should over, you can
Speaker 1:  deliver it via the cloud. You should will eventually turn its
Speaker 1:  weight. Yeah. Like
Speaker 5:  There's, there's a stop. And I can't remember the name of it right now, but
Speaker 5:  like I joked about it on Twitter a few months ago. It's just the browser
Speaker 5:  one. Yeah. Yeah. And it's like, when you think about it, like when you
Speaker 5:  initially look at it and you react to it, you think why would I pay 10 bucks
Speaker 5:  a month for a browser? And then when you think about the way things
Speaker 5:  are heading and the fact that people were picking up these old laptops, they
Speaker 5:  haven't used for years. And they're like trying to work during a pandemic
Speaker 5:  and trying to buy a new laptop and all that sort of stuff. It's like offering
Speaker 5:  them the power of an actual browser that works that just stream straight
Speaker 5:  to their computer is actually a way better experience than trying to use
Speaker 5:  the browser themselves. So like that, that that's, that is a way that we're
Speaker 5:  kind of heading with computing is especially when everything's contained
Speaker 5:  within the browser. Now
Speaker 1:  What Thomas talking about is called the mighty browser. It just runs criminal
Speaker 1:  cloud and streams to you. And every time I've looked at it, I'm like, I'm
Speaker 1:  not letting this startup have my browsing
Speaker 1:  history. And it's like five years now. Am I going to feel the same way? Like
Speaker 1:  I dunno, like everything
Speaker 6:  Else has changed. Other Google have my browsing
Speaker 6:  history.
Speaker 5:  It seems crazy right now. But like genuinely think that's the way we're
Speaker 5:  heading. And there there'll be some I'm sure
Speaker 5:  Google would do some really interesting stuff around it. Particularly, and
Speaker 5:  Microsoft knows where it's heading. Like they know that they're building
Speaker 5:  a similar sort of service themselves, a cloud PC service. So they know
Speaker 1:  Fascinating. But all that is nothing happens in a vacuum.
Speaker 1:  Like Microsoft is here, positioning itself as the
Speaker 1:  champion of openness and developers and creators. Meanwhile, Apple's
Speaker 1:  like putting out white papers about why sideloading would be dangerous on
Speaker 1:  the iPhone. It's like a long, it's like a
Speaker 1:  brochure. I didn't even know how to describe this document. It has like flat
Speaker 1:  illustrations. It looks like one of those videos from when you sign up for
Speaker 1:  a bank or whatever, it's like, you like hit play. And it's like a bunch of
Speaker 1:  flat graphics of like cartoon people like saving one
Speaker 1:  penny a day. Like it's got that startup graphic
Speaker 1:  design, but then it's like, pirates will steal your phone
Speaker 1:  if sideloading is loud. It's like, this is so in Congress,
Speaker 5:  If you don't know how to describe it, Tim Sweeney has a bunch of disparity,
Speaker 5:  descriptive tweets about it
Speaker 4:  And certainly regress. Sorry. Did you see what 10 sweetie just tweeted about
Speaker 4:  the app stuff today. He said, and I quote the 20, 21
Speaker 4:  version of Microsoft is the best version of Microsoft ever
Speaker 4:  exclamation point. Yeah. Didn't
Speaker 1:  He retweeted you saying
Speaker 1:  noodles.
Speaker 1:  So he's happy with Microsoft. It's a big epic partner, right? They like
Speaker 1:  run on the Xbox at the trial with apple. He was saying
Speaker 1:  like, we get value from this relationship. We're happy with this cut. We
Speaker 1:  understand it. We're able to negotiate around it, blah, blah, blah.
Speaker 1:  And then obviously if they do the epic store with the Microsoft
Speaker 1:  store, there's a lot of opportunity for him there. And Srini
Speaker 5:  Was on stage when he first sort of started talking about this open store
Speaker 5:  model, which was with HoloLens to a few years ago now. So
Speaker 5:  like it's been building to this point, for sure. I don't
Speaker 5:  doubt that he's happy after the WP era. And he was
Speaker 5:  not very happy about UWP. So,
Speaker 1:  But it was him seeing his quote about the apple graphic
Speaker 1:  was the epic games store. Doesn't have a shopping cart. It ought to have
Speaker 1:  a shopping cart someday. It will. But in the meantime we don't put out graphical
Speaker 1:  pamphlets, decrying the ills of shopping carts it's
Speaker 1:  absurd. And then he was like, there's a clear difference between
Speaker 1:  our 1984 Fortnite campaign and Apple's open platforms or the devil
Speaker 1:  PDF. One is a work of fiction. And the other is a
Speaker 1:  fortnight. That's funny. Good.
Speaker 1:  This is like a huge, huge reversal in this industry, right?
Speaker 1:  Apple's like Congress right now is marking up antitrust
Speaker 1:  bills. McKenna has been watching this endless markup, the
Speaker 1:  exited committee to go into the floor, largely intact,
Speaker 1:  largely intact. There's some minor changes, but congratulations to
Speaker 1:  McKenna for washing all this. They went into like three or four in the
Speaker 1:  morning and then started again today. She a hero over a reporter for
Speaker 1:  watching all this. But as theater said, all five out of committee
Speaker 1:  under the hustler, largely intact focused at apple and Amazon
Speaker 1:  and Google and Facebook in Dallas said, if you know these bills pass, Microsoft
Speaker 1:  will certainly feel the effects. But it's crazy that like
Speaker 1:  apple is a target of all of this congressional ire in
Speaker 1:  controversy for being a bullying, monopolist and
Speaker 1:  Microsoft like anything. What
Speaker 1:  goes, if you told me it's 20 years, I
Speaker 1:  just would not have believed you. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It's everything's flipped upside down. And it's this world
Speaker 5:  Google is
Speaker 1:  Considering letting like media apps like video music or book
Speaker 1:  apps get around the 30%. Like, yeah, it is amazing.
Speaker 1:  What, a little bit of controversy and a little bit of regular, like even
Speaker 1:  the threat of regulations. Oh, we should maybe stop it so much.
Speaker 1:  So let's finish on with, love it. And we got a lightning round of gadgets.
Speaker 1:  Do Tom, what are the minimum system requirements? And when does windows 11
Speaker 1:  hit
Speaker 5:  The minimum system requirements are four gig of Ram 64 gig
Speaker 5:  of storage and a 64 bit processor. So
Speaker 5:  nothing too crazy there that the actual, like, I wouldn't say crazy, but
Speaker 5:  like the surprising element of it is that you need a TPM 2.0
Speaker 5:  chip, and that has caused some controversy, but we kind of
Speaker 5:  talked about that earlier is it shouldn't be too much of a thing. You just
Speaker 5:  have to make sure that it's actually enabled in your bios. So
Speaker 4:  There is one more system requirement to talk about, which is, if you have
Speaker 4:  windows 11 home edition, you also need a internet connection.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Just for the setup. Yeah. She's
Speaker 4:  still, yeah. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Because that is obviously there to force you to use a Microsoft
Speaker 5:  account, which is like, no, Cartano when you set it up
Speaker 5:  anymore.
Speaker 6:  Thank God. There's some wifi
Speaker 6:  here.
Speaker 5:  Know that is an unfortunate part of windows 11 and also the
Speaker 5:  widget stuff. Where in that leaked build, it forces you into
Speaker 5:  edge. We still don't know. Cause obviously the build isn't out yet. But
Speaker 5:  if they've, if they're going down that route as well, like those are two
Speaker 5:  unfortunate things.
Speaker 1:  Well, this is why you have five antitrust spills, right? I mean,
Speaker 1:  this is a source of a word, like a big knock on those bills is
Speaker 1:  what we're talking about in the next time we put a big knock on this bills
Speaker 1:  is it's not clear what they're going to cause.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. So we just started out. But that's presumably that sort of self-referencing
Speaker 1:  would go away.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. But like Ben, if this whole thing is a head fake and it's like, we're
Speaker 4:  totally open except you have to use Microsoft teams and have a Microsoft
Speaker 4:  account and basically use edge all the time. But we're totally open, I think
Speaker 4:  would be sad.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Like I hope, I hope that's not how it is, but we'll be
Speaker 5:  digging into it early next week to uncover
Speaker 5:  these ghastly parts. Is that when it comes out, the preview
Speaker 5:  bill comes out early next week. So the actual release of windows 11, they
Speaker 5:  haven't said, they've said it's like holiday time, but October
Speaker 5:  like some, some point in October, probably early.
Speaker 1:  Well they've got to do it before holiday laptop
Speaker 5:  Shopping, right? Yeah. So October is almost guaranteed.
Speaker 1:  All right, we're gonna take a break. And then there's a bunch of lightning
Speaker 1:  round stuff we got to get through and to come back, we'll be right
Speaker 1:  back.
Speaker ?:  We think a lot about the two technology we use, but what about the technology
Speaker ?:  we were with our classic full zip hoodie, American giant obsessed over
Speaker ?:  every detail, both functional and aesthetic. So you'll be obsessed with it
Speaker ?:  too. They even brought in a former apple, industrial designer to help perfect.
Speaker ?:  The design American giant hoodies are built with custom developed heavyweight
Speaker ?:  cotton fleece locally grown in sown in North Carolina and are made to
Speaker ?:  last with a durable, double lined hood and reinforced elbow patches. Plus
Speaker ?:  they added side panels for increased mobility and a slim body skimming fit.
Speaker ?:  Most importantly, it's comfortable. American giant is committed to reviving
Speaker ?:  local manufacturing and they believe that all it takes is one quality piece
Speaker ?:  to set a new standard for your closet. If your capsule wardrobe has room
Speaker ?:  for only one hoodie, make it one. You will love for a long time to come
Speaker ?:  get your classic full zip hoodie at American dash giant today and use promo
Speaker ?:  code verge for 15% off your first order. That's 15%
Speaker ?:  off when you use code
Speaker ?:  verge@american-giant.com. Some things just go
Speaker ?:  together like startups and venture capital or self-driving cars and
Speaker ?:  self-aggrandizing founders. Those pairs make for certain kinds of harmony.
Speaker ?:  So if you're the hiring expert for your company, who is your partner who
Speaker ?:  works with you in perfect harmony, if you're not sure it's time to try indeed
Speaker ?:  with indeed. It's not just about working with you. It's about working for
Speaker ?:  you to make your life easier, as easy as post your job screen candidates.
Speaker ?:  And you're off interviewing. You'll get a shortlist of high caliber candidates
Speaker ?:  without the hassle of sifting through resume upon resume. Indeed matches
Speaker ?:  your job description with the appropriate job seekers. It makes it easy to
Speaker ?:  schedule and complete video interviews through the indeed dashboard. Plus
Speaker ?:  you'll only pay for the applicants who meet your must have qualifications
Speaker ?:  funding. A new employee used to be a slow process that was before indeed
Speaker ?:  with indeed instant match. You can find a quality candidates who check all
Speaker ?:  of your boxes immediately and indeed skills tests, which posts more than
Speaker ?:  130 skills tests can reduce hiring time by
Speaker ?:  27%. That's huge. So the jelly to your peanut butter it's
Speaker ?:  indeed get started right now with the free $75 sponsored job credit to upgrade
Speaker ?:  your posting. It indeed.com/vergecast. That's a $75
Speaker ?:  credit at indeed.com/vergecast offer valid through June
Speaker ?:  30th terms and conditions apply.
Speaker 1:  All right, we're back. I was just talking about the anti-trust bills.
Speaker 1:  We don't know what they're going to do. I go read McKenna's report. She did
Speaker 1:  sit through it. Congratulations to her. They did pass
Speaker 1:  largely the same as they were before. So no cell
Speaker 1:  preferencing, no conflicts of interest. The FTC gets more money for
Speaker 1:  investigations, data portability, all that stuff that we've talked
Speaker 1:  about with McKenna before it's got to get through the house. Some big
Speaker 1:  rifts in both the Democrats and
Speaker 1:  Republicans, notably all of the, all of the
Speaker 1:  representatives from California, where all the big tech
Speaker 1:  companies are like United across party lines to be like, screw
Speaker 1:  this. It's very funny. We'll see.
Speaker 1:  I think what the idea that I would put in everybody's head is a
Speaker 1:  good, meaningful criticism of these pills. We don't know what's going to
Speaker 1:  happen. Right? You pass them. You'll change the dynamics of the marketplace.
Speaker 1:  So prohibit all this stuff, you might end up breaking up a big bunch of the
Speaker 1:  big tech companies are forcing Amazon to sell AWS or
Speaker 1:  whatever. We don't know. I think that's a fair
Speaker 1:  of the bills on the flip side. What I would, I would put it in your head
Speaker 1:  is it would be weird if we did know. Right? So if the bills
Speaker 1:  were like, Amazon must sell AWS, I'd be a little
Speaker 1:  antsy, right? Like we know what this market looks like.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. It kind of looks like I've got some money. And if I bought
Speaker 1:  one Google home, now I have to spend all the rest of my money on Google services
Speaker 1:  until I'm dead. Right? Like I've got some money. I bought one apple
Speaker 1:  device. No other smart watches shall ever exist in my, in my
Speaker 1:  life because apple refuses to let anything else work with. It's
Speaker 1:  like, we know what this market looks like. I think a lot of people are happy
Speaker 1:  with it. We don't know what it looks like. If these companies have to be
Speaker 1:  more interoperable or if they can't self preference. So
Speaker 1:  ruthlessly, I'm kind of like, we'll just flip the table and find out like
Speaker 1:  they're smart, right? These are the richest companies in the world led
Speaker 1:  by people who definitely think they're the smartest people in the world.
Speaker 1:  I'm confident. They'll find ways to make money and make cool stuff. And if
Speaker 1:  you're like flip the table, it's, they're not going to quit. Whereas
Speaker 1:  I think if the government was like, we're definitely making it so that when
Speaker 1:  you swipe left on an iPhone, it runs Chrome. I'd be like, I
Speaker 1:  don't want you to design my phone. So that's like,
Speaker 6:  I would just, I don't
Speaker 1:  Know which one's right. I don't like, I think that's a totally fair credit.
Speaker 1:  I'd
Speaker 5:  Argue that we do know though, because we know, we know that competition is
Speaker 5:  best for consumers. Right.
Speaker 1:  But you have to imagine the outcome, right? There's like this big leap that
Speaker 1:  you have
Speaker 5:  To. Yeah. But if it means splitting up like ads from
Speaker 5:  Amazon, you know, windows from Microsoft, whatever. Like if it
Speaker 5:  means all that sort of stuff, then ultimately it's just going to make them
Speaker 5:  compete with each other even stronger than before. Right. Which
Speaker 5:  should mean better products.
Speaker 1:  This is the idea. This is if you've been listening to the Vergecast for however
Speaker 1:  long, like, yes. I fully believe we fully believe that
Speaker 1:  if you've got some dollars in your pocket, like you're best served. If a
Speaker 1:  lot of companies are trying to fight for those dollars, I'll give you the
Speaker 1:  opposite example of this broadband in America. We have railing with the lack
Speaker 1:  of competition in broadband America, for years optimum just
Speaker 1:  lowered its speeds to better align
Speaker 1:  with the market. So they looked around and said, man, where our
Speaker 1:  services faster on uploads than everybody else, we're just going to
Speaker 1:  lower.
Speaker 6:  Well, because no one can leave.
Speaker 1:  Like what are you gonna do? Are you gonna move to Dieter's crappy
Speaker 1:  Comcast?
Speaker 6:  Like it's the opposite of competition because Andrew
Speaker 4:  Is an excellent editor. What you don't know listening to this is I have cut
Speaker 4:  out of this podcast recording like three times because Comcast is just like,
Speaker 4:  nah,
Speaker 1:  Not today. If you've heard me vamping it's because Dieter has just disappeared
Speaker 1:  for seconds at a time. But
Speaker 1:  like Comcast NBC universal as an investor and rice being
Speaker 1:  their parent company, et cetera. Sorry, all I'm saying is part of what you're
Speaker 1:  going to hear from big tech companies over the next few months as these
Speaker 1:  bills make their way forward is we don't know what they do. We don't know
Speaker 1:  how they work. They're going to make the products worse. They're going to
Speaker 1:  force you to not have LinkedIn integrated Microsoft word, which is my favorite
Speaker 1:  example I keep using. And it's like, I don't care.
Speaker 1:  Like I can't shake the feeling that I know what this is.
Speaker 1:  Like, it's
Speaker 5:  Like working out, you know, like open stuff
Speaker 5:  up, like I'm sure there's, there's obviously gonna be security, concerns,
Speaker 5:  platforms, and all that. Like, you know, the 16 page PDF that apple puts
Speaker 5:  out all that sort of stuff. But like, like you say, they're smart, you know
Speaker 5:  that they can compete. They can figure these difficult things
Speaker 5:  out. And I feel like it's definitely for
Speaker 5:  the consumer benefit for there to be more competition.
Speaker 4:  And if they can't figure it out, they'll die and somebody else will figure
Speaker 4:  it out. And that will also
Speaker 6:  Be fine. Yeah. There's just,
Speaker 1:  I dunno, I, we haven't talked about it a lot, but the like the tech companies
Speaker 1:  are lobbying super hard. Tim cook called Nancy Pelosi. Right? The New York
Speaker 1:  times reported he was calling everybody in Congress that he knew to our UNC
Speaker 1:  spills. The money they're spending lobbying is out of control. They've they've
Speaker 1:  spun up new lobbying groups. X school executives are in charge of these
Speaker 1:  lobbying groups. It's like, yeah, it's politics. It's kind of
Speaker 1:  gross. Lobbying is just part of it. I just haven't heard a good argument
Speaker 1:  yet, besides we don't know what these bills would do. And like the,
Speaker 1:  the leap is, well, that's the idea, right? That you would
Speaker 1:  reset the market and everything would be more competitive. And
Speaker 1:  if I wanted to buy a pebble that could send messages
Speaker 1:  from my iPhone, I might be able to fry instead of that
Speaker 1:  company just dying because it didn't have access to the operating
Speaker 1:  system. And yes, there are security concerns and yes, I don't know
Speaker 1:  pirates are going to do piracy, but like, those were the
Speaker 1:  arguments I heard from the music industry when they wanted to have DRM.
Speaker 1:  Right. And like, it was bad and we, they didn't do it. And they figured out
Speaker 1:  a new way to run their, their entire industry. And
Speaker 4:  Now most of the music that people listen to is streamed and proprietary
Speaker 4:  format.
Speaker 1:  It's true. They did figure that out. I just feel
Speaker 5:  Like if we get to a point where like companies like pebble
Speaker 5:  exists and like I'm not buying all my stuff from
Speaker 5:  apple, Google, Microsoft, Amazon, these big tech companies, or
Speaker 5:  I'm not seeing these crazy startups think of something really inventive.
Speaker 5:  And then for it to be crushed because apple does the same thing a
Speaker 5:  year or two later, if we get to a point where that stops happening in
Speaker 5:  such frequency or like apple and all these big tech companies keep
Speaker 5:  acquiring all these startups because they can. And because there's no
Speaker 5:  scrutiny for these small startups, then that's way better for
Speaker 5:  consumers
Speaker 1:  Did her and I were talking about this. You can read this in one or two ways,
Speaker 1:  but there's big piece. And there were times about Google and like, maybe
Speaker 1:  it's moving in slow motion and it's not so innovative anymore. Yeah. And
Speaker 1:  like, I don't know. I, I feel that way. Other people
Speaker 1:  don't feel as, quite as strongly about that as I do. But there was this
Speaker 1:  paragraph in that story that was like a lot of Google's
Speaker 1:  products are developed in an enter something called pantry mode where they
Speaker 1:  just wait until some other startup releases them.
Speaker 1:  And then they just like fire out those products as a clone. Yeah. And it's
Speaker 1:  like, incredible. That's horrible.
Speaker 1:  Like, why wouldn't you just do it first if you already invented it. And it's
Speaker 1:  because fuel's printing money and its ad business,
Speaker 1:  it doesn't even have to take any risks. And if somebody else proves that
Speaker 1:  this is a good idea, they can just release a product,
Speaker 1:  put Google, meet everywhere and something Google meet. We have to pretend
Speaker 1:  it's like a good real competitor. And it's like,
Speaker 1:  my computer is dying. Please. Someone help me because I
Speaker 1:  tried to go to a Google meet meeting it's nuts. And that sort
Speaker 1:  of dynamic, I don't know. I would just like to see that change. The flip
Speaker 1:  side of this is chest pressure
Speaker 1:  prevents them from doing good things too. Right? So like
Speaker 1:  Google wants to turn off third party cookies and Chrome. I think Dieter,
Speaker 1:  you understand this better than anybody. If they want to turn it off with
Speaker 1:  a can't
Speaker 4:  Right. So here's the thing. Google makes the world's most popular desktop
Speaker 4:  browser. They also completely dominate the online ad
Speaker 4:  industry. And if they make a change to the
Speaker 4:  world's most popular desktop browser, it could in theory, give them
Speaker 4:  more power in the ad industry because it would cut off a bunch
Speaker 4:  of other advertisers from tracking you. And
Speaker 4:  so they want to cut off third party cookies. They've come up with this technology
Speaker 4:  called flock. That's supposed to like put you in a demographic group. Everybody
Speaker 4:  hates it. Nobody trusts them. And so they're like, yeah, no, we can't do
Speaker 4:  it. We just got to wait. We're going to like, like the EU, the UK
Speaker 4:  regulator. They're like working with them to like come up with a way to do
Speaker 4:  it. They're going to spend more time trying to come up with new technologies
Speaker 4:  to replace a third-party cookie. And they're just like stuck. They're stuck
Speaker 4:  because if they just made the browser, they can be like, yeah, we're going
Speaker 4:  to compete in the world of browsers. We're going to make a browser that like
Speaker 4:  protects your privacy. It does all this stuff. It'll be great, but they can't
Speaker 4:  do that because if they did that, it would affect their other business and
Speaker 4:  would also affect their relationship with a bunch of regulators. And
Speaker 4:  so they just kind of had to like push. And
Speaker 4:  so I, you know, no one should feel bad for Google,
Speaker 4:  but like the reason they're not doing it is because there's
Speaker 4:  like all of these other forces being applied to their
Speaker 4:  browser and it aligns, it messes with our business model. Whereas
Speaker 4:  apple messing with their browser, doesn't mess with their business model
Speaker 4:  at all. So they're like, yeah, we block everything. You can't find the URL
Speaker 4:  anymore. The tabs are over here and over there and who knows anymore. And
Speaker 4:  it's fine. And it's great. But Google doesn't have the freedom to do that.
Speaker 4:  Like when this news hit that they were delaying the goo, the cookie
Speaker 4:  apocalypse and they were, you know, not implementing Flocka, blah, blah,
Speaker 4:  blah, blah. Every ad tech company on the planet had their
Speaker 4:  stock just leap into the sky. Yeah. Because they
Speaker 4:  all, they all got to reprieve. They get more time to like try out more crap
Speaker 4:  and figure stuff out and continue to track you for another two years.
Speaker 1:  So what's really interesting about flock besides its horrible
Speaker 1:  name
Speaker 6:  Is like in the abstract,
Speaker 1:  This is also apples and sort of tracking right that
Speaker 1:  on your device, it will figure out some set of cohort you're
Speaker 1:  in, you're this old you're in this place, you have these
Speaker 1:  interests, whatever. Yeah. And then advertisers can target
Speaker 1:  that and your device will do it, but they will know who you are.
Speaker 1:  Right. Zoomed way out. That is exactly what Google is trying to do.
Speaker 1:  But because they're the dominant ad tech provider or the dominant advertiser
Speaker 1:  on the web, they run Chrome. No one wants to go down
Speaker 1:  that road with him. Whereas apple,
Speaker 4:  Well, no one trusts them. No, one's like, oh, Google is doing it. It must
Speaker 4:  be bad. So like WordPress and Amazon and every other browser and the planet,
Speaker 4:  we're like, Nope, screw this Mozilla actually did just put out a white paper
Speaker 4:  saying, yeah, here are all the problems flock in such a way where it's like,
Speaker 4:  they could maybe be convinced that they could maybe find a, not, not
Speaker 4:  problem with Fox someday, but we're so far from that. So the other part of
Speaker 4:  Google's announcement is they'd like really talked about like, there's a
Speaker 4:  process for web standards. You see, and this is how it works. And it's like,
Speaker 4:  yeah, we know. So, but they're like laying the groundwork for being like,
Speaker 4:  well, flock was a good experiment. The web standards process had it say,
Speaker 4:  and now we're doing this other thing, you know, we've evolved it and they'll
Speaker 4:  like, drop it or something. We
Speaker 1:  Talked about the web a lot. Like this is a huge deal. Yeah. And
Speaker 1:  Google cannot figure it out. And part of the reason they can't figure it
Speaker 1:  out is because of antitrust concerns because they are so
Speaker 1:  dominant. So everyone would like them to stop tracking. And
Speaker 1:  apple is going to run ad after ad, after ad hammering, Google for
Speaker 1:  tracking. But then like the UK competition authority is
Speaker 1:  like knives, keep tracking or enable enabling cookies, which
Speaker 1:  allow other people to track that. So, yeah. I don't know. Just like my, my
Speaker 1:  other proposed antitrust rule is like, maybe we just don't let at and T
Speaker 1:  buy anything and that'll solve like a whole swath of problems in the tech
Speaker 1:  industry. Like maybe the other one is like, just like block
Speaker 1:  cookies, like anti-trust except for ad tech
Speaker 1:  industry. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Let's do it. See what happens. That'd be fine. Let's
Speaker 1:  Go. We got the lightning round. Do you want to go through a theater?
Speaker 4:  We have got mobile world Congress coming up. Surprise, surprise. It's like
Speaker 4:  sort of, kind of happening. Samsung is having an event we're
Speaker 4:  expecting. They might do something with the watch. Maybe it'll be the first
Speaker 4:  new version aware O S watch maybe.
Speaker 4:  And the Z fold three and the Z flip three, just leaked today.
Speaker 4:  As a recording, this, it looks like the CFL three will be compatible to
Speaker 4:  stylists. It looks like the Z flip three has a screen that isn't the
Speaker 4:  size of your pinky fingernail, which is great. I have no idea if these will
Speaker 4:  be announced at MWC or not. And then the other big phone
Speaker 4:  rumor is apple is thinking about making a less expensive,
Speaker 4:  big phone next year, which is like welcome to 2018.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Sheep, big phones who knew. Yeah. Everybody,
Speaker 6:  Literally everybody
Speaker 1:  Actually Mitchell wrote this story for us and he's he has this
Speaker 1:  great segment in the middle of the story. That's like during the trial, a
Speaker 1:  bunch of stuff that leaked from apple was, oh yeah, they do do a bunch of
Speaker 1:  market research and they do commission analysts, firms go out
Speaker 1:  and like, there's a CCU graphs at apple commission. That's like, yep.
Speaker 1:  People like big phones and they like cheap
Speaker 1:  ones.
Speaker 1:  Yep. Pretty much. I'm glad you paid a company to tell you to
Speaker 1:  say, okay, I'm just going to
Speaker 1:  end on this. Okay. You ready for this? Here we go. T-Mobile is
Speaker 1:  selling a 5g branded gin.
Speaker 4:  Look, we already called dibs
Speaker 4:  on mobile wireless related alcohol. It's called
Speaker 4:  scissor vodka. It's true. It has a tagline. Cut. Snip, snip cut through the
Speaker 4:  night. It's just cut through the night. Let's just cut to the night. But
Speaker 4:  then you say snip, snip. They go together. Maybe even a snipping
Speaker 4:  noise. They totally just stole this idea from us.
Speaker 5:  I love how it's called a five gin. No,
Speaker 1:  And there's five ginger beer. It's good. It's hot. I will say
Speaker 1:  this a long time ago. This is a true story. A long time ago,
Speaker 1:  we were back in a gadget. We ran and gadget mobile and gadgets color was
Speaker 1:  blue and gadget mobile's color was pink and T-Mobile sends a
Speaker 1:  cease and desist to AOL saying it. And gadget
Speaker 1:  mobile had to stop using the color pink because T-Mobile was
Speaker 1:  spanked. We said, no, actually ran a
Speaker 1:  story. That was great. Well, it's my turn. All right. Mobile vodkas are
Speaker 1:  my thing. T-Mobile well, it's a gin. So
Speaker 1:  technically fine. Every summer, every
Speaker 1:  summer, the world tries to get me to drink gin. You notice this and every
Speaker 1:  summer I drink it and I'm sorry. I know you're British. And it's like in
Speaker 1:  your blood or whatever,
Speaker 6:  But it's horrible. No, that's great. What are you talking
Speaker 1:  About? Horrible. It's like drinking a tree.
Speaker 4:  The thing I'm unhappy about is last week we saw dish
Speaker 4:  try and launch a project Genesis for the S was a
Speaker 4:  five. And now we have five
Speaker 4:  gin stop taking the 5g things and incorporating
Speaker 4:  it into other words. Yeah. Don't want
Speaker 1:  It. This is what I mean about the pandemic. Like all the way down the line,
Speaker 1:  the branding consultants, just like when they were home, they didn't
Speaker 1:  get parties to go to. They have time to burn. They were just like, here's
Speaker 1:  some ideas. The,
Speaker 5:  The five ginger beer was just one step too far. Five, five gin.
Speaker 5:  Okay. Huh? Five
Speaker 6:  Ginger beer. Just look at it. It just looks
Speaker 6:   all right.
Speaker 1:  That's a good place to end it. I want to call ransomware is a big thing that's
Speaker 1:  happening. So I just want to call it Lizel Pato wrote a gigantic
Speaker 1:  story. Lots of reporting in it about what could be done about
Speaker 1:  ransomware, going through all the options. Spoiler alert. All the options
Speaker 1:  are bad. So, but check it out. It's it's, it's very smart.
Speaker 1:  And Liz is just such a funny writer. So check out that story. Lots of other
Speaker 1:  stories and we're checking out, but I want to call that. Cause I think bridge
Speaker 1:  has listeners particularly interested in that Dakota this week
Speaker 1:  was Jack haunty the CEO of Patrion. Like I said, Sasha Nadella. That episode
Speaker 1:  bonus episode decoder up now in parallel to the virtuosic. I listened to
Speaker 1:  that next week on decoder we've we've talked about the
Speaker 1:  Juul a lot, the vape on the show, Stephen and I
Speaker 1:  both have a problem. That'd be more. We're good now. We're
Speaker 1:  we're yes, definitely have a healthy relationship with nicotine. That's
Speaker 1:  the species. You've got five chin. Yeah, it's a I've I
Speaker 1:  drank now instead of vaping. It's great. It's very helpful. Transition. Lauren
Speaker 1:  Eder. Who's a reporter at Bloomberg news. Just wrote a gigantic
Speaker 1:  book about the history of Juul, where it came from, where it went, what
Speaker 1:  happened? It's called the devil's playbook. She's on decoder next week. That
Speaker 1:  episode is great. And that book is great. Actually highly recommended it's
Speaker 1:  it's like a lot of Silicon valley meets a legacy industry that was regulated
Speaker 1:  and couldn't and like all the themes we just talked about with big companies
Speaker 1:  like microcosm, right? They're only, there's also a lot of like
Speaker 1:  parties and smoking. That's very interesting. So that's next
Speaker 1:  week on decoder the Della and Jack concierge. Now you can tweet at
Speaker 1:  us. Dieter's at backlog. Tom is at Tamora and I'm at reckless. We love
Speaker 1:  hearing from you and we'll be back next week. More virtuous. That's it. Rock
Speaker 1:  and roll. Snip.
Speaker 1:  .