# Transcript
ID: eee93240-442d-11ec-98f1-9f6f668d236d
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: EV startup Rivian goes public / Judge orders Apple to allow external payment options / Microsoft announces Windows 11 SE
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/1336462472/2340223855/s93290-US-5019s-1636771758.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, Dieter Bohn, Alex Cranz, and Sean O'Kane discuss electric vehicle startup Rivian becoming a publicly traded company after executing one of the biggest initial public offerings in history.
The crew also cover multiple stories about Apple from this week, Microsoft's Windows 11 SE release, and a new Surface Laptop for schools.
Speaker 1:  This week on the verge cast, Alex Cranz and Shauna O'Kane joined the show.
Speaker 1:  We talk about revealing the new electric car company that just had one of
Speaker 1:  the hottest IPO's ever, but you get into buttons and links. Of course. And
Speaker 1:  we talked about some Microsoft news. It's coming up on the chest. Now,
Speaker 2:  This episode is brought to you by Klaviyo the SMS and email marketing
Speaker 2:  platform that empowers businesses from startups to legacy brands, to
Speaker 2:  own their data and own their growth. Klayvio makes it simple to
Speaker 2:  send personalized campaigns from customer first data, the great
Speaker 2:  data you get directly from customers all with their permission. You don't
Speaker 2:  have to outsource your marketing efforts to a distant third party who will
Speaker 2:  immediately dilute your customer relationships. Klaviyo puts you
Speaker 2:  and your business back in control. You own the data. It's time for you to
Speaker 2:  own the growth. To learn more at
Speaker 2:  klaviyo.com/holidays. That's K L a
Speaker 2:  V I Y o.com/holidays.
Speaker 2:  Today
Speaker 3:  This episode is brought to you by Klaviyo the SMS and email marketing
Speaker 3:  platform that empowers businesses from startups to legacy brands,
Speaker 3:  to own their data and own their growth. Klayvio
Speaker 3:  makes it simple to send personalized campaigns built from customer
Speaker 3:  first data. The great data you get directly from customers
Speaker 3:  all with their permission. You don't have to outsource your
Speaker 3:  marketing efforts to a distant third party who will immediately dilute
Speaker 3:  your customer relationships. Klaviyo puts you and your
Speaker 3:  business back in control. You own the data. It's time for
Speaker 3:  you to own the growth. To learn more at
Speaker 3:  klaviyo.com/holidays. That's K L a V
Speaker 3:  I Y o.com/holidays today.
Speaker 1:  Hello, welcome to Vergecast the flagship podcast, Zune
Speaker 1:  enthusiasts. There's one of you out there. We saw the photo,
Speaker 1:  explain the joke. There's 35 more. If I got five, we
Speaker 1:  have the numbers, right? Which we don't because podcast statistics are bad.
Speaker 2:  But according to those statistics, 36 of you are listening to this show on
Speaker 2:  a Zune.
Speaker 1:  We're very proud of you. And one of you sent us a photo. The rest of you
Speaker 1:  sent us a photo. We're very into it. Anyway, I'm Neil. I'm your friend Dieter
Speaker 1:  bonus. Here I am.
Speaker 2:  Actually I am the host of a run of special Tuesday.
Speaker 2:  Vergecast set. I hope you're listening to, we just did over an hour on
Speaker 2:  USB-C and next week we've got a
Speaker 2:  really cool subject to talk about.
Speaker 1:  Oh, Teeter absolute hype. I'm so hyped. Now I was going
Speaker 1:  to say that, you know, we've, we've often used the second episode of the
Speaker 1:  virtuous to pilot formats, right? Where they piloted an interview show that
Speaker 1:  became decoder. Ashley did a mini series about AI. Dieter
Speaker 1:  was doing holiday spectaculars. Yeah that's USB-C but now
Speaker 1:  instead of teasing another one, you're like a cool subject. I know it's a
Speaker 2:  Really cool subject.
Speaker 1:  Is it refrigerators?
Speaker 2:  Freezers are our listeners understand what I'm getting at? Even if you,
Speaker 1:  I believe you, Alex Kranz is here. I'm still trying to figure out what an
Speaker 1:  NFT is,
Speaker 1:  who had sent. And Sean okayness here.
Speaker 4:  I am telling Alex Cranz to go to our website to read our very good NFT
Speaker 4:  explainer.
Speaker 1:  I'm the only one who hasn't read it. And the whole
Speaker 4:  World. That's definitely true. You and the Zune owners.
Speaker 1:  So desperately trying to, I will tell you this, the
Speaker 1:  incoming traffic to our NFT explainer, it is
Speaker 1:  now like maybe the, the sixth or fifth, most popular article in verge
Speaker 1:  history. Because so many people are confused about what NFTs
Speaker 1:  are. They just are landing on that page every day,
Speaker 1:  every day. It's like every day, it's one of our top stories and we keep updating
Speaker 1:  it because it keeps changing, but it's, it's very entertaining and it's probably
Speaker 1:  a signal that we need to do more coverage there. We just all have to stop
Speaker 1:  laughing every time. Like it's, it's hard. We're going to get
Speaker 1:  there. We're going to do it. I believe in it. We've actually got an NFT decoder
Speaker 1:  episode coming up that I think it's a cool subject.
Speaker 1:  It's not the same. The joke is it's a really
Speaker 1:  cool subject.
Speaker 1:  Oh my God.
Speaker 1:  We're off to a rollicking. Start a lot to talk about. There's some news from
Speaker 1:  apple and epic that we need to get to. There's a bunch of Microsoft stuff
Speaker 1:  going on, but Sean is here because there's a new card
Speaker 1:  company, like a big deal car company. It's about, it's having a moment
Speaker 1:  and it's a good time to just like, talk about what's going on in the cars.
Speaker 1:  The Evie revolution is like in full, early swing. I would
Speaker 1:  say you might notice car company, keep car company CEOs, keep coming on
Speaker 1:  decoder to convince me that they're going to be good at batteries. It's true.
Speaker 1:  But Riviera just had its IPO reveal. And if you haven't been keeping track
Speaker 1:  as a new electric car company, they make what's. The RNT is the
Speaker 1:  pickup truck. The R one S is the SUV. They are now worth more than
Speaker 1:  Ford and GM. After this IPO, they have not shipped one car.
Speaker 1:  Sean, what is going on with Vivian?
Speaker 4:  They've started shipping the first few pickup trucks
Speaker 4:  where those exactly went, you know, did they go to employees that
Speaker 4:  they have a couple out there, but yes, in appreciable quantities, they haven't
Speaker 4:  started shipping. Riviera is, you know, in many ways it's a new
Speaker 4:  company, but it also really isn't. It was founded in 2009, the
Speaker 4:  founders. And, you know, it's like this super brainy guy
Speaker 4:  who, you know, you think back to 2009, it was that first sort of big clean
Speaker 4:  tech boom. And he was looking at Tesla and wanted to do something
Speaker 4:  similar. And they actually originally set out to make an electric
Speaker 4:  sports car that was kind of similar in some ways to the Tesla Roadster.
Speaker 4:  And, you know, as Tesla proved, that was an extremely hard thing to
Speaker 4:  do, even in Tesla's case where it was basically borrowing the
Speaker 4:  Lotus Elise to build off of. And so this founder, RJ
Speaker 4:  syringe eventually decided a couple of years down the road to pivot
Speaker 4:  to something a little more focused, you know, a brand
Speaker 4:  and electric vehicle brand that was more about adventuring
Speaker 4:  outdoors-y people, affluent people who are interested in those
Speaker 4:  things. And at the very least like to think that they're outdoorsy and,
Speaker 4:  and had, has likened it in the past to
Speaker 4:  wanting to become like the Patagonia of Evie makers and
Speaker 4:  even to the point that they even have a Patagonia executive on their board.
Speaker 1:  I just say like, that's a good, it's like, it's, that's all good. It's also
Speaker 1:  just from a more abstract business sense trucks and
Speaker 1:  SUV's are the biggest market for sure. Right? It's like remarkable that Tesla
Speaker 1:  is a success selling city
Speaker 4:  Biggest market, and also make the most money for automakers
Speaker 4:  in the case of a startup. You know, that's not necessarily going to be true
Speaker 4:  right away, but what that gives you is, you know, the biggest cost is the
Speaker 4:  battery. The higher you go, the more money you charge right out the gate,
Speaker 4:  the more you can absorb that cost of the battery and not just take a total
Speaker 4:  bath on the cost of actually building these vehicles. So, so that's what
Speaker 4:  really helps them there by going down that, that route of SEP in and pickup
Speaker 4:  truck. And, you know, they also, by doing that, they put themselves in this
Speaker 4:  position to essentially get to this point now where they have
Speaker 4:  become, you know, for all intents and purposes, the first company to ship
Speaker 4:  an electric pickup truck. There are a lot of other ones in the works
Speaker 4:  and it will, it will not be as much of a rarity in a couple of years,
Speaker 4:  but they are, you know, they beat Ford, which has the F150 lightning
Speaker 4:  to market. They beat Lordstown motors, which is a, you know, a much
Speaker 4:  smaller kind of struggling startup. That's focused on building
Speaker 4:  pickup trucks for fleets. They beat them to the market. So, so they,
Speaker 4:  they are going to be in this position where they can sort
Speaker 4:  of make themselves become known as the electric pickup truck in the
Speaker 4:  way that, you know, Tesla became the electric car company for a lot of
Speaker 4:  people. And that's, that's sort of why they want to do so. They're able to
Speaker 4:  get to the IPO. You know, there's is interesting, like their, their inflection
Speaker 4:  point was, they debuted at the 2018 LA auto show and everybody saw
Speaker 4:  these vehicles and were really wowed by them. They're a little polarizing,
Speaker 4:  but for the most part, I think people were really interested in how
Speaker 4:  specifically they tailored it to like outdoorsy lifestyle, as you know,
Speaker 4:  all wheel drive, all these sorts of cool little compartments and things
Speaker 4:  where you can stow gear and everything. And, and so that got them a lot of
Speaker 4:  buzz. And then a couple of months later, Amazon led a $700 million investment
Speaker 4:  round into them. And then a couple of months later,
Speaker 4:  Ford followed with a $500 million investment round. And they had, you know,
Speaker 4:  they were courting GM. There was a good wall street journal piece the other
Speaker 4:  day about how close GM actually got to making that investment. And it
Speaker 4:  was like, everybody should read it. It's, it's a really good scene about
Speaker 4:  like RJ syringe flying back with this Ford executive on his jet and like
Speaker 4:  basically Ford stealing Ravion out from underneath GM, which is a
Speaker 4:  really funny, and, and from there they've just taken off. There they're
Speaker 4:  9,000 people around the world. Now they have offices all around the U S
Speaker 4:  they've been building service and delivery centers. And then on top of those
Speaker 4:  two vehicles, they're also going to be building up to a hundred thousand
Speaker 4:  electric delivery vans that they designed with Amazon. So the interesting
Speaker 4:  thing about them is not just the products that they built that look really
Speaker 4:  cool and we can talk about, but they will be a lot
Speaker 4:  of, people's probably a first touch point for electric vehicles because
Speaker 4:  we've all seen these Amazon bans circulating our neighborhoods every
Speaker 4:  day. And, and there's a good chance that that might be the first time
Speaker 4:  you actually notice an electric vehicle near you.
Speaker 2:  The thing that really gets me about Vivian is, I mean, Sean, you've been
Speaker 2:  reporting on like the electric car companies that, I mean, you're reporting
Speaker 2:  in Tesla, but that's companies that aren't Tesla trying to like, make it,
Speaker 2:  you mentioned Lordstown, I'm going to bring up fair day for the
Speaker 2:  past five years. It was like, oh, it's a electric car company. Yeah, sure.
Speaker 2:  We'll we'll believe it when you actually make something and ship it. And
Speaker 2:  I feel like Ravion sort of went from that category to
Speaker 2:  holy crap, they're doing it. They're actually chipping something and they're
Speaker 2:  making something really compelling almost overnight. Like how do they get
Speaker 2:  over that ledge of we are actually real. We actually have capital. We're
Speaker 2:  actually, you know, staffing factories and making trucks. Okay.
Speaker 4:  I think one thing that actually hasn't gotten a lot of attention in, in the
Speaker 4:  run up to this IPO that I think played such an outsized role
Speaker 4:  in their success so far is that, you know, it's easy to sort of scoff at
Speaker 4:  the like Patagonia of electric vehicles kind of vibe, but what they
Speaker 4:  did that was so smart that a lot of pretty much arguably all other
Speaker 4:  electric vehicle startups done is they picked a customer. They said,
Speaker 4:  you know, they think throughout the sports car idea, they said, let's get
Speaker 4:  as like kind of narrow as possible an idea. And they really like
Speaker 4:  chiseled out a brand that like is more
Speaker 4:  cohesive than anything else. It's very future. Biten all these other
Speaker 4:  companies that have struggled and, or gone out of business are falling
Speaker 4:  by the wayside. They all wanted to be the next Tesla in the sense that they
Speaker 4:  wanted to be a mass market electric vehicle. And that's a really hard thing
Speaker 4:  to do if you're trying to be a product for everybody.
Speaker 4:  And what ribbon did that was so smart was realized halfway
Speaker 4:  through that they wanted to make something specific. And if it didn't work
Speaker 4:  out, you know, the chances are it's not going to work out. So why not take
Speaker 4:  the risk on making something that could appeal to a more
Speaker 4:  niche group of buyers, even though, again, we're talking trucks and
Speaker 4:  SUV's, but they really built a cohesive brand around it. And I think
Speaker 4:  that really helped. And then honestly, the, in the run-up to the IPO
Speaker 4:  recently, one of the things that we learned when they filed their S one with
Speaker 4:  the securities and exchange commission, is that, you know, they got a lot
Speaker 4:  of help. Like not only sort of, you know, obviously they're getting a lot
Speaker 4:  of help from Amazon on building the delivery van and, and figuring out how
Speaker 4:  that's gonna work, but Ford built the body and whites for
Speaker 4:  them, for all their prototypes. So basically everything that sits above like
Speaker 4:  the electric vehicle platform that powers the cars, Ford actually built all
Speaker 4:  of that. So I think they had a lot of work done before they came out of stealth
Speaker 4:  in 2018, which showed at the, at the LA auto show. You know, they
Speaker 4:  didn't show like cardboard cutouts that, that fell over.
Speaker 4:  But, you know, at, at that point they would have probably taken a little
Speaker 4:  bit longer to get to here. If it hadn't been for the sort of,
Speaker 4:  you know, big companies, one automotive, one tech that came in
Speaker 4:  and, and really sort of saw the potential there and partnered with them and
Speaker 4:  started sort of pushing them forward.
Speaker 1:  You and I obviously talk a lot about the car industry. Big companies are
Speaker 1:  trying to do this, right? Like Ram is trying to ship an electric
Speaker 1:  1500 pickup truck. Chevy is announced
Speaker 1:  electric Silverado Ford is presumably with the next few months
Speaker 1:  shipping the lightning they're like saying it, it just took them forever
Speaker 1:  to get on the board. Why do you think it took a startup with obviously with
Speaker 1:  help, but why do you think it's took a startup to get there for
Speaker 4:  There's a, there's definitely at the very least one big technical reason,
Speaker 4:  which is when you're talking about making larger electric vehicles, you
Speaker 4:  start to run into this problem where to get the kind of range that people
Speaker 4:  want in order to consider buying them. You need a certain amount of batteries,
Speaker 4:  the more batteries that you need to get that range to power, what are bigger
Speaker 4:  heavier vehicles, you are making them bigger and
Speaker 4:  heavier, which means you start to get into this sort of like chicken and
Speaker 4:  egg problem. And they actually have some, it's a little wonky,
Speaker 4:  but if you look at how they build their battery pack, that
Speaker 4:  whole part of the equation, it, they made like a really
Speaker 4:  big advancement there in trying to figure out that
Speaker 4:  problem, that, which I think has, I think, you know, isn't
Speaker 4:  going to, and that's not the reason that like
Speaker 4:  GMCs pickup trucks aren't going electric just yet. But
Speaker 4:  it was a reason that people were hesitant to think about going further than
Speaker 4:  a sedan for a while. So I think that's a part of it. And then,
Speaker 4:  you know, it is, you know, we hear this explanation a lot, but I think there's
Speaker 4:  some validity to it, which is like, there's just this idea
Speaker 4:  of a large corporation. Like
Speaker 4:  the automakers are, it's just harder for them to do
Speaker 4:  something new and, and cut ties to certain
Speaker 4:  baggage that they have, like the Mo the Mustang Maki is a really good example.
Speaker 4:  The only reason the Mustang Maki exists and that Ford is like
Speaker 4:  now, actually sort of in the game is that the CEO at
Speaker 4:  the time went to whoever, you know, the team that was working on what was
Speaker 4:  essentially the next focus, electric, like a small electric vehicle
Speaker 4:  that they were going to make and was like, we're going to get killed with
Speaker 4:  this. No, one's going to buy this thing, make something better. And that
Speaker 4:  turned into the Mustang Maki, and not only turned into something more interesting,
Speaker 4:  but on a much quicker timescale, they turned that around in like two
Speaker 4:  years, two and a half years for that debut in November, 2019.
Speaker 4:  So I think those are two of the big reasons why Rivi here now
Speaker 4:  also money money. A lot of us
Speaker 1:  Have a lot of money
Speaker 4:  As Steve raised $10 billion today. And that's not counting the
Speaker 4:  IPO. They've raised more than $10 billion. When you said
Speaker 2:  Picked a customer. And the customer was like people that are Patagonia vests
Speaker 2:  or whatever, isn't the customer that they picked Jeff Bezos.
Speaker 4:  Well, he is definitely the customer because not only is Amazon buying vans,
Speaker 4:  we've seen during blue origins launches
Speaker 4:  and blue origin, branded Ruby and pickup trucks, and SUV's pull up to the
Speaker 4:  launch sites and stuff, and they won't say they won't tell us, we keep
Speaker 4:  bugging them. They won't tell us if they bought those vehicles or not. But
Speaker 1:  I want to talk about the money aspect real quick, but then I actually want
Speaker 1:  to talk about the cars, but the money aspect is interesting that you have
Speaker 1:  covered a lot of EBV companies that have raised a bunch of money
Speaker 1:  in a bunch of strange ways. And they like fair to a future is like
Speaker 1:  the prime example, especially for Sean,
Speaker 5:  Wait, how did Faraday future do it? I vaguely remember this.
Speaker 4:  I'll do this as quickly as possible. I promised ferritin future was founded
Speaker 4:  by the guy who ran the Netflix of China and
Speaker 4:  also Le echo, which was like a mobile phone company and TV company
Speaker 4:  and TV company. And at one point Android bike company, he
Speaker 4:  had, you know, he had those successes in China, but the problem
Speaker 4:  that he had over there was that he would, he would build something up. He
Speaker 4:  would borrow a lot of money against it. And then when that thing started
Speaker 4:  to fall apart, whatever he built up next, he would borrow money
Speaker 4:  against that to pay off basically Ponzi scheme style, moving
Speaker 4:  money around to the point that he got chased out of China. He found it fair
Speaker 4:  to a future with a bunch of that money when things were starting to get
Speaker 4:  really heated for the first time in China. So he put like
Speaker 4:  close to $2 billion of that money into Faraday future. That was how they
Speaker 4:  originally got founded. When they first ran into their biggest cash
Speaker 4:  crunch. A couple of years ago, they actually got bailed out by ever
Speaker 4:  grand, which is the massive Chinese real estate conglomerate that is
Speaker 4:  currently facing a $300 billion debt load of its own and is maybe
Speaker 4:  going to collapse unless the Chinese government saves it. And so they survive
Speaker 4:  for a while off of that, they got in a fight with ever grand a that they
Speaker 4:  settled at the end of 2018. Evergreen kind of walked away with a piece of
Speaker 4:  the company. Fair enough. Theater just sort of stayed in stasis mode
Speaker 4:  until the end of last year or beginning of this year.
Speaker 4:  They announced that they were going to do a spec merger. Oh no, of
Speaker 4:  course. And this year in July, they completed the spec merger and they
Speaker 4:  are now a public publicly traded company with
Speaker 1:  Sells no cars that sells another car.
Speaker 4:  It's
Speaker 5:  Like $8, $5.
Speaker 4:  I don't know. It's not, it's not as high as Vivian's. I can tell you that
Speaker 4:  much.
Speaker 1:  Well, so here's my, like, I just back out of all this, cause we could probably
Speaker 1:  do the whole hour and ferret eight shenanigans. No one wants it. Trust
Speaker 4:  Me. I know.
Speaker 1:  Trust me if you want it. It's all on the website. Sean has broken more
Speaker 1:  news about fair to history than anybody, but right. They raised all the money.
Speaker 1:  They had the resources, they had the big companies behind them. They never
Speaker 1:  shipped a car. And it's a disaster, right? Fair day. Yes.
Speaker 1:  Fair day. Yes. Fair day had the money. They had the tech companies, they
Speaker 1:  had everything. They were just bad. They had all the same puzzle pieces.
Speaker 1:  They just never made a car. Like what in the reveal
Speaker 1:  story made them actually get to this point? Is it they're just better
Speaker 1:  executives,
Speaker 5:  Schemes,
Speaker 1:  Less Ponzi schemes, right? Like, cause there's a lot of electric car
Speaker 1:  company is, are just a hope and a prayer, even though they have tons of
Speaker 1:  money. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Well, I mean, one of the problems here is like tons of money is super relative
Speaker 4:  because when you're talking about the automotive space, like you need
Speaker 4:  this amount of money that ravine has raised to really actually get there.
Speaker 4:  Lucid motors is another good example. They just started shipping their first
Speaker 4:  luxury electric sedan and it took them getting well over
Speaker 4:  a billion dollars from Saudi Arabia to be able to get to the point where
Speaker 4:  they, that amount of money barely just got them to production. But then they
Speaker 4:  also just went public in a SPAC merger that raised four more billion dollars.
Speaker 4:  So the amount of money, even though parody had spent 2 billion,
Speaker 4:  that's still like kind of, not enough, especially at one point they wanted
Speaker 4:  to build their own factory. That's definitely not enough. And if you look
Speaker 4:  at reveal ones filing so far as they become a public company,
Speaker 4:  even they say, they're going to spend another $8 billion in the
Speaker 4:  next two years. So like that's definitely part of this. They were just able
Speaker 4:  to corral the right amount of capital from
Speaker 4:  sources that were, you know, less problematic, I guess you could
Speaker 4:  say. And so, and then, you know, I'm sure
Speaker 4:  there's some sort of leadership part of this as well. You know, they definitely
Speaker 4:  have poached from a lot of companies. They took
Speaker 4:  a bunch of people from McLaren and they took a bunch of people from, I mean,
Speaker 4:  they take everybody kinda hops around at this point with all these different
Speaker 4:  startups. But so I think they probably hired well and it seems like
Speaker 4:  RJ, RJ scourge seems like a very intelligent person, a very
Speaker 4:  focused person. He doesn't seem to have the sort of
Speaker 4:  parts of a personality that we've seen from people like Elon Musk
Speaker 4:  and even Fairday futures, founder that, you know, work
Speaker 4:  against that, that part that you need to be successful.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Essentially, they've got a plant and what normal Illinois is where
Speaker 1:  they're building the cars, they're going to do another
Speaker 5:  One in Texas.
Speaker 4:  Maybe they built a yes, they are. They bought this factory in
Speaker 4:  normal, Illinois on the extreme cheap, that's a former Mitsubishi factory
Speaker 4:  that had been empty for a little while. And it was one that fared a future
Speaker 4:  actually passed over in search of building their own
Speaker 4:  in Nevada instead. And so there's a connection there to,
Speaker 1:  It's just funny. Like all I know a lot of people in Wisconsin, Illinois and
Speaker 1:  ravine is the hot job to get like all a
Speaker 1:  bunch of people I know who just like worked for Harley and like Miller
Speaker 1:  Coors and like various sales. Like they all want to go work
Speaker 1:  for Vivian. And that is like, you can't buy that. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Right. To be the place where all the talent in an area wants to go. I think
Speaker 1:  it's, it's just interesting to see this company. It's been a slow road
Speaker 1:  and they're about to start shipping at scale. And like all the pieces have
Speaker 1:  aligned for them in a way that everything else is wreckage. Basically.
Speaker 5:  It also feels like there's a little bit of like self fulfilling
Speaker 5:  prophecy. And this one too, like, honestly, I didn't know what Vivian was
Speaker 5:  until they announced that they were maybe building a factory in my
Speaker 5:  hometown in Texas. And I was like, oh my God, I have to learn all about this.
Speaker 5:  Now I got to get in on this. But it was really interesting to be like
Speaker 5:  the confidence of everybody. I was reading about talking about this company.
Speaker 5:  Like there wasn't like, even with Tesla, we still get the oil. All right.
Speaker 5:  When they ship the car to you, but with this company, it's like
Speaker 5:  cyber, even just the three, the model three. But with this company is like,
Speaker 5:  no, they're doing it. It's happening. It's coming.
Speaker 1:  If ribbon can ship these cars and they don't have the panel gaps that newer
Speaker 1:  model threes, like
Speaker 5:  Your whole hand in there,
Speaker 1:  Like Tesla ships, a lot of cars and people love them. Right? Like
Speaker 1:  there are Teslas in my family. Like I've got Tesla
Speaker 1:  evangelists who are related to me. You don't have to tell me how great Tesla
Speaker 1:  is. Trust me. I can just, it's at home. It's already in my house.
Speaker 1:  But like the cars are just not, well-made like, there's, there's no getting
Speaker 1:  around it. If Rubian can like surpass that. And they're in the biggest category
Speaker 1:  in the country, lowest bar. Well, but it's still a bar.
Speaker 1:  I mean the Ford ship, the Maki. And they had to recall it like three times
Speaker 1:  in the last time they recall it because like, cause the roof was getting
Speaker 1:  unglued. Like new cars are hard. So let's say they shift the car. Let's talk
Speaker 1:  about the actual car. The RNC is really interesting. Mitchell got to drive
Speaker 1:  one. The inside of it is more Tesla like than not.
Speaker 1:  I would say it's got the big screen and they built a custom software stack.
Speaker 1:  Can we just talk about the headlights first?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I mean it's, it's definitely, if you haven't seen it, you should go
Speaker 4:  look at a photo, pull over your car
Speaker 4:  and, and take a look at a photo of your
Speaker 1:  Gas engine. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I mean a lot of electric vehicles, whereas 10 years ago,
Speaker 4:  all of the hybrids and like early electrics were like,
Speaker 4:  let's make a really funky body type and put blue accents
Speaker 4:  on everything. You know, now a lot of
Speaker 4:  electric vehicle startups are trying to signal that something's different
Speaker 4:  about the car by going with continuous light bars in the front and then in
Speaker 4:  the back and reveal and sort of mixes that up a little bit by using these
Speaker 4:  two, like pill shaped headlights that go perpendicular to
Speaker 4:  the light bar. So it gives it, yeah, it gives it, I don't know what you even
Speaker 4:  call it. It looks like a, a bug it's. It's definitely interesting. Like it
Speaker 4:  takes some getting used to
Speaker 1:  People out there who are trying to call them snake eyes to make it sound
Speaker 1:  tough.
Speaker 4:  No,
Speaker 1:  It just looks very friendly. Like it looks like it wants to give you a hug.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And like, I think that probably works to what they're going for. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. It's the, it's the, it's the blocker for me, but go look at it. And
Speaker 1:  then on the inside, right? One of the things about all these car companies
Speaker 1:  that is utterly fascinating to me is the inside of the car is
Speaker 1:  at this point more important than the outside. And like this software experience
Speaker 1:  of the car is I would say in disarray around the industry
Speaker 1:  in general, but they've had to build their own stack from the ground up and
Speaker 1:  it's all of their own stuff. What does that look like?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I mean, it's, it's still very Tesla style, you know,
Speaker 4:  like you look at the interface, if you, if you go look at Mitchell's piece
Speaker 4:  or there are definitely a lot of good videos on YouTube from the
Speaker 4:  press drives, like the interface is very, it's very similar to what Tesla
Speaker 4:  has done. It's a very like clean looking, maybe almost
Speaker 4:  a little too, sort of over done UI as far as
Speaker 4:  like a, you know, some features may be hidden. It's all touch screen based.
Speaker 4:  And so that's, that's something that they, that and the
Speaker 4:  software that actually manages the car is something that they made a lot
Speaker 4:  of hires around earlier on. And I think that's probably
Speaker 4:  the hope is that it's gonna pay off for them because like that is one of
Speaker 4:  the things that can be really difficult once these cars get on the road,
Speaker 4:  everybody talks about wanting to have over the air updates and how that's
Speaker 4:  transformative. You know, Tesla uses it to make its cars better, but there
Speaker 4:  are a lot of things that can go wrong with that stuff too. And so
Speaker 4:  they're really trying to go for, I think what Tesla offers, which is this
Speaker 4:  idea of like a living car, something that can sort of change and get
Speaker 4:  better in a way that like the traditional automakers are kind of
Speaker 4:  promising something similar, but you're never going to get
Speaker 4:  in as like fluid, like the traditional automakers are going to be like
Speaker 4:  the Samsung phone that never gets the Android update faster than
Speaker 4:  the Google. Right? Like, whereas like this is the Caribbean
Speaker 4:  is the Google play edition of electric vehicles.
Speaker 2:  Oh my God. But it does need some software updates. It doesn't like just from
Speaker 2:  watching a bunch of the videos, it seems like there's a little bit still
Speaker 2:  of lag and bugginess, and they're really upfront about it too. Like the,
Speaker 2:  who is Quinn Nelson was talking in his, his video about it, that
Speaker 2:  he would go and talk to the engineers and be like, I don't know about this.
Speaker 2:  And they'd be like, yeah, we don't, we don't like it either. Like there was
Speaker 2:  a trade-off and we're working on it. Like they were like refreshingly honest,
Speaker 2:  but like they're not, they're not shipping a perfect software experience
Speaker 2:  yet.
Speaker 4:  I think, you know, one of the problems you run into with this stuff too,
Speaker 4:  is like, because software is something you can change.
Speaker 4:  It's harder to agree upon what it should do.
Speaker 4:  You know? Whereas like you got to lock in the body type and the
Speaker 4:  frame and like, like the mechanics of the car have to be set and you can't
Speaker 4:  really tinker with those. So I think that you probably run into a situation
Speaker 4:  like that. Like I've heard from someone recently at another startup that
Speaker 4:  was just about to ship that is like running into a similar problem, but
Speaker 4:  worse than Ruby and where like, there are big disagreements about how even
Speaker 4:  UIL elements should work at a very late stage in the
Speaker 4:  game that shouldn't be happening. And I think, you know, for all of the
Speaker 4:  money that it's raised in all of the things that it's been able to accomplish
Speaker 4:  so far, something is going to have to deal with is, like I said, it's got
Speaker 4:  9,000 people already. It is a very big company
Speaker 4:  now and trying to manage all that and keep all those people
Speaker 4:  together and aim them sort of at the same, like
Speaker 4:  success target that repeat, you know, RJ syringe was
Speaker 4:  aiming them at a couple of years ago when they were a much smaller team has
Speaker 4:  gotta be really hard. So I feel like that's probably one of those places
Speaker 4:  where it shows. And it's also like you're taking advantage of the fact that
Speaker 4:  you can change it up until MEV Eva. And after you shipped the
Speaker 4:  car. So like, I don't know. I feel like, I feel like that's just going to
Speaker 4:  keep happening with this stuff when we're talking about the software or the
Speaker 4:  cars, which is kind of doesn't sound great.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I mean, this is what I mean, like I, the amount of bad car software
Speaker 1:  that you can interact with as a regular person, like just go to a
Speaker 1:  car, go to any car. If you're in your car
Speaker 2:  Right now, you're still pulled over. Just, just play with your software for
Speaker 2:  a minute and just think about how would you accept this?
Speaker 5:  I'm buying a car right now. And I've seriously looked at used cars. And I
Speaker 5:  was like, actually I need to go up a year because the UI changes. And I just
Speaker 5:  can't deal with like that very old looking UI. Cause you always, always
Speaker 5:  also look like at least 10 years older than anything on your phone.
Speaker 5:  It's just like
Speaker 1:  Walnuts, you watch any YouTube car review. And like, no one wants to admit
Speaker 1:  it. So they're all like, and this screen has CarPlay and Android
Speaker 1:  auto and they just like move on. And it's like, no, wait, hold on. Like
Speaker 1:  many other things happened on that screen. Tesla is pretty good at it. People
Speaker 1:  love Tesla. They're good at over the updates. The other car makers are now
Speaker 1:  setting goals for themselves in terms of number of
Speaker 1:  over the year updates they deliver in a year. So both Ford
Speaker 1:  and GM and still Lantis here. Sweet, still
Speaker 1:  Lantus. They all talk about Dilip like is though that that is the thing that
Speaker 1:  people want. Like I don't, I don't know if they've ever talked to like a
Speaker 1:  regular person. Like no one is like, I love my phone because it gets
Speaker 1:  so many updates a year because Tesla's delivering so
Speaker 1:  many updates a year. They think that's the thing they have to compete with.
Speaker 1:  So if we just like screw with your card multiple times a year, you'll be
Speaker 1:  happy is like kind of where their heads are at. But all of that is related
Speaker 1:  to the fact that they have none of the systems to do it. Right? So be saying,
Speaker 1:  we want to deliver 20 updates a year, requires them to build a
Speaker 1:  system such that they can even do it. And so you just see how a
Speaker 1:  corporation takes something, like make the computer good and
Speaker 1:  backs it into a metric that has no relationship to
Speaker 1:  human beings. But you understand why? The question for me is like,
Speaker 1:  Ravion has to do that. They have to fix the software in the car. They have
Speaker 1:  to ship the cars. Cars have to be good. They have to service cars, they have
Speaker 1:  to charge the cars. They want to build a charging network. Can
Speaker 1:  we talk about
Speaker 2:  That for just a minute before we move on to the
Speaker 1:  Rest of it, this is just a lot to put, like the truck is like Mitchell really
Speaker 1:  loved the truck and he, the feature of the drive tunnel in the middle where
Speaker 1:  he like crawled into the space between the bed and the body, all that stuff
Speaker 1:  is cool. Go watch the YouTube. They've done a good job, giving them to YouTube
Speaker 1:  offers like they've done excellent marketing around this truck, but you just
Speaker 1:  like, kind of look at that universe of other stuff they have to do. And
Speaker 1:  I, there's still a lot of question marks what they have
Speaker 4:  Looking for them in their favor in a weird way, because this
Speaker 4:  sort of may sound like a problem is that they
Speaker 4:  are going to be so focused on this Amazon contract
Speaker 4:  and building these Amazon delivery vehicles that they they've said they've
Speaker 4:  collected 55,000 something pre-orders for the
Speaker 4:  pickup truck and the SUV combine. And they've said, it's going to take them
Speaker 4:  until the end of 2023 just to make those vehicles. Wow. So
Speaker 4:  they, instead of being like, you know, jumping in
Speaker 4:  like Ford, for instance, actually made more than the 50,000
Speaker 4:  Mustang Maki's this year than they had planned, like only a couple thousand
Speaker 4:  more, not like an insane amount, more, but ribbons looking at only doing
Speaker 4:  that within the next two years. So there, they have a little bit of breathing
Speaker 4:  room in that sense that there isn't going to be 200,000
Speaker 4:  of their vehicles out there to get right. They can kind of control
Speaker 4:  what's out there a little better, but they also have to throw a ton of focus
Speaker 4:  on the delivery vehicle side of things. And then, and then also,
Speaker 4:  yes, do these other efforts like build out a charging network, which they're
Speaker 4:  trying to do, which, you know, if no one else is gonna do it and
Speaker 4:  there's going to be part of this and the infrastructure bill. So like there
Speaker 4:  is going to be more charging stations coming, but like that's, that's a tall
Speaker 4:  task. That's even someone like Eby go, which is like a company that's been
Speaker 4:  around for awhile. That's dedicated to making electric vehicle chargers
Speaker 4:  knows what it needs to do to build them. Even it's having trouble and
Speaker 4:  as well, capitalized, it's having trouble hitting the targets
Speaker 4:  that it's setting for how many it wants to build. Because like the permitting
Speaker 4:  process in this country differs every different place that you go to build
Speaker 4:  a charger and there's all this stuff. So like they, they have
Speaker 4:  created a lot of work for themselves. And so, so
Speaker 4:  even with the consumer products that th the two vehicles that they're
Speaker 4:  extensively selling under their brand to people, you know, you
Speaker 4:  got to hope that, that they're, they're going to be able to address those
Speaker 4:  as products in a, like a totally whole sense while also managing
Speaker 4:  all this other stuff and, and maintaining 9,000 employees,
Speaker 4:  what is
Speaker 1:  Their overall charging
Speaker 4:  Strategy? Is it just, they're basically building out their own kind of
Speaker 4:  network, like Tesla supercharging network that will be proprietary at
Speaker 4:  first, you know, maybe open up after that. They're also tapping into
Speaker 4:  this idea of doing some more like destination charters that are near
Speaker 4:  trailheads and things like that.
Speaker 2:  We're going to put all our charters next to like off-road trails. So you're
Speaker 2:  gonna, you're going to go and charge up out in the wilderness is their idea.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  That's my plan that I have the idea that the founder told me back when I
Speaker 4:  first interviewed him in 2018. That's like the galaxy brain idea for the
Speaker 4:  company was, and probably still is in some ways, but
Speaker 4:  they, you, if you notice, they're not talking as much about autonomy as they
Speaker 4:  used to, but the, the galaxy brain idea for Vivian was you
Speaker 4:  go, you know, you drive with your ribbon to the
Speaker 4:  Puddin spot, you drop your kayaks in the water. You go down the river, your
Speaker 4:  ribbon automatically drives down to where you're getting out of the water
Speaker 4:  and, oh, that's cute. Yeah. I love that.
Speaker 1:  I thought it was going to be like, then the reveal lowers
Speaker 1:  a wheel into the river and charges itself, like an
Speaker 4:  Old timey. That's a good idea, because that would be,
Speaker 1:  They
Speaker 4:  Should do that. Yeah. You should have hit up their investor relations team.
Speaker 1:  Got, I've got a great water wheel idea that you just have to
Speaker 1:  zoom out. Right? So ribbon, I think is the first new electric car
Speaker 1:  company it's hit it's at this moment. It's IPO mode. It is starting to ship
Speaker 1:  the cars. There is, I would say just a level of confidence. They're
Speaker 1:  going to hit the first mark, which is like shipping a bunch of cars, being
Speaker 1:  a real company, not a bunch of financial shenanigans in a
Speaker 1:  3d render, which is like, what most Eby startups have been for awhile.
Speaker 1:  They're going to get there. But if you just zoom out, we are in this mode
Speaker 1:  of electrification, you Shawnee. And I talked to this, like, as, maybe you
Speaker 1:  feel this way too. I don't want to buy a car without a battery ever again.
Speaker 1:  Same. And whether it's a hybrid or an Evie, like, I just feel like I should,
Speaker 1:  my next car should definitely have a battery.
Speaker 5:  I mean, I live in New York city. So where there are no chargers
Speaker 5:  that are like freely available. So it's like just unreasonable.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Yeah. But you can get like a Prius, like there's like a number of ways
Speaker 1:  to get like a
Speaker 5:  Hybrid. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  So I'm just like, there, I feel like a lot of people are there,
Speaker 1:  but the actual number of cars you can buy to meet that demand
Speaker 1:  outside of the ship shortage and all the other stuff that's going on. The
Speaker 1:  actual number of cars that are available to me, that demand is shockingly
Speaker 1:  low, right? Like every car company will show you a concept.
Speaker 1:  Car cattle could make the lyric is coming and you're like, can I buy it?
Speaker 1:  And I get on this waiting list. Test is like a cyber truck. This
Speaker 1:  waiting list is even more of a spiritual idea, right? Like,
Speaker 1:  what is, why is there such a gap? Why, why I it's, it's rare that
Speaker 1:  consumer demand is so far ahead of where the industry is.
Speaker 1:  And I can't quite, I can't quite figure it out
Speaker 5:  Oil and gas companies. Is there a conspiracy
Speaker 1:  It's, they're just running around handing out cash.
Speaker 4:  I mean, they could, I mean, and what's made it even worse is the, you mentioned
Speaker 4:  the chip shortage. It's like finding a new car right now is really hard
Speaker 4:  because there are so few of them that the demand is just taking them
Speaker 4:  right off the lot, as soon as they arrive and finding a used car,
Speaker 4:  it means you're spending way more than you need to on a car that is
Speaker 4:  not worth that much. So on top of all that, the people are turning
Speaker 4:  even more to electric vehicle sales, like electric vehicle vehicles are actually
Speaker 4:  making up far more of the market right now, still single digit
Speaker 4:  percentage points, but more than we thought they were going to this year
Speaker 4:  based on like how they were growing before. So yeah, there's,
Speaker 4:  there's definitely a lack of it. It doesn't help that GM had to pull the
Speaker 4:  Chevy bolt off of, off of dealer lots because of the
Speaker 4:  recall related to the battery fires that they experienced with that that's
Speaker 4:  definitely that's hurt them, especially because they just launched two new
Speaker 4:  versions of it that were a little more capable, a little more modern,
Speaker 4:  a little less ugly. Yeah. A little, yeah, a little less ugly,
Speaker 4:  but you know that, so that's not helped. And then, you know, I, the
Speaker 4:  Mustang Maki has done really well, but we're just still in that weird
Speaker 4:  sort of valley between the promises that were
Speaker 4:  made. The way I always think about is like mid 2010s
Speaker 4:  was when we started to see all these startups show up and say, we're going
Speaker 4:  to be the next Tesla auto makers are still not maybe taking it as seriously
Speaker 4:  as they should. A couple of years later, those first startups were
Speaker 4:  starting to really fall apart and the automakers were like, let's do it.
Speaker 4:  And so we're just, we're just about to round that corner of how long it takes
Speaker 4:  an automaker to put a vehicle on the road from when it was originally
Speaker 4:  conceived and, and the startups are,
Speaker 4:  have reignited with all this new money that's coming to this space the last
Speaker 4:  two years. And so they're actually kind of arriving at a similar point, which
Speaker 4:  is why we have Ruby and now Lisa motors shipping
Speaker 4:  and a couple other ones, you know, potentially shipping next year. So it's
Speaker 4:  like sort of an unfortunate series of events.
Speaker 1:  I just can't imagine if you back out to smartphones right there.
Speaker 1:  Weren't just a lot of people walking around me. I'm like, my next phone is
Speaker 1:  going to have a touch screen. And the industry was like, w next year. Yeah,
Speaker 1:  it was the initially being like touchscreens are here. And everyone's like,
Speaker 1:  oh, that's a really good idea. We got to catch up to it. And here, it just
Speaker 1:  really feels to me like a lot of people. And maybe it's
Speaker 1:  because I mostly hear from like for chest fans or whatever, but a lot of
Speaker 1:  people are like, I want my next car to have a battery in it. Whether it's
Speaker 1:  a hybrid or full levy, like, I'm, I feel this way about
Speaker 1:  climate. I, I want my car to accelerate really fast, which
Speaker 1:  is a lot of people really want their cars to accelerate really fast, but
Speaker 1:  there's a lot of reasons you want a battery in your car and like, your choices
Speaker 1:  are a number of compact crossovers in that. Is it?
Speaker 2:  Well, I mean, you just described the us auto industry, Nila, your choices
Speaker 2:  are a number of compact crossovers and big ass trucks. And there's only two
Speaker 2:  sedans. There's two sedans you can buy, right?
Speaker 1:  No, that's it. Yeah, that's it. But it's not to me that like, not every car
Speaker 1:  is a hybrid, right? Like that, that feels like a miss from
Speaker 1:  the auto industry. They could have gotten there. They, you know, most car
Speaker 1:  companies, like at this point, like taco belling, their platforms,
Speaker 1:  right. They have three engines and like, they're just like mixing and matching
Speaker 1:  the parts.
Speaker 5:  Th th the battery and the infrastructure is the hesitancy there, right?
Speaker 5:  Like the batteries are still limited there. The, the limited distance and
Speaker 5:  a lot of people live far away, especially you get to the rural folks and
Speaker 5:  everything. They they're further away. Like they need, they, they need to
Speaker 5:  be able to charge quickly. The charging experience is still garbage. Like
Speaker 5:  I thought about getting an electric car and then I was like, okay, first
Speaker 5:  I have to pay for whatever, a place to charge it here in the city. Yikes.
Speaker 5:  And then like, if I ever want to, you know, go back to Texas and visit family,
Speaker 5:  I've added a lot more hours on my drive just to get my car
Speaker 5:  there. And it's like, that's, that's no good. Like, that's, that's a really
Speaker 5:  bad situation. It feels like, like the desire is there.
Speaker 5:  And everybody else's behind, like the industries, like the car industry is
Speaker 5:  behind. And then like those supporting industries, like, you know, mobile
Speaker 5:  and shell and all of these companies, they could be putting charging
Speaker 5:  stations in there. And there
Speaker 1:  It's funny. Cause you said mobile and I was going to go, I thought you meant
Speaker 1:  mobile phones. Someone asked me like, for example, no one is like, I want
Speaker 1:  5g in industry is like, you desperately
Speaker 5:  KTV is nobody wanted a 4k TV or a smart TV.
Speaker 1:  Like nobody, nobody, I didn't want to, nobody wanted a
Speaker 5:  Smart TV. They're like, I want to figure that out myself and the TV companies
Speaker 5:  are like, no.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I'm just saying, there's a lot of people listening to this show who
Speaker 1:  are like, I know I did want more pixels. That's actually a thing that I wanted.
Speaker 1:  Sorry guys.
Speaker 4:  Speaking of 5g, do you know who's going to come in and save that all and
Speaker 4:  solve this problem. Foxconn baby.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Do you want it, do you want to talk about Lordstown and Foxconn and
Speaker 1:  what's going on there?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. As briefly as anyone will tolerate Foxconn
Speaker 4:  announced yesterday, they announced this in September, they kind of like
Speaker 4:  finalize it yesterday. They're buying a former general
Speaker 4:  motors plant in Lordstown, Ohio, which had
Speaker 4:  famously shut down while Trump was in office and he
Speaker 4:  got very mad about it. And then he actually really touted the
Speaker 4:  sale of it a couple months later to this new startup Lord, some
Speaker 4:  motors, which is an electric vehicle startup with no history. And
Speaker 4:  they've been trying to make, get that factory ready to make a pickup truck
Speaker 4:  over the last couple of years and have just run into a ton of problems of
Speaker 4:  their own. And now Foxconn is buying that factory and Foxconn has spent the
Speaker 4:  last year plus talking about how it wants to get to electric
Speaker 4:  vehicles. It's made its own electric vehicle platform. It
Speaker 4:  has bought up or partnering with a whole bunch of other
Speaker 4:  companies, including, you know, startups like Fisker or
Speaker 4:  big companies like still Lantis. And so now they have,
Speaker 4:  you know, unless the deal doesn't close by eight, it's supposed to close
Speaker 4:  in April and who knows what Foxconn, but Foxconn is
Speaker 4:  going to have an automotive factory and electric vehicle factory in Ohio
Speaker 4:  where it will make the pickup truck for Lordstown motors. It'll make some
Speaker 4:  new vehicle that they haven't announced yet with Fisker. And who knows what
Speaker 4:  else? There's a lot of space. They're 6 million square feet. So,
Speaker 1:  And Love's a big empty building. You can't get enough of how long is the
Speaker 1:  drive from Racine to Lordstown? No, this is actually, this is really funny.
Speaker 1:  Right? So they announced that they were going to look for a factory
Speaker 1:  and everyone thought, oh, they're going to use the one in Wisconsin that
Speaker 1:  they built to build cars for Fisker. Sure. And then Henrik, Fisker
Speaker 1:  was like, no, we're not going to do that. Like straight up that
Speaker 1:  it was either Wisconsin or Mexico. And they're like, we're deciding. And
Speaker 1:  they kept visiting the Wisconsin facility. And like, here are, these are
Speaker 1:  us ops. What Fisker was actually doing was he was lobbying to
Speaker 1:  change the rule in Wisconsin that says all cars have to be sold by a dealer.
Speaker 1:  Right. Okay. Well, I'm just going to tell you the
Speaker 1:  Wisconsin GOP, which is, you know, the group that
Speaker 1:  put the Foxconn deal in place is captured by the Wisconsin
Speaker 1:  auto dealers. So that to save their own project, they
Speaker 1:  had to, they had to go against one of their biggest constituencies. I
Speaker 1:  mean, it's just, it's like a hilarious, so they, they didn't change the law.
Speaker 1:  So fester like walked and went to Ohio where they can sell a car to attract
Speaker 1:  all in. All of this is just like, like it's and we still don't spend there.
Speaker 1:  I
Speaker 4:  Love the idea. It's really, it's really wonderful that Foxconn maybe had
Speaker 4:  a total out there to like fill its empty buildings in Wisconsin with
Speaker 4:  something and say like, Hey, we're going to do this. And here now we're going
Speaker 4:  to make EVs. And instead they've now ended up in this situation where they
Speaker 4:  have two currently very empty
Speaker 4:  large sites in the United.
Speaker 5:  I mean, they built a building, like they built buildings. That's
Speaker 1:  It's also funny that Fisker like blew up this chance to get
Speaker 1:  really good press and like do this on Wisconsin because they insisted on
Speaker 1:  selling the cars direct. Like, I don't know, Tesla's building plants in Texas,
Speaker 1:  people in Texas when they buy a Tesla, they have to import, they have to
Speaker 1:  go to another place. It's a,
Speaker 5:  And they're totally okay with it. They're like, yeah, drive an
Speaker 5:  Oklahoma. See y'all in an hour.
Speaker 1:  I mean, that's just funny to me. I don't have any strong feelings on whether
Speaker 1:  cars need to be sold through dealers or not. But I do think that the fact
Speaker 1:  that people in Texas have to do a round trip out of state to get a car is
Speaker 1:  hilarious. And the fact that Fisker blew up their own
Speaker 1:  chance to rescue the Fox on planet Wisconsin over this rule is deeply
Speaker 1:  hilarious. But what were we expecting when they announced the week? We might
Speaker 1:  build the cars in Wisconsin. I think Sean and Josh and I are like, no, he
Speaker 1:  won
Speaker 1:  before we even knew the details.
Speaker 2:  Just very briefly. We've gone way far field. And we haven't talked about
Speaker 2:  the kitchen and a tube that can fit inside the ravine track. Like
Speaker 2:  it does that a real thing. Do you think that, or is that just a really cool
Speaker 2:  gimmick? Do they actually intend to sell any of those? Because if you don't
Speaker 2:  know that the truck has this pass through chamber and you can buy like
Speaker 2:  a camping kit, that's got like a working sink and a grill that like slides
Speaker 2:  out
Speaker 1:  Of your truck. That's what you meant by kitchen and a tube. I would buy
Speaker 5:  That tube
Speaker 4:  A heartbeat. Add that to your email, to their investor relations people in
Speaker 4:  the lab.
Speaker 4:  I mean, here's, here's my answer. They're charging $5,000 for it. So
Speaker 4:  yeah. They're going to try and sell it to people. Yeah. Okay. Fair enough.
Speaker 4:  Not every vehicle is going to come with it, but yeah, if they can charge
Speaker 4:  $5,000 for someone,
Speaker 5:  Every vehicle, like right now, the only, the only versions, the only trim
Speaker 5:  levels sold are the most expensive trim
Speaker 1:  Levels. Yeah. I just price thrown out. It's $83,000.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Yeah. The base price we should have said on both of these
Speaker 4:  vehicles is like 67 grand, but you'll be waiting a while for that.
Speaker 5:  You'll be getting the 90,000. Sorry.
Speaker 2:  The new trend is set up buying a pixel phone on the verge cast. You buy an
Speaker 2:  electric vehicle on the verge cast. Is that what's happening here? Right?
Speaker 1:  I can, I can put a hundred dollars down on any number of cars that aren't
Speaker 1:  shipping
Speaker 1:  is absolutely the weirdest time to be. I mean, Alex knows she's
Speaker 1:  actually been horrible. I'm addicted to car shopping. I like,
Speaker 1:  and it's just amazing how many cars don't currently exist.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Like you can look at webpages for cars for days,
Speaker 5:  And then you go to buy and it's like, no, no, no. You have to wait four months.
Speaker 5:  And then we're, we're not, we're not going to get the one you went in. We're
Speaker 5:  going to get the one that's $20,000 more take, give us your
Speaker 1:  Money. You've all those phone mounts. You know, you need cars for all this
Speaker 1:  fun. I got to put up. I got to, yeah. That's it really
Speaker 1:  start? You start small and you go big and I'm just going to start buying
Speaker 1:  like nineties escalates. They're cheap. They're available. No one wants them.
Speaker 1:  There's no, there's all that used. Car demand is not pointed at nineties.
Speaker 1:  Technically they have a battery in them. I guess there was a,
Speaker 1:  there was a brief ill-fated escalate hybrid. It is not a
Speaker 1:  good car, but I'm at the point where I'm like, well that has a battery.
Speaker 1:  It seems fine. All right, Sean, thank you so much. We got to take a break.
Speaker 1:  Thanks for coming on, man. Yeah, of course. Alright. We're gonna take a break.
Speaker 1:  We'll be right back
Speaker 7:  Support for this episode comes from single store, the single database for
Speaker 7:  all data intensive applications. Why make the switch scaling
Speaker 7:  modern? SAS is already hard. It's even harder when you're using databases
Speaker 7:  that were built back when all your friends had pet rocks and the most stressful
Speaker 7:  part of your day was connecting to the dial up modem. Single store is
Speaker 7:  built for the smart SAS generation and all the data intensive applications
Speaker 7:  that come with it. The single store cloud powers, the new wave of SAS
Speaker 7:  technologies, displacing legacy providers with insights, for apps, effortless
Speaker 7:  operation of models at scale and easy shifts to the cloud.
Speaker 7:  Introduce simplicity and ease to your data structure and watch what happens
Speaker 7:  to your speed scale and SQL. Find out why industry
Speaker 7:  leaders trust a single store to modernize their data platforms. Learn how
Speaker 7:  single store can help you at single
Speaker 7:  store.com/vergecast that's single
Speaker 7:  store.com/vergecast.
Speaker 8:  This is paid content presented by Volvo cars. If you've never driven a
Speaker 8:  fully electric vehicle, like the Volvo XC 40 recharged before you might
Speaker 8:  be wondering, what's it like? So we developed a course for electric
Speaker 8:  vehicle first-timers they had a lot of questions.
Speaker 9:  Ah, well I understand you're all here because somehow you've never driven
Speaker 9:  a fully electric car before. Don't worry. You must have questions, but I'm
Speaker 9:  here to answer them. Yes. You in the front,
Speaker 7:  Does it have to be plugged in to drive?
Speaker 9:  What, how, how would that? No, no, no. Just plug it in when you get home
Speaker 9:  and charge it up overnight, like you charge your phone for example.
Speaker 9:  Okay. So who's ready to take a look at Volvo XC 40
Speaker 9:  recharge.
Speaker 9:  What happens when there's traffic? The XC 40 recharge has
Speaker 9:  regenerative braking. What's that? Okay. Think of it like this. You're going
Speaker 9:  to be charging your car when you're stuck in traffic. So
Speaker 9:  traffic becomes something you look forward to because it's charging your
Speaker 9:  car and it's not just the engine that's helping the environment. No, no,
Speaker 9:  no. There's more. This carpet is made from a hundred percent recycled
Speaker 9:  pet water bottles. So it's not just premium. It's not just luxurious.
Speaker 9:  It's made with a better world in mind. Oh. And Google is built
Speaker 9:  into the  recharge. So Google maps is always with
Speaker 9:  you even if, and
Speaker 8:  When you forget your phone, get ready for the next chapter in driving
Speaker 8:  with Volvo's pure electric  recharge. The future starts now
Speaker 8:  learn more@volvocars.com slash us.
Speaker 1:  Okay. We're back. It's kind of a lot of apple stuff going on.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Like just a shoe mortgage board and on the
Speaker 2:  smorgasbord is just different
Speaker 1:  Apples. Or should we start with buttons and links? I think we have
Speaker 2:  To.
Speaker 1:  Okay. So apple versus epic big court case, epic
Speaker 1:  loses on most of its charges of apple being a monopoly and the iPhone being
Speaker 1:  a monopoly in its own operating system. Okay. They
Speaker 1:  win one very important concession from the judge. The judge says Apple's
Speaker 1:  anti steering rules are bad. And to competitive under California law
Speaker 1:  writes an order saying basically crossing out the anti-stigma
Speaker 1:  rule that apple has, right? So you strike this language. Now apps
Speaker 1:  in their metadata and in the application themselves must allow buttons and
Speaker 1:  links pointing to external payment systems. Right? This led to
Speaker 1:  some discussion about buttons and links mean more importantly, it led to
Speaker 1:  apple saying, hold up, that's bad. We want to stay this order. And
Speaker 1:  so we appeal the case and we can win again. Right? So they go to
Speaker 1:  the judge and request to stay. They had oral and they filed their motion
Speaker 1:  stuff. They had oral argument in front of the same. Judge. Judge said, no,
Speaker 1:  I don't like this. Like if I grant you, this stay, nothing will change for
Speaker 1:  three to five years while you do these appeals that you're gonna do. Right.
Speaker 1:  We thought, okay, they had an oral argument. She yelled at apple a bunch,
Speaker 1:  which was really interesting. Okay. It's going to take a, you know, another
Speaker 1:  week or two, like 30 minutes later, she puts out the order saying no, stay
Speaker 1:  granted. And she like dunks on apple a lot. Yeah. Right. The
Speaker 1:  anti steering provisions are one of the key provisions upon which apple has
Speaker 1:  been able to successfully charge super competitive commissions,
Speaker 1:  untethered to its intellectual property. Apple's commission rates, depress
Speaker 1:  royalties and suppress competition in the industry generally. She's like,
Speaker 1:  no, I think your anti-competitive.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Well, and one of the, one of the key points here was apples
Speaker 2:  meant changing. This rule is going to take years. It's
Speaker 2:  going to be so hard. And the judge is like, no,
Speaker 2:  you've you've. I gave you 90 days. You could, you could figure it out. I'm
Speaker 2:  not even going to give you a 10 day extension because I gave you 90 days.
Speaker 2:  And why didn't she get started by now? It's like, it's like, why didn't you
Speaker 2:  get your homework done? You should have started it by now. It's not my fault.
Speaker 2:  You waited to the last minute.
Speaker 1:  Apple also said it would cause significant engineering resources to comply
Speaker 1:  with this rule, which no one knows what that means. Yeah. Okay. So she says,
Speaker 1:  no, she clarifies buttons and links. Yeah. But then
Speaker 1:  I pretty sure the order has a typo in it. So now we have to talk about something
Speaker 1:  else, but she does clarify buttons and links. She says with
Speaker 1:  respect to the alleged need for clarification, because some developers do
Speaker 1:  not understand the scope of the injunction in the developer agreement, prohibits
Speaker 1:  third party, in-app purchasing systems other than apple IAP. And at purchases,
Speaker 1:  the court did not enjoy that provision. Didn't say other payment systems,
Speaker 1:  but rather said, you have to be to communicate external alternative and
Speaker 1:  allow links to those external sites. I'm just going to tell you, I don't
Speaker 1:  think she actually clarified anything. Cause I don't know what happens if
Speaker 1:  you have a button in an app that opens it in a browser that already has your
Speaker 1:  login info and billing info in it. And that's how you buy Fortnite dances.
Speaker 1:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Is that an, is that an in-app purchase or is that a separate
Speaker 2:  browser earlier in the ruling? The judge writes consumers are quite used
Speaker 2:  to linking from app to a web browser. So it's like, yes, we're in the weeds.
Speaker 1:  So in the Kindle app, if it has a button that says buy book and it opens
Speaker 1:  a browser, what are they going to do? Yeah. They definitely still have to
Speaker 1:  put the other button there. I think the apple button
Speaker 1:  probably
Speaker 5:  They have
Speaker 1:  To write that when the court doesn't say so, but I think apple might say
Speaker 1:  so.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And the court doesn't say the court says apple could say, could demand
Speaker 2:  it if it wanted to. I think, yeah.
Speaker 1:  So I just, I love the judges. Like I'm clarifying this and she doesn't clarify
Speaker 1:  it, which is very important. So still we're still in the world of
Speaker 1:  buttons and links. Apple says, they're going to appeal this again. It is
Speaker 1:  every time you appeal it. Now it's like getting dicier that it'll get stayed,
Speaker 1:  but we'll see it's happened before. But that's where we are with buttons
Speaker 1:  and links is apple has won a lot of this war.
Speaker 1:  This very important battle is still not won. And by
Speaker 1:  December 9th, they have to allow developers to tell
Speaker 1:  you places, to buy things that are not apples and communicate the
Speaker 1:  prices, which means the pricing pressure on the app store is going to get
Speaker 1:  really incredible. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  And actually the judge specifically talks about this. Apple maintains convenience,
Speaker 2:  VIP. If it can compete on pricing, developers may opt to capitalize on
Speaker 2:  that convenience, including any reassure. I think she means reinsurance that
Speaker 2:  apple provides customers that may provide safer, blah, blah, blah. But then
Speaker 2:  here's the dunk. The fact remains. It should be their choice,
Speaker 2:  consumer information and transparency and consumer choice is in the
Speaker 2:  interest of the public. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Can we talk about this type of real quick? We have to.
Speaker 1:  So she puts out the, the, she puts out the opinion denying this day
Speaker 1:  and the line, the, you know, the order says apps in their
Speaker 1:  metadata, comma, buttons and links. And I'm pretty sure there's a
Speaker 1:  type of on that. And so now the order actually reads apps in their meta buttons.
Speaker 1:  And I just like lost my mind. Like what is the matter button? Where did
Speaker 1:  this come from? I can't, we have to stop using this word. It's very bad,
Speaker 1:  but I'm pretty sure it's a typo. And the, she was copying and pasting, but
Speaker 1:  we figured it out. Is apple
Speaker 5:  Gonna avoid doing what they're supposed to?
Speaker 1:  Because they've redefined the Metta buttons
Speaker 5:  Really hopes. I mean, I don't hope so.
Speaker 2:  I hope so. Here's the thing though. The word Metta button appears twice in
Speaker 2:  the ruling.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Yeah. It's real bad. I will say that.
Speaker 1:  It's still not clear. If you push a button, it opens a web view.
Speaker 1:  We know what Apple's going to say, but we still don't know what it means
Speaker 1:  to push a link, to go to a website in the context of the app store
Speaker 2:  Is a metal button, a button in the metaverse.
Speaker 1:  I don't want, I can't, I can't be talking about them out of her seat. The
Speaker 1:  CEO of Disney this week did earnings call. And he was like Disney plus is
Speaker 1:  a metaverse. And we're like, is it?
Speaker 2:  I think it was Benedict Evans. Who said that we're in, in two years
Speaker 2:  where all of this metaverse talk is going to sound like what? The information
Speaker 2:  super highway sounded like the late two thousands. Remember like in the nineties,
Speaker 2:  bill Clinton was like, we're going to go, we're going to get on the information
Speaker 2:  super highway, right after there was a bridge to the future or something,
Speaker 2:  something, something. And no one talks about the information superhighway
Speaker 2:  now, because that's a ridiculous metaphor for the internet.
Speaker 1:  You know? It's a fun thing to say, if you just like, if you really want to
Speaker 1:  like push it, don't say information super highway. Just tell someone you
Speaker 1:  were surfing the web. Just like, be like, what'd you do last night. And you're
Speaker 1:  like, I surf the web and people will look at you like you are crazy.
Speaker 1:  Do you talk, do you try to do it tonight to go to the bar?
Speaker 5:  Like
Speaker 1:  One of my favorite activities,
Speaker 5:  What were you doing this evening? Surfing the web, waiting for you to get
Speaker 5:  here, surfing the web on my phone.
Speaker 2:  Can I have feelings about surfing the web? Because it means that like people
Speaker 2:  aren't clicking links between websites, everyone's just going to Google.
Speaker 2:  It's a sign of monopoly power that we can't surf anymore. Bring
Speaker 2:  back the wave.
Speaker 1:  The worst, the worst point breaks equal of all time.
Speaker 1:  It's being pitched right now. I'm just putting it out there.
Speaker 1:  There's a bunch of other apple stuff. Tim cook gave an interview at the deal
Speaker 1:  book conference this week with Andrew Sirkin. He said he owned
Speaker 1:  cryptocurrency. He didn't think that apple would like he personally is
Speaker 1:  invested in cryptocurrency. He said, I thought it was a good idea. He said,
Speaker 1:  apple, wasn't interested in it because it's so volatile. He doesn't think
Speaker 1:  people buy apple stock to get exposure to crypto volatility, which is just,
Speaker 1:  you can just see where Tim Cook's head is at. Right? Like he gave the deep
Speaker 1:  answer on crypto volatility and the Andrew Ross Sorkin. I was like, what
Speaker 1:  about the metaphors? He's like, no, no further, no
Speaker 1:  further comments from me. He did say that he thinks
Speaker 1:  sideloading is bad. These some comments on that stuff. Can you explain
Speaker 1:  this face ID right. To repair situation. So
Speaker 2:  When you replace a screen on an iPhone 13 and you put it onto
Speaker 2:  another iPhone, there's a chip that makes face ID work.
Speaker 2:  And that stops working if you swap screens and there's
Speaker 2:  no reason it should. There's the secure enclave and all that stuff
Speaker 2:  isn't there. So I fixed it, did the tear down and they
Speaker 2:  investigated that. Like, if you like learn micro soldering and
Speaker 2:  you managed to get the chip off the board, you know, some way and move
Speaker 2:  it to the other thing, it'll continue to work. But functionally, what it
Speaker 2:  does is it takes a huge category of phone
Speaker 2:  repairs and puts it in a place where independent repair shops just cannot
Speaker 2:  do it because if face ID breaks, you're not going to get your screen
Speaker 2:  replaced from the place that breaks your face ID, just you're not going to
Speaker 2:  do it. And they iOS was putting up various warnings
Speaker 2:  about it. And it was clear that Evel had some idea
Speaker 2:  of what was going on here. And they gave
Speaker 2:  us, you know, the information they're like, actually now we're going to,
Speaker 2:  we're going to fix that. You're going to be, to not have to micro, solder
Speaker 2:  a chip from one screen to the other screen, to in order to make your screen
Speaker 2:  swap worker replace your screen. So they actually backed
Speaker 2:  off a thing that improved your right to repair, which
Speaker 2:  I don't believe happens without, you know, the current push
Speaker 2:  for right to repair and the current regulatory pressures that are being put
Speaker 2:  on big tech.
Speaker 5:  Didn't they do this with the touch ID too. Like the touch ID. You had to
Speaker 5:  switch things over. Otherwise your touch ID would break.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. It's, it's very, it's very, very similar. So you'd think conceptually
Speaker 2:  it's the same thing, but I'm pretty sure the chip didn't perform the exact
Speaker 2:  same function.
Speaker 1:  We'll also touch ID. It was not connected to the screen.
Speaker 5:  Right. But when you were replacing the front of it, if you replaced the front
Speaker 5:  of it wrong, the touch ID would break because it was like, cause it
Speaker 5:  would be like, oh, you have a new touch ID. We hate you. But yeah,
Speaker 2:  But the part on the 13, like it's connected to the screen face ID and the
Speaker 2:  screen are basically one piece, like some of that stuff. And so
Speaker 2:  swapping that stuff out is really difficult because you've got to get into
Speaker 2:  micro soldering. And so you need to be able to just buy that
Speaker 2:  part that has all that stuff on it and put it on when your screen
Speaker 2:  breaks. And only an apple authorized dealer had the
Speaker 2:  software jiggery pokery to authorize face ID on that
Speaker 2:  screen replacement. And they have now stepped back and it
Speaker 2:  no longer will break face ID. If you replace your screen, that also has those
Speaker 2:  face ID bets on it.
Speaker 5:  This is like a bug or was this intentional and
Speaker 5:  oh, they got caught. So that's
Speaker 2:  An excellent question, Alex, what do you think? Hm,
Speaker 5:  I sure have opinions on that subject.
Speaker 1:  I think I think theater is right. I think basically the right to repair,
Speaker 1:  there are bills. There are people in Congress, it's all part of the anti-trust
Speaker 1:  stuff. Like this is going to be one of those, any member of
Speaker 1:  Congress can be like, and big tech won't even let you fix your phone
Speaker 1:  anymore. If you break the screen, like why walk into that
Speaker 1:  yet?
Speaker 2:  No, I think that there's a, there's an entire category of problems now for
Speaker 2:  apple where Tim cook is like, you know what? I don't want to think about
Speaker 2:  it. Like make that go away where normally they'd be like, Nope, we're going
Speaker 2:  to, we're going to hold the line here. But I think right now there's just
Speaker 2:  a category of things. Or Tim Cook's like, Nope, that that's not worth our
Speaker 2:  time.
Speaker 5:  We're going to hold the line on the definition of button. But
Speaker 1:  Yes, I think anything that's, anything that is easy
Speaker 1:  for a politician to explain is not a battle worth fighting.
Speaker 1:  And so you're very simple. Like I love it. You want to get deep
Speaker 1:  in the weeds on buttons and links and whether or not IAP
Speaker 1:  should be 30% or 15, like whatever. Like no one at a
Speaker 1:  town hall meeting, we we've been trying to do it on the show for 10
Speaker 1:  years. And it's very hard. You want to do
Speaker 1:  blue bubbles? That's my that's still like over the head of most people and
Speaker 1:  people can feel it and they understand it. Apple made it impossible for you
Speaker 1:  to cheaply repair your screen when you crack your phone, like
Speaker 1:  that's just gold. That's political gold. And like, why, why give him
Speaker 1:  the gold? And you forced him to do RCS. That's all I'm saying.
Speaker 2:  Good luck.
Speaker 1:  Okay. More, more quick apple stuff to kind of interesting
Speaker 1:  hires one, I think makes sense. Like
Speaker 1:  conceptually the other ones. So they, the CEO of Johnson, Johnson has now
Speaker 1:  joined Apple's board. Yep. Great. Presumably because apple just wants to
Speaker 1:  do health stuff all the time and they think Johnson Johnson will help them.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Well, and like they they've been, they've been trying so long to get
Speaker 2:  health, right. Their efforts really need a booster. Very good.
Speaker 2:  I've got one shot to get it right this time.
Speaker 1:  Oh my God. That's the virtuous. Everybody only
Speaker 5:  Works in she percent of the time.
Speaker 1:  It's brutal. Wow. It is interesting how apple
Speaker 1:  invests in health. Right. And like they've run into a lot of
Speaker 1:  problems with health. Okay. They're adding an executive to the
Speaker 1:  board to, to bring some rigor to that.
Speaker 2:  And I think bring some rigor to their goals, to like, what are, what is,
Speaker 2:  what are we planning on doing, besides Tim cook saying health is going to
Speaker 2:  be our most important contribution? Well like specify the contribution a
Speaker 2:  little bit more clearly. I think having this CEO in particular on the board
Speaker 2:  helps them do that.
Speaker 5:  So does this mean they're not going to cause for awhile, they're like maybe
Speaker 5:  we'll do our own like internal clinics and hospitals. And they realized
Speaker 5:  that was bad. And so now they're like pivoting maybe away from that.
Speaker 1:  We'll see. So this brings you into the second higher, right? So you add the
Speaker 1:  CEO of the health care company to bring some rigor and some goals and
Speaker 1:  some direction. Okay. That makes sense. They've also hired yet another
Speaker 1:  Tesla, executive, the director, the former director of autopilot
Speaker 1:  to do question marks,
Speaker 5:  Unrealistic things. Well, I,
Speaker 1:  I don't know the apple car situ I mean, Sorkin did
Speaker 1:  ask cook about this. And there was just more when Tim cook shuts
Speaker 1:  down, man, it is like a robot turn. It's like booboo, booboo. Like he was
Speaker 1:  like, I'm not talking about that. So they they've added yet another
Speaker 1:  car executive to do something. They have spun this program
Speaker 1:  up. They have spun it down 500 times. We still don't know what's
Speaker 1:  happening, but they continue to hire car executives specifically ex
Speaker 1:  Tesla executives. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It's all for CarPlay.
Speaker 5:  You guys think there's a car coming. It's all CarPlay.
Speaker 2:  The thing Sean talked about earlier about how like electric car people and
Speaker 2:  like just people that are doing high end car software are just bouncing around
Speaker 2:  between the companies is very real.
Speaker 1:  What's interesting is you can break the software. There's two big chunks.
Speaker 1:  There's the stuff on the screen in front of you, which is sort of uniformly
Speaker 1:  bad. Then there's the stuff that runs the car, which is not
Speaker 1:  allowed to be bad. Right. And it at a deeply fundamental
Speaker 1:  level and they operate in very different. So you need to survive like
Speaker 1:  yeah, if your car is the body control module of your car
Speaker 1:  fails, like bad things happen to you and they're on wildly different
Speaker 1:  development timelines. And then there's self-driving, which is
Speaker 1:  supposed to connect a lot of these things, right? You need to tell a where
Speaker 1:  you want to go. And then the car has to operate another wildly
Speaker 1:  different development cycle and timeline. One of the most interesting things
Speaker 1:  about apple, like in terms of the mystery is we have no idea where they want
Speaker 1:  to play. Right? Like for awhile, they were going to build their own car,
Speaker 1:  which then they were going to build all of it. Then they were just going
Speaker 1:  to build self-driving for other car makers or a user experience or other
Speaker 1:  car makers still totally unclear what they want to do.
Speaker 5:  All CarPlay, the best music experience it's coming.
Speaker 1:  That's spatial audio in the car. Oh God. But to
Speaker 1:  what Sean was mentioning earlier, right. To succeed, you need to have a lot
Speaker 1:  of money. Apple is kind of at the point where they have so much money
Speaker 1:  that they can't be like, you know what we're gonna do? We're gonna, we're
Speaker 1:  gonna make a TV, which has something I think they should do. They're like
Speaker 1:  that doesn't cost enough money. It doesn't move the needle enough.
Speaker 1:  Like they could just buy Samsung.
Speaker 1:  We now make TVs. And they like, yeah, that was the pocket chain. They
Speaker 1:  can spend enough money to make a car. And I think part of the reason they
Speaker 1:  keep chasing after it is it's because it's one of the few places where the,
Speaker 1:  where like they, they have them. They're one of the few companies that just
Speaker 1:  has the cash balance to do it. Yeah. Yeah. And I think you can
Speaker 1:  see that as an opportunity. You can also see it as like, man, you, you should
Speaker 1:  decide what you want. Like the apple midsize
Speaker 1:  crossover is a deeply funny thing to consider
Speaker 5:  And it costs a hundred thousand dollars. Can't repair.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. With the windshield falls off, you have to call apple. Okay. Lastly,
Speaker 1:  Becca and Mario made a great video comparing the, the iPhone 13
Speaker 1:  pro and the pixel six pro the full framed and Becca, I'm not going to tell
Speaker 1:  like, it is a great video. It's super fun to watch. It is remarkable where
Speaker 1:  these cameras have landed. Yeah. And what they're good and bad at. I'm not
Speaker 1:  going to tell you their results. You should go watch it. And particularly
Speaker 1:  the Mario segment is very funny because Mario is hilarious, but go watch
Speaker 1:  it. It's really good. Becca had to take a lot of photos, like literally the
Speaker 1:  end card of this videos back and being like, I don't know if I can do this
Speaker 1:  again.
Speaker 2:  2000 photos thousand, each from each camp,
Speaker 5:  We were talking about report. She doesn't have a dog. She doesn't have a
Speaker 5:  cat. She doesn't have children. She doesn't have like naturally photogenic
Speaker 5:  things around her. And she went out and took 2000 photos. That's like, that's
Speaker 5:  incredible.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Amazing. Okay. One more quick break. We'll be back. Let's wrap this
Speaker 1:  thing up. We'll write back.
Speaker 2:  This episode of the Vergecast was brought to you by American giant. Oh boy.
Speaker 2:  The holidays are rapidly approaching and buying gifts are probably on your
Speaker 2:  radar. And with the dues, talking about shipping delays and supply chain
Speaker 2:  issues, it's more important than ever to, you know, not procrastinate on
Speaker 2:  those shopping lists these days. It's all about looking good and feeling
Speaker 2:  good in what you wear. So take the easy route and grab a classic full zip
Speaker 2:  hoodie from American giant for whoever is on your nice list. A good
Speaker 2:  hoodie from American giant can take you miles. It's casual. It says you're
Speaker 2:  laid back, but it doesn't make you look like a slob. It's versatile. You
Speaker 2:  can wear those puppies with just about anything from jeans to khakis.
Speaker 2:  And finally it's comfortable. It's got super soft heavyweight cotton plus
Speaker 2:  ribbed and a double lined hood. These are some serious credentials. And
Speaker 2:  with American giant, you're getting some quality in those threads. It can
Speaker 2:  withstand wash. After wash lasting you years was a super
Speaker 2:  tight knit fabric it's made to keep you warm on the coldest winter days,
Speaker 2:  explore America giants collection of durable
Speaker 2:  essentials@american-giant.com. And you get
Speaker 2:  20% off when you use code verge at checkout. That's 20%
Speaker 2:  off@american-giant.com promo code verge
Speaker 2:  consumers right now have more choices than ever before. We all have an
Speaker 2:  almost unlimited number of places to shop, which is why marketers jobs
Speaker 2:  have gotten harder and harder because they need to find ways to make people
Speaker 2:  fall in love with their brands time and time. Again, that means finding
Speaker 2:  creative, new methods of engaging with customers in a personal, conversational
Speaker 2:  and informative way. That's where attentive comes in. Attentive is a
Speaker 2:  personalized text message marketing platform that lets marketers communicate
Speaker 2:  with their customers in real time. Engage your list with timely campaigns,
Speaker 2:  build lasting relationships and drive revenue with the same platform. That's
Speaker 2:  trusted by thousands of brands, including CBT per Avita
Speaker 2:  and coach attentive is powering magical campaigns for those
Speaker 2:  brands and has driven more than 20% of their online revenue. If you'd
Speaker 2:  like to join them and turn SMS into one of your top three revenue channels
Speaker 2:  in just a few months, you need to try attentive, learn more about a free
Speaker 2:  trial with attentive. When you request a demo at attentive,
Speaker 2:  mobile.com/vox, that's attentive,
Speaker 2:  mobile.com/a V O X
Speaker 2:  we're back. Yeah. As much of Microsoft news. So
Speaker 2:  they have announced another version of windows.
Speaker 2:  It's another S version. It's a windows 11 S
Speaker 2:  E. And if we know anything about se it's that it's a very clearly
Speaker 2:  defined thing, right? Like the iPhone se it is a
Speaker 2:  special edition, I suppose, of windows that's aimed really just at
Speaker 2:  education. And so it's
Speaker 2:  optimized for low cost devices. It's not going to ship
Speaker 2:  with the Microsoft store, which is interesting, but they are going to
Speaker 2:  allow third party apps, including zoom in Chrome, because
Speaker 2:  you can't get into schools without zoom and Chrome because that's how they
Speaker 2:  run schools. And yeah, so it's like,
Speaker 2:  that's interesting, but it's, you know, it's easy to dunk on
Speaker 2:  Microsoft to keep trying to make lightweight versions of windows, but they
Speaker 2:  really do need to get into the education market. And this is another
Speaker 2:  shot at it. So fine to me, the more
Speaker 2:  interesting thing in some ways is alongside
Speaker 2:  windows 11 se they announced the
Speaker 2:  $249 surface laptop se
Speaker 5:  Garbage display could be pretty.
Speaker 5:  I haven't seen it. So I don't want to say it's garbage,
Speaker 5:  but, but when your resolution is
Speaker 5:  13, six by 7 68 in
Speaker 5:  2021, that's not,
Speaker 1:  Yeah, that's a classic. That's like a, it's like a mid two
Speaker 1:  thousands. I book
Speaker 5:  It's
Speaker 2:  Like it is wild that they can't it's opposite
Speaker 1:  Of pixel density.
Speaker 5:  It's Microsoft invest in, in displays please.
Speaker 2:  Well, there, there are Chromebooks at this price range that are doing better
Speaker 2:  on the display front, but in terms of making a device, other than the
Speaker 2:  display, in terms of making a low cost device for schools,
Speaker 2:  they're making it repairable. They're going to have parts it's relatively
Speaker 2:  easy to open, easy to open up. So that's actually incredibly good news.
Speaker 2:  Hopefully the thing is relatively durable. It's a bummer that they're using
Speaker 2:  an Intel Celeron processor
Speaker 5:  Bummer. It's four gigabytes of Ram. That's like, that's the
Speaker 5:  real,
Speaker 2:  So here's the thing like can windows 11 se get lightweight
Speaker 2:  enough where things can actually run well on this processor and this much
Speaker 2:  Ram cause you can get a Chromebook that can like not be the
Speaker 2:  worst at, at these specs, but more importantly, you can get
Speaker 2:  a Chromebook was slightly better specs for not that much more money.
Speaker 2:  And I don't know, I don't know what Microsoft's goal here. Do they actually
Speaker 2:  want to sell this thing in bulk to schools or is there hope that they
Speaker 2:  can prove to the rest of the windows market that they need to try harder
Speaker 2:  at making windows machines to compete with Chromebooks instead of just making
Speaker 2:  Chromebooks?
Speaker 5:  Like it's both, especially like when you look at this, because I used to
Speaker 5:  have to cover like these really cheap laptops for awhile. And once
Speaker 5:  you get under $500, you're in garbage territory for windows or
Speaker 5:  you're in like Chromebooks and even the Chromebooks start to get pretty,
Speaker 5:  pretty dicey, but like, there's just nothing in
Speaker 5:  that space. That's usable as far as windows goes. And it's
Speaker 5:  always like, I think the recommendation was always like, save your money.
Speaker 5:  Like put yourself in debt before you buy one of these, which is not a good
Speaker 5:  recommendation and it's not realistic. And the idea that
Speaker 5:  like they're going to attempt it is great. Like the surface go was
Speaker 5:  nice and, and kind of forced everybody else to say, okay, we can
Speaker 5:  think we can be a little more thoughtful. We can actually do a nice display.
Speaker 5:  So like, it's nice that they're doing it. And hopefully it forces
Speaker 5:  people. But oof, that display is just,
Speaker 5:  that's just upsetting.
Speaker 1:  We've heard a lot about different companies trying to compete with Chromebooks.
Speaker 1:  Like apple keeps. That's why they make a cheap iPad. You know, if you offer,
Speaker 1:  if you'd said you've got about 250 or $300 to spend, I would take an iPad
Speaker 1:  over this Chromebook. I think because the iPad has a much nicer display,
Speaker 1:  but then you'd have to spend a bunch of money in like keyboard cases and
Speaker 1:  whatever. But the Chromebooks like centrality to the
Speaker 1:  education market right now is like one of those things we don't talk about
Speaker 1:  enough. Like every kid just gets like handed a Chromebook in school right
Speaker 1:  now because there's just a handful of Google products. They use to all talk
Speaker 1:  to each other and like do the work
Speaker 5:  And that they somehow get Hangouts running on those Chromebooks.
Speaker 1:  Tara Lawrence once had a great story about how kids were flirting in the
Speaker 1:  comments of Google box. Just like very good
Speaker 1:  it's they can keep trying to make the entry point, but they've got to, once
Speaker 1:  a school district is bought in, switching them over is really hard. And like
Speaker 1:  the schools are pretty bought into the Google stuff right now.
Speaker 2:  I mean, this is, this is why they were explicit that windows 11 se can
Speaker 2:  run Chrome like that. It lets you install it it's
Speaker 2:  administered by the school of like, it's, it's run by like the it department,
Speaker 2:  like what software is available, it's it, there's no windows store, but like,
Speaker 1:  It's a, it's a strategy there that like your school gives you this instead
Speaker 1:  of a Chromebook and you like accidentally click on teams and you're like,
Speaker 1:  Ooh, I love this. This is way better.
Speaker 1:  We'll see. Speaking of teams, we actually, I think we were talking on this
Speaker 1:  last week, how Microsoft has all the workplace stuff and Facebook has the
Speaker 1:  hardware. Well, here they are Microsoft partners with Metta to bring
Speaker 1:  teams into Facebook's horizon workplace. Whoo.
Speaker 1:  It's not at first I rewatched
Speaker 1:  the Microsoft metaverse keynote. Yeah. And the
Speaker 1:  moment when the guy clicks the button to send their
Speaker 1:  legless bodies into the lobby of an Accenture office, I was like, this
Speaker 1:  isn't well here, Lisa matrix was cool.
Speaker 1:  At least when Kiana was like woke up and he was in the
Speaker 1:  battery facility and he was like, this is the real world. This sucks.
Speaker 1:  Like there were some people who were like, put me back in the battery. That's
Speaker 1:  a plot point in the matrix. It's like, get me back there.
Speaker 1:  No one is like, get me back to me in
Speaker 2:  Cartoon land,
Speaker 1:  Zero. People are like, I want to go to this Accenture office, but it's
Speaker 1:  happening. You can see it coming together. And then lastly, this windows
Speaker 1:  expired certificate, expired certificate stories are always good.
Speaker 2:  So I was like, I actually had a tweet. I was like, it actually makes me feel
Speaker 2:  nice that like giant companies still have expired certificate pro like things
Speaker 2:  that break their software. Cause like, you know, I forget to go to the dentist.
Speaker 2:  So like even everybody can forget things, but
Speaker 2:  actually if you just take a step back, it is really stupid that like this
Speaker 2:  basic fundamental thing broke and that Microsoft wasn't on top of
Speaker 2:  it because in windows, many companies have solved this problem of like
Speaker 2:  remembering to make sure your certificates don't expire.
Speaker 1:  All right. Want to end with people ask me this. I did not
Speaker 1:  expect this to be a big deal. It turned into a huge deal. So we
Speaker 1:  updated our background policy, which I'll explain in a second
Speaker 1:  and we didn't put it on the front page. I just tweeted it and it like
Speaker 1:  blew up. And so some people asking you spend five minutes explaining what
Speaker 1:  you mean. And I, it was just, this was a note for PR people and
Speaker 1:  most of the other reporters. So here's the thing that happens to me all the
Speaker 1:  time. I talked to Dieter, Dieter talks to me, I'm a reporter Dieter. I get
Speaker 1:  to write down what Dieter said and said, the Dieter said it unskilled on
Speaker 1:  the record. This is the standard. How it should work all the time. Then if
Speaker 1:  you watched any movie with newspaper people and I, I
Speaker 1:  love movies, newspaper people. I could watch the post all day, my
Speaker 1:  old Michael Keaton movie, the paper. Very good. Just go check it out. If
Speaker 1:  you watch any of those movies, you watch any of the Watergate movies. You
Speaker 1:  know, people are off the record. That means you can't use what they say.
Speaker 1:  And this is really a fun thing you can do with your friends. He used to be
Speaker 1:  like off the record. I'm like, it doesn't mean you can just say it
Speaker 1:  and it means you can't use it right. Then there's this gray
Speaker 1:  area in the middle where I say, Hey Dieter, can I tell you something on
Speaker 1:  background heaters? Like maybe
Speaker 2:  Define on
Speaker 1:  Background.
Speaker 1:  And then I tell him something and he, he can use the information Dieter.
Speaker 1:  I am  and he can say
Speaker 1:  sources say, and he buying T right.
Speaker 2:  Or I can say Neela is buying a Rubian rot, but I don't quote
Speaker 2:  him, gives me a long, complicated explanation of
Speaker 2:  why. And then I can paraphrase that explanation and source it to Nila.
Speaker 2:  And so some companies, when they say on background, what they mean is that
Speaker 2:  we don't want you to tell anybody that we're the ones that told you some
Speaker 2:  companies do the right thing and say, yeah, we're on background, but you
Speaker 2:  can tell people what we told you, but the definitions are all over the
Speaker 2:  place. And there's a potential
Speaker 2:  confusion there that can gum up the
Speaker 2:  works, let's say.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. And I, and I would say our responsibility as journalists and
Speaker 1:  reporters is to not, is not for us to know things. It's to
Speaker 1:  tell you what the companies are doing. Right. So when I, when I
Speaker 1:  just like magically know, I'll just keep picking on Vivian. If I just have
Speaker 1:  magically know what ravine is doing, you have no idea why I know this
Speaker 1:  information. Even no idea where it came from. And if they have lied to me,
Speaker 1:  I'm on the hook for it. And they are not,
Speaker 2:  We're only picking on reveal cause they were earlier on the show, not
Speaker 1:  I'm trying to what's the what's the fake Contoso is
Speaker 1:  that the fake company that Microsoft always uses,
Speaker 2:  I can tell. So yeah,
Speaker 1:  It doesn't matter any company you can think of, they all do it now. So a
Speaker 1:  thing that has really happened with tech companies in particular is they
Speaker 1:  tell everything to everyone on background. And they just tell you, this is
Speaker 1:  true, like all the time. And you're like, well,
Speaker 1:  who said it? Is it real? Is it Y it's you, you were saying like now some
Speaker 1:  background. So we just reset our policy to
Speaker 1:  back where it was like, if you look at the replies to my tweet about this,
Speaker 1:  there's like so many like grizzled old newspaper reporters for like, well,
Speaker 1:  those are, those are always been the rules. Yeah. And it's like, great. I
Speaker 1:  understand that those are, those are the rules that in 1978, your
Speaker 1:  local paper, when you were like beating down the doors of city hall here
Speaker 1:  in 2021, the boundaries have actually moved for tech
Speaker 1:  companies and the companies that cover them. And we're just resetting the
Speaker 1:  boundaries to yes. Where they were before, which is
Speaker 1:  everything's on the record. And if you want to be on background, you have
Speaker 1:  to ask us and we have to agree. Right. And I will tell you that, like, there's
Speaker 1:  a bunch of stuff. There are a bunch of times when, when Google,
Speaker 1:  actually we had a story yesterday where Netflix, I don't know if you saw
Speaker 1:  this. Netflix is switching to AB one is it's codec. Oh, how did we
Speaker 1:  not spend the entire Vergecast should is so
Speaker 1:  right. And so we were like, great. What, what devices are going to use? AB
Speaker 1:  one. And they sent us the list. The list is hilarious. It's just like
Speaker 1:  select 20, 28 K TVs. And it's like, well, that's got a
Speaker 1:  list of supported devices, select Amazon fire devices.
Speaker 1:  Cool. Anyways, so they sent us this list. We attributed them
Speaker 1:  list to Netflix because all we need to do is tell people
Speaker 1:  where the information is coming from. And now we've satisfied our
Speaker 1:  responsibility. So we are happy to have this conversation as long as at the
Speaker 1:  end of it, we understand and can clearly communicate
Speaker 1:  to our readers where the information that we're reporting is coming from.
Speaker 1:  And it's all we want to do is say, here's the default. If you want to change
Speaker 1:  the default, you have to ask us and we will have a conversation. And by the
Speaker 1:  way, ask us like this, ask us.
Speaker 1:  And I just was not expecting it to blow. I mean, I, it was a little salty.
Speaker 1:  The post is a little salty. Cause I'm a little salty about that. We've been
Speaker 1:  thinking about this and Dieter theater. I've been talking about this for
Speaker 1:  maybe a year. We've we've been talking about changing the policy for
Speaker 1:  months. And what finally, after all of our tenure stuff, after this last
Speaker 1:  cycle of reviews, our reporters are like, yeah, when are you rolling out
Speaker 1:  this policy? You've been talking about like, cause I'm,
Speaker 1:  you know, when, when you don't have a policy to point to whenever anybody
Speaker 1:  wants to push back, like I end up on the phone right there, like my editor
Speaker 1:  will talk to you. And so then I'm like, but we have this policy, we can't
Speaker 1:  do it. And we keep having the conversation. Now she's like written down.
Speaker 1:  Every can just like tap the sign. You need to start
Speaker 5:  C like counting. See if it drops the number of calls you have
Speaker 5:  to do expenses on background.
Speaker 1:  We'll see. But they are the examples. Like, you know, the
Speaker 1:  tech companies that email us their own website, like links to their own websites
Speaker 1:  and background. It's like guys, like, what does this even mean?
Speaker 1:  I've asked, are we supposed to read? I'm supposed to not source your own
Speaker 1:  website now it's wild.
Speaker 5:  What people will just say on background in front of you you'll ask a PR person.
Speaker 5:  Oh, did you see that movie last night on background? Yes. I wasn't going
Speaker 5:  to report that. You saw a movie it's unrelated to this laptop. We're
Speaker 5:  discussing. Thank you.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. So anyway, that's, that's just a little color. It's very inside
Speaker 1:  baseball. All of it is pointed at two things. One, we want to be
Speaker 1:  transparent and how we work. So now there's an explanation of how we
Speaker 1:  work in how we're thinking about it to this problem is out of control.
Speaker 1:  So we wanted to give cover to other reporters and newsrooms to say they use
Speaker 1:  the same policy as us, which for example, our ethics policy, right?
Speaker 1:  Our ethics policy, we lifted from all things D we lifted from Walt Mossberg
Speaker 1:  and Kara Swisher. It was a model. They had printed. They were super loud
Speaker 1:  about their ethics policy when we were starting out and we were new, we were
Speaker 1:  like, we're going to use that one. So we hope people, you know, we're 10
Speaker 1:  years old. We hope people can look at our policy and build on it and use
Speaker 1:  it and refer to it and have it be a little bit of a standard. And third,
Speaker 1:  most importantly, we just want our readers to know where the information
Speaker 1:  comes from. That's it the way we think that's an important part of our
Speaker 1:  job. And I have, I've told many PR people, because people will say to
Speaker 1:  me or other reporters, well, you look really smart if you
Speaker 1:  just know this. No. And I'm like, no, I already looked,
Speaker 1:  I already looked so smart all the time. Like, I don't need your help.
Speaker 1:  Like I just want to tell them where I came from. The other thing I'll connect
Speaker 1:  at all to you is an Daytona. You have been thinking of this as
Speaker 1:  much as I have when people cheer for us because we say disclosure,
Speaker 1:  right? Like, yeah, that's our brand is being transparent. Like
Speaker 1:  we believe in that, like that's who we are. We want you to know
Speaker 1:  like, here's where we're coming from. Here's what we believe. Here's how
Speaker 1:  we do our work. And so we're just always going to hold the line on that.
Speaker 1:  And sometimes like this week, we're gonna do it a little more loudly than
Speaker 1:  the not. And we're a little more publicly than not, but just
Speaker 1:  trust me. We're kind of always
Speaker 1:  a, it's always in the background. So that's explanation. If you have more
Speaker 1:  questions, you know, we'll do our best to explain ourselves because we believe
Speaker 1:  in transparency. All right. That's it. That's it. That is the show we've
Speaker 1:  gone over. We've gone just a little bit. Thank you for
Speaker 1:  listening. Dieter's got the Tuesday episodes. It's still
Speaker 1:  still something cool. It's really cool. Really cool
Speaker 1:  subjects. I see. All right. Yeah. That's great. It'd be
Speaker 1:  Dakota. This week was the CEO of anchor, which was actually, yeah.
Speaker 1:  Anchor has a hundred people who just think about Amazon marketplace all day
Speaker 1:  long. It's 3% of the company is incredible. It's 3% of my brain too, but
Speaker 1:  it's amazing that the hire so many. So Steven Yang from anchor next
Speaker 1:  week, next week, it's Brian Chesky. The CEO of Airbnb. That conversation
Speaker 1:  was wild. That was, it's a rocking one. So that's the coder Tuesday
Speaker 1:  episodes. You can tweet at us. I'm at reckless. Dieter's at
Speaker 1:  Baclofen. Alex is Alex H Kranz. Sean is so Kane one,
Speaker 1:  correct? That's it. That's for Chester rock-n-roll
Speaker 10:  In season one of the max original series. Love life. We met
Speaker 10:  Darby Carter played by Anna Kendrick and followed her misadventures,
Speaker 10:  finding love. Now in season two, we follow Marcus.
Speaker 10:  Walk-ins a 30 something suddenly divorced literary agent in
Speaker 10:  New York city whose dating journey is filled with unexpected humor
Speaker 10:  and heartbreaking truths played by William Jackson. Harper
Speaker 10:  Marcus learns that define love again. He must first find himself
Speaker 10:  love life. Season two. Now streaming only on HBO max,
Speaker 11:  The world is changing fast. And when it comes to online banking,
Speaker 11:  capital one and it's teams of engineers are working to keep customers safe
Speaker 11:  by developing, cutting edge technology at the forefront of what's possible
Speaker 11:  capital one, develops products like a tech company using machine learning
Speaker 11:  to lead the way like the way they fight fraud or their AI powered
Speaker 11:  intelligent assistant, you know, capital one's apps and products have
Speaker 11:  won awards for some of the best real time. Personalized customer
Speaker 11:  experiences learn more@capitalone.com
Speaker 11:  slash tech.