# Transcript
ID: 0729aa80-bb24-11eb-bfb6-5fb2cbb1de7a
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Tim Cook's bad day in Epic vs Apple
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/1336462472/2828536593/s93290-US-2404s-1621644759.mp3
Description: In part 2 of this week's episode, Nilay talks with Adi Robertson about the judge's harsh questioning of Tim Cook on the last day of testimony in Epic vs Apple.
Speaker ?:  This episode of virtuos brought to you by Okta, the leading independent identity
Speaker ?:  solution, Octa provides the best in class authorization. So your customer's
Speaker ?:  and workforce can safely access what they need from anywhere they're dedicated
Speaker ?:  to building the most reliable, neutral identity platform, because it means
Speaker ?:  protecting more than a login identity is protecting people, their ideas,
Speaker ?:  their work, and their brilliance. It's protecting your future with confidence,
Speaker ?:  learn more at, okay. T a t.com. This episode, The Vergecast brought to you
Speaker ?:  by NerdWallet got money goals. NerdWallet's got your back looking for a credit
Speaker ?:  card with better cash back. NerdWallet's got tons of tools and tips to help
Speaker ?:  you find the car. And you're looking for in finally, ready to buy your first
Speaker ?:  home. NerdWallet has calculators to help you find a mortgage that works for
Speaker ?:  you. And if you want your money to work as hard as you do NerdWallet Scott
Speaker ?:  side-by-side comparisons to help you find the smartest investing account,
Speaker ?:  whatever your money goals may be. NerdWallet helps you compare and find the
Speaker ?:  smartest financial products for you.
Speaker 2:
Speaker 2:  hello and
Speaker 1:  Welcome to The Vergecast of flagship podcast has in app
Speaker 1:  purchases. This is a special parts of it. We did a whole episode
Speaker 1:  earlier about Google IO about the Mac review,
Speaker 1:  the iPad review part two, Addie Robertson's here,
Speaker 1:  and Hey, parts of you is all about the apple versus epic trial or epic
Speaker 1:  vs. Apple, I should say. And I would, I would say it backwards. It's epic
Speaker 1:  versus apple epics. The plaintiff, literally the testimony
Speaker 1:  portion of the trial wrapped up minutes ago from when you and I are
Speaker 1:  talking, there is sort of fake version of closing
Speaker 1:  arguments on Monday where both layers are just going to get asked questions
Speaker 1:  by the judge, from what I understand,
Speaker 3:  Which is probably going to be way more fun than normal closing arguments,
Speaker 3:  probably
Speaker 1:  Way more fun. Also the term everyone is using
Speaker 1:  for that closing argument is a hot
Speaker 1:  tubbing. And she's just very funny. Liz Lopatto will
Speaker 1:  be in the courtroom for the hot tubbing, but the actual
Speaker 1:  testimony, all the witnesses on the stand, all of the presentations
Speaker 1:  of evidence wrapped up today this week saw Phil Schiller,
Speaker 1:  Craig Federighi Tim Cook on the stand. There's a lot to
Speaker 1:  talk about their, but we should just start with what just happened because
Speaker 1:  the absolute end of the testimony
Speaker 1:  portion of the trial with Tim Cook on the stand was fireworks.
Speaker 1:  Like, and it just went sideways. It was a very boring for a week. Lots of
Speaker 1:  experts that we are not even talking about. Cause they were so boring and,
Speaker 1:  and the judge kind of just lit into Tim Cook. What happened to them?
Speaker 3:  Yeah. So yeah, judge Yvonne Gonzalez Rogers, who is going to be
Speaker 3:  writing the opinion on the case and who occasionally interjects with some
Speaker 3:  usually pretty interesting, but very short questions. They more or
Speaker 3:  less finished examining Tim Cook. And then judge Rogers just steps in with
Speaker 3:  the question and she's like, okay, well it seems like most of the
Speaker 3:  revenue and the app store comes from games. So what's wrong with telling
Speaker 3:  people that they can go and make in-app purchases elsewhere. And
Speaker 3:  then that just kicks off this 10 minute long discussion where she and Tim
Speaker 3:  Cook have this like surprisingly testy exchange
Speaker 3:  over whether it makes sense that once apple put like once a
Speaker 3:  developer puts something in the store, apple brings enough value that
Speaker 3:  it should get a cut of like whatever happens in that app. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  And to me, this is kind of the central
Speaker 1:  question at the heart of this trial
Speaker 1:  is who is in control of your phone and
Speaker 1:  apples Ansar kind of nakedly throughout history. And we are in control
Speaker 1:  of your phone, right? So it doesn't matter if you download Fortnite or another
Speaker 1:  app or whatever, everything that happens inside that app,
Speaker 1:  Apple wants a part of it wants to in intermediate
Speaker 1:  your relationship to those developers in a huge variety of
Speaker 1:  ways for a huge variety of reasons. But the most important one
Speaker 1:  is if you buy something in an app, apple wants its cut. And
Speaker 1:  what struck me about this exchange is
Speaker 1:  that this is the whole trial. And we've heard all of these
Speaker 1:  reasons for apple to be in the middle of you and, and app
Speaker 1:  developer, privacy security, malware protection app
Speaker 1:  review content, review, naked bananas, the whole range of
Speaker 1:  reasons that apple should be in the middle. And when the judge,
Speaker 1:  when it cook, he was just like, no, we got to monetize our IP like
Speaker 1:  straight up. He was like, this is how we make the money. And if we don't
Speaker 1:  make the money this way, we'd have to figure out another way to make money.
Speaker 1:  And there was no pretense. All of the other stuff was out the window. Did
Speaker 1:  that, did you hear that? As clearly as I did cause it, I was
Speaker 1:  just, you know, if you've been listening to the trial, it's kind of a drone,
Speaker 1:  right? It's just like a blow quality zoom call in the background. I would
Speaker 1:  like to commend you for being able to live tweet through it as attentively
Speaker 1:  as you have in. Cause it has been a drone and this was like a jaw drop moment
Speaker 1:  for me that the judge came at cook and Tim Cook's answer was, this is how
Speaker 1:  we make the money. No pretense.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, no, it was because this and come right after a day where it was
Speaker 3:  basically, and like, I don't want to say inexplicably cause I get it. But
Speaker 3:  it was all about privacy in a completely tangential way.
Speaker 3:  It was like, okay, well what if someone doesn't want to do business with
Speaker 3:  apple because they deal with Chinese authorities and therefore
Speaker 3:  you will have the, and they just like, go on and on. And then there's
Speaker 3:  yeah. There's sudden exchange. And he's like, well, yeah, this is, we need
Speaker 3:  to leverage our IP. And then judge Rogers is like, well it seems like
Speaker 3:  gamers are subsidizing everybody else on the platform because they're spending
Speaker 3:  all this money and Tim Cook's like, yeah, well this is the business model
Speaker 1:  We pay. Yeah. And I, we wrote a story home. Gartenberg wrote a story for
Speaker 1:  us in 2019. If you remember a few years ago, apple made this big shift in
Speaker 1:  how it presented itself to investors that the future of its revenue growth
Speaker 1:  was services. And the services revenue are going to be a big
Speaker 1:  driver of Apple's growth because they had already sold as
Speaker 1:  many offenses they could sell. Right. And then there were no more co there
Speaker 1:  were no more countries to unlock. There are no more expensive models to sell.
Speaker 1:  Like the base of I-phones was out in the world. It's a huge number of hard
Speaker 1:  to move the needle. They were going to monetize the phone more aggressively.
Speaker 1:  And they're pretty open about this. Tim Cook said this on calls when high
Speaker 1:  and dug into it. And 2019, it was a pretty
Speaker 1:  obvious that the biggest chunk of services revenue, the app store and the
Speaker 1:  biggest chunk of that revenue was like candy crush,
Speaker 1:  whales, like people buying stuff and candy crush or, and
Speaker 1:  in Fortnite and, and other games was just the way that
Speaker 1:  apple was going to monetize. And that's a pretty even
Speaker 1:  just explaining it here, it's a pretty winding road, right? Like you gotta
Speaker 1:  get there. And it seemed like the judge clocked it instantly. And it was
Speaker 1:  like, but this is pretty unfair. And she was like, at some point she's like
Speaker 1:  the gamers are subsidizing Wells Fargo, which is
Speaker 1:  like almost to me. And like, it's this close to a meme.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Yeah. Judge Rogers gamers rise
Speaker 3:  up.
Speaker 1:  H I just was not expecting her to go. There
Speaker 1:  was throughout this trial. So this is day 15 of the
Speaker 1:  trial. But in the courtroom, it has seemed like epic has done kind of a
Speaker 1:  meandering bad job that judge
Speaker 1:  Rogers is kind of like unimpressed. And then she just like came,
Speaker 1:  just came out, swinging right at the end.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. No, At the Epic has really, it seems like this whole week, their strategy
Speaker 3:  is just, let's see if we can make apple look like hypocrites. So like
Speaker 3:  they listed out, they just went to the app store and search for
Speaker 3:  BDSM and just print out pages and pages of like
Speaker 3:  search results and then made Phil Schiller, like read
Speaker 3:  them. And so it was just all these things that are meant to show, okay, well,
Speaker 3:  they're not actually holding up their standards. This privacy thing is a
Speaker 3:  pretext. It's not like you don't need the security. And then
Speaker 3:  judge her and hers just, yeah. Actually asked about the substance of the
Speaker 3:  competition law and like the substance of like, what are people actually
Speaker 3:  competing on when they are in the app store and what kind of services
Speaker 3:  apple actually
Speaker 1:  Selling. Yeah. And a one of the, again, and just in this
Speaker 1:  exchange, literally there was more action in this last 10 or 15
Speaker 1:  minutes. This maybe entire previous 15 days apple has
Speaker 1:  repeatedly brought up this small business program where they lowered
Speaker 1:  rates from 30% to 15% for developers to make less than a
Speaker 1:  million dollars a year in revenue is evidence of competition and
Speaker 1:  evidence and them lowering rates. And the judge says the issue with the
Speaker 1:  small business program, from what I've seen is it wasn't really the result
Speaker 1:  of competition. That's a result of the pressure you're feeling from investigations,
Speaker 1:  from lawsuits, not competition. And then there's the back and
Speaker 1:  forth and home cook says after we did our 15, there was
Speaker 1:  competition, Google dropped their 15%
Speaker 1:  and the judge has flat out, says, I understand
Speaker 1:  perhaps when Google changed its price, that was competition, but your
Speaker 1:  action, wasn't the result of competition. And that
Speaker 1:  is, I don't know, man. We could have like David and
Speaker 1:  Mark Hanson on the show. That's what he would say. Right? Like the angriest
Speaker 1:  developers in the ecosystem say exactly this and the judges
Speaker 1:  repeating what we have heard for years now. I think what I just don't
Speaker 1:  know is what, what that will lead to, right? Like
Speaker 1:  these were skeptical harsh questions, but who knows,
Speaker 3:  It's funny that the trial is kind of proceeding along completely
Speaker 3:  different. Like there are two completely different fights that Apple's fighting.
Speaker 3:  One is we shouldn't have to let people side load apps, which they can
Speaker 3:  like make, I think a, probably a pretty strong case for, and it's, it was
Speaker 3:  a huge giant uphill ask. So they've got this entire
Speaker 3:  thread about, well, this is the protection that we bring. This is
Speaker 3:  like why our system is secure. And there was all of
Speaker 3:  that. And that's flashy. And then there's this entire separate question of
Speaker 3:  like in app payments and even, and things that are like, even smaller than
Speaker 3:  that, like steering or anti steering rules, which the judge seems super interested
Speaker 3:  in that are really specifically about what happens when you've already
Speaker 3:  installed an app. And you're a regular user of that app. And how do you pay
Speaker 3:  within that? And like, how do you see your payment options inside that
Speaker 1:  Those rules are again, the sort of like site we
Speaker 1:  talked about this last week on the show, but that decides switching here
Speaker 1:  is like pretty fascinating that the law firm that epic has retained
Speaker 1:  crevasse just won a gigantic Supreme
Speaker 1:  court case about anti steering rules for American express, where they
Speaker 1:  protected the anti steering rules, where American express was allowed
Speaker 1:  to prohibit and merchants from nudging people and to
Speaker 1:  other credit cards. And in this case that same law firm is on epic side
Speaker 1:  saying you should let us nudge people and other payments, which is like
Speaker 1:  deeply fascinating inside baseball. But I think the judge
Speaker 1:  is looking at all of that. You know, one of the big
Speaker 1:  lines and the American express opinion from the Supreme court was this market
Speaker 1:  is hyper competitive. There are lots of credit cards. They're all fighting
Speaker 1:  for you all the time. So these provisions are not unfair. It's hyper
Speaker 1:  competitive here. And the judges like others, just no
Speaker 1:  competition. There's another section here where she's like, I'm
Speaker 1:  looking at evidence and the record that says survey developers, 39% of your
Speaker 1:  developers are and are dissatisfied. How are you feeling any motivation to
Speaker 1:  address their needs? And then she says, it doesn't seem like you feel any
Speaker 1:  pressure or competition to change the manner that you act in to address the
Speaker 1:  concerns of developers. And that's like, yeah, she just
Speaker 1:  clocked it. And I D I don't think Tim, I've
Speaker 1:  not yet heard. And apple executive, I rare you
Speaker 1:  rarely hear an apple executive on their back foot ever, but in this trial,
Speaker 1:  they've all been very confident, very direct in
Speaker 1:  control. And I think Tim Cook just seemed like on his back foot because he
Speaker 1:  wasn't expecting this.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, no. I mean, I don't think most people were not expecting and it was
Speaker 3:  really refreshing. Like, I'm really glad we got
Speaker 3:  this.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. And my theory with what epics again, and I don't think epic has done
Speaker 1:  a good job here. They certainly haven't laid out a case that like a normal
Speaker 1:  person would understand. I think it's remarkable that the judge has clocked
Speaker 1:  it and then on this. But my sense has always been, they know they're going
Speaker 1:  to appeal this. If epic wins, apple is going to appeal and then they're going
Speaker 1:  to appeal again. And then they're going to feel a third time to the Supreme
Speaker 1:  court if apple wins Epix. And I do that same thing. And
Speaker 1:  once you're on appeal, once you're out of the trial court, into the appellate
Speaker 1:  court, you cannot introduce new facts. So there's a part of me that
Speaker 1:  says, oh, epic is just trying to stuff as much information
Speaker 1:  into the record of this case so that they have it
Speaker 1:  should some appellate court judge three years from now be
Speaker 1:  like, did anyone ever do a study and have it offers are happy or not? And
Speaker 1:  they just like have it. And that I think has led to like a
Speaker 1:  very odd sort of mishmash of
Speaker 1:  ideas.
Speaker 3:  Judge Rogers also periodically makes note of the fact that,
Speaker 3:  like, there are a bunch of people watching this trial in public that there,
Speaker 3:  you know, she doesn't say this, but there are like YouTube rips of the
Speaker 3:  stream that I think that there is also a question of how much of this stuff
Speaker 3:  is just being played out, sort of for public opinion and for
Speaker 3:  regulators. And like George Rogers has been made
Speaker 3:  very clear. She is like, not particularly compelled. It seems by all of the
Speaker 3:  anecdotes that are brought up about whether developers are and, or are
Speaker 3:  not satisfied, but they are a thing that if
Speaker 3:  you're just trying to get the word out about whether your company is good,
Speaker 3:  there a thing that you put out
Speaker 1:  There. Yeah. And it's funny that one of the
Speaker 1:  recurring themes here is like an apple witness will get onstage and then
Speaker 1:  ethics lawyers will be like, why aren't any developers standing up for
Speaker 1:  you? And there's no way. And so that
Speaker 1:  question, and then Tuesday in real time, apple tried
Speaker 1:  to ensure snap had its developer event yesterday. They're
Speaker 1:  releasing a bunch of stuff in real time, Evan
Speaker 1:  Spiegel was on CNBC and said, I'm happy to pay the 30% fee to
Speaker 1:  apple. And like, literally they tried to show that story
Speaker 1:  to Tim Cook, like minutes after it was published. And they're like, you
Speaker 1:  cannot do that. Yes. And I
Speaker 1:  mean, just, just wild. So that was cook. And I would
Speaker 1:  say, if not for that last 15 minutes of cook, I might
Speaker 1:  take away of this would have been epic is going to lose at trial. They
Speaker 1:  know it, but we've got 10 years of appeals to come.
Speaker 1:  Right? Like, is that, is that kinda where you were?
Speaker 3:  I don't know. My take was more like, it seems like she judged Rogers
Speaker 3:  is genuinely interested in the anti steering stuff. My take would have
Speaker 3:  been probably developers have to be able
Speaker 3:  to put a link to their websites
Speaker 1:  And apps. Yeah. And tell people about the rules. This
Speaker 1:  is like a, the John Gruber take is, it is insane to
Speaker 1:  impose rules and people that they are not allowed to talk about it. So
Speaker 3:  Yeah, I was, I've kind of figured that that might come up no matter what
Speaker 3:  it has seemed pretty clear from the start that like, Apple's not going to
Speaker 3:  have to let third party stores on iOS and the arguments
Speaker 3:  about payment processing. It's a little harder for me to parse, but yeah,
Speaker 3:  this seemed more promising for them than I would have
Speaker 3:  guessed.
Speaker 1:  My, I don't know. You never know the judges,
Speaker 1:  like she's pushing the witness. She's got precedent to
Speaker 1:  write too. She's constrained in a lot of ways. Judges also, don't like being
Speaker 1:  overturned, who knows what she's going to do, who knows how she's going to
Speaker 1:  rule, but I could see her saying, you have to allow third-party
Speaker 1:  payment processors. Right. And we're not gonna do sideloading. We're not
Speaker 1:  gonna all, all this other stuff, but you should
Speaker 1:  give people a choice. And if your version is actually better than they will
Speaker 1:  pick it because that's competition. And that seems like a very
Speaker 1:  narrow ruling for her to make, without wandering into
Speaker 1:  sideloading and privacy issues and all of this other stuff. Like you can
Speaker 1:  just have another button, maybe I'm being too optimistic.
Speaker 3:  It is funny to me that she seems like she has complete disdain for this entire
Speaker 3:  business of like micro transactions that she just keeps bringing up yet.
Speaker 3:  It seems like you just want to make impulse buys.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. It's like kids. You want kids to spend money that they don't have that's
Speaker 1:  that's your business. I think that's response. It's
Speaker 1:  entirely fair. It's Apple's own TV show.
Speaker 1:  Mythic quest has like a, like a C plot
Speaker 1:  about whether they should make a mobile game and on Apple's own show, they're
Speaker 1:  like, you're just trying to fleece middle aged women out of money on the
Speaker 1:  potty. Like that's Apple's own shows take on mobile
Speaker 1:  games. We should actually write about that show. It is a very subversive
Speaker 1:  for apple to make a show that hates the computer game industry as
Speaker 1:  much as it does. So that's cook let's bracket
Speaker 1:  cook. So that's what happened at the end. That's like the most interesting
Speaker 1:  thing that's happened this week. We heard from Schiller. I
Speaker 1:  feel like we can just get through Schiller's testimony pretty quick. He was
Speaker 1:  great on the stand. Very confident he's Apple's marketing guy.
Speaker 1:  You weren't going to get him off message and made apple
Speaker 3:  Seem fun. He was like, I invented the click wheel. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Like there's not a lot to say. They tried, they tried to come at him a little
Speaker 1:  bit with a message. They tried to come and cook a little bit with our message.
Speaker 1:  I thought we were going to hear a lot about iMessage lock-in in this trial.
Speaker 1:  And we just did not. Yeah. It's really weird. Yeah. I mean, it was just a
Speaker 1:  part like there's a lot of evidence and the world that like, I don't know,
Speaker 1:  teenagers want to have iPhones because if they have a green bubble, they
Speaker 1:  get bullied. It seems like a thing you can
Speaker 1:  say, like you put in the record to say, it's hard to switch her and I-phone
Speaker 1:  and epic just didn't do it.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. And, and to be clear, I don't mean that, like, I think that's a slam
Speaker 3:  dunk, but I think it was way stronger and more interesting than a lot of
Speaker 3:  the stuff epic did end up actually bringing.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Unsure. The judge has friends who are green bubbles and she's
Speaker 1:  like, what up get? And I feel like it's a very
Speaker 1:  relatable thing, but epic didn't pursue it very much, but
Speaker 1:  Schiller was good. Like I think he, he just handled
Speaker 1:  Epic's questioning very well. He's very S again, he's Apple's and marketing
Speaker 1:  guy has been for a long time. Very smooth, very
Speaker 1:  composed.
Speaker ?:  This episode, The Vergecast brought to you by E Cornell. If he wants to advance
Speaker ?:  your career without stepping out of your job, look no further than today's
Speaker ?:  sponsor IE Cornell with over 120 online certificates in
Speaker ?:  today's most in demand skills, taking a program with a Cornell is a great
Speaker ?:  way to better your professional self. So he wants to further your career
Speaker ?:  work in your professional expertise and preserve the strides you've already
Speaker ?:  made. Try equal NL visit and cornell.com and use code
Speaker ?:  Vergecast for 20% off certificate programs. When you enroll
Speaker ?:  more and more of these days, we are conducting our everyday business remotely.
Speaker ?:  And while there will always be a place for doing things the old way, the
Speaker ?:  convenience that comes with online, learning changes, everything it's even
Speaker ?:  changing. The way we learn with Equinox, you can gain skills and your field
Speaker ?:  without interrupting your career. Equinox offers over 120
Speaker ?:  online certificate programs to choose from. And they're flexible. So while
Speaker ?:  you're learning about data science, project management, or web design, your
Speaker ?:  career doesn't get put on hold equals 100% online classes,
Speaker ?:  feature coursework that can be done anywhere any time and most certificate
Speaker ?:  programs can be completed in two to four months. And while some other online
Speaker ?:  programs might lack that personal interaction and feedback from instructors,
Speaker ?:  Equinox doesn't sacrifice it. Of course, these are developed by Cornell university
Speaker ?:  faculty and you'll enjoy meaningful conversations about coursework with instructors
Speaker ?:  who have a wealth of knowledge in their field. Plus you get worthwhile discussion
Speaker ?:  with peers, from industry, from all over the world. Take the next step
Speaker ?:  with a professional certificate from Cornell university, visit ecornell.com
Speaker ?:  today and use code of Vergecast for 20% off certificate programs.
Speaker ?:  When you enroll Let's get real the tech world, doesn't always
Speaker ?:  like to keep it simple from over-hyped products to constant sales pitches
Speaker ?:  and endless jargon shopping for quality electronics can be overwhelming,
Speaker ?:  but it doesn't have to be cut through the usual BS with high sense, high
Speaker ?:  census, the straight talking electronics brand that offers clarity and quality
Speaker ?:  over confusion because let's get real. The most important thing about a great
Speaker ?:  TV is that it's actually a great TV with all the features you
Speaker ?:  love, like their new ULE D series, whether you're watching movies with the
Speaker ?:  kids and enjoying a date night or comfort, watching that show for the million
Speaker ?:  time, high sense brings you an unmatched 4k TV
Speaker ?:  experience and with a range of sizes, their you led series is bringing
Speaker ?:  premium products to the masses.
Speaker 4:  We can sit here and tell you all about the awesome features that come with
Speaker 4:  high sense TVs features like quantum dot color HDR, 10 plus, and Dolby
Speaker 4:  Atmos, but all you really need to know is that high sense offers
Speaker 4:  unbeatable quality and unbelievable prices. Forget the
Speaker 4:  jargon and get real to learn more, visit high sense.com
Speaker 4:  today. That's high sense.com high sense. Let's get
Speaker 4:  real S
Speaker 1:  Craig Federighi. That testimony
Speaker 1:  was also to me, just like very revealing of how apple
Speaker 1:  thinks of it's customers and what happens on the phone.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, so he was basically there to counter
Speaker 3:  epics, last expert, witness James Mickens,
Speaker 3:  the like computer science guy who was talking about why it's
Speaker 3:  really reasonable like that. You should be able to open up the store
Speaker 3:  that all of the really important security occurs on device, that you
Speaker 3:  have systems like code signing that you can deploy on the
Speaker 3:  Mac that you can also deploy on iOS. And then Craig Federighi gets up and
Speaker 3:  he's like, no, that's completely dumb. That is
Speaker 3:  not how any of this works.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I mean, that all makes sense. And these
Speaker 1:  are Grealy hard problems, like is good
Speaker 1:  that apple has in control of things on the phone at the scale they're in
Speaker 1:  control. And then, because if there is some road malware that
Speaker 1:  hits every iPhone, apple does have a kill switch and, and turn it off.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. And I think that epic has not made a super compelling case that
Speaker 3:  the iPhone is not actually more secure than a lot of
Speaker 3:  these other platforms. Like that's just kind of the trade-off that you make
Speaker 3:  with an iPhone.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I mean, there's been a lot of conflicting evidence
Speaker 1:  presented about the relative security of Android versus
Speaker 1:  iPhone. There has been dueling study
Speaker 1:  is it's funny, we're talking just after we did our IO
Speaker 1:  episode, you know, Google stood up at IO and said, Android is more secure
Speaker 1:  than anything. Samsung will tell you that knocks on. And, and
Speaker 1:  Samsung Android phone is the most secure thing on any phone possible
Speaker 1:  ever dueling size. And to me, he just came back and
Speaker 1:  watched.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, no, it seems like it. And they're also like, they're just kind of disagreeing
Speaker 3:  about what counts as security like that was Apple's big thing was that, well,
Speaker 3:  if you just look at code or zero days or something like that than malware,
Speaker 3:  then maybe it's kind of a wash. But if you look at it's really
Speaker 3:  easy to get something like, that's trying to scam you through a
Speaker 3:  third-party store that like, we're going to focus on social
Speaker 3:  engineering. So yeah, a lot of it was
Speaker 3:  complicated.
Speaker 1:  And then I don't think there's an answer there. Like it is a complicated
Speaker 1:  subject. Do you think the iPhone faces more state
Speaker 1:  sponsored zero day attacks than Android?
Speaker 1:  There's no way to know, but we also know that the answer is, yes,
Speaker 1:  it faces a lot of state sponsored zero day attacks. Are
Speaker 1:  there more scam apps in one store versus another hard to tell, but there
Speaker 1:  are a lot of scam apps and all of these review processes are supposed to
Speaker 1:  catch it and protect it. So a wash, but that I think
Speaker 1:  brings any fresh Tesla's and her nose, like the other
Speaker 1:  comparison to make is two windows on the Mac. And so epic tried to
Speaker 1:  come at Federighi about the Mac. And that was, to me,
Speaker 1:  just, just wild that the comparisons he
Speaker 1:  was making of the analogies he was using.
Speaker 3:  So the Mac is like a car it's
Speaker 3:  I'm you can drive it off road is what he'd said.
Speaker 3:  And you have to be really carefully trained to use it. He did
Speaker 3:  not say that you need a license, but apparently it's really like, you need
Speaker 3:  to be a specialist. You have to understand. And you knew that you were getting
Speaker 3:  into this thing, you were buying this metal death scene, the
Speaker 3:  Mac and, and the iPhone and the iPad. They're
Speaker 3:  great because babies can use them literally. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  I mean, literally he says with ILS, we were saved. We able to create something
Speaker 1:  where children even infants can operate an iOS devices and be safe in doing
Speaker 1:  so this is also complicated,
Speaker 1:  right? One of the great things about iOS devices and
Speaker 1:  Android devices sort of out of the box is that it's a very
Speaker 1:  hard to get malware and bad apps on them. And federally
Speaker 1:  even said, we have trained iOS users to just
Speaker 1:  download apps with abandon because you can't do too much
Speaker 1:  damage. Okay. On the flip side, it's
Speaker 1:  like, what if you do think that you are
Speaker 1:  capable of operating your max safely should not be able
Speaker 1:  to operate my iPhone that way. Like, there's just like a big question
Speaker 1:  in there. And it's like, what if I don't want to be a baby?
Speaker 3:  Yeah. And it's on one hand. It is okay. Look,
Speaker 3:  I, I have my phone and I have my computer. I have both these
Speaker 3:  devices and they serve different purposes. And if I have a
Speaker 3:  computer I'm perfectly happy to like install software on the
Speaker 3:  computer and use my phone as a lockdown, like little lock
Speaker 3:  box. The thing that's frustrating to me is that
Speaker 3:  also like apple and a lot of other companies see mobile as the
Speaker 3:  future of computing. Like they just see that as the future of what the computer
Speaker 3:  is. And that's not really the future of like, if you think of the
Speaker 3:  iPhone as a supplementary device, then I understand where they're coming
Speaker 3:  from. If you think of it as the future of computing, I don't know that I
Speaker 3:  want that to be the future of computing.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. And again, this is part two around chest Dieter. And I just
Speaker 1:  spent, I don't know, six hours talking about his iPad pro review. And this
Speaker 1:  is what we talked about that apple sees the iPad pro, which
Speaker 1:  runs iPad of us, which is basically ILS is the
Speaker 1:  future, their future product. And even other like updating the max and
Speaker 1:  they bought new chips. Every time they talk about the iPad, do you see them
Speaker 1:  just burst with pride that they've invented the computer in the future? And
Speaker 1:  it is as locked down as an iOS device.
Speaker 1:  And I just, I was just reading this quote from Federighi Mac users,
Speaker 1:  expected degree of flexibility, and it's useful to what they do because some
Speaker 1:  of them are software developers. Some of them are pros running their unique
Speaker 1:  tools and having that power as a part of it, this
Speaker 1:  implies that software developers and pros running their own
Speaker 1:  tools should not use iOS devices. And that
Speaker 1:  is, has no correlation to how they talk about those
Speaker 1:  products. And there's just a disconnect. I
Speaker 1:  keep coming back to it. Apple really thinks
Speaker 1:  that it is always in control of your phone, this
Speaker 1:  computer that you have in your pocket all the time, kind of always
Speaker 1:  belongs to apple. And some people can pay. Like I hear this when
Speaker 1:  I listen to, and I get the emails, some people are paying apple for
Speaker 1:  that, but some people are paying apple for a bunch of other stuff and getting
Speaker 1:  that as part of the deal and with no way to turn it off. And I, I just think
Speaker 1:  that's really strange.
Speaker 3:  And also just, I don't know, it's weird if you try to extend, if you try
Speaker 3:  to think if every computing device in my life worked like the
Speaker 3:  iPhone, that would feel completely bizarre. Like if I
Speaker 3:  installed a piece of software on my Mac
Speaker 3:  and then anything I bought within that software or anything I did with that
Speaker 3:  software, having to go through some kind of centralized apple system, that
Speaker 3:  seems really weird to me. Like it doesn't necessarily, I kind of
Speaker 3:  get like costs on a phone that seems
Speaker 3:  intuitive just because it's a thing that's happened so much, but if you extend
Speaker 3:  it to other devices, that seems really strange and intrusive.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. And I, this obviously comes straight to the Mac app
Speaker 1:  store and how apple has that facility on the Mac. I
Speaker 1:  will tell you, we've heard from a lot of golfers over the year. And so they
Speaker 1:  do not love the Mac app store. There's just a lot of reasons to not use it
Speaker 1:  to not be in it. Chief among them are all the complaints we hear about iOS.
Speaker 1:  They don't get to own their customer. They don't get to do updates. They
Speaker 1:  do free trials, all of a social life, but federate, he was like the
Speaker 1:  level of malware on the Mac. We don't find it
Speaker 1:  acceptable. And if we use the Mac security model on the
Speaker 1:  iPhone with all those devices, all of that value, it would get run over to
Speaker 1:  a degree dramatically worse than is already happening on the Mac. iOS
Speaker 1:  has a dramatically higher bar for consumer protection. The Mac is not meeting
Speaker 1:  that bar today. That is such a just dire evaluation of
Speaker 1:  what the Mac is. I've been trying
Speaker 3:  To not take all of this too seriously, just because this is the thing you
Speaker 3:  say in a trial. Like you have to be in a trial, you have to say trial things
Speaker 3:  that make sense for your argument, like how we've had 50 different definitions
Speaker 3:  of a game. And I'm probably pretty sure that if you asked him Sweeney, like
Speaker 3:  in a bar, can you play like, describe your platonic ideal of a
Speaker 3:  game. He'd probably say something different than what he says and trial that's
Speaker 3:  fair, but it's still, it's really grim.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I, I have struggled to sort of
Speaker 1:  balance it out as you're talking about, right. It's the trial and they're
Speaker 1:  saying it, they're also under oath. There's a level of, are we
Speaker 1:  evaluating this for the trial and, and just making the arguments are going
Speaker 1:  to move on and then they're just mercenaries and it says, the next thing
Speaker 1:  they need to say, or is this how they really feel? And I, to
Speaker 1:  me, Tim Cook, when being pushed on why he has to lock
Speaker 1:  down in at purchases saying, this is how we
Speaker 1:  monetize our software development and for the phone, that is as real as it
Speaker 1:  gets, right? There's none of this bluster about malware security. It
Speaker 1:  was just, this is our business model and we're sticking to it. We think it's
Speaker 1:  fair. And then all this stuff of federal and private and, and
Speaker 1:  securities, that's all of the distractions around it. And I I'm wondering
Speaker 1:  how much of the judge has bought the distraction versus like being
Speaker 1:  centered honed in on the business model
Speaker 1:  question.
Speaker ?:  When it comes to tech, you want the latest and greatest, but there's definitely
Speaker ?:  something to be said for time-tested design that works with everything. And
Speaker ?:  that will last for years, Baird, Winthrop, CEO, and founder of American
Speaker ?:  giant grew up with a sweatshirt from the fifties that his father gave him
Speaker ?:  today. It's still in his closet and it looks better than ever. So he set
Speaker ?:  out to recreate a timeless classic. That's the thinking behind the American
Speaker ?:  giant classic full zip hoodie. They obsessed over every detail, both functional
Speaker ?:  and aesthetic. So you'll be obsessed with it too. They even brought in a
Speaker ?:  formal apple, industrial designer to help perfect. The design American shine
Speaker ?:  hoodies are built with a custom design heavyweight cotton fleece, locally
Speaker ?:  grown in sewn in North Carolina. And they're made to last with a durable,
Speaker ?:  double lined hood and reinforced elbow patches. Plus they added side panels
Speaker ?:  for increased mobility and a slim body skimming fit, but most it's
Speaker ?:  comfortable. American giant is committed to reviving local manufacturing
Speaker ?:  and they believe that all it takes is one quality piece to set any standard.
Speaker ?:  If your capsule wardrobe has room for only one hoodie, make it one you'll
Speaker ?:  love for a long time to come get your classic full zip hoodie at American
Speaker ?:  desk, giant.com today, and use promo code verge for
Speaker ?:  15% off your first order. That's 15% off when you use
Speaker ?:  code verge@american-giant.com. What secrets do
Speaker ?:  matchmakers have up their sleeves to find the perfect match, some consult
Speaker ?:  with the stars. Others will listen to what you say you want and read between
Speaker ?:  the lines. When you're talking about finding the right candidate to fill
Speaker ?:  a job, indeed has their own set of tools to help you find the perfect fit,
Speaker ?:  take their skills test feature. You can use it to measure more than 130 different
Speaker ?:  skills and prospective hires, including hard skills, personality tests, and
Speaker ?:  work samples. Indeed says these tests reduce hiring times by
Speaker ?:  27% or their instant match feature, which delivers quality
Speaker ?:  matches over 80% of the time for your sponsored job post with indeed,
Speaker ?:  you can get a shortlist of quality candidates whose resumes match and job
Speaker ?:  description. Then you can schedule a video interviews to see if a natural
Speaker ?:  work and you only pay for the ones who meet your must have qualities. Indeed
Speaker ?:  helps you match the right candidate to the job fast and easy. Get the
Speaker ?:  $75 credit@indeed.com slash The Vergecast
Speaker ?:  offer valid through June 30th terms and conditions
Speaker ?:  apply.
Speaker 1:  Okay. We've had a couple of minutes left. I want to end. We can't end without
Speaker 1:  talking about further ridiculous definitions of
Speaker 1:  what a game is central to this trial. Walk me through what
Speaker 1:  happened with roadblocks because they, they like
Speaker 1:  changed our whole website and they changed it back and like show. And I got
Speaker 1:  to do a big smile, like what happened?
Speaker 3:  Okay. So roadblocks is, I'm going to try to describe this in the broadest
Speaker 3:  terms possible. It is a piece of software and
Speaker 3:  people can use like a language in which you
Speaker 3:  write rules to make things that people can interact
Speaker 3:  with. And they upload that to the central software and people can
Speaker 3:  launch those pieces of user created software
Speaker 3:  from inside roadblocks, the software, and
Speaker 3:  then the people who create those years of generated experiences can
Speaker 3:  sell things around that. And so you have game studios that can
Speaker 3:  basically pay their employees by selling in app purchases. Through these
Speaker 3:  things, typically call them games and roadblocks of classes. He came in this
Speaker 3:  store and the early in the trial, there was a lot of confusion
Speaker 3:  about this because apparently around 2014, somebody
Speaker 3:  actually like pointed out that look, robots, look, it looks a lot like a
Speaker 3:  store within a store that you just, it's not even like second life you go
Speaker 3:  in and you wander around. It's like, you get a list of things and you launch
Speaker 3:  the thing and the thing launches and it's a game. And so they passed it to
Speaker 3:  the review board. Apparently just nothing happened. I just kept going and
Speaker 3:  it's very successful now. And so they're one of their apps
Speaker 3:  to review executives was like, yeah, well, the thing is the things inside
Speaker 3:  roadblocks, those aren't games. He also said, roadblocks itself, wasn't a
Speaker 3:  game which has its own weird thing. And he's like, yeah, games have a beginning
Speaker 3:  and end and there's challenges in place. And then this was
Speaker 3:  reiterated a couple of times it's was like, yeah, this was like a Minecraft
Speaker 3:  map. And it doesn't introduce new code. And then
Speaker 3:  roadblocks, which like this, isn't weird for it
Speaker 3:  necessarily. It's been positioning itself as a metaverse. It's called these
Speaker 3:  things experiences a long time, but it just went and
Speaker 3:  like control, like find and replace game
Speaker 3:  with experience all over its website and like its apps, the
Speaker 3:  games tab became the discover tab. The
Speaker 3:  experiences you creating a new game became creating a new experience
Speaker 3:  and sort of max players, you of max people, they'd just like wiped everything
Speaker 3:  game related from their sites. And then Phil Schiller came to the
Speaker 3:  stand days after this had happened. And they're like, so
Speaker 3:  roadblocks, what do you think roadblocks is? And you're like, well, in my
Speaker 3:  opinion, it's a game. And you're like mugged. Yeah. I mean, I'm not in court,
Speaker 3:  so I can't see this, but yes,
Speaker 1:  You like, I was in the room and she was like a huge grin on Schiller's
Speaker 1:  face when this happened. Yeah. Amazing.
Speaker 3:  And then the distinction he said is that there's
Speaker 3:  probably games inside of it, but the games are not developed by developers.
Speaker 3:  They created by creators because
Speaker 3:  developers, they're making a thing. They're like coding and
Speaker 3:  independent app that like goes on your phone. It could
Speaker 3:  introduce malicious code. Apple has to review it. But these things they're
Speaker 3:  created, they are using a sort of sandbox that
Speaker 3:  roadblocks creates like a scripted sandbox. And we know all the code that
Speaker 3:  can run and roadblocks. And therefore, if you're building this thing inside
Speaker 3:  roadblocks, we know that it's safe. Sure. Which then raises a bunch more
Speaker 3:  questions like, okay, then what's the problem with the Microsoft, like
Speaker 3:  with X cloud, which is basically video. And then they have answers to those
Speaker 3:  questions, but it gets complicated. But the point is, I kind of feel for
Speaker 3:  roadblocks, they have gotten gone through a real roller
Speaker 3:  coaster.
Speaker 1:  I mean, I think one of your tweets was like, apple is all over the map on
Speaker 1:  the roadblocks question. Like every apple witness had a different
Speaker 1:  answer and then robots itself
Speaker 3:  Usually conflicting. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  And she started all in place. And then roadblocks itself is older than the
Speaker 1:  app store, like in the
Speaker 1:  iPhone. It's very good. I think
Speaker 1:  my favorite part of all, this is that your story was red. It was a red to
Speaker 1:  Schiller.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. It was brought up and then he read one paragraph of
Speaker 3:  it.
Speaker 1:  I mean, our, just the fact that we're so intertwined in this, but like, and
Speaker 1:  he's being too humble about it. Like they T they brought
Speaker 1:  up her story in court and had S Phil Schiller
Speaker 1:  read a paragraph. Addie's verge story about roadblocks
Speaker 1:  changing the word game to experience, which is just for
Speaker 1:  talk about a metaphor. It's like, we're just in it. Like, we're just constantly
Speaker 1:  just really strange. Okay. So on
Speaker 1:  Monday, the judge is going to have the lawyers from both sides.
Speaker 1:  She's going to hot tub them and ask both sides questions at once. That is
Speaker 1:  the quote unquote closing argument. When are we expecting a
Speaker 1:  decision before
Speaker 3:  August 13th? Probably.
Speaker 1:  So August 12th at best.
Speaker 3:  So we're going to have the, they're going to file final briefs next Friday
Speaker 3:  by next Friday. So it's definitely not before then. And then after that,
Speaker 3:  there was a jury selection for another trial and like early
Speaker 3:  June, and then this opinion could be
Speaker 3:  hundreds of pages long. There's a bunch of evidence to consider. And,
Speaker 3:  but we're hopefully going to get it before mid
Speaker 3:  August.
Speaker 1:  Okay. Well, it has been a long and strange three
Speaker 1:  weeks. I cannot believe that you've lived tweeted all day every day,
Speaker 1:  one more day, just one more day to go. But it has been, I don't
Speaker 1:  know, it's just a very revealing trial. Like I hear what you're saying. That
Speaker 1:  sometimes you say what you need to say at trial, but Apple's attitude
Speaker 1:  about what the phone is and their
Speaker 1:  constant relationship to you. For example, I think
Speaker 1:  cook use the best buy analogy again today. Why would
Speaker 1:  Apple ask best buy to publish a lower price
Speaker 1:  for the phone and best buy? Yeah, I get it the best way would probably say
Speaker 1:  no, but in Fortnite makes
Speaker 1:  no sense that like, once you take the iPhone home, it is covered with ads
Speaker 1:  for apple services. Apple itself will be like, it's time to buy a new phone.
Speaker 1:  You can buy it directly from us on your phone. They
Speaker 1:  are totally in control of that purchase experience. And they want to extend
Speaker 1:  it into every other app and extend that control. And every other
Speaker 1:  app, if this case taught me anything, if this trial taught me
Speaker 1:  anything, it's that all the way up to Tim Cook, that is their
Speaker 1:  belief that third-party apps are just extensions of
Speaker 1:  ILS, not other applications that run on top of the
Speaker 1:  phone. And I just it's as verge Casty as it
Speaker 1:  gets. Right. And that is a very narrow, semantic debate,
Speaker 1:  but it is, I thought it was super revealing. What's your big takeaway?
Speaker 3:  I mean, and in my takeaway, my takeaway is that it's weird to think
Speaker 3:  about the web in all of this, that it's
Speaker 3:  weird that everyone just points to the web constantly is this space where
Speaker 3:  you can do anything. And this is like the final frontier of things that are
Speaker 3:  not controlled by whatever company makes the system that
Speaker 3:  you're running. And we're like, oh, well, if you don't want to pay something,
Speaker 3:  just go and do it through the web. That's the most that I think I've seen
Speaker 3:  anyone talk about the web being useful for a long time, which
Speaker 1:  Is really weird, amazing. And the judge was like, all right, I've read all
Speaker 1:  the evidence. I've heard all the testimony.
Speaker 1:  Apple has to allow secondary web browsing engines on the iPhone done and
Speaker 1:  dusted. Mike walked away. I don't think that's going to happen, but it would
Speaker 1:  be an incredible outcome. Okay. And thank you so much. Thank you for
Speaker 1:  listening to hours of Vergecast this week, which is insane, but
Speaker 1:  thank you all for listening and getting us through it. We'll be back next
Speaker 1:  week. With more, you can tweet at us. Addie is at the Dexter jerky. You should
Speaker 1:  look at her. Twitter is full of treatment trial. Well, I'm at reckless. We
Speaker 1:  love hearing from you next week, rock and
Speaker 1:  roll.
Speaker 5:  Thanks to simple mobile for supporting this episode. You don't need a
Speaker 5:  contract to get a powerful nationwide 5g network. You need
Speaker 5:  simple mobile at simple mobile, you get the no contract
Speaker 5:  advantage. It's the reliability you need when you need it
Speaker 5:  with no mystery fees, no activation fees and no contract
Speaker 5:  ever get the no contract advantage. Simple
Speaker 5:  mobile out with the old, in with the simple 5g
Speaker 5:  capable devices and SIM required, actual availability covered and speed may
Speaker 5:  vary 5g network not available in all areas. 5g upload speed,
Speaker 5:  not yet available.
Speaker 6:  Whether it's delivering groceries to a neighbor or night off from cooking.
Speaker 6:  What of touching the life of one person could make a difference for many
Speaker 6:  more. Now, each time you order online or tap in store with your MasterCard
Speaker 6:  and qualifying restaurants and grocery stores, MasterCard will donate to
Speaker 6:  stand up to cancer. One precious center at a time up to $5
Speaker 6:  million, start something priceless.
Speaker 5:  And so on August 31st, 2021, where we maximum $5 million donation is reached,
Speaker 5:  whichever comes first, debit pen and international transactions and eligible.
Speaker 5:  The cancer is a division of the entertainment industry foundation terms apply
Speaker 5:  and see MasterCard dot U S slash .