# Transcript
ID: d6030e20-c51d-11eb-a406-170b6036d81f
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Huawei’s HarmonyOS arrives / Microsoft's next gen Windows / Apple's WWDC preview
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/1336462472/2086630401/s93290-US-5769s-1622795407.mp3
Description: Co-hosts Nilay Patel and Dieter Bohn talk with Verge senior editor Tom Warren and managing editor Alex Cranz about operating systems — what's coming up at Apple's developer conference next week, where Microsoft will take Windows next, and the debut of some new systems like HarmonyOS and Fuchsia OS.
Speaker 1:  This week on the verge cast, Alex Cranz and Tom Warren joined the show. We
Speaker 1:  go through everything that's coming up at WWDC next week, Tom walks us through
Speaker 1:  the new version of windows and we go through what on earth is going on with
Speaker 1:  at and T and Warner media. That's coming up on the verge cast. Now
Speaker ?:  this episode is virtuous brought to you by Okta, the leading independent
Speaker ?:  identity solution. Octa provides the best in class authorization. So your
Speaker ?:  customers and workforce can safely access what they need from anywhere they're
Speaker ?:  dedicated to building the most reliable, neutral identity platform, because
Speaker ?:  it means protecting more than a login identity is protecting people, their
Speaker ?:  ideas, their work, and their brilliance. It's protecting your future with
Speaker ?:  confidence. Learn more at okay. ta.com.
Speaker ?:  Support For this episode comes from high sets. Let's get real
Speaker ?:  buying a TV. Shouldn't require learning a foreign language, but most TV
Speaker ?:  companies love to talk in confusing jargon, making overhyped and overpriced
Speaker ?:  promises. High sense gives it to you straight. That's why all we're going
Speaker ?:  to tell you about their new ULE D series is that it's got all the premium
Speaker ?:  features. You want a TV in a wide range of sizes to suit any
Speaker ?:  room, forget the jargon and get real. Get high
Speaker ?:  sets, learn
Speaker ?:  more@highsense.com.
Speaker 1:  Hello and welcome to the cast. The flagship podcast of
Speaker 1:  alternative Android operating systems. Ooh, where
Speaker 1:  they spoon. We fork
Speaker 3:  The Vergecast. I'm
Speaker 1:  Your friend Nila. I am in our studio in the
Speaker 1:  office for the first time in over a year. And I'm giddy with excitement.
Speaker 1:  So I apologize to everyone if I'm just over the top today, but it is
Speaker 1:  super fun to be back in the studio. Dieter brown is here.
Speaker 4:  I am. You're a resident at video shields enthusiasts.
Speaker 1:  The only one that's not
Speaker 4:  Tony. We are Legion.
Speaker 1:  There are so many of you and all of you know how to use email. Tom Warren
Speaker 1:  is here.
Speaker 5:  Hello? I am Gill resident windows nine,
Speaker 5:  enthusiastic,
Speaker 1:  Fewer, and also the email client doesn't work very well. So feel free.
Speaker 1:  And we have a, we have a new guest is very exciting, Alex. Cranz
Speaker 1:  the new managing editor of the verge is here. Hi Alex.
Speaker 6:  Hey, I am also a fan of the shield. I'm sorry, Dieter. You're
Speaker 6:  not alone. I'm here with you. There's a shield. Have an email
Speaker 6:  client. Yes, it's shut. It's Android. It's got
Speaker 6:  everything. What can't it do?
Speaker 3:  No. Under shield owners
Speaker 1:  Send so many emails as a built-in angry email, very
Speaker 1:  high powered. Well, Alex, it's good to have you here. First of many
Speaker 1:  virtuous, I'm very excited to have you on the show. I want you to start.
Speaker 1:  We have a lot to talk about WWC is next week. Microsoft is
Speaker 1:  threatening to release a new version of windows. You got to talk about that
Speaker 1:  with Tom  is coming up. Other nobody knows anything about
Speaker 1:   and then we were off last week. So there's a bunch of
Speaker 1:  news to talk about from last week. Most importantly of which is of
Speaker 1:  course the at and T time Warner deal has its
Speaker 1:  come to its inevitable conclusion, which is that it's over now. So a lot
Speaker 1:  to catch up on, I do want to start where I always start with COVID, like
Speaker 1:  I said, I'm in the office. It's we're in the United States, at least elsewhere
Speaker 1:  in the world. It's still very bad, but the United States, it's still the
Speaker 1:  biggest story going. We're still not out of it, but we are coming to what
Speaker 1:  feels like an end of something. I think there's a lot of change to come.
Speaker 1:  I think this summer is going to be nuts in the United States is everybody
Speaker 1:  like emerges from seclusion. I think there's a lot of change to come,
Speaker 1:  but we do have some stories on the site that I think point
Speaker 1:  to there's a time of reflection that's happening. So Nicole Watson has a
Speaker 1:  great story about all of the tech initiatives that we saw during
Speaker 1:  the pandemic. We've talked about a lot of them on the show, there was the
Speaker 1:  exposure notification system. There was a bunch of Facebook and
Speaker 1:  Google location, data that was made available to researchers.
Speaker 1:  There was a promise of a website.
Speaker 4:  Was there a website in LA? How long, how long did it take them to make it?
Speaker 1:  It's not more than a year. And that website does not exist about where you
Speaker 1:  can get tested. So Nicole has a rundown of what worked and what didn't. I
Speaker 1:  think it is remarkable that exposure notification just kind of didn't go
Speaker 1:  anywhere. So really mixed results. She has a big breakdown of that, but the
Speaker 1:  location, data location, data that Google and Facebook made available as
Speaker 1:  part of a program called data for good. They just released the data anonymously
Speaker 1:  to researchers, and that has become a huge success in that the
Speaker 1:  scientific and academic community. So just a real, what did
Speaker 1:  we learn from all of the tech initiatives and it's I
Speaker 1:  think some surprising results in there. So that's a great story. There is,
Speaker 1:  it continues to be controversy about the origins of COVID
Speaker 1:  Nicole. Actually, it's a real three-pack from Nicole this week article. It's
Speaker 1:  a great story about how that's important to suss out, figuring out the beginnings,
Speaker 1:  isn't gonna help us figure out the end. So she has a great story, unpacking
Speaker 1:  that. And then she has another great story about
Speaker 1:  what we know the vaccine so far, which is that immunity looks good
Speaker 1:  for a long period of time to come. We obviously have to
Speaker 1:  experience the time to come to make sure that works. But right now the data
Speaker 1:  suggests it's going well. So an end of one
Speaker 1:  period, I can talk to you from our office again, but I'm so
Speaker 1:  giddy about being in this office. Again, I was not expecting it, but I
Speaker 1:  also had to drive two hours to get here. I think we're just excited about
Speaker 1:  not being in a car anymore. We'll see how this goes, as the show goes on,
Speaker 1:  but we continue to cover COVID in the vaccines and what we have learned
Speaker 1:  from this moment, very carefully, Nicole, doing a great job.
Speaker 1:  Okay? WWDC, worldwide developers
Speaker 1:  conference. It's apple time. It's apple time. There's a lot to talk
Speaker 1:  about apple updates, all of its many offices. There's like
Speaker 1:  a, a whisper of a room where they're going to announce yet another
Speaker 1:  OSTP called homo S which makes yeah, we'll
Speaker 1:  see. They, they needed advice to run on it, like putting
Speaker 1:  in a customer less than the home pod makes no sense. Like the only announcing
Speaker 1:  asked if you have apps, if you have a reason to tell people almost your Google,
Speaker 1:  in which case you just announced to us as all the time. Well,
Speaker 4:  Hang on the iPhone. Oh, S didn't have apps. Didn't have third party. It
Speaker 4:  was about it.
Speaker 1:  They actually didn't. It didn't even really have a name. It was iPhone
Speaker 1:  S and then it was iPhone O S when they announced apps. And when they
Speaker 1:  did the iPad for like a year, the
Speaker 1:  iPad ran iPhone iOS that's right. Yep. And then they changed it to iOS to
Speaker 1:  make it encompassing. And then they realized like, oh, what two years ago?
Speaker 1:  Like, oh, this is constricting. And they renamed it. Like apple is
Speaker 1:  very, they don't like making new names. Anyone they do, they don't
Speaker 1:  even mean, but Google is like, I don't know. Here's another Linux-based to
Speaker 1:  us that we made. What's the future. Here's another messaging
Speaker 1:  app in any of
Speaker 1:  them. This operating systems runs on
Speaker 1:  RCS. Anyway. WTC is where apple goes through all of its
Speaker 1:  existing operating systems, iOS, iPad, iOS, Mac iOS, Washoe,
Speaker 1:  S T V O S in the now potentially like, we'll
Speaker 1:  see, but there's a rumble that they'll do that. I want to go through on
Speaker 1:  order. But theater and I were talking before the show, Apple's like under
Speaker 1:  a cloud at this WWDC, like they just had this big trial
Speaker 1:  with epic, a little bit of one. Every, the developer community is
Speaker 1:  extremely aware that apple executives are like, huh? How can we make
Speaker 1:  money off of this idea? Let's just turn the money fountain on
Speaker 1:  and like take 30%. The rationale for that
Speaker 1:  30% you might buy it. I think it is rational.
Speaker 1:  Some of the things they say about why that 30% exists is
Speaker 1:  rational. Some of it is like, they're just stubborn. And some of it is
Speaker 1:  like, they're just greedy. And that is the first time I think
Speaker 1:  Apple's like, armor has been punctured in this way, heading
Speaker 1:  into a WTB.
Speaker 4:  How do you do a WWDC? But you remember what was, when did, Hey, go
Speaker 4:  after them? It was like the morning or the day before. It was like a few
Speaker 4:  days before. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Well that was like one email app from one popular developer who maybe it's
Speaker 1:  not so popular anymore. And like, yeah. And then like resolved it. Like
Speaker 1:  they just like solve the problem. Yeah. Like re-interpreting a rule. This
Speaker 1:  is like hundreds of emails, Tim cook on the stand
Speaker 1:  being like, this is how I monetize the phone. I think it is a
Speaker 1:  qualitatively different situation kind
Speaker 5:  Of, but they'll, they're apples though. Announcing really cool for
Speaker 5:  developers and they'll sit and forget those problems. Just like we
Speaker 5:  forget everything that happens a week or two before these
Speaker 5:  days. I feel like there there's a lot of quietness around
Speaker 5:  WWDC this year. And like, there hasn't been many big iOS
Speaker 5:  rumors or iPad rumors, which makes me think that they've kept
Speaker 5:  something secret that they're going to do. And I have theories. It's
Speaker 5:  like, where's the M one chip in the iPad, you know, like,
Speaker 5:  oh,
Speaker 1:  So you can unlock your car with your iPad. Yeah. I mean
Speaker 1:  like, think about all of the, you know, the billionaires who use an iPad
Speaker 1:  as a camera, they got to walk up to the, the rolls and they're just going
Speaker 1:  to wait. It's straight
Speaker 5:  Away. But I think, I think they will silence the, the stories that we've
Speaker 5:  seen over the last few weeks, the epic trial and stuff. We've, you know,
Speaker 5:  we've what they do best, which is just products and please
Speaker 5:  developers in different ways because they always seem to manage to do
Speaker 5:  it. I don't
Speaker 4:  Know. I think like, I think that this is not going to get quite a down quite
Speaker 4:  so easy. There's going to be, they're going to flood the zone. There's gonna
Speaker 4:  be a million stories. We're gonna write a million stories. But I think that
Speaker 4:  when that dust settles, there's a, still a
Speaker 4:  Congress that is still very interested and asking them questions and, you
Speaker 4:  know, scoring points there and finding out if they could do something about
Speaker 4:  it. I don't think it's going to go away quite so easy to me. The more interesting
Speaker 4:  question is, will there be any
Speaker 4:  kind of acknowledgement in this
Speaker 4:  online keynote, infomercial
Speaker 4:  thing of all the drama? Will there be any
Speaker 4:  gesture at all?
Speaker 6:  I don't think they can. They can't say anything because
Speaker 6:  like it's being the judges looking at it right now and deciding,
Speaker 6:  and they can't just go out and be like, we're going to cut prices or whatever
Speaker 6:  with the judge or we're going to increase prices. Like nothing. They
Speaker 6:  say
Speaker 1:  It would be amazing if they were like, we're going to
Speaker 1:  45% to me,
Speaker 1:  that'd be great. I don't know, actually right there in this period of
Speaker 1:  scrutiny, certainly the Congress in this country is, you know,
Speaker 1:  making a lot of noise, whether they can effectively pass anything, remains
Speaker 1:  to be seen. There's that court case, there's the EU complaint
Speaker 1:  against the app store. The likes to do stuff. Whether any of
Speaker 1:  that is effective also remains to be seen, but like they're under this cloud.
Speaker 1:  And the last time they were under this cloud, they announced the small business
Speaker 1:  program. Yep. Which the judge in the trial actually said, you didn't do this
Speaker 1:  for competition. You did it because of regulators and pressure.
Speaker 1:  Like, so like they haven't, they have all their moves that could make the,
Speaker 1:  I think the theaters, right. This, the keynotes are now infomercials. They
Speaker 1:  have been for over a year now from all the companies, these like tightly
Speaker 1:  scripted. They're not gonna, no, one's going to boo them. Right.
Speaker 1:  That's the, that's the danger. You have like 10,000 people in Moscone, west.
Speaker 1:  Right. It's you're gonna announce a thing. And like Tim cook is going to
Speaker 1:  expect the cheer and it's pin drop silence, right. Or like
Speaker 1:  worst people are like, boo, we hate you. They don't have any of that to
Speaker 1:  worry about, but they could announce we're lowering the cut
Speaker 1:  on subscriptions to eight and a half percent for two years. They
Speaker 1:  could announce in that purchases for all categories, except for
Speaker 1:  games are going to 10%. And we're just going to keep milling the
Speaker 1:  whales in the games category forever. Like they have moves. I think
Speaker 1:  one of the questions I have is they can't just like gesture at it. They have
Speaker 1:  to do something. Will they do something after all of
Speaker 5:  This? But I think they've already done that though. Right? Cause they, they,
Speaker 5:  they cut it to 15% for some, basically the vast majority of
Speaker 5:  developers are at 15%. If you, you know, if you take out whatever
Speaker 5:  revenues they're generating. So they kind of did that in the wake of a lot
Speaker 5:  of this drama last year, you know, the, the questions around
Speaker 5:  it. So I'm not sure that they'll do anything. It don't do a D C related to
Speaker 5:  this until there's significant regulatory
Speaker 5:  pressure. Really. We don't really know what the EU are doing with their
Speaker 5:  case and what they're going to try and convince them to do. Like th th the,
Speaker 5:  the thing that needs to happen is a regulator has to step
Speaker 5:  in and say, you need to change your product or your business model in a certain,
Speaker 5:  not bit similar, but you need to change your product in a certain way. I
Speaker 5:  just don't know if that's going to happen anytime soon. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  And the likes to do like, do things there, like when you boot up an
Speaker 1:  Android phone, you're going to pick up a search engine and they're like,
Speaker 1:  everyone picks Google, like, but they love doing this
Speaker 1:  stuff. So we'll see. I just think that that's, to me, it
Speaker 1:  is the biggest dark cloud that apple has had before an event like this in
Speaker 1:  quite some time. So we'll just have to see if they come at it, because
Speaker 1:  this is their developer event. This was just another event to
Speaker 1:  announce a Mac book or an iPhone event. I would expect nothing,
Speaker 1:  but the audience for this, even though we're all gonna watch it. And it's
Speaker 1:  them like, lots of people, consumers are gonna watch it. Apple fans are gonna
Speaker 1:  watch it. The audience is developers. That's who this is
Speaker 1:  for. And it feels like they need to address that. Maybe they'll do it in
Speaker 1:  state of the union. Like, there's all these other events they have, they're
Speaker 1:  a little bit more close to work. But to me, it's like, we're going to talk
Speaker 1:  about all the lesses, the point of developer events and announcing arrests
Speaker 1:  is earliest to get developers excited about building to your new APIs and
Speaker 1:  your, your features and like making new, innovative stuff on top of the
Speaker 1:  platforms. If they're already kind of mad at you, like the
Speaker 1:  second part of the equation is just, it's harder to get through, but we'll
Speaker 1:  see what
Speaker 4:  If they just go back to charging for OSTP updates and that that's
Speaker 4:  still they'll fund they'll fund software that way, instead of the app store
Speaker 4:  fees, you're not going to do that. No, they won't. I'm just
Speaker 1:  Saying that'd be great box in the mail. And it's just like a, it's a
Speaker 1:  tiny little lightning USB key with
Speaker 3:   flushing
Speaker 6:  Your phone. You can't get out without buying a tool. It'd be incredible.
Speaker 6:  What Tom said, kind of made me go galaxy brain on this though, which
Speaker 6:  is, you know, he said, they're going to surprise us. They're going to do
Speaker 6:  something big. And one of the distraction isn't like directly to the developers,
Speaker 6:  but what if it is stuff like this homo S what if it's, you know, they've
Speaker 6:  been, they've been flirting around AR and they've got to start getting people
Speaker 6:  somewhat excited for that, for when they eventually released their AR glasses.
Speaker 6:  What if they do a big tease? Just kind of like to distract people from the
Speaker 6:  fact that everybody loses 30% of their income when they develop an app
Speaker 6:  for the store. Like, you know, I think they're really good. I'm putting on
Speaker 6:  a big show and, and, and, and really getting us hyped about things. And one
Speaker 6:  of it's kind of like, ignore that, ignore that, look at all this other cool
Speaker 6:  stuff we're doing. You want to get excited about this. You want to be in
Speaker 6:  people's homes in a different way. You want to be in their eyeballs in a
Speaker 6:  different way. I got it. Yeah. Here's, here's what it's going to be. You're
Speaker 6:  you're hearing
Speaker 4:  It from me first, exclusively. Oh my God. I could just see
Speaker 4:  it exclusive nonsense from Dieter Bo Tim cook
Speaker 4:  gets in the middle of apple park and he's like, you know,
Speaker 4:  the future of developing for the Mac is
Speaker 4:  web apps. And we're going to talk about PWAs and he's going to do
Speaker 4:  pwn. It's just going to be web apps nonstop for 45 minutes.
Speaker 4:  He's going to call it a suite solution.
Speaker 1:  The ghost of Steve jobs sucks. Tim cook into a
Speaker 1:  swirling vortex. It is like, that's not it. And
Speaker 1:  then the logo just
Speaker 1:  appears. We wouldn't be talking
Speaker 1:  about the 30%. That's true. That is definitely
Speaker 1:  true.
Speaker 5:  They will definitely have like, like Macko is smoke and mirrors. You know,
Speaker 5:  like there's going to be like some sort of, there's gonna be something that's
Speaker 5:  going to distract. They're going to be like, you know, we're going to give
Speaker 5:  you this. This is going to be great for developers. And like, cause that's
Speaker 5:  the way the apple tackles these things. They never cash.
Speaker 1:  They're just going to give developers cash.  direct
Speaker 1:  apple pay,
Speaker 5:  And everyone's going to spend it on inferior or Bitcoin or whatever
Speaker 1:  Every day that you don't tweet apple gives you $5. Actually that would work.
Speaker 1:  I would take that deal. Let's go through the OSS. We'll see what happens.
Speaker 1:  I just wanted to put that in a context, because the point of these events
Speaker 1:  is to get people excited about building new products for the OSS.
Speaker 1:  And that is a hurdle they have to get over this year, which is
Speaker 1:  new. Let's talk about iOS, like very few rumors, but iOS
Speaker 1:  is, Tom was,
Speaker 5:  Yeah, it's weird. It's it's suspiciously quiet. That's what I mean.
Speaker 5:  It's like, I think Mark Coleman had a story about how this is
Speaker 5:  going to be some change to that notification stuff and some home screen stuff.
Speaker 5:   but that seems like there's always a home screen thing on
Speaker 5:  iPad iOS every year now
Speaker 1:  Did nothing last year. Let's talk about them separately. So the phone is
Speaker 1:  like in a pretty good place. The notifications have
Speaker 1:  long needed updates. So that makes sense. They're going to do
Speaker 1:  differently.
Speaker 4:  Actually. We need to, we need to sit on this for just a second. Okay. So
Speaker 4:  the rumor is that the government is reporting is that they're going to have
Speaker 4:  different settings for different like situations you might be in like
Speaker 4:  driving, working, or sleeping. And then you can customize how notification
Speaker 4:  works for these different settings. Like automatic applies and
Speaker 4:  whatnot. This is literally just profiles. This
Speaker 4:  is the feature that was on every single feature phone. Like you hit like
Speaker 4:  star two or whatever. And then you'd pick between like five different rank
Speaker 4:  profiles for your ringtones or whatever that we just forgot
Speaker 4:  existed because here it is, it's the Vergecast because
Speaker 4:  Palm invented the ringer switch and then you don't want 50 profiles. You
Speaker 4:  just want to, and then apple is the only company that
Speaker 4:  bothered to steal it. And then one plus a little bit later. And
Speaker 4:  so, I don't know, like, I am very happy to see
Speaker 4:  lots of different notification like management options. I'm an Android
Speaker 4:  user. And I just love how Google changes their mind about how notifications
Speaker 4:  are gonna work every year, but that has gotten them to a good place. I
Speaker 4:  don't know that the problem with notifications on the iPhone is that there
Speaker 4:  aren't enough modes. Like that's not the problem.
Speaker 1:  We have to figure out how this works. Like it's just the rumor that we're
Speaker 1:  thinking about it. It's funny because we're started with apple start cloud
Speaker 1:  with developers, apple can just exert pressure on and be
Speaker 1:  like part of app review is that we are going to set priority levels for your
Speaker 1:  notifications for you. And if you abuse the system, we're
Speaker 1:  just going to kick you out of the store. And that is the one time I'm like,
Speaker 1:  yeah, you should do that on Android. Every
Speaker 1:  app is like, yeah, we're the highest priority notification. Just like out
Speaker 1:  of the box. They're all like, no one is humble enough, no Android
Speaker 1:  app developers humbled off to be like, you know what? You don't need these
Speaker 1:  notifications.
Speaker 3:  So like, I
Speaker 1:  Would accept that like a system where after overs are incentivized, to be
Speaker 1:  honest, that, yeah. Okay. I probably want
Speaker 1:  my messaging apps to be the highest priority notifications, but I
Speaker 1:  really do not. At this point, the New York times breaking news notifications
Speaker 1:  are like, we've conducted a 5,000 word investigation into
Speaker 1:  butterflies and it's like, I don't know what this is. Like, I just need to
Speaker 1:  shut this off, but I want them, I just don't need them
Speaker 1:  at the level of everything else. Like if I could do that in an iPhone, I
Speaker 1:  would be very happy. I would also like notifications to be much more
Speaker 1:  actionable, which they're stepping towards, but they're
Speaker 1:  still not great. Right? Like if I could delete a text from the home
Speaker 1:  screen, I would be the happiest person in the world. What
Speaker 5:  You're describing there sounds like you want some serious machine learning
Speaker 5:  chops in iOS, which is something that it's kind of lacking at the
Speaker 5:  moment or,
Speaker 1:  You know, features capabilities.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. But
Speaker 5:  You want, you want it to adapt to you, right? You want it to be like, oh,
Speaker 5:  look at this New York times alert. It's not like the phone knows me in
Speaker 5:  those that won't be interested in those butterflies. I mean, that's well,
Speaker 6:  It's, it's kind of weird though, because like apple can't really get
Speaker 6:  too in-depth in machine learning because it's, it's very much about like
Speaker 6:  siloing your profiles and your user data and stuff. And that's
Speaker 6:  always why it said serious kind of stupid. And I personally loved
Speaker 6:  that. Like, let it be more stupid if it means I don't have to have like,
Speaker 6:  worry about them listening in on everything I do.
Speaker 6:  But at the same time, if, if they don't do the machine learning thing, if
Speaker 6:  they do like exert influence on the app
Speaker 6:  creators, that just kind of pushes the right back towards the
Speaker 6:  judge is currently deciding if they have too much
Speaker 6:  power over creators. And it's just like, they're in a really, it's
Speaker 6:  like, I don't think there's an easy answer because like, what's the other
Speaker 6:  one. Like you get to go and create huge profiles for yourself and you
Speaker 6:  have to create like 12 different profiles and that's like the antithesis
Speaker 6:  of apple and just being able to open and use your phone. And so
Speaker 6:  it's like, I'm just curious to see what they do because every single route
Speaker 6:  seems very not what I would expect from apple.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 1:  I mean, I think the thing that's true right now is that notification management.
Speaker 1:  I know iPhones has been horrible since the day, the first iPhone came out.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Like right now getting a phone call and an iPhone is just an
Speaker 1:  incredible experience of like, you get the dropdown banner over
Speaker 1:  whatever you're doing, you can answer it. But then if you put it to your
Speaker 1:  ear, it's not in the app. So it doesn't shut off the
Speaker 1:  screen. So your cheek is just touching a bunch of stuff. So
Speaker 1:  that's like, it doesn't even make any sense. It's not in speaker phone, but
Speaker 1:  then he'd go to push the speaker button. It doesn't just default to the phone
Speaker 1:  speaker. It'll bring up the speaker menu and be like, do you want
Speaker 1:  to take this call on your Mac book pro? And then the person on the line is
Speaker 1:  like, are you there? And you're like, hang on. I'm still
Speaker 1:  answering the phone call.
Speaker 6:  And they're probably hearing you being called on your Mac, on your
Speaker 6:  iPad, on your watch, on every other product at your house that uses
Speaker 6:  apple. Yes.
Speaker 1:  You definitely know if you've caught somebody using iOS because you hear
Speaker 1:  that ringers around them come to a class when they answer. And
Speaker 1:  that's just like satisfying. That's the, that's the primary
Speaker 1:  notification of a phone. I just
Speaker 1:  like, they need to make that system more powerful. Whether it's with machine
Speaker 1:  learning, whether it's giving the users and endless series of
Speaker 1:  controls, whether it's, I don't know, just shutting it off, like just
Speaker 1:  do something like start it over and like rethink it. But it is
Speaker 1:  to me, this, it has always been and will continue to be
Speaker 1:  the single biggest pain point of an iPhone. And so if that's the thing, they
Speaker 1:  announced iOS, if you have nothing else, like, that'd be great.
Speaker 5:  I liked the way that, that over the last year or so in iOS
Speaker 5:  they've they have kind of been learning some of your behaviors to sort of
Speaker 5:  make it a little bit smarter. So like everyday I'll swipe down and
Speaker 5:  it'll be like, oh, you watch this Twitch stream. It's like, why don't you
Speaker 5:  watch this today? Or it will be like, oh, you messaged this person a lot
Speaker 5:  when you missed this, this person, you know, like at least tiny little things
Speaker 5:  that don't always quite work properly. But when they do, they're
Speaker 5:  kind of like those delight things. It's like, oh, let's save me. Like, you
Speaker 5:  know, a couple of seconds or whatever. Always just reminded me to do a task.
Speaker 5:  I like if they can really play on that with like not
Speaker 5:  being too into the privacy stuff and the creepiness of it. Cause it can be
Speaker 5:  creepy when these stuff pops up and like predicts your behavior.
Speaker 5:  Then I think that's a way of like layering iOS to be a bit
Speaker 5:  more, you know, power user-friendly or just a bit more
Speaker 5:  usable for, especially for stuff like notifications. If they, if they apply
Speaker 5:  that sort of ML to notifications.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Like you've pushed the answer call button and now our
Speaker 1:  advanced differential privacy ML system has
Speaker 1:  determined that you wish to answer the phone call. I'll take it. Here's
Speaker 1:  a, here's a question right now. Who are they lifting more from? Are they
Speaker 1:  lifting old windows phone ideas with app tiles and
Speaker 1:  like deep links? Are they lifting more Android
Speaker 1:  ideas? Because Andrew has a bunch of this stuff too, but it's, it's all just
Speaker 1:  very different than how windows funded it. And you can see apple is kind
Speaker 1:  of going in that leg app clips, app tiles, deep links
Speaker 1:  direction. More than that, the Android. What if the app was just kind of
Speaker 1:  running in this window all the time?
Speaker 5:  I think they're lifting from everyone and even the jailbreak community as
Speaker 5:  well. Right? Like we've seen a bunch of stuff from, from that community that's
Speaker 5:  bubbled up in tiredness. I think they just pick out wherever, wherever it's
Speaker 5:  good and works, works well, but they take their to refine it, which, you
Speaker 5:  know, we know from the decades of watching well,
Speaker 4:  The other rumor is that they're going to lift from WhatsApp because the
Speaker 4:  government says that they're working on quote upgrades to I message. With
Speaker 4:  the eventual goal of acting more like a social network and better competing
Speaker 4:  with Facebook links, WhatsApp disclosure for your bingo card. My wife
Speaker 4:  works for a division Facebook reality
Speaker 4:  labs, a division of Facebook. I
Speaker 4:  don't know what that means, but I do know that, you know, I message is nowhere
Speaker 4:  near as popular in the rest of the world, as it is in the U S and maybe apple
Speaker 4:  does feel like a desire to compete in some way. But I also
Speaker 4:  know that apple, the last thing that company would want to
Speaker 4:  do right now is deal with a, yet another like
Speaker 4:  moderation problem. Right. They got enough going on with the app
Speaker 4:  store. If there's like, you know, WhatsApp has had all sorts of
Speaker 4:  moderation issues and like, like having to disable automatic forwarding and
Speaker 4:  a whole bunch of other stuff. I don't know what apple is thinking with iMessage,
Speaker 4:  but trying to make it into a social network. That's like, that's a thing
Speaker 4:  that apple has not successfully done. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  The last one they tried
Speaker 5:  Ping, ping mobile meters. It was pretty great.
Speaker 1:  Wait, hold on. These are, these are all different apple failures. Ping was
Speaker 1:  their social network for music that made no sense. Oh. But
Speaker 4:  There was, there was an apple music one since then, but I forget what it
Speaker 4:  was called. Right.
Speaker 1:  Then there was one in apple music where artists like when they announced
Speaker 1:  apple music, they're like, and then artists will just like, not use Instagram.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Like that quickly fizzled into
Speaker 1:  nothing hit the brick wall of reality. Mobile me was their
Speaker 1:  cloud services that turned an iCloud mobile me famously
Speaker 1:  like Steve jobs stood up in front of like the mobile me team.
Speaker 1:  And it was like, Walt Mossberg hates this. How did he screw this
Speaker 1:  up? Which is like, amazing
Speaker 3:  Wall has very conflicted feelings about,
Speaker 1:  But like that was the, the, the level of failure was like, Steve jobs was
Speaker 1:  like, look at this, look at what Walt said, how'd you screw this up so bad,
Speaker 1:  but not a social network. I do think the last thing they tried to do with
Speaker 1:  iMessage was they tried to add apps to it in that era when Apple's answer
Speaker 1:  to everything was what if this had an app store. And so they tried to
Speaker 1:  put apps into iMessage and that has gone
Speaker 1:  effectively nowhere, except that it is now much harder to add
Speaker 1:  a photo to a text than an
Speaker 1:  iPhone.
Speaker 5:  So funny, the ego is like in the U S LMS is just such a huge thing because
Speaker 5:  I literally only ever go inside a message to look at like a scam
Speaker 5:  SMS. And so that's literally it.
Speaker 1:  That's amazing. Okay. So that's iOS. We think there's some notification stuff.
Speaker 1:  We think there's some high message stuff. Lots of mystery. Shrouding what
Speaker 1:  else they will do. Apple's most important platform. That can't be it. But
Speaker 1:  that's what we know so far. I pad OOS equally
Speaker 1:  mysterious, but I will say after the last round of iPad, pro
Speaker 1:  reviews, everyone is like, well, they got to do
Speaker 1:  something except for Dieter. Who's like, I dunno, man. I've been hearing
Speaker 1:  that for years
Speaker 3:  Tired. No,
Speaker 4:  I just, I, the rumors are gonna, they're going to let you like place widgets
Speaker 4:  wherever you want on the home screen. Cause they did that for the iPhone,
Speaker 4:  but they didn't do it for the iPad. And nobody knew why. And just the
Speaker 4:  hope that they're like, Apple's going to do something. Well, I could do like,
Speaker 4:  let you run Mac apps on the  powered, iPad
Speaker 4:  pro I just don't. They're not, no, I just, I
Speaker 4:  I've, I no longer have hope,
Speaker 1:  No way. They're gonna let you do that because then you would have a touchscreen
Speaker 1:  Mac. I think
Speaker 5:  That it will have some form of it will happen, but like, it's going to
Speaker 5:  be years in the making, like these things don't, you know, they don't just
Speaker 5:  put an M one chip in the iPad and then six months later, go
Speaker 5:  there. You see mock-ups
Speaker 1:  I hear that, that they put the chip in the, the iPad, the
Speaker 1:  and that feels like it's going to lead to a logical conclusion. But I
Speaker 1:  also think apple is a master of its own supply chain and there's a chip
Speaker 1:  shortage. And the M one is really just like the a 13 X
Speaker 1:  or whatever. Like fundamentally it is just the next evolution of the chip
Speaker 1:  they were using. And they're like, whatever, we're just using it, all the
Speaker 1:  computers. Like I don't, th there's no reason like the existence of the chip
Speaker 1:  does not make them have to do anything. The existing of governments around
Speaker 1:  the world doesn't mean apple wants to do anything.
Speaker 5:  It doesn't. But like the fact that everything apart from the iPhone
Speaker 5:  is on M one. Now, like I said, everything's still, I pad the max.
Speaker 5:  Basically. There's a reason behind that other than chip shortages, I
Speaker 5:  think. Yeah. I just don't think we're going to get to that this
Speaker 5:  year. Like he is, it's a, it's a multi-year process.
Speaker 6:  Can't do it this year. They were so emphatic about the
Speaker 6:  Mac Mac iOS wouldn't become the iPad. Right? Like they
Speaker 6:  can't take one and make it the other they've been so emphatic about that
Speaker 6:  for so, so long that the minute they do it, we will like, I will be
Speaker 6:  delighted as I, as I gleefully throw it back in their
Speaker 6:  face, just in a blog form. Like they can't do
Speaker 6:  it. Like they have, it's going to have to be subtle and like low
Speaker 6:  key. And, and so I think it is, I think Tom's right. That is going to
Speaker 6:  be years and years and years. But it's also like, this is the
Speaker 6:  natural next step. And I think it's going to be kind of like
Speaker 6:  when they finally blew that the iPhone up and they had all these other
Speaker 6:  different things to distract you from the fact that you could no longer fit
Speaker 6:  it in your pocket. And, and, you know, Steve jobs had always said, oh, I
Speaker 6:  will never, never do a big phone. They're terrible. And it's the same thing.
Speaker 6:  He was like, I'll never do a touch Mac. And like, yeah, they just got to
Speaker 6:  go slow and then distract us with something else. I
Speaker 1:  Think Steve jobs actually, when he said that when I was ready to punch didn't
Speaker 1:  he have the alligator arms, he like put up a slide and he was
Speaker 1:  like, this will give you out like real arms, gorilla arms. That was an
Speaker 1:  animal. It was a type of animal arm that he thought was very bad. And
Speaker 1:  those animals are still to this day, very angry at apple. You'll never
Speaker 1:  see a crocodile using a Mac, just the fat
Speaker 4:  With the iPad. It's been 10 years of us saying, Hey, this screen is pretty
Speaker 4:  good. And this processor is pretty fast and you should, you should, you know,
Speaker 4:  you could do a lot more of this. And Apple's like, nah. And then a couple
Speaker 4:  of years ago, the iPad iOS are like, all right, here's the new system. Here's
Speaker 4:  how everything, the new windowing system it's. And I was like, so excited.
Speaker 4:  Cause apple finally let the iPad get complicated. It was just what needed
Speaker 4:  to happen in order to turn it into a computer that didn't feel like it was
Speaker 4:  like limiting you. And it's like, you're just, you're
Speaker 4:  waiting for them to finally do the thing that you've picked up, all
Speaker 4:  your hopes and dreams for it. I've been picked up over a decade. There just,
Speaker 4:  I think that they are actually really content with where the iPad is and
Speaker 4:  what the iPad is like to wit multi-user
Speaker 4:  support. Like if, if all they do is walk up on stage, I said, this last year,
Speaker 4:  if all they do is walk up and say, it's just say, here's the iPad. Here's
Speaker 4:  the login screen. Look, there's icons on it. One for you and one for your
Speaker 4:  kid. And then they walk off stage and that's the entire
Speaker 4:  iPad section done a plus five
Speaker 4:  stars.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. They're going to dunk. They're going to announce like more home kit
Speaker 1:  automation features and said,
Speaker 5:  But so your point about like, we've been waiting a decade for
Speaker 5:  certain stuff. If you'd gone back five years and said that the iPad for
Speaker 5:  mouse and keyboard support, I think most people would've been like, nah,
Speaker 5:  it's never going to happen. Or like, yeah, I want it. But like it's never
Speaker 5:  going to happen. And even apple was like at the time. No. And they did it
Speaker 5:  in their own unique way. So I think, I don't think that the iPads, if we
Speaker 5:  can run macro S or anything like that, but I feel like they will get to a
Speaker 5:  point where they will, the wind during is different. Like they've kind of
Speaker 5:  gone that way. It's, it's kind of very windows eight sort of hybrid at the
Speaker 5:  moment, but I think it'll get a bit more free flowing. Like it makes
Speaker 5:  sense if they allow you to run Mac up apps on there at some point
Speaker 5:  when they, when they just like to bridge gaps, that's what the iPad has been
Speaker 5:  doing for like 10 years. It's just slowly been bridging those gaps.
Speaker 5:  So I don't
Speaker 1:  Know. I feel like, look, air travel is coming back. A lot of
Speaker 1:  executives are going to need to do email in first class. Apple's got a
Speaker 1:  $2,000 computer that can solve that problem for you. They're just going to
Speaker 1:  sell a lot of them
Speaker 3:  That like,
Speaker 1:  I think they might just be happy with that. And that to me is like
Speaker 1:  across all these product lines. Right. We should talk about the watch next,
Speaker 1:  like apple faces. So little competition. I go back to that question of
Speaker 1:  like, who are they lifting from more? We're talking about one
Speaker 1:  operating system, Android that exists that they kind of live from all the
Speaker 1:  time. But even the pace of that back and forth has slowed.
Speaker 1:  And then we're talking about two dead operating systems like apple. So like,
Speaker 1:  I don't know whether the last 70 ideas let's use some of those. Like, there's
Speaker 1:  not a lot of like pressure to
Speaker 1:  innovate in a lot of these spaces anymore. And then in particular
Speaker 1:  with the watch and with the iPad, where are they feeling any
Speaker 1:  heat at all right. It's just like only from within, does apple
Speaker 1:  feel the pressure to make something better? It's good and lucky that
Speaker 1:  apple seems to feel a lot of that pressure all the time. Like that's the
Speaker 1:  company, that's their DNA. I think that just should be commended for that.
Speaker 1:  They're not lazy with the products, even though they have these monopoly
Speaker 1:  positions, but like there's a reason the is moving a lot
Speaker 1:  slower than it did with Steve jobs. Once I remember, like years ago, he got
Speaker 1:  on a quarterly results call and did like a 10
Speaker 1:  minute rant, about seven inch Android tablets. Like he was fired
Speaker 1:  up about seven inch Android tablets. He's like, this is the wrong size or
Speaker 1:  broken. And it's because Google was going to do like the nexus seven or whatever.
Speaker 1:  Like I guarantee you that no apple executive has thought about it. An Android
Speaker 1:  tablet in any capacity, except Amazon sells cheap. One for
Speaker 1:  kids. And apple would prefer that you just gave your old iPad to a
Speaker 1:  kid. But
Speaker 5:  I think all of that speaks to the maturity of particularly the iPhone, but
Speaker 5:  obviously the iPad's pretty mature now as well. And I think if they're going
Speaker 5:  to, if the high frame is going to face any sort of competition of than, you
Speaker 5:  know, whatever Google does, an Android is going to be foldable
Speaker 5:  stuff. And like, we're like if we ever get to the point where you're folding
Speaker 5:  these things out and using them as actual computers, then there has to be
Speaker 5:  the flexibility of the operating system and whatever else. But
Speaker 5:  again, we're probably years out from that ever being a reality. So
Speaker 5:  until that's the case, yeah. They just have to slowly pitch the
Speaker 5:  gaps.
Speaker 6:  I'm still holding out for an Android E ink
Speaker 6:  tablet that can play a video it's going to happen. And
Speaker 6:  then an Apple's going to be like, oh my gosh. And just
Speaker 6:  going to be absolutely wrecked by that first beautiful tablet. You
Speaker 6:  won't be able to read anything in it. It's going to be great. That's two
Speaker 6:  frames a
Speaker 1:  Second. Your mind, this is a black and white. It's like you're watching a
Speaker 1:  silent films,
Speaker 6:  Get a, cult-like give it two or three years. We're going to have the
Speaker 6:  perfect iPad replacement. And everybody's going to be going and
Speaker 6:  buying their E ink tablets that are like 13 inches
Speaker 6:  wide lasts for four weeks on a charge. Can't play
Speaker 6:  video, but look fabulous
Speaker 5:  And they'll call it the career.
Speaker 4:  I mean, that scenario is more likely than genuine competitive pressure on
Speaker 4:  the apple watch. Like they're getting massive version of watch over us. And
Speaker 4:  I, I honestly, they're not going to give us custom, watch
Speaker 4:  faces behind what, you know, they'll add like 10 more watch faces to it.
Speaker 4:  There'll be 13 different ways to like track your workouts that
Speaker 4:  are new. And I don't know what else is left because
Speaker 4:  there's nothing for them to like get
Speaker 4:  straight.
Speaker 1:  No, they're going to merge it with Tyson. They're
Speaker 3:  Like, we are also merging our platform with Tyson. The thing
Speaker 3:  happening in wearables
Speaker 4:  Is Amazon has a wrist strap that will tone
Speaker 4:  police you.
Speaker 3:  Right? What are they worried about in the
Speaker 3:  world?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, we are facing small, tiny
Speaker 6:  bits of competition from companies like aura ring and a lot of
Speaker 6:  these companies that are going that health rat and the, and the, the, the
Speaker 6:  further those companies go down that health route. Like the first time somebody
Speaker 6:  gets glucose monitoring on your wrist, like
Speaker 6:  apple is going to be scrambling to buy all those patents. So
Speaker 6:  I can also get cookies monitoring the wrist, like, like there's
Speaker 6:  competition there, but it's, it's less than like the fun kind of like
Speaker 6:  user experience and much more in like the, how much more of your medical
Speaker 6:  data can we put in front of your eyeballs on a given
Speaker 6:  day.
Speaker 1:  Right. And then also, I mean, they're airing cool product people really like
Speaker 1:  it. There's been studies about the data it produces and how it can be
Speaker 1:  helpful. It's super interesting to use one. You need to run an app on
Speaker 1:  your phone
Speaker 3:  Because the app store, like, if you
Speaker 1:  Can just be like, no, what are the orange didn't update its app for a couple
Speaker 1:  of weeks. Y'all like, that's a, it's a weird dynamic that they have where
Speaker 1:  all these ancillary products also have to filter through the phone
Speaker 1:  for maybe not the primary user interface. Cause it's like a piece of hardware,
Speaker 1:  but a very important secondary user interface that includes
Speaker 1:  setting it up for the first time. And like, yeah, I think,
Speaker 1:  I think that level of control across the broader ecosystem is interesting
Speaker 1:  to think about that said, I couldn't tell you what they should do at the
Speaker 1:  watch at this point in time. Like, what do I need, watch us to do?
Speaker 1:  Like, maybe I'm thinking like maybe
Speaker 1:  the walkie-talkie feature, it could be slightly faster. I would take that.
Speaker 1:  I use my wife and I used to, I could take a feature like everyday
Speaker 5:  I would like different vibration sayings for different notifications and
Speaker 5:  stuff like that. Like, cause there are, but like, there's not a way
Speaker 5:  for developers to set that
Speaker 6:  Better access to using home automations and
Speaker 6:  stuff. Like I would like to be able to, you can do it from your watch, but
Speaker 6:  it's miserable. It's just the worst experience
Speaker 6:  in the world. And I would like to just be able to look at it and be like,
Speaker 6:  I'm going to turn off the lights and tap my wrist and the lights are off.
Speaker 6:  You're supposed to ask Siri. I do. And she does
Speaker 6:  it, but sometimes I want to, I just want to touch it. I don't want to have
Speaker 6:  to shout it through my house. Yeah. See, see
Speaker 5:  What if it learned that it was 10:00 PM at night and that you did that. So
Speaker 5:  when you swipe down from the top, that was just an option.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  I will allow it. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  By the way, it does. It should not have to learn that it's 10:00 PM at night,
Speaker 3:  Like that does not require AI
Speaker 4:  One controls. Where does that? It like shows up my, my night automations
Speaker 4:  at night. Like, it's pretty good about that. But I would say like talking
Speaker 4:  about home gadgets, like the rumor is that they might introduce homo S maybe
Speaker 4:  they'll like convert the, both the home pod and the apple TV
Speaker 4:  to run this renamed thing. It's flip on
Speaker 4:  that thread radio later this year matter, which
Speaker 4:  is the used to be called chip, which I used to call choice, which has a
Speaker 4:  connected home over IP, a smart home thing, which is basically HomeKit, but
Speaker 4:  everybody can use it as like launching. So it's possible
Speaker 4:  that we could see apple, like actually try really
Speaker 4:  hard with home kit in a way that I feel like it
Speaker 4:  hasn't. And because it was really limiting and it was very hard to
Speaker 4:  find home kit devices for awhile. And they've slowly been opening that
Speaker 4:  door. And some maybe, maybe we'll see like a big push
Speaker 4:  there and that that'll be one of the big surprises that Apple's
Speaker 4:  actually going to try and take on Alexa when it comes to smart home
Speaker 4:  stuff.
Speaker 6:  I think they absolutely can, especially when you see stuff like
Speaker 6:  sidewalk happening and there's more and more conversations about
Speaker 6:  how intrusive Amazon and Google have gotten in the home.
Speaker 6:  Apple has positioned itself for years as this big privacy
Speaker 6:  protector. And now it can say like, yeah, we like you
Speaker 6:  can control your whole smart home and not have to sell all of your
Speaker 6:  data to, to, you know, give it all away. Like I think, I
Speaker 6:  think that's something very doable and there's not a lot of competition.
Speaker 6:  Like Samsung smart things was probably one of the biggest competitors and
Speaker 6:  it still exists. But like people love shored things. Yeah. I
Speaker 6:  loved it. I used it for years and I moved into a new house and I
Speaker 6:  made the switch to HomeKit just to like, see how good if HomeKit could
Speaker 6:  work. And I will never go back. It's like, yes,
Speaker 6:  I had to program all of my lights in home kit instead of the hue app
Speaker 6:  and all this other stuff. But it just like, it did exactly what I needed
Speaker 6:  it to do. And I think if they actually give it some
Speaker 6:  more, if you have stronger automations and,
Speaker 6:  and just people can program that stuff a little better than it currently
Speaker 6:  is like, yeah. There's no reason it
Speaker 6:  couldn't just dominate in, in this kind of budget, smart home
Speaker 1:  Area. Yeah. Yeah. Can I say the nerdiest thing about smart things? Yes.
Speaker 1:  Do you know the sleeper smart things product is the absolute sleeper.
Speaker 1:  It's the wifi router. It's good. The Samsung smart things, wifi
Speaker 1:  router. They didn't make it themselves. They licensed all the tech
Speaker 1:  from plume, which is like one of the, the new
Speaker 1:  wifi companies plume sold itself to Comcast
Speaker 1:  disclosure. God,
Speaker 1:   whatever they licensed attack. And so
Speaker 1:  what the plume app lets you do is assign
Speaker 1:  devices to V lands so they can only see certain other
Speaker 1:  devices. So you can bracket all of your
Speaker 1:  smart home stuff on one virtual network. And
Speaker 1:  then like only let certain people see it in your house or only let certain
Speaker 1:  device to see one another. So if you, for
Speaker 1:  example, desire to control your garage doors with a
Speaker 1:  very dodgy, smart garage door openings and stuff, you can
Speaker 1:  hide it away from the rest of your network so that it can't send it out.
Speaker 1:  And it's like, it's absolutely the sleeper on. Cause we buy a
Speaker 1:  plume, you got to pay a monthly fee, a subscription fee, but
Speaker 1:  Samsung just like covers it. It's just free. So there's an entire
Speaker 1:  like underground community of smart things. Router, her people were
Speaker 1:  like, we're getting away with it. Y'all
Speaker 3:  It's very good. You just call them out.
Speaker 3:  You're going to ruin it. It's over. I think
Speaker 1:  That when people know that they signed this deal,
Speaker 1:  but like, that's like come back to like apple and HomeKit and it's
Speaker 1:  like, it is wild that Samsung makes that product
Speaker 1:  and they make an entire range of smart things. Things
Speaker 1:  not to mention washers and dryers and refrigerators,
Speaker 1:  right? Like Samsung has this huge product range that can't
Speaker 1:  quite integrate, but you could see how it could work. Apple's
Speaker 1:  like, I dunno, choice y'all want some
Speaker 1:  choice.
Speaker 5:  Well maybe Homarus is around her memory nap. We used to do those.
Speaker 6:  Oh Ooh. My dad still uses his. He has not
Speaker 6:  replaced it in 45 years. Yeah, we
Speaker 4:  Actually we're. We just moved in. I was unpacking a random box and there
Speaker 4:  was an airport just like, it was like what? Oh my God, I
Speaker 4:  want to just use it. Okay. Macko S what do you, what do you want from
Speaker 4:  echo S I hope
Speaker 1:  They D ugly big, sir. It's all that I
Speaker 1:  want. Just try again. Just be
Speaker 1:  like, we made this thing that looks like you should touch it. We keep
Speaker 1:  insisting that you shouldn't touch it. And it instead looks like Disney
Speaker 1:  world. And we're just going to turn that. Maybe they're just bridging the
Speaker 1:  gaps. I
Speaker 1:  think it sounds so evil. It's like is playing risk with all of
Speaker 3:  Computing, like slowly
Speaker 3:  advancing
Speaker 6:  Love them to take the little X in a notification and make
Speaker 6:  it a big X. If your
Speaker 4:  Notifications in macro S we don't run these
Speaker 4:  offerings so bad, the notifications in the back
Speaker 4:  of us are terrible
Speaker 1:  And they they've gotten worse with everything they've done up in the corner.
Speaker 1:  Just
Speaker 6:  Go find growl. What's left of growl by
Speaker 6:  it and just put it on there and done. And I'll be fine.
Speaker 1:  Raul is a deep cut. So for most of
Speaker 1:  our listeners
Speaker 3:  In the early two
Speaker 1:  Thousands growl was an open source notification framework for
Speaker 1:  Mac O S. It was actually called OSM back then. And like, all
Speaker 1:  the actual offers were like, that's great. We'll use it. And they'll just
Speaker 1:  use it. And then apple built its own notification system that
Speaker 1:  is oddly used and growl faded away. Right. So you're
Speaker 1:  saying go find the remnants of growl.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Like give that guy $5.
Speaker 1:  His name is John
Speaker 1:  rowel,
Speaker 6:  George, George Brown.
Speaker 6:  Like just, just buy it from him. I would love to be able to put my
Speaker 6:  notifications on the one part of my screen. I never go to, rather
Speaker 6:  than the part where, like, it always covers up all of my slacks with
Speaker 6:  other slacks.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I think  with, they're able to make
Speaker 1:  new form factors to the max. I think big Sur predated those form factors.
Speaker 1:  Like now looking at big Sur, you can see it's
Speaker 1:  big and colorful and bright. It was like, they knew, they knew the new
Speaker 1:  MNI Macs are coming and they've gotten an aesthetic or hardware, software
Speaker 1:  aesthetic for those computers. There is a rumor of a new MacBook pro theirs.
Speaker 1:  It's obvious they're going to update all the other computers along the way.
Speaker 1:  There's some leaks about the chips they're going to put in Mac pros and how
Speaker 1:  many cores they have. Like, they've got an entire cycle of
Speaker 1:  Mac redesigns coming. And I think maca less has to go with it, like
Speaker 1:  go for that ride. But I couldn't tell you that, like right now, what Mac
Speaker 1:  listen, like, we're going to get an interminable demo of like
Speaker 1:  safari cookie blocking or something, right? Like that's where they're at
Speaker 1:  with Mac iOS. They need to add more features to it. And like the big
Speaker 1:  feature that everybody wants is a touch screen and they don't want to do
Speaker 1:  it. Tom say bridging the gap again, bridging the
Speaker 1:  gap. I'm sitting here in
Speaker 1:  10 years.
Speaker 1:  Do we think we're going to get a New Mexico press? Oh, a hundred
Speaker 1:  percent.
Speaker 4:  Oh God. I just don't. I don't want to set myself up for
Speaker 4:  disappointment cause I want it so bad. Here's here's the thing. I
Speaker 4:  there's a bunch of rumors or some analysts saying that it'll happen. John
Speaker 4:  Prosser says it will happen. But if they're going to introduce new macro
Speaker 4:  pros, they have to introduce new processors. And that entire
Speaker 4:  experience of new MacBook pros justifying the
Speaker 4:  return of ports, because that's the rumor there's going to be
Speaker 4:  ports again, my God and explaining how fast the
Speaker 4:  processor is. Apple will never do that in less than 45
Speaker 4:  minutes, maybe half an hour. Right? I mean, they knew they move faster in
Speaker 4:  these, like in this online world, but for them to
Speaker 4:  cram new version of our hot shit processor, that's faster than anything
Speaker 4:  else and brought parts back. And there's an all new design and
Speaker 4:  this is computer that everybody is truly waiting
Speaker 4:  for. They're not going to cram that in at like, you know, a 10 minute
Speaker 4:  segment of WWDC
Speaker 6:  One. They absolutely should because I too need this, this
Speaker 6:  Mac book pro mine's the 26 key to original touch
Speaker 6:  bar monstrosity. And I'm on my third one,
Speaker 6:  but you know, I think the processor, so for the last couple of years, they've
Speaker 6:  spent so much time talking about processors. And I think it was less about
Speaker 6:  like telling us about processors and more about like hyping their, their
Speaker 6:  abilities in the space. And at this point they've kind of like shown they
Speaker 6:  can do it, right? Like if, if all they're doing is a little, you know, a
Speaker 6:  talk for the tick, that was the  and
Speaker 6:   is just a couple additional
Speaker 6:  cores and slightly less power efficiency. Like I think they can
Speaker 6:  communicate that pretty quickly and, and be like, all they have to do is
Speaker 6:  be like, it's going to be like the old Mac book pro two more
Speaker 6:  cores.
Speaker 1:  I feel like sync over the ports is a thing they will absolutely do. They'll
Speaker 1:  be like, yeah. Now applaud for this SD card reader.
Speaker 1:  And then literally you'll hear the applause around the world in a virtual,
Speaker 1:  even on a virtual event. I know they bumped the USB-C to
Speaker 1:  support more power recently, but I I'm sitting here with a
Speaker 1:  16 inch MacBook pro and a hundred watt USBC charger. And this
Speaker 1:  thing often does not charge well, it is often still
Speaker 1:  drawing too much power for this gigantic hundred watt brick.
Speaker 1:  And I plug anything else in the brick it's like game over. So
Speaker 1:  I think one of the reasons to bring the ports back is they might as well
Speaker 1:  just have a dedicated power adapter like USBC. And I know
Speaker 1:  that, but it's true. Like if they need, if they need to
Speaker 1:  put 90 Watts into some ultra powerful M series
Speaker 1:  chip, then like you might as well have a dedicated power
Speaker 1:  adapter.
Speaker 6:  It's going to be a powerful chip. I think it's not going to be as powerful
Speaker 6:  as like the big power users want it to be. Right. Like, I don't think
Speaker 6:  it's going to be the thing that every, like all the video programmers and
Speaker 6:  audio producers and stuff, just Chuck out their 16 inch and go
Speaker 6:  get, I think they're going to, like, I think it's, it's going to be less
Speaker 6:  powerful than that because apple is going to wait until that
Speaker 6:  big Mac pro to really show off like how good it is at
Speaker 6:  processing. But I think, I think it's like, I think this is going to be
Speaker 6:  kind of their half step between the Mac book air, like, right. This is just
Speaker 6:  the little step up of like slightly more powerful, slightly more
Speaker 6:  power hungry and look a nicer, bigger screen and
Speaker 6:  ports.
Speaker 1:  I know, I think that they already have that in the 13 inch MacBook pro, which
Speaker 1:  is like, what if this computer had a fan? Yeah. Right. And then the
Speaker 1:  16 inch pro. And if they do a 14 inch pro, which I think is one of the
Speaker 1:  whispers and the Hamilton
Speaker 5:  And 16 of the rim is like,
Speaker 1:  Those are that's their like bread and butter pro machine. Those things have
Speaker 1:  to be fast. So I don't know. We'll see. I just think that they ran into
Speaker 1:  the Ooh, USBC was a mistake. We might've sold put a
Speaker 1:  power port back on here. Cause we need to pull that much power from a
Speaker 1:  dedicated USBC brick. They can,
Speaker 5:  They can be like, what they did with the Mac approach is like, you know,
Speaker 5:  we heard you, this is what we've got sort of thing. Yeah. Like they can,
Speaker 5:  they can do that. I don't know. Yeah. I'm like with diva there, I'm not
Speaker 5:  sure whether they have enough time to cram it
Speaker 5:  in.
Speaker 1:  I mean, based on our preview here, they could be like, watch it last. Like
Speaker 1:  whatever nothing happened on his
Speaker 1:  back, we are at an
Speaker 1:  hour in. We need to take a break and talk about the next version of
Speaker 1:  windows. I will say. I doubt anything of note is
Speaker 1:  happening in TBOs because all of Apple's efforts, aren't getting the apple
Speaker 1:  TV app on other platforms, including the Nvidia
Speaker 1:  shield. Huh? See positive shield
Speaker 1:  mentioned. Think about that before you send your emails and the rest of Android
Speaker 1:  TV. It, that seems where their efforts are. They just released
Speaker 1:  new box Criswell trivia. The new box through new remote is great. You
Speaker 1:  should buy it. And it's amazing. Apple can get another $70
Speaker 1:  out of me if we can. Entire Google TV is 50 bucks. So
Speaker 1:  because, okay, we're gonna take a break. We'll be right back talking about
Speaker 1:  windows.
Speaker ?:  This episode of Vergecast brought to you by Cornell. If he wants you to advance
Speaker ?:  your career without stepping out of your job, look no further than today's
Speaker ?:  sponsor E Cornell with over 120 online certificates in
Speaker ?:  today's most in demand skills. Taking a program with Cornell is a great way
Speaker ?:  to better your professional self. So he wants to further your work on your
Speaker ?:  professional expertise and preserve the strides you've already made. Try
Speaker ?:  Cornell visit E cornell.com and use code Vergecast for
Speaker ?:  20% off certificate programs. When you enroll more and more of these days,
Speaker ?:  we are conducting our everyday business remotely. And while there will always
Speaker ?:  be a place for doing things the old way, the convenience that comes with
Speaker ?:  online, learning changes, everything it's even changing. The way we learn
Speaker ?:  with Equinox, you can gain skills in your field without interrupting your
Speaker ?:  career. You Cornell offers over 120 online certificate programs to
Speaker ?:  choose from, and they're flexible. So while you're learning about data science,
Speaker ?:  project management or web design, your career doesn't get put on hold
Speaker ?:  equals 100% online classes, feature coursework that can be done anywhere.
Speaker ?:  Anytime and most certificate programs can be completed in two to four
Speaker ?:  months. And while some other online programs might lack that personal interaction
Speaker ?:  and feedback from instructors, Equinox, doesn't sacrifice it courses are
Speaker ?:  developed by Cornell university faculty, and you'll enjoy meaningful conversations
Speaker ?:  about coursework with instructors who have a wealth of knowledge in their
Speaker ?:  field. Plus you get worthwhile discussion with peers, from industry, from
Speaker ?:  all over the world. Take the next step with a professional certificate
Speaker ?:  from Cornell university is the cornell.com today and use code of
Speaker ?:  Vergecast for 20% off certificate programs. When you
Speaker ?:  enroll Let's get real the tech world, doesn't always like to keep
Speaker ?:  it simple from over-hyped products to constant sales pitches and endless
Speaker ?:  jargon shopping for quality electronics can be overwhelming, but it doesn't
Speaker ?:  have to be cut through the usual BS with high sense, high census, the
Speaker ?:  straight talking electronics brand that offers clarity and quality over confusion
Speaker ?:  because let's get real. The most important thing about a great TV is that
Speaker ?:  it's actually a great TV with all the features you love like their new
Speaker ?:  you D series, whether you're watching movies with the kids, enjoying a
Speaker ?:  date night or comfort, watching that show for the million time. High sense
Speaker ?:  brings you an unmatched 4k TV experience and with a range of
Speaker ?:  sizes there you led series is bringing premium products to the
Speaker ?:  masses. We can sit here and tell you all about the awesome features that
Speaker ?:  come with. High sense TVs features like quantum dot color HDR, 10 plus,
Speaker ?:  and Dolby Atmos, but all you really need to know is that high sense
Speaker ?:  offers unbeatable quality at unbelievable prices.
Speaker ?:  Forget the jargon and get real to learn more, visit high
Speaker ?:  sense.com today. That's high sense.com high
Speaker ?:  sense. Let's get
Speaker ?:  real.
Speaker 1:  We're back. Tom, are they going to skip another
Speaker 1:  number? That's what I want to know. So
Speaker 5:  You want it to be windows 12 or when there's
Speaker 5:  13? I think I can exclusively reveal the
Speaker 5:  name. Okay. This is a Vergecast it's clear. So it's gonna be windows
Speaker 5:  nine. It's going to go back
Speaker 5:  to
Speaker 5:  the one they missed. Yeah. But when they let it get
Speaker 5:  away, but yeah, like it
Speaker 5:  looks like it's going to be windows 11. I think that's at least that's what
Speaker 5:  Microsoft wants us to
Speaker 1:  Think. Okay. So it's going to be windows 20.
Speaker 4:  How are they going to justify saying just kidding. When we said we're never
Speaker 4:  going have a new version of windows as could be windows 10 forever, whatever
Speaker 4:  we promise. Wait,
Speaker 1:  Hold on. I have an idea. Open windows,
Speaker 1:  2000.
Speaker 5:  I see. I see. I think he's gonna, it's going to go one of two ways, right?
Speaker 5:  It's going to be one of freeways. It's going to be windows, windows, or
Speaker 5:  living or windows free six, five. Oh my God. Or
Speaker 5:  some fit or something. You know, like windows
Speaker 5:  series,
Speaker 5:  windows series. X-Box
Speaker 5:  confident that the, the name or branding
Speaker 1:  Around this is Xbox live colon
Speaker 1:  windows.
Speaker 4:  Oh, it's it's it's going to be, it's going to be Azure intelligent edge
Speaker 4:  iOS.
Speaker 3:  Okay.
Speaker 1:  So what do we know about windows a windows
Speaker 1:  2000?
Speaker 5:  Well, windows 2000 came, so windows 11. So, so they've
Speaker 5:  put out, they've been teasing us for months. So panel said the next
Speaker 5:  generation back ignite such in Adela even just a week
Speaker 5:  ago, said like this is gonna be the biggest change to windows in like a decade
Speaker 5:  and the next generation of windows. And then they put out this
Speaker 5:  invite, which is basically, it's just saying, we're talking about the next
Speaker 5:  generation of the windows, but also alongside at
Speaker 5:  the invite has like a, sort of a shadow light pulling
Speaker 5:  through the window, but it doesn't have the vertical bars at the horizontal
Speaker 5:  bars. Right. So it just looks like it's the shadows creeping in so
Speaker 5:  11 and nine  maybe not
Speaker 5:  like, you know, everyone overanalyzes apple invites. So like
Speaker 5:  whatever the event starts at 11:00 AM
Speaker 5:  of surface and windows events never usually start at that time. It's usually
Speaker 5:  like nine or 10:00 AM. So it's kind of could be
Speaker 5:  confidential. And then one of the mitotic sets is put on
Speaker 5:  Twitter. I'm lucky. Can't wait for this new version of windows. So
Speaker 5:  no, I've not heard them say a new version of windows. Like that's
Speaker 5:  different language than they've used. They've always said the next generation
Speaker 5:  of windows, whatever that means. So I think that combining those three
Speaker 5:  things together is why I think there's gonna be some sort of naming
Speaker 5:  happening here, like a new, a new windows name.
Speaker 1:  What does a new windows name mean? So as Dieter was saying, when they did
Speaker 1:  windows 10, they're like, we're just gonna update windows 10 forever. This
Speaker 1:  is that. Here we are. What does it mean to have a new name? Is it
Speaker 1:  signifying a strategy shift? Is it a new product, a new interface?
Speaker 5:  Yes. I think, I think the new name probably signifies a bit more
Speaker 5:  of a reinvestment in windows. So these, they split up windows into two parts
Speaker 5:  internally a few years ago and then panel sort of came on
Speaker 5:  board and then the pandemic kit and like that combination of like
Speaker 5:  penicillin taken over windows and the pandemic, the resurgence of like
Speaker 5:  PC computing. Cause people see trying to work from
Speaker 5:  home that has made them think, oh, actually, you know, there are still like
Speaker 5:  wherever it is 1.3 billion people using this operating system every day.
Speaker 5:  So we should probably fix things
Speaker 3:  Like make it a bit better,
Speaker 5:  Make it like look better and stuff. So I think it's the opportunity of
Speaker 5:  doing all that, fixing up work, a new
Speaker 5:  UI and all that sort of stuff is probably just led them to the point of
Speaker 5:  like, we should just call it this something different. You know, like they
Speaker 5:  were trying this thing called windows 10 X. It was going to be on
Speaker 5:  Juul screen devices before the pandemic hit. And then they were like, we're
Speaker 5:  going to put it on single screen devices. And then they were like, you know
Speaker 5:  what, we're just going to take all of the work that we did on that. Like
Speaker 5:  the good UI work and a good bits of like reorganizing windows,
Speaker 5:  essentially making it a bit more lightweight and we're going to put it into
Speaker 5:  windows. And I think that's what this is. So like a lot of that work. So
Speaker 5:  it's, it's basically consists of like free things. It's like you, I
Speaker 5:  work new store and it's some rumors about that. We can get into
Speaker 5:  that. And then the final thing is, is basically
Speaker 5:  I try and I just completely lost my train of thought, but yeah, new
Speaker 5:  store, new UI and like a more of an opportunity for app developers, I
Speaker 5:  think, and like opening up a little bit. I think
Speaker 5:  probably bringing some of the walls of the store down will help with that
Speaker 1:  Because they want to be in that app distribution game. Like
Speaker 5:  Yeah, like they have realized, I think I've had like conversations with
Speaker 5:  panels in the past. Like when you, when you took over from windows site,
Speaker 5:  like conversations with him in briefings about windows and like
Speaker 5:  expressing like the way that I see windows and other people who use it
Speaker 5:  frequently says that it's like a tool, right? It's the, it is like, you
Speaker 5:  know, a productivity tool or whatever. But I think a lot of the time they've
Speaker 5:  been chasing like the wrong set of people for it. Like they did this creators
Speaker 5:  update, they tried to create to go for that group of people that didn't really
Speaker 5:  work out and he keep, they kept, they've constantly be trying to chase
Speaker 5:  growth for windows rather than just realize that it's valuable
Speaker 5:  to a lot of people and that they can improve it and build upon it, fix
Speaker 5:  things that will make it more valuable to those people rather than having
Speaker 5:  to, you know, add another a hundred million people using it or
Speaker 5:  whatever. So I think that they have finally come to realize
Speaker 5:  that and perhaps a lot of that's to do with the pandemic learnings and stuff
Speaker 1:  And the absolute growth in PC sales. Right. I mean, it's like
Speaker 1:  explosive growth in PC sales.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And like OEMs have obviously seen them experiment with these versions
Speaker 5:  of windows over the years, like 10 S and 10 X was another
Speaker 5:  experiment. And like they've been waiting for like, for OEMs having a
Speaker 5:  different name windows like a, a version that they can
Speaker 5:  sell attached to hardware. It's like a gold mine for them. Cause like, it's,
Speaker 5:  it just immediately generates like hype and interest in products like, oh,
Speaker 5:  there's a new word windows working, oh, I should get a new laptop. Like it
Speaker 5:  triggers, you know, consumer spending and all that sort of stuff. And
Speaker 5:  obviously on the enterprise as
Speaker 1:  Well. Do you think we just want to be able to reuse the letters or like,
Speaker 1:  oh, we want to do another S windows 11
Speaker 1:  S it is. Cause I mean, that, that strategy was to,
Speaker 1:  to apply in SIFY windows.
Speaker 4:  Well, so it was also to take on Chromebooks. Right. And so if they're, yeah,
Speaker 4:  if they, they've never succeeded at making there's the S
Speaker 4:  mode, you know, they've never really succeeded at making like a light
Speaker 4:  version of windows. Do you think they're giving up on that dream or is it
Speaker 4:  that somehow part of this? I think that's
Speaker 5:  Part of this. I think like some of it is obviously making it a bit more lightweight,
Speaker 5:  the UX improvements, but I think the tennis stuff was more than just competing
Speaker 5:  with Chrome iOS. It was also like control with the operating system
Speaker 5:  who's taking that control back. And there's, there's many legitimate
Speaker 5:  reasons to that. Like ransomware that we're seeing across the world happens
Speaker 5:  on windows computers, because they're open blah, blah, blah. But the
Speaker 5:  way they win ahead, they force people down a route where they'd have to package
Speaker 5:  their apps into the store. It's very much like the iOS debate, right? Like
Speaker 5:  apple has all the control over the app store. That's the control that Microsoft
Speaker 5:  ultimately wanted wherever they wanted the same sort of control, who knows.
Speaker 5:  But I think that was the primary driving driver there. And it's way like
Speaker 5:  Tim Sweeney, he was dead against that sort of app model. And I think the
Speaker 5:  realization with windows now is that that stuff is just not never really
Speaker 5:  going to work for windows. They're never going to truly make it lightweight
Speaker 5:  unless they just blow it up and do something totally new, which I guess 10
Speaker 5:  X was like trying to go down that route by fixing the
Speaker 5:  realization of like who uses windows and what this
Speaker 5:  product is for. I think that's, that's, that's the main
Speaker 1:  Thing. So they did the surface Neo and the duo at the same
Speaker 1:  time, the duo runs Android. And they'd, you know,
Speaker 1:  we heard all the stories about how they work with Android and Hiroshi at
Speaker 1:  Google and pantos at, at Microsoft or like tweet and hearts. And he shared
Speaker 1:  with her that product has like kind of gone nowhere. It was just
Speaker 1:  deeply discounted. I seriously considered impulse buying one. And then I
Speaker 1:  didn't because I was like, I don't, it's essentially a fire sale right now.
Speaker 1:  I don't go anywhere. So I don't need another phone, the social one
Speaker 1:  that flips over and do a slightly bigger fund maybe next year
Speaker 1:  that's over there. And then the Neo was 10 X dual
Speaker 1:  screen. And the entire story we heard was like, dual screens are the future
Speaker 1:  of productivity. You want to do two things at once on a phone,
Speaker 1:  you need to run two apps, the assignment side by side, over here, we're
Speaker 1:  rearchitecting windows for dual screens. Once again,
Speaker 1:  the future of productivity that appears to be out the window,
Speaker 5:  Yes. Tastes totally out the window like that. They don't talk about the Niro
Speaker 5:  at all anymore. Like he's basically a canceled product right now because
Speaker 5:  the operating system that powers, it doesn't exist anymore. They're bringing
Speaker 5:  that to windows. So what
Speaker 6:  Happens to all those like laptops from the OEMs, because they were
Speaker 6:  all kind of going all in on it too. And
Speaker 5:  You really Lenovo really went all in and actually launched their X one,
Speaker 5:  fold, ThinkPad, X pump fold, or whatever it was called. And that was supposed
Speaker 5:  to come, you know, 10 X was gonna come to that. So I don't know what happens
Speaker 5:  there, but I'm sure the two people that brought one,
Speaker 5:  we're not going to be disappointed.
Speaker 6:  Well, I know, because we saw, like we saw a Seuss, did like, they're there
Speaker 6:  too. They're kind of dual monitor. And I think they're still doing it right.
Speaker 6:  Where they have like the little monitor down at the bottom and stuff. And
Speaker 6:  I know Dell kept saying they were going to, and then kind of stepped
Speaker 6:  back and said, they're going to, and it just like, did they all just say,
Speaker 6:  oh, the, the display technology and everything else that needs to be there
Speaker 6:  just isn't there. And windows at the same time said,
Speaker 6:  nah,
Speaker 5:  Yeah, that sort of stuff is slightly different to the sort of windows, 10
Speaker 5:  X stuff. So that was just like pure windows. And like, they were doing like
Speaker 5:  custom OEM, like panels above the keyboard and stuff like that to, to
Speaker 5:  power that. And like, they've those OEMs have experimented with that
Speaker 5:  sort of stuff for years. So I think that stuff will still be there and we'll
Speaker 5:  still see, I just don't, I don't think much is going to support it in like
Speaker 5:  a big effort. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  I, just, to me that what really drives the upgrade
Speaker 1:  cycle is a form factor change. When we just, we know this
Speaker 1:  thing, we even note inside of the iPhone, like the change, the way the iPhone
Speaker 1:  looks, everybody buys a new iPhone. This is just happened with the iPhone
Speaker 1:  12, even while lots of people were at home, lots of people bought iPhone
Speaker 1:  12 because they looked different to me. It's like it is to me, the
Speaker 1:  silliest, but most consistent thing I know about technology is if you want
Speaker 1:  people to buy a new one, you just change the way it looks. It
Speaker 1:  can. The iPod is like the example, like the
Speaker 1:  iPod rarely got new functionality, but every year they made it look different.
Speaker 1:  And I was like, I need a new iPad. And
Speaker 5:  It's kind of like the reverse at the moment. Cause it's like, what's driving
Speaker 5:  PC growth is the reverse, like people who are going from picking up their
Speaker 5:  phones to being like, I need something to work on. Like I can't, I,
Speaker 5:  you know, I usually have something in the office or at school or
Speaker 5:  whatever, and I don't have that now. So I need, I need something. So it's
Speaker 5:  like, it's still a form factor thing. That's driving it. But it's just the
Speaker 5:  opposite way. Like we, we used to everyone buying mobile phones and just
Speaker 5:  not really touching desktop PCs or laptops as
Speaker 5:  frequently. And that's, that's driving this, this group at the
Speaker 5:  moment who knows, once everything starts to go hybrid work or
Speaker 5:  whatever you want to call it, how that shakes out. Like, I'm sure the growth
Speaker 5:  will go away somewhat, but then do they pick
Speaker 5:  that chore screen
Speaker 1:  Stuff up? Yeah, Mike, that's what I'm saying. Microsoft was like gung ho
Speaker 1:  on form factor change. Cause they thought they could crack back into the
Speaker 1:  phone market and they could do something to juice the
Speaker 1:  PC market and now they've dropped it cause they didn't, they kind of didn't
Speaker 1:  need it. Like Monica, Shannon. I just interviewed the CEO of Acer. Acer just
Speaker 1:  had its best quarter in years and they're just like making
Speaker 1:  everything and we kept asking it like, w what's your bet?
Speaker 1:  Like, is it Chromebooks? Is it windows on arm? Is it whatever? And he was
Speaker 1:  like, yeah, we're just gonna make whatever, like everyone's buying everything.
Speaker 1:  We're good.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. They're in like that. It's, it's almost like the two
Speaker 5:  thousands sort of era of PCs at the moment, just because there's such a demand
Speaker 5:  for them, an unusual amount of demand. So Acer is
Speaker 5:  definitely well-positioned for that sort of stuff, because they can just
Speaker 5:  experiment and people, people will buy it. But yeah,
Speaker 5:  like the fact that Microsoft was, you know, it was basically putting
Speaker 5:  its, its surface brand on the line here for like a Juul screen device and
Speaker 5:  stuff. And it has obviously on the Android side, it's surprising
Speaker 5:  that they dropped it so quick during the pandemic and they get, and I feel
Speaker 5:  like they kind of used it as like, I don't want to say an excuse, but like
Speaker 5:  it's definitely like, I don't think he was getting the way that they thought
Speaker 5:  it was going to go the development cycle on it. So it was like, it was a
Speaker 5:  good point in time for them to like, sort of say, okay, let's not do
Speaker 5:  this right now. Let's focus more on windows.
Speaker 5:  But yeah, like I'm curious to see where they go with that in the future.
Speaker 5:  And there's like, there's rumors about like this windows 11 stuff that they
Speaker 5:  might bring back some of the touch stuff that they kind of did
Speaker 5:  widgets, seeing some stuff that flying around about
Speaker 5:  that. I've got a feeling that they're doing quite a
Speaker 5:  lot and a lot hasn't leaked. Cause they've, they've somehow managed to keep
Speaker 5:  it very tight. So I feel like there's gonna be a lot, a
Speaker 5:  lot that we won't know until the event. How extensive
Speaker 6:  Is the user interface change going to be? Because like with
Speaker 6:  windows 10, they did like a surface change and then
Speaker 6:  you'd go to menus and, and you just be back in seven.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Like I think a lot of it is cleaning up. Like they've been
Speaker 5:  sort of working on this over the last sort of couple of years, like some
Speaker 5:  of the icons staff, the system icons or all that sort of stuff, like
Speaker 5:  cleaning up, you know, when you like open up a driver installation and then
Speaker 5:  suddenly you feel like you're back in windows 95, like that should not be
Speaker 5:  happening. So I think some of that will be going
Speaker 5:  away and I'd hope that all of it goes away, but like I just can't see it
Speaker 5:  all fully going away. And then it's like, there's a focus on like rounded
Speaker 5:  corners, a new start menu, a lot of the stuff you saw in 10 X
Speaker 5:  where they simplified like the fly outs and a task bar and like basic stuff
Speaker 5:  like controlling volume, all that sort of stuff. It looks a bit more like
Speaker 5:  mobile friendly, almost like a bit more tablet touch friendly as well.
Speaker 5:  Cause I think they really stepped back from that stuff in windows 10.
Speaker 1:  Well, because it went so badly with eight it's, like the pendulum is swinging,
Speaker 1:  right. Like, and we just spent all this time talking about apple.
Speaker 1:  Microsoft has a giant installed base of touchscreen pieces.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. They've got a lot of data on how people actually use them. Right. And
Speaker 5:  the things that they want to do with them, which is usually just like get
Speaker 5:  that notification
Speaker 3:  Or like,
Speaker 5:  But yeah, like I'm curious to see where they go with that stuff. If they're
Speaker 5:  bringing widgets back and let slide to bring in widgets and stuff like
Speaker 5:  that, like, I dunno, I feel like they're going to add some stuff
Speaker 5:  that a lot of people are just going to turn off. Right. But I hope
Speaker 5:  that they get to the point where they don't have to do stuff like force edge
Speaker 5:  down your throat or force being down your throat. And some of those sort
Speaker 5:  of businessy decisions that they tried to do to obviously, you
Speaker 5:  know, make things seem
Speaker 5:  relevant and seemed like it has
Speaker 5:  users and also like generate some search and ad revenue
Speaker 5:  and that sort of stuff. Like I hate they get away from that. Cause I want
Speaker 5:  to type into my start menu and have it search the web on
Speaker 5:  the provider that I wanted to do and to open up the browser that I have set
Speaker 5:  as a default. So I'm hoping that they kind of do that sort of stuff as well.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. It's, it's one tap for being two taps for Google. Is
Speaker 1:  there, if there's going to hide it behind a series of
Speaker 1:  incomprehensible finger presses,
Speaker 5:  But th the second fit, like the user interface, things I think is going to
Speaker 5:  be, you know, it's going to be just smashing windows up. And if your windows
Speaker 5:  is terrible, it's just like, they haven't, whenever they've done stuff like
Speaker 5:  dark mode, they've not really, they've done it 75% of the
Speaker 5:  way. And it's those little cracks that may let some signs you're rape and
Speaker 5:  stuff up. And you're like, eh, why does it look like
Speaker 5:  that? And it's like, I think going to a hundred
Speaker 5:  percent on that sort of stuff will make a big difference. It's, it's very
Speaker 5:  minor stuff, but ultimately all the little cuts add up.
Speaker 5:  So
Speaker 6:  That going to go to like the app developers. Cause I know with, with,
Speaker 6:  like when you look at backhoe S it has all these really good and good
Speaker 6:  looking apps that it's because like apple kind of thinks about how
Speaker 6:  things look and windows is just kind of like, it works go
Speaker 6:  like, are they going to be trying to push that more with this new app
Speaker 6:  store?
Speaker 5:  Well, yeah, not necessarily the app store, but like, they have been
Speaker 5:  trying to push that with a lot of the API work over the years. And there
Speaker 5:  are some like, better looking windows apps, because, because of it, but I
Speaker 5:  will say like, as a desktop operating system, I can't think
Speaker 5:  of an app that's launched in the last five years. That's important
Speaker 5:  apart from browser updates, right? Like kids. Yeah. It's at that
Speaker 5:  point where the entry for iterative versions of like Adobe
Speaker 5:  creative suite, but like big news, but like, there's never usually a new
Speaker 5:  app that comes along,
Speaker 1:  You know, I dunno. They're all electronic apps. That's the
Speaker 1:  province.
Speaker 5:  They're web apps browser, basically. This is I'm telling
Speaker 4:  You WWD, let me WDC three hours of web
Speaker 4:  apps, PWAs. Let's
Speaker 4:  go, Tom, when is this event?
Speaker 5:  June 24th. But the, the other thing, the other big thing is the store. So
Speaker 5:  they're going to open that up and allow like Chrome and Firefox and stuff.
Speaker 5:  You know, that, remember when they opened the store and they were like, Chrome,
Speaker 5:  can't be in there. Everyone was like, my browser that I use, can't be
Speaker 5:  okay. You can't sit with us. And they're also gonna allow third
Speaker 5:  third-party payment process processes through
Speaker 1:  The store. They're just going to come for app. I see what they're doing.
Speaker 1:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Like, yeah. So that's another big part of this as well. And then it's
Speaker 5:  just like fixing up stuff like multi Monter Monter Monter to support some,
Speaker 5:  some Bluetooth stack stuff that they should have fixed years
Speaker 5:  ago. Yeah. It's like the big fix. I think it
Speaker 5:  justifies a new version. So
Speaker 1:  The 24th, 11:00 AM wherever you are or wherever Microsoft
Speaker 1:  is in all times zones at 11:00
Speaker 1:  AM. Yeah. All right. We're going to take a break. We have more operating.
Speaker 1:  So this is talking about this wild adventure on this show we were at
Speaker 1:  back.
Speaker ?:  This episode of our show has brought to you by story blocks. If you're a
Speaker ?:  content creator, marketer or freelancer, it's time to ditch the pictures
Speaker ?:  taken on your phone or the sock puppet infotainment pieces. You keep shooting
Speaker ?:  on your webcam. It's time to get Storybox with a subscription to
Speaker ?:  Storybox. You get access to a demand driven over 1 million high quality stock
Speaker ?:  assets, which includes 4k footage after effects and premiere pro
Speaker ?:  templates and a host of sound effects, music, and more. If you're tired of
Speaker ?:  whitewash, stock libraries, Starbucks, here's you with a restock initiative,
Speaker ?:  they've committed to ensuring that 20% of their footage portrays people of
Speaker ?:  color and those in the black and indigenous communities by 2022,
Speaker ?:  and they're hiring a diverse array of filmmakers to make it happen by capturing
Speaker ?:  authentic experiences of underrepresented communities, like people of color
Speaker ?:  and the LGBTQ plus communities. Starbucks has affordable
Speaker ?:  subscription plans to fit any budget. And with the unlimited all access plan,
Speaker ?:  you get endless downloads of everything in their library. Those assets are
Speaker ?:  not only royalty free, meaning you can use them anywhere for commercial and
Speaker ?:  personal use. They're also yours forever. Even if your subscription ends
Speaker ?:  everything you download stays with you. So try Starbucks today, explore the
Speaker ?:  library and subscribe, say it's storybox.com/verge that's
Speaker ?:  storybox.com/verge. What secrets do matchmakers have up their
Speaker ?:  sleeves to find the perfect match, some consult with the stars. Others will
Speaker ?:  listen to what you say you want. And then read between the lines. When you're
Speaker ?:  talking about finding the right candidate to fill a job, indeed has their
Speaker ?:  own set of tools to help you find the perfect fit, take their skills test
Speaker ?:  feature. You can use it to measure more than 130 different skills and perspective
Speaker ?:  hires, including hard skills, personality tests, and work samples. Indeed
Speaker ?:  says these tests reduce hiring times by 27% or the instant
Speaker ?:  match feature, which delivers quality matches over 80% of the time for a
Speaker ?:  sponsored job post with indeed, you can get a shortlist of quality candidates
Speaker ?:  whose resumes match your job description. Then you can schedule video interviews
Speaker ?:  to see if a natural work and you only pay for the ones who meet your must
Speaker ?:  have qualities. Indeed helps you match the right candidate to the job fast
Speaker ?:  and easy. Get started now with a free $75 sponsor job credit
Speaker ?:  to upgrade your job post at indeed.com/vergecast. Once again,
Speaker ?:  get a $75 credit at indeed.com/vergecast
Speaker ?:  offer valid through June 30th terms and conditions
Speaker ?:  apply.
Speaker 1:  All right, we're back. There's more operating systems to talk about. That's
Speaker 1:  the real week of operating systems,
Speaker 1:  including from Google, but really the news
Speaker 1:  here, Dieter, I'm gonna let you walk us through this while a basically got
Speaker 1:  banned from using Android from, by the Trump administration, basically they
Speaker 1:  were put on the entity list, which was still a great name. And now
Speaker 1:  they've created a new us, which is not Android, but like
Speaker 1:  it's, it's like three Android and a trench
Speaker 1:  coat. It's
Speaker 1:  called POS. They should've called it
Speaker 1:  entity.
Speaker 3:  It's not, it's not
Speaker 4:  Three Androids and a trench coat. It's like three Androids in a very pretty
Speaker 4:  trench coat with like flowers in it. It's
Speaker 4:  like flows in the wind. It looks fine. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  But like ours tactic actually did some really good deep dives on here. When
Speaker 4:  you actually ask Huawei about it. They're like, yeah, it's
Speaker 4:  different. It's like, no, we, we all know it's based on Android, which is
Speaker 4:  frustrating because they could just admit it, right. Like Android
Speaker 4:  is open source, Google can't directly offer stuff to Huawei,
Speaker 4:  but like it's out there, Google can't stop them there. I'm sure there's some
Speaker 4:  way they could get around it. I don't know. And it is also weird cause like
Speaker 4:  how long we just spent talking about needing competition and more app stores
Speaker 4:  and whatever. And we're all just sort of turning our nose up at harmony LS
Speaker 4:  before it's even out. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  I mean, Huawei is the biggest player in phones in China still and thereabouts
Speaker 1:  and standby for two years ago. We actually, I actually have Sam update this
Speaker 1:  piece, but he did a whole piece about how the Chinese smartphone
Speaker 1:  market is ultra competitive. There are lots of different apps for us, lots
Speaker 1:  of them, forks of Android. They all use complete reps of the iPhone camera
Speaker 1:  app, which is amazing. How
Speaker 4:  Many of us actually, if you will actually a better way to describe it as
Speaker 4:  three Androids in a, in a iPhone look and
Speaker 4:  trench,
Speaker 1:  But so that's like, that is always fascinating to me. Like why does
Speaker 1:  the camera app get ripped off the most? It's because it's the thing that
Speaker 1:  everybody uses and lowering the switching cost of the camera app is good.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. It's, it's just as dead simple as that. Like, it is not worthwhile
Speaker 1:  to innovate on how the camera app works because you want people to pick up
Speaker 1:  a new phone and be able to do the thing they're going to do the most without
Speaker 1:  any cognitive load whatsoever. Then you can be like, we have
Speaker 1:  ideas about notifications and like, just go down that
Speaker 1:  road. But it's the market in China is just like booming with Android
Speaker 1:  forks. And so harming us is going to be a big player in that. And it is
Speaker 1:  true because we don't get these phones are like, ha, you're not allowed
Speaker 1:  to use Android. And then while we was like, but we are.
Speaker 1:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Well, and it's also like, we, we won't bother we think any, any
Speaker 4:  Android phone that doesn't have the Google play store as a failure, but it's
Speaker 4:  actually like, I wouldn't mind having alternative afterwards. I wish that
Speaker 4:  don't know Amazon app store was good, but what you need are Google's apps
Speaker 4:  and Google will never put its apps on anything that doesn't have Google's
Speaker 4:  play store and all those exclusivity agreements. Anyway,
Speaker 4:  harmony was coming. There's also harmony Wes on the hallway watch, but it
Speaker 4:  seems like that's really just a rebrand of light O S which was the version
Speaker 4:  that they ran their watches on before, because nothing runs on where
Speaker 4:  until the new version of where that's merging with Tyson comes
Speaker 4:  out. I like
Speaker 6:  The optimism that something will run on where then
Speaker 6:  I
Speaker 3:  Look
Speaker 4:  And then they teased, but did not really release the
Speaker 4:  Huawei P 50, which looks amazing. There are two
Speaker 4:  giant like owl eye camera rays on the back, just like
Speaker 4:  big, giant circles with cameras in them to go for it. It's just, they
Speaker 4:  just went for it. It looks great. And then you're like, oh, and you're releasing
Speaker 4:  it. And this is the quote from the company quote, we're
Speaker 4:  trying to figure out how to make this great product available to
Speaker 4:  you. Would you like to,
Speaker 4:  would you like to read the chip shortage to do that? Would you like to read
Speaker 4:  the entity, listen to that? Which you, any number of things are keeping
Speaker 4:  us from having this great product made available to us.
Speaker 4:  But yeah. That's I love, I love it's not like coming weeks. It's like, we're
Speaker 4:  actually, we're trying to figure out how to release this thing. You don't
Speaker 4:  know if we can't or if it's going
Speaker 3:  To happen. That's amazing.
Speaker 1:  Okay. And then there's fuchsia, which we've been
Speaker 1:  diligently tracking the status of Google's fuchsia for
Speaker 1:  years. And they finally did a thing. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  It's arriving on the original nest hub, formerly known
Speaker 4:  as the Google home. Oh my God. It is just going to be the
Speaker 4:  underlying, nothing's going to change about its functionality or features.
Speaker 4:  It's just, it's going to run on top of fuchsia. Now, if
Speaker 1:  All they said was it's going to be faster. I would be so happy.
Speaker 1:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Well, I guess we'll see whether or not this is a
Speaker 4:  stepping stone towards fuchsia. Doing more things is
Speaker 4:  unclear. The thing that amuses me the most, isn't the
Speaker 4:  confusion about whether fuchsia is going to be the future foundation
Speaker 4:  of phones and tablets and laptops and whatever it isn't.
Speaker 4:  If it's going to replace Android and chromo S it's
Speaker 4:  that Google's smart home
Speaker 4:  gadgets now run on
Speaker 4:  caste fuchsia. And I'm pretty sure there's some like Android
Speaker 4:  home floating around in the world somewhere. So the
Speaker 4:  Google literally doesn't care what LS runs. Its gadgets. It's basically,
Speaker 4:  they'll just let whatever. Yeah. If you show you, you, you bought ready shirt,
Speaker 4:  they will throw it. Oh
Speaker 3:  Shit. I was just
Speaker 1:  Deeply confusing. Why they even announced this? Yeah. Because like
Speaker 1:  it, they could have just done it. And then like the fuchsia team would have
Speaker 1:  been like happy. Yeah. And they would have had a secret and they would have
Speaker 1:  walked the streets of San Francisco, the glimmer in their eyes. They knew
Speaker 1:  something that you didn't know. No.
Speaker 4:  The way this news broke is like, somebody from the future team was like,
Speaker 4:  it's not every day ship a new OOS. And it was like, wait,
Speaker 4:  what's
Speaker 5:  A secret. We installed a Linux micro
Speaker 5:  kernel
Speaker 3:  Got away with it,
Speaker 1:  But you announce it and all this. And then, and they're like, no, it's gonna
Speaker 1:  be exactly the same. And so we've taken the glimmer in the eye is
Speaker 1:  gone. Now everybody knows the secret. And the secret is nothing has
Speaker 1:  changed.
Speaker 6:  It's such a let down to like, like the early
Speaker 6:  hypoperfusion was just going to be, it was going to be totally different
Speaker 6:  to replace Android. Yeah. It was going to replace Android. It was going to
Speaker 6:  be incredible. It was going to be amazing. And now it's on like a
Speaker 6:  Google device. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  That you're really not supposed to interact
Speaker 1:  with.
Speaker 3:  Like
Speaker 1:  They've you are not supposed to touch it so much that the new one
Speaker 1:  encourages you to just wave at it instead of touching. It's
Speaker 1:  pretty good. I will say I've, I've stopped a lot of timers. Like very
Speaker 1:  insistently. It's good. Slap it. I get why they did it. It's
Speaker 1:  just like, stop. I know the rice is done.
Speaker 1:  You shut up. I think that's it for operating systems, Tom,
Speaker 1:  before we go, I want to, I want to end with a segment on, on the
Speaker 1:  30 ADTs. Cause you have one a day. You're like one to five people and they're
Speaker 1:  like, are you afraid for your safety? I also
Speaker 5:  Manage to buy one today. I kind of did it as a half test,
Speaker 5:  but
Speaker 1:  Now it's now you're showing off
Speaker 1:  start some Bitcoins.
Speaker 3:  I don't know. I don't know how any of that works during some
Speaker 3:  days.
Speaker 5:  I think that's how it works. Yes. The first year at UCLA.
Speaker 5:  So I reviewed it. It's, you know, better than the 30,
Speaker 5:  80 as you'd expect for 4k in 10, eight, 14,
Speaker 5:  40 P gamey. But I think it's a little bit pricey for Ford. It is,
Speaker 5:  especially in this market, like, and even today we're seeing them, like,
Speaker 5:  I think I looked at some UK parts and it was like supposed to be
Speaker 5:  1,049 pounds. And like people were sending them on eBay for two and a half
Speaker 5:  thousand pounds right now. So it's like, yeah, but it's,
Speaker 5:  it's a good card. It's pretty much as close as you can get to the 30 19,
Speaker 5:  which is the $1,500 card. But I think if you're spending
Speaker 5:  1200, $1,500 on a, on a, on a card, like it's, it's a
Speaker 5:  kind of a niche area of, of, of GPS that I
Speaker 5:  think. And I think the 38 is just like the bargain card
Speaker 5:  really for the six, nine, nine. Like, I don't
Speaker 5:  know why you'd go for the 38 ETI really, unless you really wanted the extra,
Speaker 5:  like 10%
Speaker 1:  So. Well you can't, you can't get either. No.
Speaker 6:  How many 4k monitors do you need to justify? The
Speaker 6:  38.
Speaker 5:  Exactly. Yeah. Like you really have to really want to
Speaker 5:  play a little bit extra higher frame rate at
Speaker 5:  4k. And I think for most people they're making the move to, to 40,
Speaker 5:  40 P a lot of the, of the vast majority is still on 10 80 P
Speaker 5:  so yeah, I, I would buy the 30, 80, I think that would be my
Speaker 5:  recommendation over the 30 ATI, but you can't behave with them. So
Speaker 5:  yeah,
Speaker 1:  It is a very odd, we were looking at pictures. There were lines in front
Speaker 1:  of best buy here in the states. Like it's a very odd moment
Speaker 1:  for these products. It is. They're just not available.
Speaker 5:  It's unfortunate because they've so good. Like compared to the
Speaker 5:  previous generations, like he's come at like the worst possible time, a global
Speaker 5:  ship chip shortage in the middle of like, you know, when
Speaker 5:  everyone wants to buy a GPU and if one wants to buy a laptop and yeah,
Speaker 5:  everyone wants to do everything. So it's really unfortunate. And like, you
Speaker 5:  can't really fault in video for like competing with itself and watching another
Speaker 5:  card. And I know a lot of people were like, why are they launching this?
Speaker 5:  But it's like, you know, this is what these companies do. You didn't want
Speaker 5:  to want them to sort of stand, stand, still do so. But it's
Speaker 5:  unfortunate because no one can really buy them. There is signs though, like
Speaker 5:  the fact that I could buy once a day and also John and our team managed to
Speaker 5:  get 38 today. Like that, that's like a sign
Speaker 5:  of an, your bony UK. Yeah. So basically moves to the
Speaker 5:  UK.
Speaker 1:  The sound. This sounds like a scam. This sounds like some sort of British
Speaker 1:  Brexit scam. It's a boost to our population.
Speaker 3:  Now that one's disappeared.
Speaker 1:  C'mon member nations of the EU. We need individual trade agreements. We have
Speaker 1:  GPU's available. Let's get this done. You can mind
Speaker 1:  freely. Yeah. So what's actually really interesting with the chip shortage
Speaker 1:  thing is on several episodes. Dakota. Now people have told
Speaker 1:  me executives, the CEO flux told me that the CEO Ford told me this, the
Speaker 1:  shortages at old process nodes, right? It's at like
Speaker 1:  55 and 98 meters. These ships are Samsung eight
Speaker 1:  nanometers. Like the overall global chip shortage
Speaker 1:  is, is elsewhere. The demand for these
Speaker 1:  GPU's is there's not enough capacity, you know, it's, it is incredible
Speaker 1:  that there's this much demand for GPU's right now. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I mean, I think it's because Nvidia did the 20, 80 series and like,
Speaker 5:  they were good cards, but people were like, okay, I'll just hang out, hang
Speaker 5:  on to my 10 80 for a little bit longer. I'm gonna see what they do next.
Speaker 5:  And like, yeah. It took them while to do the next bit. And now people are
Speaker 5:  like, okay, I really need to upgrade now. So there, you know, people
Speaker 5:  even buying 28 is like off of eBay for like, you know, whatever the
Speaker 5:  crazy price is. They're like, well, over a thousand dollars. So which is
Speaker 5:  just nuts, like it's is, is a crazy situation. Really? You
Speaker 5:  can't
Speaker 1:  Discount the Bitcoin renderers. Yeah. I mean, I refuse to know
Speaker 1:  how that works. They rendering those coins every
Speaker 1:  day. The, the, it is true that like the Ethereum
Speaker 1:  market is still largely GPU based. I actually do know how this works. I'm
Speaker 1:  sorry, just to be clear. I'm aware that Bitcoin is about
Speaker 1:  saying ASX and Ethereum is also in GPS, but that market is still driving
Speaker 1:  a ton.
Speaker 5:  Oh, it is. Yeah. And that's what, that's why they nerfed the mining. But
Speaker 5:  particularly if you're IM on these cars, because they know that that is
Speaker 5:  those people still building farms with these GPS. So
Speaker 1:  How is that? Nerfing easy to get around. Well, in video made it
Speaker 5:  Really easy to get around because they released a driver that basically
Speaker 5:  undid the nurse.
Speaker 5:  So, but yeah, like they
Speaker 5:  are bringing out new 30 eighties and new 30 seventies that have the
Speaker 5:  enough, hopefully they don't bring out a driver that takes enough
Speaker 5:  away. But like people, I think people have been figuring
Speaker 5:  out ways of getting around it. Like it's like anything, right.
Speaker 5:  Nothing's ever fully uncrackable.
Speaker 5:  So we'll see,
Speaker 1:  You got to use the deal. You got to use one GPU to crack the other GPU, which
Speaker 1:  means you got to get to, and now I know what you did, Tom.
Speaker 1:  Okay. That's ridiculous. Last note, before we go, we
Speaker 1:  didn't talk about this last week. A lot of streaming news last week, in addition
Speaker 1:  to Alex fans, our new managing editor, who's wonderful. We have a new streaming
Speaker 1:  reporter stepping into the very big shoes of Julia Alexander is Katy
Speaker 1:  Keck, who you need to have on the show. Soon if we'd had a show last week,
Speaker 1:  I would have demanded Katie, walk us through all the craziness and streaming
Speaker 1:  we'll do that soon, but he
Speaker 1:  anted just decided to walk away from the Warner
Speaker 1:  brothers deal, which is incredible. They're spinning it off and merging it
Speaker 1:  with discovery. There is an excellent New York times piece about how this
Speaker 1:  deal came together by ed Lee, who used to work at Recode.
Speaker 1:  We're very friendly with ed, but he was just like, go read it. It's
Speaker 1:  incredible. The CEO of discovery is a very rich man. He has a
Speaker 1:  townhouse in New York, but that the townhouse, the owns, which is a second
Speaker 1:  home in New York was under renovation. So he rented another townhouse for
Speaker 1:  this deal. It's just like a perfect detail for me and
Speaker 1:  decorated with pictures of rockstars. And they all they made, they did the
Speaker 1:  deal under a giant photo of Steve McQueen and all the
Speaker 1:  executives like Steve McQueen is the hero of the deal. And you just read
Speaker 1:  it. And you're like, none of this makes any sense. Like none of this is related
Speaker 1:  to what you are going to do by merging these companies and it's putting them
Speaker 1:  off at and T but it is happening. They announced a tagline and a
Speaker 1:  logo and a name. It took them one week. It is the
Speaker 1:  worst name, logo and tagline combination I have
Speaker 1:  ever seen from any company ever. It's not that the
Speaker 1:  name is bad. The name is just Warner bros discovery.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Which is just the two names together. It makes sense. But the fact
Speaker 1:  that they've gone with Warner bros instead of Warner
Speaker 1:  brothers is incredible with a period. The
Speaker 1:  logo looks like it was made in 1995 on a Quadro
Speaker 1:  700. Like it's like extruded gold
Speaker 1:  3d on a sky background. Yeah. And then the
Speaker 1:  tagline, which I am told is from a, like a classic
Speaker 1:  Warner brothers movie is the stuff dreams are made of which is
Speaker 1:  ungrammatical. And also no one alive today has seen that
Speaker 1:  movie. Like it's like from like Casablanca or something. Like it's some deeply
Speaker 1:  famous movie that no young streaming customer is.
Speaker 4:  If you know the movie, please tweet at
Speaker 4:  reckless non-stop every day. Remind them what the
Speaker 4:  movie. Well, here's what I,
Speaker 1:  I just Googled it. I just Googled it. It's a song by Carly
Speaker 1:  Simon. It's an episode of law and order organized crime.
Speaker 1:  No, the Maltese Falcon. That's the movie. It's so very,
Speaker 1:  very famous movie, but I assure you, most people have not seen this
Speaker 1:  movie or get this reference. I feel
Speaker 6:  Like that's also like a really bad movie to choose a quote from
Speaker 6:  like, it's a big film nor like, why would you, why would you be like, you
Speaker 6:  know what? This will inspire people, murder
Speaker 6:  black and
Speaker 6:  white.
Speaker 5:  It's a mood. It's the stuff that dreams are made of
Speaker 5:  right.
Speaker 3:  18 T street.
Speaker 1:  Just look at this and just go look at the picture. It is, I tweeted
Speaker 1:  it. It's on the website. The font that they printed, the stuff dreams are
Speaker 1:  made up is like, I mean, it's a Collibra, it's like a default font.
Speaker 1:  Like it's so bad. I
Speaker 6:  To find the, the, the designer it's paint shop
Speaker 6:  pro. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  They got dumped on so hard that they released this statement to
Speaker 1:  variety being like, none of this is no, no, this isn't
Speaker 1:  final
Speaker 3:  Seven,
Speaker 1:  Walking it back already in an auspicious beginning for complete
Speaker 1:  unwinding of 18. T's massive investment in Warner
Speaker 1:  media. They're just selling it off again. That means 18
Speaker 1:  T they bought direct TV, destroyed its
Speaker 1:  value and spinning it off. They bought Warner media, destroyed its
Speaker 1:  value and are spinning it off in the middle of autism, HBO, max. And nobody
Speaker 1:  knows what they're gonna do
Speaker 6:  If and T is buying you run. Well, you're
Speaker 6:  doomed. I knew
Speaker 1:  Katie was the streaming reporter for us because yesterday in slack is we
Speaker 1:  were talking about all this. She's like, is there anything ATNT can't
Speaker 3:  Kill? And I was like, oh, like one
Speaker 1:  You're a fresh faced. And you're like, you believe that there's an answer
Speaker 1:  to that question. That isn't and to
Speaker 1:  you've you've already got it. Like you've already figured it
Speaker 1:  out, but it's like amazing that this
Speaker 1:  deal, I mean, it was a huge deal. The Trump
Speaker 1:  administration sued to block it because Trump was mad at CNN and he just
Speaker 1:  want to revenge on CNN. They failed. The
Speaker 1:  entire impetus of this deal was they were going to bundle HBO max
Speaker 1:  with and T services that made no sense
Speaker 1:  because there was a pandemic and people were not streaming HBO, max on their
Speaker 1:  phones so much on ATCs network. It's
Speaker 1:  still just like, they will throw HBO max at you. If you're an at and T subscriber,
Speaker 1:  for any reason whatsoever, you like sneeze, the 18 T website, would
Speaker 1:  you like HBO, max? But none of that worked out and now
Speaker 1:  they're spinning off. They filed a document. The sec it's like an FAQ for
Speaker 1:  investors and all the questions, like why, why was
Speaker 1:  this deal ever a good idea? And they're like, we still think it was a good
Speaker 1:  idea. We just think we have a better idea. Now
Speaker 1:  it's very good. So that's that w we're going to unpack it. It is not
Speaker 1:  closed. As we were talking about earlier in the show, there's a lot of anti-trust
Speaker 1:  action in the world. That's got to get approved. I can't imagine the government
Speaker 1:  being like, we sued to block this deal. And now we're going to
Speaker 1:  PR we're going to Sue you to unwind it, but it does have to
Speaker 1:  pass muster.
Speaker 6:  Merging with discovery though, is going to really suck if you're like a cable
Speaker 6:  provider, because now, like there's just this
Speaker 6:  huge packet of channels that can
Speaker 6:  negotiate big pay, like big rate
Speaker 6:  increases. And that's not going to be great. Like
Speaker 6:  I could, I could definitely see there's still some protest into this
Speaker 6:  merger, spin off whatever it is. I
Speaker 6:  don't know. How did they create a new entity?
Speaker 3:  Also the revolving
Speaker 1:  Door of executives is wild. So
Speaker 1:  18 T bought time Warner. They installed a new set of executives,
Speaker 1:  all the old Warner executives, including the head of HBO left tons of
Speaker 1:  creative, left Warner. Then they installed a new CEO. Jason
Speaker 1:  Kolari, who was the ex CEO of Hulu. KLR said, all my
Speaker 1:  movies are going to streaming day and date with theaters from now on pissed
Speaker 1:  off everyone, including Christopher Nolan, who said, I'm done working with
Speaker 1:  Warner brothers. Then they spun it off. And they were like, ,
Speaker 1:  you might be gone. And they've been, I think he's agreed to stay on for one
Speaker 1:  year, but after that he's out. So like just the wreckage
Speaker 1:  in the wake of
Speaker 6:  This story, and they killed two incredible streaming networks
Speaker 6:  too. Cause they killed FilmStruck with the merger, the original
Speaker 6:  merger. And it was just like devastating. If you were one of the four people
Speaker 6:  who subscribed it was me, it was just me
Speaker 6:  in a trench coat. And then they killed, they killed the DC universe. That
Speaker 6:  was actually almost good. If you were a giant, giant nerd
Speaker 6:  and enjoyed comic books again, it was just me.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Sorry, Alex, have you heard of HBO max? Because we are happy to give
Speaker 1:  you HQ master free. If you're an at and T subscriber
Speaker 6:  Never paid for it. I think I have four subscriptions already. They
Speaker 1:  Did however, launched the HBO max ad tier this week. So
Speaker 1:  they're going to try to grow that market, but just look, I know I have a
Speaker 1:  lot of thoughts about Anish that's all the time. I would be happy if the
Speaker 1:  only antitrust law in this country was 18 T is not allowed to buy things
Speaker 1:  just for a bit. I think it would work out. I'm
Speaker 5:  Just glad I live in the UK and things are a little less complicated over
Speaker 5:  here. We just have to watch government
Speaker 5:  programming.
Speaker 1:  Sure. I don't know. I'm just saying Senator club chart. If you're listening,
Speaker 1:  I'm just assuming that after she was on Decatur, she's a hardcore virtuous
Speaker 1:  Lister. Now that's a fair assumption, right? That's my idea for an
Speaker 1:  antitrust spill. Just put that out there. And then lastly, speaking of other
Speaker 1:  streaming news, Amazon entered a deal to buy MGM, which is super interesting
Speaker 1:  because that one attracted way more anti-trust interest, right? You're Josh
Speaker 1:  Holly's or club like across the spectrum. We're mad at Amazon.
Speaker 1:  We're not going to let them buy this extremely defunct film studio
Speaker 1:  they're going to that's definitely. It's going to be fine. I just can't
Speaker 1:  imagine that they're not going to clean house at MGM. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Right? Like Amazon is going to Amazon of five, that whole thing.
Speaker 1:  And then like the, you know, the centerpiece of that studio is James Bond
Speaker 1:  and they don't even know the rights. Tom is a British person. I think you're
Speaker 1:  legally allowed to know the ownership structure of James Bond, right?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. He owns an Aston Martin.
Speaker 5:  Right.
Speaker 1:  It was a BMW for a long time. But yeah, James Bond is creatively controlled
Speaker 1:  by the broccoli family to this day. And so Amazon can't even like
Speaker 1:  make that into a TV show. Although I'm confident Jeff Bezos is
Speaker 1:  just going to throw money at that Providence hill sells itself. That's how
Speaker 1:  you, that's how you solve that problem. I think, come on, put me in the bond
Speaker 1:  movie.
Speaker 4:  So clearly the villain though. Well, he doesn't know that
Speaker 1:  Twist. Look, if you, you know, James Bond
Speaker 1:  from, from a different perspective, James Bond is the villain of all those
Speaker 1:  movies. I'm just putting that up there. Oh yeah. For sure. For some people
Speaker 1:  in those movies, James Bond is like very much bad guy. He's just in the way
Speaker 1:  he's blowing stuff up. He's sleeping with your girlfriend. Like teasers shows
Speaker 1:  up and ruins all your plans.
Speaker 5:  Well, he just sounds like a typical British person, man.
Speaker 6:  Get your giant pit with sharks
Speaker 6:  installed. You're happy, everything looks perfect. And then
Speaker 6:  James Bond, just swans in steals, your girl blows up your sharks
Speaker 6:  and murders. You, it takes your cat
Speaker 1:  Chest. Everybody. We're going to end on that note. It was Alex's for a show.
Speaker 1:  She's just as bad as James on his. I am a lot going on this
Speaker 1:  week. As you can tell a lot going on next week, I want to call out a thing.
Speaker 1:  We were not able to talk about. There's also a chicken wing shortage in this
Speaker 1:  country. In addition to his sheep, he is shortage. Trust shows. I looked
Speaker 1:  into why it's not an obvious thing for a tech reporter to do it is
Speaker 1:  because of SEO delivery apps. This is a real thing. You just go read the
Speaker 1:  story. It's very good. It is one of those, oh, computers
Speaker 1:  led to an unexpected result stories. It just in the
Speaker 1:  wildest way. That's it. We, we went long. We actually went long. This
Speaker 1:  time Alex was going to have you here. We're going to have you on again.
Speaker 6:  It was super fun. I loved it, Alex. What's your Twitter. My
Speaker 6:  Twitter is very simple. It's Alex H Kranz. It's absolutely
Speaker 6:  terrible. Please subscribe.
Speaker 1:  It's Tom Warren Diener is at backlog. I'm at reckless. You can tweet at
Speaker 1:  us. We had her Roseo Gutierrez from Spotify and Dakota
Speaker 1:  this week. Next week. It's the managing director of Y Combinator, the
Speaker 1:  startup accelerator, a lot of startups, including
Speaker 1:  Coinbase, Coinbase, Dropbox, Airbnb who runs out of
Speaker 1:  Slayer. Michael Seibel. He's on decoder next week. That's a really good one.
Speaker 1:  I look forward to it and we've got DBC. Okay. That's it. Rock and
Speaker 1:  roll. Snip, snip, bridging the gaps.