# Transcript
ID: 3aa270d0-5f1c-11ec-9bff-755e7b7fcf96
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: James Webb Space Telescope to launch next week / cool gadgets announced this week
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-2178709330474975618/1400877147061356739/s93290-US-4328s-1639732849.mp3
Description: Nilay Patel, Dieter Bohn, Alex Cranz, and Loren Grush discuss NASA's plan for launching the James Webb Space Telescope, the successor to NASA’s Hubble telescope.
Second half of the show, the crew go through all the gadgets and software updates announced this past week.
Stories discussed this week:
NASA’s massive next-generation space telescope arrives in South America ahead of launch
NASA sets new date for James Webb Space Telescope launch
Five former SpaceX employees speak out about harassment at the company
Sony Glass Sound Speaker review: it’s not what it looks like
Analogue Pocket review: Game Boy games have never looked so good
Opal’s C1 offers DSLR-rivaling video quality in a small form factor
Dell’s Concept Stanza converts your chicken scratch to digital text
Amazon Echo Show 15 review: Alexa’s on your wall
Oppo’s Find N is an impressive first folding phone
Huawei’s P50 Pocket is a stylish clamshell foldable launching this month
Samsung’s working on a rollable smartwatch with a camera
Apple releases iOS 15.2 with App Privacy Report, Digital Legacy, and more
Apple scrubs controversial CSAM detection feature from webpage but says plans haven’t changed
Universal Control won’t be coming to macOS Monterey until sometime this spring
Adobe launches Creative Cloud Express, a new app that simplifies its powerful editing tools
Snap launches Story Studio, a standalone video editing app for mobile
Log4j is patched, but the exploits are just getting started
‘No easy solution’ for Tesla Cybertruck’s comically large windshield wiper, Elon Musk says
Chrome OS tablets are getting fancier but not better
Former FCC officials are worried about air safety fears delaying 5G rollout
Toyota is going to make you pay to start your car with your key fob
Delivery failed
How to sneak into a Bored Ape Yacht Club party
Matter’s plan to save the smart home
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Disabled
Speaker 1:  This weekend of our chest, Alex Cranz and Lauren Gruss joined the show. We
Speaker 1:  talk all about the James Webb space telescope. And so launching at the end
Speaker 1:  of the year, then it's a lightning round of gadgets and tech news
Speaker 1:  taking us out of 2021. That's going up on the Vergecast. Now
Speaker 2:  This podcast is brought to you by Twilio, for businesses around the
Speaker 2:  world, unlocking and unifying real-time customer data is critical,
Speaker 2:  especially for delivering truly personalized campaigns at scale.
Speaker 2:  That's why companies like Instacart into it. And IBM are turning to Twilio,
Speaker 2:  which was recently ranked number one for 2020 market share and customer data
Speaker 2:  platforms by IDC to learn how Twilio can help your business
Speaker 2:  harness real-time data and build customer engagement like no other visit
Speaker 2:  twilio.com.
Speaker 3:  It's a tough time to be a small business owner. That's why visa has committed
Speaker 3:  to helping the world. Small businesses bounce back. Visa believes that
Speaker 3:  inclusive economies uplift everyone everywhere. So the company is on a
Speaker 3:  mission to connect the world, to enable individuals, businesses, and
Speaker 3:  economies to thrive. The company made a multi-year pledge to digitally
Speaker 3:  enable 50 million small and micro businesses. This can help small and micro
Speaker 3:  businesses drive greater efficiencies in sales, through acceptance and usage
Speaker 3:  of digital payments as well as help build online businesses. And to
Speaker 3:  date visa has granted over $1 million in hyper-local grants, across the
Speaker 3:  U S with a focus on disproportionately affected women and black business
Speaker 3:  owners. To learn more about how visa is helping uplift everyone everywhere.
Speaker 3:  Visit visa.com/small business hub.
Speaker 1:  Hello, and welcome to rich cast the flagship podcast of 2022.
Speaker 1:  They're leading right into
Speaker 4:  Cause we're just, we're not going to do any twenties 21.
Speaker 1:  This is it. This is our last show of the year. It's true. I'm your friend,
Speaker 1:  the line dealer bonus. Here
Speaker 4:  I am. The guy wishing Nila, happy birthday. Oh
Speaker 1:  God.
Speaker 1:  I was telling Dieter that I think odd numbers, they sound older than
Speaker 1:  even numbers. So am turning an odd number. And I just like, don't want to
Speaker 1:  think about it, but next year will be an even number. I'll be like, this
Speaker 1:  is my birth.
Speaker 1:  This is my theory of aging. Anyway, Lauren crushes here.
Speaker 1:  Surprise. I'm here and now trans is here. Hello. So it is in fact my
Speaker 1:  birthday and I'm just going to admit it. I've barely prepared for the show.
Speaker 1:  I just like, just like I got all day. I hope just
Speaker 1:  grant me this affordance is all I'm saying. I didn't want to miss our last
Speaker 1:  show of the year, but it was also my birthday. So Dieter is going to
Speaker 1:  trust the show.
Speaker 4:  And you like for your birthday, I, I want to tell you that I have come
Speaker 4:  around to believing that I are as stupid and I, our blasters are
Speaker 1:  Stupid. They're dumb. They've always been dumb,
Speaker 4:  But I was thinking about it some more and I'm like, you know, it's still
Speaker 4:  like a relatively easy, cheap, almost interoperable standard
Speaker 4:  that anybody can use to communicate with anything else if they have the IRR
Speaker 4:  ports. So maybe it's sort of analogous to a headphone Jack.
Speaker 1:  Maybe the fact that wired headphones are trying to, again, it's like my personal,
Speaker 1:  it's like a, it's like a victory for me. Every time I see one of those stories,
Speaker 1:  Maria, who people might know this from lots of videos, you know, she's
Speaker 1:  one of the trendiest people on our staff and she did it. She had an Instagram
Speaker 1:  story about her wired headphones the other day. And I was like, I did it.
Speaker 1:  That was me. I don't think that she knows that. I think that so Mara, if
Speaker 1:  you're listening, just, I want you to know you gave him that moment. That
Speaker 1:  personal victory. Yeah, no, it's all last year. The year we're taking that
Speaker 1:  subway software. We back after CS, everybody has a good break,
Speaker 1:  but there's still like a lot going on, including a big thing happening towards
Speaker 1:  the end of the year. That's why Lauren is here. The James Webb space, telescope
Speaker 5:  Nila. It's not just happening at the end of the year. It's happening
Speaker 5:  currently on Christmas Eve.
Speaker 1:  Hooray. We're going to hit Santa with a telescope,
Speaker 1:  hit
Speaker 1:  Merry Christmas boys and girls.
Speaker 5:  I'm doomed forever to cover some major
Speaker 5:  launch on another really important holiday.
Speaker 5:  That is just how these things shake out.
Speaker 1:  So moody was supposed to be 22nd and I moved to Christmasy. Why did that
Speaker 1:  happen?
Speaker 5:  18th? Actually, it was supposed to be 20 years ago.
Speaker 5:  And now it is happening on December 24th.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. All right. Let's start at the beginning. What is the James Webb space
Speaker 1:  telescope? It is a big deal. It's when people are working on this for a long
Speaker 1:  time, what is
Speaker 5:  So James Webb or JWST for short
Speaker 5:  is widely considered the successor to the Hubble space telescope. You might
Speaker 5:  be aware of some of its iconic images. It's currently orbiting around the
Speaker 5:  earth and it sees an optical wavelengths, but JWC is just
Speaker 5:  going to be so much more powerful and more sensitive than Hubble. And it
Speaker 5:  also sees an infrared light. So it's, it's a
Speaker 5:  special type of light on the, on the part of the
Speaker 5:  optical or the light wavelength spectrum. And the
Speaker 5:  reason we use infrared to
Speaker 5:  CCN is because we're trying to look at some of the most distant
Speaker 5:  galaxies in the universe. So these would be galaxies
Speaker 5:  that are roughly 13.6 billion, light years
Speaker 5:  away. And that's an important number because we think the universe, as we
Speaker 5:  know it after the big bang was
Speaker 5:  13.8 billion years ago. And so
Speaker 5:  because light takes such a long time to reach us.
Speaker 5:  If these things are 13.6 billion, light years away, then we
Speaker 5:  think that they formed roughly a hundred to
Speaker 5:  250 million years after the big bang. So we're basically looking
Speaker 5:  at baby pictures of the universe is kind of how I think of it.
Speaker 5:  And they're also moving away from us when they're, when they're that
Speaker 5:  far from us, they're moving away from us because the universe is expanding.
Speaker 5:  So they're moving. The farthest ones are moving the fastest away from us.
Speaker 5:  And when you move away, the light from those galaxies gets
Speaker 5:  shifted. It gets red shifted. So it moves towards the
Speaker 5:  infrared side of the spectrum. So that's why we have this amazing new infrared
Speaker 5:  telescope. It's going to be able to see all this infrared light from these
Speaker 5:  distant galaxies and really show us like what the universe
Speaker 5:  looked like when it was in its infancy.
Speaker 1:  You said the successor to Hubble, whatever. It's my birthday. I'm an old
Speaker 1:  man. Now I'm just going to date myself. I was in like elementary school when
Speaker 1:  the Hubble launched, it was a huge deal. The mirror was broken. They had
Speaker 1:  to fix the mirror. Yeah, don't remind me. But this was like, I mean, this
Speaker 1:  is like the highlight of fifth grade. It's like they fixed the mirror, right?
Speaker 1:  It does. I mean, I was like, I'm an astronaut. It didn't work out.
Speaker 1:  Spoiler alert got
Speaker 5:  A couple of billion dollars.
Speaker 1:  You can still do it. Well, yeah. Now I'm just going to like float around
Speaker 1:  on Michael strand. It's great. But is the Hubble over or we send a
Speaker 1:  crashing in the ocean what's going on with it?
Speaker 5:  No, no. And helpful is definitely not over. It would definitely won't last
Speaker 5:  forever, but I know we is still a very valuable part
Speaker 5:  of astronomy and continues to work to this day. This is
Speaker 5:  actually, yes, it's called a successor, but really it's a compliment because
Speaker 5:  Hubble has these amazing capabilities and how we'll actually solve
Speaker 5:  some really distant galaxies. You know, there's this really great
Speaker 5:  image called the Hubble deep field. And it has all these incredible number
Speaker 5:  of galaxies as far off galaxies that we were able to see what the telescope,
Speaker 5:  but it just can't go back as far as the JWC will be able
Speaker 5:  to. And so this is really just kind of adding to our knowledge and
Speaker 5:  having an even more amazing tool at our disposal. But Hubble will
Speaker 5:  still be a very valuable tool as long as it's up and running.
Speaker 4:  So one of the big primary unanswered questions, we're hoping to get
Speaker 4:  answers to here, you know, beyond very, very pretty pictures of far off
Speaker 4:  galaxies,
Speaker 5:  Basically everything. I mean, that's a pretty big one dealer,
Speaker 4:  You know, I, I never turned down a baby picture. Don't get me wrong, but
Speaker 5:  Well, the, the evolution of stars and galaxies is big. So we really
Speaker 5:  wanted to know, you know, how the earliest galaxies evolved
Speaker 5:  over time. Also, we want to have a better idea of just kind of the large
Speaker 5:  scale structure of the universe. So, you know, one thing hovel that
Speaker 5:  was really great at it was, was proving that the universe is
Speaker 5:  expanding. And so we really want to get like a better understanding of just
Speaker 5:  how fast it's expanding and what that means for the
Speaker 5:  future of the universe. And then probably the biggest
Speaker 5:  thing, not the biggest, but one of the biggest things that JWC will
Speaker 5:  do that nobody really even thought of when they came
Speaker 5:  up with the telescope, you know, roughly three decades ago
Speaker 5:  is using it to look into the atmospheres of
Speaker 5:  exoplanets. So exoplanets are planets that are outside of
Speaker 5:  our solar system or being around other stars. And we didn't even know
Speaker 5:  exoplanets existed prior to the 1990s. Obviously
Speaker 5:  people theorize that they existed, but we just didn't have a confirmation
Speaker 5:  of them. And now we know about thousands of exoplanets
Speaker 5:  because we've sent missions into space to actually find them and study them.
Speaker 5:  But the problem with studying exoplanets is, you know, it's a really
Speaker 5:  dark rock or gaseous object right next to a really
Speaker 5:  bright star or sun. And it's hard to
Speaker 5:  see that because the stars light drowns out that object. So the
Speaker 5:  only way that we really can know that an exoplanet exists is
Speaker 5:  through a technique called transiting. It's not the only way, but it's probably
Speaker 5:  the best way. So basically when the planet passes in front of the
Speaker 5:  star, it like momentarily dips the stars light just because there's a
Speaker 5:  little bit of blockage there and we can infer that
Speaker 5:  a planet is there, but we want to know like what's on the planet,
Speaker 5:  right? Cause we're, we're looking for earth 2.0, we're looking for
Speaker 5:  possible signs of life outside of our solar system. And the best way to
Speaker 5:  do that is to see what's in a planet's atmosphere. But like I
Speaker 5:  said, it's incredibly hard because there's, it's getting, getting
Speaker 5:  drowned out by the stars light. So what JWST might be able to do is
Speaker 5:  because it's so powerful and so sensitive is that it will be able to
Speaker 5:  look at the edges of that exoplanet as it passes in front of
Speaker 5:  the star or the edge of the star and see the light as it
Speaker 5:  filters through the edges of the atmosphere. Once that
Speaker 5:  light passes through all those gases and all those molecules, it works the
Speaker 5:  light in such a way that we can actually tell what molecules are present
Speaker 5:  and what gas is present. And depending on what gas is there,
Speaker 5:  you know, then we might be able to infer if there are signs of life on the
Speaker 5:  planet below, because you know, people, we put a lot of
Speaker 5:  gases into our planet's atmosphere that wouldn't be
Speaker 5:  there if we weren't here. Sorry. I hate to say it, but
Speaker 5:  we're discussing.
Speaker 1:  Look, I stand outside, just shooting off my hairspray into the
Speaker 1:  every day being like, find a salient like on my
Speaker 1:  Aquanet, just like looking for little green men,
Speaker 5:  We looking for disgusting aliens. Yes. Yeah. We're looking for
Speaker 5:  discussing private byproducts of alien life Nila. You're just doing your
Speaker 5:  part to help others.
Speaker 1:  I'm running SETI at home and I'm shooting hairspray into the
Speaker 1:  sky. You said this was supposed to launch 20 years ago. I mean,
Speaker 1:  it has, it has been like a long,
Speaker 5:  I believe the most ambitious projected
Speaker 5:  launch date was in 2007 and probably somewhere between 2007 and
Speaker 5:  2011. I mean, they first came up with the most, the
Speaker 5:  earliest concept. It wasn't the iteration that we know now, but people
Speaker 5:  started talking about having a telescope of this nature as early as
Speaker 5:  1989. And then it, then it became more
Speaker 5:  formulated in the nineties. And yeah, they had
Speaker 5:  these really naive cost estimates of, you know,
Speaker 5:  500,000 to a billion dollars. And it would launch in
Speaker 5:  2007, between 2007 and 2011. Obviously
Speaker 5:  we overshot all of that. And now we're looking at
Speaker 5:  a price tag of roughly, you know, nearly two,
Speaker 5:  $10 billion. So
Speaker 6:  You're saying it's a James Cameron movie,
Speaker 5:  But that's also a great point that you bring up perspective is key here because
Speaker 5:  you know, this is going to revolutionize astronomy and
Speaker 5:  astrophysics and yes, 10 billion sounds like a lot of money, but it is
Speaker 5:  chump change when we put it in the perspective of other things that we spend
Speaker 5:  money on, you know, either from the federal government or like just how much
Speaker 5:  we spend on potato chips. Somebody reminded me.
Speaker 6:  I just think it's wild that like, we're going to see
Speaker 6:  what happened right after the big bang. Yeah. I messaged you earlier
Speaker 6:  this week about this because I was still stuck earlier this
Speaker 6:  week, thinking that the big bang was like a single explosion
Speaker 6:  and everything exploded out. I think I messaged you just saying,
Speaker 6:  what direction are they going to look? And that's not how the universe
Speaker 6:  works.
Speaker 5:  No, really the way to think of the big bang is just
Speaker 5:  that's it sparked the expansion of our universe. And so
Speaker 5:  that's how we, we, it's a, it's a very pivotal time, obviously in our
Speaker 5:  history, but yeah, it's, it's really when the expansion began and it's,
Speaker 5:  and it's, there are smarter people that can talk about this than me, but
Speaker 5:  yeah, it it's when the first galaxies and
Speaker 5:  there was, you know, very basic elements in the universe at the time.
Speaker 5:  And then they kind of formulated to form stars and formed galaxies. So
Speaker 5:  what we're really seeing is the first signs of that
Speaker 5:  formulation of, of stars and galaxies coming together, which is incredible.
Speaker 6:  And we might also find dark matter. Like we might be able to find
Speaker 6:  dark matter or see dark matter with this.
Speaker 5:  I have not looked into that as much, but yes, there are dark matters
Speaker 5:  studies, but you pointed that out to me, reminded me to look into it,
Speaker 5:  but I've been more fascinated with like the exoplanets.
Speaker 6:  I mean, aliens are also cool.
Speaker 6:  I get it.
Speaker 1:  So I hate to be the downer. We're talking about what we are going to be able
Speaker 1:  to do with this thing, but it's got to get off the ground. It is
Speaker 1:  itself very complicated. I've I am always, I'm totally
Speaker 1:  fascinated by the pictures of the mirror, which is this enormous mirror.
Speaker 1:  They're launching it from the middle of nowhere. How, how are they getting
Speaker 1:  it to where it needs to go, keeping it safe and getting it into the sky safely?
Speaker 5:  Probably the most wild part. And the reason why everyone has such
Speaker 5:  anxiety leading up to this is because it can't launch the
Speaker 5:  space the way that it needs to be in space. It has
Speaker 5:  to launch folded up because no current rockets that we
Speaker 5:  have available are wide enough to get it in
Speaker 5:  its full configuration out into space. So it has to fold up
Speaker 5:  like, you know, a little origami figuring, and
Speaker 5:  then once it gets into space, it ignites this really
Speaker 5:  complicated unfurling process. And you have to understand
Speaker 5:  that the telescope is a mixture of hard and
Speaker 5:  soft things. So the mirror obviously is this
Speaker 5:  very intricate gold-plated mirror, very tough,
Speaker 5:  you know, stuff. But then in order to make sure that it
Speaker 5:  stays super cold, which is important because it sees in the infrared, it
Speaker 5:  has to have a sun shield that is made out of this very
Speaker 5:  thin. Almost. It looks kind of like a plastic-y materials called
Speaker 5:  captain and that has to unfurl in space
Speaker 5:  too. So then it blocks the rays from the sun. And so it doesn't get so
Speaker 5:  high. It has to, it has to operate at a temperature close to
Speaker 5:  negative 400 degrees Fahrenheit. But this CA this material, the sun
Speaker 5:  shield is so thin and it's such a very thin membrane and there are four
Speaker 5:  layers of it. So there is a process in space where that
Speaker 5:  sun shield slowly opens up and, you know,
Speaker 5:  it has to work or else the whole thing kind of falls apart.
Speaker 5:  So that's just one of many different
Speaker 5:  things that have to happen while it unfurls in space. And I
Speaker 5:  think we are, we've been, I'm working on a story about that unfurling
Speaker 5:  process and the numbers I've heard is, you know, somewhere
Speaker 5:  over 300 single points of failure.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And obviously it's you think it means it's
Speaker 5:  like, that thing must happen or else the entire
Speaker 5:  thing does not work. And it's just a
Speaker 5:  terrifying thing to think about. So, so yeah,
Speaker 5:  normally when, I mean, not normally, but most of the time when I'm following
Speaker 5:  a launch, we aren't happy until the thing separates from the
Speaker 5:  spacecraft. And then it unfurls its solar panels and it started getting
Speaker 5:  power. That's usually when we declare victory, but with
Speaker 5:  JWST, we won't be declared victory for at least another month
Speaker 5:  because that's how long it takes to unfurl and to get out to
Speaker 5:  its intended orbit, which is a million miles from,
Speaker 1:  Oh, so actually speaking to the intended Arbor, can you explain why this
Speaker 1:  thing is launching in the middle of nowhere? And actually, can you define
Speaker 1:  middle of nowhere?
Speaker 5:  Well, it's launching in crew French Guyana, which is the site of
Speaker 5:  Europe's primary spaceport. So this is an
Speaker 5:  international collaboration it's been to be, you know, used
Speaker 5:  by astronomers and scientists all over the world. And
Speaker 5:  so we, we made a deal with Ariana space to launch the
Speaker 5:  JWC on their area and five rocket and their primary
Speaker 5:  launch site is infringed Ghana. And I mean, for
Speaker 5:  most launches, I don't know if this has to do with
Speaker 5:  JWST. So forgive me for minimal mechanics people. But the
Speaker 5:  reason that a crew is such a great site is because it's near the
Speaker 5:  equator. And so we really liked to launch from near the equator
Speaker 5:  because that's where the earth is moving the fastest. So you get a
Speaker 5:  really like a little boost when you launch closer to the equator when you're
Speaker 5:  getting satellites into orbit. So that's why it was
Speaker 5:  located there.
Speaker 1:  What are the next like that month? 300 points of failure? Are
Speaker 1:  they clustered at the beginning of that month? Like we know right away or
Speaker 1:  is it like 30 days later? We're like crap, 16 things have to happen
Speaker 1:  today.
Speaker 5:  It's a two week process of unfurling. Okay. So the
Speaker 5:  sunshield deploys over a period of many days,
Speaker 5:  so there's really no time to relax
Speaker 1:  Adult anxiety. Well,
Speaker 4:  Let's be clear. We can't, if something goes wrong, we can, can we, can we
Speaker 4:  send astronauts up there to fix it?
Speaker 5:  No, not, not really.
Speaker 1:  I wish I wish everybody could have seen Lauren's face.
Speaker 1:  No, no, no.
Speaker 4:  Can Bruce Willis get up there for the drill and do
Speaker 4:  something, right?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. We don't even have the capabilities that astronauts to where JWC
Speaker 5:  is going, cause it's going a million miles from earth. But even if we
Speaker 5:  did, the telescope was not made to
Speaker 5:  be serviceable, like Hubble was, you know, from the
Speaker 5:  beginning, Hubble was designed to be serviceable. So the
Speaker 5:  way that they built the components, they built them in such a way that you
Speaker 5:  could swap things out and fix them with certain tools. They even did. They
Speaker 5:  designed completely new tools just to
Speaker 5:  work with Hubble. But with DWC, that was just, it was
Speaker 5:  just not an option. Now I did talk to
Speaker 5:  some NASA folks about this. There are targets on it so that
Speaker 5:  if maybe we want to try refueling at some day, we could
Speaker 5:  do that. But if say an actuator just completely
Speaker 5:  breaks or if the sun shield doesn't deploy or many other, these things
Speaker 5:  happen, then we are kind of out of luck.
Speaker 4:  Once again, the right to repair is so important.
Speaker 1:  I mean, the whole thing is like really, like, it was a totally different
Speaker 1:  paradigm of space, right? Like they thought the space shuttle would just
Speaker 1:  be going up every day to fix satellites. Yeah. And so they, like,
Speaker 1:  I don't know. It was just like crazy to think that that's what we thought
Speaker 1:  would be happening in space. And then like quickly we're like, wait, that's
Speaker 1:  it. We just launched another satellite. That's easier.
Speaker 5:  This is the Microsoft surface of satellites. Right.
Speaker 5:  Very difficult. What you've ordered is what you get.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Is there a reason that they designed it? I mean, it's been a long
Speaker 1:  time they're ready to launch it, but is there a reason that it's designed
Speaker 1:  with so much anxiety built into the unfurling
Speaker 1:  process? Could it have been more redundant?
Speaker 5:  I asked that question and the answer is basically no.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Just because there, I mean, there's the thing in the launch
Speaker 5:  industry known as the tyranny of the fairing and
Speaker 5:  essentially what they're talking about. So at the top of a rocket, it's known
Speaker 5:  as a payload fairing, and it's what covers the payload so that it doesn't
Speaker 5:  burn up as you're launching to space. The problem with that
Speaker 5:  is that the bigger you make your rocket, the more fuel you need in it.
Speaker 5:  Right? So at some point you have to limit how big your rocket
Speaker 5:  is. And that size limit is what
Speaker 5:  often dictates the design of a satellite, right?
Speaker 5:  So you can't launch something that's wider than Falcon
Speaker 5:  nine on the Falcon nine, unless you fold it up. So that's, that's
Speaker 5:  where this comes in and this, and the thing is they decided they
Speaker 5:  wanted to have this mirror be how, you know,
Speaker 5:  over, I think roughly it's like roughly more than 20 feet long, right?
Speaker 1:  Because you haven't seen a picture of this mirror go goo. It's like a wild
Speaker 1:  thing to look at.
Speaker 5:  And because they wanted that size of a mirror, they knew they had
Speaker 5:  to figure out a way to fold it up because there was no rocket that was going
Speaker 5:  to be able, like the mirror alone is too wide for any rocket available.
Speaker 5:  Now all the space X people come at me and be like, well, one
Speaker 5:  day we'll have star ship. And that could eventually launch
Speaker 5:  really big telescopes, which Ilan has definitely talked about, but that
Speaker 5:  rocket is not available to us at the most.
Speaker 1:  And then it's being delayed like day by day, right. 18th to 22nd, 24th. Why
Speaker 1:  is that happening?
Speaker 5:  It was a communication issue between
Speaker 5:  the rocket and the payload, as I understand it, but they think they
Speaker 5:  have it resolved with they're having a meeting at 6:00 PM on
Speaker 5:  Thursday. So it's very possible that it could be Christmas
Speaker 5:  day launch by the time this podcast airs, which would be
Speaker 5:  amazing.
Speaker 5:  That was the latest thing. And the other one that, I mean, they had to push
Speaker 5:  it back a few days because some clamps snapped
Speaker 5:  and sent vibrations throughout the entire
Speaker 5:  spacecraft that wasn't supposed to happen. So they wanted to make sure that
Speaker 5:  that didn't damage anything. But yeah, I, you
Speaker 5:  have to understand we've never launched anything of this
Speaker 5:  complexity ever before. And so yeah, we have
Speaker 5:  experienced putting payloads on rockets, but we definitely do not have experience
Speaker 5:  putting this kind of payload on a rocket. So everything that we've done
Speaker 5:  before does it, it helps, but it's not, it's
Speaker 5:  all a whole new experience. So of course there's going to
Speaker 5:  be challenges along the way because putting the most
Speaker 5:  complicated space telescope on top of its rocket is just a completely new
Speaker 5:  experience for us.
Speaker 6:  Is this more or less comp complicated from a
Speaker 6:  engineering perspective than putting somebody on the moon? Oh,
Speaker 1:  My Alex was like the existential. Oh my
Speaker 5:  Goodness. I don't know. Cause I keep hearing that like,
Speaker 6:  This is the most complex thing we've ever sent and it's like maybe when we
Speaker 6:  sent like three guys,
Speaker 1:  Then they were an emotionally complex. I've watched it. I see
Speaker 1:  first man. That's like a,
Speaker 5:  That's a great question because once you're in space,
Speaker 5:  the people can potentially, you know, fix
Speaker 5:  errors. And I mean, obviously it's really still very
Speaker 5:  hard, but they can still have some agency over the
Speaker 5:  spacecraft. If something goes wrong with JWST, we have
Speaker 5:  to send signals to it from the ground.
Speaker 5:  That's our only way of, you know, fixing it. But then
Speaker 5:  again, it does not need life support systems or food or anything.
Speaker 5:  So I don't know, this is a great question. Something for
Speaker 5:  engineers to debate who are not me.
Speaker 1:  All right. So this is hopefully happening Christmas Eve a the time you're
Speaker 1:  listening to this Christmas day, we'll be looking forward to that. Lauren,
Speaker 1:  last thing I wanna ask you about, you wrote a pretty big piece about the
Speaker 1:  culture at space X this week five former employees have spoken
Speaker 1:  out about that culture about harassment. That SpaceX is one of those companies
Speaker 1:  that we just don't hear a lot about internally, but it seems like this was
Speaker 1:  a big deal. There was another essay by one of these employees. I know what
Speaker 1:  a whistleblower site called lioness. It's hard to describe what lioness is,
Speaker 1:  but you can go look at it. Tell us about that story. A little bit.
Speaker 5:  One former employee decided Joe, who just recently left,
Speaker 5:  decided to pin this essay in lioness
Speaker 5:  and the allegations that she made were pretty shocking. And
Speaker 5:  so, you know, we kind of worked to
Speaker 5:  find other former employees, mostly interns, I
Speaker 5:  realized who worked at space X to see if they could kind of
Speaker 5:  corroborate some of her experiences. And they
Speaker 5:  definitely did. And yeah, I would just encourage everyone to go read it.
Speaker 5:  It's a rare glimpse inside of space. X is culture. And I think the main
Speaker 5:  theme is that they all felt like they themselves
Speaker 5:  experienced inappropriate behavior or they saw other women
Speaker 5:  and non-binary individuals experiencing inappropriate behavior.
Speaker 5:  And when it came to whether or not to report it, they all had
Speaker 5:  very different and inconsistent responses from the HR department
Speaker 5:  or their managers, many of which that they did not see as adequate.
Speaker 5:  And they all have their various opinions as to why that is.
Speaker 5:  So I'll leave it to them to explain it. So
Speaker 1:  Yeah, that piece is on the site. It's just really great work. And I wanted
Speaker 1:  to call it up before, let you know, so you can go read that. And then sometime
Speaker 1:  around Christmas, Lauren will be crewing the verge. It'll be Lauren
Speaker 1:  Santa and the James Webb space telescope altogether. All right, thanks a
Speaker 1:  lot, Lauren. Thank you.
Speaker 4:  This episode of the Vergecast is brought to you by streak. If you're running
Speaker 4:  a business, according to investors or in the super early stages of getting
Speaker 4:  a great new idea off the ground, you're probably living out of
Speaker 4:  your inbox. The Gmail icon is haunting your dreams at this
Speaker 4:  point because you rely on email to track sales, fundraise,
Speaker 4:  and hire great new teammates. It is a mess. Thankfully streak
Speaker 4:  can help you get back on top of your email. Streak is a CRM
Speaker 4:  that will help you stay on top of all of your processes. All without
Speaker 4:  leaving Gmail streak has a bunch of vital free tools. That'll
Speaker 4:  allow you to see if your emails have been opened and scheduled bulk emails
Speaker 4:  with automated follow-ups to boost your response rates. It's all built to
Speaker 4:  work inside of Gmail, which means streak will slot into your everyday
Speaker 4:  workflow in seconds. And if you're part of a bigger team, you can use
Speaker 4:  streak to collaborate by automatically sharing specific emails
Speaker 4:  and notes with your coworkers. See today, Y streak was recognized
Speaker 4:  as Google's technology partner of the year. It's free to use on your own
Speaker 4:  or use the pro plan with your team. Get 20% off your first
Speaker 4:  year of the pro plan. Their most popular option by going to
Speaker 4:  streak.com/verge that's S T R E a
Speaker 4:  k.com/verge for 20% off.
Speaker 3:  How many times have you gone to the pharmacy with absolutely no idea how
Speaker 3:  much your prescription is about to cost. Prescription prices can vary between
Speaker 3:  pharmacies by as much as a hundred dollars. Honestly, that's not
Speaker 3:  okay, but if you checked good RX, you can find out how
Speaker 3:  much your medication is going to cost. And you'll also know you're getting
Speaker 3:  the lowest price. Good RX allows you to instantly compare
Speaker 3:  prices at pharmacies in your neighborhood before you go. So you know
Speaker 3:  exactly what you'll pay when you get there. Checking good RX is free and
Speaker 3:  easy. It only takes a few seconds to find discounts that can save you up
Speaker 3:  to 80%. You can check out good RX directly on their
Speaker 3:  site or their app. So for simple, smart savings on your
Speaker 3:  prescriptions check, good RX go to good
Speaker 3:  rx.com/verge. That is good.
Speaker 3:  rx.com/verge. Good RX is
Speaker 3:  not insurance, but can be used instead of insurance in
Speaker 3:  2020 good RX users saved an average of 79% off
Speaker 3:  retail prices. So check out good
Speaker 3:  rx.com/verge.
Speaker 1:  All right, we're back theater. You've assembled a list of
Speaker 1:  gadgets here for us to talk about.
Speaker 4:  Usually we save the wacky gadgets for the end, but I, it, it it's,
Speaker 4:  you know, it's the holidays.
Speaker 1:  I tell people usually there's like themes and how these are ordered, but
Speaker 1:  this list is just titled cool gadget.
Speaker 4:  So look, Sony made a speaker that looks
Speaker 4:  like a bong. And I just think that they deserve some credit
Speaker 4:  for making a bong shaped speaker it's glass. It's
Speaker 4:  got a light on it. The glass is part of the speaker
Speaker 4:  and it does a little candlelight thing. And I don't know what's going on
Speaker 4:  with CES this year. As of this recording, some of us are going,
Speaker 4:  we'll see if COVID allows that to happen. This is the sort of thing that
Speaker 4:  we would expect to see at CES, but I kind of liked that. Sony
Speaker 4:  just said, you know what, here it is, here's the thing we made this
Speaker 1:  There's a throwaway line. So Chris waltz reviewed this thing. It's called
Speaker 1:  the Sony glass sound speaker. There's a throwaway line as a reading it. And
Speaker 1:  like, he's well, just like Sony believes in this so
Speaker 1:  much that this is the third generation of this device.
Speaker 1:  And I, you know, there's like, there's just a handful of teams at Sony
Speaker 1:  that I am desperate to know better. Like there's the
Speaker 1:  team that makes the party speakers. And they're like, here's what
Speaker 1:  the frat boys need this year. And they ha they have to have that meeting
Speaker 1:  right there. Like, and then there's right next to them. I'm assuming it's
Speaker 1:  very competitive. There's like the karaoke speaker department. Right?
Speaker 1:  And you can just see that they kind of overlap with the donut and the party
Speaker 1:  speakers are not karaoke speaker. Like I know it. I know that that's a fight
Speaker 1:  inside the halls of Sony. If anybody wants me to write that XYZ, I am
Speaker 1:  ready and willing to do it. Then there's like the
Speaker 1:  high-end home theater stuff that makes no sense department.
Speaker 1:  Like here's a $20,000 short range projector that you can put one inch from
Speaker 1:  the wall and it'll pull it up 400 inch, seven
Speaker 1:  20 P picture. And it's like, none of that makes sense. But
Speaker 1:  I love that you've made 15 of these. Yeah. Then there's like the part that's
Speaker 1:  like, if we made yet another memory card format,
Speaker 1:  right? Like Sony just does that. So what they do, that's just a core part
Speaker 1:  of their business. And then there's this group that's like the
Speaker 1:  wacky gadgets that you would never expect. Like
Speaker 1:  this one, it's a glass tube has an led in the middle that flickers like a
Speaker 1:  candle. Why? But they've done it for three generations and
Speaker 1:  running. Yeah. And I just want to know, I just, I just like, if
Speaker 1:  those PMs call me, they can come on decoder. If anyone knows,
Speaker 1:  like, do they have a P and L do they have to go to like the Sony
Speaker 1:  executive meeting and be like, you know, our budget for this year. And our
Speaker 1:  revenue really, really suggests that we should make a fourth generation of
Speaker 1:  the bond candle.
Speaker 4:  Here's the, here's the answer. Are you ready? Yeah. The amount of R and
Speaker 4:  D that goes into making a bond candle speaker is
Speaker 4:  so intense that the people who make it have to cut themselves
Speaker 4:  off from the world. And so nobody has given them the message yet
Speaker 4:  that there are no more WIWORK lobbies to fill.
Speaker 6:  They're just out there, they're on like an oil rig in the middle of the ocean
Speaker 6:  working on this project. They just send missives back.
Speaker 1:  There's there's some account at Sony with it like a spreadsheet, right. That's
Speaker 1:  like Mo like sales projections for bond candles
Speaker 1:  tear.
Speaker 4:  Okay. And no one will pay attention to them.
Speaker 1:  I'm just saying, I'll give you the whole show, like that account. Like
Speaker 1:  talk to me. Yeah. Okay.
Speaker 4:  Another cool gadget is the analog pocket. This thing
Speaker 4:  is great. So it's a, it's a game boy. It's a modern game. Boy that could
Speaker 4:  play gameboard cartridges. You could also get an adapter to play game gear,
Speaker 4:  cartridges. It is incredibly well designed. It has an amazing
Speaker 4:  screen. Andrew Webster reviewed it. And I just, I look at this
Speaker 4:  thing and I can see in my mind's eye,
Speaker 4:  a box in my parents' attic with my GameBoy cartridges,
Speaker 4:  all I want to do is go find them. Yeah. So
Speaker 4:  we had one here in San Francisco cause Viren was taking photos of it for
Speaker 4:  Andrew's review. And it is, it's amazing. It's it? It feels great.
Speaker 4:  The plastic isn't quite like ultra premium, I guess is how I would say it's
Speaker 4:  like, you can kind of feel like there was maybe like the tiniest of cost-cutting
Speaker 4:  there, but in terms of like a thing to play game
Speaker 4:  boy games, there's literally nothing better. And they really didn't need
Speaker 4:  go this hard, but they did. And it's amazing
Speaker 1:  Synthesize of like the original game boy or like the game
Speaker 1:  boy pocket.
Speaker 4:  Oh, it's like the original game. Boy. It's like a little tiny bit bigger.
Speaker 4:  Maybe even than the original game. Boy, it's that big? It's pretty big. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  But like, it feels comfortable, right? Because like the shoulder buttons
Speaker 4:  are at the base of where the cartridge goes in and it's got four buttons
Speaker 4:  instead of two. And so like, if you think about the ergonomics of your
Speaker 4:  hand, you, you don't want, if you're going to make it much smaller,
Speaker 4:  you're, you're going to make a whole bunch of other trade-offs. And like
Speaker 4:  the trade-offs they chose to make was having a really great screen and the
Speaker 4:  ability for it to do more stuff than just be a game boy run
Speaker 4:  game by cartridges said, can, you can put the adapter in for game gear. And
Speaker 4:  so it's like, it's a more interesting versatile gadget, just a
Speaker 4:  game boy game.
Speaker 1:  The reason I ask is not to give any budding
Speaker 1:  young students, this idea that the game boy pocket fit
Speaker 1:  perfectly into the slide cover of a Tia 82 calculator.
Speaker 1:  And so when I was in high school, we'd
Speaker 1:  pretend that we are programming our TA 80 twos and calculus, but
Speaker 1:  really we were playing Zelda. And so at the beginning of calculus, we
Speaker 1:  would have, we would do it, but you turn it on. And the only sound you could
Speaker 1:  not mute on the gateway pocket was the startup time. The Dean. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  And we got coffee. Cause
Speaker 4:  You weren't like going in
Speaker 1:  The middle of the winter. Like we did that for like weeks on end. We're like,
Speaker 1:  yeah, like, anyway, I was just, it brought back. I saw this thing and I was
Speaker 1:  like, oh, I could probably slide this into a TA to bring it
Speaker 1:  back. I guess people probably slide their phones into their TA 80 twos. Now
Speaker 4:  People don't know the difference between you and me. Like you grow up rock
Speaker 4:  and roll playing game boy. And your, your  thing. I grew up just like
Speaker 4:  programming the TA 80. No,
Speaker 4:   on
Speaker 4:  the TA. Come on.
Speaker 1:  We've done all that. But w when the game boy pocket came out, when we, I
Speaker 1:  remember this shout out to my friend, Ryan, he was like, let me see that
Speaker 1:  for a second. And he went, we're like, oh,
Speaker 1:  heavens opened
Speaker 1:  this thing is great. I'm probably going to buy one. I don't know why, but
Speaker 1:  I'm super into it
Speaker 4:  Presales this week for it. Yeah. I'm still waiting for my
Speaker 4:  play date. Yeah. So waiting on my play date, they had to push some stuff
Speaker 4:  back, but good on them. They like, they were, they've been very transparent
Speaker 4:  to the whole process. So I'm not actually agitating about it.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. They've been very open and they've just got a massive supply chain
Speaker 1:  issues, right? Yep. All right.
Speaker 4:  Ah, man, I actually there's, there's something I want to talk about, but
Speaker 4:  we're going to talk about it later because now we're going to talk about
Speaker 4:  the Opal C1. This is a webcam
Speaker 1:  I'm super into this.
Speaker 4:  So Cameron reviewed it.
Speaker 1:  That counts. Your camera is off right now because it's overheated. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I mean, come on. This thing has a giant like heat fin on the back of it.
Speaker 4:  I'm going to buy
Speaker 1:  One of these for you. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  So it's a high end webcam with good, with a good microphones that are like
Speaker 4:  supposed to be great at noise canceling they're okay. But it's basically
Speaker 4:  like all the stuff that makes smartphone a better camera than your average
Speaker 4:  webcam. There's like, well, let's just make a bespoke webcam. That's based
Speaker 4:  on smartphone parts. So it's got a, the Sony sensor, I think from the pixel
Speaker 4:  one, it's got a bunch of other like smart Senate. It's better at background
Speaker 4:  blur than like, Zoom's really ugly background blur. It's like
Speaker 4:  300 bucks. So
Speaker 1:  It's expensive. But I was thinking about this, like my
Speaker 1:  Zevi one that I use, I use a Sony Z one is my webcam.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, same. It is expensive. It was four or 500 bucks or whatever it was.
Speaker 1:  It's complicated. Like I would never send this to anyone
Speaker 1:  else to use as a webcam because you have to monkey with the settings, you
Speaker 1:  need a USB capture card, or you have to use Sony imaging edge, which is
Speaker 1:  Alex's personal nemesis.
Speaker 1:  All that's a mess. But this thing is like a little more expensive than what
Speaker 1:  you might spend on a webcam. Yep. I think the sensor part of it's really
Speaker 1:  interesting. Right. We, we have not spent a lot of time in the show talking
Speaker 1:  about the sensor from the pixel. One is like a great
Speaker 1:  sensor. It was the software that made and it was, it's a Sony sensor.
Speaker 1:  It is the same Sony sensor, but it's a software that made that sensor good.
Speaker 1:  And they basically with the pixel anyway, they ran it to the
Speaker 1:  edge of its limits. And now they've had to go to a new sensor. Yep. So it's
Speaker 1:  like fascinating to me that they're using that sensor. And it's like on the
Speaker 1:  website, they're hyping up the sensor. But in the context of the show, we're
Speaker 1:  like, here's this whole,
Speaker 4:  The sensor made by the way, designed by the same person who designed the
Speaker 4:  Google clips camera.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, it does. Doesn't like an all star team writes X, Google, X, apple.
Speaker 1:  What's really interesting to me is their pricing models. You can buy the
Speaker 1:  thing right now. It's plug and play with windows,
Speaker 1:  plug and play with Mac. But if you want all the software features that like
Speaker 1:  really get the most out of it. You need software at the softwares Mac only
Speaker 1:  right now. And it's a subscription.
Speaker 6:  Yep. So it's like, do I want to just have my camera overheat every day?
Speaker 6:  Or do I want to pay us?
Speaker 4:  I want you to, I want you to pay a subscription so bad.
Speaker 6:  I know what this room, the thing
Speaker 4:  I will pay you a subscription. I will pay your subscription
Speaker 1:  Fee. I mean, it's cheap. It's like,
Speaker 6:  It's very, I I've been investigating the C1
Speaker 1:  And right now it's free for early customers. So if you pre-order, it it's
Speaker 1:  free. They say, but it's just as one of those things, right? Like
Speaker 1:  every one of these products is turning into a recurring revenue stream.
Speaker 1:  So now you're now a hardware. Webcam has like subscription
Speaker 1:  software. The remote starting a Toyota requires a
Speaker 1:  subscription. Oh, we're going to get to that. It's just coming to everything.
Speaker 1:  It's killing me
Speaker 4:  The other hand on the, on the flip side of that, I just bought this a Garmin
Speaker 4:  venue too. And I wanted to buy this watch face. And the way you buy the watch
Speaker 4:  face is you read the description and the guy says, please PayPal me and make
Speaker 4:  sure you pay pal me as a friend. So we don't have to pay the fees. And then
Speaker 4:  a couple of days later, he gets back to you with the code to unlock the pro
Speaker 4:  features, which currently
Speaker 1:  I love it. It's very, it's very personal. It's very, it's like, artisinal
Speaker 1:  watch faces. I will say the OPL. You should. It looks good. That's
Speaker 1:  actually the point of this, all this. Like it is not just like a pixel one
Speaker 1:  quality video. They've done a bunch of computational
Speaker 1:  photography stuff with that sensor. They've got an Intel chip in there. Cameron
Speaker 1:  really likes it when he reviewed it. I'm like, like immediately emailed them.
Speaker 1:  I was like, give me a code to buy this.
Speaker 4:  We'll see this next one is for Alex. It's the Dell,
Speaker 4:  it's a concept device from Dell. It's called the stanza. It's basically just
Speaker 4:  a little tablet that you can like take notes on. And then that's all, it's
Speaker 4:  literally all it does. And then you'd like to have the thing and it'll digitize
Speaker 4:  it. And it'll
Speaker 6:  You use it as a monitor, right?
Speaker 4:  Sure. But I mean, let's not get too crazy here. The idea here is they're
Speaker 4:  trying to simplify it down to the core idea of taking
Speaker 4:  notes. And I just want to know why
Speaker 4:  isn't this e-cig
Speaker 6:  That's that's what would be my question too? That's why Dell didn't allow
Speaker 6:  me in the room. No, I didn't. I didn't go. They probably would have allowed
Speaker 6:  me, but when I said eating, they probably would have kicked me out. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  But yeah, I just, I mean, I get it. I think
Speaker 6:  that's the big push pull, right? Like a lot of people really want full color
Speaker 6:  that he has terrible still at. So they're like, okay, let's do this.
Speaker 6:  Let's try to like mimic writing, even though I think it's a lot worse. Like
Speaker 6:  the writing experience on an iPad versus remarkable too, is
Speaker 6:  just night and day different. But this could be cool if it comes out
Speaker 4:  Of, I don't think they're ever going to make this and this feels like
Speaker 1:  Classic it's CS time. There's some designers at
Speaker 1:  Dell. Here's some stuff. Yeah. And they just did it kind of early, you know?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. It looks kind of like an iPad. Like I got very iPad
Speaker 6:  feelings from it. Yeah. Okay.
Speaker 4:  Okay. Oh wait. You know what, I'm going out of order. I was going to say
Speaker 4:  this to the Android section, but we're, we're still in cool gadget zone.
Speaker 4:  So here we go. The APO find N it is a new
Speaker 4:  folding phone from APO only it be available in China. Basically
Speaker 4:  take your standard galaxy Z fold three. But instead of, instead of having
Speaker 4:  it be super tall, just make it a little shorter when it's
Speaker 4:  closed. So if you open it up, it's almost square and it takes the
Speaker 4:  like weird dude
Speaker 4:  strangeness, remote quality of the other thing and makes it feel,
Speaker 4:  I dunno, more like a human size, like, like pocketbook or like a notebook
Speaker 4:  or something. Yeah. And it's just like the build quality is
Speaker 4:  really, really nice. And for a company that,
Speaker 4:  you know, like we're going to get into some of the problems they've been
Speaker 4:  having with the OnePlus foot, but for a company that is just rolling into
Speaker 4:  foldable phones as a first entry, standby for tactical, took a look at this
Speaker 4:  thing. It looks great. It's a beautiful little phone. And they
Speaker 4:  didn't overextend themselves like Samsung did with like the under screened
Speaker 4:  selfie camera, you know, and that the size of the
Speaker 4:  screen what's unfolded. They don't have to bother with a bunch of like
Speaker 4:  multitasking questions because it's not quite big enough for that.
Speaker 4:  It's just a nice big screen that folds up into a size that doesn't feel ridiculous.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I think one of the things we keep talking about with folding phones
Speaker 1:  over and over and over again is what is the form factor
Speaker 1:  for this technology? Like what does a folding screen
Speaker 1:  actually enable? Yeah. And Samsung kind of went big
Speaker 1:  phone to big tablet, which is a very Samsung, like it's just in keeping
Speaker 1:  with her. It's what you would expect from them. They also went like flip
Speaker 1:  phone to little guy.
Speaker 4:  Right. And while he has got one of these now to the  flip, but
Speaker 1:  I think this, this is like an unexplored, middle zone is what you're getting
Speaker 1:  at. Right. Like small phone to small tablet. Yeah. But
Speaker 1:  like a small tablet is just a big phone. Like there's something in there.
Speaker 1:  That's
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Well it's doesn't have the complications. I like the two screens on
Speaker 4:  like the surface duo service do a two. I would like to see
Speaker 4:  more foldable form factors. And not just because I like seeing wacky phones,
Speaker 4:  but like LG has given up the ghost. So it's
Speaker 4:  good to come from places like APO Huawei, Sharmi, because
Speaker 4:  Samsung is like set. And I think that for, in this zone
Speaker 4:  of folding phones and then like in the zone of like Android innovation,
Speaker 4:  Samsung has had way too much leverage at least outside of China in terms
Speaker 4:  of like how people think about what the trajectory of phones should be. And
Speaker 4:  so I really hope that stuff like this will encourage other companies
Speaker 4:  to do more experimental stuff and
Speaker 4:  like experimental stuff that actually could be sold because like TCL we'll
Speaker 4:  show you wacky prototypes all day long, but no, they're, they're
Speaker 4:  bad. I actually want to see more stuck at closer to like
Speaker 4:  actual production. And this is a, this is a good sign. That's a good, good
Speaker 4:  step on the way
Speaker 1:  I'm looking at this wall, AP 50 pocket that you just mentioned that we have
Speaker 1:  unless too, and it's the same rules. It's
Speaker 4:  Cool. Right. It's got the two circles on it once for the display once for
Speaker 4:  the camera array. It looks great. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  I mean, it's funny. Cause like, you know, this thing was not announced for
Speaker 1:  the United States at all. Like yeah. It was announced in a Harper's bizarre
Speaker 1:  China photo-shoot
Speaker 1:  Rules because it was in a fashion photo shoot. Yeah. Like we have no
Speaker 1:  idea, but I just keep looking in it's like, what is, what is the big
Speaker 1:  question? Like what form factor does this display technology
Speaker 1:  actually enable that people want? And we've, we've only taken a couple
Speaker 1:  shots.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And like we've only taken a couple we've taken, well, there's more
Speaker 4:  than a couple, but we've only taken like two, like good shots. Everything
Speaker 4:  else has been like bad. Like just like you hit the uprights,
Speaker 4:  if
Speaker 1:  Can you just dog like talked it off the uprights. I mean, like
Speaker 1:  I get it, like there's other stuff like LG will make you a hundred thousand
Speaker 1:  dollars TV that rolls up at the foot of your bed. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Where's the fan
Speaker 1:  Version. Yeah. Like that's what I want. Right. Like none
Speaker 1:  of that stuff exists.
Speaker 4:  What about the watch version? Because there's a patent for a Samsung
Speaker 4:  watch that unrolls and expands out and
Speaker 4:  it's like, it's split down the middle for some reason. So if you're like,
Speaker 4:  you want to watch a video on your watch. It's like split in the middle, which
Speaker 4:  is incredible. This is one of the,
Speaker 1:  Those patents were like, you know, I've spent a lot of my life
Speaker 1:  covering patent. I looked at this one, I was like, shouldn't the patent examiner
Speaker 1:  sent this back with like, you gotta try harder. Like literally the drawing
Speaker 1:  is like a watch and two fingers and the fingers unpinched in the watch gets
Speaker 1:  bigger. And it's like kinda, it's like an eight year old could have come
Speaker 1:  up with this guy.
Speaker 4:  I also watched iron man too. Come on.
Speaker 1:  I'm sure it is a much more complete Baton obligation. It just those first
Speaker 1:  few pictures,
Speaker 6:  The way it rendered for like fours on
Speaker 6:  half of the screen and then just the ax on the other. This
Speaker 6:  is incredible. I like, I love that. They were like, yeah, sure.
Speaker 6:  Patent go
Speaker 4:  Movies. Don't ever put stuff in the middle of the picture. It's always on
Speaker 4:  the left and the right. So of course, you know,
Speaker 1:  Well then you just started talking about how it rendered Thor with no explanation
Speaker 1:  of the fact that one of the patent images is a Thor.
Speaker 6:  This is one of the patent images is a Thor. I didn't just like
Speaker 6:  have that idea. I've already seen it. It's great.
Speaker 6:  Thor's on
Speaker 1:  Very good. But you got it. These pictures are just, it's like, think
Speaker 4:  So the last gadget is the thing that should be cool. But instead it's a
Speaker 4:  disappointment. Jen reviewed it. It's the echo show
Speaker 4:  15, which is like the final form of what the echo show should have been,
Speaker 4:  which is a picture frame. But
Speaker 4:  it's got this widget system, which is not great. Like the
Speaker 4:  smart home controls are really not great. And also it's got this new
Speaker 4:  fancy, Amazon custom bespoke processor in it,
Speaker 1:  But it's still slow. That's unforgivable. Come on.
Speaker 6:  What I'm looking at? Like I'm looking at one of the pictures she took and
Speaker 6:  I'm looking at the widgets and the buttons look like they were designed in
Speaker 6:  2007. Like yeah. The UI is just
Speaker 1:  Ugly. It's funny. We were talking about fridges last week. Like it looks
Speaker 1:  like the Samsung fridge UI. Yeah. Like this is
Speaker 1:  what a Samsung smart fridge tablet looks like. And it's like, I don't know
Speaker 1:  today, Amazon knock at the memo that they did not set the world on fire with
Speaker 1:  smart fridges. Like I don't, I don't know. The photo thing is
Speaker 1:  really interesting because we had Dave, Dave limp on decoder and I was like,
Speaker 1:  Alexa, like the thing holding me out of that ecosystem is that Google
Speaker 1:  photos is better than Amazon photos. He was like, Amazon photos are slips
Speaker 1:  me a week later. Great. At keeping the cards close a week
Speaker 1:  later, Amazon launched a huge update. Tam is on photos iOS only.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. So the app on Iowa. Cause that's, if you think about this, the most
Speaker 1:  important place, like most of your photos on your phone, if you've got iOS
Speaker 1:  app, you're doing the auto import. Great. Now you can feed them to Alexa
Speaker 1:  devices. So, okay. The first bits and bobs of this
Speaker 1:  are coming together, we're going to compete with Google photos, but then
Speaker 1:  it's slow. It's like you might as well just get a digital photo frame at
Speaker 1:  that point. Like you're still doing better than having a slow computer on
Speaker 1:  your wall.
Speaker 4:  Well, so here's my thing. Like Amazon is trying very hard to create the
Speaker 4:  ambient OS. Right. But trying to make ambient computing, they're even trying
Speaker 4:  to like move beyond the whole concept of OSTP in the first place and just
Speaker 4:  have it be ambient computing. But there's a step in the
Speaker 4:  middle before you get there where like people still need
Speaker 4:  screens and they need to do stuff on those screens and they need the stuff
Speaker 4:  that they do in those screens to connect to the rest of their life and connect
Speaker 4:  to their phone. And I don't know how often you
Speaker 4:  interact with the Alexa app on your phone, but it's not
Speaker 4:  fun. And you know, there's like shopping lists here. And like, there's
Speaker 4:  like we mentioned the pictures, there's the widgets for your smart home.
Speaker 4:  There's like all of this stuff that looks like it's connected
Speaker 4:  to a whole and complete ecosystem in the way that, you know,
Speaker 4:  an iPad is, or even an Android tablet might be, but it's not,
Speaker 4:  it's all like a veneer. It's the veneer of an ecosystem with a bunch
Speaker 4:  of widgets on it. It's not an actual ecosystem unless you are
Speaker 4:  willing to bring your whole family in and use
Speaker 4:  the Lexa app to do all your stuff.
Speaker 1:  I, I would say like, I would be more offended by this. If
Speaker 1:  the product was good, you know what I mean? Like it's a giant, slow
Speaker 1:  picture frame. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Like
Speaker 1:  Short, like of course the software is kind of, I can't keep it. Like, that's
Speaker 1:  why I, it's just weird that Amazon, this is true.
Speaker 1:  I'll offer this criticism to Google too. They, they just put out that new
Speaker 1:  Google nest hub, Mia, like same design, new processor. They told
Speaker 1:  us still pretty slow. And now they're like, Google is adding, there's like
Speaker 1:  a browser on that thing. But you can just open web pages.
Speaker 1:  There's an apps doc. And it's like, guys, you did not design these to be
Speaker 1:  computers in this way. Like you are overtaxing
Speaker 1:  the hardware here, but turning them into baby iPad, plugged
Speaker 1:  into the wall. Yeah. Also they're plugged into the wall. Why not put faster
Speaker 1:  chips in them. Right. And like, we're just kind of like, it seems like
Speaker 1:  they can't sell you a tablet. They know they can't sell you a tablet. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And actually just reviewed a couple of chromo S tablets. And they're like,
Speaker 4:  they're they, they haven't gotten there yet. They're not there. You should
Speaker 4:  still do like Chromecast is great. Kronos tablets are not,
Speaker 1:  Let's make these weird crappy tablets out of our smart
Speaker 1:  home displays. Yeah. Is where they're going. And it just doesn't make any
Speaker 1:  sense to me. Well,
Speaker 6:  So cheap. Like, I mean, I guess yeah, they have to be cheap. Right? It's
Speaker 6:  Amazon's whole thing is undercutting everybody else, but it's just
Speaker 6:  like, looks like so cheaply made, it's got the, the super
Speaker 6:  slow processor and then it's just like zero effort.
Speaker 6:  And, and there's the other side of it, right? There's the really, really,
Speaker 6:  really nice, super expensive billionaires. Have
Speaker 6:  it in their home, like what? This is aping and isn't the Cantor just be
Speaker 6:  something in the middle for people who don't want to spend
Speaker 6:  no money on a garbage piece of technology. Like
Speaker 1:  I would say this stuff, the billionaires have on there, the loss of their
Speaker 1:  homes is it's actually worse.
Speaker 1:  Like have you ever like encountered one of those systems? I have a friend
Speaker 1:  who he used to install them and he was like, they're all intentionally designed
Speaker 1:  broken so that our service contracts are more lucrative. Like
Speaker 1:  it's like pretty brutal, but they're billionaires, whatever, just like milk.
Speaker 1:  And they don't care. It's a good business model. It's good work. If you get
Speaker 1:  it, we got to take a break. But then we're going to come back. And Deidre
Speaker 1:  has promised that we'll be sad about software updates.
Speaker 4:  This episode of the Vergecast is brought to you by Nord VPN. If you listen
Speaker 4:  to this show, you probably have some pretty strong opinions about VPNs.
Speaker 4:  At the very least, you understand that a VPN is the best way to guarantee
Speaker 4:  privacy encrypt your data and protect yourself online. Here's the problem
Speaker 4:  though, with so many different options out there, how do you find the best
Speaker 4:  VPN for you? Here's an idea you might want to start with the fastest one,
Speaker 4:  the one that's guaranteed to not get in the way of your streaming, zooming
Speaker 4:  and everything else that you need to do online. Start with Nord. VPN
Speaker 4:  Nord VPN offers the incredible encrypted protection. You
Speaker 4:  demand from a VPN while testing repeatedly as the
Speaker 4:  fastest VPN on the market. One subscription offers protection across a
Speaker 4:  whopping six different devices, and you can secure each of them with just
Speaker 4:  a single click. Plus Nord VPN has a seriously awesome
Speaker 4:  number of servers more than 5,000 of them spread across 60 different
Speaker 4:  countries. So you're never going to have to worry about getting locked out
Speaker 4:  of location specific content again, grab your holiday season deal by going
Speaker 4:  to Nord vpn.com/vergecast or use
Speaker 4:  coupon code Vergecast and get up to 73% off of
Speaker 4:  your Nord VPN plan. Plus a bonus gift.
Speaker 2:  This podcast is brought to you by Twilio for businesses around the
Speaker 2:  world, unlocking and unifying real-time customer data is critical,
Speaker 2:  especially for delivering truly personalized campaigns at scale.
Speaker 2:  That's why companies like Instacart into it. And IBM are turning to Twilio,
Speaker 2:  which was recently ranked number one for 2020 market share and customer data
Speaker 2:  platforms by IDC to learn how Twilio can help your business
Speaker 2:  harness real-time data and build customer engagement. Like no other visit
Speaker 2:  twilio.com.
Speaker 1:  We're back.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I front-loaded the fun stuff. And now we're going to have some sad
Speaker 4:  stuff. It was just suffer updates. Merry Christmas,
Speaker 1:  Everyone.
Speaker 4:  Well, we'll say we'll have some fun at the end. We'll have a lighting round.
Speaker 4:  It'll be okay. So apple got out a bunch of its false stuff. So
Speaker 4:  iOS 15 dot two with the app privacy report. And
Speaker 4:  some weirdness was, see Sam universal is still Mia on
Speaker 4:  Monterrey, but you can do share play now. Hooray. And
Speaker 4:  then, I don't know, like Google put out a massive update for the pixel six,
Speaker 4:  but it still hasn't arrived on a bunch of here, at least here in the U S
Speaker 4:  one. Plus had the pull it's O S update for oxygen O S
Speaker 4:  12, just had they, did. They just screwed it up.
Speaker 4:  I think that everyone needs to take a beat on your big software
Speaker 4:  updates. Just like, hold them back a little bit
Speaker 4:  longer. Don't announce features till you can ship them. Don't
Speaker 4:  do this, this, this fall in particular. I
Speaker 4:  expected, you know, I expected a little bit of chaos
Speaker 4:  last year from COVID and everyone learning how to work remote or whatever,
Speaker 4:  but the fact that we've had so many major OS updates this fall
Speaker 4:  just go sideways. Yeah. Is infuriating. And
Speaker 4:  I don't know, I don't have it like a thesis here other than
Speaker 4:  I am seeing similar stories across apple
Speaker 4:  and Android. So
Speaker 1:  Can I, oh, here's my shot in the dark. Okay. I am like a huge proponent of
Speaker 1:  remote work. So don't take this the wrong way. These companies
Speaker 1:  are in like, kind of like open conflict with their employees. So return
Speaker 1:  to office, right. And apples are turned certainly as hardware employees,
Speaker 1:  but the we're seeing like here's the fruits of 19 months of
Speaker 1:  remote software development. I just like, I honestly wonder if
Speaker 1:  maintaining that relentless yearly updates
Speaker 1:  schedule and maybe it's not just being remote. Maybe it's the stress of the
Speaker 1:  pandemic. Like I wonder if maybe they shouldn't have eased up on the
Speaker 1:  aggressiveness of the yearly update schedule to just account for the fact
Speaker 1:  that their workforces are totally distributed now. Yeah. I mean, I I've no
Speaker 1:  science behind this and I don't think apple engineers still go back to the
Speaker 1:  office or whatever. I'm just saying like, it's, you can see those
Speaker 1:  two things may be colliding in this being a result. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  I was going to say it like apple had already struggled with this, but also
Speaker 6:  I want to point out there is one company that had a major update just like
Speaker 6:  last week to all of its Android
Speaker 6:  tablets that may be run on E ink. And it was wonderful.
Speaker 6:  It's beautiful.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. That's four people work there. They probably all just got on a zoom
Speaker 1:  and wrote it together.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it was beautiful. I love it. So not everybody is
Speaker 6:  screwed up their updates this year,
Speaker 1:  There is a little concert. This SI something that you mentioned with apple,
Speaker 1:  there's some controversy that they changed the web pages and maybe it was
Speaker 1:  going away. Apple tells us Nope. Still coming.
Speaker 1:  They're still working on it. Still collecting feedback. So yeah. We'll see
Speaker 1:  if that happens. The other part, I mean, I was 15 is missing a
Speaker 1:  lot of features. Right. They're slowly rolling them out. Universal control.
Speaker 1:  Not being there. This is like a highlight feature of all of it. And
Speaker 1:  there's still, we don't know some spring, which is a long time away.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And I really want it. It's like a great
Speaker 1:  Feature. The end of spring is like, now you're starting to start thinking
Speaker 1:  about Iowa 16 on this cadence, for sure. Right. The end of
Speaker 1:  spring rolls you is pretty close to June, which is when they will announce
Speaker 1:  Iowa 16. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  It's just like, wouldn't the Mac book air. Like the second generation Mac
Speaker 6:  book air is going to be coming out and also finally universal control.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. There's this moment that has become lore
Speaker 4:  amongst people that have watched apple keynotes over the years and I'm forgetting
Speaker 4:  the last, was it snow leopard? The snow leopard. Yeah. Where they got out
Speaker 4:  and they're like, all right, here are the new features. This year are none
Speaker 4:  just bug fixes and speed improvements. And like the crowd
Speaker 4:  erupted in. Cheers. Yeah. And I'm just saying
Speaker 4:  20, 22 blank check to every major software
Speaker 4:  company redo that keynote,
Speaker 4:  Microsoft, apple, Google company that makes
Speaker 4:  Alex's weirdo E ink tablet. They did a great job this
Speaker 4:  year. Come out and say, all we're doing this year is clean and stuff up.
Speaker 4:  That's it like Microsoft just come on me. You know what? The settings
Speaker 4:  and the control panels thing. Yeah. W we're we've been, you know, we've been
Speaker 4:  working on it. It's w it's fixed. They're all in one place now. And that's
Speaker 4:  the only feature we're shipping. Yeah. All apple needs to do is like ship
Speaker 4:  the features they promise last year and bug fixes blank check. Do it.
Speaker 1:  I always thinking about the local news test of the apple keynote. Like,
Speaker 1:  what thing are they going to announce that breaks through to like the local
Speaker 1:  news or the today show or whatever. Yeah. And they're kind of like out
Speaker 1:  like universal control they'll ship. And like, can you just imagine you're
Speaker 1:  like a local news anchor being like, and now you can wave an iPad at your
Speaker 1:  laptop,
Speaker 1:  but if they're apple announces, we're taking a year off to
Speaker 1:  clean up all the bugs. Like literally every local news, like the today show
Speaker 1:  we'll do the full hour. Yeah. On apple said, they're just going to fix
Speaker 1:  the iPhone. And like, you can just see it. Like, it's like an earned victory
Speaker 1:  for them. Yeah. All right. They're never going to do it. Snow leopard was
Speaker 1:  the best sauce ever made. I still think about it with way I was at, I was
Speaker 1:  taking our trash to the, I live in the woods. So I take my own trash to the
Speaker 1:  dump and they have a, they have like a shed, like the electronics recycling
Speaker 1:  shed. Yeah. And they had like an original I book in there
Speaker 1:  who, and I was like, I should take this home and run snow leopard.
Speaker 4:  The other software stuff I wanted to talk about is two things happened.
Speaker 4:  Adobe launched creative cloud express, which is a,
Speaker 4:  like a light version of its editing tools. And then
Speaker 4:  snap launched story studio, which is a standalone
Speaker 4:  video editing app for phones. And I feel like
Speaker 4:  the cycle of everybody realizing, oh God, Tik TOK is a video editing
Speaker 4:  app. And we need to catch up to that. But we don't know quite how. And like
Speaker 4:  what's, how's it connect to our social network or not is going to be hitting.
Speaker 4:  And it's going to be hitting in waves over the next year or so
Speaker 4:  I'm not going to bring us back around to apple clips, although I really want
Speaker 4:  to, but I don't know, like I'm excited to see another
Speaker 4:  shot from other companies besides tech talk at innovating
Speaker 4:  on the like mobile editing workflow. Despite the fact that
Speaker 4:  inherently, when I see Adobe announced a light version of its software, I
Speaker 4:  hate it. Cause I've used a bunch of their, like the way they used to
Speaker 4:  think about mobile software there, you know, elements or whatever the heck
Speaker 4:  they used to call that stuff. It was terrible. I believe Adobe can get
Speaker 4:  it better now because they seem to have a clear
Speaker 4:  mindset of how their stuff works on multiple platforms and cloud and
Speaker 4:  whatever. But yeah, I dunno. I think it's
Speaker 4:  time to, to have a little bit more innovation in like the UI
Speaker 4:  of video editing. I think Tik TOK has definitely led the way, but we are
Speaker 4:  like, we need something that feels like, I dunno, we need like that
Speaker 4:  movie moment, like where there's like a coherent, like, oh, I am rethinking
Speaker 4:  how this thing works in a way that isn't sort of like tacked on tacked on
Speaker 4:  tacked on and the way it was on Tik TOK and
Speaker 1:  A little bit on reels. So I don't make a lot of tech talks. Yeah. It's not
Speaker 1:  my thing. But I would argue that that movie moment
Speaker 1:  actually already happened with Tech-Talk like the tick-tock video editor
Speaker 1:  is complicated, but it works nothing like a premiere or whatever. It doesn't
Speaker 1:  even work like a movie, which is right. No one understands
Speaker 1:  it's its own thing. And like users have different expectations
Speaker 1:  out of it. And I think that's part of partially what drove snapped to do
Speaker 1:  this. Like yeah. The audience of tick-tock users and Snapchat users
Speaker 1:  is a Venn diagram. Like there's perfect overlap. It's both young audiences
Speaker 1:  is Alex. He will always remind us. Snapchat is very popular people like lots
Speaker 1:  of people use it just doesn't get the attention of the other platforms. So
Speaker 1:  snap making a tool that's better for, Tech-Talk just reinforces the
Speaker 1:  affinity people already have for snap. Right. And I don't think snap is going
Speaker 1:  to make a Tik TOK clone. I think they just want people to using its tools
Speaker 1:  instead of thinking of Tik TOK is a creative place that then it gets
Speaker 1:  shared out elsewhere. So I think there's value here. And I think the reason
Speaker 1:  apple never got there with clips is like apple. Once you're
Speaker 1:  done making the thing, apple is, there's no value
Speaker 1:  to apple once they're done. Right. Right. It's just like, you're going to
Speaker 1:  share it on Instagram or whatever. You
Speaker 4:  Don't feel good about clips. The only person that feels good about clips
Speaker 4:  is me.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. But like, but they don't have like this big distribution network that
Speaker 1:  is their business. Right. Whereas with Tik TOK, getting you to
Speaker 1:  participate in the Tik TOK economy is great for tech
Speaker 1:  business. So there's a huge incentive to make that video editor like
Speaker 1:  fun to use. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Adobe doesn't have that ecosystem, but it seems like they're, they're starting
Speaker 4:  to think about doing a better job with, with mobile and like
Speaker 4:  that.
Speaker 6:  I think they're only thinking about it because they have like a finite
Speaker 6:  number based out, right? Like they have professionals,
Speaker 6:  all of these young people and stuff no longer are going to go and buy
Speaker 6:  Photoshop. They're not going to go buy premiere. They never would have to
Speaker 6:  begin with, but like, they're going to go pirate or they're going to go
Speaker 6:  get the gimp has a gimp Blake free
Speaker 6:  Photoshop. Like they need this younger audience that actively hates
Speaker 6:  them because of the last, like how
Speaker 6:  difficult they've made the path to entry into Photoshop and
Speaker 6:  premiere. Like they actively hate them. And this is like, oh yeah, we can
Speaker 6:  go for them. Even though it's I guess it's mainly this new
Speaker 6:  software suite is mainly geared for like social media managers.
Speaker 1:  So Scott Belsky was on declutter just recently. And
Speaker 1:  like that's where Adobe lives, right? Like Adobe is search to finish
Speaker 1:  a commercial operation. Right. Social there. Their
Speaker 1:  big competitors are not necessarily tech stock. Although it takes out, creates
Speaker 1:  the paradigms for the tools that Adobe has to live in. So they're very aware
Speaker 1:  they need to participate. So they know, but their competition
Speaker 1:  is Figma and Canva. Right? You are, you own a
Speaker 1:  flower shop and you want to do some Facebook ads. What tools are you gonna
Speaker 1:  use to make your, your Facebook ads? Adobe wants it to be their tools,
Speaker 1:  right? Like that's, that's where they live is like the second you become
Speaker 1:  a business. Adobe is like a hundred bucks a month.
Speaker 1:  Where else are you going to go? Yep. Here we are. And I,
Speaker 1:  I think that's the line for them. Although that that whole interview is fascinating.
Speaker 1:  It's fascinating. But I, I do think they're not,
Speaker 1:  they're not chasing teens need to care about Photoshop. They're they're
Speaker 1:  chasing the second you graduate to, this is revenue.
Speaker 1:  You're going to move to Adobe stools.
Speaker 6:  Right. Are you going to move to them on your phone?
Speaker 1:  No. You're gonna move to them onto your iPad. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  But like a less good version than what you can get on a
Speaker 6:  computer. I don't know. I just feels like they still haven't answered. Like
Speaker 6:  they still haven't solved the problem.
Speaker 1:  What is a computer Alex? Yes.
Speaker 6:  They haven't solved the problem of lake. The difference
Speaker 6:  between Photoshop and premiere on a computer or a
Speaker 6:  laptop, excuse me, you know, something with an x86
Speaker 6:  processor and, and mobile based stuff.
Speaker 1:  Oh, they've saw that problem with a format of file format called cloud PSD,
Speaker 1:  which is a lot like
Speaker 4:  One, one last offer up thing. Speaking of like software updates, actually
Speaker 4:  like spare a thought for, since admins around you, because
Speaker 4:  this log forge bug is not bug
Speaker 4:  vulnerability. It's out of control. And I, I actually don't have any
Speaker 4:  interesting things to say about it. I'm happy that CloudFlare is like trying
Speaker 4:  to block it off at a system level there. But
Speaker 1:  Yeah, you're happy about it. You're happy that there's a centralized gatekeeper
Speaker 1:  on the internet. Who's like, we're just going to fix it, man. That cuts both
Speaker 1:  ways.
Speaker 4:  It's rough. Right. But this is one of these levels of catastrophe or
Speaker 4:  it's so big that it's impossible to wrap your head around because it's
Speaker 4:  big, but it's also like slow moving. So there's not like
Speaker 4:  an immediate, like, oh my God, this thing is broken. And I feel it right
Speaker 4:  now, or this hack just happened. Like this was the exact effect of it is
Speaker 4:  this fundamental piece of Java is like
Speaker 4:  broken and there's fixes for it. But it's going to take a long time. And
Speaker 4:  in the meantime, it's trivially easy to attack. And so get
Speaker 4:  ready for bad stuff. Question mark period. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  And I will say it's a great time for us to hire a new senior security report.
Speaker 1:  Our corn faith corn's did a great job.
Speaker 1:  Like literally I was like, wow, just in the Nick of time. Yeah. So Corrine's
Speaker 1:  headline is a lot forward is patched. The exploits are just
Speaker 1:  getting started. Right. So we'll see. But, and
Speaker 1:  by the way, this is like open source contributors choosing to work
Speaker 1:  nights and weekends to fix this thing. The internet is a wild place.
Speaker 1:  Like on the one hand CloudFare is like, we'll just stop it like
Speaker 1:  between you and everything is us. So we'll stop it. And on the other hand,
Speaker 1:  it's like, we're a loose collection of volunteers and we'll fix it.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. And like the dynamic between those parts of the internet is
Speaker 1:  I always think about it when things like this come up, it is underexplored
Speaker 1:  I think,
Speaker 4:  All right. We should do like two lightening round things. I don't know. I
Speaker 4:  mean, I made a bunch of lists of stuff here. I personally want to ask
Speaker 4:  why, when designing the cyber truck, Elon Musk didn't think of the fact
Speaker 4:  that it would need a windshield wiper. And so instead it has one that's like
Speaker 4:  eight feet long.
Speaker 1:  There's a video of the cyber track testing. Yeah. I will
Speaker 1:  say that it looks sick, right? Like it just it's a
Speaker 1:  triangle car. I can't, they actually went and built a
Speaker 1:  stainless steel triangle car. Like, yeah, it's cool.
Speaker 6:  It looks,
Speaker 4:  It's like, it's like tank wars, but in real life, it's great. The first one
Speaker 1:  That was too big, by the way. So they were always saying, we got to scale
Speaker 1:  this down. It's clear. They didn't think about what scaling
Speaker 1:  down would mean. And like complying with road laws
Speaker 1:  would mean. So even in the scale down version, it's got the
Speaker 1:  three lights across the front. That mean it's an extra wide 80 inch car,
Speaker 1:  like big pickup trucks have those lights. So it's got those. They didn't
Speaker 1:  think about where to Mount the actual headlights. So the headlights are like
Speaker 1:  at the bottom of the, you can't even call it a F it's the
Speaker 1:  front of the triangle. Like, I don't know what else you'd call the flat
Speaker 1:  front of the wedge of the car that lights are at the bottom.
Speaker 1:  It's got side mirrors that look ridiculous. And even Ilan on Twitter was
Speaker 1:  like, I am, we have to ship the side mirrors, but people can
Speaker 1:  do other things. And she needs to take off the side,
Speaker 1:  which is a horrible idea, but maybe we could replace on the cameras. And
Speaker 1:  then this wiper, which is just a huge ass wiper, the
Speaker 1:  size of the windshield. And I like, I know he
Speaker 1:  was responding someone else, but he was like, the wipers is what troubles
Speaker 1:  me the most about the whole triangle car. And it's like,
Speaker 1:  man, that is an incredible list of priorities. But like I made
Speaker 1:  a triangle car. Here's the problem, the wiper number one on the list. And
Speaker 1:  it's like, there are many other questions. Yeah. I've been saying this to
Speaker 1:  Andy and Sean, our transportation reporters for awhile. Like we are just
Speaker 1:  in this incredible vaporware moment with EVs. Yep. Everything is
Speaker 1:  vapor. And so the cyber truck was extremely vapor for awhile.
Speaker 1:  It's cool to see it running around on a track, but you see all of the
Speaker 1:  problems from the initial design to reality
Speaker 1:  expressed in this video, including the swiper and the wife. I mean, it just
Speaker 1:  looks slightly ridiculous.
Speaker 6:  It just feels like it's getting more and more to that Homer Simpson designed
Speaker 6:  car. No, like I'm just waiting for the 64 ounce cup
Speaker 6:  holder.
Speaker 1:  The Homer did not have a vision. This thing has a vision. And it's what if
Speaker 1:  the triangle was a car
Speaker 6:  Slightly
Speaker 1:  Better vision. I love it. Everyone should watch this video. That's great.
Speaker 1:  Okay.
Speaker 4:  Last thing in the lightning round, we touched on this, I believe before,
Speaker 4:  but the fight between the FCC and the
Speaker 4:  FAA over 5g at airports has gotten like
Speaker 4:  to the point where they're just like sniping at each other.
Speaker 1:  So this list, so a bunch of ex FCC wrote a letter
Speaker 1:  being like the FAA is dumb. Yeah. Here's the
Speaker 1:  list, Tom Wheeler Democrat mean unclimbed born
Speaker 1:  Democrat, Juliana, Caskey, Democrat, GTE pie,
Speaker 1:  Michael Powell. Like you've got like, it's just
Speaker 1:  nuts. Like these are people who do not agree with each other. Like literally
Speaker 1:  people who reversed each other as policies at the FCCS
Speaker 1:  immediately upon taking office. And they're all saying
Speaker 1:  the FAA is overstepping their authority. The FAA position threatened to derail.
Speaker 1:  The reason conclusions reached by the FTC FCC after years of technical
Speaker 1:  analysis and study nuts. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  The FAA saying that like 5g will destroy plane.
Speaker 4:  They're saying it'll make it harder for certain systems to automatically
Speaker 4:  land the plane under certain conditions.
Speaker 1:  Yes. There is an FAA study, sewing 5g interference with altimeters.
Speaker 1:  But the argument is that many other countries have already approved this
Speaker 1:  radio equipment in these bands, the spectrum bands. There's a
Speaker 1:  great quote from Harold Feld, from public knowledge, old friend of the verge.
Speaker 1:  And he's like either physics works differently. United States or the report
Speaker 1:  at the center of this controversy needs to explain why interference hasn't
Speaker 1:  shown up in any other country.
Speaker 6:  It's it does work different
Speaker 1:  Here, but you know, honestly, we'll turn the web here at the end of
Speaker 1:  2021. You could probably convince me that we'll be able to see birds. Aren't
Speaker 1:  real. Yeah. All right. This is a good one. Yeah. For
Speaker 1:  last of the year,
Speaker 4:  We haven't complained at all about the fact that Toyota is making remote
Speaker 4:  start from a key fob. Part of a subscription service. I think cellular radios
Speaker 4:  were a mistake.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Anytime you add a radio on a chip, someone is like, what if you pay
Speaker 1:  me some money every month? That's the future of all technology
Speaker 1:  soon to be the future of, you know, like what was the last
Speaker 1:  semester refrigerators like anything where there's like a
Speaker 1:  server on the other end that might do stuff. They're like, what if we, you
Speaker 1:  paid us to use the server? Yeah. It's going to happen.
Speaker 1:  That's my prediction for 2022, the rebellion against the
Speaker 1:  services revenue.
Speaker 4:  My prediction is no more software features for the whole year.
Speaker 1:  Oh, that'd be so great. Oh, that'd be so great. If your prediction was right
Speaker 1:  and mine is wrong. That's my hope for you. Anyway. It's
Speaker 1:  been a great year. Return 10 this year. Thank you all for participating.
Speaker 1:  We're going to take a couple weeks off. I hope you get some rest. Get to
Speaker 1:  hang out with your families. You can send us nice sweets at the end of the
Speaker 1:  day. If you want to. Dieter is at backlog. Alex is Alex H Crans
Speaker 1:  Lauren is at Lauren Rush. I'm at reckless. We'd love to hear from you. I
Speaker 1:  want to call it just a handful of stories right at the end here, Sean. O'Kane
Speaker 1:  congratulations, Sean. You just took a big new job at Bloomberg, but he has
Speaker 1:  his last big feature about an Evie startup. They're all vapor.
Speaker 1:  I'm telling you ed startup called  with Jay change with
Speaker 1:  Jay. It's really good. It's got everything. It's got, it starts with Iowasca
Speaker 1:  and it just like goes from there. We ran a great story
Speaker 1:  about singing's the board ape yacht club party. It's just really good. It's
Speaker 1:  just such an incredible story. You'd have to go read it. It reads like,
Speaker 1:  like old school, nineties tech writing. If you know I'm talking it's it's
Speaker 1:  just got a vibe to it. It's really fun. And then Jen, who you mentioned earlier,
Speaker 1:  wrote three gigantic pieces on matter, the new standard. She did verge house
Speaker 1:  with Dieter about it. It's great. It's really fun. Tony. Fidel's like all
Speaker 1:  over the big feature. Just excitedly talking about how he had the right idea
Speaker 1:  as thread was his idea. It's A-plus definitely was
Speaker 1:  reading. Okay. We've got a couple more decoders in the new year, but other
Speaker 1:  than that, the verge cast is off. So we'll see you in
Speaker 1:  2022. That's it. Rock roll. Happy new