# Transcript
ID: 2580e170-caa5-11eb-b081-55fb0d03b8dc
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: WWDC 2021: Apple's iOS 15, spatial audio, macOS Monterey, and more
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/1336462472/901612968/s93290-US-5243s-1623407471.mp3
Description: Nilay Patel, Dieter Bohn, Alex Cranz, and Chris Welch discuss all the announcements from Apple's Worldwide Developers Conference that took place this week.
Ad Filtering: Disabled
Speaker 1:  Coming up on the verge cast, Alex Kranz and Chris Welch. Join us to talk
Speaker 1:  about everything that happened at WWDC, including updates to iOS, iPad,
Speaker 1:  iOS, and spatial audio everywhere. That's the virtuous coming up.
Speaker ?:  Now, this episode of Vergecast brought to you by Cornell. If he wants to
Speaker ?:  advance your career without stepping out of your job, look no further than
Speaker ?:  today's sponsor E Cornell with over 120 online certificates
Speaker ?:  in today's most in demand skills, taking a program with eCornell is a great
Speaker ?:  way to better your professional self. So he wants to further your career
Speaker ?:  work on your professional expertise and preserve the strides you've already
Speaker ?:  made. Try I-Corps Nell visit E cornell.com and use code
Speaker ?:  Vergecast for 20% off certificate programs. When you enroll
Speaker ?:  more and more of these days, we are conducting our everyday business remotely.
Speaker ?:  And while there will always be a place for doing things the old way, the
Speaker ?:  convenience that comes with online, learning changes, everything it's even
Speaker ?:  changing. The way we learn with Equinox, you can gain skills in your field
Speaker ?:  without interrupting your career. Equinox offers over 120
Speaker ?:  online certificate programs to choose from. And they're flexible. So while
Speaker ?:  you're learning about data science, project management or web design, your
Speaker ?:  career doesn't get put on hold equals 100% online classes,
Speaker ?:  feature coursework that can be done anywhere. Anytime and most certificate
Speaker ?:  programs can be completed in two to four months. And while some other online
Speaker ?:  programs might lack that personal interaction and feedback from instructors,
Speaker ?:  Equinox, doesn't sacrifice it. Courses are developed by Cornell university
Speaker ?:  faculty and you'll enjoy meaningful conversations about coursework with instructors
Speaker ?:  who have a wealth of knowledge in their field. Plus you get worthwhile discussion
Speaker ?:  with peers, from industry, from all over the world. Take the next step
Speaker ?:  with a professional certificate from Cornell university. There's the ecornell.com
Speaker ?:  today and use code of Vergecast for 20% off certificate programs.
Speaker ?:  When you enroll this episode is brought to you by NerdWallet, got money
Speaker ?:  goals. NerdWallet's got your back looking for a credit card with better cash
Speaker ?:  back. NerdWallet's got tons of tools and tips to help you find the card you're
Speaker ?:  looking for. Finally, ready to buy your first home. NerdWallet has calculators
Speaker ?:  to help you find a mortgage that works for you. And if you want your money
Speaker ?:  to work as hard as you do, NerdWallet's got side-by-side comparisons to help
Speaker ?:  you find the smartest investing account, whatever your money goals may be.
Speaker ?:  NerdWallet helps you compare and find the smartest financial products for
Speaker ?:  you.
Speaker 1:  The flagship podcast platform
Speaker 1:  arbitration. That's what I knew. This is a really
Speaker 1:  technical administrative law podcast. I hope you enjoy it anyway. I'm Neil.
Speaker 1:  I'm your friend date around us here. I
Speaker 2:  Am your bento box architect.
Speaker 1:  Who very good. Well, explain that reference in a bit. Alex cranes is here
Speaker 1:  again. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  I am also here and I'm more a fan of a Lunchable. So I don't
Speaker 3:  know.
Speaker 1:  Amazing that America took a hard look at the bento box and it's like
Speaker 1:  Lunchables.
Speaker 3:  We got it. Crackers and cheese go. Crystal else is
Speaker 3:  here. Good to be back as always.
Speaker 1:  There's a lot going on in this episode. There's WWDC. I feel like
Speaker 1:  Chris and I could just do an, a full hour on spacial audio. Cause that got
Speaker 1:  rolled out this week. We could do a full hour of Dieter, just sighing
Speaker 1:  about the multitasking situation and the iPad. So
Speaker 1:  mad it's this one's going to be a ride,
Speaker 1:  but I want to start where we always start. COVID it's not over. It feels
Speaker 1:  over. I will tell you this, where I live here in upstate New York,
Speaker 1:  no one gives a shit anymore. Like that's just where we're at. There's no
Speaker 1:  mass like everyone's inside. It's great. I had dinner inside the other day.
Speaker 1:  It was amazing, but it's still happening. It's still raging around the world.
Speaker 1:  The United States is it's not the only place in the world as much as
Speaker 1:  Americans like to feel that way. And even inside the United States, things
Speaker 1:  are all over the place. So we have a bunch of stories this week. COVID-19
Speaker 1:  hospitalization rates actually went up for adolescents in March and April,
Speaker 1:  which is not a great sign. So please keep those vaccinations up. By
Speaker 1:  the way, I want to call this out because it just makes me laugh so
Speaker 1:  hard. The byte administration set a vaccination target
Speaker 1:  goal for July 4th, we met, we might not hit it. It's like a
Speaker 1:  real thing. Bud light announced this week that they would buy everyone in
Speaker 1:  America beer. If we hit the,
Speaker 4:  Which is like the most American,
Speaker 5:  Just that last push we really needed to get.
Speaker 1:  It's like world. It's like, I've
Speaker 1:  been on the fence, but can't turn on free beer
Speaker 3:  Free bud light. Like not even a good beer.
Speaker 1:  I applaud them. It just made me laugh so hard. Anyhow, it's
Speaker 1:  still happening, please. If you're not vaccinated, we have a lot of
Speaker 1:  information on the site. There's a lot of other sites, please get it done.
Speaker 1:  I want this to be over badly. Speaking of reasons, people are
Speaker 1:  hesitant to get vaccinated. We have a deep dive into where the COVID
Speaker 1:  vaccine and microchip conspiracy came from and it
Speaker 1:  is just a ride. It started with a Reddit post spun
Speaker 1:  out of control. It got picked up and mutated. It is one of
Speaker 1:  those very verge stories about just a little piece
Speaker 1:  of information spiraling into a big thing. It
Speaker 1:  is it's really, it's really great. You should just read it. It's on the site
Speaker 1:  now. And lastly, if you're ever a chest listener, you know, we cover the
Speaker 1:  digital divide a lot, which is everything from the broadband gap to the devices.
Speaker 1:  People use to who gets the message to the
Speaker 1:  pandemic, lots and lots of second order effects as we've discussed. One of
Speaker 1:  them is e-waste might be going down. The other one is the digital
Speaker 1:  divide, my beginning wider. So one of those things to re it's just,
Speaker 1:  I think there's a lot of policy initiatives happening in the world that we
Speaker 1:  always talk about, but broad brand and infrastructure spending the digital
Speaker 1:  divide is one that cuts across both parties. It is staggeringly
Speaker 1:  bi-partisan people thinking about how to get broadband places, how to get
Speaker 1:  students everywhere, better devices, go check it out because I think
Speaker 1:  there's gonna be a lot of action about this stuff in the, in the years to
Speaker 1:  come. Okay. But speaking of the far end of the digital divide, apple
Speaker 1:  Inc, they're the fancy ones. That's
Speaker 1:  how I think of that. I mean, WTC, we talked about it a lot last
Speaker 1:  week, Alex, in her first episode with us, we just like went for an hour and
Speaker 1:  40. It was great deep dives and that old notification
Speaker 1:  systems we did, but then it happened. I'm just going to say it
Speaker 1:  directly. Wow. Was that
Speaker 1:  underwhelming? I mean, like, I
Speaker 1:  think this is a lot of people had this response to it. First of
Speaker 1:  all, we were all hoping for a new MacBook pro it didn't arrive. Shawn
Speaker 1:  Hollister did a great post. I think he just needed to get it out
Speaker 1:  of, get it out of his brain. Look emotionally processed the lack of a MacBook
Speaker 1:  pro, but apple tagged its YouTube stream with
Speaker 1:  M one X mix. Like people like
Speaker 1:  over-thought it to the point where like, oh, they, they they've
Speaker 1:  kind of acknowledged it. And I, I don't know about that. I like, I
Speaker 1:  understand why Sean did the story. Like sometimes you just
Speaker 1:  have to be like, I had all these feelings and I need to write them down so
Speaker 1:  that, but that's, it happened. There was no hardware of any kind really.
Speaker 1:  And then, you know, we went through what they could do to the various platforms.
Speaker 1:  We'll talk about what they announce. Everything is very iterative, except
Speaker 1:  for some of the privacy stuff they've added, which is kind of a big step
Speaker 1:  forward, but also very complicated and how it works. So I just like, I don't
Speaker 1:  know, Dieter what'd you think?
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I think iterative is fair. The thing that struck me is it was really,
Speaker 2:  really hard to suss out when they were announcing features, where
Speaker 2:  they would go and what platform they were for the, like, it was like every
Speaker 2:  single feature is kind of for everything. The privacy stuff kind of
Speaker 2:  works everywhere. The health stuff has kind of between the
Speaker 2:  iPhone and the watch. The, just all, all of the features are
Speaker 2:  kind of fuzzy between platforms, which to me is a real metaphor
Speaker 2:  for how all of the apps now are fuzzy between
Speaker 2:  platforms. There are Mac apps and iPad apps and iPhone
Speaker 2:  apps, and they're all different, but they're increasingly the same, but
Speaker 2:  not. And that's how I felt like most of these announcements with,
Speaker 1:  Yeah, it's kind of a function of all the apps are really just front ends
Speaker 1:  for services now. Yeah. A lot of services, but it's like in the background
Speaker 1:  of everything. So like if you announce an update to the iPhone health app
Speaker 1:  where you are really announcing as an update to health, a service provided
Speaker 1:  from apple that is exposed across all of your devices. Right. And the other
Speaker 1:  thing I'll say is I think apple just, they've gotten very good at making
Speaker 1:  these hour and a half long infomercials that take the
Speaker 1:  place of their events, but here they didn't, they didn't follow like the
Speaker 1:  rules of great public speaking. They didn't tell you what they were going
Speaker 1:  to tell you and then tell you, and then tell you again, it was just like,
Speaker 1:  you were just off to the races. You had no idea what would happen next, which
Speaker 1:  I think for a developer event, I think that feedback, we talked about the
Speaker 1:  context of this event and the unhappiness and the developer community a
Speaker 1:  lot. They didn't feel the pressure to like address the elephant in the
Speaker 1:  room. They waited quite a long time before they got to any developer
Speaker 1:  stuff. And I, I just think it was an odd event.
Speaker 1:  Hopefully it's the last infomercial event that we have.
Speaker 1:  Like I would really like to start going back to live events and like seeing
Speaker 1:  people. And there's something really important that you get from these
Speaker 1:  events in person. But I think here it was just a flood of
Speaker 1:  stuff and Dieter you're very good at, at calling out. Apple's great at writing
Speaker 1:  narratives about itself. And I didn't catch narrative. There was very little
Speaker 2:  Narrative at all. Like the story coming out of this thing
Speaker 2:  is they announced a bunch of stuff.
Speaker 4:  And like there
Speaker 2:  Were, there were so many missed opportunities. Like they could have just
Speaker 2:  done an entire narrative that they've done it before, around
Speaker 2:  like privacy and AI. Right. There's a bunch of new Siri
Speaker 2:  updates that are actually really interesting. It's a little bit of catch
Speaker 2:  up to Google assistant, honestly, because, so it can do like reading texts,
Speaker 2:  which has sort of like Google lens. It can do on-device Siri stuff, which
Speaker 2:  is actually a huge deal because that's been forever that you haven't been
Speaker 2:  able to just use Siri when you are offline and it's way faster. And they
Speaker 2:  could have just connected that to privacy. And they can just like
Speaker 2:  run through, run that thread through almost half or more of the
Speaker 2:  things they announced. And people would have been able to like understand
Speaker 2:  where things were going. But instead it was just a bunch of
Speaker 2:  sort of disparate things. I don't know. I'm excited by
Speaker 2:  about a bunch of the stuff that got announced and I'm really excited to
Speaker 2:  try a bunch of the stuff that got announced, but I don't see a
Speaker 2:  vision for what Apple's stuff is for the next year here. I
Speaker 3:  Kind of do actually I think, I think it was everything they
Speaker 3:  weren't saying. I think it, I think like just the very structure of this
Speaker 3:  WWDC, like it was so weird and
Speaker 3:  all over the place. And I think this is part of them trying to like part
Speaker 3:  of apple, trying to do this, this, you know, it's moving from this company
Speaker 3:  that sells software, this company that sells services. And we were, this
Speaker 3:  was the transition dub dub for that, like where we were really seeing that,
Speaker 3:  like we shouldn't have had an iOS and a Macko S and an
Speaker 3:  iPad iOS. It should have been Siri home,
Speaker 3:  TV, health. Yeah. I think it's just the growing
Speaker 3:  pains of this transition we're seeing from apple.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Let's talk about, let's talk about iOS. They did announce a bunch of new
Speaker 1:  features. Some of like Steve was saying, some of them are just features
Speaker 1:  for everything, but you know, they're like very
Speaker 1:  specific they're extending digital identity
Speaker 1:  cards, ease to be able to put credit cards in your wallet, put your driver's
Speaker 1:  license and apple
Speaker 3:  Wallet. I don't want to do that. I
Speaker 1:  Am not going to do that. But like, they're extending the
Speaker 1:  capabilities in the places you might use your phone, the
Speaker 1:  on-device series stuff. Right. That was a really good Siri demo of just
Speaker 1:  like it working really fast in a way that Siri doesn't work really fast.
Speaker 1:  Right.
Speaker 4:  I don't know.
Speaker 1:  What's what's that to you, Alex? I liked
Speaker 3:  All of the stuff I got to say. I downloaded the, the I've got my
Speaker 3:  developer account that, that I pay for, even though I have not even
Speaker 3:  attempted to develop an app in like 10 years and I
Speaker 3:  downloaded it. I've been playing with it. And, and so far it's
Speaker 3:  all the tiny things. There's no, like I didn't download it and just go, wow.
Speaker 3:  Yes, I'm here. This is the future. I need to go actually put this on
Speaker 3:  my regular daily driver phone. It was just like, okay.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I've, I've, I've got iOS now. And it's slightly
Speaker 3:  taped in lots of little tiny ways. Like, I love that they've improved
Speaker 3:  the print dialogue. I love that we've gone from, you could never print on
Speaker 3:  an iPhone. You enter the print dialogue. You can
Speaker 3:  like the print dialogue has improved.
Speaker 3:  Like that. Wasn't one of my first things. That was one of those
Speaker 3:  things where I saw it online and I was like, Ooh, I'm going to go check that
Speaker 3:  out. Yeah. They also
Speaker 2:  Fixed the fix. They, so with
Speaker 2:  iOS 14, they broke the time thing where you like enter a time, the time
Speaker 2:  picker, where it like loses focus and you can't tab between them. And I like
Speaker 2:  tap on this tiny little box and like enter in a number and sometimes it just
Speaker 2:  gets lost. And so they, they didn't, they kept that. But then they brought
Speaker 2:  back the giant dials. So like now it's both of those
Speaker 2:  things. So like, I'm glad, I'm glad they brought back the dials. Cause that's
Speaker 2:  easier to use, but there's just a bunch of like, oh, we tried some
Speaker 2:  stuff in an hour. We're just going to keep trying some stuff. Like it
Speaker 2:  was very, very Android in that way. There's a bunch of
Speaker 2:  UI stuff that like, really, you just you're going to go that way. Okay.
Speaker 2:  It
Speaker 3:  Feels cleaner. It does feel like slightly
Speaker 3:  cleaner. Like when it booted up, I was like, no iOS, heck yeah. Look
Speaker 3:  at this. It's like the bubbles have a little bit more shape to them
Speaker 3:  and they're losing a little like the shadow and
Speaker 3:  okay. We're transitioning in our, in our, in our design language. But
Speaker 3:  like, it was very, is so, so tiny the
Speaker 3:  changes. Okay. But
Speaker 1:  Some of the features are like huge underneath this like little,
Speaker 1:  yeah.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. There's a lot of like stuff lurking under the surface. Like I don't
Speaker 3:  know, ex the, the SIF data data thing is, is one that I was
Speaker 3:  like, oh, that's awesome. Like that's a very
Speaker 3:  under talked about things,
Speaker 1:  Such a apple move, right? Like for years,
Speaker 1:  people have been like, I'd like to see all of the info about my photos and
Speaker 1:  the photos app and apples. And like, no. And then there's
Speaker 1:  like an, our, like there's an entire economy of
Speaker 1:  apps to do this very simple thing. And
Speaker 1:  now they've added it. And everyone's like, amazing. And it's like, no, dude,
Speaker 1:  they, you just got some water. You were just so thirsty and they
Speaker 1:  just gave you some water. I was absolutely
Speaker 3:  Parched. And now I can delete all of these apps. I never use to
Speaker 3:  begin with that. Like I had on my phone just to like, be like,
Speaker 3:  that'll show apple. I do want this.
Speaker 1:  That's one of the highlight. Some of the highlight features, I think we should,
Speaker 1:  we should start with FaceTime. And that in a context of everything is the
Speaker 1:  same across all of its platforms. And there's, they're just kind of exposing
Speaker 1:  services. FaceTime took a gigantic step
Speaker 1:  into being a competitor, to zoom in many
Speaker 1:  ways and into a cross-platform
Speaker 1:  service in the sense that Android and windows, people can
Speaker 1:  now participate in FaceTime calls. They can not start them.
Speaker 1:  They cannot write one, but they can join one, which is very
Speaker 1:  strange. I think I said this in the live, well, apple runs on WebEx and they
Speaker 1:  like have, if listeners have used, WebEx is for
Speaker 1:  software. There's a part of me that says that Tim cook was like, I can't
Speaker 1:  use this anymore. Like we got to do something in on the
Speaker 1:  FaceTime team was like, oh, crappy means
Speaker 1:  us just started like developing
Speaker 1:  FaceTime. But so FaceTime, they've added some of the basics that you would
Speaker 1:  expect. They went away from there. Their weird bubbles view. There's just
Speaker 1:  a straight up grid view in FaceTime. They needed to do that a long time ago.
Speaker 3:  Well, no, it's an option now. Yeah. Yeah. Because, because there's, there's
Speaker 3:  the bubbles and the bubbles will now have spatial audio and you'll be able
Speaker 3:  to be like, oh, he's over there. Oh, she's over there. And, or you can
Speaker 3:  just do a grid and I guess they'll all just hit you in the face with their
Speaker 3:  voices. I'm not sure how that part's worked. I have not done the FaceTime
Speaker 3:  yet.
Speaker 1:  Well, it's interesting on the microphone side, if they're going to be able
Speaker 1:  to capture that kind of depth right.
Speaker 1:  From the people in the room with you. So we'll see, like, there's a lot of
Speaker 1:  questions about how spatial audio work with FaceTime, but they have built
Speaker 1:  it out into a more full featured zoom competitor. I think fairly their
Speaker 1:  assumption is, and this is true in my family. I'm not
Speaker 1:  sending zoom links when I want the grandparents to see my kid, right?
Speaker 1:  Like we're just like FaceTiming them. And if you can make that better than
Speaker 1:  you're going to eliminate an entire consumer use case for zoom that people
Speaker 1:  have started doing in the pandemic. Great. Then there's
Speaker 1:  this send a link and it'll work on the web, which Peter, I know you
Speaker 1:  have just a litany of thoughts about,
Speaker 2:  Well, I mean, it's, so what you can't FaceTime call somebody on Android or
Speaker 2:  windows or whatever you can, you can create the link. And then that link
Speaker 2:  allows other people to join. And I believe there's like
Speaker 2:  some moderation stuff built into that. I mean, there would need to be, yeah.
Speaker 1:  There's like the, it's like the waiting room. Like you can join the link
Speaker 1:  and whoever owns the call can invite, let you in or not.
Speaker 2:  You have to get approved to get in. And then they, I think they can boot
Speaker 2:  you. And you know, I'm sure it's just using web RTC,
Speaker 2:  which is how pretty much every video conference on the web works these
Speaker 2:  days, which is great. You know, we've been dunking on Steve
Speaker 2:  jobs said FaceTime would be an open protocol for what a
Speaker 2:  decade.
Speaker 4:  And
Speaker 2:  You know, it would, it would be nice if this were, I dunno, I
Speaker 2:  feel like FaceTime links and having
Speaker 2:  Android and windows users join them is going to be the video equivalent of
Speaker 2:  green bubbles. Right. You can't call them, you got to like hit an extra button
Speaker 2:  to bring up the link. And then you got to figure out how to text the link
Speaker 2:  and it's going to take them over green bubbles and blah, blah, blah, blah,
Speaker 2:  blah, blah, blah. It is going to be another sort of
Speaker 2:  subtle incentive for people to be like, oh, can you just get on an iPhone?
Speaker 2:  This'll be easier. That's like, I feel like it's great that they're opening
Speaker 2:  up to other platforms, but I feel like they did it in the way that would
Speaker 2:  be most likely to get people back onto their platform.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. There's a part of it. That's fair. Right? Set windows
Speaker 1:  aside like apple making a full on FaceTime windows app. Okay.
Speaker 1:  That's like a, that's a high bar. They're not going
Speaker 1:  to apple making a FaceTime Android
Speaker 1:  app bank sense. I think it seems like an eminently reasonable thing. They
Speaker 1:  obviously make apple music for Android. If you make a FaceTime
Speaker 1:  app, then you might as well just put a message on it. Like you're so
Speaker 1:  close to having that message an Android and you can't do
Speaker 1:  it. That's the end of that conversation
Speaker 1:  because just a standalone app that only does video calling to
Speaker 1:  iPhones. It's nuts.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. So I think there's a reason they went with a
Speaker 1:  web ID. We don't know how it works yet on the web. I
Speaker 1:  think there's a lot of question marks around like what set of web technologies
Speaker 1:  is apple using to make this work? Because if it is the standards that we
Speaker 1:  kind of suspect they might be using that opens the door to a lot of
Speaker 1:  other things happening. Yeah. But I will say that Dieter's, Dieter's
Speaker 1:  making a face at
Speaker 2:  Me. I think, I don't know what it's going to open the door to honestly, like
Speaker 2:  they're going to use like the standard that everyone's using, their he's
Speaker 2:  whatever RTC there'll be some moderation stuff. Hopefully they've thought
Speaker 2:  through that. Yeah. I actually am like, I'm less enthused and think this
Speaker 2:  is less big deal than I think everybody else.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. It's like, again, it's, you're so thirsty. It's like apple did something
Speaker 1:  cross-platform and you're like, oh, the world will reorder it. And it's like,
Speaker 1:  nah, we'll see. We'll see how it goes. I don't
Speaker 2:  Think that Android and windows users get to participate in share play. Alex,
Speaker 2:  can you talk like, what's your perspective on this, this
Speaker 2:  feature,
Speaker 3:  The share play the way that you can now watch movies with your, your
Speaker 3:  friends. I mean, like, I think it's, I think it's a really
Speaker 3:  interesting idea. And I also think it's mainly so apple, like it's for apple.
Speaker 3:  I think it's less for the services because the services have all had this.
Speaker 3:  They've all been able to do it. And now it's like, Apple's the first, you
Speaker 3:  know, big phone operating system maker
Speaker 3:  too, to kind of glom onto this and make an actual API that everybody could
Speaker 3:  use. And, and Google and, and windows are probably both like Microsoft, both
Speaker 3:  kicking themselves that they didn't think of this first. And so I think
Speaker 3:  it's, I think it's really smart. And I'll be curious to see who
Speaker 3:  actually uses it because I've done the whole
Speaker 3:  watching movies with a friend over the phone. Like you both have your phones
Speaker 3:  and you started at the same time or whatever. And it's awful. It's just a
Speaker 3:  really boring way. Like it is not the it's like a zoom call. It is
Speaker 3:  not the same as being in the same room as somebody and like watching it on
Speaker 3:  the couch together, put back in you
Speaker 1:  Is the mayor of east hand finale happened the other
Speaker 1:  day. My wife wanted to watch it with her mom and I fell down
Speaker 1:  just an insane rabbit hole of making a new
Speaker 1:  HBO max account on my wife's 18 T phone
Speaker 1:  number, not ours. Cause we didn't want to like, cause we both get it for
Speaker 1:  free with our plans. So we're not technically cheating.
Speaker 1:  And like, I don't know if you've ever tried to walk your mother-in-law
Speaker 1:  through. I need you to log in first I needed Becky to change
Speaker 1:  her 18 T password so she could share it with her mom. Oh my God. And
Speaker 1:  then her mom could log into her 18 T account and HBO max, like if I
Speaker 1:  could just like, I need you to push this button. Yeah. Watch this
Speaker 1:  show together. That would have been much better.
Speaker 3:  And my mom's had an apple TV for three years now and I think she's turned
Speaker 3:  it on twice. So I've not really, really pumped for her
Speaker 3:  to, to, to fully embrace it. But I think it's, I think it is super, super
Speaker 3:  easy. I think we're going to see more like younger people using it than us
Speaker 3:  old. I could be wrong about that, but I think it's
Speaker 3:  just brilliant of them to do it.
Speaker 1:  We have a list of partner to save announce at launch Disney plus Hulu HBO
Speaker 1:  max makes sense. Twitch super interesting
Speaker 1:  because everyone's already watching Twitch. It's like, it's strange to think
Speaker 1:  about watching more Twitch more together than you are already watching Twitch
Speaker 1:  together. Take talk, which is a deeply
Speaker 1:  fascinating psychological experiment into other people's Tik TOK
Speaker 1:  algo. I'm not sure I want to open that door. I don't want to open it
Speaker 1:  close master class, which just
Speaker 1:  like, you're very hopeful, very
Speaker 1:  hopeful idea that I'm going to sit down and watch like Robert DeNiro
Speaker 1:  teach us the act together, NBA and ESPN plus that makes sense. Paramount
Speaker 1:  plus make sense players. He didn't make sense. Chris was not on the list,
Speaker 1:  man.
Speaker 5:  The streaming company that now thinks it's too big to deal with any of these
Speaker 5:  features from other companies that will be Netflix.
Speaker 1:  I mean just like a fascinating emission, right? Like they, as I was saying,
Speaker 1:  they do have, Netflix has its own version of doing this it's cross platform.
Speaker 1:  It works everywhere. If you're that big, you just don't need to use the system
Speaker 1:  feature. And so we're just gonna like, see how that works. We do
Speaker 1:  have some information on like how Champlain operates. So the demo that
Speaker 1:  they gave to developers was not a streaming video app. It was a whiteboard
Speaker 1:  app. Oh really? Yeah. Yeah. So there's an element of
Speaker 1:  this where, you know, for the video apps, what they're really doing is they're
Speaker 1:  just sinking video players. So if I try to
Speaker 1:  share, let's assume HBO max is
Speaker 1:  operating. It's a 50, 50 proposition most days, but
Speaker 1:  yeah, we're going to watch HBO max together. I hit share play it.
Speaker 1:  Doesn't I'm not like rebroadcasting the stream to you over
Speaker 1:  FaceTime. Right? It's just sending a deep link into the HBO
Speaker 1:  max app. That app opens on your phone. You have to be
Speaker 1:  authenticated to it. And then the video players are sinked
Speaker 1:  up. So there's like, there's something very simple underneath all of this
Speaker 1:  that enables you to do a whole bunch of other stuff with apps, which I think
Speaker 1:  is super interesting. But that means everybody has to
Speaker 1:  have a Hulu account or whatever. And it's kind of unclear. Like you can have
Speaker 1:  all these different tiers of these various things. Like what if Chris
Speaker 1:  has Pula without ads? And I have Hulu with ads
Speaker 1:  Chris after just like, stop, watch some horrible
Speaker 3:  Chris, it's just like potty break every 10
Speaker 3:  minutes.
Speaker 1:  I'm like, oh no, I'm watching the same commercial again. Chris, would you
Speaker 1:  like me to tell you that? So I
Speaker 1:  think there's like some stuff in here that is like fascinating to
Speaker 1:  see how it plays out and have the services implement it because the API
Speaker 1:  itself is kind of very simple, but it is very cool. I think a lot of people
Speaker 1:  are gonna try to use it. I think one of the big questions I have is how discoverable
Speaker 1:  is this UI? Like there's a lot of floating iOS
Speaker 1:  boxes that just like show up on your screen. You've got to move them around.
Speaker 1:  You can like swipe to pull them down. We'll see. I might, I'm excited to
Speaker 1:  use it just because I did have this HBO max experience the other day. And
Speaker 1:  I was like, oh man, if only I could have just pushed this button for that,
Speaker 1:  I left the room. I was like, I'm, I've done my part. You're both watching
Speaker 1:  the show.
Speaker 3:  One of you is five seconds ahead. Deal with it. I
Speaker 3:  believe
Speaker 1:  I've gotten as close as I can get. Oh, that's super cool. I
Speaker 1:  just we'll see how it, how it plays out. Chris, anything stand
Speaker 1:  out.
Speaker 5:  I think the map stuff seems pretty cool. It seems like they are really, really
Speaker 5:  focused on making maps really, really good. I mean they did a lot of like
Speaker 5:  visual stuff. It looks really pretty. They're like overpasses and stuff and
Speaker 5:  maps. They stole that feature from a Google where you point your phone at
Speaker 5:  like a building to see which way you're facing. And so that's great. And
Speaker 5:  just seems like there's sort of like  kind of stuff in there so
Speaker 5:  you can see where that's kind of starting to come together. But yeah, I think
Speaker 5:  that they've got a pretty huge focus on that this year too.
Speaker 1:  The power of apple is that I've forgotten. Google has that feature.
Speaker 1:  So like the next day I was like in New York city and I came up out of
Speaker 1:  the subway and I was like work super well. And I was like, I'm gonna use
Speaker 1:  this Google feature. I forgot about
Speaker 5:  Why my phone compass can tell which way I'm pacing in the year 2021.
Speaker 5:  But sometimes it still happens.
Speaker 3:  So there's a little circle over and over and over again. And you just
Speaker 3:  like, you go with it. If you walk four blocks the wrong way, it's just a
Speaker 3:  little exercise.
Speaker 1:  What do you think of the new look in maps? It's they, you know,
Speaker 1:  Google kind of tends towards realism or very
Speaker 1:  sparse like outlines of buildings. Like
Speaker 1:  Google is either like full on street view or it's like, here's some lightly
Speaker 1:  rendered buildings to give you a suggestion. Apple's like, it's a
Speaker 1:  cartoon.
Speaker 5:  You can zoom in and like, see inside the apple store, as you assume it, you
Speaker 5:  mean close enough.
Speaker 1:  I think people really responded to it. How do you feel about it?
Speaker 5:  I like it personally quite a bit, just because like you're saying Google
Speaker 5:  is kind of like basic and plain and it's like very efficient, but like Apple's
Speaker 5:  clearly going for some more visual flash and flourishes. And as long
Speaker 5:  as like the data is there and that part's gotten a lot better too, over the
Speaker 5:  last few years, I think it's going to be pretty nice. And especially the
Speaker 5:  turn by turn directions, look a lot better now from what I saw. So
Speaker 1:  Dieter, you called this out in the lifeline, right? They said, okay, here's
Speaker 1:  the new turn by turn. They're very cool. They're like swoopy
Speaker 1:  overhead. They show you the roads, do all this zooming. And they're like,
Speaker 1:  we'll be on CarPlay in the next few months. Yeah. And I, that, I don't
Speaker 1:  understand it all because CarPlay fundamentally is just a second monitor
Speaker 1:  for your phone. Well, there's not like a lot happening. Well, there's
Speaker 2:  A lot happening graphically with some of these animations and some car
Speaker 2:  plates rendered on your phone, right. Maybe
Speaker 5:  It's too visually intensive now, like for a phone screen.
Speaker 2:  Right. But if you've got CarPlay wireless, maybe there,
Speaker 2:  you know, they did this stuff, knowing that how to do it on a phone with
Speaker 2:  direct pipe, but they haven't thought through how are they going to do it
Speaker 2:  to make sure it works on a bunch of different car displays. I think
Speaker 2:  that for all of Apple's strengths, one of its weaknesses is that it is,
Speaker 2:  does, does, does not have the muscle of working with a huge open ecosystem
Speaker 2:  of manufacturers. And so it might just take them a minute to
Speaker 2:  get this for carpet.
Speaker 1:  I feel like sometimes I know how CarPlay works. And
Speaker 1:  then in moments like this, it's like, oh, I have no idea.
Speaker 1:  My impression of CarPlay is that it's just sending, it's just a
Speaker 1:  monitor. It's just sending a 60 frames per second video screen to your card
Speaker 1:  display. That's essentially all that processing is happening on your phone.
Speaker 1:  And you're just saying the sizes and shapes of other displays in the world
Speaker 1:  have confounded apple, which seems ridiculous.
Speaker 2:  I mean, remember like the iPhone was made you hard code to
Speaker 2:  pixel dimensions for like almost a decade before they're like, oh wait, we
Speaker 2:  might want to do different screen sizes. We should think about this a little
Speaker 2:  bit more. Yeah. So, okay. I'm going to, I want to change subjects.
Speaker 2:  Can we talk about focus modes for like three hours, maybe
Speaker 2:  four, because that's how many emotions I have about it. Create a
Speaker 2:  focus
Speaker 4:  Now to talk about focus modes.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I'm going to hit the button. All notifications of pause. Oh dear.
Speaker 2:  Okay. So they've created profiles the way that you had profiles on
Speaker 2:  your Nokia phone in 1997, you can now do them
Speaker 2:  on your iPhone. So you basically can choose like
Speaker 2:  do not disturb or sleep or driving or
Speaker 2:  personal or work, or you can make your own like fitness exercise,
Speaker 2:  whatever podcasting, podcasting. Yeah. When you turn on one of these
Speaker 2:  modes, it changes all your notification settings. You can have custom settings
Speaker 2:  for who and who is not allowed to contact you. You can have custom notification
Speaker 2:  settings for which apps are and are not allowed to show up here.
Speaker 2:  You can have custom home screens that appear disappear depending on what
Speaker 2:  focus mode that you're in.
Speaker 1:  By the way, I just want to cry to you. Apple's official terminology
Speaker 1:  is that you're in a focus. No. Which is right next
Speaker 1:  to like do a blog in terms of just like, I
Speaker 1:  know what you're saying, but I need you to not say it anymore. Oh God sponsored.
Speaker 1:  But yes, go ahead. When you're in a focus when you're in a
Speaker 4:  Focus, oh my God.
Speaker 1:  That's what they keep saying. It was this just kind of saying it. I was
Speaker 1:  like, I want to ask you about it, but I really don't want to know the
Speaker 1:  answer. So you
Speaker 2:  Can already like show and hide different home. So different photo
Speaker 2:  PSI focuses can show and hide different home screens. And
Speaker 2:  that means by the way, that you can have more than one app app icon on your
Speaker 2:  different home screen. So you can have Twitter in like four different places
Speaker 2:  and they can appear and disappear. So the number of calls that I'm gonna
Speaker 2:  have to deal with my relatives who aren't super tech savvy with, like
Speaker 2:  where'd my icons go, is going to be off the charts. Now I will say
Speaker 2:  that there is, there is one thing I want to give apple credit for. With
Speaker 2:  focus. Focus modes is all a bunch of these were already there in
Speaker 2:  iOS 14, we already had drive mode, do not disturb mode and
Speaker 2:  sleep. What they've done is they've actually just put a proper UI
Speaker 2:  on it. And they subsumed all of those modes that were sort of weird before
Speaker 2:  into this feature. So there's something smart about that,
Speaker 2:  but I'd be very curious to see if anybody actually uses this. If anybody
Speaker 2:  can actually figure out how to configure it. And if Apple's AI, which is
Speaker 2:  going to automatically, pre-configure the different focus modes. When you
Speaker 2:  turn them on, we'll actually do what you want it to do. So many
Speaker 2:  feelings.
Speaker 1:  I feel like these are all connected to, I don't even, it's just like, all
Speaker 1:  of this is also connected to how they're handling notifications. Yeah. Which
Speaker 1:  seems extremely complicated. And this is all
Speaker 1:  stuff that works really well. When I reviewed the home pod
Speaker 1:  I had in the back of my mind, like the apple man,
Speaker 1:  right? Like dress in all black wire-frame glasses
Speaker 1:  that has a design job. Yeah. You know, lives
Speaker 1:  alone only uses apple services and is very
Speaker 1:  demanding. And there is not a one straight icon on their
Speaker 1:  desktop. Yeah. And it's like, they made the home pod for that
Speaker 1:  person. That market was small and they discontinued the whole
Speaker 1:  pot. Right. Then there's like me and like the
Speaker 1:  icons everywhere, just screenshots for, from five years ago or so littering
Speaker 1:  my screen. Yeah. And I'm not, I'm never going to sit here and
Speaker 1:  like beat my way through all the settings sort of focus Smiths. But
Speaker 1:  yeah. AI is supposed to like somehow bridge that gap. Right. And I
Speaker 1:  that's like the, the big question mark is whether you can
Speaker 1:  deduce from my chaotic phone usage, some
Speaker 1:  set of order in rules about how I might
Speaker 1:  use my phone at any moment in the answers like, oh, just
Speaker 1:  take Instagram off that thing and just, just get rid of
Speaker 1:  that. And I will be more productive at work.
Speaker 2:  So we should talk about the ecosystem for half a second too, because focus
Speaker 2:  modes can automatically sync across all your apple devices, Mac
Speaker 2:  watch, phone, iPad, whatever. And if you so choose,
Speaker 2:  you can make your focus modes available to other iPhone Mac
Speaker 2:  iOS, apple users. So they can see your focus mode. They can see that you're
Speaker 2:  on a, do not disturb or whatever. And the time
Speaker 2:  from this is a cool feature. That's sort of like an away message. I don't
Speaker 2:  know, but it's not quite the thing, but maybe I'll use it to
Speaker 2:  teenagers harassing each other by setting focus modes, explicitly designed
Speaker 2:  to tease their friends or enemies is going to be so short.
Speaker 2:  That's. I mean, I mean, I'm doing it tonight
Speaker 1:  On the scale of I've enabled malicious teens. I
Speaker 1:  yeah. Focus mode billing is okay. Yeah. Okay. Can't
Speaker 1:  hurt people too badly. They got to learn it somewhere. One of the things
Speaker 1:  that's really interesting about needing to be an ecosystem in several of
Speaker 1:  the focus modes, they're like, we'll let notifications from certain people
Speaker 1:  through, right. Which is like conceptually
Speaker 1:  great. There are many situations in which you'd like, I just want my
Speaker 1:  family to get to me, but I need to focus otherwise unclear
Speaker 1:  how they're detecting, who is who inside of apps. So if I want,
Speaker 1:  if, if I want to turn everything off, but Dieter can slack me. I have no
Speaker 1:  idea if that's possible, because I don't think slack is exposing
Speaker 1:  who messages are from to the notification system. It's
Speaker 1:  just sending notifications. There's like another layer of data that has to
Speaker 1:  happen here. And then another layer of app vendors, not just lying
Speaker 1:  because they will like the New York times where like Dieter needs you to
Speaker 1:  know about this breaking news.
Speaker 2:  And also a third-party apps can also read those focus
Speaker 2:  statuses if they want. So in theory, if slack wanted
Speaker 2:  to, it could display your focus mode, notification haven't
Speaker 2:  changed your slack status, which I guess when you think about it,
Speaker 2:  you want your fundamental status to be handled by the
Speaker 2:  platform, I guess. But there is sort of a potential future tussle
Speaker 2:  for who's in charge of what status I'm telling other people I'm
Speaker 1:  In. Yeah. I mean, we've written about the desire to have a
Speaker 1:  universal living. It's basically an away message, but I can set a system-wide
Speaker 1:  away message and have a bunch of messaging apps, respect it, and
Speaker 1:  like use it a, we would have brought back away messages.
Speaker 1:  We should be great and be like, it would be tremendously useful. Now, do
Speaker 1:  I want my slack away message to be a bunch of emails,
Speaker 1:  song lyrics the way that I want my iMessage away message to be that. I mean,
Speaker 1:  that's, I don't know. I mean, that's how I ran with it in
Speaker 1:  aim
Speaker 4:  In college. I
Speaker 3:  Really want my mom to get a different away message than, than
Speaker 3:  work because she won't get that. She won't get the emo lyrics. She'll just
Speaker 3:  be very confused and continue to like text or call.
Speaker 1:  I continue to be successful in my career please. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  That's that's all I want for my mom. That's
Speaker 4:  All she needs
Speaker 3:  Doing fine. Can't talk.
Speaker 1:  I mean, this is the reason they announced the suffer early after developers
Speaker 1:  have to build towards it. They have to use it. What it
Speaker 1:  actually comes out and those apps are ready and they'll get updated. That
Speaker 1:  is when we know how well it works. The ideas are there. I
Speaker 1:  just, that one of like, I want to turn off all my
Speaker 1:  notifications, even now when I do that, I end up
Speaker 1:  enabling slack, which is the most distracting one of all right. And it's
Speaker 1:  like, I have to, because some of the people that need to be able to break
Speaker 1:  through the wall, messaged me on slack, or I have to go to all of them individually
Speaker 1:  and say, please text me for the next two hours, which makes no sense. We'll
Speaker 1:  see. I'm very curious how this works. There's a lot of messaging apps. I
Speaker 1:  think they're going to try to find ways around it or through it, but we'll
Speaker 1:  see. Do you want to talk about the privacy stuff real quick?
Speaker 2:  Ah, so there's a bunch, there's an ancillary thing, which we should maybe
Speaker 2:  circle back to, which is putting your ID on your phone. They're adding a,
Speaker 2:  sort of a, they changed the name from the pavers of iCloud icon plus, but
Speaker 2:  it's just iCloud that you pay for it. Now has this sort of double
Speaker 2:  proxy. That's not quite a VPN, but serves similarly the same sort
Speaker 2:  of functions as a VPN, kind of makes it harder for people to track what you're
Speaker 2:  doing on the web. They're finally doing something
Speaker 2:  to try and stop tracking pixels and mail unclear
Speaker 2:  how effective that will be. And similar it is to the thing that's
Speaker 2:  been on like Gmail for years upon years. And
Speaker 2:  then the other thing they're doing is they're creating an app privacy report
Speaker 2:  and they've also got an app privacy dashboard. So you can see when various
Speaker 2:  apps are using various sensors, this is similar to what just got announced
Speaker 2:  for Android 12. The app privacy report is sort of like the safari
Speaker 2:  report that like tells you how many trackers are on a webpage. I think with
Speaker 2:  app, with the app privacy report, that might be a little bit more actionable
Speaker 2:  than the safari one, but I don't know. We
Speaker 2:  shall see, but that's the big stuff is they're doing a
Speaker 2:  little bit better. Like obviously skating your activity online and they're
Speaker 2:  doing a little bit better showing you what other apps are
Speaker 2:  doing and they're not making
Speaker 1:  Some of this stuff available in China. Yeah. So the, the relay thing is
Speaker 1:  super interesting because there's actually two realized involved. One is
Speaker 1:  controlled by apple and the other by a third-party the third-party
Speaker 1:  might change in different countries from what we
Speaker 1:  understand so far as people have been using it, I think it's been
Speaker 1:  CloudFlare. Yeah. The, basically the first hop is through
Speaker 1:  apple, which obscures who you are.
Speaker 1:  And the second hop is to the third party provider, which obscures where,
Speaker 1:  where you're trying to go. Right. That's a lot of hops, right? So
Speaker 1:  like, I'm curious, will it be fast? Like, will
Speaker 1:  it interrupt anything? Will it break anything like, you know, Apple's
Speaker 1:  position is like, of course we tested it, but yet we have to see
Speaker 1:  then on the male side, I think Casey read about this on the, on the verge
Speaker 1:  suite cases, businesses running a newsletter. He's very interested
Speaker 1:  in how email analytics might be changed by this.
Speaker 1:  He published this stat, which he sourced from Neiman lab, which source it
Speaker 1:  from a third party analytics company, 93% of mobile
Speaker 1:  mail opens or in the mail app, which seems completely wrong to me. It can't
Speaker 1:  be right.
Speaker 2:  I mean on iPhone maybe, but it's yeah,
Speaker 2:  it's definitely higher than I think I'm willing to admit to myself because
Speaker 2:  I never used the mail app and I do not enjoy it. And I haven't for many
Speaker 2:  years, but I can't believe it's that
Speaker 1:  High. Yeah. If, if there's anybody out there in email marketing is panicking,
Speaker 1:  please tweet us your, your apple mail number or email us. I'm
Speaker 1:  very curious. It's one of the stats that we just don't ever think
Speaker 1:  about. And here it might have this like downstream impact. Yeah. The other
Speaker 1:  thing that all this privacy stuff, why is apple doing
Speaker 1:  all this privacy stuff? Yes. They want to protect your identity.
Speaker 1:  But the mechanism of like wanting to track you is all because of
Speaker 1:  advertising, right? Like the reason that your privacy is under risk is because
Speaker 1:  there's a gigantic advertising business model, the internet. Yeah. The advertising
Speaker 1:  ecosystem really wants to know who you are so they can target ads at you
Speaker 1:  and sell your things on Instagram. It works. People trust me, it's a
Speaker 1:  real problem for me. But the other side of it is, is
Speaker 1:  apple closes the funnel of advertising. It makes advertising businesses really
Speaker 1:  hard. They're they're ready and waiting to take
Speaker 1:  30% from any other purchases you might make on the phone
Speaker 1:  for things like newsletters or paid podcasts or anything like
Speaker 1:  that. So there's, I think Apple's in a complicated situation
Speaker 1:  here. Most of the media ecosystem, us included. I'm sure there's going
Speaker 1:  to be some to read on this podcast shortly,
Speaker 1:  but most of the media ecosystem runs on ads. The ads run on targeting. We
Speaker 1:  just know how this works. If you want to change that, the
Speaker 1:  burgeoning way of changing that is direct payments, right? That
Speaker 1:  is going and paying Casey for platform or directly. That
Speaker 1:  is tipping people in apps like Twitch and
Speaker 1:  Twitter with super follows and all that stuff that is
Speaker 1:  platforms like only fans and Patriot and all this stuff. And if you
Speaker 1:  think of those as digital products, because it's all just digital products,
Speaker 1:  right? You can't buy a Kindle book. What does it mean to buy a newsletter
Speaker 1:  on the iPhone apps and services that produce that stuff are
Speaker 1:  going to run into 30% tax. And so I think there's a little bit of a dilemma
Speaker 1:  here for apple, just in terms of they're shutting down, they're
Speaker 1:  closing down a bunch of advertising stuff and rightfully so. I
Speaker 1:  think people think that stuff is invasive and I think they have a great moral
Speaker 1:  case for it. They're also the absolute tollbooth
Speaker 1:  for the creator economy, unless the entire creator economy happens on the
Speaker 1:  web, which should be cool. I just didn't seem right. Well
Speaker 1:  also, I don't
Speaker 2:  Know if you notice, but they sure didn't announce any big improvements to
Speaker 2:  progressive web apps at the WWDC conference.
Speaker 2:  So that's, that's a thing didn't happen now.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. And like their improvements to safari or like now it'll be
Speaker 1:  harder to use because the address bar is going to
Speaker 1:  float around all over the place. I mean, like they didn't do any core web
Speaker 1:  stuff. They made safari like look better.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. They put the address bar on the bottom and like, hooray. That's great.
Speaker 2:  That's a better place for it on a phone
Speaker 1:  Because the phones are huge. Yeah. They moved, they moved a
Speaker 1:  bunch of UI to the bottom of the phone. So you can use it with one hand.
Speaker 1:  I can
Speaker 3:  Actually like use it with one hand now cause I have very, very small
Speaker 3:  hands. And so before I, if I wanted to like use the top, I'd have to like
Speaker 3:  get both hands out. And I'm very excited to just use it all with
Speaker 3:  one thumb. It's going to be great whole,
Speaker 5:  But back to the privacy thing for a second, there was one new feature
Speaker 5:  that not to get a little morbid, but I, with iOS 15, there'll be a new
Speaker 5:  feature that lets your family access your data and your photos should you
Speaker 5:  die? And they were super casual about this at the keynote, which came off
Speaker 5:  a little strange, but they were like, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
Speaker 5:  So when you're gone, as you know, to, without any kind of
Speaker 5:  like, but yeah, it's kind of surprising that like this did not, was not
Speaker 5:  there before and now it will be now, which is good. I think,
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I'd say then it's actually a big policy change for apple because before
Speaker 1:  that was it, if nobody had your password, like all your stuff was gone.
Speaker 1:  So they've like made this change. I think Joanna wrote a big piece and had
Speaker 1:  a video about this. So like be you're right. It was
Speaker 1:  very casual. It was like, and now on the spatial audio and I was like, wait,
Speaker 1:  hold on. I'm still grappling with
Speaker 1:  inevitable mortality. Cause we just pumped the brakes for one
Speaker 1:  second. We should take a break actually and come back and talk about spatial
Speaker 1:  audio. We'll be right
Speaker 1:  back.
Speaker ?:  This episode of our show is brought to you by story blocks. If you're a content
Speaker ?:  creator, marketer or freelancer, it's time to ditch the pictures taken on
Speaker ?:  your phone or the sock puppet infotainment pieces. You keep shooting on your
Speaker ?:  webcam. It's time to get Storybox with a subscription to story
Speaker ?:  box. You get access to a demand driven library over 1 million high quality
Speaker ?:  stock assets, which includes 4k footage after effects and premiere pro
Speaker ?:  templates and a host of sound effects, music and more. If you're tired of
Speaker ?:  whitewash stock libraries, Storybox here's you with a restock initiative,
Speaker ?:  they've committed to ensuring that 20% of their footage portrays people of
Speaker ?:  color and those in the black and indigenous communities by 2022,
Speaker ?:  and they're hiring a diverse array of filmmakers to make it happen by capturing
Speaker ?:  authentic experiences of underrepresented communities, like people of color
Speaker ?:  and the LGBTQ plus communities. Starbucks has affordable
Speaker ?:  subscription plans to fit any budget. And with the unlimited all access plan,
Speaker ?:  you get endless downloads of everything in their library. Those assets are
Speaker ?:  not only royalty free, meaning you can use them anywhere for commercial and
Speaker ?:  personal use. They're also yours forever. Even if your subscription ends
Speaker ?:  everything you download stays with you. So try Starbucks today, explore the
Speaker ?:  library and subscribe, say it's storybox.com/verge that's
Speaker ?:  storybox.com/verge. Let's get real
Speaker ?:  the tech world. Doesn't always like to keep it simple from high products
Speaker ?:  to constant sales pitches and endless jargon shopping for quality electronics
Speaker ?:  can be overwhelming, but it doesn't have to be cut through the usual BS
Speaker ?:  with high sense, high census, the straight talking electronics brand that
Speaker ?:  offers clarity and quality over confusion because let's get real. The most
Speaker ?:  important thing about a great TV is that it's actually a great TV with all
Speaker ?:  the features you love like their new ULE D series. Whether you're watching
Speaker ?:  movies with the kids, enjoying a date night or comfort, watching that show
Speaker ?:  for the million time, high sense brings you an unmatched 4k TV
Speaker ?:  experience and with a range of sizes, their you led series is bringing
Speaker ?:  premium products to the masses.
Speaker 6:  We could sit here and tell you all about the awesome features that come with
Speaker 6:  high sense TV features like quantum dot color HDR, 10 plus, and
Speaker 6:  Dolby Atmos. But all you really need to know is that high sense
Speaker 6:  offers unbeatable quality at unbelievable prices.
Speaker 6:  Forget the jargon and get real to learn more, visit high
Speaker 6:  sense.com today. That's high sense.com high
Speaker 6:  sense. Let's get
Speaker 6:  real.
Speaker 1:  Okay. We're back. Yeah. There's a, there's more to talk about, but Chris,
Speaker 1:  you've been living in a spatial audio universe for these
Speaker 1:  past few days. Tell us what's going on here. Cause there's like a lot of
Speaker 1:  spatial audio news. It was took, it was tucked into every nook and
Speaker 1:  cranny of this announcement and it's actually really hard to unpack
Speaker 5:  It. Yeah, because now there are two kinds of spatial audio from apple, which
Speaker 5:  isn't confusing at all. There's a head
Speaker 5:  tracking kind of special audio, which came out last year
Speaker 5:  for and TV shows. So if you watch through certain apps and you have air pods,
Speaker 5:  you can turn your head and the sound will stay like planted or fixed, like
Speaker 5:  on your source device, like your iPad or Europe or your iPhone, which is
Speaker 5:  cool. That works super well. But this past week they
Speaker 5:  launched special audio for apple music and that works with
Speaker 5:  all headphones. So that's cool. But this whole thing about like surround
Speaker 5:  sound music is not a new concept. I don't know how many people listening
Speaker 5:  to the shove, her like a super audio CD, but the music industry has been
Speaker 5:  pushing this kind of thing for years and years and years. And so this is
Speaker 5:  like the latest take on that. And that's all done through Atmos and
Speaker 5:  a certain tracks sound really special, but I'd say
Speaker 5:  70%, you're just kind of sitting there wondering what happened to the song
Speaker 5:  that you knew before
Speaker 1:  70% really? Oh, it's so hit and miss dude.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. So, so there's like a lot to unpack here. So the
Speaker 1:  spatial audio with the video, the reason that it does head tracking makes
Speaker 1:  a lot of sense because, but it's basically just taking
Speaker 1:  surround sound for a movie. We've got a center channel and the
Speaker 1:  voices are always coming out of the center channel. Right. And kind of recreating
Speaker 1:  it in a 3d sound field around you. So if you
Speaker 1:  turn your head, it still seems like the voices are coming out of the people
Speaker 1:  on the screen. I totally buy it. It is
Speaker 1:  one of the cooler sort of like AirPods demos you can
Speaker 1:  do with someone, which is very impressive. It has a
Speaker 1:  utility to it. Like I, there's a part of me. That's like, I, it's more fun
Speaker 1:  to watch movies this way. Cause it's like, everything's all moving around.
Speaker 1:  Right. And then I'm like, wait, I own several televisions. What am I
Speaker 1:  doing? The music stuff is different. Like
Speaker 1:  it's different from like a business way. It's different from a
Speaker 1:  experience way. And then it's different as Chris was saying and
Speaker 1:  like, nobody knows how to use this stuff yet. It is just a mess. Like
Speaker 1:  it, some of these tracks are really impressive and cool. And some of them,
Speaker 1:  I think the joke I made is I listened to a simple man by Leonard Skinner
Speaker 1:  yesterday. And it just feels like it's hardest. It's like creepy
Speaker 1:  Ben up behind
Speaker 1:  you.
Speaker 1:  Why are you over there, dude? Like the rest of the band is on
Speaker 1:  stage, get to work, man.
Speaker 2:  Is it like a Looney tunes? Like your bugs buddy and the
Speaker 2:  guitarist is over FID and he's just getting closer and
Speaker 2:  closer. It's like, are we just
Speaker 2:  late?
Speaker 5:  Seems like a newer albums are better because like now producers actually
Speaker 5:  do mix like for Atmos, since like newer, newer albums, like the St. Vincent
Speaker 5:  one that people have been talking about. I think with some other stuff that's
Speaker 5:  been out recently is all mixed for Atmos. So it sounds good. But if you go
Speaker 5:  back to like, you know, old stuff, it's mostly like remasters and that really
Speaker 5:  comes down to like how much people care about like making it sound good on
Speaker 5:  Atmos. And it seems like if you're a fan of blink 180 2, you're going to
Speaker 5:  be disappointed.
Speaker 2:  That's really an evergreen state. But there
Speaker 2:  Chris,
Speaker 5:  They were the songs that are like the ones that check out to hear it bad.
Speaker 5:  And so I wasn't a Papa wrote yesterday for the first time in like 20 years,
Speaker 5:  because it was like a particularly bad
Speaker 5:  example, spatial audio. So I had to
Speaker 5:  experience
Speaker 1:  Well. So it's really interesting with that. Right? All those like big rock
Speaker 1:  songs, pop punk songs, they're all mixed for two channels and they're all
Speaker 1:  mixed to be pretty loud. Like all those sounds
Speaker 1:  or they're mixed, like in the studio that they caught frequencies. They
Speaker 1:  stack them to layer those sounds and make those songs sound
Speaker 1:  huge and like, right. They're just big sounding
Speaker 1:  songs. If you like disassemble them and move all the
Speaker 1:  instruments into corners of the sound field, like their
Speaker 1:  songs start to sound really empty. Right. And there's like the, I think that's
Speaker 1:  what most people have described as like, they feel really echo-y and empty
Speaker 1:  because you're not supposed to be able to pick out every little instrument.
Speaker 1:  It's supposed to be like a big wall of noise that like, right. We're just
Speaker 1:  going to learn how it works. And just like with stereo, like really, really
Speaker 1:  early stereo records, like the producers were overexcited and were just like
Speaker 1:  hard pan the guitars all over the place and they don't do it anymore. Like
Speaker 1:  they figured out how to use it. So we'll see. But there's just a
Speaker 1:  part of this where apple Eddie cue gave an
Speaker 1:  interview to Michael Singleton at billboard. Like he used to work at the
Speaker 1:  verge. It was
Speaker 5:  So mean about lossless my heart was broken.
Speaker 1:  It's like, no one can hear it. Your ears aren't good enough. Like, but he's
Speaker 1:  like, spacial is like HD. It's like, it's the jump to HD. Everyone can hear
Speaker 1:  it. And it's true. Everyone can hear it. Cause it sounds so different, but
Speaker 1:  it's not like you're getting more necessarily. It's just a different kind
Speaker 1:  of tool.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. He had tried to sell it quite a bit by saying it sounded like you're
Speaker 5:  like in the room with the band, which it's not that great. Even like I'm
Speaker 5:  seeking, listen, listen to it through headphones. But if you have like a
Speaker 5:  fallen Atmos system, you can play it from the apple TV 4k. And there, it
Speaker 5:  sounds really, really nice. But I think like the both of people, how they
Speaker 5:  hear this'll be through the AirPods most likely
Speaker 1:  Or any headphones, because you only need two channels. And all they're really
Speaker 1:  doing is playing weird phasing and delayed tricks. So you can do
Speaker 1:  it with any headphones. Cause you're just sending the signal out. What's
Speaker 1:  really interesting to me is that I think apple is making a big deal out of
Speaker 1:  it. They're like kind of owning it, right? Like this, it feels like apple
Speaker 1:  announced spatial audio. Correct. But like it's actually Warner
Speaker 1:  brothers and Dolby and universal.
Speaker 5:  They're just giving you these mixes. They already have
Speaker 1:  Three years ago. They're like, this is the, this is the thing. And I think
Speaker 1:  their hope was that everyone would charge more money for it and then pay
Speaker 1:  them more money because that's how the music industry works. They're
Speaker 1:  like, would you like to pay us for dark side of the moon again? We know you
Speaker 1:  would. And then like off they're off to the races, but like
Speaker 1:  these Atmos files are the same files that Amazon music
Speaker 1:  has. The title has that. Right. They're not getting special apple remasters.
Speaker 1:  So it's, I'm very curious to see if these things sound different across different
Speaker 1:  services, or if apple is doing some system level spatial
Speaker 1:  audio stuff, like there's just a lot of parts of the sort of
Speaker 1:  signal where I'm not sure what who's doing, what
Speaker 1:  when
Speaker 5:  Right. And they said this fall, they are going to bring the head tracking
Speaker 5:  stuff to apple music too. And so I think that's going to be pretty strange.
Speaker 5:  I'm not sure why.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. So you can like back up to the guitarist and get
Speaker 3:  closer.
Speaker 5:  You can turn around to that Skinner to guitarist.
Speaker 1:  I really want everyone. I'm sure you haven't listened to Skinner in a long
Speaker 1:  time. It's just feels like a fair bet. But apple made a
Speaker 1:  bunch of playlists right. Called like for apple music
Speaker 1:  in special audio. And it's, there's a rock one and a hip hop one. So like
Speaker 1:  just dive through them. They're fun to listen to, and like, just go into
Speaker 1:  the Rocklin and like, just listen to this dude.
Speaker 3:  I'm so excited. Like I'm honestly going to do it after, after we finish this
Speaker 3:  podcast. And it's only in those, like the spatial audio stuffs
Speaker 3:  only in those specific playlist. Right? Like you, can't just, it's not
Speaker 3:  like if you already had that song on a playlist, it's suddenly going to convert
Speaker 3:  it dependence.
Speaker 1:  I have it downloaded. You have to delete it and re download it. Obviously.
Speaker 1:  That makes sense. If it's just in a playlist and streaming, it'll just
Speaker 1:  play one thing. That's I, Chris and I were talking about this
Speaker 1:  yesterday. You can't turn it on and off in the
Speaker 1:  app per song, which I would really like to be able to
Speaker 1:  do. It's either on for apple music or it's
Speaker 1:  off. And like there's one setting in the middle called
Speaker 1:  automatic, which I don't quite understand, like the credits. Maybe you
Speaker 1:  can explain it better, but either way you're like enabling it
Speaker 1:  all the time or you're disabling it. And like, there are some songs
Speaker 1:  like, oh, this sounds great. Like classical music in spatial audio is
Speaker 1:  like very cool sounding jazz too. But any rock
Speaker 1:  song just sounds empty and like, I should just be able to turn it on and
Speaker 1:  off. Yeah, you
Speaker 5:  Should. I think so. Yeah. That's the auto mode. I think that does actually
Speaker 5:  look for Apple's own devices like the AirPods or certain beats and phones.
Speaker 5:  And so it'll just play those by default, which is kind of wild. Like millions
Speaker 5:  of people are now just going to hear this by default for their music. So
Speaker 5:  I guess that kind of shows how excited apple is about it. We'll have to see
Speaker 5:  where it goes. I mean, I have left it on and off to hear the difference.
Speaker 5:  And there's one shortcut where you can like use the control center and like
Speaker 5:  turn off spatial audio real fast. And that'll like switch the mics back to
Speaker 5:  the stereo version. And so that's the fastest way I've found to go back and
Speaker 5:  forth. And that's in the control center of the phone. So you can just pull
Speaker 5:  that down and do that, but there should just be like a button to press to
Speaker 5:  like switch between the two. I don't know as
Speaker 3:  Much about music as you guys do, because Neil, I started
Speaker 3:  talking about like all the bandwidth and stuff and I was like, oh, wow. I
Speaker 3:  didn't know any of that. This is new information. I was just listening. Isn't
Speaker 3:  really like HD for, for video. Or is it more like when they started
Speaker 3:  color like colorizing black and white films, whereas like these things were
Speaker 3:  never meant for this. And we're like, you know what? We're gonna, we're going
Speaker 3:  to put a bit of splash of color on here to get people excited about
Speaker 3:  it's a wonderful night.
Speaker 1:  That's I think this is like a very Vergecast question. What's is
Speaker 1:  like HD for video implies so many things.
Speaker 1:  It implies higher resolution. Obviously it also,
Speaker 1:  for most people imply to dis different aspect
Speaker 1:  ratio and then further implied a different form
Speaker 1:  factor of a TV that got everyone to buy a new TV. Yeah. There were some very
Speaker 1:  strange like HD
Speaker 1:  CRTs and they like were owned. They roamed the
Speaker 1:  earth like a dinosaur. And I was like, but for most people, when you say
Speaker 1:  HD, it's like, you might not have been seen the extra resolution. You might've
Speaker 1:  just been seeing that it was 16 by nine. Now you might not have been
Speaker 1:  perceiving 16 by nine. And I promise you most people, when you
Speaker 1:  start trying to explain aspect gracious to them, they very quickly stopped
Speaker 1:  dating
Speaker 1:  you
Speaker 1:  to a first Leicester. You might've just been perceiving that the TV was thinner
Speaker 1:  and on the wall. Right. So there's like a lot to unpack from HD and like
Speaker 1:  what people really meant and why you want that because it drove this
Speaker 1:  big buying cycle, isn't it
Speaker 2:  Better analog, just 3d, 3d TV. It was a desperate attempt to get
Speaker 2:  people to buy stuff and remaster stuff.
Speaker 5:  She had to buy stuff for 3d TV. Like here it's just there and
Speaker 5:  works. And where your little glasses. Yeah. So there are no glasses to buy
Speaker 5:  or like TVs to buy it, which was the worst part of the whole equation in
Speaker 5:  that case.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. But like so higher resolution is the reason Eddie Q is donking lossless
Speaker 1:  audio or the reason that, you know, it's fun to laugh at
Speaker 1:  audio files, you buy a $5,000 cables is because they Sue
Speaker 1:  people swear. They can hear it. And most people can't hear anything
Speaker 5:  Quote, from a Steve jobs. I think it was like one of the, all things D appearances
Speaker 5:  where he said like music is one of the first cases where people just settled
Speaker 5:  and stopped caring about quality. Like, whereas film, you just want like
Speaker 5:  4k and HD and it's gotten higher and higher, but for music, we just kind
Speaker 5:  of settled on like MP3 and AAC. So I guess that the question is now is
Speaker 5:  special audio. The thing that'll like send us to a new new
Speaker 5:  era.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. But the thing is like what you perceive when you see something
Speaker 1:  like the Delta between you seeing that it's different is like pretty
Speaker 1:  small compared to music. Right? Most people are like, I'm very happy
Speaker 1:  listening to the song. I like on a very tiny AirPods
Speaker 1:  AirPods sound like garbage people love them. What are you going to do? Right.
Speaker 1:  Like they like them. They're happy. They're moving on with their lives.
Speaker 1:  That's the job. That's the job. So you have to make it sound
Speaker 1:  really different for people to notice it in. This sounds really
Speaker 1:  different. And I think in some places is Chris and I have
Speaker 1:  both experienced. It sounds really cool. And some places that just like,
Speaker 1:  yo Gary Rossington was late to the concert today and
Speaker 1:  he just soloing his way up to the stage. And in some
Speaker 1:  places it sounds I've, I've seen this on Twitter a few times now, like you're
Speaker 1:  pushing the hall button or the concert button or the stadium button on
Speaker 1:  an old receiver, you know, and you're doing that kind of crazy DSP effect.
Speaker 1:  And you just like adding a bunch of echo and it's like, why did they build
Speaker 1:  these features? Like who, if you are out there and your primary listing
Speaker 1:  mode is like, stadium, I just want, I want to know who you
Speaker 1:  are. Like, I'm so curious, like, let's hang
Speaker 1:  out, I'll buy you a beer. We can listen to some echo-y
Speaker 1:  music at your house together. But like, it does feel like one of those
Speaker 1:  gigantic permanent DSP effects. And I think maybe the industry
Speaker 1:  has to like catch up to it. But it's also fascinating to me that
Speaker 1:  apple is like really grabbed it. It's a Marvin Gaye song. Right. It's like
Speaker 1:  their big demo was Zane Lowe. Yeah. In one of the playlist.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. They're like, here's the mono version. Here's the stereo version. Now
Speaker 5:  here's spatial audio
Speaker 1:  And it's cool demo in Zillow is very exciting. Like he's
Speaker 1:  just with Zane, Lowe's excited. You're on that rollercoaster was though,
Speaker 1:  like he's a compelling figure. It is also the
Speaker 1:  exact same demo that Adobe does on its website with a less exciting person.
Speaker 1:  Right? Like this is happening somewhere else in the industry and apple is
Speaker 1:  just sort of grabbing it. So we'll see. I told you, we get on one spatial
Speaker 1:  audio for an hour. Deidre. Do you want to do iPad multitasking for the next
Speaker 1:  hour? I do.
Speaker 2:  You actually, I want to, I want to think about that a long time. I
Speaker 2:  want to talk about Monterey before we get there. So here's, what's new in
Speaker 2:  Monterrey, all the stuff that we talked about for the iPhone. So
Speaker 2:  FaceTime stuff, the share stuff and
Speaker 2:  FaceTime. Oh, by the way, whenever anybody sends you a link to
Speaker 2:  anything. Now, if it exists in an apple service, apples, all of
Speaker 2:  Apple's news and video and whatever services will not have an extra tab saying,
Speaker 2:  here's stuff that people shared with you. This is the social update to
Speaker 2:  iMessage. I don't, I don't think that's going to work, but
Speaker 2:  it's there. They have focus
Speaker 2:  mode. They have the new quick notes thing, all that
Speaker 2:  stuff. And then the coolest demo is universal control. Oh
Speaker 2:  yeah. And there's a bunch of other stuff you can airplay to a Mac
Speaker 2:  now, but don't try and use it as a monitor. Cause airplay is not that good.
Speaker 2:  I could talk about shortcuts for a long time, but like universal control
Speaker 2:  is you start it from a Mac and then you slide your mouse over
Speaker 2:  to the left or right. Edge of the screen. And when you do that, the Mac has,
Speaker 2:  like I mentioned, there's an iPad over there. And then it tries to put the
Speaker 2:  cursor onto the iPad and then you keep sliding and then it gets accepted
Speaker 2:  by the iPad. And now your cursor's on an iPad and your keyboard and mouse
Speaker 2:  in your Mac control the iPad. And then once you've made that
Speaker 2:  connection, you know, they're just together. You can actually use the iPads,
Speaker 2:  keyboard and mouse to control your Mac. If you want. It just becomes like
Speaker 2:  a mouse that you can move around with any of the attached,
Speaker 2:  you know, mice controllers and whatever, where, whatever screen the mouse
Speaker 2:  is on. It's controlling that screen and your keyboard works on that
Speaker 2:  screen. It's a very cool demo. And I made a
Speaker 2:  video about it based on basically technologies that Apple's had for like
Speaker 2:  three or four years. They just finally like put them together in the right
Speaker 2:  way. I love
Speaker 1:  The fact that they're just sort of assuming that if you add a third screen,
Speaker 1:  it's on the other side, like yeah. You know that they tried to whiteboard
Speaker 1:  some extremely complicated technical
Speaker 1:  solution. And then the one person in the back of the room was like, well,
Speaker 1:  there's already one on the right. Isn't it probably just on the left. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  And that was just like the end of that conversation.
Speaker 2:  Here's the question for Vergecast everywhere. If you are one of the
Speaker 2:  people and I, I respect you, I believe
Speaker 2:  in your right to make this choice. Even though I
Speaker 2:  fundamentally disagree with it, having tried it myself for many years. But
Speaker 2:  what if you are one of these people that puts your dock on a left to right
Speaker 2:  at the screen? Ooh, what happens then? Ooh,
Speaker 3:  You're still around. I didn't know. They existed still. Oh yeah.
Speaker 3:  Don't don't I, again, I think I used to do it when I had, when I
Speaker 3:  had two monitors when I just had like two monitors. That, that was
Speaker 3:  that it made sense then. Cause you would put it on one monitor to one
Speaker 3:  side and you'd be like, this is my big boy monitor. This is my, my main
Speaker 3:  monitor. And then there'd be the other monitor. And that's just where you
Speaker 3:  played all the anime that you got off, like bit tore
Speaker 3:  it. If, if you're
Speaker 2:  A, if you're a doc on the side user Alex's Twitter account is Alex H
Speaker 2:  Kranz and you should let her know.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Just, just let me ask, what anime are you watching and
Speaker 3:  what like site did you use?
Speaker 1:  Amazing. I used to be a doc on the side person. Then I got a
Speaker 1:  bigger laptop.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Yeah. You get a bigger screen. You get like, like the last time I
Speaker 3:  did it, I think we all, we were still in like full screen mode. You know,
Speaker 3:  we were still doing that, like the, the little terrible squares. And so I'm
Speaker 3:  like, cool. I guess there are people still using those, I guess. It's it
Speaker 3:  makes sense. But I do, I am really like curious. Who's still doing
Speaker 3:  it now. Cause it just, oh, we're going to hear from, yeah, I like
Speaker 3:  my DMS. I should probably close them
Speaker 1:  Where it's going to be like a 500 to one ratio of people who
Speaker 1:  have the dock on the side to people who listen to everything in stadium
Speaker 1:  mode. That's my current feedback ratio.
Speaker 1:  Guests
Speaker 2:  Shortcuts is going to sync between iPad and Mac
Speaker 2:  and iPhone, which means that all the shortcuts you've set up on your iPhone
Speaker 2:  will appear on your Mac. And then if you try and run them, they'll just air
Speaker 2:  out if they don't work because they don't have the appropriate
Speaker 2:  app, they're keeping automator around. But the future is
Speaker 2:  shortcuts. So who knows how long automator is going to stick around?
Speaker 2:  Hopefully a while. Probably awhile. A multi-year process.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Yeah. I'm excited for circuits on the Mac. I I'm, I'm excited for apple
Speaker 2:  to actually actively develop some sort of automation system on the Mac instead
Speaker 2:  of, you know, ignore it, which is what they did with automater for the past
Speaker 2:  five years. So that'd be good. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  I think what's, I've seen people do amazing things with shortcuts on the
Speaker 1:  iPhone. I think I am sort of excited about the idea that
Speaker 1:  apple is committed to an automation platform that works across devices because
Speaker 1:  that means they might commit to it working in home kit
Speaker 1:  better. Because right now that is a mess. Yes,
Speaker 1:  please do it apple. So this is just like a baby step
Speaker 1:  towards acknowledging that sometimes you just want shortcuts in your
Speaker 1:  house and then maybe they should run on a home kit hub. And that should
Speaker 1:  not explode in your face every time. Try to do it. That would be very cool.
Speaker 1:  Also being able to edit that stuff, those kinds of short cuts on a Mac
Speaker 1:  way easier than doing it on a phone or iPad. So for sure, I
Speaker 1:  do think that's pretty exciting. Okay. Let's take a break and then
Speaker 1:  we can talk about this iPad situation. How's that feel
Speaker 1:  great. We're going to take a break. Dieter is going to emotionally prepare
Speaker 1:  himself. We'll be right
Speaker 1:  back.
Speaker ?:  What secrets do matchmakers have up their sleeves to find the perfect match.
Speaker ?:  Some consult with the stars. Others will listen to what you say you want
Speaker ?:  and read between the lines. When you're talking about finding the right candidate
Speaker ?:  to fill a job, indeed has their own set of tools to help you find the perfect
Speaker ?:  fit, take their skills test feature. You can use it to measure more than
Speaker ?:  130 different skills and prospective hires, including hard skills, personality
Speaker ?:  tests, and work samples. Indeed says these tests reduce hiring times by
Speaker ?:  27% or the instant match feature, which delivers quality matches
Speaker ?:  over 80% of the time for your sponsored job post with indeed, you can get
Speaker ?:  a shortlist of quality candidates whose resumes that match your job description.
Speaker ?:  Then you can schedule a video interviews to see if a match will work and
Speaker ?:  you pay only for the ones who meet your must have qualities. Indeed helps
Speaker ?:  you match the right candidate to the job fast and easy. Get started right
Speaker ?:  now with a free $75 sponsored job credit to upgrade your job post at
Speaker ?:  indeed.com/vergecast. Once again, get a $75 credit at
Speaker ?:  indeed.com/vergecast offer valid through June 30th
Speaker ?:  terms and conditions apply Innovation.
Speaker ?:  Isn't a box. You check off your to-do list. It's a calling. You can't
Speaker ?:  ignore a project with no end date, an open book. That's
Speaker ?:  constantly being rewritten and you need technology. That's
Speaker ?:  built to handle it all no matter when or where inspiration
Speaker ?:  strikes, whether you're in your home office or out in the
Speaker ?:  field, because no matter where you are, Lenovo knows that
Speaker ?:  high-performance comes from within. That's why their PCs and
Speaker ?:  ThinkPads are equipped with the Intel Evo platform. From the
Speaker ?:  first foldable PC to the X one nano and the X one
Speaker ?:  titanium. They can handle your work as well as you do. That
Speaker ?:  means that no matter how many applications are open or videos or downloading
Speaker ?:  or apps, you're toggling through your Lenovo ThinkPad will keep
Speaker ?:  up and it'll keep up for a long, long time as
Speaker ?:  one of the world's longest lasting and most portable PCs,
Speaker ?:  according to PC mag, because after all solving the world's biggest
Speaker ?:  problems and changing the way we live, learn, and work, take speed
Speaker ?:  and flexibility. It takes Lenovo smarter
Speaker ?:  technology for all learn more at
Speaker ?:  lenovo.com/x
Speaker ?:  one.
Speaker 1:  Okay. We're back Dieter. Here's
Speaker 1:  wait before it, before we get all emo, one way to think about the iPad.
Speaker 1:  Multitasking reboot is that you won. Yeah. Have you
Speaker 1:  thought about considering this as a victory? Yes I
Speaker 1:  have. Okay. Gotta go. It's a Pyrrhic
Speaker 1:  victory.
Speaker 2:  So two years ago, when they first unveiled the new way
Speaker 2:  to move windows around on the iPad, I made a video
Speaker 2:  suggesting that it was not discoverable or
Speaker 2:  intuitive, that it's very powerful once you learn it, but you have to
Speaker 2:  watch a bunch of how to videos in order to figure it out. And then
Speaker 2:  once you do, it's great. And two years later, apple like, yep,
Speaker 2:  that that is true. And so they kept everything basically the
Speaker 2:  same, but they added hamburger menus to the top
Speaker 2:  of every single window on an iPad that you can now tap to
Speaker 2:  bring up little window options to either move it left
Speaker 2:  screen on left or right. Or turn it into a slide over or
Speaker 2:  whatever. That's fine. It's great. People will find it that way more
Speaker 2:  easily. I just can't help point out that this is the system that
Speaker 2:  Samsung has used for years.
Speaker 1:  Like
Speaker 2:  If you've, if you've given up and copied Samsung's windowing
Speaker 2:  system, you definitely failed. You've definitely
Speaker 2:  given up. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  There's only so many ways for them to go though. Right?
Speaker 2:  Well, here's, here's a way windows. Just, just, just let
Speaker 2:  me, let me, let me just like pop it out. You can have a, like a
Speaker 2:  floating window for certain things inside certain apps,
Speaker 2:  but it floats over the app itself.
Speaker 2:  It's like, you can, it only exists in like,
Speaker 2:  like three or four different modes and there's a new center mode for a window
Speaker 2:  to existed. So that's fine. I feel bad that they had to
Speaker 2:  like make a button that you can see in tap, but I make sense. I get
Speaker 2:  it. I accept it in my heart. The thing that drives me batty is the
Speaker 2:  shelf. So apps on the iPad can have multiple
Speaker 2:  windows. And before, if you wanted to get to one of
Speaker 2:  them, you have to open the app. You wouldn't know which window would open.
Speaker 2:  It would be the last word you use, but maybe you remembered. And then you'd
Speaker 2:  have like long press on the icon on the dock. And then it would show all
Speaker 2:  the windows and then you'd pick another window and you'd go. Now what they've
Speaker 2:  done is as soon as you open the app, it shows the shelf, which has
Speaker 2:  all of the open windows for that app. Now this is an app
Speaker 2:  by app thing. So the shelf only exists for windows
Speaker 2:  from a certain app. And it only shows up inside that app, unless
Speaker 2:  you're in split-screen, then the shelf will show the windows from the two
Speaker 2:  apps that are in split-screen wait. Yes. See exactly
Speaker 2:  that. I just, I just explained it as succinctly and clearly as possible to
Speaker 2:  explain it. And all of you were just like, wait.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Well, where they took away was a bunch of hidden UI, right?
Speaker 1:  They just like made a bunch of UI visible, a bunch of windowing
Speaker 1:  controls. Basically they have made
Speaker 1:  it, I think a little bit easier for this multi window
Speaker 1:  situation. Although the, one of the things
Speaker 1:  that I was just like, I've never really been able to share an iPad. Maybe
Speaker 1:  this will make it simpler is like, I don't know which apps support multiple
Speaker 1:  windows going. That's
Speaker 2:  I got that. Yeah. You know, you just got a long press on some stuff in the
Speaker 2:  app and see what happens. That's how you, that's how you pop out a new window
Speaker 2:  from an app. You long press or LA or dragon something. And you just
Speaker 2:  see like you just grab a safari tab and you just go.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. So I can do make sense. Like safari is like, has like windows,
Speaker 1:  like that has always made sense to me the other apps. And like, I don't even
Speaker 1:  know. I'm not going to try. What if I'm disappointed? I don't wish to be
Speaker 1:  disappointed today. Yeah. But like that's like that, that turn you're describing
Speaker 1:  where like, and then you enter a split screen mode and these behaviors start
Speaker 1:  to change. That's the one where I don't think they added any more
Speaker 1:  visible UI to like guide you through it.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. No, it's, it's tough to figure out how that works. And
Speaker 2:  it's a real pro user thing. And I think that popping open multiple windows
Speaker 2:  from a single app on an iPad is genuinely a pro user thing. And
Speaker 2:  so I am basically okay with it being a little bit complicated
Speaker 2:  or hidden in some ways, because I mean, it's
Speaker 2:  so rare that anyone actually uses that stuff that it's fine. Like the people
Speaker 2:  that know that, that know it and need it. They can grab it. I've
Speaker 3:  Only ever used it on accident. I have opened do windows on
Speaker 3:  safaris so many times. And then I'm like, I just want you to go. I don't,
Speaker 3:  I don't want you here. And like, when you were telling us how to get to
Speaker 3:  the shelf, I was taking notes so that I can actually go close some
Speaker 3:  windows on my iPad after this. I
Speaker 3:  had no idea. One
Speaker 1:  Thing I would really like, and I don't think they've added, this
Speaker 1:  is like presets presets once upon a time when
Speaker 1:  I would like, go on airplanes, remember those
Speaker 1:  iPads are great on airplanes. Did they use a lot of power loss on that? And
Speaker 1:  like, I'd be like, okay, here's what I want right now. I want slack. I want
Speaker 1:  a safari window. And I want messages. Right. And like having
Speaker 1:  to configure that every time always just seemed bonkers to me. Like, yeah,
Speaker 1:  let that just be a button I can push. It's like, here's this app layout I
Speaker 1:  want, that's gonna make me like, productive, like right
Speaker 1:  away. And I don't think they've solved that problem. In some ways it actually
Speaker 1:  made it more complicated because I have all these like, like split-screen
Speaker 1:  app instances all over the place. Let's see, I'm willing to give it a shot.
Speaker 1:  But like, that's actually, the thing I want is like, here are the three things
Speaker 1:  I want to use. Just let me use them. Couldn't you do a shortcut, I guess,
Speaker 1:  to find out, can you do a shortcut that moves windows around
Speaker 2:  And I've had that. I don't know. I haven't tried that yet. I'm sure.
Speaker 2:  Frederico. The TICI would be a failure answer to that
Speaker 2:  question. Someone
Speaker 1:  Should start like a shortcut consultancy. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  That's actually a really good idea. I didn't pay, but I'd go to them. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  So
Speaker 1:  You're just like, wait outside the door
Speaker 3:  Please. Yeah. And tried to get some, some help from them when they're
Speaker 3:  leaving. Yeah. I saved
Speaker 2:  By other emotion for the iPad section, even though it could have gone to
Speaker 2:  the Monterey section, what the hell have they done to
Speaker 2:  safari? I think it looks cute. So
Speaker 2:  what they, if you don't know what they've done is they've introduced tab
Speaker 2:  groups on the left, which is great. And then they have taken the entire toolbar
Speaker 2:  and collapsed it into a single line. So on the
Speaker 2:  iPhone, it's at the bottom and you have to hit extra buttons to get to share.
Speaker 2:  That's fine on the iPad and on the Mac, all the tabs
Speaker 2:  are at the top and the URL bar has been integrated into the
Speaker 2:  tab. And so if you want to go click on the URL
Speaker 2:  bar, you have to find where it is on the left or the
Speaker 2:  right. The tabs are also floating and they're not actually attached to the
Speaker 2:  page. That's open anymore. They're just sort of up there in a different
Speaker 2:  color. And so if you're on like fourth tab
Speaker 2:  from the right and you want to go to the URL, you either gotta remember the
Speaker 2:  keyboard shortcut. Or if you'd go up to click, you gotta like, I don't
Speaker 2:  know, like, no, it's the fourth tab from the right or happy to see a suddenly
Speaker 2:  different color. Cause that's the only visual indication that that is the
Speaker 2:  tab URL that you're on. And then on top of all of that,
Speaker 2:  because the URL has been integrated into the tabs
Speaker 2:  themselves, the ability for you to like do stuff with
Speaker 2:  the URL has diminished even further. I fundamentally
Speaker 2:  believe that apple hates URLs and does not want anybody to ever see them.
Speaker 2:  And it is trying to get there as quickly as it can, but it doesn't want anybody
Speaker 2:  to like notice. So it's just doing it in baby steps
Speaker 1:  Did that. But the entire web, just trying to
Speaker 3:  AOL the entire internet.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I, the, the part where the tab, so really
Speaker 1:  what's the rule fits his rule fits his law fits law. Yeah. Right. We're
Speaker 1:  like fixed points on the screen are the easiest to get to and like require
Speaker 1:  the least cognitive load. The Wikipedia.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. It's it's the edges of the screen that's fits law, but I get where
Speaker 2:  you're going. Yeah. Right.
Speaker 1:  So like right now in Chrome or even the current version of safari, the
Speaker 1:  top of your browser is like pretty fixed in space. Like things aren't
Speaker 1:  moving around so much. And so like, you know where things are, you
Speaker 1:  know, where tabs are, whatever, and you have this kind of
Speaker 1:  like spatial relationship to them. And then the guitarists from Leonard Skinner
Speaker 1:  and sneaks up the browser, the new version of safari,
Speaker 1:  all that stuff is always moving. So when you switch a
Speaker 1:  tab, like the address bar opens up and all of the other tabs
Speaker 1:  like scoot over. So you have, you don't have this like fixed
Speaker 1:  like physical reference to where your things are. And I just
Speaker 1:  don't know like, apple is better at UI design than most
Speaker 1:  companies, most of the time. And this one feels like they,
Speaker 1:  they missed the basics of just let people know where things are
Speaker 1:  in a predictable way. Right.
Speaker 3:  Can you imagine trying to walk someone who doesn't use their computer a
Speaker 3:  lot through opening multiple tabs now and
Speaker 3:  like jumping between them? Can you imagine, like, I, I'm
Speaker 3:  just not going to take phone support calls from family members for a
Speaker 3:  while after this happens. Cause it's just going to be brutal. I think people
Speaker 3:  are going to get lost, but I also think it's, I still think it's
Speaker 3:  cute. It does look nice. It looks really nice.
Speaker 1:  And like the, you know, they're doing some sinking stuff. They are part of
Speaker 1:  a, a new industry-wide consortium with Google and Microsoft and
Speaker 1:  others Missoula to do standardized web extensions, which I think
Speaker 1:  is really cool and like a big move for apple.
Speaker 2:  It's very good that apple did this. Let's not give apple credit for it in
Speaker 2:  the way that like they like, oh matter like apple, everyone's basically
Speaker 2:  adopting some HomeKit standards for the low-level for smart home stuff. That's
Speaker 2:  like an apple driven thing because they had to fix home kit, apple
Speaker 2:  adopting web extensions for safari is like, oh, everyone else is doing this.
Speaker 2:  And no one's making stuff for our stuff anymore. We should probably get on
Speaker 2:  board finally.
Speaker 1:  No, I just think like, we'll see. It's it's another one of
Speaker 1:  those. I don't know that like really basic
Speaker 1:  computer users even use tabs or another exist or care about tab
Speaker 1:  groups. Right. And then like, yeah, we are, we exist in a
Speaker 1:  community, a very online people who are like, I have 500 tabs open today.
Speaker 1:  One of my favorite newsletters is literally called today in tabs. Like, yeah.
Speaker 1:  There's just a huge yawning, chasm of
Speaker 1:  expectations from computers here. So we'll
Speaker 1:  see. I just, the fact that all the stuff is moving around seems like
Speaker 1:  the it's the, that's the basics. Right? It's like leave the UI
Speaker 1:  alone and then let the, the content change. Don't
Speaker 1:  have the content just like completely move itself around all the time. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  All right. That's the iPad. And that's also happening by the way on the Mac
Speaker 1:  version of safari too. Whereas I think it's going to be even yet
Speaker 1:  another reason for me to not use safari too often, you want to run
Speaker 1:  through the watch real quick. It's like not a lot
Speaker 1:  happening with the wall a lot.
Speaker 2:  I like the most interesting watch stuff is actually not watch stuff. So you
Speaker 2:  can share health data with trusted family members. And so you
Speaker 2:  could theoretically set up your parents or your grandparents watch to like
Speaker 2:  send you alerts when they have a fall or something else. There's a lot of
Speaker 2:  privacy stuff related to that. They've added workout types for
Speaker 2:  Tai-Chi and Pilates. Okay. They
Speaker 2:  also on the watch, they have new photo stuff. So you can
Speaker 2:  like browse through photos more nicely. And then there's a new photo watch
Speaker 2:  face that like pops out the face and puts it over the clock.
Speaker 2:  And it's like, zoom, you can scroll the digital crown to like make the face
Speaker 2:  zoom. If that's the thing that you want to do. And then of
Speaker 2:  course the most important feature that is only available in watch
Speaker 2:  OOS and nowhere else is you can set multiple
Speaker 2:  timers.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Oh my God. Finally,
Speaker 2:  finally, but of course the iPhone, I don't think could do it just,
Speaker 2:  just the watch. So once again, the clock app on the iPhone continues
Speaker 2:  to be hot, garbage that apple refuses to touch and the clock up on the watch
Speaker 2:  is good. Oh, we should also mention iPhone and watch are also getting
Speaker 2:  a bunch of key stuff. BMW. Once again, promises that you'll be able to
Speaker 2:  unlock your car with your phone six months in the future. It feels like that's
Speaker 2:  been going on for a while now, but they're adding NFC keys. And
Speaker 2:  so they've got, they've got, I think they've got slake
Speaker 2:  and another like Yale on board and a Hyatt
Speaker 2:  to riot. There'll be a bunch of hotels as well. So
Speaker 1:  Hotels, office buildings, all that stuff.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. It's we're long overdue for just, just use NFC
Speaker 2:  all. It's fine. And yeah. So hopefully that gets out there really
Speaker 2:  fast.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. We have not really talked about the, the ID card
Speaker 1:  thing. I'm just going to, I'm going to say this very directly. If I'm
Speaker 1:  pulled over and the cop wants my driver's license. Yeah. The chance that
Speaker 1:  I am going to hand them, my smartphone is zero and it should
Speaker 1:  be zero for you to get, right. Like that is
Speaker 1:  just, it's just not acceptable. And so like maybe there's
Speaker 1:  going to be this huge infrastructure of, I don't know, police
Speaker 1:  technology that lets you like beep a smartphone to get your ID off it. And
Speaker 1:  onto there, like maybe that will exist. You tap their phone.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I don't, it's not that doesn't seem
Speaker 1:  likely also these phones unlock with your
Speaker 1:  face. So even if you hand them a phone that's locked in, like
Speaker 1:  in that ID mode, their opportunity to unlock,
Speaker 1:  it just requires a clear view of your face and they're
Speaker 1:  the police. And they can definitely get you to give you a clear view of
Speaker 1:  your face. So like, I just, this is one of those features
Speaker 1:  where the tech industry is just moving down the track, right? They want to
Speaker 1:  replace your wallet, all the cards in it. I get it. I
Speaker 1:  understand there's a bunch of state by state level initiatives to
Speaker 1:  do this work. Completely understand it. But down here on the ground, it's
Speaker 1:  like, I am never ever going to use this feature.
Speaker 1:  I will always want a piece of plastic that I can handle a police officer
Speaker 1:  or a TSA agent or something because my life is on my smartphone. And I am
Speaker 1:  not handing that over. Like, there's a nice, like that little fourth
Speaker 1:  amendment vignette in 99 problems is like just in my head all of the
Speaker 1:  time. Right? So you're just not going to legally search my shit.
Speaker 1:  Like that's it. That's like, that's where your head should be at all the
Speaker 1:  time. And your phone is like the gateway to illegally searching you.
Speaker 1:  So I don't know. I don't want to be on too much of horse. I'm certain we're
Speaker 1:  going to hear a lot about this. The chances of me ever using this feature
Speaker 1:  are zero. And it's a very high bar to get me off a
Speaker 1:  zero. Yep. Okay. See, we needed to end with a
Speaker 1:  lecture. It's not just web standards all the time here on
Speaker 1:  the verge has sometimes there's stride and lectures about privacy. There
Speaker 1:  is a bunch of other news. We should just mention it very quickly, Microsoft
Speaker 1:  today and now inst X-Box TV app. Actually Phil Spencer
Speaker 1:  was on decoder and he hinted at this stuff pretty clearly a few months
Speaker 1:  ago. So X thought has come basically going everywhere. So they're
Speaker 1:  going to do apps for smart TVs, at least stream X-Box games.
Speaker 1:  They're going to make their own streaming stick, which seems
Speaker 1:  dangerous. See like, well, why is that dangerous? What operating
Speaker 1:  systems that stricken around, right? It's going to be Android. It's going
Speaker 1:  to be Andrew. It's like, they're going to make a weird fire TV that runs
Speaker 1:  X cloud. Yeah, of course they are. Yeah. It's
Speaker 3:  It's going to be your little like $50
Speaker 3:  X-Box on a stick. What's
Speaker 2:  Dangerous about this. This is great. I love
Speaker 2:  it.
Speaker 1:  Like these devices are Chris reviews. A lot of
Speaker 1:  them, little tiny, cheap streaming devices are harder
Speaker 1:  to execute than you think Microsoft we're making yet.
Speaker 1:  Another fork of Android is like, what are we doing? Or
Speaker 1:  they're going to do an official, like, they're going to do like a Chrome
Speaker 1:  cast one, which is less dangerous, but like, or they're gonna,
Speaker 1:  it's going to run windows, which would be incredible if Microsoft went to
Speaker 1:  like Disney and Netflix and it's like, we need to make a window
Speaker 1:  streaming,
Speaker 2:  But you used to be able to buy a windows, computer and a stick like Intel
Speaker 2:  soul to Knuck. That was literally a stick that you could stick in the back
Speaker 2:  of a TV. Yeah. Back in the day,
Speaker 1:  The marketing genius of calling that a Knuck
Speaker 1:  anyway, really bold stuff for Microsoft. And it's the middle of eateries
Speaker 1:  this weekend. So it was just like gaming announcements everywhere. Google
Speaker 1:  is doing a deal with at and T to get stadia out in the world, which is
Speaker 1:  sure. Ooh.
Speaker 3:  When quippy did partnered with T mobile
Speaker 2:  Or when, when H T and T partner with magic leap, like come
Speaker 2:  on.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, no, that's great. When at and T does things, it always works out and
Speaker 1:  no one ever loses their job. And it really builds up for Microsoft. This
Speaker 1:  is what stadia like, this is what Google wanted to be first too. And they
Speaker 1:  didn't execute well. And Microsoft is just showing up. And I think they're,
Speaker 1:  I think they're this stuff is gonna be really compelling, especially the
Speaker 1:  apps on TV, other TV platforms, Alex Heath, new
Speaker 1:  Virginia reporter scoop machine scoop that
Speaker 1:  Facebook is playing a smartwatch for next summer with two cameras and a heart
Speaker 1:  rate monitor. One of the cameras appears to like, be like constantly
Speaker 1:  taking. It's like very Facebook.
Speaker 3:  You can like detach one of the cameras. Right?
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Facebook's goal is to make a piece of hardware that is so compelling.
Speaker 1:  You will not use your phone to get around apple. The Facebook,
Speaker 1:  apple war is like building to a head.
Speaker 1:  And so there's some, some of this hardware stuff, then there's like
Speaker 1:  Facebook, it's going to start telling creators and Instagram and other
Speaker 1:  platforms, how much apple is taking out of their digital services when they
Speaker 1:  sell things like ticketed events and like they're gearing up.
Speaker 1:  But I don't know about Facebook smartwatch. I dunno. I don't know,
Speaker 1:  man. Chris, you reviewed the new Sony. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It's been a busy June for earbuds. Last week was the Google pixel buds day
Speaker 5:  series, which were a nice set of $99. Earbuds, Sony just put
Speaker 5:  out these WF thousand XM, 40
Speaker 5:  earbuds. And they're much better than the first pair where
Speaker 5:  these are now the best noise canceling earbuds you can get. So that's all
Speaker 5:  you care about is music quality and a noise cancellation. This is, this
Speaker 5:  is the one they cost $279. It's circle. They're not
Speaker 5:  cheap, but they sound amazing. And, and the battery life is great.
Speaker 5:  And hint, hint, we're not quite done with earbud news.
Speaker 5:  So maybe check out the verge early next week and see what
Speaker 5:  else I tell you. It's just ended there.
Speaker 1:  I want to, but we think there's a falling pixel coming this year right
Speaker 1:  here.
Speaker 2:  I dunno about coming this year. The, the news is that the Samsung is
Speaker 2:  like ramping up supply to provide to Google this year.
Speaker 2:  That to me suggests that it's more likely next year we
Speaker 2:  know they're working on it. So that's true. Whether or not they're going
Speaker 2:  to have guts or the ability to announce one
Speaker 2:  this year, TBD also it's Google. And so it would have
Speaker 2:  leaked for real, like a visible thing this year. Just, you know,
Speaker 2:  like, but it's definitely coming. I just, I am iffy on
Speaker 2:  whether or not they're actually gonna be able to announce it this year. And
Speaker 1:  Then lastly, president Biden revoked the Trump ban on tech
Speaker 1:  talk and we chat, which I have to pay attention. It never actually banned
Speaker 1:  anything. It was like one of, one of the extreme,
Speaker 1:  low lights of like pandemic year
Speaker 1:  was the Trump rally. And then, you know, the tick-tock
Speaker 1:  teens, a credit for making no one come to it, which by the way, has never
Speaker 1:  like been conclusively proven or disproven. We all like a lot of people
Speaker 1:  want to believe it's correct. Right? Like it's a great story. I think the
Speaker 1:  people on Tik TOK want to believe they disrupted this route. We just, I'm
Speaker 1:  just telling you it's there's the causal link has never really been conclusively
Speaker 1:  proven. It feels right. And like, I'm not going to tell you how to feel.
Speaker 1:  I'm just going to tell you that there's never been conclusive
Speaker 1:  anyhow, but that spiraling into
Speaker 1:  Trump potentially believing it. And then a bunch of China Hawks convincing
Speaker 1:  Trump to ban Tik TOK and then takes out getting scared. And then
Speaker 1:  Trump requesting a finder's fee for Microsoft because he was going to sell
Speaker 1:  tech, talk to Microsoft, like, yeah,
Speaker 1:  I'm saying this. It doesn't seem like it happened, but it
Speaker 1:  absolutely happened. And we had to fucking take it seriously every
Speaker 1:  day. And I just remember the look of pain. I'm like Russell and
Speaker 1:  McKenna's face because every morning we'd wake up and like
Speaker 1:  another random company would be in the mix to buy tick
Speaker 1:  talk, remember? And then Julia was on the show every couple of weeks.
Speaker 1:  And she'd be like another Disney executive is like been forced out and works
Speaker 1:  for tick-tock now. But he quit anyway, Biden rescinded this order
Speaker 1:  that never took any effect. Tik TOK was actually suing and kind of winning,
Speaker 1:  but there's a new framework for evaluating how Chinese tech companies
Speaker 1:  can work. United States. The byte administration does not want to seem soft
Speaker 1:  on China, so that will continue. But I just was remembering how
Speaker 1:  much I had to think about Tik TOK and Oracle at the same
Speaker 3:  Time, Oracle. That was, that almost happened.
Speaker 1:  We came maybe, maybe, but it's just like two great tastes that do not
Speaker 1:  taste great together. Talking to Oracle, like what were
Speaker 1:  you doing? Anyhow, all that needs on the
Speaker 1:  site. As much as other WWC analysis on the site, a
Speaker 1:  bunch of features we didn't have time to talk about in depth plus all kinds
Speaker 1:  of other stuff. Also, if you're listening to this Friday, this one's out
Speaker 1:  on Friday this morning, as you listened to this, Ashley Carmen has a feature
Speaker 1:  that she's been working on for months about a podcasting hype
Speaker 1:  house from the depths of hell. It is one of the
Speaker 1:  wildest stories we've ever published. Like I read that. Okay. You can tweet
Speaker 1:  at us. I'm at reckless theaters at backline. Alex is Alex H
Speaker 1:  Kranz. Chris is Chris Welch and shore is decoder.
Speaker 1:  Next week is a big one. Jamie Hyman, the CTO of John
Speaker 1:  Deere. And let me tell you, did we ever talk about repairing
Speaker 1:  tractors? Tractors
Speaker 1:  are crazy. Some of the wildest tech you could ever think. Do you know? There's
Speaker 1:  like, like Invidia GPU's and modern John Deere tractors that can identify
Speaker 1:  individual plants it's oh, that's amazing. Okay. Yeah, it was a good
Speaker 1:  one. That's coming on Tuesday. Okay. That's
Speaker 1:  it
Speaker 7:  For fans of the ninja UV and final fantasy. There's an enhanced
Speaker 7:  version of the critically acclaimed to final fantasy seven remake coming
Speaker 7:  out. It features the rebellious ninja in her own episode as the main
Speaker 7:  character, final fantasy seven remake antegrade
Speaker 7:  that's a mouthful, but trust me, it has better lighting textures and
Speaker 7:  background environments that bump up the visuals. You can switch between
Speaker 7:  graphics mode in 4k and performance mode, which has super smooth
Speaker 7:  action at 60 frames per second. If you've got a PS five, you've got
Speaker 7:  to see this for yourself. Visit S Q E
Speaker 7:  x.link/premake Vergecast for more information.