# Transcript
ID: bfd5d9b0-4083-11ed-8145-2fb30e851522
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Google is shutting down Stadia / Amazon's hardware launch event
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-7438351630705001881/1993605344220106688/s93290-US-5302s-1664516905.mp3
Description: The Verge's David Pierce, Alex Cranz, and Jay Peters discuss Google deciding to shut down its game streaming service Stadia. Jennifer Pattison Tuohy joins the show to chat about all the products Amazon announced at its hardware launch event this week, including the new E Ink tablet for reading and writing.
Google is shutting down Stadia
Google is trying to reinvent search — by being more than a search engine
Google’s trying to become a one-stop shopping destination
Google will help you find better results without tagging ‘Reddit’ onto every search
The 11 biggest announcements at Amazon's hardware launch event
Amazon’s Kindle Scribe is an E Ink tablet for reading and writing
Amazon fifth-generation Echo Dot smart speakers get a host of new features
Echo speakers can now be Eero mesh Wi-Fi extenders
Amazon’s new Echo Auto is smaller and easier to mount in your car
Amazon’s latest 4K TVs improve picture quality and borrow ideas from The Frame
The new Amazon Fire TV Cube has an HDMI input for controlling cable boxes
Alexa is getting some much-needed smart home upgrades
Amazon’s Halo Rise is a bedside light to track your sleep and wake you up
Blink's new Mini Pan Tilt adds robotics to its compact home security camera
Ring's new Spotlight Cam Pro mashes its most advanced features into a wireless design
Sonos Sub Mini review: low end for a lower price
Intel and Samsung are getting ready for ‘slidable’ PCs
Leaked Galaxy S23 renders suggest Samsung could ditch the camera bump
A smart lock with long-range wireless power is finally a reality
Asus launches massive 17-inch Zenbook with Ryzen 6000
Intel’s 13th Gen processors arrive October 20th with $589 flagship Core i9-13900K
Wacom announces the Cintiq Pro 27, its latest display graphics tablet
Logitech announces its first mechanical keyboard specifically for the Mac
Stage Manager isn’t just for M1 iPads anymore
Hands-on with aptX Lossless, the new tech promising CD-quality audio over Bluetooth
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we'd love to hear from you.
We are conducting a short audience survey to help plan for our future and hear from you. To participate, head to vox.com/podsurvey, and thank you!
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (7 ads detected)
Speaker 3:  Welcome
Speaker 5:  To the Vergecast, the flagship podcast of the Google graveyard. I like to
Speaker 5:  imagine we're like the local radio station we just like broadcast from the
Speaker 5:  top of the Google Reader tomb. That's just, That's just where we are. That's
Speaker 6:  Where we're at.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I'm your friend David Pierce. Alex Kranz is here. Hi
Speaker 5:  Alex.
Speaker 6:  Hi. I'm still upset about Google Wave. It could have been a thing.
Speaker 5:  It could have. I wholeheartedly grew with that. I also don't remember which
Speaker 5:  one is Google Wave and which one is Google Buzz? Don't ask me to tell the
Speaker 5:  difference. I couldn't
Speaker 7:  Tell you. Google Wave was, it was the better one.
Speaker 5:  Okay, that's good to know. That's j Peters. J Peters is here. Hi Jay.
Speaker 7:  I am Google Wave.
Speaker 6:  Jay is the
Speaker 5:  Wave you work like half the time, but you seem cool. Is that, is that
Speaker 5:  basically the fine?
Speaker 7:  That's accurate. Yeah, that's what I lost that, but yeah,
Speaker 5:  Eli is not here. Excuse he made was that he has like
Speaker 5:  45 weddings to go to this weekend. So if you have tips on how to be a good
Speaker 5:  wedding guest, please send them all to Eli. He's at Reckless on Twitter and
Speaker 5:  I'm sure he would love to hear all of your wedding tips. We have a lot to
Speaker 5:  talk about, but we definitely need to start with the big breaking news of
Speaker 5:  today. Just a couple hours before we started recording this, Google Stadia
Speaker 5:  is dead. Yeah. Jay, you, you found out about this like 10
Speaker 5:  minutes before it was happening. Tell us what's going on.
Speaker 7:  Yep. So Google is shutting down Stadia.
Speaker 7:  It's cloud gaming service. It'll stay
Speaker 7:  online for folks who subscribe or play games on it until
Speaker 7:  January 18th of next year. The good news is if you've
Speaker 7:  invested into hardware or software on Stadia,
Speaker 7:  Google's gonna refund everything to you. But if you loved Google Stadia
Speaker 7:  because of the dream of cloud gaming, Stadia will not be part of
Speaker 7:  that dream anymore, unfortunately. So
Speaker 5:  Wait, every penny that anyone ever spent on Google Stadia, Google is giving
Speaker 5:  back.
Speaker 7:  Not quite. Okay. If you subscribed to its Stadia Pro
Speaker 7:  subscription, they're not gonna refund those. But if you
Speaker 7:  were subscribed, you can still use Stadia Pro
Speaker 7:  through until the shutdown happens.
Speaker 5:  Got it. What are like incredible admission of not only
Speaker 5:  failure, but like we are sorry we conned all of you into thinking this
Speaker 5:  was a thing we were actually doing. Yeah. That they're just giving all your
Speaker 5:  money back.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, it's not, you know, I mean, I'm happy that people get their money back
Speaker 7:  cuz I think a lot of people, well maybe not a lot, but a fair
Speaker 7:  amount of people, people really, really believed in what this could
Speaker 7:  do. And you know, it very pie in the sky sounds awesome, right? You can
Speaker 7:  stream your games onto whatever platform, whatever screen you're in front
Speaker 7:  of. But for Google, that's not reality. I
Speaker 6:  I think it's, cuz it was always a beta, It was, it was always a beta that
Speaker 6:  they just charged for.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. I mean, it it it launched super rocky and without a bunch of the
Speaker 7:  really cool features that they announced right at the start. And, you know,
Speaker 7:  they slowly added some of those things, but like, it wasn't enough. And,
Speaker 7:  and when you have to think about like, is my internet connection gonna even
Speaker 7:  work to play this game? Like, I think that's enough of a barrier for people
Speaker 7:  that it, it just can't catch on.
Speaker 5:  I was talking about this with Tom on Wednesday show that like, there is just
Speaker 5:  this invisible barrier for people that it's like internet gaming is
Speaker 5:  a good idea. It's probably definitely the future and it is just not
Speaker 5:  something people are ready for. And the thing that really amazed me was going
Speaker 5:  back and reading some of the stuff from the launch in 2019, like
Speaker 5:  this service was never very good, was the thing that I forgot.
Speaker 5:  It was like a cool idea. And there were some people who were like, Yeah,
Speaker 5:  this could really turn into something. But even at the very beginning it
Speaker 5:  was like, there is some big important stuff missing here,
Speaker 5:  namely, like, there aren't really very many good games to play. That
Speaker 5:  wasn't true. That's like if we have learned one thing, it's like just have
Speaker 5:  good games.
Speaker 6:  There were good games, they had good games. The problem was were there,
Speaker 6:  The internet in the United States is
Speaker 6:  garbage. Yes. Like it's bad. Everybody has
Speaker 6:  bad internet. Very few people have good internet. We are currently
Speaker 6:  recording this podcast and all of our videos are super
Speaker 6:  pixelated. Yep. Because the internet is so bad it can't handle
Speaker 6:  video streams. So of course I wasn't gonna be able to handle stadia. And
Speaker 6:  like I remember talking to the heads of Stadia when it came out and
Speaker 6:  I was like, What are you gonna do about this? And they're like, Well, you
Speaker 6:  know, ISPs recognize when things are bad and they improve them. And I was
Speaker 6:  like, that's just, are you dumb?
Speaker 7:  But Alex,
Speaker 6:  Like they were, they were like, No, it'll happen. And I was like, but it
Speaker 6:  didn't, it wasn't gonna happen. Alex, how are you gonna make that happen?
Speaker 7:  Well, 5G was the obvious answer for that one. Of course.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Yeah. Everybody's like, 5G gonna be
Speaker 6:  5G and cloud gaming together hand in hand will transform the
Speaker 6:  world. And it's like they won't because you still have to get
Speaker 6:  fast internet 5g.
Speaker 5:  You say that like, it's a joke by the way. But that really is what they said,
Speaker 5:  like that really genuinely is what they said. You did
Speaker 6:  Say that they were like, this is gonna save the world. You're gonna be able
Speaker 6:  to like cloud game doing laparoscopic surgery on
Speaker 6:  your best friend's dying mother with
Speaker 6:  Stadia. They didn't say that part, but these were all these huge,
Speaker 6:  massive promises and they kept forgetting the fact that at
Speaker 6:  the end of the day, you still have to have pipes that pipe the internet to,
Speaker 6:  to the 5G broadcast towers and to the people's homes.
Speaker 6:  And nobody wants to pay for those.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And I think,
Speaker 6:  Sorry, I get very passionate about internet infrastructure.
Speaker 7:  I mean, it's important, It's important for a technology
Speaker 7:  that requires good infrastructure to make the
Speaker 7:  games work. So I think you're really justified
Speaker 7:  in being passionate about this one.
Speaker 5:  Well, and I think yeah, if you're, if you do the business in a
Speaker 5:  very different way, I think you can maybe get away with it. Like I, I
Speaker 5:  have PS4 down in my basement and I use
Speaker 5:  the PS4 remote play to play video games on a computer and
Speaker 5:  it's like, it's kind of what you're describing. It's like occasionally blocky,
Speaker 5:  there's a little lag, but it's a free thing that just sort of exists.
Speaker 5:  And so anything about it that like works at all
Speaker 5:  feels like a victory. And I will take that. Google came out
Speaker 5:  and said, not only are you gonna pay for the games that you want, you're
Speaker 5:  gonna pay for the privilege of streaming the games that you want. And at
Speaker 5:  the beginning they were making people buy that like weird, expensive package
Speaker 5:  that also included a Chromecast and it's just like they set it up as this
Speaker 5:  very premium, very like high intensity future
Speaker 5:  of gaming thing and you know who's gonna buy that as people who need way
Speaker 5:  more out of their games than Google Stadium is gonna give them.
Speaker 6:  Yes, a hundred percent.
Speaker 7:  I really like Microsoft's approach personally where it feels like
Speaker 7:  cloud gaming is like an add on to
Speaker 7:  the things you can already, you know, you can buy game from the store and
Speaker 7:  just play out your Xbox and that's fine, but if you want to test one, you
Speaker 7:  can test that using the cloud. I think that's a really perfect application
Speaker 7:  of cloud gaming technology with the internet infrastructure
Speaker 7:  for the vast majority of Americans right now.
Speaker 6:  And I think it's like notable that Microsoft
Speaker 6:  and Nvidia are the two that are still like really in
Speaker 6:  this. Amazon's out there doing Luna, I'm sure it's gonna get
Speaker 6:  canceled next week. They're gonna be like, Oh, oh, we're canceling these
Speaker 6:  now. Yeah, we're out of this game too. But you know, Microsoft
Speaker 6:  and Nvidia both have been doing this for a lot longer. Microsoft
Speaker 6:  has been doing this for since I think at least in
Speaker 6:  2019, right? Was when they first launched their beta. I
Speaker 7:  Think. I think that sounds right. NVIDIA's
Speaker 6:  Invidia's been doing it even longer and, and doing a free
Speaker 6:  beta don't charge you any money. They only started charging very recently
Speaker 6:  when everybody else started ing before that. They're like, Yeah, this is
Speaker 6:  cool technology, but we know it's not worth your money yet.
Speaker 5:  I've been wondering about Invidia actually, and I'm, I'm curious what you
Speaker 5:  both think because like the, the state of GForce now is exactly
Speaker 5:  what you just described and I think Invidia got away with it because Invidia
Speaker 5:  was just selling all the Bitcoin mining rigs that
Speaker 5:  existed in the universe and I was
Speaker 6:  Doing it before Bitcoin,
Speaker 5:  But like the, the GPU business has been so good for so long that like
Speaker 5:  Invidia could kind of get away with this. Right? And now like what's clearly
Speaker 5:  happening here is all of these companies are going through and saying, okay,
Speaker 5:  where are our money pits where we can go and actually like the,
Speaker 5:  the economy is not great. We're like potentially headed to a recession. Everybody's
Speaker 5:  doing hiring freezes. It's like if I'm Google, it's pretty easy to look at
Speaker 5:  this and say, Okay, we're paying a fortune for games because we set it up
Speaker 5:  in this weird way where you have to like build an extra version of your game
Speaker 5:  just to run on Stadia. We have all this cloud infrastructure
Speaker 5:  that's really expensive and no one is signing up for our services.
Speaker 5:  So like obviously we should kill this thing. And I wonder if there are going
Speaker 5:  to be a bunch of other companies who make that same kind of
Speaker 5:  calculation.
Speaker 6:  I don't think Invidia and Microsoft will be those companies. Okay.
Speaker 6:  Microsoft, because it's j like rightfully pointed out, it's treated very
Speaker 6:  much like an add-on. This is like a nice bonus perk. And they've got the
Speaker 6:  infrastructure in place, right? Like they're one of the largest cloud computing
Speaker 6:  companies in the world. Invidia also really big cloud computing company.
Speaker 6:  Like they've had these servers for a long time and they've been doing this
Speaker 6:  for a long while and it's, it's a different thing for them,
Speaker 6:  but they've actually, like, it's an actually good service. I
Speaker 6:  can go play. I've been, I've played civilizations six on
Speaker 6:  Nvidia GForce now since like 20 17, 20 18.
Speaker 6:  Been doing it for ages and like Yeah. Is it pixelated?
Speaker 6:  Is it Bucky? Sometimes Sure. Is there one time where like it just wouldn't
Speaker 6:  quit the game and I would like go away and I'd come back and my game was
Speaker 6:  still running like four hours later even though I'd left the browser.
Speaker 6:  Yes.
Speaker 5:  This is not a compelling case that you think its
Speaker 6:  It's great. I love it.
Speaker 7:  I mean I, I think it's nice purely is an option. Like when I
Speaker 7:  was visiting family one time, I played through all of Donut County
Speaker 7:  on my phone using Xbox Club gaming and that was like, oh, this is a fun
Speaker 7:  game about a hole that just gets bigger and bigger and eats up all the stuff.
Speaker 7:  But like if I was really into Destiny, I don't know
Speaker 7:  if I would invest, you know, tons of time into Destiny on
Speaker 7:  Stadia where you have to shoot good, right? Like, and I don't know if I can
Speaker 7:  do that. I don't know if I can do that on Stadia or other cloud platforms.
Speaker 7:  You can't.
Speaker 5:  So what happens to all this stuff now? Like there's all the
Speaker 5:  infrastructure, there's people, the strangest thing I've been noticing is
Speaker 5:  there are a million people who are really curious about the controller. I've
Speaker 5:  never actually used this Stadia controller, but people seem to really like
Speaker 5:  it. What's, how, what's happening here? I
Speaker 7:  Haven't used the controller either. It looks like a good deep, you know,
Speaker 7:  a good controller. Like it looks fine. Like it's
Speaker 7:  nice.
Speaker 6:  It, it lets you play the games.
Speaker 5:  People are psyched about it. They're like, Okay, you can shut down Stadia.
Speaker 5:  I don't need my games, but like this deep ad y'all like I need, I need
Speaker 5:  the deep A Well
Speaker 7:  What I think what I was, what I've been reading and I haven't dug into this
Speaker 7:  myself, you know, all the way, but I think like you can't connect it to
Speaker 7:  your be a Bluetooth to your computer or whatever. You can plug it in with
Speaker 7:  a wire, but like way more controllers, you know, probably
Speaker 7:  everybody has a couple just sitting in a drawer somewhere can connect to
Speaker 7:  a computer. Another thing with Bluetooth. And so like, I think there's a
Speaker 7:  good chance that people just stop using these controllers.
Speaker 6:  Well, the, they like the, the controller doesn't serve a purpose after this
Speaker 6:  because the controller was built to connect directly to
Speaker 6:  Stadia. It didn't like connect to your Chrome's. Yeah. And then go through
Speaker 6:  it connected straight to the cloud. It's got its own wifi
Speaker 6:  and I'm sure somebody will get out there and hack it. Please,
Speaker 6:  please hit me up on Twitter. If you're that person and you successfully do
Speaker 6:  it, I wanna talk to you. Yeah. But for most people
Speaker 6:  it's, it's now just a piece of plastic that is gonna go into a
Speaker 6:  landfill and be bad for the environment.
Speaker 5:  Google made so many weird decisions here. Yeah. The like, I forgot that the
Speaker 5:  controller was connected to the internet. Like it just, Google tried way
Speaker 5:  too hard here. I think because
Speaker 6:  They wanted to avoid the
Speaker 7:  Lab. I wanted to avoid the
Speaker 5:  Google thing.
Speaker 7:  I mean, I think, I think the real death now happened more than a
Speaker 7:  year ago when it shuttered its internal game studios. Like
Speaker 7:  if you are trying to make cloud gaming a thing and you're not
Speaker 7:  gonna keep your own game studios for, let's assume they're
Speaker 7:  in production for two years. Like most AAA games take at least
Speaker 7:  three years to make, like that was a pretty
Speaker 7:  clear sign that they were not in this for the long haul.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I have been wondering why Google didn't just shut this down
Speaker 5:  a year ago, Like in a certain way it would've been cleaner. And then everybody
Speaker 5:  has been resurfacing these like vociferous denials that Google
Speaker 5:  is shutting it down and it all, it's so brutal now because everyone
Speaker 5:  of them is like, we're in this for the long haul. Like we know you think
Speaker 5:  Google kills lots of products, but we'll never kill Stadia. It
Speaker 7:  Was like two months ago too. Like Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  It's, it's not a great situation.
Speaker 5:  No. And it, it causes it like all the things everybody already thinks about
Speaker 5:  Google products, this just makes even worse. But to your point about the
Speaker 5:  games, I do think the one thing that makes me think like Luna might still
Speaker 5:  live is that Amazon potentially against all
Speaker 5:  odds and rational thinking is very invested in making video games
Speaker 5:  and seems to have just continued to try spending money on making
Speaker 5:  video games that people will play. I don't know if it's ever gonna work,
Speaker 5:  but it seems to be trying. Yeah,
Speaker 7:  I think the gap we still need to see them cross is like them to
Speaker 7:  take New World, which is this fairly popular mmo, I
Speaker 7:  don't remember how big it is now, but like I don't think you can play that
Speaker 7:  on Luna yet. Right. I think the the big when that, that will all
Speaker 7:  come together when Amazon makes these big ambitious live service
Speaker 7:  games and then you can just play in with your Luna subscription,
Speaker 7:  Right? I think that's when that will all happen. But will it happen
Speaker 7:  is the real big question mark.
Speaker 6:  I don't think it's gonna happen. Like I just, I fundamentally do not think
Speaker 6:  Luna is going to survive. It's, it's got, here is my, my my
Speaker 6:  my litmus test for a cloud gaming platform and whether or
Speaker 6:  not it's got legs go on Reddit, look up the subreddit for the
Speaker 6:  cloud gaming platform. And how many followers does it have? Stadia has
Speaker 6:  over a hundred thousand.
Speaker 7:  How many does Luna have?
Speaker 6:  Let's see.
Speaker 7:  Reddit, Luna. Oh
Speaker 5:  Man. Can I just say the, the the mood in the Stadia
Speaker 5:  subreddit is so bleak right now.
Speaker 5:  Like it's really just the, the top comment
Speaker 5:  on like, the main thing saying it's shutting down just says sad,
Speaker 5:  but probably the best possible way to shut the service down. It's like,
Speaker 5:  they're not even mad. They're just like, Oh, what a, this thing had like
Speaker 5:  a beautiful life and now it's over and let's just
Speaker 7:  Warning my money back.
Speaker 5:  I guess that's so bleak.
Speaker 7:  But
Speaker 6:  But to the point of like who's actually using these services? Stadia
Speaker 6:  had over, you know, dedicated cloud gaming service, over a
Speaker 6:  hundred thousand followers on subreddit, on the subreddit, Luna Cloud
Speaker 6:  gaming, just like kind of the main subreddit for Amazon Luna.
Speaker 6:  2000,
Speaker 7:  2,700 is a big difference. Sorry.
Speaker 6:  Sorry. Big
Speaker 7:  Difference.
Speaker 6:  Huge difference.
Speaker 7:  Like, yeah,
Speaker 6:  This thing is, this thing is, is not gonna survive. And
Speaker 6:  you look at like the, the, the games are all games that have been out for
Speaker 6:  three or four years. It's like, come on,
Speaker 5:  I should stop reading this Stadia subreddit. Sorry.
Speaker 5:  Somebody's very mad that Stadi is being shut down. And the biggest reason
Speaker 5:  that they're mad is because today is the same day that Hot Wheels Unleash
Speaker 5:  was released. And I was looking forward to playing that on
Speaker 7:  Stadia. Oh man, that's brutal.
Speaker 5:  R i p Hot Wheels unleash. So
Speaker 7:  Sad. Tough,
Speaker 5:  Tough.
Speaker 6:  It's notable though, Jay, how are you feeling about the fact that
Speaker 6:  Stadia, the Stadia subreddit scooped you on,
Speaker 6:  on Stadia being shut
Speaker 7:  Down? You know, I'm glad for them, honestly. They were watching so close.
Speaker 7:  This is, this is their Friday Joy. They love it. Like
Speaker 7:  I'm glad that they, I'm glad they were able to come to terms with
Speaker 7:  this a little bit sooner than everybody else was.
Speaker 6:  They noticed 15 minutes before it was official
Speaker 6:  because they were all, somebody went on the store
Speaker 6:  to buy a Stadia game, presumably. And there was just a sign saying,
Speaker 6:  this is closing in January, 2023. And they were
Speaker 6:  like, Is this real? And there's like a whole flurry of it and then it's like
Speaker 6:  Jay's story and they're like, Yep, it's, it's real.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, it's real. I think what is, it doesn't seem
Speaker 7:  like Google told hardly anybody, like it sounds like
Speaker 7:  Bungee, which makes Destiny. They, they're learned at
Speaker 7:  the same time pretty much how everybody else did. I feel like I've read a
Speaker 7:  couple of developers on Twitter who were not aware of this and
Speaker 7:  so, you know, Lian
Speaker 6:  Studios,
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Like Stadia will be going away, but
Speaker 7:  this creates some collateral damage that developers have to deal with, which
Speaker 7:  kind of sucks for them, especially since they had no warning that this is
Speaker 7:  what they'd be waking up to.
Speaker 6:  I am really curious about, so Larry's Studios does
Speaker 6:  big RPGs. They, they have the new one coming out. Boulders
Speaker 6:  Gate, three people bought the game on Stadia cuz it was like
Speaker 6:  one of the first games announced for Stadia and it was gonna have this really
Speaker 6:  cool exclusive to Stadia feature where it's like, it's Dungeons and
Speaker 6:  Dragons, but a video game. And so you were gonna be able to roll dice,
Speaker 6:  well like streaming it directly to YouTube via Stadia
Speaker 6:  and people could roll the dice for you, like viewers could. And it was gonna
Speaker 6:  be like, okay, that's cool. That's neat.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  All gone just all dead and you go and like
Speaker 6:  Larry Studio has made no comment, they have not talked about this.
Speaker 6:  Boulder's Gate is still not out of beta. It's
Speaker 6:  still not
Speaker 7:  Ly Yeah. I mean they have to pivot so fast. Although is
Speaker 7:  that game coming to other systems? It must be. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. It's totally coming. So it's coming to a lot of systems. But there
Speaker 6:  was like, a big thing was, well we're not being exclusive to Stadia,
Speaker 6:  but we are giving Stadia exclusive
Speaker 6:  features like this dice rolling
Speaker 6:  mechanism that's that's really cool. And oh, you
Speaker 6:  just wasted three years.
Speaker 5:  You can only assume that they're, say as they're saying that Phil Harrison
Speaker 5:  is like standing behind them just like hucking a hundred dollars bills at
Speaker 5:  them, right? Like no, no one in their right mind is making a
Speaker 5:  stu a Stadia exclusive or even like a stadia optimized game without
Speaker 5:  Google. And I think
Speaker 6:  There were Stadia exclusive. There
Speaker 7:  Are, there's very few of them I think like yeah they were, they were there
Speaker 7:  but there were not many of them
Speaker 5:  And you're not doing it unless Google really, really, really makes it worth
Speaker 5:  for awhile. Which is, I think part of has been part of Google's problem is
Speaker 5:  like, it's kind of like meta with the quest, right? Like at some point yeah
Speaker 5:  it just becomes so expensive to fund this thing unless other
Speaker 5:  people buy in and meta seems to so far have the
Speaker 5:  stomach to keep funding vr, but Google seems to have just run out with
Speaker 5:  Stadia.
Speaker 6:  I think it was the same thing we see time and time again with new game
Speaker 6:  consoles where you have to have a lot of established relationships
Speaker 6:  with developers. Yeah. And that was besides the
Speaker 6:  internet problem, the big problem for Stadi was they don't have those
Speaker 6:  relationships Invidia and Microsoft do. That's been their success.
Speaker 6:  Amazon bought those relationships by buying studios and
Speaker 6:  and building their own studios. Stadia was always just like, anybody
Speaker 6:  wanna put a game on a, on a service?
Speaker 7:  We got this great class service.
Speaker 7:  Do
Speaker 6:  You wanna come on over to Stadia
Speaker 7:  Town? It streams from the internet. Everybody did. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Well excuse me, a hundred thousand people in the Stadia subreddit maybe
Speaker 6:  did
Speaker 5:  10,200 of them are online. This is like, this is, this is the
Speaker 5:  most interesting Stadia has ever been in its history, including to Stadia
Speaker 5:  fans. It's very sad the whole this, I cannot
Speaker 5:  get over this subreddit. Everybody is just like, they've gone through the
Speaker 5:  five stages of grief so fast and they're just moving on to like, you know,
Speaker 5:  we had a good run and now Stadia is in a better place and that place is like
Speaker 5:  the landfill along with my controller and it's, it's just, it's just bleak.
Speaker 5:  Game Pass is the big winner here, right? Like this game pass now
Speaker 5:  becomes the, if you want cloud gaming Game Pass is is like
Speaker 5:  the default answer and it kind of was already right, but like this is now
Speaker 5:  even clearer than before.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, it
Speaker 6:  Invidia
Speaker 7:  Invidia too, but I, I mean like for the average
Speaker 7:  consumer to just jump into cloud
Speaker 7:  gaming in any way, shape or form, doing it through Xbox Game Pass
Speaker 7:  is probably the way most people can and
Speaker 7:  may want to do it.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Like I just always liked it as this
Speaker 6:  nice extra, the other people we're not talking about is Sony.
Speaker 6:  Sony does in fact kind of have cloud gaming,
Speaker 7:  Right? Yeah. I mean you can get it
Speaker 6:  Technically
Speaker 7:  You can get it through their PlayStation press. I think it's the
Speaker 7:  ultra, ultra premium tier offers cloud gaming,
Speaker 7:  but like
Speaker 6:  That like $400 a month you to buy a PS five
Speaker 7:  Every month. Yeah. And that's before you can get the VR
Speaker 7:  headset. What I'm curious is what this all
Speaker 7:  means in five to 10 years. Because I feel like there was a big rush of cloud
Speaker 7:  gaming stuff in like the early 2010s and then it went away for a little bit.
Speaker 7:  Yep. And we had this rush a few years ago and this could
Speaker 7:  be the dip of that next next movement and it's like, are we gonna
Speaker 7:  see this again in 10 more years? Like, I don't know.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. My guess would be it's, it seems unlikely that it's gonna go all the
Speaker 5:  way away again just because Microsoft in particular
Speaker 5:  is just so in on this being the long term future
Speaker 5:  with Azure and Xbox and it's like, it is the perfect confluence of
Speaker 5:  everything Microsoft wants to do. Sony
Speaker 7:  Relies on Azure for its cloud gaming. So like
Speaker 7:  you're right that that Microsoft stands to gain quite a bit,
Speaker 7:  especially now that Stadia is going away.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Is Google trying to make this a Google cloud thing? They're trying
Speaker 5:  to like, they've been like white labeling it for folks, right?
Speaker 7:  They have been white labeling it and the blog today they kind of talked about
Speaker 7:  how the technology in Stadia will be utilized in
Speaker 7:  other ways that parts of the company. I mean, I don't
Speaker 7:  think that's gonna mean like at and t can buy
Speaker 7:  Stadia on Google Cloud or whatever. Like
Speaker 7:  I doubt that that's, I I, this to me feels like a big retreat
Speaker 7:  from cloud gaming.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. That definitely means like you can connect the controller to your
Speaker 5:  phone and use it to play. Right? Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Sudoku. Like that's, that's what that means. Like I don't, no one's, I
Speaker 5:  don't know. I would not be on anything else. Yeah. Well
Speaker 6:  I was always curious, did they own, like we know AMD
Speaker 6:  worked with them on the servers they used, Were those servers just always
Speaker 6:  just Google servers that they repurposed to do Stadia Or were those
Speaker 6:  like specific built for Stadia servers?
Speaker 7:  I don't know. I mean you have to imagine that at least the plan was
Speaker 7:  to have built for Stadia servers, but like, I'm not
Speaker 7:  sure about that.
Speaker 5:  Google has talked a lot about the infrastructure behind it. Yeah. And the
Speaker 5:  amount of work that it did. And I would assume in the same way that
Speaker 5:  like building data centers serves gaming, it
Speaker 5:  also serves other things, right? So there's probably a version of stuff that
Speaker 5:  they would've had to build and they're gonna build both the hardware and
Speaker 5:  the software slightly differently to do games than to like run Gmail. But
Speaker 5:  I can't imagine very much of that stuff is just gonna be like
Speaker 5:  mothballed because they're not doing gaming anymore.
Speaker 6:  They're just gonna like switch Google Docs over to it now. Google Docs is
Speaker 6:  just gonna like, Google Doc is gonna be
Speaker 5:  So fast. It's gonna
Speaker 6:  Be incredible.
Speaker 7:  Google Meet is gonna look great you guys. It's gonna be so
Speaker 7:  good. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  This
Speaker 6:  Is how they get Google meet. This is how, this is how it comes.
Speaker 5:  Do your video chat in a Hot Wheels car. Why didn't,
Speaker 7:  Why didn't they put games in Google Meet? This is why Stadia failed. You
Speaker 7:  guys like this is, this is it. We figured it out. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  I think we fixed it. Yeah. Yeah. This is great.
Speaker 7:  Well they have, they got three months to turn that around
Speaker 7:  and unannounced that, you know, Oh, Stadia is coming back as your favorite
Speaker 7:  new meat feature
Speaker 5:  And we're now renaming it. There's gonna be Meat, Meat Original and Meet
Speaker 5:  Stadia. There's gonna be Three Meat. It's gonna be amazing. You're gonna
Speaker 5:  love it. It'll
Speaker 6:  Be, Cause it'll be like the Destiny Edition will be the Hot Wheels
Speaker 6:  edition. No, the Boulder Skate edition.
Speaker 7:  It's gonna be great. I'll track this idea. I don't want it
Speaker 7:  anymore.
Speaker 5:  The absolute best part of that is you just described Mark Zuckerberg's vision
Speaker 5:  for the Metaverse. Like I just, I just want you to know that is, that is
Speaker 5:  what he wants. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Maybe, maybe he's the one. He's gonna be like those servers. What you doing
Speaker 6:  with them? I got some ideas. Get in on this. Mata
Speaker 7:  Meda has their big Quest event soon.
Speaker 7:  You know, big announcement.
Speaker 6:  That's
Speaker 5:  True. That's, yeah, that's in two weeks. We
Speaker 6:  Bought Stadium
Speaker 5:  The amazing Phil Harrison works for
Speaker 7:  Me now. I mean he's, he's, he's worked at Sony and then it was
Speaker 7:  Microsoft and then it was Google. So meta seems like a logical
Speaker 7:  next jump if he, you know, if he wants to work at all the companies,
Speaker 6:  Not Amazon.
Speaker 5:  It's gotta be web three next. It's
Speaker 7:  Gotta I hope not. Oh boy, I
Speaker 5:  Hope not. He's gonna go like run Axi Infinity and, and everything's gonna
Speaker 5:  be insane.
Speaker 7:  Good luck to him. I wish him all the best.
Speaker 5:  We should quickly talk about the other Google News of the week. They had
Speaker 5:  their big search on event this week. Jay, you and I both
Speaker 5:  wrote some stuff you wrote about multi search, which I actually think is
Speaker 5:  like the most interesting new Google product when
Speaker 5:  it comes to search stuff. What, what was new this week? What
Speaker 7:  Happened? So multi search is this pretty cool technology
Speaker 7:  where on your phone you can hold up through the Google app.
Speaker 7:  You use Google Lens to take a photo of something and then you can add
Speaker 7:  text to that photo search. So it's like
Speaker 7:  pointing at a jacket that you like and saying, what if it was in
Speaker 7:  green? And Google will show you a jacket like that that is in
Speaker 7:  green. And so it, it, it's a really neat way, I think to
Speaker 7:  search a little bit differently in ways that just writing out a query in
Speaker 7:  text doesn't let you do that. It's currently available globally in
Speaker 7:  English and it will be expanding to more than 70 different
Speaker 7:  languages in the coming months is, which is what Google announced.
Speaker 6:  Is it gonna understand that I'm very into
Speaker 6:  brands and like I want my designer labels Or is it
Speaker 6:  gonna be like, you can go buy this $2 knockoff at
Speaker 6:  h and m?
Speaker 7:  I don't know that I, I tested it by pointing it
Speaker 7:  at my AirPods Pro case and then I typed
Speaker 7:  green black is what I think I did just to like really see what it would
Speaker 7:  throw up. And it showed me like greenish air, original
Speaker 7:  AirPods case. So like it was okay close. It wasn't perfect, but like, it
Speaker 7:  was definitely like in the right direction of what I was intending.
Speaker 7:  And and of course Google's gonna invest a whole lot into this,
Speaker 7:  unlike other products that we've recently talked about. And so I
Speaker 7:  think you'll get better over time.
Speaker 5:  Alex, I'm just imagining all of your searches where you just like take a
Speaker 5:  picture of somebody's clothes and then you type but make it fashion. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  and that's, that's just, that's that's the Alex Grands way. What's
Speaker 6:  The expensive version?
Speaker 5:  This times 10.
Speaker 7:  Have I not tested
Speaker 5:  That one? But at zero
Speaker 7:  I need the Gucci version. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And Jay, you did forget one part of the step, which is that then Google will
Speaker 5:  send you to Google shopping and say, please, dear God, do not buy this on
Speaker 5:  Amazon.
Speaker 7:  That's right. Yeah. I forgot that step.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, they, they'll they'll beg you to do that. Do they,
Speaker 6:  Do they like blacklist Amazon results?
Speaker 7:  I don't think they're legally allowed to do that
Speaker 5:  But, But can they shove them so far down the page below a bunch of
Speaker 5:  Google shopping results that you never even see them? Yes they can. And they
Speaker 5:  And they will. I bet
Speaker 7:  They will.
Speaker 5:  Alright, we should take a break. We're gonna come back and talk about
Speaker 5:  Amazon because the tech news just keeps coming. Jay, thanks for hanging out.
Speaker 5:  Thanks for having me. We will be right
Speaker 5:  back
Speaker 5:  We're back. Jay's gone. Jen two is here. Hi Jen.
Speaker 5:  Hi. You're in Texas, is this correct? I
Speaker 5:  am
Speaker 10:  In, yes. I'm in Dallas, Texas right now. Having a great
Speaker 10:  time at the CIA trade show, which is the custom integrator,
Speaker 10:  smart home, audio, visual, all that kind of fun stuff.
Speaker 5:  Alex, how aggressive is your fomo right now?
Speaker 6:  It's, it's super aggressive because
Speaker 10:  She was tweeting me places to go and eat while I'm here.
Speaker 6:  She was like, I can't get to any of those. I was like, they only serve cheese
Speaker 6:  and beans and beef. That's it. Do you want healthy
Speaker 6:  food? You're not getting it in Dallas. But yeah,
Speaker 6:  no, I love the show though too. Like Dallas obviously sucks
Speaker 6:  because I'm from Fort Worth and we always call it Dallas because they call
Speaker 6:  us Fort Worth. I like that. And it's big rivalry. So I'm
Speaker 6:  sorry you're in the worst of the two towns of the
Speaker 6:  metroplex. There's more than two towns, but I'm sorry you're in the worst
Speaker 6:  one. But CIA is cool. Like CIA is a, is a show
Speaker 6:  I actually really enjoy because it is all of these custom
Speaker 6:  installers doing all this really weird cool shit. And then
Speaker 6:  like LGS there, Samsung's there. It sounds like Amazon is
Speaker 6:  there showing off arrow stuff. Like there's a lot happening
Speaker 6:  there.
Speaker 10:  Yeah, it's big Google's here. Google's actually sponsored the whole
Speaker 10:  thing. Oh wow. So yeah. Yeah, Google
Speaker 10:  Pro. I guess they're calling it, you know, it's everyone's here.
Speaker 10:  It's a big show but it's a little show like it has, it feels comfortable
Speaker 10:  and small. It's not scary and huge like ces.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it's
Speaker 10:  Intimate. I've been enjoying it.
Speaker 6:  It's an intimate show.
Speaker 10:  Yes. Very intimate. Next time you'll have to come with me.
Speaker 6:  I know we, we'll go together and then we will drive out to Fort Worth to
Speaker 6:  go to get real good food. It's not in Dallas.
Speaker 5:  I just, I'm really hung up on the fact that Fart Worth is a much funnier
Speaker 5:  joke than Dallas.
Speaker 10:  In Dallas
Speaker 5:  And I just, it's like Fort Worth is just very
Speaker 6:  Good. That's something DAAs person would say.
Speaker 10:  Everybody
Speaker 6:  Knows Fort Worth is superior. We have culture. What does Dallas have?
Speaker 6:  They got cdf. That's it. And they only is cd. I think they only get like
Speaker 10:  This year. That's true. Yeah. Yeah, it does not here every year. So
Speaker 10:  we'll have to wait until it comes around again. Well, we'll go together.
Speaker 10:  But there's a lot of cool stuff. The show floor is exciting and there's,
Speaker 10:  it's packed, There's a lot of people here. This is the first big in person
Speaker 10:  show that we've had for a long time, so everyone's excited. There's
Speaker 10:  a, there's a real good vibe here and lots of
Speaker 10:  loud, loud sounds everywhere. Yeah. Everyone playing
Speaker 10:  their speakers as loud as possible. Oh boy. Lots of music
Speaker 10:  And it's, It's a party. It's a party here. Sure.
Speaker 6:  Oh my God, I love it. Well we, we had, we wanted to talk to you today
Speaker 6:  because in addition to being at CIA seeing a lot of the stuff that's happening
Speaker 6:  at the show, Amazon also had this massive event this week and
Speaker 6:  I feel like you were blogging all week to cover this event.
Speaker 6:  A lot of stuff happened. Kinda kinda walk me through
Speaker 6:  some of the, walk us through some of the stuff that happened,
Speaker 10:  Right? Yeah. So big event. Not actually as
Speaker 10:  big as Amazon has done in the past. We've sometimes
Speaker 10:  had, you know, 72 product announcements in five minutes
Speaker 10:  but they still managed to cra cram a lot in and
Speaker 10:  press for David Li's diction at that speed. He does well. Yeah,
Speaker 10:  Very impressed. But yeah, well the most important, most exciting thing
Speaker 10:  I'm sure, and I can't believe you haven't mentioned this yet, if you've
Speaker 10:  been on the Vergecast for like more than two seconds, is that Kindle now
Speaker 10:  comes with a stylist.
Speaker 5:  We've been waiting as long as we could. I'm very proud of Alex for making
Speaker 5:  it this long and I think at this point we have waited long enough that
Speaker 5:  Alex, we, we've reserved three hours for you to just talk about the
Speaker 5:  Kindle.
Speaker 6:  I know there's a very special episode. I was like emergency
Speaker 6:  meeting. We need a four hour verge cast just so I can talk about
Speaker 6:  this. Yeah, no the Kindle was definitely, I think
Speaker 6:  for me the most exciting thing that came out of this because this is their
Speaker 6:  10.2 inch, 300 PPI Kindle that
Speaker 6:  you can also write on. It is not the first product that's
Speaker 6:  a 10 inch writing ink
Speaker 6:  tablet, not buy a long shot. Remarkable. Obviously has
Speaker 6:  done two of these already and we're waiting for a third. Books is out
Speaker 6:  there, Big mes out there. We've got a lot of
Speaker 6:  companies doing this. But this is Amazon and Amazon is like the biggest,
Speaker 6:  biggest e ink producer in the United States. Like they're the only ones
Speaker 6:  really doing it at the scale. Cobo is way, way, way behind them. They sell
Speaker 6:  the most e-readers in America. So this is a huge, huge
Speaker 6:  deal because like they're kind of the defacto e-reader in the
Speaker 6:  United States, which means this is now the defacto e ink
Speaker 6:  writing tablet thing in the US Maybe I worry.
Speaker 10:  Well and they were showing off little, you know, how you could use it to
Speaker 10:  sort of annotate while you're reading stories to your children
Speaker 10:  or add notes when you are doing your research. I mean I can see a
Speaker 10:  lot of use cases for this. I mean it's expensive though.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it's, it's actually, it's interesting because the prices,
Speaker 6:  it's kind of right between the remarkable and, and my personal favorite of
Speaker 6:  these devices, which is the really log of obnoxious name. I'm so
Speaker 6:  sorry. The Onyx books spelled with an
Speaker 6:  X. Yeah. Nova Air
Speaker 6:  two catchy.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Rolls right off the tongue. That one. Yeah. Hold
Speaker 6:  On. You didn't let me finish. Oh my God. Plus which is,
Speaker 6:  which is another 10.3 inch another, you know, 10 plus
Speaker 6:  inch device, Same weight pretty much as, as the new
Speaker 6:  Amazon one, same size, same form with
Speaker 6:  the, with the, the handle on the side, all of the same
Speaker 6:  stuff. But it has Android on it. So I can also do
Speaker 6:  like Barn and Noble Nook or the Cobo e-Reader or Libby.
Speaker 6:  Right. This is very explicitly for writing
Speaker 6:  and reading in Amazon's ecosystem.
Speaker 10:  Yeah, yeah. Which is a large ecosystem but definitely
Speaker 10:  limits the wider appeal
Speaker 6:  For, and I think for some people, for myself I try to, I've been trying to
Speaker 6:  like cut back on the stuff I used in Amazon cause I'm like eh, how
Speaker 6:  great things are ethically sometimes.
Speaker 5:  But you're like amped about using a tablet from a company no
Speaker 5:  one has ever heard of
Speaker 6:  In China that
Speaker 5:  Where
Speaker 6:  I have to like do weird hats.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, right. Of mysterious
Speaker 6:  To like activate the place store. I am not
Speaker 6:  consistent in my, my moral code.
Speaker 6:  Let's, let's be clear on that.
Speaker 10:  That's
Speaker 6:  Famous. Amazon ran it with Android. I'd probably be like buy five.
Speaker 5:  My, my big theory about this is it is going to be like a, just a
Speaker 5:  monster slam dunk. Huge success a hundred percent instantly. Like
Speaker 5:  if it's good and we've only seen demos and stuff, but
Speaker 5:  like the, the closest thing I got to a demo is I was on a call with one of
Speaker 5:  the execs on the Kindle team and he held his up to the
Speaker 5:  webcam and wrote Hi David on it and it looked really good. Oh. But that
Speaker 5:  is the extent of which, like that's the only in the wild. That's
Speaker 10:  All you
Speaker 5:  Saw Kindle scribe I've actually seen. But if this thing is good, it's gonna
Speaker 5:  be a gigantic success because it's like, it's the kind of thing a
Speaker 5:  lot of people want, especially like business people, which I thought was
Speaker 5:  really interesting. Like they make, they're making a big pitch for this is
Speaker 5:  like, it's a way to take meeting notes. You can have to-do lists on it.
Speaker 5:  It's like a thing to bring into the room with you for business meetings,
Speaker 5:  which is like classic Amazon way of thinking about things. But I think
Speaker 5:  it's, if it's, if it's not bad, I think it's gonna be a huge
Speaker 5:  hit and it might be bad.
Speaker 6:  I, I like, I think it's, I think it will absolutely be a hit one because
Speaker 6:  it's, it's the first really big e-reader that, that Amazon's done
Speaker 6:  since what the dx They haven't had a big one. Yeah, it's like a decade. And
Speaker 6:  people love that thing. People want a big e-reader. Like that's,
Speaker 6:  that's a, that's a common complaint is why are they so small? I want like
Speaker 6:  a big screen so I can look at it from this far so I don't have to put on
Speaker 6:  reading glasses or anything like that. I can just read it. And so one,
Speaker 6:  it's really big and two it can write and if they can get the writing down,
Speaker 6:  but that's hard to do. It took remarkable long, long time to do it and a
Speaker 6:  lot of the other people in the space have really struggled with it. Books
Speaker 6:  is a great example. Like the first few miserable, there's
Speaker 6:  one that I'll write on and feel even remotely Okay. Writing
Speaker 6:  on and Remarkable has kind of a crummy ui.
Speaker 6:  It's the, the experience outside of the actual writing, which is wonderful,
Speaker 6:  is kind of crummy. And so if they can get those things down,
Speaker 6:  like that's a big success.
Speaker 5:  I think that's right. Yeah.
Speaker 10:  Yeah. I'm excited to try it. I I, I have, I upgraded to the
Speaker 10:  paper white from the original Kindle recently, so I'm
Speaker 10:  really behind the curve. So yeah, I'm
Speaker 5:  Wait like the, like the original like with a keyboard Kindle
Speaker 6:  That, that's incredible.
Speaker 10:  It was old. I don't think it had a
Speaker 10:  keyboard.
Speaker 5:  Okay.
Speaker 10:  But it was very old.
Speaker 5:  That's very
Speaker 10:  Important. Still though, this is what's so good about the Kindles though,
Speaker 10:  you know, you don't need to upgrade. It's not like a phone that you have
Speaker 10:  to do it every, every or feel compelled. You don't have
Speaker 10:  to to upgrade every year or two years. I mean, you read a
Speaker 10:  book on the Kindle, it still works that I only upgraded because I
Speaker 10:  like, I needed the bigger size cuz you know, I'm getting old. Yeah. Needed
Speaker 10:  bigger fonts. But yeah, I'm excited to try
Speaker 10:  it.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, it's
Speaker 10:  But you know, Amazon did announce a lot of
Speaker 10:  stuff. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  They had a lot of stuff.
Speaker 10:  Do we have any more Kindle fields
Speaker 5:  Or? No, we'll have more Kindle fields next week. We have lots more Kindle
Speaker 5:  stuff
Speaker 6:  To do. Like I think I'll, I'm like forcing David
Speaker 6:  to do an entire special episode about the Kindle. So, so I think we can save
Speaker 6:  a lot of those feelings for future day. But yeah, there was a lot of
Speaker 6:  other stuff there. We got a lot of like router news. We got
Speaker 6:  Matter news. News that matters. I'm sorry,
Speaker 10:  News
Speaker 6:  I had to pun.
Speaker 10:  Well the, Yes, It's, it's just, it's like they
Speaker 10:  made that name, they chose that name because they're like The Verge is gonna
Speaker 10:  have so much fun with this name with all their puns.
Speaker 10:  But yes, it was so Amazon they started out with their same
Speaker 10:  shtick that they do every year. The ambient smart home, which is
Speaker 10:  Amazon, your smart home will work without a smartphone. That's essentially
Speaker 10:  what Amazon is saying because who doesn't have a smartphone?
Speaker 10:  Amazon. So you need to be able to use to control your home
Speaker 10:  without needing a smartphone. I am out totally on board with this though.
Speaker 10:  I do not like using a smartphone to control my home. So I'm good with that.
Speaker 10:  And the Ambient Smart home is what Amazon is trying to move. That's its
Speaker 10:  vision that it's bringing us to in its smart home
Speaker 10:  sensors, devices that react
Speaker 10:  intuitively hunches. I mean they used the, I
Speaker 10:  think personalization was kind of a big focus of this.
Speaker 10:  They've got new features for routines that can be
Speaker 10:  personalized. So when you say good morning to Alexa in the morning, it will
Speaker 10:  tell you your personal calendar events and your
Speaker 10:  traffic rather than say your husbands or your spouses. So it
Speaker 10:  those, there's lots of small sort of updates to how Alexa works
Speaker 10:  in the smart home.
Speaker 6:  Jen had a good run.
Speaker 5:  What I was gonna say did, did
Speaker 10:  You lose
Speaker 5:  Me? Not allowed to talk about Amazon. Oh you're back. You're asked you for
Speaker 5:  a second.
Speaker 10:  You lost me. Sorry. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  We heard, we heard your husband or your spouse and then you were gone.
Speaker 10:  Okay. That was okay. All right. So yes, Amazon
Speaker 10:  is trying to get in on the personalization front, which is, which
Speaker 10:  is a good angle to go for because you know most homes, they're a lot,
Speaker 10:  they're more than one person and the smart home does not work well
Speaker 10:  for more than one person right now, especially my family will
Speaker 10:  attest to that cuz they, they get very frustrated. But that, you know,
Speaker 10:  I'm a use ca I'm a, I'm a unique use case. I know I have
Speaker 10:  like all four voice assistant. I
Speaker 6:  Was gonna say, how many times are you act accidentally like turned all
Speaker 6:  the lights off on somebody in your home often just like plunge someone
Speaker 6:  in darkness possibly in a bathroom situation?
Speaker 10:  Well the biggest problem I have, and I wish someone could solve this for
Speaker 10:  me and this is a personalization issue, my husband is a firefighter
Speaker 10:  paramedic so he works shifts, which means I, if I have
Speaker 10:  any kind of automations or routines that work every day,
Speaker 10:  that is not good for someone that's trying to sleep in the middle of the
Speaker 10:  day and you can't set something for every third day. It just
Speaker 10:  doesn't exist. And that's a solution I would love to see. I want a button
Speaker 10:  that I can just press and this is something you can now do with Amazon.
Speaker 10:  They introduce buttons, we can get to that. They used to have buttons, they
Speaker 10:  took them away. Now they brought them back. But you, I would love a button
Speaker 10:  I could press it just turns off all my automations just shuts it all
Speaker 10:  down because I, you know it he, I get yelled
Speaker 10:  at Jenny, there's music playing, turn the
Speaker 10:  light off.
Speaker 6:  He's just trying to sleep and you're like, no
Speaker 5:  They did add some scheduling there. There were some new scheduling stuff
Speaker 5:  right?
Speaker 10:  Yeah, there were quite a few. And these
Speaker 10:  enhancements aren't live now. They're coming later. There was a lot of coming
Speaker 10:  soon coming shortly and coming soon and not coming this
Speaker 10:  year. Which I think was very specific
Speaker 10:  wording. But yes there was some scheduling updates. So you can now say
Speaker 10:  to Alexa, Sorry am I setting off everyone's devices? You know turn, lock
Speaker 10:  the front door in an hour or turn the lights off in 15
Speaker 10:  minutes. And that's a really nice feature to have and that could be yeah
Speaker 10:  that, that would help. That might help my situation a little bit. But the
Speaker 10:  biggest news, the thing I was most excited about and I actually got to,
Speaker 10:  I didn't get to see the Echos here, but they have new
Speaker 10:  echo dots and they're going to be mesh wifi
Speaker 10:  extenders. Now this is only very exciting if you already have an arrow
Speaker 10:  mesh network. It's only gonna work with Arrow. But the concept is
Speaker 10:  a good one and you know, we may see it trickle down to
Speaker 10:  other manufacturers that also have smart home devices and
Speaker 10:  routers Google. So, you know, We'll I like the idea
Speaker 10:  Smart home needs connectivity and Amazon realizes we
Speaker 10:  need to bathe your home in wifi and
Speaker 10:  aero devices whilst less expensive than they used to be are an investment.
Speaker 10:  And this way you've already got uni needed by one and if you have
Speaker 10:  a couple echo speakers already in your house, you are extending your, your
Speaker 10:  range. And it's not like super extending. Like it's not super fast wifi,
Speaker 10:  it's not, you're not gonna get the sick wifi six
Speaker 10:  gig. So areas wifi six has great
Speaker 10:  speeds if you get those speeds into your home. But most people
Speaker 10:  don't. Right. You know, most people aren't on gig speed internet. This gets
Speaker 10:  you a hundred megabits, which you know is more than enough for streaming
Speaker 10:  would help connect say your camera if you have a camera on the side of your
Speaker 10:  house. So I think this is a really good new feature because not
Speaker 10:  only is it in the Echo dot that they announced, which was the new Echo dot
Speaker 10:  and echo dot clock, which is the fifth generation, but it's also gonna be
Speaker 10:  enabled on the existing Echo dot, which is the fourth
Speaker 10:  generation Echo dot with clock and the existing Echo fourth
Speaker 10:  generation speaker. So if you have Arrow mesh, you've now
Speaker 10:  got so
Speaker 6:  So, but these are all like products that are like $50, a hundred dollars,
Speaker 6:  like these are are cheap. Whereas an era is usually like $200.
Speaker 6:  This is like a big kind of price cut to extend your
Speaker 6:  wifi.
Speaker 10:  Yes, yes. And that's what's, I mean you need good wifi for a smart
Speaker 10:  home to work. You need good wifi for the ambient Smart Home. And so it really
Speaker 10:  is in the, in the company's best interest to make sure our am our wifi
Speaker 10:  is good And this is, you know, why Ring ended up with its ring
Speaker 10:  alarm Pro with a built in era because so many
Speaker 10:  problems consumers have with Ring video doorbells are connectivity
Speaker 10:  based and you know, Ring can't, it's, it's too hard for them to sort of
Speaker 10:  troubleshoot that. And so, you know, if you, you have strong wifi, you get
Speaker 10:  a strong smart home and you know, there's a few other really
Speaker 10:  interesting upgrades for the echo dots,
Speaker 10:  especially the Echo Dot with clock is now gonna have a
Speaker 10:  scrolling l e d display, which I think is really fun. I love, yeah I love
Speaker 10:  l e d displays so you can have your song title scrolling along,
Speaker 10:  maybe your next calendar appointment. It's kind of a nice way of
Speaker 10:  having information without having to have a screen in your face, which I'm,
Speaker 10:  I'm all for cuz there's too many screens in my world.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I think, I think it's very cool and I think to me the the like
Speaker 5:  the era thing is very clever to me because like we should be clear it's not
Speaker 5:  turning your echo dot into an era, right? Like it is not
Speaker 10:  No it's not an access point. No. It's a good old fashioned wifi
Speaker 10:  extender like you used to plug into, you know those terrible ones you used
Speaker 10:  to plug in. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Exactly. Yeah. That's what it's doing. So it's like you're gonna get more
Speaker 5:  latency, you're gonna get slower speeds, but what it is going to do is it's
Speaker 5:  gonna put wifi in places you might not have otherwise had wifi and that
Speaker 5:  alone is awesome. And I think that kind of thing is gonna be
Speaker 5:  super useful to tons of people. But it, and it is, especially for Amazon,
Speaker 5:  which is like very invested like you were saying in the idea that everything
Speaker 5:  in my house should be able to connect to a network. It makes that possible
Speaker 5:  in a way I think is very cool. And I really like the idea, like it sounds
Speaker 5:  like, and correct me if I'm wrong, the technology behind that is not
Speaker 5:  terribly sophisticated. It's just Amazon figuring out how to basically reuse
Speaker 5:  a thing that has wifi capabilities and so in theory this could be much more
Speaker 5:  pervasive even than just putting it in the Echo dot. Right?
Speaker 10:  Yeah. So I spoke to Nick Weaver who's the CEO of Arrow and
Speaker 10:  he said yes it's definitely something. So the concept is called I Built
Speaker 10:  In and he said they're looking at other ways of extending that
Speaker 10:  they, I asked about the echo shows and he said yes, that's definitely something
Speaker 10:  we are considering. He says more, it's a little bit more complicated but
Speaker 10:  it's possible. And yeah, it's all done over a software firmware update.
Speaker 10:  So it's not something you're gonna have to buy new hardware for. And this
Speaker 10:  is something the smart home's been really bad about, you know, again, like
Speaker 10:  the smartphone every two years buy a new smart thermostat, you know, that's
Speaker 10:  not the way the smart homes should work. Right. So yeah,
Speaker 10:  I think I love seeing upgrade into existing devices in,
Speaker 10:  in our home and that's another that ERO came out with. They now are gonna
Speaker 10:  have a new capability for internet backup.
Speaker 10:  So your wifi goes down because say Comcast
Speaker 10:  cut someone, cut a cable somewhere, you can actually have your entire
Speaker 10:  network so everything that's on your network default over to your mobile
Speaker 10:  hotspot from your smartphone. Or if you have another
Speaker 10:  wifi network in your home, some people have to, or maybe
Speaker 10:  you can steal your neighbor's wifi and so you can
Speaker 10:  keep everything up and running, which is a feature they introduced
Speaker 10:  with the ring alarm pro last year. It's, you know, when I tried it, my
Speaker 10:  smart home kind of killed it because I had so many
Speaker 10:  things. But it's a good feature to have, especially
Speaker 10:  when everyone's at home and you've gotta do both my kids are home today
Speaker 10:  and e-learning days because there's a hurricane and they need to do their
Speaker 10:  schoolwork, but if the, if the wifi went down, they'd have a backup. And
Speaker 10:  so I think that's another good feature that now is coming to any arrow.
Speaker 10:  So I really love this backwards up, you know, backwards compatibility for
Speaker 10:  devices.
Speaker 5:  It really does feel like we're, we're heading in the direction of Amazon
Speaker 5:  eventually just being like, we will be your isp, we'll give you internet
Speaker 5:  for free. We will run cables to your house. Just please don't let your
Speaker 5:  smart home go offline. Which has become, it's like the, the
Speaker 5:  theme of this episode is like, if only our internet connections were better,
Speaker 5:  right? Like wouldn't the world be a magical place? And it, it's really, it's
Speaker 5:  just really interesting to see Amazon in particular basically like hack
Speaker 5:  around every edge it can to try to find ways to make sure your
Speaker 5:  stuff doesn't go offline because like you just see it all the time and there's
Speaker 5:  like the, I I always think about the horror stories people have about like
Speaker 5:  when, when the Nest services go down and all of a sudden your like
Speaker 5:  house plunges to freezing and it's like, it just takes so little
Speaker 5:  for this stuff to fall apart in these really spectacular ways. And if you're
Speaker 5:  Amazon, you have to do absolutely everything you can to make sure that that
Speaker 5:  doesn't happen and it's gonna, like that fight is gonna get messy
Speaker 5:  cuz our internet sucks real bad everywhere.
Speaker 6:  Yeah,
Speaker 10:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  The other day my wifi died or my, my internet died
Speaker 6:  and I just, I was trying to go to bed and I usually use like an automation
Speaker 6:  to go to bed and I was like, just couldn't get my lights to turn off. I was
Speaker 6:  like, I just wanna sleep now.
Speaker 6:  Switches. What is the stacking, Oh
Speaker 10:  You finished going
Speaker 6:  Dare. It was like very upset.
Speaker 5:  You just slipped at the lights on, didn't you be honest? You just slipped
Speaker 5:  at the lights on?
Speaker 6:  No, I have, I have a Phillips hu little light
Speaker 6:  switch in the other room and that I guess worked over local network, so that
Speaker 6:  one still worked. It didn't need to call out, so I got it turned
Speaker 6:  my lights off. Did I have to get outta bed? Yes,
Speaker 10:  Yes. Really well speaking of sleep, Amazon
Speaker 10:  is gonna try and help you sleep with their new halo rise. So
Speaker 10:  I'm not that excited about this product, but, but because there's a lot
Speaker 10:  already out there that offer this capability, but it's, it's
Speaker 10:  definitely something, they've done a nice job. There's no cameras,
Speaker 10:  there's no microphone, there's no speakers. So for anyone that doesn't
Speaker 10:  want to put any of those things by their bed, which is, you know, the large
Speaker 10:  majority of us, it's a good option. And I
Speaker 10:  like, I'm, I'm a big proponent and I'm excited about circadian
Speaker 10:  lighting, you know, lighting that helps you wind down or helps you wake
Speaker 10:  up and so that's it. It takes from the Phillips lamp that
Speaker 10:  Phillips has a lamp that is very similar looking to this that will,
Speaker 10:  you know, the light will come on gradually to wake you up in the morning
Speaker 10:  and apparently there's some algorithm and learning that will actually figure
Speaker 10:  out when you should wake up the best time to wake you up. So that'll
Speaker 10:  be interesting to try out. Otherwise it has a lot in common with the Google
Speaker 10:  Nest hub, which has the sleep sensing. Yeah, it
Speaker 10:  uses, I don't think they've specifically said, but I, I think it uses
Speaker 10:  some sort of ultrasound detection to see how your breathing rate
Speaker 10:  and to track your sleep. Right.
Speaker 6:  They said it was gonna use ultrasound to like kind of bounce off of you
Speaker 6:  to figure out where you are and determine if it's you, if
Speaker 6:  it's somebody else in the bed, if it's a pet that's some fancy
Speaker 6:  ultrasound
Speaker 10:  And to do sleep tracking so you don't have to wear a wrist fan or
Speaker 10:  Yeah, basically they don't, you know, you don't have to wear a
Speaker 6:  Wristband, anything in your bed with you. Like no
Speaker 6:  wearables. I thought it was kind of an interesting thing, but I did think
Speaker 6:  it was also weird that they're like, you know, we're not gonna put a microphone
Speaker 6:  in it. We're not gonna put a camera in it, but we are still
Speaker 6:  going to track your entire body and how your body
Speaker 6:  moves in the bed. So we are still doing the
Speaker 6:  tracking,
Speaker 5:  But not in a creepy way. Super normal, but
Speaker 6:  In a, in a, like in somehow, like, not a creepy way, but a
Speaker 6:  very creepy, like it was just a weird, an interesting way I think, but
Speaker 6:  yeah, that's, that's wild.
Speaker 10:  I still think they need, someone needs to come up with a smart alarm clock
Speaker 10:  that doesn't rely on a battery. Cuz I mean it does have a backup
Speaker 10:  battery. It doesn't rely on hardwired power because I've written about this,
Speaker 10:  but my, back to my husband who's gonna be so mad about me talking about
Speaker 10:  him so much, he will not use
Speaker 10:  any smart alarm clock I've tried to get him to use because he doesn't trust
Speaker 10:  that it's gonna wake him up because what if the power goes out
Speaker 10:  and you, you know, old fashioned battery, old alarm clocks always have
Speaker 10:  batteries in like, at least his did and you just stick it on your bedside
Speaker 10:  table and it always worked or it, it plugged in but it had a battery backup.
Speaker 10:  But none, you can't get smart alarm clock with a battery backup, which I
Speaker 10:  think is a fail. I would've, that's the one thing I was listening when they
Speaker 10:  announced this. It's like, come on, tell me it's got a battery in it.
Speaker 6:  No. Like, nope. Yeah, it tracks the, it also like tracks
Speaker 6:  the humidity in the room, the temperature in the room, the amount of light
Speaker 6:  in the room, which you can go get a thing at a Walmart or
Speaker 6:  a Target that does almost all of that for about $12. It does. That
Speaker 6:  runs off a battery. Like doesn't shine a light in your face. Yeah. And
Speaker 6:  no when to wake you up
Speaker 10:  To wake you up.
Speaker 6:  So,
Speaker 10:  Well, and the other neat thing here, and this goes to the ambient Smart
Speaker 10:  home again and I I I was impressed with this is when it senses that you've
Speaker 10:  woken up, it can run your good morning routine so you don't even have to
Speaker 10:  say anything or do anything. And, and that's a really nice touch. I dunno
Speaker 10:  how it, it's gotta be tricky there though because if it gets it wrong
Speaker 10:  and wakes you up, you can be really mad.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. If it does that once you're, you're yeah,
Speaker 10:  Hose it's going in the trash.
Speaker 5:  I will say, Jen, the, the next thing we need to do is we need to start slowly
Speaker 5:  sabotaging your husband's alarm clock. That's the move here is
Speaker 5:  like maybe just pour a little water on it maybe just
Speaker 5:  to like, like you don't want it to like totally break just slowly over the
Speaker 5:  course of a week, kind of fall apart and then you can start making the case
Speaker 5:  for all of your cool technical stuff. But I did wonder
Speaker 5:  the halo rise, the more I think about it, the weirder it strikes me
Speaker 5:  as a thing for Amazon to even do, like to
Speaker 5:  your point, there's a ton of these out there. The idea of like a, a light
Speaker 5:  that wakes you up based on the right time to wake you up is not particularly
Speaker 5:  like new or novel. People who want it can get it and it
Speaker 5:  doesn't, it's not really, it's not a way to talk to Alexa.
Speaker 5:  It's not a speaker, it's just, it's just like a, a
Speaker 5:  thing. I don't like What's your sense of why this is worth doing
Speaker 5:  for Amazon?
Speaker 10:  Well I think it, the last point that we just discussed is probably where
Speaker 10:  it's coming from, helping to kind of integrate it, the routines into
Speaker 10:  your sleep. So sleep was one area they hadn't really got their
Speaker 10:  wearables haven't, don't seem to have taken off. Nope. Nope. Not
Speaker 10:  popular. And people don't like putting echoes by their
Speaker 10:  bed because they have cameras in them. The echo dot with clock was
Speaker 10:  kind of the solution there and that has ultrasound motion sensing. So
Speaker 10:  you could use that. They could have, I, I'm surprised they didn't work somehow
Speaker 10:  work that into the new echo dots in the way that Google Nest
Speaker 10:  has done with its hub. But I, I feel like this is kind of
Speaker 10:  a bit of a like me too, not me too. That's the wrong word.
Speaker 10:  Samesies. You know, we've gotta have one too
Speaker 10:  because our, because our competition has it, it's
Speaker 10:  very similar in functionality to the Google Nest hub Max,
Speaker 10:  which is good. Not Max, sorry, Google Nest hub without the camera.
Speaker 10:  And actually my husband does like that. He likes the sleep tracking for
Speaker 10:  that one. Okay. That was the one he allowed to have on his bedside for more
Speaker 10:  than a week. But it doesn't, not having a
Speaker 10:  microphone means it can't track snoring. Which is is
Speaker 10:  something quite key I think for sleep, for good sleep habit is to
Speaker 10:  understand if you are having sort of respiratory issues at night, that can
Speaker 10:  be one of the biggest issues from a, from preventing you from having a good
Speaker 10:  night's sleep. And I don't think this is gonna help with that at all. So
Speaker 10:  it, it's, yeah like I said, it seems a bit like they felt like they
Speaker 10:  needed a space on your bedside tables. They needed That's fair. They didn't
Speaker 10:  want it to go somewhere else.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, no, I buy that and I think it's, it's going to be really interesting
Speaker 5:  to see Amazon try to start to put some of that stuff
Speaker 5:  back into devices like this. Cuz I, I'm just assuming that
Speaker 5:  like V2 or V3 of something like the halo rise will start to have
Speaker 5:  speakers and microphones and more sensors and start to do some of that other
Speaker 5:  stuff and I think Amazon is starting to get very good at just like sort of
Speaker 5:  slowly normalizing these things into people's worlds. But I still feel
Speaker 5:  like I don't, I don't know about either of you, but like I don't have
Speaker 5:  just totally anti microphones on the bedside table. No
Speaker 5:  cameras on the bedside table, no speakers on the bedside table. I have one
Speaker 5:  of those old Casper lights that they made for like 15 minutes
Speaker 5:  before Casper stopped being a good business. I love that thing. It's awesome.
Speaker 10:  Yeah, it is
Speaker 5:  Great. And then my phone, which is of course all of those things and I'm
Speaker 5:  sure un undo all of the privacy concerns that I'm trying to solve, but it,
Speaker 5:  it does feel like the bedroom definitely feels like it, it's gonna be the
Speaker 5:  hardest for any of these companies to make real
Speaker 5:  moves inside of. So I guess if, if Amazon can do it here, I think you're
Speaker 5:  right. They're in a pretty powerful spot. I
Speaker 6:  Think it's gonna be, I think it's always gonna be a challenge, right?
Speaker 10:  Well they are hampered by, you know, by that PR angle people
Speaker 10:  don't want Amazon tracking them. So Yeah,
Speaker 10:  it is, it, it's a tough one and I think,
Speaker 10:  I'm not sure this product's gonna hang around honestly I don't know that
Speaker 10:  we'll see a version two or a version three. I feel like this is kind of
Speaker 10:  maybe something they started developing a while ago and they're like, we
Speaker 10:  don't have much else. Let throw this one in.
Speaker 10:  Yeah,
Speaker 6:  Just a little Tesla balloon. Pretty
Speaker 5:  Quiet. There are a lot of Amazon products. Yeah,
Speaker 10:  I mean we have, so there is the glow lamp they have which is similar so
Speaker 10:  the Casper Glow that you can put on your bedside table and can wake you
Speaker 10:  up gently. It doesn't have the smarts that this does in terms of
Speaker 10:  tracking your sleep. But they have other devices that you know you could
Speaker 10:  use that don't have speakers and cameras that give you light on your bedside
Speaker 10:  table. I dunno. And I just, the design of this one too is it's
Speaker 10:  doesn't really fit in with the whole kind of Amazon Echo
Speaker 10:  ecosystem but we'll see. See if it might be a huge hit, who's gonna,
Speaker 10:  who's testing it out? I dunno who's gonna review it. I guess that's probably
Speaker 10:  gonna be me.
Speaker 5:  I don't know. Sounds like not, I don't know. We'll see if your husband the
Speaker 5:  last that
Speaker 6:  Yeah. You, your husband or Victoria like just all fighting
Speaker 6:  over it. Yes. Or not fighting over it.
Speaker 5:  It is a useful reminder that Amazon's product strategy is basically to like
Speaker 5:  make everything it can think of. Yeah. Make 60 of them and then put it
Speaker 5:  on sale on amazon.com and just sort of see what happens. Yeah. So it's like
Speaker 5:  all of this comes with like the gigantic grain of salt with the possible
Speaker 5:  exception of like the Echo dot, which I suspect they know they will sell
Speaker 5:  an awful lot of that. All of this is just like, see what happens. There's
Speaker 6:  Also the TVs though, right? They they just, they announced a TV this
Speaker 6:  week. Yeah, the 4K one that's ostensibly like
Speaker 6:  the frame from Samsung because it lets you put pictures on your
Speaker 6:  wall and it'll just like stay on all the time. But it doesn't look like
Speaker 6:  a frame. It is just a tv. Like people
Speaker 6:  will still look,
Speaker 5:  It's just called leaving your TV on like what I, I don't understand this
Speaker 5:  at all.
Speaker 10:  Yeah, it's not,
Speaker 5:  You're just leaving your TV on. I can do that already.
Speaker 10:  Yeah, it, it doesn't really have the same aesthetic as the Frame. It doesn't
Speaker 10:  have that nice kind of matte look but it is essentially a huge
Speaker 10:  echo show on your wall now because it has all of the Alexa
Speaker 10:  capabilities and built in and the widgets that you got
Speaker 10:  on the new Echo show 15, which has now become a TV
Speaker 10:  because they've turned that in. You can now use Fire TV on the Echo Show
Speaker 10:  15. So those two, the fire TV products to sort
Speaker 10:  of, and it makes sense to put Fire TV on the Echo Show 15, you could
Speaker 10:  even put it on the Echo Show eight. I mean I try and watch
Speaker 10:  TV on shows on that screen. It's not a terrible experience
Speaker 10:  but it's, Amazon has had a very limited support
Speaker 10:  for video streaming services on any of its devices other than the
Speaker 10:  15. So I was excited to see Fire TV built into that. But
Speaker 10:  this obviously is an echo, it's like an echo show on your wall for
Speaker 10:  with the tv, but it's not a touchscreen. So you use this remote
Speaker 10:  and actually the remote I was most excited about. I thought the new remote
Speaker 10:  really was really quite interesting. Well it,
Speaker 5:  It's, I totally agree. I'm so glad you said
Speaker 10:  That. Well why do you like it? You tell us because
Speaker 6:  You guys really love it. Peacock and Direct tv,
Speaker 6:  like you needed those buttons at the bottom.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, well a, I love a good remote just at all times
Speaker 5:  love a good remote and b, I think they, they did a
Speaker 5:  couple of things that I thought were very smart. One is to have like a, a
Speaker 5:  big Alexa button, right? But the other is to like, they seem to have imagined
Speaker 5:  this as a thing that you both like use sitting
Speaker 5:  in front of your TV but also maybe sort of carry into the kitchen while you're
Speaker 5:  doing stuff. Like you can program routines into wizard and two of the
Speaker 5:  buttons I think are there for you to pick, to have routines
Speaker 10:  And that's genius. I mean and they should be doing that with more,
Speaker 10:  we need more buttons. Totally. And that's something else they've announced
Speaker 10:  that we alluded to earlier. So they used to have these really cool
Speaker 10:  buttons. Do you remember the Echo buttons? Yes. You could use them to like
Speaker 10:  play Jeopardy. They were so far and I used, I get emails
Speaker 10:  regularly from readers saying why did they take those away cuz they discontinued
Speaker 10:  them and you can't use them anymore. And they were Bluetooth, so they were
Speaker 10:  kind of flaky, but now they're introducing compatibility with
Speaker 10:  more wireless access is I think is what is the phrase that they
Speaker 10:  used. But I don't know what, they haven't given us any specific models,
Speaker 10:  but being able to press a button and have one of your smart home
Speaker 10:  routines run is, you know, well they don't have a smartphone so
Speaker 10:  they need buttons back to that point. And it's a nice experience. Like if
Speaker 10:  you sit down with your remote in front of your tv rather than having to
Speaker 10:  say, Hey Alexa, run movie time and maybe shout because
Speaker 10:  it didn't hear you properly. You just press your button. So I,
Speaker 10:  I think that's a nice experience. I, I'm here. Well one of the things I'm
Speaker 10:  going to see while I'm here at CIA is a custom, fancy, high
Speaker 10:  end remote that you can't buy unless you're a custom integrator and
Speaker 10:  spending a lot of money on your home. But it's, it run, it
Speaker 10:  runs Google Android on the remote. So, and you can
Speaker 10:  control your whole smart home from it. It's by Ava. Ava
Speaker 10:  and I wanna go look at it because I wanna write a piece about how you can
Speaker 10:  create the best smart home remote so someone will go and, and do it because
Speaker 10:  since we lost the lottery tech harmony, we have no, there is nothing good.
Speaker 10:  There are no good solutions.
Speaker 5:  I agree. The world needs more remotes.
Speaker 6:  Thank you for also being upset about the harmony remote. I still
Speaker 6:  use mine. I've got the little button for my lights. I can just
Speaker 6:  be like, okay, new routine. I just, I want all the lights off so I can
Speaker 6:  watch Marvel movies and darkness. And it's wild that you can't do that
Speaker 6:  with more remote. You have to use your phone. Yeah,
Speaker 10:  Yeah. And you know, I wanna get the phone out of the living room, you know,
Speaker 10:  because otherwise you need to really engage with your content No to
Speaker 10:  scrolling while you are watching a good episode of Seahawk.
Speaker 5:  Amen to that. No, and I think the buttons is such a good one because it's
Speaker 5:  like, and Jen, you and I have talked about this before that like the, the
Speaker 5:  gold standard for the smart home is like, the only way I'm gonna use it is
Speaker 5:  if it's easier than walking up and flipping that light switch. And you know,
Speaker 5:  it's easier than walking up and flipping that light switch is like mashing
Speaker 5:  the giant green button that I have sitting right here on my desk and like
Speaker 5:  I'm in like put buttons. I want, I want like a wall of buttons that I can
Speaker 5:  just do all kinds of stuff with. I'm gonna have like a, I'm gonna have like
Speaker 5:  a suit of buttons that I just walk around my house in like this. I
Speaker 5:  can't, this sounds awesome. I'm
Speaker 6:  All bolt a bunch of stream decks together and just wear all of them as a,
Speaker 6:  a nice little vest.
Speaker 10:  Exactly. That I would love to see.
Speaker 5:  My pajamas are just gonna be buttons everywhere.
Speaker 6:  You look great David. I
Speaker 10:  Love this. I was just gonna say just the one thing, the last thing on wifi
Speaker 10:  we didn't mention is the new fire TV cube has six E,
Speaker 10:  which is quite exciting. Ooh,
Speaker 6:  That is exciting.
Speaker 10:  Oh yeah, that is a real use case. Like I've struggled to find a use case
Speaker 10:  that I really need for six E at the moment and but streaming is the perfect
Speaker 10:  one because that's the one where you want the wide bandwidth
Speaker 10:  so that you, you know, when someone goes and like turns on their
Speaker 10:  computer upstairs and does some work, you don't suddenly drop your streaming
Speaker 10:  when you're watching your movie. So I think that that's, and you know,
Speaker 10:  that's a really good use case. I'd like to see more of that and
Speaker 10:  I I I've never really gotten comfortable with the fire TV cubes
Speaker 10:  than ever worked that well for me. But I'm interested, I'm really interested
Speaker 10:  in this one because of that 60 capability and being able to, I
Speaker 10:  think it also connects, It has, what was the other thing? It it does, it
Speaker 10:  connects to your, it
Speaker 6:  Connects, it connects to your, your cable box. So you can you can plug
Speaker 10:  Yes, the cable box. So you,
Speaker 6:  My cable from your cable box directly into this and
Speaker 6:  funnel it.
Speaker 10:  Voice control. Yeah. Not that I have a cable box,
Speaker 10:  but,
Speaker 5:  So since, since ELI is not here, I feel obligated to be the one
Speaker 5:  to remind our listeners that the HDMI pass through
Speaker 5:  IR blaster combo is a bad idea and no one should ever try
Speaker 5:  it. And everyone who has tried it, it always goes
Speaker 5:  badly. Microsoft was like, Oh, turn your Xbox into your cable
Speaker 5:  box. Htm I pass through. That went horribly and they lost a whole generation
Speaker 5:  of game consoles. Google tried to do it with Google tv, which went
Speaker 5:  just horrifically badly. Like Mili tweeted a thing that he
Speaker 5:  wrote in 2013 where he said, we've been overlaying fancy
Speaker 5:  interfaces on top of cable signals and praying for IR blasters to adequately
Speaker 5:  control the boxes for years now. And it's never worked. And that was in
Speaker 5:  2013. So kudos to Amazon for trying, but I
Speaker 5:  I I am not holding my breath on this particular one, but I like the idea
Speaker 5:  it should work. But
Speaker 6:  You got wifi feels good six E. Yes. So you can,
Speaker 6:  you don't even have to do any of it. You can skip all of that and
Speaker 6:  and just go enjoy 4k Even when people in your
Speaker 6:  home are deciding to scream stadia in the next three months before
Speaker 6:  Stadia dies.
Speaker 10:  Before it goes away.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Get rid of your cable and stream so fast over a wifi 60 pro
Speaker 5:  solve.
Speaker 10:  Well and there were a lot of other announcements. I know Ring have
Speaker 10:  announcements, blink hand announcements, but I do have to just say I went
Speaker 10:  to the ring booth to see their new cameras. They have new cameras and I
Speaker 10:  saw the drone. You saw the
Speaker 6:  Drone? How big? Oh,
Speaker 5:  It's real. It's
Speaker 10:  Real. It's, it's not that big
Speaker 10:  but it's like the size of a toast. Piece
Speaker 10:  of toast. Okay.
Speaker 6:  All right.
Speaker 10:  Okay. It's quite small and, but they wouldn't let me touch it but it was
Speaker 10:  up in the air but it was hanging from
Speaker 10:  strings. Suspicious.
Speaker 10:  Yeah. Suspicious.
Speaker 5:  Oh. So it's nothing that doesn't count. But I
Speaker 10:  Did talk to someone who told me he has it in his house and
Speaker 10:  promises it does actually work. So he says it's coming
Speaker 10:  soon. Did he
Speaker 6:  Show you video footage?
Speaker 10:  No.
Speaker 5:  It sounds like they showed you a chandelier in the shape of a drone.
Speaker 6:  Very tiny chandelier.
Speaker 5:  A very tiny chandelier.
Speaker 10:  Yeah, it was. I was like, can I bring it down? Nope.
Speaker 10:  Can I reach up and touch it? Nope. No.
Speaker 10:  So
Speaker 6:  It exists. It's really
Speaker 5:  Exists. It exists. Take it. It's out of the renders phase so
Speaker 5:  we'll we'll
Speaker 10:  That seen it in person. So I felt like that was a step forward. It's in
Speaker 10:  the
Speaker 6:  Physical mockup phase.
Speaker 10:  Yes.
Speaker 6:  And in disguise home apparently.
Speaker 5:  Thank goodness. Alright, we really do need to take a break. Jen, do you have
Speaker 5:  a few more minutes to hang out and do a little lightning ground thing with
Speaker 5:  us before we
Speaker 10:  Go? Sure. Happy to.
Speaker 5:  Excellent. Okay. Alright, we're gonna take a quick break and then we'll be
Speaker 5:  right back to do a lightning
Speaker 5:  round.
Speaker 5:  We're back. There was so much other news this week, so we're
Speaker 5:  just gonna do a little lightning round. Basically, Jen, since you're, you're
Speaker 5:  new to this part of the show, everybody just picks a thing that happened
Speaker 5:  this week that we haven't talked about yet that you thought was interesting
Speaker 5:  and cool and worth talking about. And you can go last so you can have a minute
Speaker 5:  to decide what you thought was interesting that you wanna talk about. Alex,
Speaker 5:  what do you have?
Speaker 6:  Oh, it was absolutely the Intel Samsung slidable
Speaker 6:  pc. Yeah. That they showed off at the Intel event. We, we've, we've
Speaker 6:  kind of, everybody's been alluding to something like this was gonna happen
Speaker 6:  at some point. We've seen phone versions of this, this was a laptop
Speaker 6:  version and it, you're initially like, that's so cool. And then you
Speaker 6:  watch the video and the guy's kind of fighting with it a little as he pulls
Speaker 6:  it out. So, you know, like, oh that's, that experience is not
Speaker 6:  smooth yet. That's not coming this month to a Best
Speaker 6:  Buy. Dear you,
Speaker 5:  I've watched that video so many times now and I cannot figure
Speaker 5:  out how it works. It's just like, it, it's, I just keep
Speaker 5:  getting like fruit by the foot vibes from it where it just sort of, you just,
Speaker 5:  you just like peel it out from itself as it opens up. It's very,
Speaker 5:  it's very weird. I don't know. It's
Speaker 6:  It's, it's the same thing that, that LG is doing with its
Speaker 6:  rollable TVs, which I think Jen, you get to, you might get to see one,
Speaker 6:  I know they're showing one at cia. They just announced a 42 inch one.
Speaker 6:  I'm stealing all of the lightning rounds. I'm sorry.
Speaker 10:  Yeah, I haven't got to see it yet, but it is here. But
Speaker 6:  It's just an all led and all LEDs have gotten to the point where you can
Speaker 6:  kind of, I want you to please like send me pictures
Speaker 6:  just just to me personally. You don't have to put them on the website or
Speaker 6:  anything like that. We don't need that, but I just, I just wanna see them
Speaker 6:  myself. But but it's the same, it's the same concept, right? It's just an
Speaker 6:  all LED display that that's really kind of tightly wound
Speaker 6:  up and, and because it's Samsung and Samsung's gotten very good at
Speaker 6:  this like bindy old led technology, right? They,
Speaker 6:  they're better than anybody. They figured out a way to like make it tight
Speaker 6:  enough to make it pretty selt looking device.
Speaker 6:  Notably it just showed an image. There's was no
Speaker 6:  computing or anything really happening with the thing. Yeah, I
Speaker 6:  wouldn't, this is just a proof of concept that a
Speaker 6:  display like this could work and then now they have to pack it into a thing
Speaker 6:  and every other time we've seen like what about foldable laptop
Speaker 6:  that Scott screens everywhere that like the
Speaker 6:  mockup is, you know, a few millimeters tall
Speaker 6:  and then the actual product's like four inches, right?
Speaker 6:  So yeah, this is not gonna be in your next iPad,
Speaker 6:  but it's just cool.
Speaker 5:  These always kind of bum me out if I'm being completely honest. Really? Because
Speaker 5:  they're like, they're very cool and you look at them and they're very exciting
Speaker 5:  and then inevitably there's that like one line in the story
Speaker 5:  that's basically just like, this is just a science project that some guy
Speaker 5:  made in a lab. Yeah. And they have no plans to do anything with it. And this
Speaker 5:  one screen that they showed you, this demo costs $6 million and,
Speaker 5:  and it will almost certainly never be a product. And I just get to the end
Speaker 5:  and I'm like, ah, that was a cool like basically
Speaker 5:  animated gift that I, that's
Speaker 6:  What we, that's the way that was the foldable phone for years
Speaker 6:  now it's like an That's
Speaker 5:  True.
Speaker 6:  Maybe almost mature
Speaker 10:  Everywhere here. Everyone has it here. Really? That's cuz everyone's
Speaker 10:  from Samsung
Speaker 5:  Is everybody just walking around doing like cool moves where they like aggressively
Speaker 5:  close their flip phone when they're done slap
Speaker 6:  It close
Speaker 5:  Or it's like at the end of the meeting everybody like folds on cue and then
Speaker 5:  you stand up and
Speaker 6:  The end of every presentation they snap 'em shut and walk off
Speaker 10:  Stage. I do. I want one. So cool. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  All right. David, what was yours?
Speaker 5:  I I feel obligated to talk about Stage Manager. I don't want
Speaker 5:  to to be clear Stage manager just makes me
Speaker 5:  angry and sad. But there was stage Manager news and I feel
Speaker 5:  obligated to talk about it. So the, the news this week was that Apple is
Speaker 5:  bringing Stage Manager, which it originally said was only gonna be
Speaker 5:  for iPads with an M one processor to I think
Speaker 5:  the most recent two generations of iPad
Speaker 5:  Pros, it's coming to those without one feature, which is the external
Speaker 5:  display support. So you won't be able to run Stage Manager on a monitor while
Speaker 5:  also having your, your screen. Oh no. But it's
Speaker 5:  terrible. But they, but they're bringing Stage Manager to other things, which
Speaker 5:  to strikes me as exactly the wrong impulse. Like to me there should just
Speaker 5:  be one, they should make one iPad, not even like a model, just
Speaker 5:  one iPad that runs Stage Manager and give it to Craig UE because he
Speaker 5:  really likes it and no one else should have to have stage manager like Fork
Speaker 5:  iOS for Craig and leave the rest of us alone. No one else
Speaker 5:  do not have Stage Manager. That's, that's that's what I want. Not more,
Speaker 5:  less. And it does seem like the, the betas keep coming of
Speaker 5:  iPad OS and Stage Manager seems to be getting it's coming David.
Speaker 5:  It's, I know it's coming and it makes me sad and it seems to be getting better
Speaker 5:  in some ways and worse in other ways and it's like, it's just, it's
Speaker 5:  just a mess. But the good news is many more people are going to get to experience
Speaker 5:  the mess. So congratulations everybody.
Speaker 6:  I'm, I'm so excited to experience the mess with all the M one
Speaker 6:  iPad Pro owners. It's
Speaker 5:  Just not good. That's the thing. It's just not good. You're
Speaker 6:  Like, it's just bad. What, what are you gonna do if it
Speaker 6:  comes out and somehow between the latest beta release
Speaker 6:  and, and the release of the new os it, it
Speaker 6:  gets good.
Speaker 5:  I'll be psyched. Are you kidding? I've spent a decade trying to get
Speaker 5:  better multitasking on the iPad out of Apple. And this is like
Speaker 5:  the most, I was gonna say the most interesting
Speaker 5:  idea. It's, it's, it's un Kyle be
Speaker 6:  Good ever.
Speaker 5:  I don't know, maybe potentially I could be onto
Speaker 6:  Something.
Speaker 5:  Craig loves his piles, that's all I know. And Craig, Craig
Speaker 5:  likes weed jokes and piles. Those are the two things that we know about Craig.
Speaker 10:  I've given up on trying to multitask on the iPad. Honestly I
Speaker 10:  just, I it it was so it's never been a good
Speaker 10:  experience. So, but also I don't want to multitask
Speaker 10:  on my iPad that much. I like using my iPad as my non multitasking
Speaker 10:  device. It's like Picker Lane. Is this a computer? It's
Speaker 6:  My focus device. That's fair.
Speaker 5:  Well I think the problem is that there continues to be this very small
Speaker 5:  but incredibly loud minority of people who want
Speaker 5:  to do like real like capital P power user stuff on their
Speaker 5:  iPad. Yeah. And those people have tend to have a very loud voice
Speaker 5:  on the internet and talk about this stuff a lot on the internet. And so they
Speaker 5:  drown out the people I think who are most iPad users and, and it seems
Speaker 5:  like Apple has struggled to make both sides happy and I think
Speaker 5:  is sort of increasingly pushing towards this. Like how do we give the power
Speaker 5:  users more stuff to do and I'm not sure that
Speaker 5:  that actually turns out to be the right strategy all the time. Well
Speaker 6:  I think they run into this problem of like they've got this M one, they've
Speaker 6:  got these really nice processors in it, they've got the M one process in
Speaker 6:  it. Yeah. And so it's like, okay, that's the same one as then the laptop.
Speaker 6:  So it should be able to do laptop stuff and it's like, no it shouldn't. Maybe
Speaker 6:  you shouldn't have put that in there. Maybe we don't need a $2,000 when
Speaker 6:  you get the stuff. iPads.
Speaker 10:  I was sold on the argument that the iPad was now a
Speaker 10:  computer once they brought the iPad Pro out with the
Speaker 10:  keyboard and my husband went back to school, I'm sorry, my husband
Speaker 10:  again. So we got him an iPad
Speaker 10:  Pro and he did three year, three years of college within
Speaker 10:  it as his main computer. Wow. I felt like this was a big test for
Speaker 10:  how com and he's not techy, he doesn't really
Speaker 10:  use computers. He, you know, so this was a real challenge
Speaker 10:  and it failed spectacularly And
Speaker 10:  it really did. I mean he survived, he
Speaker 10:  graduated with honors but it, it
Speaker 10:  couldn't half the time I would have to pull out my computer to help him
Speaker 10:  access something and then upload it to the, to the iPad for him and,
Speaker 10:  and it just, he could write his paper on it. That was fine.
Speaker 10:  That's what the main thing he wanted to do. But to use things, some of these
Speaker 10:  tools like Blackboard and Canvas that a lot of these college programs use
Speaker 10:  and schools use, it just didn't work. It was,
Speaker 10:  anyway, it was, it was, it was not a good experience. And that
Speaker 10:  Apple keyboard that comes with it or doesn't come with it, Sorry that you
Speaker 10:  spend a very small fortune on it's worn
Speaker 10:  away. I can't read any of the keys on it. Oh. And it was,
Speaker 10:  he's only had it for a couple of years. So yeah, it was not, it was not
Speaker 10:  a success. I was very disappointed. But now it's a great TV watching device
Speaker 10:  for him now that he's graduated.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, there you go. It it does the the iPad fails very gracefully
Speaker 5:  over the course of its life, which I appreciate about it. It, it's, I've
Speaker 5:  always liked that. Alright, Jen, what's, what's yours? What's your lightning
Speaker 5:  round?
Speaker 10:  Okay, so I have big gadget news in the smart home
Speaker 10:  is Roomba has its new or iRobot has, its new Roomba this week.
Speaker 10:  They announced just the day before the Amazon event because technically
Speaker 10:  they're, no they're not owned by Amazon yet, although Amazon is trying.
Speaker 10:  Right. And they have announced
Speaker 10:  finally very late to the party AO
Speaker 10:  vacuum and mop in one. But what's neat
Speaker 10:  about it is that it actually is a robotic mop.
Speaker 10:  So all the other mops you have to kinda, although other robot vacuums that
Speaker 10:  have mops, you have to stick the mop on, like you have to pick it up and
Speaker 5:  Oh right,
Speaker 10:  Stick it on the bottom of the robot. Yeah. And then it goes off and does
Speaker 10:  its job. This one Roomba has, it kind of
Speaker 10:  raises itself up on aluminum arms and then slides itself
Speaker 10:  underneath the robot and then goes off and does its mopping and then when
Speaker 10:  it's done or if it comes to up to carpet, it will
Speaker 10:  stop and then lift the mop up and put it on back on top
Speaker 10:  of the robot, vacuum the carpet and then vice versa
Speaker 10:  as it goes off around on its merry way to clean your house. So
Speaker 10:  basically it's the two in one. You don't have to get your hands dirty
Speaker 10:  at all if you want to mop and vacuum.
Speaker 5:  So is there just a gross wet mop inside of your Roomba
Speaker 5:  at all times now?
Speaker 10:  So you do. Yes, that's the option.
Speaker 5:  Okay. I mean that's fine. It's just gonna take me a minute to get used
Speaker 5:  to.
Speaker 6:  What's that smell? I haven't changed the mop in my Roomba lately.
Speaker 13:  Yeah. Yes,
Speaker 13:  yes.
Speaker 10:  It's, it's removable. You just rip it off, it's Velcro
Speaker 10:  washable, throw it in the washing machine and then you do have to
Speaker 10:  manually attach it to the bottom of the mop plate when you,
Speaker 10:  when you want it to be clean. But it has, it has a water tank in,
Speaker 10:  so it's squirting water onto the mop. So keeping it damp as it goes
Speaker 10:  around and it has, it's smart enough. So iRobot has their, what
Speaker 10:  they call the robot os the fifth generation that kind of
Speaker 10:  helps make the robot smarter and it applies to all their robots, not
Speaker 10:  just the new one, which is called the Roomba combo J seven
Speaker 10:  plus that it will go, when it goes into a
Speaker 10:  room, it does the, it will go intelligently
Speaker 10:  and do like the mopping first and then vacuum the carpets or vacuum the
Speaker 10:  carpets first and then mop. So it can be efficient rather than having
Speaker 10:  to stop and reload its mop every time it comes across a carpet
Speaker 10:  because it can map your room so it knows where your carpets
Speaker 10:  are or where your rugs are versus your hardwood floor or your tile
Speaker 10:  floor. So I'm, it's an inex very expensive robot over
Speaker 10:  a thousand dollars. But it does come with the auto empty base so you don't
Speaker 10:  have to get your hands dirty, empty in the, the little bin. Yeah. You do
Speaker 10:  have to fill it up with water and yes, you do need to clean them mop.
Speaker 10:  You can't just leave the mo.
Speaker 6:  So sort of like every morning before you leave, leave the house, you feed
Speaker 6:  the dog, you give the dog water and then you go and you like
Speaker 6:  feed the mop into your Roomba. You're like, goodbye guys, have fun
Speaker 6:  and, and, and leave. That's like the idea. Yeah.
Speaker 10:  And then the robot will will actually that, that's one of the good things.
Speaker 10:  They just came out with a new capability in this new os to
Speaker 10:  avoid pet bowls or if you want clean really
Speaker 10:  well around pet bowls so that it has, so it has visual, it has
Speaker 10:  artificial intelligence that helps identify a pet bowl
Speaker 10:  and know that it shouldn't bang into it because rumors do bang into furniture.
Speaker 10:  I've actually had a rumor knock my chairs down
Speaker 10:  regularly, but now it can identify a pet bowl
Speaker 10:  or a litter box and not bang into it, but it will
Speaker 10:  also, but it'll clean and mop closely around it so
Speaker 10:  that you can come home to a nice clean pet bowl rather than a
Speaker 10:  sloshed mess that your, that your rumor is created
Speaker 10:  while you are gone.
Speaker 5:  That's pretty good. I I make a lot of fun of fancy Roombas, but I also own
Speaker 5:  a fancy Roomba and I love it to pieces like it is, it is a
Speaker 5:  truly glorious device to own. And I got the one that
Speaker 5:  like empties itself and it just, it just runs and I don't think about it.
Speaker 5:  And it is, it is truly, truly delightful. So when they make one of these
Speaker 5:  that goes into like a swimming pool and cleans itself at the end of the day,
Speaker 5:  like that's, that's where the magic happens. I want one that goes right into
Speaker 5:  my washing machine at the end of the day and cleans itself and then
Speaker 5:  just sort of scoots
Speaker 6:  Back.
Speaker 10:  Well they do have, there are two that will clean their own bottoms as I
Speaker 10:  like to say, but they, and it goes in,
Speaker 10:  there's the Omni by Debar and then Robo Rock has one
Speaker 10:  and it goes in and like scrubs the mop and then like blows little hot air
Speaker 10:  on it to, to dry the mop so that you never have to deal with it.
Speaker 10:  But that one's even more expensive.
Speaker 5:  It's like a little car wash for your, for your robot bag. It
Speaker 10:  Is a car wash for your robot vacuum. Exactly. And it makes it funny little
Speaker 10:  noise. It's like,
Speaker 10:  yeah,
Speaker 5:  That's, that's pretty good.
Speaker 6:  I love it. This is the closest I've ever felt to wanting to buy one of these
Speaker 6:  things. Thank you.
Speaker 5:  It's it's worth it. It will change your life. It, it feels ridiculous when
Speaker 5:  you're buying it from experience. I can say there, there is a time when you're
Speaker 5:  gonna look at it and be like, am I really about to spend all of this money
Speaker 5:  on this thing? Like I could just vacuum like a person and
Speaker 5:  then, but
Speaker 6:  Then your floors are clean
Speaker 5:  And then you don't have to vacuum like a person. It's great.
Speaker 10:  I do have one more gadget if you want, if you want one more lightning gadget
Speaker 5:  For it.
Speaker 10:  Sure do it. So ufi, which is Anchor's Smart Home
Speaker 10:  brand, has released a very interesting new camera
Speaker 10:  system. It is the UFI cam three
Speaker 10:  and it comes with a home base three. And what it, it's artificially
Speaker 10:  intelligent intelligence powered data processing that does it all
Speaker 10:  locally on the little home base in your house. So it's not sending your
Speaker 10:  video up to the cloud. And it has facial recognition,
Speaker 10:  animal pet recognition, vehicle detection. So
Speaker 10:  that the idea is you shouldn't get hundreds of annoying alerts saying there's
Speaker 10:  motion at your door. It'll say there's a person at your door or there's
Speaker 10:  a dog or a pet or a vehicle and then the facial
Speaker 10:  recognition kicks in and it can say there's a stranger in your yard as
Speaker 10:  opposed to your husband's in your yard or David's in his yard. Oh wow. Alex
Speaker 10:  is in and that's,
Speaker 6:  I don't have a yard.
Speaker 5:  Alex is frequently in my yard though I never, I never ask but she's frequently
Speaker 5:  in my yard
Speaker 6:  At the window Peaky again, which has,
Speaker 6:  there,
Speaker 10:  You get facial recognition on a number of cameras these days, but most of
Speaker 10:  it has has to have some kind of cloud component for the
Speaker 10:  processing. Whereas this is all edge processing, which is really makes a
Speaker 10:  lot faster, which means for a security system is is pretty crucial.
Speaker 10:  And it also has up to 16 terabytes of local
Speaker 10:  storage, which they tell me can hold 60 years
Speaker 10:  of video before you need to erase any of it. You have
Speaker 10:  to buy the extra storage separately. Cause obviously a 16 terabyte
Speaker 10:  hard drive is not cheap. Yeah. But it, when
Speaker 10:  you buy one of these, when you add a hard drive to it, you could add a
Speaker 10:  terabyte hard drive up to 16. It gives you continuous
Speaker 10:  video recording. So 24 7 video recording, which again is something that
Speaker 10:  really doesn't exist in this in the DIY smart home space right now Google
Speaker 10:  Nest has it on some of its cameras, but it's not a big, it's
Speaker 10:  something a lot of people ask for but most companies don't offer because
Speaker 10:  you're using cloud storage but this doesn't
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And it's not going to the cloud. So it's like if, if I fall down
Speaker 6:  and accidentally record myself looking like a dumbass because I fell
Speaker 6:  down, no one will ever know.
Speaker 10:  No one's gonna, no one's gonna see it. No. And
Speaker 10:  they,
Speaker 6:  I can delete the footage
Speaker 10:  And bringing this back to how we started, what I really love about this
Speaker 10:  is they have new cameras that come with the home base three's, the UFI cam
Speaker 10:  three, you know 4k, they have built in solar power. It's,
Speaker 10:  it's a, it's, it's an impressive system. But if you have UFI
Speaker 10:  cams and you buy the home base three, this AI
Speaker 10:  capability, which UFI calls its bionic mind will
Speaker 10:  work on all your existing cameras. So it works every,
Speaker 6:  That's
Speaker 10:  Dope. UFI cam. So you're basically upgrading your existing
Speaker 10:  cameras by adding this hub. So and that's a
Speaker 10:  really, you know, that's a good strategy for companies. I think that's improve
Speaker 10:  the company, improve what you already have.
Speaker 6:  I was like that. No, that's like I, I don't need any cameras in my home,
Speaker 6:  but if I did, that would be incredible. That's what I would want. That's
Speaker 5:  Perfect. Yeah. And especially now that that stuff is like trickling down
Speaker 5:  to all these other brands that, that's especially ones
Speaker 5:  that aren't trying to like charge you an arm and a leg for other stuff. That's
Speaker 5:  pretty exciting.
Speaker 10:  Yeah, there's no fees for this. You just buy the device, stick it in your
Speaker 10:  home and it will keep going for 60 days, 60
Speaker 5:  Years, 60 years. And I'm sure all the gadgets will last that
Speaker 5:  long also. It'll be great. Alright, we have gone way over
Speaker 5:  Jen. Thank you for going to that deeply sad looking press room
Speaker 5:  to hang out with us. But yeah, thank you both. Tons of good stuff on the
Speaker 5:  verge. Esther weighing wrote a great piece about the campaign to stop Asian
Speaker 5:  hate. You should go read that. I'm supposed to promote decoder on this show,
Speaker 5:  but NE's not here. So I will absolutely not do that. Don't do it. And no
Speaker 5:  circumstances should you go listen Toco, don't watch it. We're gonna have
Speaker 5:  the third episode of our future music series on
Speaker 5:  Monday. The first two have been really awesome. It's been, it's been really
Speaker 5:  fun. Yeah, it's two, two great, great shows so far. I'm hosting the third
Speaker 5:  one and I'm confident it will be the least good of the three, but it'll still
Speaker 5:  be fun. So check that out. We're gonna be back next Wednesday. We're doing
Speaker 5:  some more earbuds testing and I know there are some people who hate that
Speaker 5:  segment, so I'm sorry, but we're doing it anyway. We're gonna have more Amazon
Speaker 5:  stuff to talk about because we're not done talking about Kindles. We're also,
Speaker 5:  if you have cybersecurity mysteries, we're doing an episode at the end of
Speaker 5:  October all about cybersecurity. So if you have some weird cybersecurity
Speaker 5:  thing going on in your life and you would like to talk to us about it on
Speaker 5:  the show and maybe we can help you solve your problems, hit us up. That is
Speaker 5:  eight six Verge one one. You can follow us on Twitter.
Speaker 5:  Alex is Alex. Six Crans. J is JP Peters. Jen is
Speaker 5:  jp. Two E and I'm Pierce. That's it. That's Vergecast
Speaker 5:  Rock and
Speaker 5:  roll.
Speaker 1:  And that's a wrap for Vergecast this week. Thanks for listening. If you enjoy
Speaker 1:  the show, subscribe in the podcast app of your choice or tell a friend, you
Speaker 1:  can send us feedback at vergecast@theverge.com. This show is produced
Speaker 1:  by me, Liam James, and our senior audio director, Andrew Marino. This
Speaker 1:  episode was edited and mixed by Amanda Rose Smith. Our
Speaker 1:  editorial director is Brooke Mins and our executive producer is
Speaker 1:  Eleanor Donovan. The Verge Cast is a production of the Verge and Box Media
Speaker 1:  podcast network. And that's it. We'll see you next
Speaker 1:  week