# Transcript
ID: 9a8450a0-4999-11ed-be16-d9ebc900600b
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Zuckerberg on the Quest Pro, our impressions, and the state of VR games
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/6701215652283725255/-5115192056003191010/s93290-US-4371s-1665515868.mp3
Description: Today on the flagship podcast of low-latency head tracking:
02:35 - Meta CEO Mark Zuckerberg chats with deputy editor Alex Heath about Meta's new headset, the Quest Pro.
22:00 - Alex Heath and senior reporter Adi Robertson chat with David Pierce about their first impressions using the Quest Pro.
47:45 - Group Publisher for The Verge Chris Grant chats with David about what's happening in VR for video games.
You can listen to the rest of the chat with Mark Zuckerberg on Decoder with Nilay Patel, watch it on The Verge's YouTube channel for the video version, or read it on our site.
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we'd love to hear from you.
We are conducting a short audience survey to help plan for our future and hear from you. To participate, head to vox.com/podsurvey, and thank you!
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (4 ads detected)
Speaker 2:  Welcome to the Vergecast, the flagship podcast of low latency head tracking.
Speaker 2:  I'm your friend David Pierce, and I am currently sitting in my car
Speaker 2:  futzing with its settings because apparently that's a thing you have to do.
Speaker 2:  Now, I've never owned a new car before and then we bought a cool new
Speaker 2:  Hyundai Tucson hybrid, which I like a lot, but it makes all these
Speaker 2:  dumb noises and it beeps at me every time I forget to use the turn
Speaker 2:  signal or just open the door and it's halt just a lot.
Speaker 2:  So I'm doing what any good tech geek does. I'm ignoring the manual entirely
Speaker 2:  and I'm just sitting here hitting all the buttons and seeing what happens.
Speaker 2:  Wish me luck. We have a great show today, all on a single
Speaker 2:  subject, well, a few subjects, virtual reality,
Speaker 2:  augmented reality, mixed reality, whatever you wanna call it, the
Speaker 2:  future of reality. The reason we're publishing this episode a day early is
Speaker 2:  because today is Meta Connect. And Meta is releasing both a new Quest
Speaker 2:  Pro headset and a lot of information about its plan for the future of
Speaker 2:  all this technology. We're gonna dig into the games, the headsets, and
Speaker 2:  everything else it'll take to make VR and AR and mixed reality
Speaker 2:  work if in fact it's ever going to. All that's coming
Speaker 2:  in just a sec. But first I have to apparently go put electrical tape
Speaker 2:  on the speaker in front of my car because that's the only way to make
Speaker 2:  the reverse noise quieter. I mean, listen to this, it's
Speaker 2:  awful.
Speaker 2:  This is the Vergecast. See you in a
Speaker 2:  sec.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. So the first thing I wanna do today is play a chunk of
Speaker 2:  an interview that the vers Alex Heath did with meta CEO Mark Zuckerberg last
Speaker 2:  week ahead of Meta Connect. They had a long conversation about a lot of things.
Speaker 2:  Turns out there's a lot going on at Meta and if you wanna hear the whole
Speaker 2:  thing, it's available both on the Verges YouTube feed and on the decoder
Speaker 2:  podcast feed. But for our purposes, I just want you to hear the chunk of
Speaker 2:  their conversation about virtual reality and mixed reality and augmented
Speaker 2:  reality and the new Quest Pro headset and all of that good stuff. Although
Speaker 2:  Alex is sitting here with me right now. Hi Alex.
Speaker 4:  Hi David.
Speaker 2:  Tee this up for us. You've been spending a lot of time with Meow
Speaker 2:  people, including Mark Zuckerberg over the last couple of weeks. Like the
Speaker 2:  setting for this is obviously it's me connect, they have a lot of stuff to
Speaker 2:  announce, but like just tell us what you've been up to.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, so I've been traveling around a little bit. This started with an
Speaker 4:  invite to go up to their research center where they
Speaker 4:  build all of this future VR and AR stuff in the research
Speaker 4:  phase in Redmond outside of Seattle. And we did a bunch of research demos,
Speaker 4:  but we were mainly there to see this new headset that
Speaker 4:  Zuckerberg has been teasing in drips and drabs on his
Speaker 4:  Instagram for the last year, really called the Quest Pro. They've
Speaker 4:  been calling it Project Cambria leading up to this.
Speaker 2:  And you've been reporting on this for like a long time.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, this has been a long time coming and the idea with
Speaker 4:  the Quest Pro is that it, it's obviously more expensive. It's
Speaker 4:  1499, which is dramatically more than the current quest. It
Speaker 4:  introduces two big things that I think are meaningful on the kind of
Speaker 4:  just timeline of these headsets, right? Which is mixed reality.
Speaker 4:  So this concept of blending the real world with the virtual,
Speaker 4:  using pass through video and face tracking and eye tracking, which
Speaker 4:  really lets your avatars become a lot more lifelike and feel like
Speaker 4:  you're actually talking to people and not just, you know, basically
Speaker 4:  3D sims from the nineties like it has been. So that was the main
Speaker 4:  reason we were there. Tried a bunch of demos and then the week after that
Speaker 4:  I went back to San Francisco to met his headquarters
Speaker 4:  to sit down with Zuckerberg. He wanted to chat about the Quest Pro and
Speaker 4:  about everything they're working on, the rebrand, how it went, the metaverse,
Speaker 4:  why he basically feeds off of his doubters, which
Speaker 4:  I thought was interesting. And then we also talked about social media, how
Speaker 4:  they're competing with TikTok, his thoughts on what the government should
Speaker 4:  do about TikTok, all that stuff. So it was, it was, you're right, it was
Speaker 4:  a long conversation, but a lot of it is talking about this new hardware.
Speaker 4:  And I would say this second biggest thing that they're announcing is this
Speaker 4:  big sweeping partnership with Microsoft on the
Speaker 4:  software and services side for vr to integrate basically all of Microsoft's
Speaker 4:  enterprise technology and even Windows itself into the Quest,
Speaker 4:  which is a pretty big deal hashed out between Zuckerberg and Sat
Speaker 4:  Nadella. So there's a lot to talk about. Mark was gracious with his time.
Speaker 4:  We didn't get to everything, but you know, I hope it's an interesting conversation
Speaker 4:  for people.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, it was a good one. And I, I agree that the window stuff is fascinating.
Speaker 2:  So we're, we're gonna get back to some of that and a little bit, but that
Speaker 2:  is enough wind up. Let's just get to it. Here is Alex and Mark
Speaker 2:  Zuckerberg.
Speaker 4:  Well let's talk about the Quest Pro, cause I got got to try it at your research
Speaker 4:  center in Redmond recently and it's very different from
Speaker 4:  the existing Quest line. And I think there's two big things that
Speaker 4:  people will have probably not experienced until they try it. It'll be the
Speaker 4:  first time they try it and see this is the face tracking and mixed
Speaker 4:  reality. And I wanted to kind of talk about those two points with
Speaker 4:  you. Maybe starting with mixed reality, which is this isn't
Speaker 4:  VR in the traditional sense, you're actually mixing video of the world around
Speaker 4:  you with vr. Yeah. Why is this something that needs to exist?
Speaker 4:  I mean, what, what does mixed reality represent on the continuum of like
Speaker 4:  where you've gone with VR today? Just
Speaker 6:  First for for background, you know, mixed reality. What it basically is that
Speaker 6:  you see the physical world around you and then you can overlay digital
Speaker 6:  objects. So you can think about virtual reality
Speaker 6:  is the system is basically painting every pixel, right? So you're in a fully
Speaker 6:  immersive world, you're, you're in a completely different place over the
Speaker 6:  long term. You'll have augmented reality, which are, you know, glasses, something
Speaker 6:  like what you're wearing now is basically like the target of what we would
Speaker 6:  like to get to. I don't know if you'll be able to get that much smaller than
Speaker 6:  that cuz there's a lot of, a lot of electronics to cram in there. Yeah, right.
Speaker 6:  The, you know, all the silicon and the projector and the wave
Speaker 6:  guides to display the holograms and the cameras to basically make sure that
Speaker 6:  all the objects and the holograms are locked in the right place in the world
Speaker 6:  and the speakers and batteries, right? So, so a lot of stuff to
Speaker 6:  fit into those glasses. But you'll get that and when you have glasses like
Speaker 6:  what you're wearing now, you'll see the kind of actual
Speaker 6:  photons from the world, things around you and then you'll overlay holograms
Speaker 6:  just in that place. So mixed reality is sort of this in between where it's
Speaker 6:  a VR device that basically every kind of pixel
Speaker 6:  that you're seeing in your, in your vision is rendered by, by the
Speaker 6:  graphics pipeline in the device. But it does this thing
Speaker 6:  called pass through where you have cameras on the outside an array of cameras
Speaker 6:  because you know your eyes, you we see in stereo, right? That's how we get
Speaker 6:  3d. So it's not just one camera. It's important that we get the different
Speaker 6:  perspectives and it can basically pass that through
Speaker 6:  in high resolution and in color. And then
Speaker 6:  given the screen, it can either print what the photons are that it's getting
Speaker 6:  from the outside or they can overlay digital objects.
Speaker 6:  So you can be sitting at a, at a desk and have your kind of perfect workstation
Speaker 6:  up with three huge monitors and, but you can see your physical keyboard
Speaker 6:  in front of you and your physical mouse so you can control your, the digital
Speaker 6:  monitors that aren't actually there.
Speaker 4:  I tried this, I tried this last week and I will say the monitor thing is
Speaker 4:  compelling. What I noticed was the keyboard itself was a little fuzzy
Speaker 4:  still, and I didn't feel like I could see the keys super well to
Speaker 4:  feel like confident typing.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I mean I think that all the stuff will get better over time.
Speaker 6:  There's some kind of tracking augmentation that we can do for
Speaker 6:  certain keyboards too. Sears may just not have had that, but in general you
Speaker 6:  can get a sense of where, where this is going. Right? And I don't think,
Speaker 6:  I mean this is a V1 device, right? So it's not the perfect
Speaker 6:  incarnation of this. I mean, just like Quest one de Quest two is this huge
Speaker 6:  jump and there's a, you know, many times more sales. I I I do think, you
Speaker 6:  know, it's like, well we'll keep on building this out, but, but I, this is
Speaker 6:  the best mixed reality that anyone has built right so far. And this is, yeah.
Speaker 6:  And this kind of, I think is enough to introduce the concept to the world
Speaker 6:  show where it's going, get the development ecosystem starting to go. So you'll,
Speaker 6:  you're, you'll get people building use cases for, for work,
Speaker 6:  whether it's the, the desktop, you know, solo productivity example.
Speaker 6:  You'll be able to have kind of hybrid meetings where, you know, instead of
Speaker 6:  work rooms, which we have today where you're in VR and you can see people's
Speaker 6:  avatars now you'll be able to have hybrid meetings where you can see some
Speaker 6:  people can physically be there and you'll see them, but then other people
Speaker 6:  will just show up in VR and you'll see their avatars. So that'll be pretty
Speaker 6:  sweet. So
Speaker 4:  There's a, I mean there's a lot of mixed reality use cases I think that will
Speaker 4:  show out over time. The other component of this is face tracking and being
Speaker 4:  able to see your face movements and your eye movements. And I see the value
Speaker 4:  in, in the experience. I, I did a demo where I was with one of your employees
Speaker 4:  in workroom and it, it felt, it did feel more visceral like being able to
Speaker 4:  see how our face reacted in real time. Yeah, yeah. So I understand the
Speaker 4:  use case of it completely. I'm curious how you thought about building that
Speaker 4:  into the product from a privacy perspective. Cuz obviously there's gonna
Speaker 4:  be concerns about face tracking. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  Sure, sure. I mean, first let's talk about like what it is and why it's valuable.
Speaker 6:  Sure. I mean, I think, well, I can answer your question quickly on the privacy
Speaker 6:  side. Yeah. The face sensing data stays on the device, right? And we don't
Speaker 6:  send the raw data to apps and people basically have to opt in if they want
Speaker 6:  the, an app to, to be able to know where, where they're looking, the eye
Speaker 6:  tracking or, or their face expression.
Speaker 4:  And importantly, you don't have the raw data either, like medical,
Speaker 6:  No, it's, it's on the device and, and it's, and it's encrypted and then it
Speaker 6:  basically gets thrown away as soon as it's processed. So, so I think that,
Speaker 6:  that, that's, so from a privacy perspective, I think we can Okay. I I actually
Speaker 6:  think that that's been,
Speaker 4:  You think that's solid?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I mean we've also had people come and audited and, and you know, I'm
Speaker 6:  sure over time we'll we'll add more capabilities and we'll need to keep thinking
Speaker 6:  through this. So security is never a thing that's done. Sure. Right. But
Speaker 6:  it's, it's something that we've thought through very carefully given the,
Speaker 6:  the sensitivity around it. But I do think it's worth just talking about why
Speaker 6:  the, this is such a big deal, right? So mixed reality I think is clearly
Speaker 6:  a big deal because it's this bridge between virtual reality, which you can
Speaker 6:  build today an augmented reality, which you kinda want, but it's, it's still
Speaker 6:  a few years away from really being able to get built. So this, this sort
Speaker 6:  of starts to bring that experience and even if it's in a VR form factor,
Speaker 6:  the face expressions are critical because it gets to why we're
Speaker 6:  in this at all, which is we're really focused on
Speaker 6:  the potential of VR and AR to deliver
Speaker 6:  this authentic sense of presence. No other technology can do
Speaker 6:  this, right? It's like when you're on your phone or if you're on a Zoom call,
Speaker 6:  it's nice to be able to see the person, you can like pick up some context
Speaker 6:  around them, but you brain is under no illusion that you are
Speaker 6:  there with them, right? It's like you, you, if if anything you're trying
Speaker 6:  to convince yourself that you're kind of having a closer interaction, you
Speaker 6:  obviously know you're in a different room and all that, the, the magic of
Speaker 6:  VR for people who have experienced this, you know, that it just, it it
Speaker 6:  basically immediately convinces your mind that you are present
Speaker 6:  in another place and with the people who are there. And when you see
Speaker 6:  avatars, you know, even if they're expressive avatars that aren't yet photo
Speaker 6:  realistic, it, it feels very rich and present when you're there
Speaker 6:  in, in a lot of ways, you know, even more so than, you know, what you would
Speaker 6:  get on a zoom call today, where obviously people show up in a photo realistic
Speaker 6:  way, but there's, there's just so much that it doesn't feel like you're actually
Speaker 6:  present. Whereas even if you have this expressive, somewhat cartoon
Speaker 6:  avatar, you know, next to you, it, it actually, you know, you feel like you're
Speaker 6:  there next to each other even if you're, you know, thousands of miles apart
Speaker 6:  if they're on the other coast or something like
Speaker 4:  That. And that to you is compelling in and of its own right for this technology
Speaker 4:  to where you think that's gonna be a reason people gravitate towards
Speaker 6:  That. To me that is the primary value of it is
Speaker 6:  basically the ability to feel and deliver this sense of
Speaker 6:  presence. I think this like human sense of presence is such
Speaker 6:  a profound and magical thing that, and we're a
Speaker 6:  company that just like everyone here wakes up in the morning and thinks about
Speaker 6:  how we're gonna like help people connect and communicate. You can't
Speaker 6:  deliver that kind of sense of presence on any of the platforms that we've
Speaker 6:  had the opportunity to build on yet, right? So we build on web, on pc,
Speaker 6:  on mobile, there's a lot of good things about all those platforms, but if
Speaker 6:  you think about like what is the ultimate expression of social technology,
Speaker 6:  you're not gonna get it on a phone, right? So that's why we're
Speaker 6:  investing so much money in, in like so many of our, our top
Speaker 6:  people in trying to invent and, and accelerate the development
Speaker 6:  of, of this next platform because it's gonna enable, I think the ultimate
Speaker 6:  expression of, of what we set out to do. Building, building social
Speaker 6:  software. So then the question is, okay, what are all the things that we
Speaker 6:  just need to like burn down to make it so that like on the list of things
Speaker 6:  that get in the way of feeling like you're even more immersed and present
Speaker 6:  with other people, one of them obviously is realistic expressions,
Speaker 6:  right? So, you know, I think that this is gonna be one of the defining characteristics
Speaker 6:  of, of this product and, and hopefully a lot more that we do going
Speaker 6:  forward, is the accurate kind of face
Speaker 6:  expressions and ability to make eye contact, which is also
Speaker 6:  really powerful and also something you can't really do on video calls today.
Speaker 6:  It's, it's kind of, yeah. You know, it's like if you try to look at someone's
Speaker 6:  eyes, you're not looking at the camera. Yeah. You know, so all these kinda
Speaker 6:  weird issues that break the sense of presence. Yeah. But in order to do that,
Speaker 6:  it's a pretty big trade off in the design because you putting a bunch of
Speaker 6:  different sensors in there. Yeah. Which consume a lot of
Speaker 6:  the CPU on the device and, and the, the kind of silicon
Speaker 6:  power budget that you have basically processing the input from
Speaker 6:  these sensors in order to make it so that when you're in VR and
Speaker 6:  mixed reality and eventually augmented reality, your representation of yourself
Speaker 6:  will have realistic expressions. So I'm interested to see what happens, but
Speaker 6:  I think other folks in the space and you look at like, Sony's coming out
Speaker 6:  with a new headset this year. I mean this isn't like a thing that I think
Speaker 6:  that they're prioritizing.
Speaker 4:  I think Apple's headset is gonna look and work a lot like this actually.
Speaker 6:  Well, we'll see. Yeah. I mean it's, I dunno, it's, it's actually, it's been
Speaker 6:  very hard for us to have any sense of what they're doing. So I, I find it
Speaker 6:  best to just,
Speaker 4:  I think we'll know soon. Well, we'll yeah,
Speaker 6:  That'll be interesting too. Yeah. But it's something that this really gets
Speaker 6:  to the mission of what we're, of what we're
Speaker 4:  Doing in terms of tradeoffs too. This is an expensive device. This is a lot
Speaker 4:  more expensive than the Quest two. Yeah. You've been very clear that you
Speaker 4:  want to make these devices as cheap as possible to get them in the hands
Speaker 4:  of as many people as possible. Yes. I think in, in 2017 you said you want
Speaker 4:  a billion people in vr, that was your goal. Well, it's a good start.
Speaker 4:  I think the, I think the Quest two has done over 10 million
Speaker 4:  sales to date. Does that sound accurate to
Speaker 6:  You? I mean, I'm not, don't estimates we haven't shared any numbers. Why
Speaker 6:  not? Why not? That's a good question. I I think we tend to
Speaker 6:  not share numbers until things are a lot bigger, but a lot.
Speaker 4:  So you're waiting for a certain number.
Speaker 6:  I, I don't actually have a number in mind, but, but I,
Speaker 4:  I'm not sure
Speaker 6:  That, yeah, I'm not sure that there's
Speaker 4:  Any particular, So the estimates are that you've done over 10 million with
Speaker 4:  Quest, I'm sure it's higher than that. You're obviously far from a billion.
Speaker 4:  But who is this device for at this price point? Because I think, you
Speaker 4:  know, the Quest two is considered kind of a gaming device. There's a lot
Speaker 4:  of social stuff starting to happen. There's fitness with Supernatural, who
Speaker 4:  is the target customer for this?
Speaker 6:  So there, there are really two sets of folks. One are just people who
Speaker 6:  want the best VR device that anyone has made. So I, I think if you want
Speaker 6:  that, this is it, it is better than the Quest two.
Speaker 6:  It's a lot more expensive so it won't be for everyone, but there is some
Speaker 6:  group of people who want that. The second is people who
Speaker 6:  want basically a device that's for productivity. When I think about
Speaker 6:  the market, I think that there are gonna be two basic different kind of tiers
Speaker 6:  and price segments. I think there's gonna be a, a kind of consumer oriented
Speaker 6:  segment that is, you know, maybe three, four, $500
Speaker 6:  devices that people widely can, can afford sort of in the
Speaker 6:  price of an Xbox or a PlayStation. A lot of the use cases there will be entertainment
Speaker 6:  focused, whether it's gaming or social and, and kind of hanging out with
Speaker 6:  people or things like fitness and that that list of use cases
Speaker 6:  will just continue growing. But it's, it's been pretty cool to see, see how
Speaker 6:  that's expanded so far. If you think about how you use computers, there's
Speaker 6:  also clearly a market for people who want to pay,
Speaker 6:  you know, are willing to pay $1,500, $2,000
Speaker 6:  kind of high end professionals for their workstations.
Speaker 4:  That's what you imagine being the alliance for
Speaker 6:  This. Yeah, I mean for this and for the future of the pro line
Speaker 6:  overall, right. I do think that there's going to be a market for people who
Speaker 6:  want to get, the people are really interested in VR being
Speaker 6:  able to be their primary workstation over time.
Speaker 6:  I think that that's, there's gonna be a market around that and people who
Speaker 6:  are sort of high-end professionals there, you're already paying thousands
Speaker 6:  of dollars for your workstation. So I think that's pretty clear that the
Speaker 6:  ability to get more technology into there to make that even better.
Speaker 6:  You'd do it. Yeah. Right. If I could, if I could give all of our engineers
Speaker 6:  a device and have them, you know, be 3% more productive, I'd give them a
Speaker 6:  $1,500 device for for sure. So that's kind of the, the, in terms
Speaker 6:  of the market segmentation, what we expect to happen, there's
Speaker 6:  also this advantage in developing both of them, which is that we
Speaker 6:  can introduce new technology
Speaker 4:  First in this one, in this,
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Before we can get it into the price point for the consumer one. Right.
Speaker 6:  And being able to work on it and developing it actually helps us get it into
Speaker 6:  the consumer one faster and better. And by the
Speaker 6:  time that it is in the consumer one, we already have a developer ecosystem
Speaker 6:  and content around it because even if fewer people are buying the Quest one,
Speaker 6:  it's more of a high end device, it'll be enough to kinda get the developer
Speaker 6:  ecosystem going. So of course we're working on more devices in the consumer
Speaker 6:  line too, where there will be a Quest three at some point, not this
Speaker 6:  year, but, you know, I'd love to get, you know, some of these features into,
Speaker 6:  into future devices. Whether it's Quest three, Quest four, and you know,
Speaker 6:  the fact that we're building Quest Pro and have that and people can start
Speaker 6:  building for mixed reality and, and all that is, is I think it'll be just
Speaker 6:  a pretty big advantage on that too.
Speaker 4:  You've been pretty open that on the Quest too. You are not making money on
Speaker 4:  the hardware. Are you making money on this like on a unit basis or,
Speaker 6:  I, I mean I'd have to look there lots of different ways to basically
Speaker 6:  do the accounting on this as I've learned. So
Speaker 4:  Is this a profit generating
Speaker 6:  Device? No, I think the, the, the strategy overall is
Speaker 6:  not to make money on the hardware but to make it that it can help develop
Speaker 6:  the ecosystem and then over time the business model will be based on
Speaker 6:  software and services. So that, that remains the approach. I
Speaker 4:  Wasn't sure because I you invest so much in hardware, you have so many people
Speaker 4:  working on this, you're spending so much money on hardware. I wasn't sure
Speaker 4:  if you had landed on a hardware. That's, that's why I think business
Speaker 4:  or not,
Speaker 6:  It probably depends on how exactly you account
Speaker 6:  for it. So like if, if you're just saying what is like the materials
Speaker 6:  that go into the device, maybe we're charging a little bit more for that,
Speaker 6:  for, for the device than the materials that go into it. But if you account
Speaker 6:  for all the r and d and everything, then no way. But no, the, the
Speaker 6:  strategy is not, I mean we're not trying to have
Speaker 6:  premium device prices and make a profit on that.
Speaker 6:  Our whole approach as a company is get as many people as possible
Speaker 6:  to be able to access these tools and then over time you build a better
Speaker 6:  ecosystem that way. Got it. And that, this is like a pretty deep part of
Speaker 6:  our philosophy around this overall. We also wanna help build the open
Speaker 6:  ecosystem around all of this. So rather than being kind of
Speaker 6:  insular and you know, trying to do everything ourselves and a
Speaker 6:  big part of the theme for this year's connect is all the partnerships that
Speaker 6:  we have for the, the partnership with Microsoft, which is gonna be fundamental
Speaker 6:  for you. We're not talk about, we're not enterprise company, right. So, so
Speaker 6:  making it that this can basically succeed with
Speaker 6:  enterprises
Speaker 2:  Like I mentioned before. You can hear the rest of that conversation between
Speaker 2:  Alex Heath and Mark Zuckerberg in the decoder podcast feed. Or you can watch
Speaker 2:  the whole thing on our YouTube channel, youtube.com/the Verge. We
Speaker 2:  need to take a break but Alex is gonna stick around and we're also gonna
Speaker 2:  grab add Robertson to come on and talk about the Quest Pro itself. We'll
Speaker 2:  be right
Speaker 2:  back.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. So we've heard a lot now about Mark Zuckerberg and Meta's,
Speaker 2:  big plans for like your legs and mixed reality and
Speaker 2:  the metaverse and how we're all just gonna bop around in the future.
Speaker 2:  But let's talk about the here and now, which is the Quest pro. Addie Robertson's
Speaker 2:  here. Hi Addie. Hi. And Alex is still here. Hi Alex.
Speaker 2:  Hey. And if I'm not mistaken, you now have both seen and used
Speaker 2:  the Quest Pro, correct? That's right.
Speaker 8:  That is correct.
Speaker 2:  Okay, so Addie, why don't you go first tell me like walk me through
Speaker 2:  this thing in context of like what quests have been like before. Tell me
Speaker 2:  about the Quest Pro.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, in some ways the Quest Pro is imagine everything about the quest. Imagine
Speaker 8:  a lot of the things you don't really like about the quest that's super front
Speaker 8:  heavy. It's default strap is really bad, it's screen
Speaker 8:  is decent but not the most absolutely high resolution. And
Speaker 8:  you can do this pass through ar but it's only black and white and it's
Speaker 8:  pretty rudimentary. So then just take that and upgrade all of
Speaker 8:  it and fix a lot of that. So it's lighter and
Speaker 8:  thinner. It's, it's not remotely at pair of glasses territory but it's a
Speaker 8:  lot less front heavy. They've done things like move the battery to the back.
Speaker 8:  It's got this high resolution screen that can do color pass through.
Speaker 8:  So you can do this kind of, it's not foe, it's pass through
Speaker 8:  AR that lets you see everything around you. It's got an
Speaker 8:  upgraded processor, it's so it's another snap drag and XR two
Speaker 8:  plus this time instead of XR two, you've got also eye tracking
Speaker 8:  in it, which means that it can do things like a foviated
Speaker 8:  rendering, which is if you're looking at a thing, you're pointing your eyes
Speaker 8:  at it, it renders the image really sharply. Otherwise if it's on
Speaker 8:  your peripheral vision it gets to be a little blurry. And so that saves processing
Speaker 8:  power. It also means that it can read your facial expressions. Mark Zuckerberg
Speaker 8:  made a really big deal out of this with Joe Rogan's podcast where
Speaker 8:  if you're in anything with an avatar, if you're in horizon worlds
Speaker 8:  or a different quote unquote metaverse service, it can mirror your
Speaker 8:  facial expressions, see if you are smiling, see when you're blinking
Speaker 8:  or winking. So it has a lot of those features. It also, I'm sure that we
Speaker 8:  will get into this a little. It's one really big downside is it
Speaker 8:  has, from what I can tell, having not experienced one long
Speaker 8:  consecutive session myself, very bad battery life, I'm told one to
Speaker 8:  two hours, which is compared to like two to three. And I think I've stretched
Speaker 8:  it maybe a little beyond that for the Quest two.
Speaker 4:  I think on the hardware front, like Addie was saying,
Speaker 4:  it's remarkably better than the quest too. And really anything
Speaker 4:  that I've tried, I think Addie's maybe tried some more headsets than I have,
Speaker 4:  but I haven't tried anything that has this level
Speaker 4:  of comfortability optics. I should note this is an important thing. If you
Speaker 4:  wear glasses like me, this thing is much easier to wear with glasses because
Speaker 4:  of just the way it's designed, which is a huge difference for me. I get
Speaker 4:  that like it's just, you know, still large, right?
Speaker 4:  And there's battery constraints, but you can see where it's going. There's
Speaker 4:  a huge question of who this is for, right? It
Speaker 4:  costs 1499 and at that price point you're
Speaker 4:  really not including that kind of
Speaker 4:  casual curious VR user that the Quest two is
Speaker 4:  really targeted at. So they're really making this a
Speaker 4:  concerted enterprise push. I mean we heard with Zuckerberg,
Speaker 4:  he thinks there's really two cohorts of people who will wanna buy
Speaker 4:  this VR diehards who are on the cutting edge and wanna try everything. I'm
Speaker 4:  not sure how many people there are that fit into that bucket, but I'm sure
Speaker 4:  they're out there. It's
Speaker 2:  Like the three of us and 12 other people I think is basically the, the entirety
Speaker 2:  of that
Speaker 4:  Audience there is honestly a budding developer economy here. So, you
Speaker 4:  know, I think that's the other key piece is the point of this is to really
Speaker 4:  kickstart a developer flywheel for mixed reality that can then be poured
Speaker 4:  into the more, you know, consumer cheaper quest lines and
Speaker 4:  future headsets and even air glasses down the road. And then, you
Speaker 4:  know, with the enterprise side, I think because of the price point they're
Speaker 4:  thinking can we just position this for businesses? And you've got that Microsoft
Speaker 4:  partnership that's really broad. It encompasses pretty much all of
Speaker 4:  Microsoft services and most importantly their sales
Speaker 4:  muscle in terms of getting it into businesses that use
Speaker 4:  Azure and Microsoft's device management stuff. So I think that could
Speaker 4:  turn out to be the wild card that if that partnership works, we could all
Speaker 4:  of a sudden see this headset really do well. But
Speaker 4:  if that doesn't work, I'm just really not sure who buys
Speaker 4:  this because with everything a mentioned in the battery life and all that,
Speaker 4:  it's just, it's kind of a tough sell. It's a very cool demo. Like I want
Speaker 4:  to be clear, like we did these, all these demos in it and I was
Speaker 4:  very impressed with the mixed reality and you know, just with the
Speaker 4:  comfortness of it and, and the the fidelity and the, and the face tracking,
Speaker 4:  you know like when you're, when you're looking at an avatar and their eyes
Speaker 4:  actually move and their face moves as they laugh, it's, it's a
Speaker 4:  strange experience. I think people will have kind of a, a bit of an
Speaker 4:  aha moment the first time they experience full face and eye tracking
Speaker 4:  in one of these, you know, virtual worlds. It really does just add a
Speaker 4:  new layer. Yeah, but it's still early. I mean this is, this thing is really
Speaker 4:  a nice piece of hardware and search of software that makes sense for
Speaker 2:  It. Totally. Yeah. The two things I'm, I'm most curious about just from like
Speaker 2:  a demo perspective and I wanna hear kind of the stuff you guys got to try
Speaker 2:  but is the pass through thing, which seems like obviously if we're on this
Speaker 2:  like long road to augmented reality, like making pass through that works
Speaker 2:  really well is really important. So I, I'm curious to hear like what you
Speaker 2:  guys have seen in terms of how that goes. So let's start there. Like what,
Speaker 2:  what did you guys get to try, How did the actual sort of
Speaker 2:  reality pass through camera stuff work?
Speaker 8:  Maybe growing with like two separate categories of demo. There were things
Speaker 8:  that were more or less pure tech demos. There's a face
Speaker 8:  tracking test where you're looking at this alien avatar that can mirror your
Speaker 8:  facial expressions and you can tweak the responsi so you can see
Speaker 8:  how much it perfectly mirrors your face and like how extreme the
Speaker 8:  expressions are. There's a system that's an update of
Speaker 8:  toy Box where it's just a bunch of little things that you can test to see
Speaker 8:  how advanced the controllers are and how precise they are. So you can
Speaker 8:  play operation which is actually kind of great and I love it.
Speaker 8:  Oh wow. In vr
Speaker 2:  That's actually pretty impressive cuz Toy Box is, at least until now has
Speaker 2:  been pretty rudimentary. Like it's fun, you can goof around but like
Speaker 2:  there's nothing that I would call like fine motor skills in a lot of that
Speaker 2:  stuff.
Speaker 8:  You can play Jenga
Speaker 2:  Nice, all right
Speaker 8:  Badly, but I'm bad at real Jenga too. So there's that. And then there's things
Speaker 8:  that are a little bit less clearly toy like and Tech Domo e but are still
Speaker 8:  not really what I would class enterprise or business applications. So they
Speaker 8:  have this genuinely very cool paint system
Speaker 8:  that is a bunch of physical brushes.
Speaker 8:  When I say physical, I mean virtual, but you're in like AR space. You wander
Speaker 8:  around your room, you can pick up these brushes, you have this virtual easel,
Speaker 8:  you can slap paint all over it. You can then take your paintings and you
Speaker 8:  can pin them to the wall because it can detect edges. And so you can
Speaker 8:  create this little virtual gallery. And
Speaker 2:  Just to be clear, this is all in your, you're doing this in your actual space,
Speaker 2:  right? This is not in some like fake VR world. This is happening like if
Speaker 2:  you're in your living room, the idea is you're doing all of this in your
Speaker 2:  actual living room. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  It can detect your walls, it can do some limited object detection. This
Speaker 4:  Is where the concept starts to click, right? I did a
Speaker 4:  painting, the painting demo too, and you, you create a giant
Speaker 4:  canvas and you just stick it on the wall, but it's the real wall in front
Speaker 4:  of you, right? And so that same concept could be applied to monitors,
Speaker 4:  virtual monitors, which was another demo we tried. When you see that and
Speaker 4:  you use it, you go, oh wow, this is actually so much
Speaker 4:  more compelling than this just cutoff fully
Speaker 4:  immersive VR experience that the Quest and every other headset has really
Speaker 4:  had to date. We should note that there have been mixed reality headsets out
Speaker 4:  there. VAIO is one. In Europe it's, it's even more expensive than the
Speaker 4:  Quest Pro. The software's not as good. So this, this is really the first,
Speaker 4:  I think anyone could try this and theoretically get into mixed
Speaker 4:  reality headset. Apple's headset will do something very similar to
Speaker 4:  this when it comes out as soon as next year, which I think is interesting.
Speaker 4:  But this concept of blending the real with the virtual
Speaker 4:  just has a lot more. I think it just makes you wanna stay in it
Speaker 4:  more because you're not just like bumping into things and you, when you're
Speaker 4:  wearing vr, it's like hard to reach for coffee and drink it while you're
Speaker 4:  doing something, right? I mean the Quest has its guardian and all that, but
Speaker 4:  this just really supercharges that and feeling like you're not totally cut
Speaker 4:  off from the world was for me a huge unlock. I don't know about you Addie,
Speaker 4:  but for me it was,
Speaker 8:  It gets a lot closer to the actual, the things we have talked about is
Speaker 8:  mixed reality heads so far, which is things like ho Lens and Magic Leap which
Speaker 8:  have been able to do the pin a virtual screen to the wall thing
Speaker 8:  forever. Microsoft HO Lens has done really sophisticated occlusion. You can
Speaker 8:  like roll a little ball around a room and it'll mirror the physics.
Speaker 8:  But this does it in a package that is a lot
Speaker 8:  more polished for one thing and more comfortable because they've been working
Speaker 8:  on these headsets for ages and that doesn't have the same field of view restrictions
Speaker 8:  like field of view, headsets, field of view in like wave guide
Speaker 8:  based headsets. The kind where you can actually see the real world. It's
Speaker 8:  getting better but it's still just a fraction of what you would get in an
Speaker 8:  Oculus style headset that's like 110 degrees
Speaker 4:  And just the quality of the graphics and the fidelity because you're cheating
Speaker 4:  and essentially just having a video feed piped in of the world around you,
Speaker 4:  you're not actually trying to put graphics over, you know, real light coming
Speaker 4:  in to your eye, right? I mean you're, I, I wouldn't say that this is like
Speaker 4:  approaching real life at all graphics, but it's definitely like I
Speaker 4:  would actually look at a virtual monitor and this thing and it would feel
Speaker 4:  almost as good as like looking at my real monitor, which says something for
Speaker 2:  Folks who haven't actually been able to try this like me, where would you
Speaker 2:  put that on the spectrum of like, you know, cartoon version of my living
Speaker 2:  room all the way up to it looks like my real living room. Like is
Speaker 2:  it like watching a TV show set in my living room kind of vibes.
Speaker 2:  Like how, how good is this actually coming through?
Speaker 8:  That's actually a really good way to put it but that's the way that I think
Speaker 8:  of it is it's a pretty good quality video but
Speaker 8:  it's a fario is still, it has this weird little quirk where
Speaker 8:  it has this super high resolution screen right in the middle of your face.
Speaker 8:  And that is, I still think better. Like if you're looking at a virtual screen,
Speaker 8:  it's not as sharp as a retina display. You can, it starts getting a little
Speaker 8:  fuzzy if you're looking at, I don't know, Google search results. But it's
Speaker 8:  real good
Speaker 4:  And you know, I think to trying this, it kind of fit in well with
Speaker 4:  these other demos that a and I did, you know, I was in Redmond
Speaker 4:  A was in New York, I went to ME'S research headquarters with
Speaker 4:  Michael Abrash and Z was there and and Boz and all these executives
Speaker 4:  and we tried all these demos and I think Addie, you tried them too. And
Speaker 4:  really what you see is like Meta's just constantly trying to say like
Speaker 4:  look we are working on cool stuff that's going to one day
Speaker 4:  blow your mind. And that's been kind of their story since they really
Speaker 4:  got into hardware and especially since the rebrand and the
Speaker 4:  Quest Pro kind of fits into that. Obviously it's a real product. And the
Speaker 4:  other things we tried weren't, like for example, I tried this personalized
Speaker 4:  spatial audio demo. Addie did you get this? I
Speaker 8:  Don't
Speaker 4:  Think I did. Okay. They'd had this incredible like thing where it
Speaker 4:  was spatial audio but like personalized to
Speaker 4:  where movement was in the room in a way that I can't even describe in this
Speaker 4:  podcast. Like it's something you really have to experience. It was one of
Speaker 4:  the coolest, most visceral demos of technology I've ever
Speaker 4:  experienced. It's not gonna be a product for a really long time. Same thing
Speaker 4:  with their EMG control labs band that lets you
Speaker 4:  essentially control, you know, these headsets with you know,
Speaker 4:  very fine neurons movements and muscle movements in your
Speaker 4:  arm. Which
Speaker 8:  We should be clear that's not like even remotely linked to this, the Quest
Speaker 8:  Pro at this time.
Speaker 4:  No it's not. They hope it will be but like just the theme of the day for
Speaker 4:  me and this included the pro demo was like look at all this cool stuff we're
Speaker 4:  building. We are a serious hardware and research company and they are, they
Speaker 4:  just don't have a compelling mainstream product
Speaker 4:  yet. Right. The quest too is I think estimates say it's, it's sold more
Speaker 4:  than the Xbox, right? It's at a 15 ish million units, which is nothing to
Speaker 4:  like, you know, shake a stick at like I wanna be clear but you know with
Speaker 4:  this pro device it's just like this isn't gonna set the world on fire, right?
Speaker 4:  Like they may sell a few million of these, right? They may get some big enterprise
Speaker 4:  deployments, they're gonna do one with Accenture, right? Which is a ton of
Speaker 4:  people but you know, it still is just gonna be a while for this tech I think
Speaker 4:  to really catch on. And I don't think the pro is that device that maybe
Speaker 4:  some people expected would be like that big aha moment for
Speaker 4:  these headsets.
Speaker 8:  The pro really feels like it is one generation before the thing that actually
Speaker 8:  is useful. It's, yeah so in like tech development there's the concept of
Speaker 8:  the time machine, which is where you compromise on all the stuff that you
Speaker 8:  think is gonna get really good in like five years or so if, I don't know,
Speaker 8:  prices of things come down, batteries get better or whatever. And then you
Speaker 8:  just try to make the best version of the actually hard
Speaker 8:  stuff. The stuff you think is actually hard. That's kind of what this feels
Speaker 8:  like. The battery's not great, the screen, like the pass through camera
Speaker 8:  could get sharper, the screen could get sharper but it has all of
Speaker 8:  the sort of building blocks of this thing that it seems like they think are
Speaker 8:  gonna get into all headsets in five years. Stuff like
Speaker 8:  eye tracking
Speaker 4:  And they have a lot of work to do on the software, right? I think they're
Speaker 4:  actually a lot farther along on the hardware front here. It's,
Speaker 4:  it's impressive honestly that a software company has managed to build
Speaker 4:  such quality hardware in a short amount of time. I think it's actually, I
Speaker 4:  mean Google's starting to do this as well but I think on the software side
Speaker 4:  there's just so much room left. Like you know Addie, I think you
Speaker 4:  mentioned your work rooms, which is their kind of VR like work
Speaker 4:  experience demo was buggy, mine was buggy as well. It was hard to
Speaker 4:  like load certain apps.
Speaker 2:  Well and Alex you had a story just last week that about
Speaker 2:  basically like even Meta knows Horizon is not where it
Speaker 2:  needs to be for all of this stuff.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I mean they can't get their own employees to dog food and
Speaker 4:  internally test horizon, right? Like the head of Horizon is sending memos
Speaker 4:  saying, look, I'm gonna make you all at least use this once a week because
Speaker 4:  it's just not compelling yet. And that, and I'm talking about Horizon Worlds,
Speaker 4:  which is essentially like their Roblox meets the Oasis in
Speaker 4:  VR type experience where you just hang out with avatars. Like there wasn't
Speaker 4:  a Horizon Worlds demo with the Pro, right? They're really trying to say like,
Speaker 4:  no, we want you to use this for Autodesk and we want you to use this for
Speaker 4:  Adobe software.
Speaker 8:  But it's also notably me that they did not show Autodesk or Adobe software
Speaker 8:  or flight simulators or any of the things that if you go to a company that
Speaker 8:  like HTC that actually cares about enterprise that they will show you,
Speaker 4:  Right? This stuff's not ready. Like the Microsoft stuff. I didn't see any,
Speaker 4:  I didn't get to experience any of the Microsoft stuff like teams in VR or
Speaker 4:  anything like that. Not that that's like a thrilling experience or a demo
Speaker 4:  to write about but this stuff is just early, right? I think like I kind of
Speaker 4:  expected there to be more done on the software side this year frankly.
Speaker 2:  Well and I think one of the big open questions for me, especially with some
Speaker 2:  of this news stuff is like what are they gonna give
Speaker 2:  you to do with it, right? Cause like you're, you're describing these like
Speaker 2:  very cool tech demos. It's, it's like neat and fun but then it's like okay,
Speaker 2:  what most people do when they put on these headsets is like they play Beat
Speaker 2:  Saber and like being able to read my facial expressions is
Speaker 2:  like not gonna make Beat Saber any more fun in any obvious way that I
Speaker 2:  totally understand. And so we're sort of getting to the point where it's
Speaker 2:  like either things like horizon worlds need to start to like really click
Speaker 2:  for people or meta needs to keep inventing and coming up
Speaker 2:  with new things to do for people that actually matches
Speaker 2:  this very cool technology that it's building. Like it's, it's funny you mentioned
Speaker 2:  teams Alex, because that's the kind of thing where it's like, okay now I
Speaker 2:  can see why if you're gonna work with Microsoft having
Speaker 2:  expressions that work and match human expressions, like that's a real meaningful
Speaker 2:  edition you've just made to my like video conferencing life in VR. And we
Speaker 2:  can debate whether video conferencing in VR is like a thing that should exist
Speaker 2:  in the world, but that's a whole separate story. But I do wonder, like I
Speaker 2:  feel like we're at this pace now we're at the, the sort of r and d team is
Speaker 2:  so far ahead of even what the like product team is trying to think
Speaker 2:  about what to do with at this moment. It's gonna be weird, it's gonna be
Speaker 2:  interesting to see if they can catch up to that. But Addie also, it feels
Speaker 2:  like that's the whole industry right now, right? Like I feel like every headset
Speaker 2:  you try on, that's the story. It's like cool technology, I don't know what
Speaker 2:  I'm supposed to do with this. Some
Speaker 8:  Of it, I think that the thing about a lot of enterprise work is that
Speaker 8:  it ends up making compromises that seem like they're
Speaker 8:  making a consumer experience worse but it's because they have
Speaker 8:  actual partners who are using their headsets for real things and the partners
Speaker 8:  say this is the extremely specific thing I need and then they just
Speaker 8:  tailor it toward that. And this seems like meta deliberately not doing
Speaker 8:  that. It seems like they're trying to make an all around consumer headset.
Speaker 8:  They just know that they can't sell it at a consumer price yet.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I think that's fair. And I think just they don't have the enterprise
Speaker 4:  software side built up yet. You know, if we talk again in, in a year, right,
Speaker 4:  and we're on the Quest Pro two, the Microsoft software has been integrated,
Speaker 4:  it's starting to get deployed in like factories and tankers, you
Speaker 4:  know, oil rigs, stuff like that. We may be having a different conversation.
Speaker 4:  I think, you know, know Zuckerberg based on my conversations with
Speaker 4:  him, seems okay with this thing being kind of a
Speaker 4:  dud in terms of sales as long as it starts getting developers interested
Speaker 4:  in this mixed reality face tracking stuff and if he can just build, start
Speaker 4:  to build that ecosystem with the hardware, you know, maybe build better hardware
Speaker 4:  down the road, I think that's still a win for them. So I don't think they're
Speaker 4:  expecting this thing to set the world on
Speaker 2:  Fire. So does that mean in meta's head that the Quest two is still kind
Speaker 2:  of the mainstream device for the foreseeable future?
Speaker 4:  For now what they've basically decided to do is create two lines. So there's
Speaker 4:  gonna be a pro line and then the more consumer quest line,
Speaker 4:  you know Zuckerberg said in the interview there's gonna be a Quest three,
Speaker 4:  I think you mentioned four, even five, right? They have multi-year hardware
Speaker 4:  amendments. They're like in this like Google tells you they're in hardware
Speaker 4:  for the long haul, right? I, what I think we're gonna see is the cadence
Speaker 4:  of a new consumer quest next year and then a pro again the following
Speaker 4:  year and then every other year it's gonna be that back and forth. It's funny
Speaker 4:  like there he wasn't really clear with me as we heard like
Speaker 4:  about how they're making money on this, but it's clear that it's still gonna
Speaker 4:  be a long, long time before these headsets give any kind
Speaker 4:  of, you know, money back to meta that that flows in a meaningful way
Speaker 4:  to them. I think they're may be making a slight profit on the, on a per unit
Speaker 4:  basis, but I mean we heard 'em say like no way when you factor in everything
Speaker 4:  else,
Speaker 2:  Right? Yeah, I mean I liked that his, his overarching message whenever you
Speaker 2:  asked him about money was basically like, we are prepared to spend a
Speaker 2:  tremendous amount of money to make all of this work and like if it does we'll
Speaker 2:  make so much money in the long run it won't matter and if it doesn't we're
Speaker 2:  all screwed anyway so it doesn't matter. Like
Speaker 4:  That's I think a pretty good, pretty good assessment. But
Speaker 2:  I guess the good news is then it seems like for Quest two users is
Speaker 2:  that like if they've done all this work to make it more balanced and feel
Speaker 2:  better on your head, like this should give people hope for the Quest three,
Speaker 2:  right? That some of this stuff might come to that even the less advanced
Speaker 2:  tech but like a nicer headset to wear for long periods of time could be in
Speaker 2:  folks' future, which seems like a win.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I think you're gonna see this face tracking and mixed reality stuff
Speaker 4:  come into the cheaper quest line. They just have to figure out how to do
Speaker 4:  that at a cheaper price point and at scale. And that's what this first pro
Speaker 4:  was kind of meant to show them. So this tech is definitely gonna come downstream
Speaker 4:  to everything. That's the whole idea is to seed the more expensive far
Speaker 4:  out stuff in the pro line before the the Quest line and eventually the ideas
Speaker 4:  this all eventually converges with AR glasses, which are
Speaker 4:  still several years out.
Speaker 8:  Alex, what did you think of the stylists, the stylist is the goofiest part
Speaker 8:  of this headset to me? Yeah,
Speaker 4:  They have this, you know, the I the controllers are a huge upgrade and they
Speaker 4:  have this haptic kind of stylist experience. I don't know, I
Speaker 4:  thought I was fine. I'm not gonna be like writing on little virtual sticky
Speaker 4:  notes on a, they love this idea of like, you go up to a whiteboard
Speaker 4:  in VR or mixed reality and pen of VR sticky note and you can
Speaker 4:  have unlimited ones and you can erase everything and move. I'm just like,
Speaker 4:  I, I don't like sticky notes in real life. I don't know why I would want
Speaker 4:  them in virtual reality or why I would want to like the time it takes
Speaker 4:  to draw something, right? Like if I'm in a computer, I wanna
Speaker 4:  do things as quickly as possible. That's the whole reason I'm using a computer.
Speaker 4:  So I think this concept of like bringing human, you know, the way that
Speaker 4:  we have to do things physically into VR is like how iOS used
Speaker 4:  to be sic, right? It's like we're just in this phase of like trying to
Speaker 4:  integrate virtual and physical and we haven't figured out the new virtual
Speaker 4:  paradigms of how we actually do things efficiently, right? And the same,
Speaker 4:  I don't know. So I guess I'm saying I wasn't that impressed
Speaker 2:  About this is just sitting here like I have thousands of virtual sticky notes
Speaker 2:  all over my apartment right now.
Speaker 8:  I should maybe describe it a little bit because it's honestly even weirder
Speaker 8:  than the thing that, the way you're describing it, which is that there is,
Speaker 8:  you can hold the controller and typically there's this wristband at the bottom.
Speaker 8:  You can unclip the wristband and then put the world's tiniest
Speaker 8:  plastic nub onto where the wristband at the bottom was. And then you flip
Speaker 8:  the controller around and you hold it backwards and then you can hold it
Speaker 8:  like a pen, like incredibly thick marker and you press down on
Speaker 8:  a real surface and the ideas that it's supposed to give you actual visceral
Speaker 8:  like feedback because you're on a table or a wall or something. It's just
Speaker 8:  such a weird addition. I don't know, I'm just, I want
Speaker 8:  to understand the process by which they came up with this idea and
Speaker 8:  decided to implement it.
Speaker 4:  I get it. This, we wanna have this for businesses. You know, you need a stylist
Speaker 4:  if you're, you know, a thought worker or whatever. Like do
Speaker 8:  You, does anyone think
Speaker 4:  That? I don't know. Please write into David call the Verge cast
Speaker 4:  hotline if you use a stylist on a daily basis and we'll put them all in the
Speaker 4:  next episode per
Speaker 2:  Sold eight hours on stylists. I'm ready for this. Literally anytime. Well
Speaker 8:  The thing that makes me wonder about is like whether they're going to try
Speaker 8:  to sell this as AER art device. Like one of the only
Speaker 8:  actually business oriented things business loosely that I tried was a DJ
Speaker 8:  deck where the idea was that it was super clear and it has all this very
Speaker 8:  fine feedback so you can turn little knobs and see everything. And I think
Speaker 8:  that if you're trying to do something that you wanna have a really
Speaker 8:  big canvas for, here's a world where VR headsets are good art
Speaker 8:  tools. I think this is not the world we're in right now, but I wonder if
Speaker 8:  that's the kind of thing that eventually they try for,
Speaker 2:  It's also what all of these companies are desperate to have people do, right?
Speaker 2:  It's why these VR companies talk so much about like architects
Speaker 2:  and creatives and car designers. It's like, it's just such a sexy
Speaker 2:  use case to have people making this stuff. And if you give them these
Speaker 2:  like fine tools, like I can totally imagine the meeting that led
Speaker 2:  to we have to make a VR stylist. Whether or not anybody will use it I, I
Speaker 2:  think is a, is a completely different story. But I can absolutely imagine
Speaker 2:  like the room in the Microsoft offices where somebody was
Speaker 2:  like, but but how will I create my beautiful drawings in virtual
Speaker 2:  reality with these dumb controllers? And then somebody is like, I don't
Speaker 4:  Think anybody draws on whiteboards anymore. If, correct me if I'm wrong,
Speaker 4:  you know, DME at Alexy Heath. I don't, I think whiteboards are
Speaker 4:  not long for this world personally. I will just say before we move
Speaker 4:  off this, cuz I feel like this is important going into this demo, I really
Speaker 4:  wanted the virtual office demo to blow me away cuz I've been
Speaker 4:  been reporting on what this headset is gonna be like. I know the direction
Speaker 4:  they're going. Mixed reality, the concept of not having a big
Speaker 4:  monitor in front of me at my desk, having a comfortable headset and huge
Speaker 4:  giant monitors everywhere I want and a keyboard in front of me and being
Speaker 4:  able to do my work that way. That I would buy a headset, I would buy a
Speaker 4:  $2,000 headset for that, right? If it had spatial audio and all these things,
Speaker 4:  the demo was not that good and it wasn't because the mixed reality
Speaker 4:  wasn't great. It's just, you know, these little things like the keyboard
Speaker 4:  tracking, like my keyboard was fuzzy, right? And so I'm like looking and
Speaker 4:  I don't touch type like Addie, so like I need to look down sometimes and
Speaker 4:  it was buggy and kind of slow and it's like you just, you feel that one to
Speaker 4:  two second like delay between your input and
Speaker 4:  something happening that's like I could be more productive in real life.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 8:  You have an operating system on top of your operating system at
Speaker 4:  This point. Exactly. And until they cross that threshold where, you
Speaker 4:  know, it is literally just as fast as like typing into my browser on
Speaker 4:  my monitor at home. I think the work from home
Speaker 4:  mixed reality headset idea that all these companies want to have is
Speaker 4:  not gonna happen. And I really thought it might happen with this headset,
Speaker 4:  but I don't think anyone's gonna be sitting there even plugged in at their
Speaker 4:  desk cuz they have to be, cuz the battery life, I don't think people are
Speaker 4:  gonna be sitting there for hours, you know, browsing in their Quest
Speaker 4:  Pro.
Speaker 8:  I'm really curious where reality os, if they had really pushed on the
Speaker 8:  idea that they wanted their own operating system would've gone
Speaker 4:  Well, they're still working on it. I think, you know, I and others have reported
Speaker 4:  on this that there was some internal tension about do we do a fully custom
Speaker 4:  OS in the near future or do we still rely on Android? This is an still an
Speaker 4:  Android based system, I think they still want to do a
Speaker 4:  fully integrated os. It's just doing that on the
Speaker 4:  time scale that they wanted for the air glasses wasn't gonna make sense.
Speaker 4:  And it's one of those things that they're working and kind of fiddling with
Speaker 4:  in the background and maybe one day, you know, we'll see something like that.
Speaker 4:  And maybe that does solve it. You know, that's the problem is that they're
Speaker 4:  not this kind of full stack software to hardware company like Apple
Speaker 4:  is. And that's really where I think Apple's strategic advantage in this space
Speaker 4:  where that really matters in something like a headset is gonna make a huge
Speaker 4:  difference.
Speaker 2:  Totally. All right, we needed to take a break. Thank you both. But stick
Speaker 2:  around and we are gonna come back and talk about VR gaming, which is not
Speaker 2:  what Mark Zuckerberg wants to talk about, but it's a thing a lot of people
Speaker 2:  do when they put on their headsets while we
Speaker 2:  ride
Speaker 2:  back.
Speaker 9:  Kara Swisher here, you may know me as the person who made Mark Zuckerberg's
Speaker 9:  sweat pushed Kim Kardashian to talk dollars or got Secretary
Speaker 9:  Mayor Pete Buttigieg to eat a juicy strawberry live
Speaker 9:  on stage. Okay, that one was awkward, but
Speaker 9:  that's what I like to do. Make powerful people comfortable with
Speaker 9:  being uncomfortable. Now I'll be doing that on my new show from New
Speaker 9:  York Magazine on with Kara Swisher. We'll bring you news and the news
Speaker 9:  makers I'm paying attention to and we'll do it twice a week on Mondays
Speaker 9:  and Thursdays. Go check it out on with Kara Swisher wherever you
Speaker 9:  get
Speaker 9:  your
Speaker 9:  podcasts.
Speaker 10:  Hey everybody, it's Eli Editor in Chief of the Verge. I am thrilled to announce
Speaker 10:  that after two years of work we're unveiling a brand new redesign of
Speaker 10:  our site@theverge.com. We've got all the basics, we've got a fresh,
Speaker 10:  modern, new logo, we've got really fast and beautiful new article
Speaker 10:  pages. They're bright colors all over the site that highlight our award-winning
Speaker 10:  journalism. But most importantly, we have a brand new homepage.
Speaker 10:  It brings the best of old school blogging to a modern
Speaker 10:  newsfeed experience so we can take the entire noisy world of
Speaker 10:  tech and science all over the internet and have our expert, senior reporters
Speaker 10:  and editors curate it for you all day long. It's a really big change. I
Speaker 10:  like to say that we're gonna revolutionize the media with blog posts and
Speaker 10:  I think we are, Check it out, it's at the verge.com
Speaker 10:  right
Speaker 10:  now.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. As we've been talking about the tech industry's vision for
Speaker 2:  VR and mixed reality and AR and whatever you wanna call it,
Speaker 2:  is huge, too huge, some would argue, but it's huge.
Speaker 2:  But even Mark Zuckerberg knows it's gonna take a number of years to
Speaker 2:  get to that point. So what is VR good for right now? Ask
Speaker 2:  around and almost everyone will give you the same answer. Games
Speaker 2:  before. VR is the future of video chat and music and like
Speaker 2:  society at large. It is potentially the future of video
Speaker 2:  games, but how's that going to figure it out? I called up Chris Grant, who
Speaker 2:  is the Verges group publisher and was formerly the editor in chief of our
Speaker 2:  sister publication Polygon Chris Grant. Hello, thank you for being
Speaker 2:  here.
Speaker 11:  Great pleasure.
Speaker 2:  You are a person who plays video games. I think it is safe to say, are you
Speaker 2:  also a person who plays VR video games? Like what's your, what's your
Speaker 2:  VR setup right now?
Speaker 11:  I do have a quest too. I have been known to play games inside
Speaker 11:  virtual reality at times. I would say I largely find those to be, let's
Speaker 11:  call them detours in my gaming habits, not necessarily
Speaker 11:  destinations. What
Speaker 2:  Do you play? What gets booted up first when you start playing the Quest
Speaker 11:  Re before, which is a whole as game that they put
Speaker 11:  into vr. Yeah, and one of the things that we could talk about, but I, VR
Speaker 11:  for me is not a place to play whole as games. It's a, it's a place
Speaker 11:  to play 20 minute sections of games here and there. So I, I would
Speaker 11:  say the game I'm playing is resonating before still maybe forever.
Speaker 2:  Wait, that's really interesting. So I wanna talk about the like business
Speaker 2:  mechanics of all this, but you just raised to think I think is really interesting.
Speaker 2:  Like my assumption with all of this has been that if only VR
Speaker 2:  could get good enough games, it would move up
Speaker 2:  that ladder and start to be like, instead of sitting down on your couch to
Speaker 2:  play your PS five, you would stand up and put on your quest too. And the
Speaker 2:  only reason you're not doing that is because the games aren't good enough.
Speaker 2:  But you're kind of making me think that maybe that's just not true. Like
Speaker 2:  maybe the activity is so different that it's just not the thing you're gonna
Speaker 2:  wanna do. Even if the games are amazing. Resume
Speaker 11:  Before is a banger all time classic and the VR
Speaker 11:  adaptation's excellent, not only does it look good, but they redid the whole
Speaker 11:  thing in Unreal Engine, but it plays really well. It's a, it's a smart reinterpretation
Speaker 11:  of the game. It just, I don't wanna spend more than half an hour at a time
Speaker 11:  with a heavy sweaty headset on my head getting freaked out by
Speaker 11:  zombies with their heads popping off. I do think the mechanics of games,
Speaker 11:  and we could talk about the sort of business of, of the Oculus store, but
Speaker 11:  the mechanics of games and the refinement of game mechanics to a controller.
Speaker 11:  We can say keyword of mouse too, if that's your, that's your thing. But
Speaker 11:  the refinement of those mechanics is not a casual thing. Right? That's 30
Speaker 11:  years of UX and player input evolution. Yeah. And the games and the sort
Speaker 11:  of systems and vernacular of games that have been adapted to that are pretty
Speaker 11:  sophisticated. And so I think a VR cement like the we, it has a huge
Speaker 11:  wow effect. You play a VR game and you go, Whoa, I I'm gonna
Speaker 11:  get me one of those, I'm gonna lose weight tomorrow. Right? In the same
Speaker 11:  way that the we and we fit where this huge wow effect, right? You're gonna
Speaker 11:  play we sports every day. This is the next step in your journey
Speaker 11:  to physical perfection. And people bought the Wes and they bought the wee
Speaker 11:  fits and they, and that system had relative so very low attach rate. People
Speaker 11:  were not buying games, they got the we and they put it under their couch.
Speaker 11:  Interesting. And so for me, the big question on Quest is like people buy
Speaker 11:  them, it's selling very well. Quest two, what are they doing with it, right?
Speaker 11:  It was a huge seller last Christmas. What are they doing with it? Are they
Speaker 11:  actually playing games? How much are they playing? What kinds of games are
Speaker 11:  they playing? And then in turn, what kinds of games should developers build
Speaker 11:  for that audience? What do they want? What will they pay for it? And I don't
Speaker 11:  know, I'm I'm, I don't think there's right answers there yet.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I mean it's interesting cuz like I I think about the the like canonical
Speaker 2:  games of vr, right? You get the like the Beat Savers and the Super Hots of
Speaker 2:  the world and the thing a lot of those games have in common is they're
Speaker 2:  super deliberately designed to be played for short periods of time that it's
Speaker 2:  like there is no game in VR that is like play this for eight straight hours.
Speaker 2:  Like it just, it just doesn't exist. It's like a 30 minute activity and then
Speaker 2:  you move on.
Speaker 11:  Yeah. Arcade tower, even short levels, right? Supernatural being another
Speaker 11:  sort of VR hit, very beat savory, but with all
Speaker 11:  the self-help mechanics of going to the gym or going club
Speaker 11:  plus a subscription which fixes the economics. Yeah, the logic of that makes
Speaker 11:  a lot of sense to me. That's something that VR is very good at and can sort
Speaker 11:  of duplicate. There's the exercises you're gonna do are somewhat limited,
Speaker 11:  but you're not gonna exercise for eight hours. You're not gonna have a sesh
Speaker 11:  in the same way. But I think before is like a famously long game,
Speaker 11:  games long, it's a lot of, it's not an eight hour game, it's like a 20 hour
Speaker 11:  game. And so you're playing games like that and you're not gonna do it in
Speaker 11:  the same kind of session. It's exhausting both physically but also like
Speaker 11:  input wise, right? The amount of inputs you're receiving is is just a
Speaker 11:  lot. There's some eye strained stuff and like Perce and
Speaker 11:  other things where you might just get a little bit, you know, soured on
Speaker 11:  a stint that long but at some point maybe glasses get better, they get
Speaker 11:  smaller, all those other things might fix that problem. But you still wanna
Speaker 11:  be moving around and like doing gun play in your living
Speaker 11:  room for more than 30 minutes at a time. And I, you know, I do think that
Speaker 11:  there's a world in which we use VR headsets to play traditional games with
Speaker 11:  a controller our lap on a giant 200 inch virtual screen
Speaker 11:  that seems interesting to me. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  It's like the Netflix things where basically it's like you're watching Netflix
Speaker 2:  but it's as if you're in a movie theater on a gigantic screen. I think like
Speaker 2:  as resolutions get higher, that actually seems like it'll be very cool. It's
Speaker 2:  not there yet but it's the kind of thing that I can sort of see where that
Speaker 2:  would go with something like the experience that we've had. It's like, it
Speaker 2:  always reminds me of the people who like sit in stadiums and play
Speaker 2:  Mario Cart on the jumbotron. It's like just the, the novelty of
Speaker 2:  that is worth it and is very cool. But, so, okay, so coming at this from
Speaker 2:  like the business side right there, there's been this question for a long
Speaker 2:  time of like where are the AAA games, right? Like where is the the halo for
Speaker 2:  vr, why isn't Call of Duty coming to vr? And my assumption
Speaker 2:  has just always been that there's this like chicken and egg problem of these
Speaker 2:  games are very expensive to make and there aren't enough people who have
Speaker 2:  these headsets to be able to make them very profitable. And until they are,
Speaker 2:  they're not gonna make the games. But until they make the games, there's
Speaker 2:  not gonna be enough people buying the headsets to make them profitable. Do
Speaker 2:  you think it's that or is it just that this is like a fundamentally different
Speaker 2:  thing and we're gonna have to do fundamentally different things with it?
Speaker 11:  I don't think it's just chicken or egg. So I think some of it, you know,
Speaker 11:  they've sold 15 million or so Quest twos, that's
Speaker 11:  roughly what they've sold of Xbox Series X and S to
Speaker 11:  date came out roughly the same time. There's more triple A games on that
Speaker 11:  platform. Why the audience is proven that they will purchase
Speaker 11:  60 to 78 now dollar games and play them for long periods of time and purchased
Speaker 11:  them over and over again. That the, the console lifespan has a certain
Speaker 11:  fixed expectation. I think a lot of development just isn't clear on what
Speaker 11:  that is for vr. You're gonna make a big investment for what? For Facebook's
Speaker 11:  digital store. Like is that, how long will it be around for? Will the, will
Speaker 11:  my game work on Future Hardware? Where is their long term hardware commitment?
Speaker 11:  Do they wanna make games? I think Facebook has already sort of, I don't
Speaker 11:  wanna say straight up like Osborne effect, but they're already very
Speaker 11:  clearly telegraphing this isn't a game platform, right? This is where you're
Speaker 11:  gonna do your job in the future. This is where you're gonna go on dates,
Speaker 11:  right? Like they're, they're just out there. I think even in the store they
Speaker 11:  call it experiences now, not games. Like what are the top selling experiences?
Speaker 11:  Which
Speaker 2:  Is bonkers to me because it is so transparently going to either work or not
Speaker 2:  work as a game platform way before any of that becomes anything like this
Speaker 2:  is the thing about this that drives me kind of nuts
Speaker 11:  I think. So some of it is is about that it's about, you know, it's the install
Speaker 11:  basis strong, but what's that attach rate? How many people are gonna buy
Speaker 11:  games on it? How many games are they gonna buy? How much time are they gonna
Speaker 11:  spend in the game? And and consoles like the Xbox and PlayStation
Speaker 11:  consoles, Nintendo's consoles obviously have proven to have very high attach
Speaker 11:  rates and very high amounts of time spent. I think it's also about the price
Speaker 11:  and what kind of games you can make with it. And this isn't to diminish
Speaker 11:  the hardware, right? The Switch is an old Tera based
Speaker 11:  Android console. But the quest too is, is also
Speaker 11:  running effectively cell phone hardware. And so from a production
Speaker 11:  standpoint, they're not gonna make a AAA game the way we think of AAA on
Speaker 11:  at least an Xbox in a PlayStation. They could make something where we think
Speaker 11:  of it on a switch, but from a sheer production
Speaker 11:  cost standpoint, it will not be as expensive to make games on that
Speaker 11:  platform because it doesn't have the graphics capabilities that would require
Speaker 11:  that kind of production to develop. It's part of it.
Speaker 2:  So like the reason to not make Call of Duty for VR is because you literally
Speaker 2:  just can't, you
Speaker 11:  Can make a Call of Duty, right? And Call of Duty on mobile's successful
Speaker 11:  PUBG on mobile's successful. Like there's other ways to make those games.
Speaker 11:  Fortnite on mobile's obviously successful when and if you can get it in
Speaker 11:  various app stores in per ongoing lawsuits. But
Speaker 11:  for mobile games and I think you know VR thing of VR is a way like
Speaker 11:  a mobile adjacent platform. This is not as simple
Speaker 11:  as just porting something from a thing. It's entirely different audience
Speaker 11:  in some ways of who's buying these things and what they intend to get out
Speaker 11:  of it. I think you can also look at the store, just look at the stores themselves
Speaker 11:  and see what the average price is for games that are on the top selling
Speaker 11:  list. It's not $60, there's nothing for $60 on
Speaker 2:  There, right? It's a lot of like 20 and 30 bucks.
Speaker 11:  Which also tells me like what do people think they're getting when they
Speaker 11:  spend $20 on a game? They don't think they're getting a $60 game on sale
Speaker 11:  for 20, they think they're getting a $20 game. It's gonna have a different
Speaker 11:  level of engagement and have a different level of depth, probably a different
Speaker 11:  level of length. A lot of these games and you look through the top sellers
Speaker 11:  list, they are aad, you know Creed, Rice Glory, you have like a
Speaker 11:  boxing game. It's punch Audi not again, not to diminish that kind of game.
Speaker 11:  I think that is the kind of experience you want. Richie's plank walking
Speaker 11:  experience is still on the top list. Like that's a one of my fas on Quest
Speaker 11:  too. Yeah, it's the best party game for vr. You give it to people and you
Speaker 11:  watch them embarrass themselves is they walk out over a plank. Yeah. You
Speaker 11:  know, down the side of a skyscraper. This is I guess to be fair
Speaker 11:  to, to meta slash Facebook, this is not a game, this is an experience
Speaker 11:  and that's a top seller. So like what do people want out of this? And I
Speaker 11:  love what they want is novelty. They want to move their bodies, they want
Speaker 11:  fitness and they want motion. I don't know what the triple A
Speaker 11:  audience looks like there and in so much as there is a triple A audience
Speaker 11:  that wants triple A games, these are in some ways solved
Speaker 11:  problems. We have triple A experiences on console and I'd
Speaker 11:  be, we're miss have to bring up obviously PlayStation vr, PSV two.
Speaker 2:  I was just about to ask Yeah cuz Sony seems like it should be the one with
Speaker 2:  the most to gain by theoretically like fusing some of those two things together,
Speaker 2:  right? Like big install base full of people who will spend money, who
Speaker 11:  Like triple A games, right?
Speaker 2:  Who like big feeling expensive games
Speaker 11:  And PSV R one sold you know like 6 million units. This is not going to change
Speaker 11:  the world. This is, I don't think there was anything close to like a runaway
Speaker 11:  hit. They had some interesting experiences there. They had Batman Acam
Speaker 11:  game kind of thing that was neat that ran off the same engine was maybe
Speaker 11:  the same team getting games that exist in this world that are really
Speaker 11:  good. They had a Sobo Studios who, who did Astro bot, which
Speaker 11:  was still is the best PlayStation five game. I'm sorry, please don't at
Speaker 11:  me, but that's the right answer. Fair enough. They made a VR version of
Speaker 11:  that game that was excellent, right? Platformer graphics weren't super,
Speaker 11:  didn't have to be, it was a lot of fun to play in VR and the same, I thought
Speaker 11:  Lucky Tale was a lot of fun to play. And then the first quest when the Rift,
Speaker 11:  when it came out, geez, long time ago. So I think there are these sorts
Speaker 11:  of experiences that are like triple A light that you can do in vr. You know,
Speaker 11:  Sony showed off for places of VR too, which will be a tethered
Speaker 11:  headset, it will not be standalone the way Quest is, which gives it the
Speaker 11:  power, the processing power of the PlayStation five. They can put
Speaker 11:  significantly better graphics in this thing than they could put on a quest
Speaker 11:  by a long shot. But you have a tether on you which also limits the amount
Speaker 11:  of physical freedom or mobility you're gonna have, which probably changes
Speaker 11:  the kind of games you're gonna make. The install base isn't portable to
Speaker 11:  other VR headsets depending on the kind of game you make. If you're making
Speaker 11:  a game that's gonna use all that power, it's kind of pretty much going PC
Speaker 11:  and on PlayStation five and that's it. But they have a horizon game, a
Speaker 11:  game using the the horizon setting. And I think you
Speaker 11:  play Allway in it but it's a bow and arrow game, you know what I mean? Like
Speaker 11:  there's all these different combat mechanics in the console game but in
Speaker 11:  the VR game you shoot a bow. Why? Cuz it feels good
Speaker 11:  to shoot a bow in vr. Yep. It does not feel good to jump
Speaker 11:  into, run into all these other things. And so playing to the strengths of
Speaker 11:  the platform is good at that. What feels good inside of VR is
Speaker 11:  smart, but that game, as far as I can tell, I have not demoed PSV two yet.
Speaker 11:  It's gonna be AAA in a sense production wise, but is it gonna
Speaker 11:  be triple A in terms of length, in terms of game play depth now? But I think
Speaker 11:  we have to reevaluate what, what triple A might mean on vr.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, it does seem like, I just get a kick outta the fact that like in the
Speaker 2:  Quest store in particular, it seems like the single most common review
Speaker 2:  is like fun game too short four stars, it's like over and
Speaker 2:  over and over again. It's like, boy that was cool and it was 20 minutes and
Speaker 2:  now I'm kind of wondering like, okay, if they took that game and gave you
Speaker 2:  six hours of it, like is that, is that actually what you want? Are we
Speaker 2:  sure And I think it's super interesting but then I think about the, the sort
Speaker 2:  of flip side of this, like to go back to the the sort of Fortnite and pubs
Speaker 2:  of the world, that kind of thing seems like it should be in
Speaker 2:  theory like perfectly suited for some of these devices. Whether they
Speaker 2:  become like the VR versions of themselves and like game streaming theoretically
Speaker 2:  solves some of these processing problems over time. And so it feels, it
Speaker 2:  just feels like maybe we're sort of winding towards a world
Speaker 2:  where a thing you wear on your face with a mobile processor isn't the sort
Speaker 2:  of gating thing at once was. And then we come back to this sort of like fundamental
Speaker 2:  question of is this actually what you want? Like is, is VR Fortnite the
Speaker 2:  way Fortnite is currently constructed actually a thing that you would want?
Speaker 2:  And the longer we talk, the more I'm thinking the answer is maybe not.
Speaker 11:  I mean to make a decision VR I'll, I'll redefine Fortnite not as a first
Speaker 11:  person shooter slash building battle royal game, but just a game. A
Speaker 11:  place you hang out with friends. Yes. In the sense, in that sense, Fortnite,
Speaker 11:  Roblox, Minecraft, maybe those are all different solutions to the same kind
Speaker 11:  of problem. I do think it's reasonable to assume that there might be some
Speaker 11:  kind of game that you have a VR interface where you are mostly
Speaker 11:  socializing or hanging out while also performing a shared activity like
Speaker 11:  shooting something. Mark
Speaker 2:  Zuckerberg is so happy you just said that by the way.
Speaker 11:  I know I'm gonna mark cool your chat's butt. I'm about to, about to take
Speaker 11:  you down a notch I think for vr I, I wanted to bring up two other examples
Speaker 11:  on, on consoles, but something that's about the time you spend or or what
Speaker 11:  you're doing there. You know on consoles one of the things you get from
Speaker 11:  console based VR headset is you get AL seven. I think it's still a go to
Speaker 11:  example of a full blown actual game that's new. This is not
Speaker 11:  a port like Revo five where they just put a VR mode in it, right?
Speaker 11:  V re oh seven was first unveiled, was unveiled in a, what was called the
Speaker 11:  kitchen demo and it was just this kitchen scene that ended up being in the
Speaker 11:  game kind of a version the game. But in VR it's unveiled for psvr it was
Speaker 11:  freaky af and it turns out the whole game's in vr, they just announced re
Speaker 11:  eight is also gonna have a full VR mode. Like this is kind of wild that
Speaker 11:  they do this, but this idea that like that's a, that's an actual triple
Speaker 11:  A game in vr. How big is the audience for that? How many people wanna do
Speaker 11:  that? I mean Max for PlayStation VR max 6 million,
Speaker 11:  it's not that big of a hit and that's not enough to make full games for
Speaker 11:  it. But if you're adapting existing games that already have first person
Speaker 11:  interfaces, maybe it's a reasonable cost. You mentioned game streaming,
Speaker 11:  I wanna get back to that too. Game streaming is really fascinating for a
Speaker 11:  lot of reasons. Rip Stadia where I went out, if you guys can't see me on
Speaker 11:  camera, but game streaming comes with its own latency problems that are
Speaker 11:  at some point the laws of physics make it impossible. Our brains can cover
Speaker 11:  some lag on a TV screen. I think that the kind of latency that you would
Speaker 11:  need to have in a VR headset to not get sick, you're sort
Speaker 11:  of pushing up against maybe what's possible there. Yeah. So I dunno if games
Speaker 11:  streaming necessarily solves it, at least if you're not streaming off something
Speaker 11:  local, There are wireless adapters for quests that work now and stuff,
Speaker 11:  but, but games I think where people wanna spend time, the idea of hanging
Speaker 11:  out and hanging out in virtual reality, Big Mark really wants that to
Speaker 11:  be the thing, right? Horizons Yes is this bet
Speaker 11:  they're making. It's a very weird bet the last time that
Speaker 11:  they broadcast their user, they boasted they had 300,000
Speaker 11:  players, 300,000 players, inhabitants. What do you even call, I
Speaker 11:  know 300,000 people,
Speaker 2:  People with no legs just sort of bobbing around the
Speaker 11:  Metaverse. Tell us how you looking things. You have 3000 people and and
Speaker 11:  they boasted about it, right? That was like a press release. They put that
Speaker 11:  out there in the world and my immediate thought reading that's like 300,000
Speaker 11:  is the number that you shut your thing down at, right? That's like this
Speaker 11:  isn't big enough to sustain. You got 15 million users and you're bragging
Speaker 11:  about 300,000 of them showed up to your goofy thing. If I was making Triple
Speaker 11:  A games and you told me your hit is 300,000 you sold depending on the size
Speaker 11:  of the game, I might make a game for it if I was a small studio. But that
Speaker 11:  is not anywhere close to where a AAA studio is gonna
Speaker 11:  need that attach rate to be. And Horizons is free. And
Speaker 11:  so for me this really pushes the question of like, what do people want do
Speaker 11:  in here? I I thought about with Horizons, I thought about Project Spark.
Speaker 11:  Do you remember Project Spark?
Speaker 2:  I don't think so.
Speaker 11:  Well nobody else does it either. This is kind of my point. Project Spark
Speaker 11:  was a game game building thing that Microsoft released with Xbox One when
Speaker 11:  it first came out. Okay, It was paid and then certain amount of people used
Speaker 11:  it. They eventually went free to play to try and drive engagement when they
Speaker 11:  had about 200,000 users. And this was a thing that grew after that. When
Speaker 11:  it was once it was free but it still was not big enough to sustain and they
Speaker 11:  shut it down. That's like what a game decision looks like.
Speaker 11:  And with Horizons, from my vantage point, the audience data
Speaker 11:  suggests that this is not a hit. And the only reason it's still here and
Speaker 11:  being both of us is cuz it's so key and integral to Meta's
Speaker 11:  entire play here. That this is not just a gaming console, this is
Speaker 11:  in fact the gateway to your virtual reality future that
Speaker 11:  we insist is going to happen any day now stay tuned, just
Speaker 11:  hold tight. It's gonna happen. And
Speaker 2:  Meta has made very clear that it's willing to like burn a lot of money and
Speaker 2:  waste a lot of time waiting for that day to come. And so I think
Speaker 2:  the fact that Meta is going to say 300,000 people as a smashing success is
Speaker 2:  like the goal posts are weird and confusing and Meta is gonna move them
Speaker 2:  every time it has to in order to continue to seem like it's being
Speaker 2:  successful. But Meta can also afford to burn tens of billions of dollars
Speaker 2:  trying to make this thing happen without any knowledge that it's gonna happen.
Speaker 2:  And most of the folks making games can't do that. And you know
Speaker 2:  the game making industry much better than I do. But it seems like there are
Speaker 2:  a lot of places where every game you make is like an existential
Speaker 2:  thing functionally every time
Speaker 11:  The ongoing economics of Triple A game development are increasingly make
Speaker 11:  or break. You are all in and these games have to be
Speaker 11:  monstrous hits or failure is more or less catastrophic. The amount
Speaker 11:  of time that a AAA studio will sit on a game to lay a
Speaker 11:  game launch in order to get it to a place where they can be somewhat
Speaker 11:  assured that it'll be enough of a hit. I think Ubisoft is a really fascinating
Speaker 11:  study here, right? Ubisoft is giant AAA studio. They kind of only make
Speaker 11:  hits, it's their whole business. They spend a lot of time, their teams are
Speaker 11:  comically large and they skeleton bones still is not
Speaker 11:  out. This game is supposed to be out years and years and years and years
Speaker 11:  and years ago and it's supposed to be out this year. And it's like, is it,
Speaker 11:  I don't know, I don't think they've even delayed it, but, well it doesn't
Speaker 11:  seem likely. This is a company that like will just wait until they have
Speaker 11:  the product that they think is enough of a hit decided by focus groups
Speaker 11:  and play tests and mock reviews and everything else. Then once they release
Speaker 11:  a game, they will wait until it becomes a hit. Rainbow
Speaker 11:  Succeeds for honor, right? They'll put these games out that do not inspire
Speaker 11:  confidence at launch and they'll just wait. They will iterate and wait until
Speaker 11:  it is a hit because they have to be hits. You see this in some of the acquisition
Speaker 11:  strategy for both Xbox and PlayStation. PlayStation buying Bungee.
Speaker 11:  Yep. For Destiny and Bungee now went from being, we don't wanna just be
Speaker 11:  the halo company to not being just the Destiny company. Yeah. Microsoft
Speaker 11:  buying active vision in part for not, not just call duty,
Speaker 11:  but World Warcraft and Candy Crush, these other massive hits. And I think
Speaker 11:  that having a hits driven business is increasingly putting a lot of pressure
Speaker 11:  on triple A game development. In part that's the production cost. It's the
Speaker 11:  winner takes all nature of hits driven business. It's the social dynamic.
Speaker 11:  If you play a game, you play it with your friends and then they all play
Speaker 11:  then by the same game and they play it over time. That's Fortnite, that's
Speaker 11:  also Destiny. That's also World of Warcraft for the last 15 years. I think
Speaker 11:  it creates this interesting fun space underneath Triple A where you also
Speaker 11:  see some of Microsoft's investments for Game Pass, right? Getting a studio
Speaker 11:  like Obsidian to make a AAA game rpg. But instead
Speaker 11:  of being 40 hours, it's like 10 right? With
Speaker 11:  Outer Worlds. That's exciting for me. That's like as somebody who doesn't
Speaker 11:  have a hundred hours to spend on RPGs anymore. So I think there is a lot
Speaker 11:  of fun room in the middle and I think VR can be a big part of that. Making
Speaker 11:  games that are different experiences that don't have to have the same level
Speaker 11:  of production value cuz they bring something else to the table. They're
Speaker 11:  bringing unique, innovative experiences, different kinds of play dynamics.
Speaker 11:  And that's partially why I even have a quest, even though I don't play it
Speaker 11:  a lot. I like trying things on it. I like seeing what they're
Speaker 11:  doing there. And I usually am not looking for triple A games if I
Speaker 11:  wanna play triple A games, I've got an RTX 30 80 that I don't
Speaker 11:  use enough just waiting for me to put something on it.
Speaker 2:  Big picture question before I let you go here. Like is there a world in the
Speaker 2:  near future in which it would ever make sense for somebody to
Speaker 2:  do like full Triple A, like for GTA six to be like
Speaker 2:  a, a true first class VR citizen? Like is that a
Speaker 2:  thing we want, Is that a thing they're gonna do? Like are we close to that
Speaker 2:  making any sense short of Facebook? Just like writing checks for billions
Speaker 2:  of dollars to get people to do this.
Speaker 11:  And quite frankly if, if we're talking exclusively, I don't think there's
Speaker 11:  enough money under the sun to get grant theft auto to that's fair be if
Speaker 11:  you are exclusive, but
Speaker 2:  Even if, if Mark Zuckerberg goes to the, the Grant Theft Auto team and is
Speaker 2:  like, I will, I will give you, you know, we, we want it to be just
Speaker 2:  as good on Quest as it is on any other platform. We want this big open world
Speaker 2:  game that people are gonna spend thousands of hours in. Like does everybody
Speaker 2:  kinda look at that and be like, that's not, I'm not sure that's what VR game
Speaker 2:  should be.
Speaker 11:  Yeah. As a thought experiment, I say no, I don't think they would do it
Speaker 11:  for a bunch of reasons. Not least switches. It's a distraction from their
Speaker 11:  core business, which is over here. Fair. Do I think that there's a world
Speaker 11:  in which on something like psv, do you get an exclusive first person mode
Speaker 11:  where some parts of the game or some modes in the game are, there's a first
Speaker 11:  person mode on Grand Theft five, or maybe that is in vr similar to the way
Speaker 11:  Res and Evil seven and eight soon to be, have this VR functionality
Speaker 11:  maybe. And maybe some people do wanna play it that way, or maybe some people
Speaker 11:  at least want to experience what it's like to walk around inside of that
Speaker 11:  world, even if it's not the actual full gameplay suite
Speaker 11:  of mechanics. You know, I think about the VR headset that came with Nintendo
Speaker 11:  Labo, the Labo VR set, and just being able to go in
Speaker 11:  Mario Odyssey and like look around certain environments with the
Speaker 11:  VR headset, a crappy VR headset looking at environments built
Speaker 11:  on now seven year old or so Android mobile
Speaker 11:  hardware. And it was fun. Yeah. And so I do think that there's this novelty
Speaker 11:  that would I want to do that? Sure I would, but I wanna play the whole game
Speaker 11:  and is that how I would wanna experience it every day? I, me personally
Speaker 11:  know the studio, I think it's way too high of a risk and too high of a distraction.
Speaker 11:  What they really need is for that game to be as big of a hit or bigger than
Speaker 11:  grant theft. Auto five was, You know, I think even with re evil eight VR
Speaker 11:  mode coming later, the answer is that they have to make a hit game
Speaker 11:  first. That's the obligation, that's the requirement. That's the harder
Speaker 11:  thing to do these days. And so it's not to say it's an afterthought, I think
Speaker 11:  it's gonna be neat. I think you'll continue to see investment in it, but
Speaker 11:  I don't think anyone has really figured out what it is that
Speaker 11:  VR gamers consumers want to spend their time doing
Speaker 11:  besides getting fit. Listen to some good tunes and swing in
Speaker 11:  bats or swords or other objects around.
Speaker 2:  And not only their time, but their $60 and their $70
Speaker 2:  and that kind of stuff.
Speaker 11:  Yeah. Has yet to be, you know, at least exclusively a VR game that's commanding
Speaker 11:  that kind of price.
Speaker 2:  Totally. All right, Chris, thank you. Appreciate it. This was
Speaker 2:  fun.
Speaker 11:  Absolutely.
Speaker 2:  All right, that's it for the Vergecast. Thank you so much for listening.
Speaker 2:  As always, there is tons more coverage on everything, including, like I said,
Speaker 2:  the full interview with Mark Zuckerberg on the website, on YouTube all over
Speaker 2:  the place. verge.com, that's where to go. You can also follow all of us on
Speaker 2:  Twitter. Alex is Alex E. Heath. Addie is
Speaker 2:  the Dexy. Chris is Chris Grant, and I'm Pierce. This show is
Speaker 2:  produced by Andrew Marino and Liam James Nori Donovan is our executive producer
Speaker 2:  and Brook Mins is our editorial director of Audio. The Vergecast is Verge
Speaker 2:  Production and part of the Fox Media podcast network. If you have thoughts,
Speaker 2:  feedback feelings, know how to get legs in the metaverse, you can always
Speaker 2:  email vergecast@theverge.com. You can also call the Vergecast hotline, eight
Speaker 2:  sixty six Verge one one or send a voice memo to vergecast verge.com.
Speaker 2:  Send us all your questions, we'd love to hear 'em. Oh, and speaking of the
Speaker 2:  hotline, I know I've mentioned this a few times already, but we're still
Speaker 2:  working on our cybersecurity episode to run in a couple of weeks. So
Speaker 2:  if you have cyber security questions or crazy mysteries that we might be
Speaker 2:  able to help you solve, call the hotline, eight sixty six Verge one, one,
Speaker 2:  Ask us your questions and some of our favorites. You might actually be getting
Speaker 2:  a callback from Liam, our producer. It's all very exciting. Stay tuned for
Speaker 2:  that. Alex, Neil and I will be back on Friday. We're gonna talk about all
Speaker 2:  of the craziness with Elon Musk. We're gonna talk about more meta
Speaker 2:  stuff, more Microsoft stuff, prime day. There's a lot going on and we'll
Speaker 2:  get into all of it. We'll see. Then rock and roll.