# Transcript
ID: eb2b4240-5ab3-11ed-ac3c-7d5165c97e8a
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Why Signal won’t compromise on encryption, with president Meredith Whittaker
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-8386194028004914580/-8082448870705272402/s93290-US-4475s-1667396357.mp3
Description: Today we're sharing an episode of Decoder with Nilay Patel featuring an interview with Meredith Whittaker, president of Signal.
Signal is the popular messaging app that offers encrypted communication. You might recognize Meredith’s name from 2018 when she was an AI researcher at Google and one of the organizers of the Google walkout. Now she’s at Signal, which is a little different than the usual tech company: it’s operated by a nonprofit foundation and prides itself on collecting as little data as possible.
Listen to more of Decoder with Nilay Patel anywhere you get your podcasts.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (6 ads detected)
Speaker 1:  Hey, Verge has listeners, It's Eli. A regular Wednesday show is off this
Speaker 1:  week. So I wanted to share an episode of decoder that I did recently with
Speaker 1:  Meredith Whitaker. She's a president of Signal, the Encrypted messaging app.
Speaker 1:  If you're VER has listener, you're gonna like this conversation. It's a whole
Speaker 1:  show about messaging apps. After all, Signal has way different priorities
Speaker 1:  than Google and Apple. Meredith is gonna explain all that to you during this
Speaker 1:  show. We'll be back on Friday to talk about all the news from the week. But
Speaker 1:  in the meantime, here is my chat on decoder with Meredith Whitaker,
Speaker 1:  President of Signal.
Speaker 1:  Hello and welcome to decoder. I'm Nelia Patel, Editor in Chief of the Verge
Speaker 1:  and Decoder is my show about big ideas. The other products.
Speaker 1:  Today I'm talking to Meredith Whitaker. She's a president of Signal.
Speaker 1:  That's the popular messaging app that offers encrypted communication.
Speaker 1:  Now, you might recognize Meredith's name from a different context. In 2018,
Speaker 1:  she was an AI researcher at Google and one of the organizers of the
Speaker 1:  Google walkout during which 20,000 employees protested the
Speaker 1:  company's handling of sexual misconduct. Meredith also protested the
Speaker 1:  company's work on military contracts before ultimately leaving Google in
Speaker 1:  2019. Now she's at Signal, which is a little different
Speaker 1:  than the usual big tech company. It's operated by a nonprofit
Speaker 1:  foundation and it prides itself on collecting is a little Data is possible
Speaker 1:  for that reason. Signal is popular with journalists, with activists. People
Speaker 1:  who care about their privacy signal even popped up in the Elon versus Twitter
Speaker 1:  trial because Elon was using it. But messaging apps,
Speaker 1:  especially encrypted messaging apps are a complicated
Speaker 1:  business. Governments around the world really dislike encrypted messaging
Speaker 1:  and often push companies to put in back doors for surveillance and
Speaker 1:  law enforcement, because yeah, criminals use encrypted messaging for
Speaker 1:  all sorts of deeply evil things. But the thing is, there's no half
Speaker 1:  step to breaking encryption. You either have it or you don't. So companies
Speaker 1:  like Signal often find themselves in a difficult position of
Speaker 1:  refusing to help governments. You might recall that Apple has refused to
Speaker 1:  help the FBI break into iPhones, for example. I wanted to know
Speaker 1:  how that trade off plays out its signals much smaller scale, and with
Speaker 1:  signals much more idealistic mission. Then there's just the basic
Speaker 1:  reality of messaging apps. You have to get users, you have to have enough
Speaker 1:  people on the platform so that the network is really valuable. So you
Speaker 1:  choose Signal to message someone instead of something else. You have to add
Speaker 1:  features, you have to have customer support. The whole thing. Signal just
Speaker 1:  added stories like every other app in the world. I wanted to know how they
Speaker 1:  generate ideas like that without being able to track any user behavior.
Speaker 1:  And I wanted to know how the fight to take users from Apple's iMessage and
Speaker 1:  met as WhatsApp is going. Other companies like Google have struggled
Speaker 1:  mightily to compete. After all, Signal just dropped support for
Speaker 1:  SMS on Android, and then we talked about that trade off and what it means
Speaker 1:  for users and if the company can support the new RCS standard that Google
Speaker 1:  is pushing quite hard. Lastly, we talked about Meredith's biggest decision
Speaker 1:  as president, helping to hire a new full-time CEO for Signal.
Speaker 1:  And of course I asked why she's not just taking the job herself.
Speaker 1:  This is a really good episode with a lot of decoder themes in
Speaker 1:  the mix. Honestly, we have to start doing checklists or something. Okay.
Speaker 1:  Meredith Whitaker, President of Signal. Here we go.
Speaker 1:  Meredith Whitaker, you are the president of Signal. Welcome to decoder.
Speaker 5:  Thank you. It is wonderful to be here.
Speaker 1:  There is quite a lot to talk about. The messaging market is pretty
Speaker 1:  ferocious. The encrypted messaging market has lots of complication with it.
Speaker 1:  Signal is a really interesting company. It's structured interesting way.
Speaker 1:  One of your jobs as president is to hire a ceo, which is itself
Speaker 1:  interesting in a pretty fascinating decoder question. But let's start with
Speaker 1:  the very basics. Explain what Signal is and where it fits into
Speaker 1:  the messaging universe.
Speaker 5:  Absolutely. Signal is the
Speaker 5:  most widely used, truly private messaging
Speaker 5:  app on the market. It's used by millions and millions of
Speaker 5:  people globally. And for people who use Signal,
Speaker 5:  it may feel similar to other messaging apps. You open it, you send a
Speaker 5:  meme, you get party directions. You know, you close it when you're done talking
Speaker 5:  to your friends. But below the surface signal
Speaker 5:  is very different. It is truly private. We
Speaker 5:  go to great lengths not only to keep the
Speaker 5:  contents of your messages, who you're talking to, et cetera,
Speaker 5:  private, but to keep, you know, to collect as little data
Speaker 5:  as possible while providing a functional service. So we
Speaker 5:  differ from our competitors in that our mission
Speaker 5:  is to provide a private app. And in that, you know,
Speaker 5:  we are not in any way connected to the surveillance
Speaker 5:  business model. So we have a very different model and a very different mission
Speaker 1:  Signals really interesting because it has this non-profit foundation, it
Speaker 1:  sits over the top of it. One of the reasons the surveillance business model
Speaker 1:  exists is because that is an easy way to make a lot of money. Signals
Speaker 1:  obviously not doing that. There is a nonprofit. How is it structured? How
Speaker 1:  does it all work?
Speaker 5:  The Signal Foundation is a non-profit. The, you know,
Speaker 5:  Signal Messenger LLC is, you know, part is under
Speaker 5:  that non-profit umbrella. And the foundation exists
Speaker 5:  solely to support the messaging app. So
Speaker 5:  in kind of more colloquial terms, we can think of Signal as a non-profit.
Speaker 5:  It is a non-profit, which means, you know, we don't have shareholders,
Speaker 5:  we don't have equity. So we are not being structurally
Speaker 5:  incentivized to prioritize profit and growth
Speaker 5:  over our core mission. And you're not gonna see a billion dollar
Speaker 5:  exit coming. So, you know, we're not just biting our time until we can
Speaker 5:  get rich and move to a super yacht. So it's a, you know, it is a different
Speaker 5:  structure. It is a different model. That doesn't mean it's any
Speaker 5:  cheaper to develop Signal than it is to develop a high
Speaker 5:  availability surveillance messaging service. We are counting
Speaker 5:  on, you know, a sustainability model that relies on donations and
Speaker 5:  relies on a more nonprofit model than on a model where we are secretly
Speaker 5:  monetizing data in the background or otherwise. Again, participating
Speaker 5:  in the surveillance business model, which is the dominant paradigm across
Speaker 5:  the tech industry,
Speaker 1:  Across the tech industry, but not so much in
Speaker 1:  messaging specifically. I actually wanna just push on that a little bit.
Speaker 1:  There are obviously messaging services that look at everything that you send
Speaker 1:  across their service and then aggressively try to monetize you based on what
Speaker 1:  you're saying. Specifically, I'm thinking of dating apps, which
Speaker 1:  really read all of your messages to figure out when they should nudge you
Speaker 1:  into going on a date, which every time I hear about it just strikes me as
Speaker 1:  completely bonkers. But that's their universe. Some your competitors though,
Speaker 1:  your head up competitors, iMessage, WhatsApp, those are fully
Speaker 1:  encrypted. Obviously WhatsApp is owned by Facebook. There's a lot of controversy
Speaker 1:  there. There's a connection to Signal with Brian Acton, who was a co-founder
Speaker 1:  of WhatsApp now on the signal board. But those are inherently encrypted,
Speaker 1:  right? They're not reading your messages in the way that, you know, the
Speaker 1:  surveillance business model is predicated on collecting a lot of data. What
Speaker 1:  is the difference in your mind between the two things,
Speaker 5:  Right? Well, let's take WhatsApp as a specific example,
Speaker 5:  right? You know, again, WhatsApp uses the signal encryption
Speaker 5:  protocol to provide encryption for its messages. And that
Speaker 5:  was absolutely a visionary choice. And you know, something
Speaker 5:  that Brian and his team led back in the day. So, you
Speaker 5:  know, big props to them for doing that. But you can't just look at
Speaker 5:  that and you can't just stop at message protection, right? WhatsApp does
Speaker 5:  not protect metadata the way that Signal does.
Speaker 5:  So if Signal knows nothing about who you are,
Speaker 5:  doesn't have your profile information introduced,
Speaker 5:  you know, groups encryption protections, so that we don't know
Speaker 5:  who you're talking to or who the membership of a group is, has gone
Speaker 5:  above and beyond to minimize the collection of metadata.
Speaker 5:  WhatsApp on the other hand, you know, collects the information about, you
Speaker 5:  know, your profile information, your profile photo, who's talking to
Speaker 5:  whom, who is a group member. And that is powerful metadata.
Speaker 5:  It's particularly powerful and this is where we have to back out into kind
Speaker 5:  of a structural argument for a company to collect that
Speaker 5:  data that is also owned by Meta slash Facebook. So Facebook
Speaker 5:  has a huge amount just, you know, unspeakable volumes of
Speaker 5:  intimate information about billions of people across the globe. And
Speaker 5:  so it is not, you know, it, it is, it's not trivial to
Speaker 5:  point out that WhatsApp metadata could easily be joined
Speaker 5:  with Facebook data could easily reveal extremely intimate
Speaker 5:  information about people. And the choice to remove
Speaker 5:  or enhance the encryption protocols is still in the
Speaker 5:  hands of Facebook. So we have to look structurally at, you know, what that
Speaker 5:  organization is who actually has control over these
Speaker 5:  decisions. And you know, and look at some of these details
Speaker 5:  that don't often get discussed when we talk about sort of message encryption
Speaker 5:  overall, you know, Signal again is a nonprofit. We
Speaker 5:  don't have any access to data like Foot Facebook. We avoid having
Speaker 5:  access to that data. We don't buy sell trade your data. So it's,
Speaker 5:  you know, it is a different paradigm and I think we can't, you know, we can't
Speaker 5:  point to WhatsApp however slick their marketing is and say that is
Speaker 5:  truly secure and private because, you know, all of these details add up to
Speaker 5:  us needing to conclude that it is not, well, you know, Signal exists solely
Speaker 5:  for that purpose.
Speaker 1:  Let me ask you a hard question there. You have a long history as a, a
Speaker 1:  critic of big tech. You, you obviously believe in these criticism of big
Speaker 1:  tech. I don't believe that while you are the president of Signal, you're
Speaker 1:  gonna switch the business model. Mark Zuckerberg has his own reputation and
Speaker 1:  he can say things about privacy and people can believe whether Facebook is
Speaker 1:  or whether Meta is going to do those things based on their evaluation. Mark
Speaker 1:  Zuckerberg, how do you actually audit the service as a consumer? How do I
Speaker 1:  actually make sure that what you're saying is true?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, Well, Signal makes its code open source. It makes
Speaker 5:  the signal protocol and the key cryptographic
Speaker 5:  primitives that we use to ensure privacy and security
Speaker 5:  open for review. So, you know, a big part of our model
Speaker 5:  is telling people not to take our word for it, the people
Speaker 5:  who do have the specialized training and skill have engaged, you know,
Speaker 5:  thousands and thousands of hours pouring over our code. There are people
Speaker 5:  in the Signal community forums who every time we have a new,
Speaker 5:  you know, a new kind of piece of code that drops on GitHub,
Speaker 5:  sort of look at it, comment on it, deduce what features might be coming
Speaker 5:  through that. So there is an active and vigilant community that actually
Speaker 5:  sort of checks signals, claims against the code,
Speaker 5:  against the cryptographic protocol we use. And time and time again,
Speaker 5:  you know, our, you know, cryptographic protocol again, is not just used by
Speaker 5:  Signal, right? This is what, what Facebook uses, which other companies have
Speaker 5:  chosen to use because you know, it's the best. We rely on
Speaker 5:  that vigilant community and we rely on transparency
Speaker 5:  and the kind of community auditing. So we, but
Speaker 1:  But that's the, the protocol, right? That's not the app.
Speaker 5:  That is the app. The
Speaker 1:  Whole app,
Speaker 5:  Yeah, this open source.
Speaker 1:  So if I just want to fork signal and make my own signal, I can just take
Speaker 1:  the code and do it today.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, people do it. There are many of those we don't, you know, because
Speaker 5:  we can't guarantee them. Yeah. Because we can't validate them because we
Speaker 5:  don't have the time or the resources for that. We don't endorse them. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  But there are many out there.
Speaker 1:  That's really cool. Yeah. Let me ask another question
Speaker 1:  just about the structure here. So it's a nonprofit. You said you don't have
Speaker 1:  equity Facebook in a different time. Facebook equity was very valuable.
Speaker 1:  Maybe not so much today as we speak, but in a different time. Facebook equity
Speaker 1:  is really valuable. So Facebook, Apple, Google, whoever would pay
Speaker 1:  a high base salary and then give engineers a ton of equity and say, if you
Speaker 1:  work really hard, the stock price will go up, you'll get Rich. You don't
Speaker 1:  have that key. Are you just paying people more in cash or are you hoping
Speaker 1:  that people take a discount cuz they believe in your values?
Speaker 5:  Well, we are, we do have competitive salaries. I think that's part of Signal
Speaker 5:  as an organization also has a labor politics. We wanna make sure we're
Speaker 5:  compensating people. We wanna make sure that, you know, people aren't being
Speaker 5:  asked to sacrifice their lives Crypto
Speaker 5:  standard of living to come work for Signal. We wanna hire the best people
Speaker 5:  we can find. So we do have competitive salaries. Of course
Speaker 5:  we don't have equity, so that's not part of the package. But we are a fully
Speaker 5:  distributed organization. So there is, you know, flexibility with where you
Speaker 5:  live, which communities you might be able to live in. And there is also,
Speaker 5:  you know, we have, we have other benefits that we think make it a great
Speaker 5:  working environment for people who want to apply their
Speaker 5:  talents to something outside of the surveillance
Speaker 5:  tech ecosystem.
Speaker 1:  But on a straight comp basis, are you, do you match Big Tech or are you
Speaker 1:  lower, or where are you?
Speaker 5:  I mean, I don't have a spreadsheet in front of me and Big Tech is a
Speaker 5:  big amorphous entity. So Big tech in Europe or Big Tech in Palo
Speaker 5:  Alto. There are a lot of variables there, but what I can say straight up
Speaker 5:  is we are competitive.
Speaker 1:  How many people are at Signal right
Speaker 5:  Now? About 40 total. That's the org.
Speaker 1:  And how is that structured? Is that mostly engineers? Is it policy people?
Speaker 1:  Is it the C-suite? How's that work?
Speaker 5:  It's mostly engineers. We have a, you know, it's not a very complex
Speaker 5:  organization by which, you know, I'm avoiding using the term flat because
Speaker 5:  it is not flat, but it doesn't have, you know, many layers of bureaucracy.
Speaker 5:  There's a, a leadership team. We have a, a coo,
Speaker 5:  we have myself as president, we have a director of products. We have
Speaker 5:  two engineering executives, one that looks more at architecture, one that
Speaker 5:  looks more at People management. And then we have Brian Acton as acting ceo.
Speaker 5:  I'm like imagining in my head the kind of org chart right now.
Speaker 1:  That's the whole show. That's what we do here. By all means, it's
Speaker 5:  Primarily developers, but of course, like development isn't just
Speaker 5:  sort of, you know, submitting a pool request. Right? We also have a really
Speaker 5:  talented, you know, what we call the user voice team. And those are the people
Speaker 5:  who engage with the community. Those are the people who, you know, do a little
Speaker 5:  bit of QA test for bugs. I am tasked in my new role with
Speaker 5:  sort of bringing policy awareness. So we don't have a policy team, but
Speaker 5:  that's, you know, that is something I'm, you know, I'm working on what the
Speaker 5:  right calibration there is for Signal and kind of bringing in my
Speaker 5:  network and my many years of work on those topics. And then we
Speaker 5:  have, you know, what I'll characterize as like a narrative team. You know,
Speaker 5:  we have writers, we have people who, you know, think about how we translate
Speaker 5:  kind of arcane concepts to people who rely on
Speaker 5:  Signal in a way that they'll actually understand. And you know, we have folks
Speaker 5:  like that, but it's, it is primarily developers because what we do
Speaker 5:  is produce a high availability app across three platforms, which takes
Speaker 5:  a lot of labor, constant vigilance, constantly squashing bugs,
Speaker 5:  constantly thinking about new features, making sure there's parody across
Speaker 5:  all the versions. It is, you know, it is endless and
Speaker 5:  difficult work and I'm, you know, I'm happy to be working with the people
Speaker 5:  who are doing it.
Speaker 1:  You have a new role at Signal President of Signal new role for you. I don't
Speaker 1:  think you were the president of a company before you, or no, Google, obviously
Speaker 1:  president of a company is one of those roles that you kind of can be whatever
Speaker 1:  you want it to be, is my understanding of it. How do
Speaker 1:  you conceive of the role of President Single?
Speaker 5:  Well, I, I have core lanes in that role. So,
Speaker 5:  you know, and, and to back up for a second, I've been on the board for a
Speaker 5:  number of years. I've worked with Moxi and kind of a community there. There's
Speaker 5:  a kind of a open source community of folks who think hard about
Speaker 5:  technical privacy preservation. And I've been, you know, in and out of
Speaker 5:  that community for, you know, almost a decade now. So I'm, I'm very
Speaker 5:  familiar with the folks in this space. I'm familiar with the folks at Signal.
Speaker 5:  And so this was almost like a gradual transition into this role
Speaker 5:  of just like intensifying my, my attention to signal until it's
Speaker 5:  my, my whole work life in this role, I'm gonna be,
Speaker 5:  you know, I'm gonna be focusing on the narrative aspects. Like how do we,
Speaker 5:  you know, how do we communicate what Signal is why it's so
Speaker 5:  wonderful to people who might want to use it, right? And this is
Speaker 5:  particularly in an environment where there is increasing understanding
Speaker 5:  of the harms of the surveillance business model, increasing understanding
Speaker 5:  of the monopoly power of big tech, but not many
Speaker 5:  actions people can do when they're like, I feel really uncomfortable with
Speaker 5:  this, but what do we do? Right? It, you know, kind of inter interpolate our
Speaker 5:  entire life. So, you know, I think getting, getting the word out there, the
Speaker 5:  signal is truly different. And then building that network effect of
Speaker 5:  encrypted com communications. So anyone who picks up Signal
Speaker 5:  can talk to anyone they want to on Signal without having to think about it,
Speaker 5:  without having to be a privacy ideolog, right? It's not, you know,
Speaker 5:  my friends aren't just cryptographers who live in Berlin. My friends are
Speaker 5:  a number of people with varied interest. Some truly probably don't care about
Speaker 5:  privacy, but nonetheless, they're cool people. I like to hang out with them,
Speaker 5:  right? So I need to be able to reach them on that app. And, you know, if
Speaker 5:  they're not there, signal is significantly less useful to me. So, you know,
Speaker 5:  I'm gonna be working on working on that narrative aspect.
Speaker 5:  I'm also, you know, I mentioned policy awareness. So that is just, you know,
Speaker 5:  thinking about the global landscape that, you know, regulatory
Speaker 5:  and legislative landscape and how that, how that
Speaker 5:  affects Sig signal. How do we think about that during a product development
Speaker 5:  process? How do we think about that in terms of, you know, our high level
Speaker 5:  strategy? And then I will also be working with the leadership team
Speaker 5:  to direct strategy. So we're at, you know, as an organization,
Speaker 5:  we grew from what I would characterize as a, you know, passion
Speaker 5:  driven hypothesis project. This was, you know, an open
Speaker 5:  source project on a shoestring, Big thanks to Moxi, Marlon,
Speaker 5:  Spike, Tyler Reinhardt, a number of the sort of original folks at Signal
Speaker 5:  who made a bunch of sacrifices and worked extremely hard
Speaker 5:  to get this effort off the ground. In the last few years,
Speaker 5:  Signal has matured and I would say is at an inflection point as
Speaker 5:  an organization, you know, it's time to take the next step. We have, you
Speaker 5:  know, over a hundred million do downloads in the play store, but, you know,
Speaker 5:  what does it look like when we, you know, reach the next stage
Speaker 5:  and are serving, you know, hundreds of millions of people across the
Speaker 5:  globe? And how do we build a signal that can, can really meet
Speaker 5:  this moment? And I think, you know, sustainability is definitely part of
Speaker 5:  that. What is a business model that, you know, I don't think has been
Speaker 5:  done yet that can, you know, sustain technology like signal outside of the
Speaker 5:  surveillance paradigm?
Speaker 1:  So you talked about narrative and, and reaching people and you know,
Speaker 1:  the network effect of everybody you know, is using signals. So you, you're
Speaker 1:  not even thinking about it. You don't have to evangelize the service. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Another way to characterize that is growth, right? Your job is to grow the
Speaker 1:  product, and then the back end of it is what you just said, which is figure
Speaker 1:  out how to monetize that product against that growth and run a product at
Speaker 1:  that scale in a way that's sustainable. Is growth the imperative here?
Speaker 5:  Like I've consciously avoided some of those terms because they're so
Speaker 5:  closely aligned with like profit motives, and I don't wanna
Speaker 5:  be misunderstood, right? Yes, of course we wanna grow because our,
Speaker 5:  you know, our mission is to provide, you know,
Speaker 5:  truly private communication to anyone who wants it across
Speaker 5:  the globe at any time, right? So, you know, we grow
Speaker 5:  so that we can fulfill our mission, not so that we can just, you know, we're
Speaker 5:  not looking at like growth hacking or adding like, you know, weird features,
Speaker 5:  you know, to get a, an inflated boost. We're looking at, you know, how do
Speaker 5:  we actually reach the people who do need to use this tech
Speaker 5:  reach, the people who want a convenient messaging service
Speaker 5:  and sort of, you know, ensure that they, you know, are able to use
Speaker 5:  signal quickly and easily that they know about it, that, you know, when they
Speaker 5:  open it up, all their friends are there. That it's a seamless and pleasant
Speaker 5:  experience. So yes, you know, I think, I think you can put it in those terms.
Speaker 5:  I have intentionally not put it in those those terms because I want to,
Speaker 5:  you know, not even echo the language of, you know, the
Speaker 5:  alternatives which are doing something that is, you know, may look the same
Speaker 5:  on the surface, but is, you know, substantively very, very different.
Speaker 1:  I wanna come back to that because I think there's a lot there to unpack and
Speaker 1:  there's growth regardless of the motive for the growth
Speaker 1:  comes with a pretty fixed set of challenges once you get to that scale.
Speaker 1:  So I do wanna come back to that, but I have to ask you this sort of classic
Speaker 1:  decoder question. How do you make decisions? You've been in a lot of
Speaker 1:  different companies, a lot of different environments, a lot of different
Speaker 1:  roles. You must have a pretty robust way of thinking about big decisions
Speaker 1:  you have to make. How do you make decisions? You
Speaker 5:  Know, I don't have a flow chart for decisions, right? I don't have like,
Speaker 5:  you know, my VC Twitter thread, like the three things I
Speaker 5:  know about decision making.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, that's not, that's not, I hope that's not what I implied. I I just
Speaker 1:  meant like you've made a lot of decisions in your life, a lot of high stakes
Speaker 1:  decisions. Yeah. How do you think about it?
Speaker 5:  I mean, I, you know, it is a combination of as much
Speaker 5:  research as I need to do until I'm satisfied I have the ground truth
Speaker 5:  around something. So, you know, I will ask very dumb
Speaker 5:  questions until I am sure that like there isn't some like trick
Speaker 5:  or some sort of, you know, issue that I haven't, you know,
Speaker 5:  fully understood. That means, you know, I'll read academic papers
Speaker 5:  or I'll call people who've worked in a certain sector, or I will reach
Speaker 5:  out to a mentor who maybe doesn't know much about the space, but has a sense
Speaker 5:  of dynamics and might, you know, lend a different eye, right? You know, it's,
Speaker 5:  I basically have as big a toolbox as I can and I will pull from any tool
Speaker 5:  that, you know, feels useful. And then, you know, I think
Speaker 5:  it will be, you know, again, some combination of instinct. Like when has
Speaker 5:  this worked well in the past, when is it not, right? Like, the benefit of
Speaker 5:  having been in this industry for almost 20 years is you just like, build
Speaker 5:  up a big set of experience and there's a lot of like pitfalls you've fallen
Speaker 5:  into before so you can avoid them. And then I think there's also sort of
Speaker 5:  a, you know, it needs to be accompanied with humility. Like, this
Speaker 5:  is the decision we're making, here is the basis for this decision, which
Speaker 5:  I'm really committed to, you know, making sure everyone understands, you
Speaker 5:  know, my basis, right? Like, this is why this decision is made. You don't
Speaker 5:  have to agree, but you can see the logic that led me to it, right?
Speaker 5:  And then if it, you know, how do we measure that it's the right decision,
Speaker 5:  right? What are the benchmarks we're looking at going forward and how do
Speaker 5:  I remain willing to say like, Look, that was wrong. You know, let's,
Speaker 5:  let's back up because like, clearly it's not going the direction we wanted
Speaker 5:  it to go, so, you know, let's, let's recalibrate, let's look
Speaker 5:  into our assumptions, let's do it over. And I think, you know, there's kind
Speaker 5:  of a, a combination of like iterating and learning on the go
Speaker 5:  in, you know, while being sensitive to like, you know, what is, what is our,
Speaker 5:  what are our ultimate goals? Why, you know, why is this decision being made?
Speaker 5:  And I think bringing everything I have, you know, my experience, my
Speaker 5:  knowledge, and any research I need to do to bear on the
Speaker 1:  Decision. So let's put that into practice. There is a big decision for Signal
Speaker 1:  coming up. You mentioned Brian Acton is currently the interim CEO l
Speaker 1:  Marlin Spike, who was the, one of the co-founders. He was the ceo, he stepped
Speaker 1:  down in last January. You gotta hire a new ceo. What are you looking for?
Speaker 1:  How are you gonna
Speaker 5:  Do it? Yeah, I mean, I think we're looking for somebody with, you know, stellar
Speaker 5:  product experience. We want somebody who can really
Speaker 5:  focus in on the organization. So, you know, how
Speaker 5:  do we get our development practices and coordination as
Speaker 5:  cleanly calibrated and well oiled as possible?
Speaker 5:  How do we think about, you know, scaling this organization,
Speaker 5:  growing this organization, growing our users, you know, ensuring that
Speaker 5:  we are, you know, choosing the right features and, you know,
Speaker 5:  innovations to function on while understanding that
Speaker 5:  this is not, you know, your average tech startup, right? That our growth
Speaker 5:  is in service of something different. That our organization does have
Speaker 5:  the luxury to say no to certain choices,
Speaker 5:  to reject the, you know, move quick and break things paradigm
Speaker 5:  if, if that's not going to serve our ultimate mission. So I think it's
Speaker 5:  somebody with those who, who has that experience, but who also has
Speaker 5:  sensibilities that will enable them to sort of discern the
Speaker 5:  differences between a signal and between, you know,
Speaker 5:  x, Y, z, you know, kind of, I don't know, some
Speaker 5:  social app that's a shim for data collection that goes into, you know, some
Speaker 5:  DD algorithm or something. You know, the, the, the truly,
Speaker 5:  you know, the truly dark side of tech.
Speaker 1:  I feel like you might have some history with not being happy with DOD related
Speaker 1:  to projects.
Speaker 5:  I will just say the more you know about so-called ai, the more
Speaker 5:  skeptical you become.
Speaker 1:  Fair enough. Why is it not you? I mean, you're very passionate
Speaker 1:  about Signal, It seems like you could do all those things. Why not? Why not
Speaker 1:  just pick yourself? Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Well, one reason is I wanna go deep on the areas that I have
Speaker 5:  experience in and that I just love doing, right? And
Speaker 5:  this was, you know, this was a role. I talked to the board, you know, for
Speaker 5:  a long time, and this was a role that we sort of shaped around some of
Speaker 5:  my interests and around some of my, you know, it's not increasing
Speaker 5:  realization, right? Like, I think I've always been a massive signal
Speaker 5:  booster. I use Signal when it was called Red Phone and Tech Secure, like
Speaker 5:  way back in the day, you know, before there was an iOS app.
Speaker 5:  But I think, you know, as I have moved through my career
Speaker 5:  and occupied, you know, different positions in, you know, academia, in tech,
Speaker 5:  you know, very briefly at the Federal Trade Commission, it was just
Speaker 5:  a realization that this is really something I thought a lot about and a
Speaker 5:  place where I could very meaningfully put my time. And I, you know, it,
Speaker 5:  it just was clearly the most meaningful thing I could do with my
Speaker 5:  energy and expertise. And I think, you know, what we want from a
Speaker 5:  CEO is also somebody who has, you know, on the ground product
Speaker 5:  experience, which I have some of, but you know, I have not been in the messaging
Speaker 5:  space. I just think it would be, it would be great to work side
Speaker 5:  by side with that person and to work on the leadership team. But it was,
Speaker 5:  you know, this was a very intentional choice and it was sort of shaped around,
Speaker 5:  you know, what I think I do best and, you know, I, we wanna shape
Speaker 5:  the CEO role for somebody who, you know, fits those specific
Speaker 5:  needs. And it's, you know, really inward focus, getting everything on
Speaker 5:  Rails. And this is not to say things aren't on rails now, but you know, if
Speaker 5:  you're preparing for growth, if you're preparing, you know, to meet this
Speaker 5:  moment, to really recognize this inflection point and mature the
Speaker 5:  organization, we need somebody who's able to focus inward on those issues.
Speaker 1:  How's the search going? Do you have a timeline?
Speaker 5:  We don't have a timeline, but it's, it's active.
Speaker 1:  And then who, what does it look like at the end? Do you have a board meeting
Speaker 1:  and you all sit down, you yeah. Throw secret ballots on the table. Do you
Speaker 1:  raise your hand? What's the most people are never gonna pick a CEO and give
Speaker 1:  them a vision of what that process is like at the end.
Speaker 5:  Cool. There are interviews, we wanna make sure that this is,
Speaker 5:  you know, somebody that leadership and the team feel,
Speaker 5:  you know, just wildly enthusiastic about, right? Somebody who
Speaker 5:  just, you know, lights up every interview and is, is sort of, you know,
Speaker 5:  clearly showing their knowledge of signal and their vision and their insight
Speaker 5:  about the space. And then we get real excited about that person. We
Speaker 5:  pop virtual champagne and then we have, have a board meeting
Speaker 5:  and the board votes and then, you know, there's all sorts of, you
Speaker 5:  know, the, the sort of background logistics, right? You would need to make
Speaker 5:  sure somebody can transition out of another role. If you're hiring a ceo,
Speaker 5:  they probably have significant responsibilities. So you, you know, create
Speaker 5:  an offboarding and onboarding timeline. You work with them on that
Speaker 5:  you, you know, meet, you make sure they have all of the documentation and
Speaker 5:  information they need. You sort of think about, you know, the, the sort of
Speaker 5:  classic timeline is like first hundred days for executives. But you know,
Speaker 5:  what is the, what is the timeline for impact? What is the initial vision?
Speaker 5:  And you know, at that stage I see myself as like a, you know, as a champion
Speaker 5:  and a supporter, right? Like, how do I back this person up? How do I make
Speaker 5:  sure they are sort of elevated to do, you know, the best job they can
Speaker 5:  and that they have, you know, all the resources and insight I have to give
Speaker 5:  and all the resources and insight, you know, that the org can offer as well.
Speaker 1:  We're back. So let's talk about growth.
Speaker 1:  It it, we've mentioned it by different names several times. I understand
Speaker 1:  exactly why you don't want to use the word growth. That implies a bunch of
Speaker 1:  Silicon Valley tropes, but you want to add users
Speaker 1:  to Signal. And so growth is a yes, is fundamentally the
Speaker 1:  thing you're talking about. User growth, yes. Is the goal Everyone on the
Speaker 1:  planet,
Speaker 5:  The goal is everyone who wants to, needs to
Speaker 5:  has a smartphone, right? Everyone on the planet,
Speaker 5:  Yes. That is, that is the goal. But it's also that just that almost
Speaker 5:  like abstracts it into the land of fantasy, right? Like I don't even, you
Speaker 5:  know, I don't, I don't have the latest numbers, but not everyone on the planet
Speaker 5:  has access to internet, right? Not everyone on the planet has access to a
Speaker 5:  smartphone that's running an operating system that can support Signal, right?
Speaker 5:  So there's, you know, sort of planetary distinctions
Speaker 5:  and inequities and contexts that you know mean that I don't, I feel like
Speaker 5:  throwing that out would just be like a bombastic tech
Speaker 5:  founder kind of goal and not actually anchored in reality.
Speaker 5:  However, like everyone who wants to use Signal, we want them to be able to
Speaker 5:  use it, right? And again, the, you know, the premise there is that signal
Speaker 5:  is more useful the, for the people who use Signal, the more people who
Speaker 5:  use Signal, right? Like a messaging app that no one use uses
Speaker 5:  is useless, right? A, you know, hyper secure, privacy aware
Speaker 5:  messaging app that only three people use is only useful and
Speaker 5:  secure and private to three people, right? So we want, you know, we really
Speaker 5:  want that network effect because that's, you know, that's what
Speaker 5:  makes messaging work.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, I, I asked the question that way cuz there's what somewhere between,
Speaker 1:  it's a little under 8 billion people on the
Speaker 1:  planet. 1.7 billion of those people live in China, which is
Speaker 1:  Block Signal. One and a half billion of those people live in India, which
Speaker 1:  the government does not like encryption. Just off the bat, are those markets
Speaker 1:  that you want to go into or those fights you want to have, are those compromises
Speaker 1:  you would make or are those people just off the books for you?
Speaker 5:  I mean, let's be clear, we are not in the business of
Speaker 5:  compromising on privacy and we're not in the business of, you know,
Speaker 5:  handing people who want and need signal a compromised
Speaker 5:  version of Signal, which, you know, we're not, we're not gonna
Speaker 5:  do, right? But, you know, are there people in South and
Speaker 5:  East Asia who want to be able to talk privately,
Speaker 5:  safely, intimately outside of the gays of corporate state surveillance?
Speaker 5:  Absolutely. Do we want them to have access to signal? Absolutely we do.
Speaker 5:  Right? You know, do we want signal to be available there? Yes.
Speaker 5:  Can we kind of magically transform the geopolitical
Speaker 5:  dynamics? No, we can't. But you know, we will do what is in within
Speaker 5:  our power to make sure that signal is available to as many people as possible.
Speaker 5:  And we will do that without compromising our privacy
Speaker 5:  promises.
Speaker 1:  So the Chinese government has effectively block signal. You don't have
Speaker 1:  plans to go into China in some way?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I mean, I don't know what going into China would mean, like, you know,
Speaker 5:  a ticket to Beijing handout, you know, QR codes. I don't know.
Speaker 5:  That's a joke. I'm saying like, we're not doing that, but
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Right. You're not sure. You're not, you're not doing like Uber
Speaker 1:  styling gorilla user acquisition in China. I meant you're not talk actively
Speaker 1:  talking to the Chinese government about what it would mean for Signal to
Speaker 1:  be active in the Chinese market.
Speaker 5:  No, we are, you know, full stop. We're not gonna compromise. And you know,
Speaker 5:  that would imply that we are sort of in a negotiating stance. And
Speaker 5:  again, this, you know, this is sort of the magical thinking that comes
Speaker 5:  up and I've been in tech almost 20 years, so I've seen this sort of
Speaker 5:  recur, right? And it's this, you know, desire
Speaker 5:  particularly by state actors to kind of like break
Speaker 5:  encryption for their purposes without understanding that
Speaker 5:  that breaks it fundamentally across the board. So, you know, there's no,
Speaker 5:  I don't know, this sounds like a little bit dated, you know, there's no
Speaker 5:  compromising with math, I guess is what I'll say, right? Like if encryption
Speaker 5:  is broken, it is broken and then Signal doesn't
Speaker 5:  keep its privacy promises and then there's no real point for us to
Speaker 5:  exist as a non-profit whose sole mission is to provide
Speaker 5:  it, you know, safe, private, pleasant place for,
Speaker 5:  you know, messaging and communication in a world where those
Speaker 5:  are vanishingly few and far between, you know, it's signal
Speaker 5:  and then there's, you know, there are a number of other services, but because
Speaker 5:  very few people use them, they're very, you know, they're much, much,
Speaker 5:  much, much, much less useful to most people who pick them up and
Speaker 5:  try
Speaker 1:  Them, right? So putting this out there, Apple's solution to this problem,
Speaker 1:  because China is a gigantic market for Apple and its devices
Speaker 1:  is to say iMessage is encrypted. But to allow
Speaker 1:  a state operated company to actually run the iCloud data centers
Speaker 1:  in China, which seems like a right, they have threaded the needle in a way
Speaker 1:  that allows them to claim the thing they want to claim, even though the government
Speaker 1:  holds the encryption keys. You're not gonna do that. You're not even like
Speaker 1:  allowing for a solution like that to exist.
Speaker 5:  Let the record show hell no, we're not gonna do that.
Speaker 5:  No, I mean, and this is again, like let's pin, let's like flip
Speaker 5:  this and talk about the business model. Apple is doing that because like
Speaker 5:  every quarter they have to report their growth and revenue stats to the board.
Speaker 5:  And if those stats are like, you know, not looking to
Speaker 5:  acquire a new but Unac acquired market, then eventually their
Speaker 5:  executive team is gonna get fired and new people brought in because the imperative
Speaker 5:  of their company, to put this in machine learning terms, the objective function
Speaker 5:  of their company is increasing profit and growth forever.
Speaker 5:  Like literally the definition of metastasis, right?
Speaker 5:  That's not us, right? Like we don't need to do that. We do not need to, you
Speaker 5:  know, make those compromises like myself and our CEO will not get fired
Speaker 5:  if we're not sort of bringing new market strategies.
Speaker 5:  However, you know, twisted the compromise is
Speaker 5:  to the board. We have a different mission and a different set of incentives.
Speaker 5:  So, you know, which makes it easy to say hell no to a question like that.
Speaker 1:  So Signal is in India right now, India has claimed signal sought in
Speaker 1:  compliance with some regulations there that would require one of these magical
Speaker 1:  thinking back doors. Are you gonna leave India? Are you gonna stay there?
Speaker 1:  Are you gonna fight? How's that gonna work?
Speaker 5:  We are still available to people in India who want to
Speaker 5:  use Signal, right? We are not gonna compromise on privacy.
Speaker 5:  And that is our stance and we'll, you know, we'll do everything
Speaker 5:  we can to continue to be available to the people in India who
Speaker 5:  want and need signal.
Speaker 1:  But if India passes a law or deems signal to not be in compliance with
Speaker 1:  whatever encryption regulation you'll walk,
Speaker 5:  I mean, if the choice is, you know, breaking signal
Speaker 5:  or walking, but again, you know, I think a lot of times these
Speaker 5:  policy strategies and discussions just, you know, they're not, it's not like
Speaker 5:  a bullion, right? It's not a, you know, cut and dry engineering decision.
Speaker 5:  These are very muddy and like frankly not things
Speaker 5:  that it's usually best to sort of go into detail on
Speaker 5:  publicly because you're, you know, you're having to think about a lot of
Speaker 5:  different sort of, you know, political, social, et cetera,
Speaker 5:  dynamics all at once and sort of make, you know, make up to the
Speaker 5:  minute choices based on like it, you know, dynamic situation.
Speaker 5:  So, you know, that's, that is a very broad answer. But again, like
Speaker 5:  there, you know, I think we're gonna, we're gonna be keeping our eye on it.
Speaker 5:  We're gonna again be doing everything we can to remain available to
Speaker 5:  as many people as possible without breaking signal.
Speaker 1:  Well, it's a broad answer to a specific question, right? If a
Speaker 1:  government and the world says, in order to operate in our country, we want
Speaker 1:  the keys to your encryption, would you just walk?
Speaker 5:  Yes, we would walk, we will not hand over the keys to our encryption. We
Speaker 5:  will not, you know, break the encryption and in fact, the way we're built,
Speaker 5:  we don't have access to those keys.
Speaker 1:  So then there's the flip side of it, which is sort of internal to signal
Speaker 1:  and like what value Signal has as a company and
Speaker 1:  what it, what things you can and can't do because you cannot see into the
Speaker 1:  content, which I think is maybe the most difficult
Speaker 1:  thing for any company to reckon with when they operate a service with
Speaker 1:  lots and lots of users who might do lots and lots of things, things. In 2021,
Speaker 1:  we hosted a story from Casey Newton about that group chat feature
Speaker 1:  you mentioned where you can share links to group chats,
Speaker 1:  thousands of people can join them. Signal obviously cannot see what is going
Speaker 1:  on inside of this group chats because it's encrypted. That means bad actors
Speaker 1:  can do bad things inside of Signal and spread the, their
Speaker 1:  messages inside of Signal. Is that something that that concerns you?
Speaker 5:  I mean I think that that story from Casey Newton was not
Speaker 5:  a totally clear picture of the real dynamics inside signal. I think,
Speaker 5:  you know, the place where we really think about these
Speaker 5:  is in the sort of, you know, product direction, right? When we're, you know,
Speaker 5:  thinking through new features and capabilities, a number of very
Speaker 5:  smart people who spend a lot of time, you know, thinking through the implications.
Speaker 5:  You know, I think the, you know, the question of like, but what if bad actors
Speaker 5:  did it is, you know, it's, it's compelling and it's often very emotionally
Speaker 5:  charged, right? Like these are, you know, the truth remains
Speaker 5:  however, that like, you can't provide a service
Speaker 5:  that truly protects the privacy of good actors. You know, many of
Speaker 5:  whom often have a lot less power than the people they're, you know, not
Speaker 5:  wanting to be surveilled and tracked by while sort of
Speaker 5:  opening up that service to allow surveillance of bad actors. Like there isn't,
Speaker 5:  you know, there is no squaring that circle and you know,
Speaker 5:  I think we are committed to providing a service that is,
Speaker 5:  you know, again, truly private for both. And I can, you know, I can talk
Speaker 5:  about, you know, when I was, when I was participating in labor organizing
Speaker 5:  at Google, we used Signal and we were, you know, I knew
Speaker 5:  because I'd been at the company for, you know, like over a decade
Speaker 5:  at that point, you know, that the company was, had teams
Speaker 5:  that were looking for a pretext to, you know,
Speaker 5:  fire me, right? And, and those pretext exists. I was part of,
Speaker 5:  you know, ethical whistle blowing networks, right? We were sort of sharing
Speaker 5:  information we thought was in the public interest with the public and with
Speaker 5:  journalists, which I, you know, I stand behind. There's a lot of this information
Speaker 5:  should not be behind the walls of proprietary tech companies
Speaker 5:  where the decisions are being made based on profit, not on social good full
Speaker 5:  stock.
Speaker 1:  Yes, I agree with you.
Speaker 5:  There's, yeah, I know the least controversial statement
Speaker 1:  As, as someone who also participates in that dynamic. Yes, I agree.
Speaker 5:  Right? So I was participating along with many
Speaker 5:  others in networks of ethical whistle blowing, which would have provided
Speaker 5:  that pretext, right? Like easy, like pick this person off. But
Speaker 5:  we were using Signal and we knew Signal was secure and we were, you know,
Speaker 5:  using Signal on our personal devices. So there was no like device manager
Speaker 5:  that was able to key log very important detail for those of you taking notes.
Speaker 5:  And that meant that I could feel safe
Speaker 5:  being part of those activities. And I, you know, it's very,
Speaker 5:  it's hard to describe in like clear, you know, kind of analytical,
Speaker 5:  sterile technical terms what that meant. But it was, you know, it's the difference
Speaker 5:  between that like stomach dropping fear when you're like,
Speaker 5:  shit did one of the most sophisticated technical adversaries just like,
Speaker 5:  you know, blow up my spot, you know, which means that like I'm
Speaker 5:  unsafe, my health insurance is unsafe. I might, you know, implicate some
Speaker 5:  of my friends who I'm, you know, also working with on this.
Speaker 5:  You know, the difference between that and being able to sort of like clearly
Speaker 5:  and securely sort of participate in those ethical activities.
Speaker 5:  And again, you know, there is no, there is no, you
Speaker 5:  know, splitting the baby on this question, right? Either it is secure and
Speaker 5:  it's private for everyone or it's not. And then there's a big
Speaker 5:  question like an existential question like why do this at all?
Speaker 1:  Like I said, I agree with you, but there's idealism and then there's
Speaker 1:  in practice, So there's an election coming up.
Speaker 1:  If the Proud Boys post a signal group chat link to
Speaker 1:  recruit people to go storm the capital because they don't believe in the
Speaker 1:  election results, what, what happens? Do you have a a moderation team that
Speaker 1:  takes it down? Do you just let it happen? How does that go?
Speaker 5:  I think like if we look back at like January 6th, that's actually like a
Speaker 5:  pretty good example that was planned in the open, right?
Speaker 1:  Sure. But I'm, but I'm asking you specifically if this happens on Signal,
Speaker 1:  what happens?
Speaker 5:  I mean, we would not know that, right? Like Signal is fully private
Speaker 5:  and fully encrypted,
Speaker 1:  But if, But the links are not private or Right, the you can just post the
Speaker 1:  links.
Speaker 5:  Well the links could be posted in a forum, right? And the groups have
Speaker 5:  a limit of a thousand people.
Speaker 1:  So you, you can't even see that a thousand people have clicked this link
Speaker 1:  and started planning the
Speaker 5:  Thing. No, we can see that a link exists to a group we don't know about.
Speaker 1:  And if the link isn't a proud Voice forum, you would not take any action
Speaker 1:  against it. If you're like, if it's like click this link to help plan,
Speaker 5:  So are you, are you asking do we have people out there clicking every link
Speaker 5:  that is, you know, and then like checking out, does the forum sort of comport
Speaker 5:  with an ideological position that Signal agrees with? Cuz we don't, we don't
Speaker 1:  Have that. Yeah, I think in the most abstract way I'm saying do you have
Speaker 1:  a content moderation
Speaker 5:  Team? No, we, I mean we don't have Con we're not, you know, we're also not
Speaker 5:  a social media platform, right? We don't amplify content. We don't, you know,
Speaker 5:  we don't have sort of kind of Telegram, I think they're called channels,
Speaker 5:  right? Yeah. Where there's sort of broadcast only to like, you know, thousands
Speaker 5:  and thousands of people. We have been really careful in our product development
Speaker 5:  side not to develop Signal as a social network that
Speaker 5:  has sort of algorithmic amplification that allows that, you know,
Speaker 5:  one to millions, you know, amplification of content. We are a,
Speaker 5:  you know, we are a messaging platform so we don't, you know,
Speaker 5:  we don't have a content moderation team because one, we are fully private,
Speaker 5:  we don't see your content, we don't know who you're talking about. And two,
Speaker 5:  because we're not, you know, we're not a content platform. It's a different
Speaker 5:  paradigm.
Speaker 1:  So Signal has a terms of service, there's stuff you're not allowed to do
Speaker 1:  with it. How do you enforce that terms of service?
Speaker 5:  You know, we don't have access to your messaging, we don't have access to
Speaker 5:  who you're talking to. We have, you know, minimized our access to
Speaker 5:  information about you, about your conversations, about your friends, about
Speaker 5:  your networks. So, you know, we are not, we are not out there
Speaker 5:  policing who you talk to, to policing what you talk about.
Speaker 5:  You know, that's anathema to the mission of Signal.
Speaker 1:  So you've added stories, which is the ephemeral messages people aren't probably
Speaker 1:  familiar with. The reason that those are popular, especially for app is cuz
Speaker 1:  they're sticky, right? It gets people to come back and use the app more and
Speaker 1:  you can measure it and you can say, we need to add more sticky features.
Speaker 1:  Does Signal measure the stickiness of the app? Are you like measuring how
Speaker 1:  people use it to add features that are sticky like
Speaker 5:  That? No, we don't do analytics or tracking. So we actually
Speaker 5:  don't have that information, which is, which means we have to use
Speaker 5:  other pieces of information and intuition when we're making product choices.
Speaker 5:  But you know, we don't measure that. We have very, very limited information.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. You know, when people last use the app, is
Speaker 1:  It so when, when you have product people and engineers deciding what features
Speaker 1:  to add, they don't have the data to back up their arguments, they just have
Speaker 1:  to say, this is a good
Speaker 5:  Idea. Yeah, we don't track or analyze use on, on specific
Speaker 5:  features. So, you know, there are insights that are produced outside of Signal.
Speaker 5:  There is sort of, you know, basic sensibilities that come from, you know,
Speaker 5:  folks having experience and sort of, you know, oftentimes decades of
Speaker 5:  experience in the messaging space. So it's not, you know, we're not riding
Speaker 5:  blind, we're just not relying on, you know, surveilling our users to make
Speaker 5:  our choices.
Speaker 1:  That seems extremely refreshing. We need to take another break, but when
Speaker 1:  we come back, we're gonna talk about signals revenue.
Speaker 1:  We're back with Meredith Whitaker. Let's just talk about government regulators
Speaker 1:  for a minute. Usually when regulators, particularly in this
Speaker 1:  country lately want to break encryption, they
Speaker 1:  immediately turn to child abuse. It is maybe a new and
Speaker 1:  and somewhat startling trend that this is what regulators have focused on
Speaker 1:  to break encryption. They have pointed that gun at Apple
Speaker 1:  really strongly. Apple developed a system, it has not yet rolled it out
Speaker 1:  to scan your devices in this way. They claim protects your
Speaker 1:  privacy so you can't use their devices or child abuse material.
Speaker 1:  Is that something that Signal would do to say we don't even we to protect
Speaker 1:  everyone. We know that there has to be some amount of child abuse material
Speaker 1:  that's just the unnerving reality of all services at scale
Speaker 1:  and signal saying we don't, we, we can't even see it, we can't take any action
Speaker 1:  against it. Or is there something you would do to take action against it?
Speaker 5:  I would point to the work of folks like Rayna Ricco,
Speaker 5:  Matt Blaze, Susan Landow, who've looked at sort of
Speaker 5:  content scanning and what, you know, we might refer to as
Speaker 5:  analog backdoor. You know, the issue with Apple's
Speaker 5:  proposal to scan everything on your device is that they
Speaker 5:  still control sort of, you know, what they're scanning for.
Speaker 5:  And I would, you know, I would also point to a number of the, you know, the
Speaker 5:  sex worker organizers and people who are more on the margins, who
Speaker 5:  are more fearful of being kind of caught up in these
Speaker 5:  scannings. These, you know, often arbitrary, arbitrarily enforced.
Speaker 5:  Very rarely are there ways to contest these decisions.
Speaker 5:  And you know, when you have a company like Apple, it's very
Speaker 5:  unclear whether, you know, whether through some
Speaker 5:  national security letter or another mechanism, the US
Speaker 5:  government or another state could, you know, mandate scanning for just a
Speaker 5:  little extra, right? It is a extremely dangerous slippery slope
Speaker 5:  that is right at the nexus of state corporate surveillance.
Speaker 5:  These techniques, you know, whatever you call them, you know,
Speaker 5:  need to be understood as sort of back doors into privacy and
Speaker 5:  encryption. So no signal is not, you know, has absolutely no plans to
Speaker 5:  scan anyone's messages to decide which messages are okay or, or not.
Speaker 5:  That is our general stance there.
Speaker 1:  So we've actually had peppercorn on the show. Let's talk about the Apple
Speaker 1:  system before.
Speaker 5:  Fabulous. Hi Rena,
Speaker 1:  She's wonderful. Yeah, go, go listen to that episode too. Listen, finish
Speaker 1:  listening to this one and then go listen to that one. But you know, Apple's
Speaker 1:  position there is, well we think this is bad. We are getting this government
Speaker 1:  pressure. We've built this complicated system. You know,
Speaker 1:  Microsoft has built a complicated system to hash against this known imagery.
Speaker 1:  There's other ways to do it. It is all very complicated. It comes with a
Speaker 1:  set of tradeoffs, but the goal of those trade-offs is to eliminate
Speaker 1:  the bad things, right? And you can say the trade-offs are to
Speaker 1:  costly, but the goal
Speaker 1:  is potentially a good one, like probably a good one, right? Don't have
Speaker 1:  this material on our service. You're saying the tradeoffs are far too costly.
Speaker 1:  We're gonna just allow this material on the, on the signal service.
Speaker 5:  I'm saying the, the tradeoffs aren't tradeoffs, right? There isn't like some,
Speaker 5:  you know, kind of scale of justice that we are sort of, you know, like
Speaker 5:  evening out, right? Like, you either break it or you don't. Either
Speaker 5:  signal's core premise is intact or it's not. And that's just, you know,
Speaker 5:  that's that. And I also, you know, there are arguments that
Speaker 5:  I think there are better people positioned to make than I,
Speaker 5:  but there are a lot of techniques for law enforcement
Speaker 5:  that don't involve immediately turning
Speaker 5:  to digital surveillance, right? And there are a lot
Speaker 5:  of, I think, I think we need to dig into a more troubling history
Speaker 5:  of where is, you know, where are these bad things not
Speaker 5:  prosecuted? Who doesn't get prosecuted for them, right? Like, where are there,
Speaker 5:  you know, where are they allowed to exist in the analog world?
Speaker 5:  Because there's an unwillingness or political pressure not to check them,
Speaker 5:  or a lack of focus on these. And,
Speaker 5:  you know, really explore like what other mechanisms exist to, you
Speaker 5:  know, check these dynamics that are not often using, you know, the
Speaker 5:  most emotionally, emotionally stirring arguments,
Speaker 5:  which really, you know, it is. I don't think any of us can sit here and like
Speaker 5:  listen to, you know, stories about child abuse and not being moved
Speaker 5:  unless we're, you know, sociopaths, right? Yeah. Like, you know, this really
Speaker 5:  matters and it is horrific, right? Full stop. But
Speaker 5:  too often I think that pretext gets used to
Speaker 5:  sort of reflexively instill in people a response
Speaker 5:  to these questions that's like, break anything. We have to break. Cause this
Speaker 5:  is like too emotionally meaningful for me to like sit by, right? Without,
Speaker 5:  you know, it almost short circuits that sort of, you know, deliberate
Speaker 5:  and, you know, discerning analysis of the, the whole
Speaker 5:  scope of the problem. So I think that is also an issue with this debate.
Speaker 1:  So we've talked about government pressure, we've talked about the content
Speaker 1:  moderation problem. Those are problems that come with scale, right? Is you
Speaker 1:  get more and more scale, more and more governments are gonna pressure you
Speaker 1:  to break things. Is you get more and more scale, you'll get more and more
Speaker 1:  pressure from your users, from your employees potentially to, to moderate
Speaker 1:  in some, some way. Let's actually talk about how you would get that skill
Speaker 1:  right Now in United States, for example, almost everybody has
Speaker 1:  a phone, right? There's a significant population of people who don't
Speaker 1:  have access. But it is reasonably fair to say the people who can get phones
Speaker 1:  have phones in the United States. You have to take
Speaker 1:  market share away from competitors in order to grow, right? You
Speaker 1:  have to, people have to start using signal and stop using sms. They have
Speaker 1:  to stop using iMessage. They have to stop using WhatsApp. iMessage is pretty
Speaker 1:  dominant, right? There. There is like a trope about blue bubbles and green
Speaker 1:  bubbles that exist for a reason. iMessage users are not willing to switch
Speaker 1:  away from those blue bubbles. How do you get them to switch?
Speaker 5:  Well, first just install signal, right? Use it with
Speaker 5:  the people who are using signal, you know, in a sense like,
Speaker 5:  yes, of course we want people to switch, but you know, many people
Speaker 5:  use many different, you know, services, you know, potentially overlapping
Speaker 5:  services for many things, right? So I think, you know, I think
Speaker 5:  we first need to make it clear that signal is sort of different,
Speaker 5:  right? You know, what we offer is, you know,
Speaker 5:  true privacy, not, you know, privacy claims with little
Speaker 5:  caveats, you know, in a 15 page term of service and make it
Speaker 5:  clear like this is, you know, extremely valuable is something that will,
Speaker 5:  you know, protect you allow for, you know, intimate, safe
Speaker 5:  conversations with you and your friends. And I think, you know, we do see
Speaker 5:  people sort of understanding that, you know, understanding those
Speaker 5:  distinctions increasingly, you know, over the fir the, the last five years.
Speaker 5:  And then our task is to make signal as pleasant and useful
Speaker 5:  as possible, right? What are the features we can add that competitors
Speaker 5:  might not be willing or able to because of our
Speaker 5:  unique business model? Because our incentives are different, You
Speaker 5:  know, because, you know, privacy is forefront in, in our, in our product
Speaker 5:  and in our mission. Then we just need to make sure like, people know about
Speaker 5:  it and people are able to quickly and easily use it, right? You should open
Speaker 5:  signal. And again, you shouldn't have to really, you know, you can believe
Speaker 5:  that it's important, you can know why you downloaded it, but the second you're
Speaker 5:  using it to like, you know, share directions, you shouldn't be
Speaker 5:  actively thinking about that. It should just work. There should be a seamless
Speaker 5:  experience. You know, you get in there, you know, share your story. We have
Speaker 5:  a, a new feature that is in beta right now as stories. They're very cute.
Speaker 5:  I encourage people to use that when they're fully available.
Speaker 5:  And, and you know, it, it looks and feels and,
Speaker 5:  you know, acts like a messaging app, which again is, you know, this is not
Speaker 5:  easy, right? Like the, the norms and expectations about what
Speaker 5:  messaging apps should do have been set by these big, you know,
Speaker 5:  surveillance messaging apps, right? These, you know, big kind of
Speaker 5:  corporate structures, right? And, and signal, you know, just by way of
Speaker 5:  comparison, this is the sort of stat I've thrown around in a, in a couple
Speaker 5:  places, but WhatsApp has over a thousand engineers, and that's just
Speaker 5:  their engineering team. I think if you added sort of, you know, support and
Speaker 5:  policy, et cetera, et cetera, you're looking at many thousands of people
Speaker 5:  just, you know, sustaining WhatsApp. That's not meta. You have Telegram has,
Speaker 5:  you know, somewhere around 500 employees. So that's, you know, fairly big.
Speaker 5:  And Signal is 40 people, you know, it's 40 people maintaining
Speaker 5:  an app across, you know, three clients. It's not, you know,
Speaker 5:  it's not, it's, it's hard thankless constant work. And I'm, you know,
Speaker 5:  I'm privileged to work with the brilliant people who do it, but nonetheless,
Speaker 5:  they work really hard doing it. It's not any cheaper for us just because
Speaker 5:  we don't participate in the surveillance business model, right? So it's tens
Speaker 5:  of millions of dollars a year, and that's like hosting transit
Speaker 5:  registration, you know, et cetera, et cetera. All of the costs
Speaker 5:  of just, you know, making sure Signal is available everywhere, always
Speaker 5:  seamlessly, which are the expectations that have been set, you know, by the
Speaker 5:  current tech ecology. So I think, you know, we, we do need
Speaker 5:  to, you know, continue developing and building signals so it meets those
Speaker 5:  expectations and figure out ways that a, that a service like
Speaker 5:  ours can sustain given, you know, given the forever cost
Speaker 5:  and given the labor requirements.
Speaker 1:  So, but that's the, the forever cost is what I'm getting at, is it's hard
Speaker 1:  enough to get people to not use iMessage. Like Google
Speaker 1:  has now failed for a decade to get people to switch off of iMessage.
Speaker 1:  So like, doing this truly
Speaker 5:  Appalling strategy,
Speaker 1:  Right? I mean, but like it is in Google's best interest
Speaker 1:  to develop a messaging app that works, and they google's Google and
Speaker 1:  they can't get outta there. They
Speaker 5:  Developed 40,000 that didn't work. So, you know,
Speaker 1:  Sure. But they can't do it, right? Microsoft can't do it. Facebook
Speaker 1:  can't do it. Facebook will happily tell you that more, there's more action
Speaker 1:  on Instagram in messaging than there is on the grid or in stories,
Speaker 1:  but they haven't displaced iMessage. You've got that problem.
Speaker 1:  And then on top of it, you've got the, also the users need to like us so
Speaker 1:  much they donate to our foundation so we can keep the thing running. Well,
Speaker 5:  Not every user needs to donate, right? We need, you know,
Speaker 5:  again, we're never gonna, we're never gonna charge to use Signal because,
Speaker 5:  you know, privacy shouldn't be only for people who want to,
Speaker 5:  you know, pay for it or can pay for it. But we do think that
Speaker 5:  people will recognize, you know, I I, I don't subscribe to,
Speaker 5:  to the theory that like, people are idiots, right? I think people are very
Speaker 5:  discerning and they get it when they hear it, right? And, you know, people
Speaker 5:  get that the surveillance business model is no good, right? They get
Speaker 5:  that we are, you know, some here somewhere fairly scary with the power
Speaker 5:  that has been, you know, sort of seated to these large, you know,
Speaker 5:  surveillance tech giants, right? And, you know, they
Speaker 5:  understand that like alternatives are necessary. So it, you know, it doesn't
Speaker 5:  have to be everyone, but some percentage of the millions of people
Speaker 5:  who use Signal donating five bucks a month, right? Like,
Speaker 5:  that's what we're looking at, like a casual Patreon model that is again,
Speaker 5:  at scale so that we are, you know, we're able to support the
Speaker 5:  significant, you know, maintenance costs for Signal. And
Speaker 5:  that, you know, frankly is, is the hardest
Speaker 5:  to kind of cut off at the knees, right? What we don't want is to have, you
Speaker 5:  know, we, we are really, really fortunate that, you know, Brian
Speaker 5:  Actins generous, you know, long-term loan has allowed
Speaker 5:  us this foundation to sort of experiment with sustainability
Speaker 5:  models, to like, you know, grow signal to get it in
Speaker 5:  shape. But I think, you know, we're really aiming for small donors both
Speaker 5:  because we think people will be willing to donate and because we want
Speaker 5:  a model that, you know, where, where one person pulling out, wouldn't camp
Speaker 5:  capsize the ship?
Speaker 1:  Is that the model you have or is that the model you want? Because it's, it
Speaker 1:  seems like it's the model you want, but right now you've got Brian's money
Speaker 1:  and a bunch of other big donors.
Speaker 5:  We have like a hybrid, right? It's, you know, we have only
Speaker 5:  started experimenting with the donation model. So, you know, it was buried
Speaker 5:  like for a while there was like a donate page buried on our
Speaker 5:  website that, you know, people probably rarely found. And now we
Speaker 5:  are sort of, you know, experimenting, which is in app nudges
Speaker 5:  that are like, Hey, if you wanna kick down, kick down, we have
Speaker 5:  badges, which are like cute little signifiers that go on your profile
Speaker 5:  image that just, you know, demonstrate that you donated. People can click
Speaker 5:  on your badge, they can sort of click through to make their own donation.
Speaker 5:  But this is very recent, This is like, you know, in the last year or so,
Speaker 5:  and I think we are again sort of iterating and experimenting with that
Speaker 5:  model and, you know, everyone listening, you know, download signal, if you
Speaker 5:  haven't make a little monthly donation, you know, it's, it's easy.
Speaker 5:  And I can use some like boring non-profit trope. It's like
Speaker 5:  a cup of coffee or whatever, but like, oh no, you know, really this is existentially
Speaker 5:  important for like a livable future. We have to have a private way to communicate.
Speaker 5:  And you know, folks, particularly folks who are in and around tech, I
Speaker 5:  think will understand that at a visceral level. And, you know,
Speaker 5:  come on, join the community kick in.
Speaker 1:  Are you, is it gonna be like Wikipedia? Are you gonna ask us for money every,
Speaker 1:  every three months?
Speaker 5:  Well, no, we are, we're gonna have a lot of chill
Speaker 5:  and
Speaker 5:  we, you know, we wanna remind people that we need money, but we also, you
Speaker 5:  know, like the app is a messaging app, right? Like what we're dedicated to
Speaker 5:  first and foremost is you open it, it's useful, it is pleasant,
Speaker 5:  it's not in your face. So, you know, we wanna be, we wanna
Speaker 5:  remind you, but we wanna be really subtle about it. And that is actually
Speaker 5:  something we have a lot of discussions about. Like what is the minimum viable
Speaker 5:  sort of notice to folks that we can get away with and still
Speaker 5:  ensure that people, people who can donate, know, and,
Speaker 5:  and can sign up easily.
Speaker 1:  Last year we reported that I think it was Moxie's assessment that
Speaker 1:  for Signal to be self-sustaining, it would need a hundred million users.
Speaker 1:  Is that still the number in your mind, or how close are you to that goal?
Speaker 5:  You know, number of users is like, that's a shorthand
Speaker 5:  assessment from Moxi, right? It's number, you know, percentage of a
Speaker 5:  hundred million users who also donate, right? Yeah. Like more users
Speaker 5:  is more hosting, more transit, more
Speaker 5:  registration costs, which is actually sort of, you know, a cost without folks
Speaker 5:  donating. But yeah, I, you know, I think it's tens of millions of
Speaker 5:  dollars a year. So we need enough users donating
Speaker 5:  as a percentage of any user base so that we are, you know,
Speaker 5:  we are able to, you know, cover those costs.
Speaker 1:  Are you at a hundred million users? How close are you
Speaker 5:  To it? We are not at, we, we don't share user data
Speaker 5:  publicly. We, we are not at a hundred million users, I guess is the,
Speaker 5:  the straight answer to that question. But our user base is growing
Speaker 5:  and you can see, you know, we have over a hundred million in downloads in
Speaker 5:  the play store. You know, we have a significant user base, which is,
Speaker 5:  which is increasing. And I think, you know, I definitely think we will get
Speaker 5:  there.
Speaker 1:  So you recently announced that you're dropping SMS support from the Signal
Speaker 1:  app. Google's pushing rcs really hard, converting
Speaker 1:  people into messaging apps is really hard. Getting people to not use iMessage
Speaker 1:  is really hard. Why drop sms?
Speaker 5:  This is one of those decisions that has been a long time
Speaker 5:  coming, has been agonized over, you know, by the leadership
Speaker 5:  team, you know, before and after I joined, you know,
Speaker 5:  surfaced at the board level. So this was not an easy decision.
Speaker 5:  And for kind of a little bit of color on this signal is dropping SMS
Speaker 5:  support for Android. So on Android, not iPhone,
Speaker 5:  Android allowed people to set Signal as their default messaging app.
Speaker 5:  So that meant they could send signal messages, which are, you know, fully
Speaker 5:  encrypted, fully private and secure, or they could also
Speaker 5:  answer insecure SMS text messages. So the SMS text messages were kind
Speaker 5:  of like a guest in their text messaging house and were answered through
Speaker 5:  Signal, you know, alongside signal messages. This has been a feature that
Speaker 5:  has been in the Android client for, you know, almost a decade
Speaker 5:  at this point. And in that decade, a lot has changed.
Speaker 5:  You know, SMS has always been insecure, but you know, SMS
Speaker 5:  basically gives your messages in plain text to your telecom
Speaker 5:  provider. So that is the opposite of signals stance
Speaker 5:  and signals mission. And you know, frankly it was, we got a lot of reports
Speaker 5:  that this was confusing to people. People didn't realize the difference between
Speaker 5:  SMS and a signal message. And you know, we take that seriously
Speaker 5:  because that can be, you know, that can be existentially dangerous
Speaker 5:  for some people who are using signal in some high risk situations.
Speaker 5:  There was also the issue, and this is not something that would've hit users
Speaker 5:  in the US or in sort of, you know, historically rich
Speaker 5:  countries, but in a number of disinvested regions, we were having people
Speaker 5:  who would confuse an SMS message for a signal message,
Speaker 5:  send a bunch of SMS texts, and because SMS
Speaker 5:  messages are Bill at a very high rate, would get a huge bill when they
Speaker 5:  were thinking they were using their data to use signals. So, you know, those
Speaker 5:  are a couple of the key reasons. I think the security was really the,
Speaker 5:  the biggest reason. But there's also, you know, times have changed since
Speaker 5:  10 years ago. So as you said, Google is pushing rcs and RCS
Speaker 5:  is, you know, know they hope and, and it, you know, it, it
Speaker 5:  appears it's, it's set to replace SMS at some point, and
Speaker 5:  that was leading to more and more errors with the SMS integration.
Speaker 5:  So, you know, you would not receive a message if your phone defaulted to
Speaker 5:  rcs or something like that. And that meant, you know, that was
Speaker 5:  increasingly hard for us to deal with on the user report
Speaker 5:  side. That meant that it was increasingly difficult to sort of, you know,
Speaker 5:  support SMS as a degrading standard.
Speaker 5:  And it was, you know, it was something where, you know, there still isn't
Speaker 5:  an official API for rcs, you know, for Signal
Speaker 5:  to implement it, even if we were considering it, which was not, you know,
Speaker 5:  that's not on our roadmap at this point. So, you know, those are the
Speaker 5:  considerations that went into making this choice. Again, like I am a
Speaker 5:  lifelong or well, the life of Signal long Android Signal
Speaker 5:  user, who's used it as my default the whole whole time. So this is, you know,
Speaker 5:  like this is the front of my pain points, but weighing the kind of security,
Speaker 5:  the confusion, and the fact that SMS is a deprecating standard
Speaker 5:  were, you know, were things that waited in the direction of removing it and
Speaker 5:  sort of moving onto a future where Signal is fully secure and there's no
Speaker 5:  ambiguity.
Speaker 1:  Let me push you this a little bit. Obviously Apple
Speaker 1:  has played this game for a long time.
Speaker 1:  iMessages, depending on your iMessage settings are
Speaker 1:  encrypted end to end. They're blue, they're more feature rich.
Speaker 1:  SMS is green, everyone understands Green is worse than Blue in
Speaker 1:  iPhone world. Why can't you just do a solution like that? Because what you're
Speaker 1:  losing is the opportunity to convert SMS users into
Speaker 1:  signal users by saying, just use this one app for everything. And
Speaker 1:  by the way, if your messages turn blue, you're in
Speaker 1:  signal, you're encrypted to get all these other features.
Speaker 5:  Let's be clear, Apple has advantages. We don't, there, you know,
Speaker 5:  they control the hardware, they are the gatekeeper for the,
Speaker 5:  you know, iOS and the iPhone and they have a lot of levers they
Speaker 5:  can pull that we can't, right? You know, they also don't support rcs,
Speaker 5:  right? And we're talking about the Android ecosystem here, but right now
Speaker 5:  there are two competing, you know, protocols. There's SMS and there is
Speaker 5:  rcs and you know, it is difficult to implement a third party
Speaker 5:  SMS app when you know the phone will default to rcs, right?
Speaker 5:  So there are a lot of other issues that we face as you know,
Speaker 5:  we are not a big tech company that controls the hardware, that has
Speaker 5:  that sort of closed ecosystem at our disposal so that we
Speaker 5:  can sort of reliably make those choices for users. But yeah, you know,
Speaker 5:  we did a lot of work trying to disambiguate SMS between signal
Speaker 5:  messages and you know, this is no fault of the people who use Signal. This
Speaker 5:  is simply like when people pick up tech, it's not so that they can be taught
Speaker 5:  small nuances, right? So they can quickly communicate with their friends.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And so getting someone to sort of clock the difference in like a
Speaker 5:  protocol layer security property, that's a, you know, that's an
Speaker 5:  education task that is pretty steep. It is very difficult to accomplish
Speaker 5:  and it's particularly difficult to accomplish if unlike Apple, you don't,
Speaker 5:  you know, control every, you know, part of the ecosystem you're operating
Speaker 5:  in.
Speaker 1:  You said rcs isn't on the roadmap, You said Google doesn't
Speaker 1:  have an API for rcs Android. If Google had an API for RCS
Speaker 1:  and Android, would rcs support go back on the roadmap for Signal and
Speaker 1:  Android?
Speaker 5:  You know, I haven't looked deeply enough at that to have a clear answer.
Speaker 5:  I think that the answer is tbd, right? Like our goal is
Speaker 5:  for signal to offer unequivocal casual, you know,
Speaker 5:  just completely reliable security and privacy. So we
Speaker 5:  would want to make sure RCS wasn't an issue, vivi
Speaker 5:  those goals. I know, you know, rcs is certainly much better than sms, but
Speaker 5:  I haven't, I have not poured over the spec because again, you know, our primary
Speaker 5:  motivation in this was get rid of this, you know, confusing and
Speaker 5:  inherently insecure option. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  One of the criticisms that I read after the announcement came out was,
Speaker 1:  Hey, I was able to put signal on my mom's phone and she didn't have to
Speaker 1:  know anything, but I knew that I was now sending her signal messages. This
Speaker 1:  is how you grow the network. Now I need to have two apps. They need to have
Speaker 1:  two apps. This is actually worse for signal adoption because you're not sort
Speaker 1:  of seamlessly onboarding people onto the encrypted network away from sms.
Speaker 1:  Are you worried about that? Or do you think this is just straight up we got
Speaker 1:  a market and make the thing better?
Speaker 5:  This is why this was a hard decision, right? Like, those folks are not wrong.
Speaker 5:  That's real, right? Like I'm one of them, right? My dad uses Signal, he
Speaker 5:  doesn't really know, he uses Signal, right? Yeah. He just uses the, you know,
Speaker 5:  the app where the messages come in. You know, it will, this will probably
Speaker 5:  be very confusing. And yeah, we, I think what we did is make
Speaker 5:  a hard kind of crappy choice. We were presented with two
Speaker 5:  options we didn't like, and we chose the one that, you know, privileged privacy
Speaker 5:  and security and a kind of a long-term roadmap where again,
Speaker 5:  you know, SMS is being deprecated, People were confused, it was causing an
Speaker 5:  increasing amount of errors. And you know, the development effort of maintaining
Speaker 5:  that in addition to doing all the other things was, you know, non-trivial.
Speaker 5:  So yeah, no, you know, those, those folks are right. You know, when we
Speaker 5:  weighed all of the variables, this is what we came out with.
Speaker 5:  I do think people will continue to use Signal. Of course people will continue
Speaker 5:  to adopt it, but, you know, it does make me really, you know, I'm not
Speaker 5:  happy about, you know, as I put on Twitter, like pulling up on, on ramp to
Speaker 5:  adoption, right? I'm not happy that it's gonna be harder for me to like explain
Speaker 5:  this to my dad and my brother and you know, other folks. But
Speaker 5:  you know, we don't, we don't create the reality that we're kind of
Speaker 5:  operating in. And we had to face that
Speaker 1:  One of the promises of rcs is that it will be encrypted. I'm not
Speaker 1:  sure how well carriers around the world are gonna keep that promise or Google
Speaker 1:  will keep that promise, but that is one of the promises. Do you think that
Speaker 1:  RCS represents competition for Signal?
Speaker 5:  Not at the moment, no.
Speaker 1:  Why's that?
Speaker 5:  Well, again, I haven't poured over the rcs spec, so I wanna be really
Speaker 5:  careful with like, you know, any flip answers and you know, I could do that
Speaker 5:  and come back on and we could have a whole conversation about it. Signal
Speaker 5:  is not just encrypted, right? Like WhatsApp uses the signal
Speaker 5:  protocol to encrypt its messages. Signal doesn't just encrypt the
Speaker 5:  message content, right? It is encrypting metadata. It is,
Speaker 5:  you know, it did, you know something which I considered like fairly
Speaker 5:  revolutionary with its, you know, its new groups, methods
Speaker 5:  and infrastructure, which was figure out a way to prevent signal
Speaker 5:  from knowing who is in a group and who's talking to whom, right? Like these
Speaker 5:  things are, you know, huge, you know, true, like kind of scientific
Speaker 5:  innovations that are also innovations in privacy. That is
Speaker 5:  sort of signal trying as hard as we can to collect as little information
Speaker 5:  about you, about who you talk to as little meaningful information about,
Speaker 5:  you know, what people are saying, who they're saying to it, who's using our
Speaker 5:  server, our service, et cetera. So, you know, I would need to
Speaker 5:  look at like the entire kind of end to end infrastructure,
Speaker 5:  what incidental or metadata is being collected. And then
Speaker 5:  I think we have to consider the concept of privacy structurally, not just
Speaker 5:  technologically, right? Like people use encryption for a number of things.
Speaker 5:  They still collect data, right? Like, you know, if we're looking at an app
Speaker 5:  that is controlled by Google, it is pretty trivial to
Speaker 5:  join that metadata with a lot of the other, you know, wildly
Speaker 5:  intimate and personal data that Google has and sort of make conclusions about
Speaker 5:  people, right? So, you know, we need to also look at the organizational and
Speaker 5:  structural differences, but between a Signal and a Google and, you know,
Speaker 5:  Google Signal doesn't have any of that data. We don't buy data from data
Speaker 5:  brokers. We don't, you know, scrape data from anywhere. We don't have it.
Speaker 5:  We don't want it. We actually go out of our way, as I just described, to
Speaker 5:  avoid having it or touching it or knowing it, right? So I
Speaker 5:  think that, you know, I think that we're talking about a difference in kind
Speaker 5:  and that difference in kind is not just Visa vr technological
Speaker 5:  implementation or you know, whether we're using this variety of end-to-end
Speaker 5:  encryption, although, you know, the people who are using the state-of-the-art
Speaker 5:  messaging encryption system are using the signal protocol. I think what we're
Speaker 5:  talking about also is what our incentives and how are we structured to ensure
Speaker 5:  that we, you know, live by our mission and not, you know, in the name of
Speaker 5:  profit and growth. Well,
Speaker 1:  Meredith, it's been really great having on decoder. Thank you for all this
Speaker 1:  time. What's next for Signal? What should people be looking for?
Speaker 5:  Well, you should definitely check out for, you know, look out for the stories
Speaker 5:  update that's in a, you know, a couple of weeks. We should be rolling out
Speaker 5:  stories, which are, you know, cute little ephemeral messages that you may
Speaker 5:  be familiar with from other services, but on Signal they will be, you know,
Speaker 5:  fully private and secure. And that, you know, that's the
Speaker 5:  next big feature launch and we're all using it inside Signal. We all love
Speaker 5:  it and it's gonna be great when we can actually use it with, you know, all
Speaker 5:  of our friends and, and colleagues on single.
Speaker 1:  Great. Thank you Saa. Koder, great. It's
Speaker 5:  Great talking. Thank you.
Speaker 1:  Thanks again to Meredith Whitaker for being on Dakota today, and thank you
Speaker 1:  for listening. I hope you enjoyed it. As always. I'd love to hear what you
Speaker 1:  think of decoder. You can email us at decoder@theverge.com or you can hit
Speaker 1:  me up directly. I'm at Reckless on Twitter. If you like the show, please
Speaker 1:  share it with your friends and subscribe wherever we get your podcasts. If
Speaker 1:  you really like decoder, give us that five star review. And as many of of
Speaker 1:  you have noticed, if you tweet at me about decoder, I will almost certainly
Speaker 1:  retweet you. Decoder is a production of The Verge and part of the Vox Media
Speaker 1:  podcast network. Today's episode is produced by Creighton De Simone and Jackie
Speaker 1:  McDermott was researched by Liz Leanne, and edited by Kelly Wright. The
Speaker 1:  decoder music is by Breakmaster Cylinder. Our senior audio director is Andrew
Speaker 1:  Marino. Our editorial director is Brooke Miners, and our executive producer
Speaker 1:  is Eleanor Donovan. We'll see you next time.