# Transcript
ID: e44757f0-3d8c-11ed-a749-2b0b22ae0fe8
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: The complicated relationship between musicians and platforms
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-4145578475635237724/4238759883817590231/s93290-US-1138s-1664191054.mp3
Description: Today’s Future of Music episode comes from Ariel Shapiro, The Verge’s lead reporter of HotPod, our weekly newsletter about the audio industry. Last week on the show we talked about old music… specifically how the back catalog is a big part of what makes “new” music. This week Ariel picks up right where we left off, with the revival of stars from the past on platforms like TikTok. But what about new… undiscovered talent? Is that even a thing anymore? Can a budding artist find their place in the world of viral video? Ariel explores the complicated relationship between musicians and platforms.
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we'd love to hear from you.
We are conducting a short audience survey to help plan for our future and hear from you. To participate, head to vox.com/podsurvey, and thank you!
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (2 ads detected)
Speaker 2:  Welcome
Speaker 3:  To the Vergecast the flagship podcast of four on the floor. I'm your friend,
Speaker 3:  David Pierce. And this is the second part in our mini series. All about the
Speaker 3:  future of music. Today's episode comes from Ariel Shapiro, who is the verges
Speaker 3:  lead reporter of Hotpod, which is our weekly newsletter about the audio industry.
Speaker 3:  It's awesome. You should subscribe. Last week on the show, we talked about
Speaker 3:  old music specifically how the back catalog is a big part of
Speaker 3:  what makes new music this week. Ariel picks up right where we
Speaker 3:  left off with the revival of stars from the past on new platforms
Speaker 3:  like TikTok. But what about new undiscovered
Speaker 3:  talent? Is that even a thing anymore? Can a budding artist
Speaker 3:  find their place in this weird new world of viral video? It's more
Speaker 3:  complicated than you think, but I'll let Ariel explain. Let's go.
Speaker 4:  The powers that be anticipated, music streaming a lot earlier
Speaker 4:  than you might think back in 1995, before my
Speaker 4:  parents even had a CD player in their Subaru, the late Senator
Speaker 4:  Oren hatch pushed through a bill that would extend music copyright to the
Speaker 4:  digital space. He emphasized the rise of what legal circles
Speaker 4:  then referred to as the celestial jukebox, a
Speaker 4:  surprisingly poetic term for a tool that would allow listeners to access
Speaker 4:  any music they wanted at any time. The tech available
Speaker 4:  at the time was nowhere near that. This is before even Napster
Speaker 4:  entered the scene, but it was on the horizon. For the most part.
Speaker 4:  The promise of the celestial jukebox has been realized
Speaker 4:  practically, any song is available with the tap of a finger, maybe
Speaker 4:  for $10 a month, or maybe for nothing at all. If you're willing to sit through
Speaker 4:  ads, people are listening to more music than ever before. In the
Speaker 4:  first six months of the year, consumer streamed songs,
Speaker 4:  2.5 trillion times. And if you
Speaker 4:  ever dreamed of being a rock star, a rapper or a pop queen, it
Speaker 4:  has never been easier to make and share your tracks. Anyone with a
Speaker 4:  song in their heart, a laptop and a subscription to tune core could
Speaker 4:  upload their stuff right alongside Beyonce. It should be a golden age
Speaker 4:  for music. And yet many of the artists reaping
Speaker 4:  the benefits of this new landscape are not who you would expect,
Speaker 4:  like Fleetwood Mac going viral on TikTok. Thanks to Nathan
Speaker 4:  Apodaca cruising on his skateboard. Half gallon of ocean spray in hand,
Speaker 4:  simply vibing to dreams
Speaker 4:  or Kate Bush, the art pop queen of the 1980s, who finally
Speaker 4:  got her due when a well placed spin of running up that hill in
Speaker 4:  stranger things catapulted the song to the top of the billboard charts
Speaker 4:  or the 81 year old Paul ANCA whose 1959
Speaker 4:  classic put your head on my shoulder was remixed and slowed down
Speaker 4:  for a sexy silhouette challenge on TikTok.
Speaker 2:  Put your head on my show.
Speaker 4:  The remix has appeared in over 600,000 videos on
Speaker 4:  the platform, but if streaming is reviving the
Speaker 4:  stars of the past, how do aspiring stars fair in the new music
Speaker 4:  landscape?
Speaker 4:  More new music is flooding the platforms than ever before. And plenty
Speaker 4:  of amateur musicians go viral. They have a moment maybe even a hit
Speaker 4:  and then they fade as quickly as they rose. And that's not just my
Speaker 4:  elder millennial negativity. That's in the data. According to
Speaker 4:  illuminate the research firm behind Billboard's charts, the amount of time
Speaker 4:  consumers spent listening to new music declined 1.4%,
Speaker 4:  even as listening to older music or catalog jumped
Speaker 4:  19%, there are also simply fewer hits to stream
Speaker 4:  in the first place. In the second quarter of
Speaker 4:  twenty twenty one, a hundred and twenty
Speaker 4:  six new albums debuted on the billboard 200
Speaker 4:  during the
Speaker 4:  same period in 2022, only 102 did. So what gives,
Speaker 5:  I think discovery is the biggest challenge for certainly for new artists.
Speaker 4:  Rob Jonas is the CEO of illuminate and worked on the study.
Speaker 5:  There's been lots of coverage in recent months around the number of new
Speaker 5:  songs per day. We're now seeing about 74,000 new songs a day right now
Speaker 5:  coming into different platforms. It's just very, very hard to get discovered
Speaker 5:  and breakthrough right now, probably harder than ever. One thing we hear
Speaker 5:  consistently is they're struggling with the fact that they have to be always
Speaker 5:  creating new pieces of content, right? So it's not just around creating music
Speaker 5:  anymore. It's like, how do I create something that's relevant for this platform
Speaker 5:  or this platform? It's a continuous marketing challenge and content creation
Speaker 5:  challenge, because there's so much out there. They have to make sure they're
Speaker 5:  top of mind and relevant all the time.
Speaker 4:  Was it always this way in the late two thousands, early
Speaker 4:  2010s, it seemed possible for artists to get big on the internet
Speaker 4:  because artists were getting big on the internet and a good chunk of
Speaker 4:  them became bonafide stars. YouTube gave us Justin Bieber
Speaker 4:  and the weekend
Speaker 4:  my space gave us Taylor swift
Speaker 2:  Is we young and,
Speaker 4:  And Adele Adele,
Speaker 4:  before we go on a disclosure of bias, I was in my late
Speaker 4:  teens during that time, which means the music that I found on my space
Speaker 4:  that populated my turquoise iPod mini, for which I paid
Speaker 4:  a full 99 cents per song will forever be
Speaker 4:  burned into my brain. I can't remember where I put my wallet at any
Speaker 4:  given time, but I still know the harmonies of menos despite
Speaker 4:  having listened to fleet foxes, maybe a few times in the past
Speaker 4:  decade, that being said, there seemed to be something objectively special
Speaker 4:  about what was happening on MySpace and the industry knew it. Courtney
Speaker 4:  halt saw it firsthand as an executive at Interscope gin.
Speaker 6:  MySpace was the first time that I really saw artists and fans coexisting
Speaker 6:  in a space for me, it's sort of replicated that idea of seeing a
Speaker 6:  band you loved in a small club before they were big. So I don't know
Speaker 6:  how I could describe it other than it was just a feeling I had. I don't remember
Speaker 6:  something feeling like that in the music industry. Hadn't felt like that
Speaker 6:  in a long time.
Speaker 4:  My space was such a hot music destination that MTV wanted to buy
Speaker 4:  it before being undercut by Rupert Murdoch's news court
Speaker 7:  News Corp has been, I think, smart enough to let us continue to do
Speaker 7:  what we do and really keep hands off, which is not typical for a big
Speaker 7:  corporation like that. You sort of expect them to screw it up.
Speaker 4:  It continued to grow. And in 2007 had
Speaker 4:  67 million users when Facebook
Speaker 4:  only had a third of that.
Speaker 8:  Now Facebook, well, it was created by a guy from Harvard people,
Speaker 8:  praise it for its clean looks and controlled feel. But at the same time,
Speaker 8:  it's a little stuffy. Dare I say geeky.
Speaker 4:  In 2008, the company pushed to make MySpace a one stop
Speaker 4:  destination for music listening to make it more like the celestial
Speaker 4:  jukebox that was promised Holt was tapped to lead the music division
Speaker 4:  and bring established catalogs from Sony Warner and universal onto
Speaker 4:  the site. There was just one problem. Well, my space was
Speaker 4:  great for bonding over bands and building fandoms. It wasn't
Speaker 4:  actually that good for everyday listening.
Speaker 6:  Some of the features became bugs. The idea that I could
Speaker 6:  self-express and I could make this cool player and I could promote my
Speaker 6:  music again. I could celebrate my fans was great, but then to
Speaker 6:  actually make a playlist at a point in time, when we were starting to move
Speaker 6:  towards mobile, my space, wasn't ready for that in discovery,
Speaker 6:  lean forward, click play consume, interact. My
Speaker 6:  space was great at that lean back. I just want the music I
Speaker 6:  want, I want to take it with me. I want to have a playlist. It became a lot
Speaker 6:  harder for that to be the case. So you sort of look at the lack of
Speaker 6:  investment and innovation that Newsco wanted to put into it at
Speaker 6:  the time that there was an evolutionary shift in how music was being
Speaker 6:  consumed. So they had this really incredible magic engine, but it wasn't
Speaker 6:  adaptable for all of the evolutions that were gonna happen in music,
Speaker 6:  discovery and demand.
Speaker 4:  We're gonna take a quick break. When we get back, how we got from
Speaker 4:  my space to TikTok and saw the rise of the artist slash
Speaker 4:  influencer
Speaker 2:  Fox creative.
Speaker 9:  This is advertiser content brought to you by amp.
Speaker 10:  I was just singing all the time and everybody was like, you're gonna
Speaker 10:  be a pop star. And I was like, you know what? Yeah, I am gonna be a ball
Speaker 10:  star. My name is Jay Stevens. I am a singer
Speaker 10:  songwriter, producer, all of that from Los
Speaker 10:  Angeles, California. My parents said that I was singing before I could
Speaker 10:  talk my very own Chris Jenner. My mom, you know, she would always give me
Speaker 10:  songs to sing. And they were either gospel songs or like really old
Speaker 10:  ass R and B. My heart is breaking, blah, blah, blah.
Speaker 10:  I was like, look, I'm tired of this. I wanna write my own songs.
Speaker 9:  Jay wanted to create something fresh, something inspired by the artists
Speaker 9:  and songs. She loved most.
Speaker 10:  You got your Beyonces, you got your brandies, you got your Mariahs
Speaker 10:  that's Bible. Like you need it they're fundamentals. But then there was
Speaker 10:  my rebellious years where I was like, I wanna be edgy. I wanna be dark.
Speaker 9:  Those influences transformed. Jay's voice into something, uniquely her
Speaker 9:  on her. Self-produced single. Hi, my name is,
Speaker 10:  I wrote it in London at 3:00 AM and I
Speaker 10:  was high and I was in love. And that was what I wanted the song to feel
Speaker 10:  like
Speaker 2:  My name is
Speaker 2:  got
Speaker 9:  Find your next favorite song and discover the artists who will shape your
Speaker 9:  voice on the amp. The amp app offers live radio shows curated by
Speaker 9:  real people, not algorithms. Download amp on the app store today.
Speaker 4:  As MySpace attempted to build out its music platform, it was
Speaker 4:  declining on the social side by 2011, it had less than
Speaker 4:  one 10th of the number of users of Facebook, which was pretty agnostic
Speaker 4:  to music sharing that same year, Swedish music,
Speaker 4:  streamer, Spotify launched in the us. And unlike MySpace,
Speaker 4:  it was very good at the lean back experience,
Speaker 2:  Whatever you want
Speaker 11:  Whenever you wanted,
Speaker 4:  It gave you exactly the music that you wanted with little to no
Speaker 4:  interference at a price. Once unimaginable 10 bucks
Speaker 4:  a month in Spotify, the celestial jukebox was realized
Speaker 4:  and pushed companies like apple and Amazon to build similar subscription
Speaker 4:  services. But all that scale has made it harder for new artists
Speaker 4:  to break through Larry Miller, who leads the music business
Speaker 4:  program at NYU and has his own podcast
Speaker 4:  Musonomics explains what experts have witnessed.
Speaker 12:  One thing that we've observed is that the magnitude of
Speaker 12:  most hits is smaller. We've also noticed
Speaker 12:  that the amount of music that is uploaded
Speaker 12:  to all of the major streaming services every day
Speaker 12:  has increased. And the vast majority of them don't
Speaker 12:  ever get listened to more than once or twice, including by the
Speaker 12:  uploaders mom and dad or grandparents they're just never, ever, ever
Speaker 12:  listened to.
Speaker 4:  So for an aspiring musician, there are a few ways to break through the noise.
Speaker 4:  You land on a great Spotify playlist, or you ride the algorithms
Speaker 4:  onto a streamer's radio station, but the golden ticket is going viral
Speaker 4:  on TikTok, which happens constantly. Last year,
Speaker 4:  Nigerian artist CK became a global phenomenon when his single
Speaker 4:  loved one TD, which had been released a year prior blew
Speaker 4:  up on the app.
Speaker 4:  It has since been certified platinum in August,
Speaker 4:  Scottish singer songwriter, Katie Gregson, MLO posted a
Speaker 4:  minute long clip of her song complex, which got
Speaker 4:  7.4 million views and landed her contract with
Speaker 4:  Columbia records.
Speaker 13:  If I need like one, he, on
Speaker 13:  the last line, I cry in his
Speaker 12:  Bathroom. The streaming services, including TikTok are
Speaker 12:  amazing at breaking a track. They're less
Speaker 12:  great at breaking an artist and building a career. And that
Speaker 12:  is what record companies are still really, really good at. Just ask
Speaker 12:  little NAS X, just ask Olivia Rodrigo. And so
Speaker 12:  on the one hand, the opportunity, the potential that still
Speaker 12:  exists in these services and the open distribution policies
Speaker 12:  that they have and the platforms that they utilize are fabulous
Speaker 12:  and have dramatically furthered this theme
Speaker 12:  of the democratization of music, discovery and
Speaker 12:  consumption. That's now, you know, more than a generation
Speaker 12:  along, you know, there's a big difference between having a
Speaker 12:  moment and having a sustainable career or actually being
Speaker 12:  the biggest artist in the world
Speaker 4:  For Erica Leman, a singer songwriter based in Rochester, New York,
Speaker 4:  who goes by boy junior social has definitely opened doors.
Speaker 14:  I think most of the things that have come my way have just been, because
Speaker 14:  I'm like putting myself out there and just like having my weird little ideas
Speaker 14:  and being a weirdo online with
Speaker 4:  Spoofs of indie rock culture and remixes of beloved songs, like a
Speaker 4:  hyper pop version of Mr. Brightside,
Speaker 4:  she has over 300,000 followers on TikTok. That's helped
Speaker 4:  drive ticket sales to her live shows and garner over 2
Speaker 4:  million streams on
Speaker 4:  Spotify. She's gotten sponsorship deals with companies like fender and extra
Speaker 4:  debit cards.
Speaker 14:  And there were people who were like, yeah, I saw you in an ad. So I discovered
Speaker 14:  your music that way. And now I'm here at your show. And I was like, wow,
Speaker 4:  Loveman's not a star yet, but she's making a living as an indie artist,
Speaker 4:  which may not have been possible without the exposure she gets through social
Speaker 4:  and streaming. But she's also realistic about how fickle the
Speaker 4:  algorithms can be.
Speaker 14:  Sometimes it has a lot of benefits for artists who are not working
Speaker 14:  with a team with a budget for really significant marketing. It can be
Speaker 14:  a great stroke of luck, but it is so easy to become kind
Speaker 14:  of addicted to that kind of luck and the way that people come in
Speaker 14:  with their comments and the way that it's treated when a video gets viral
Speaker 14:  and that people are instantly like, oh my God, how are you not famous?
Speaker 14:  Someone get this person a record deal immediately. You know, you need to
Speaker 14:  be on TV shows, blah, blah, blah. And I'm like, oh, I appreciate those comments
Speaker 14:  a ton, but there's a really good chance. You won't see another video from
Speaker 14:  me for months because your TikTok algorithm is gonna just show you
Speaker 14:  other things. And you're gonna forget about me,
Speaker 4:  The pressure to perform on TikTok bleeds into the songwriting itself.
Speaker 4:  Certain types of lyrics are more likely to go viral than others
Speaker 4:  and artists are keenly aware of that.
Speaker 14:  I think it's very easy to become jaded about that concept as like, oh,
Speaker 14:  if you wanna make something that does numbers, you have to like sell out
Speaker 14:  and just like make songs where you list different
Speaker 14:  personality traits or characteristics so that people will make talks where
Speaker 14:  they put green arrows or red. X's next to it. There are certain
Speaker 14:  things I'm writing now that I know are not gonna
Speaker 14:  be really like talkable. And like that has to be
Speaker 14:  okay. Otherwise I would lose my marbles as an artist.
Speaker 4:  The kind of work Erica puts into her content. In addition to her
Speaker 4:  songwriting is standard. Now it's not enough to just make the music
Speaker 4:  anymore.
Speaker 6:  I think you need to be a multihyphenate in today's ecosystem. Do that because
Speaker 6:  you're competing with people who are multihyphenate and multis skew. And
Speaker 6:  if that's the reality of what it takes to be an artist today, yes, there'll
Speaker 6:  always be those artists that are evergreen artists that can break through
Speaker 6:  because they already built that before this whole world has changed.
Speaker 6:  You have artists that are gonna come up that might have a moment of morality
Speaker 6:  where a song breaks through a video breaks through it's a
Speaker 6:  meme. It's something that cuts through, but then it's the capacity that you
Speaker 6:  have to take that advantage of that to take that and turn it into something
Speaker 6:  else.
Speaker 4:  So for an aspiring artist, what is more daunting impressing
Speaker 4:  the gatekeepers of old label executives influenced by their own
Speaker 4:  whims and prejudices or the bottomless unfeeling
Speaker 4:  algorithms of the celestial jukebox, which can make you a sensation
Speaker 4:  for one day, just to forget you the next. I'm not sure
Speaker 4:  I have the answer to that, but even if I have trouble making sense of
Speaker 4:  the kind of stardom that emerges from this new landscape, these hybrid
Speaker 4:  influencer artists, there is some 19 year old out there who
Speaker 4:  will look back as fondly on the TikTok era of music. As I do the
Speaker 4:  MySpace era, less fleet foxes, more boy junior.
Speaker 4:  This episode was produced by Liam, James, Andrew Marino
Speaker 4:  and me Ariel Shapiro Nori Donovan is our executive
Speaker 4:  producer and Brook mins is our editorial director of audio.
Speaker 4:  The Vergecast is a verge production and part of the Vox media podcast
Speaker 4:  network. We'll be back with another episode of the future of music.
Speaker 4:  Next Monday