# Transcript
ID: e3a49780-5c05-11ed-b22b-1542d2f77f41
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Elon Musk's first week at Twitter / Matter's newest smart home devices
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/5857140905326614433/3258575261872088942/s93290-US-5406s-1667541481.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, David Pierce, Alex Cranz, and Alex Heath discuss what has happened with Twitter since Elon Musk has taken over the company.
Then, Nilay, David and Alex discuss the first Matter-compatible devices since the launch of the smart home standard.
Speaker 1:  Today on the Verge cast, Alex Heath joins us to break down all the drama
Speaker 1:  going on at Twitter. This week, Amazon Prime Music releases a new plan
Speaker 1:  that surprises, but mostly annoys existing users. And of course, we'll get
Speaker 1:  into all the Gadget news from this week that's coming up right after this.
Speaker 2:  Hello
Speaker 5:  And welcome to vercast, the flagship podcast of Free Speech
Speaker 5:  and Weed with exceptions, both things.
Speaker 5:  All right, so we have a weed update, a studio weed update. Alex and
Speaker 5:  I are in the studio today. I friend El Eli. Alex Kranz is here. Hello. David
Speaker 5:  Pierce is here.
Speaker 6:  Hi
Speaker 5:  Alex Heath is joining us for the first segment to talk about obviously Elon
Speaker 5:  Musk. Hi Alex. Hi. All right. Before we, but we have a, we a studio. We
Speaker 5:  update much
Speaker 7:  More important update than Elon.
Speaker 5:  Okay. We have, I don't know that we've ruled out Kara Swer is the weed in
Speaker 5:  the studio culprit? I want, we've
Speaker 6:  Ruled out that Elon Musk is the weed in the studio Like
Speaker 5:  Is that, I mean, he
Speaker 6:  Could be. It seems possible.
Speaker 5:  It's very possible. Where in his head, I'll tell you that much
Speaker 5:  we, So I'm not saying it's conclusively not Kara. Yeah, but I will say that
Speaker 5:  we walked in today, Kara has not been in the studios. I don't even know if
Speaker 5:  Kara's in the studio last time, but I know I've been in the office all day.
Speaker 5:  I've not seen her. Yeah, I think she lives in DC so she's not here.
Speaker 5:  Not here often. Kay. Still open. Yeah. Still a suspect of interest,
Speaker 7:  Right? We haven't ruled
Speaker 5:  Her out, but it smells like weed again. It
Speaker 7:  Does Smells a lot like wheat. Having a
Speaker 5:  Great time. And today we are informed that we share an air duct with another
Speaker 5:  team at the company. I will not say who the team is. I think the
Speaker 5:  listener should try to guess.
Speaker 7:  Please send
Speaker 5:  Us once you guess. Yeah. It is very obvious it
Speaker 5:  will land. It will click which group and
Speaker 5:  not even accusing. We don't know for sure.
Speaker 7:  We don't know. It could be Recode. It's,
Speaker 5:  Yeah, just think about it. What, what it's,
Speaker 6:  It's the Packer's blog. They're dealing with a lot right now.
Speaker 8:  Be even alone.
Speaker 5:  That's just more of a boo situation. That's a brown liquor problem.
Speaker 5:  That's not a weed problem. All right. There's a lot going on in the world,
Speaker 5:  Elon. It's his first week at Twitter. It has been
Speaker 5:  absolutely chaotic. On the other happier side of tech news,
Speaker 5:  it's matters launch day. Speaking of weed matter, the smart Home standard
Speaker 5:  is launching currently in Amsterdam. Our own times, their place,
Speaker 5:  they are just turning lights on and off, just stoned outta their
Speaker 5:  mind to all corners of the earth. Jen Tooey and Thomas Ricker are actually,
Speaker 5:  Thomas lives in Amsterdam. Jen flew over there. We got lots of news. The
Speaker 5:  matter event we should talk about. It's pretty exciting. I, we got a bunch
Speaker 5:  of ga talk about, Let's start though with Elon speaking of Brown
Speaker 5:  Liquor. Let's start with Elon. Take a shot, Alex. It's been his first
Speaker 5:  week. It's been chaotic. You kind of blew up the world over the weekend
Speaker 5:  by reporting that Twitter blue would cost $20. Our friend Casey New had reported
Speaker 5:  it would cost four and then it landed at eight. It sounds like
Speaker 5:  layoffs are happening maybe as soon as tomorrow for half the workforce. What's
Speaker 5:  the latest?
Speaker 9:  Yeah. So layoffs will most likely have started by the time
Speaker 9:  this podcast drops. If not, I would expect soon after.
Speaker 9:  Yeah, it's been, to sum it up, you know, just chaotic inside Twitter, I
Speaker 9:  would say the current vibe is perfectly encapsulated by the fact that Elon
Speaker 9:  Musk has almost 90 direct reports inside Twitter's internal
Speaker 9:  directory. Which, you know, I think
Speaker 9:  speaks to just the fact that he's fired everyone that would be below him.
Speaker 9:  That's super funny. Kept them. Yeah, you know, the, it started
Speaker 9:  with me having to Google Lima on Friday, which
Speaker 9:  was very unfortunate. Don't recommend that. And then
Speaker 9:  throughout the weekend it became apparent that Musk's first
Speaker 9:  big project was going to be rehauling verification on Twitter.
Speaker 9:  And I'd heard that he was making people stay in the office over the weekend
Speaker 9:  to get a demo together to show him of this new idea. And
Speaker 9:  I, I really do think that the price, the team building the
Speaker 9:  feature found out that the final price was gonna be $8
Speaker 9:  by him tweeting it to Stephen King. I don't like that's
Speaker 9:  Well, so yeah, I think Stephen King props to
Speaker 9:  my guys for pointing this out, who also testified in the
Speaker 9:  big, that was at the Simon and Schuster merger trial.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, Penguin Random
Speaker 9:  House. Yeah, Penguin Random House. You know, Stephen King said, you know,
Speaker 9:  basically fuck this. Like I'm not gonna pay $20. After we reported that Twitter
Speaker 9:  was planning on making it $20. And then Elon responded and was like, How
Speaker 9:  about eight? And then the next day said eight. So Stephen
Speaker 9:  King had a product at Twitter. Congrats. Yeah.
Speaker 9:  Wonderful. It's, it's actually, it's just remarkable. Like people, employees
Speaker 9:  are literally just looking to Musk's Twitter account to see what their next
Speaker 9:  directive is gonna be and how their product is actually gonna work, which
Speaker 9:  is, is just an amazing time we live in. Meanwhile, they're all sprinting
Speaker 9:  to get this new Twitter blue subscription product out the door by
Speaker 9:  this coming Monday, November 7th, or else they're all going
Speaker 9:  to be fired and they all may be fired or half them fired
Speaker 9:  anyway by Saturday or Friday when this comes out, since he's about to cut
Speaker 9:  estimate it around half of the company, almost 4,000 people on Friday. So
Speaker 9:  yeah, that's the lay of the land.
Speaker 7:  Is this push to, to get it all like Twitter, blue, completely
Speaker 7:  redone by the seventh. Is this like, is the intent to make
Speaker 7:  people so miserable they quit so he doesn't have to lay them off? Is
Speaker 7:  the intent to make them fail so that he can be like, that's why
Speaker 7:  you're fired. Like is that kind of the calculus there before the layoffs?
Speaker 9:  You know, Alex, only Elon can see the mind of Elon.
Speaker 7:  Has he tweeted anything on the on the Well,
Speaker 5:  No, if you're, if you're just like a Twitter engineer, you got like an engineering
Speaker 5:  brain. Yeah. Just a little game theory. Yeah. There's, you cannot be
Speaker 5:  miserable enough to quit at this moment in time. There's no amount of misery
Speaker 5:  that would make you walk away from a severance that is coming if you
Speaker 9:  Get, Yeah, I mean this is already, this is already super sadistic, this whole
Speaker 9:  process. I think it's more to send a message, right? Like I reported that
Speaker 9:  literally the first day he took over, he was like redirect, logged out,
Speaker 9:  homepage to explore and had that pushed through the code freeze. It's just
Speaker 9:  kind of like a, I'm here and we're gonna start changing things that we
Speaker 9:  thought we would never change. Right? That was a hugely political thing before,
Speaker 9:  Talked about it in a story of the weekend. Anyway. And I think
Speaker 9:  the same thing with Blue. It's more to just show A, we can do stuff
Speaker 9:  fast if we're forced to like on point,
Speaker 9:  and B, I'm showing you where my priorities lie. So this is the big
Speaker 9:  project that everyone's working on. The, the lead PM of this literally tweeted
Speaker 9:  that she was sleeping on the floor in the conference room the other day.
Speaker 9:  Hashtags sleep where you work. And so I, I think it's just to
Speaker 9:  say this is a new company. I mean, Twitter is a company that has had a monthly
Speaker 9:  day of rest for the last two years, which Musk also
Speaker 9:  got rid of. Aww. And it is just like the opposite
Speaker 9:  of a musk company. Like this is the most dramatic cultural
Speaker 9:  reset of a company that I've ever witnessed. And it's happening in real
Speaker 9:  time and less than a week. And that's probably also why he
Speaker 9:  fired the entire executive team is he's just saying like, We're not, we're
Speaker 9:  changing things.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. That to me is really one of the more sort of
Speaker 6:  instructive parts of all this is, this is also in keeping with how Elon Musk
Speaker 6:  does business. Like any of the people who have come over to Twitter from
Speaker 6:  Tesla, I guarantee you this is not phasing them. This
Speaker 6:  is just how it works. He says in insane things that are probably impossible,
Speaker 6:  pushes everybody like crazy to make it work. And if it doesn't, there's hell
Speaker 6:  to pay and or he just tweets a new crazy thing and then everybody chases
Speaker 6:  that. This is just like, this is the price of doing business with Elon Musk.
Speaker 6:  And it, it's in a strange way. Like part of it is, it's incredible
Speaker 6:  how quickly he has pulled this off. Like the sheer force of personality to
Speaker 6:  just roll into the building and be like, What's up? Everything is different.
Speaker 6:  Ready Go is like, yeah, deeply messed up. But also in a certain way, like
Speaker 6:  kind of impressive.
Speaker 9:  I will say that I've had several Twitter employees compare this to
Speaker 9:  like the Trump White House and the, the transition team there.
Speaker 9:  And I think that's a very apt analogy. I mean, the guy
Speaker 9:  that Musk is leaning on to help him come up with the layoff plan, his last
Speaker 9:  name is Sax. I mean, you couldn't write this as a Hollywood
Speaker 9:  script any better. And to what David was saying before, there
Speaker 9:  are dozens of people from Tesla, the boring company,
Speaker 9:  Neural link, including Musk's own cousin, other aides,
Speaker 9:  other advisors, VCs in the building
Speaker 9:  that, you know, are helping Musk do all this. And that's been very jarring
Speaker 9:  for Twitter employees too, is to be like, Wait, my fate is gonna be dictated
Speaker 9:  by the all in podcast.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So there's two things there. One, just to, to
Speaker 5:  David's point. How many times have we seen a company get a new ceo?
Speaker 5:  How many times have we talked to new leadership at companies? Even
Speaker 5:  when we have done new things, like what's the first thing happens? Like the
Speaker 5:  leader is like, I need to listen to everybody. Everyone needs to feel hurt.
Speaker 5:  I just need to go make everyone comfortable. And then we'll start doing changes.
Speaker 5:  Like, and then we'll destroy you. I, I swear to God, there's a new CEO
Speaker 5:  playbook that's like the first, here's what you first month, you just tell
Speaker 5:  everyone you're listening. Even if you're not. Yeah. You just say loudly.
Speaker 5:  Like, first I need to listen to everyone. Yeah. It's literally called the
Speaker 5:  listening tour. You do the listening tour, it's what you do. You're like,
Speaker 5:  walk around, you're like, I'm listening to you. And in the back of every
Speaker 5:  CEO's head it's like, to see if I'll fire you, but you do it.
Speaker 5:  There's no listening at Elon. Right? Like he, he's been paying
Speaker 5:  attention. He's addicted to Twitter. The thing I keep saying is like, it's
Speaker 5:  like someone addicted to cigarettes was given a cigarette factory and
Speaker 5:  they don't realize that no one else is addicted to cigarettes the way that
Speaker 5:  they are addicted to cigarettes. And they're like, I have, I've been having
Speaker 5:  thoughts about cigarettes for a long time and we're gonna
Speaker 5:  do them all right, all of them this week. It's just something
Speaker 5:  that's hilarious. And then the, the second part of that is this like kitchen
Speaker 5:  cabinet of his, which is mostly comprised
Speaker 5:  of investors, not people who do things. And yes,
Speaker 5:  we know there's a bunch of engineers and people from his other companies,
Speaker 5:  but the public face of the decisions is a bunch of
Speaker 5:  finance people. Yeah. And it's just very, it, it's like
Speaker 5:  someone finally allowed them to play with the Legos and
Speaker 5:  they're like, Alright, here's what you do. You make a huge tower
Speaker 5:  with a skinny bass. I've been thinking about these Legos for a long time
Speaker 5:  and they have no idea what they're doing because they're just
Speaker 5:  the money. Yeah. And that to me is like the funniest part of this whole
Speaker 5:  thing is all these VCs are like, we need a team, we need a product,
Speaker 5:  we need founders, we need people who know the product. And they
Speaker 5:  themselves are not taking their own cliche advice.
Speaker 9:  Money is important because Musk has a, I think he's on the hook
Speaker 9:  for about a billion a year in interest payments alone on this Twitter deal.
Speaker 9:  And interestingly, the rumor I keep hearing is that internally there's a
Speaker 9:  push to cost save about a billion a year in opex between
Speaker 9:  all the cuts that are about to come. And they're, they're scrutinizing
Speaker 9:  every vendor contract their cloud spend everything to cut
Speaker 9:  costs. So yeah, it is like a, it is a thing of
Speaker 9:  financial engineering that is the Twitter problem on day one. And
Speaker 9:  then the product stuff will happen and he wants to obviously move quickly
Speaker 9:  on the product stuff, but he's gotta first make it work financially.
Speaker 5:  So $8 a month, there's currently, there's what, 400,000
Speaker 5:  verified users. So we can tell that number comes from
Speaker 5:  the number of people that the at verified account follows. I'm Twitter,
Speaker 9:  Which is, which is automatic and is everyone who's verified. I've confirmed
Speaker 9:  that. Okay. I think I, I have a, So I'm really, I want to know what you guys
Speaker 9:  think about this verification thing and if everyone's gonna pay. I mean,
Speaker 9:  of course we are, but like
Speaker 5:  I will, if you, That's the cigarette factory talk. You don't have
Speaker 5:  to smoke cigarettes, Alex, you don't have to do it.
Speaker 7:  You can quit, get a patch.
Speaker 9:  I, I get all of the blow back to this and you know, when I published the
Speaker 9:  first, you know, that they were contemplating 20, it just was like people
Speaker 9:  freaked out. Blue check Twitter went on red mode.
Speaker 9:  I, I think people are underestimating the incentives to,
Speaker 9:  to buy into this because it's not just that you have a check mark. The way
Speaker 9:  that Twitter verification has worked, and I don't think people get this,
Speaker 9:  is that if you're verified, you're actually, it's, it's a quality signal
Speaker 9:  in Twitter's algorithms. So you're boosted more in the timeline. You're boosted
Speaker 9:  in replies. There's that verified filter that we have if we're check mark
Speaker 9:  where we can see verified responses and the next update, that verified tab
Speaker 9:  is gonna become the first tab in the notifications tray. So basically he's
Speaker 9:  gonna just bifurcate the audience. Yeah. And I think people are gonna be
Speaker 9:  so pressured to pay for this because they're gonna realize that, oh, I am
Speaker 9:  in the cheap seats all of a sudden. Not just in terms of like what I'm paying,
Speaker 9:  but in terms of my reach and in terms of like my, my quality of like
Speaker 9:  what I can see. And so I think that's why a lot of people, because it's also
Speaker 9:  a network effect thing will buy into this. And I actually, I actually think
Speaker 9:  this will be like something that millions of people do.
Speaker 7:  I think it's the exact opposite. I think the blue check mark is
Speaker 7:  about to be the mark that you're a weirdo who
Speaker 7:  uses Twitter so much, you're willing to pay $8 a month for it. And I
Speaker 7:  think it's gonna be a point like where people say, Oh, you have a blue check.
Speaker 7:  Ew, you really pay for this. And maybe that
Speaker 7:  won't happen. But I genuinely think that this is gonna be like a big moment
Speaker 7:  for this company and for social media and all right, like social media that
Speaker 7:  generally the thing is we are going to mind the crap out of your data
Speaker 7:  and in return you get all of this free access to communicate with other people.
Speaker 7:  And now he's saying, we are going to mine the crap out of your data. And
Speaker 7:  if you want a better experience, you have to pay $8 a month. And if you don't
Speaker 7:  want like that, you can use the shitty version or you can walk. And I'm like,
Speaker 7:  are people really going to pay that $8 many for people
Speaker 7:  who already say they hate the site and they use it anyway? Are those people
Speaker 7:  really gonna be like, Yeah, buy this pack of cigarettes, or are they gonna
Speaker 7:  be like, Actually
Speaker 5:  I'm very happy that I'm,
Speaker 7:  I can go get the filter list, enroll myself. Oh my god, I
Speaker 7:  that's maed on, I assume
Speaker 5:  That's Texas coming through is
Speaker 7:  I saw someone this week who was like, Yeah, I rolled my own cigarettes and
Speaker 7:  I'm like in 2022.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Well did you meet someone else who smoked cloves?
Speaker 5:  Like let's get into it.
Speaker 7:  Tumblr is cloves in this situation, by the way.
Speaker 5:  Okay. So I, my prediction is that the reality of this is gonna be far more
Speaker 5:  boring and it's gonna mean nothing. And the, the
Speaker 5:  best comp is TSA pre-check, which is neither a status
Speaker 5:  symbol nor a thing that people love. It's just what you do if you
Speaker 5:  just want to be degraded slightly more by the government of the United States,
Speaker 5:  Right? Like you can have a better experience if you pay for it. This much
Speaker 7:  Shoes on.
Speaker 5:  It's not clear. You don't, the seat doesn't lay back all the way.
Speaker 5:  You just get to keep your shoes on and that that, like,
Speaker 5:  I already pay for Twitter. I I'm already paying for it paying it's $4 a month.
Speaker 5:  They're doubling the price to add a check mark and take away the ad free
Speaker 5:  experience on some publisher websites.
Speaker 6:  No, but but the thing is, nobody who follows you on Twitter knows that you
Speaker 6:  pay for Twitter. Sure. Which I think is, is really important. Right? Where
Speaker 6:  like, think about all the people you see in your timeline.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And when you're in the pre-check line, everyone knows that you pay
Speaker 5:  for pre-check. It doesn't mean anyone thinks you're cool. They're just like,
Speaker 5:  Wow, you pay for
Speaker 6:  Pre, you're not thirsting for retweets in the pre-check line. Like I don't
Speaker 6:  think that analogy works at all if I'm being honest. It's like
Speaker 6:  they're, if you're like, if there's like a thirst trap camera when you get
Speaker 6:  in the TSA pre-check line, like then I'd be into it absolutely.
Speaker 5:  Gonna start doing thirst traps in the pre-check
Speaker 7:  Line. I think it's more like when you play a video game
Speaker 7:  and, and you get like a cool little like World Warcraft, you get a cool little
Speaker 7:  pet, right? And if you go and you do all these really cool events, you get
Speaker 7:  a cool pet. And so people would be like, this is my pet. And that was like
Speaker 7:  the blue check mark. And then other people would be like, I spent $5
Speaker 7:  at Subway and I also have a cool pet. And you'd see
Speaker 7:  those pets and you'd be like, Well you're lame because you spent $5 at Subway
Speaker 7:  for that pet. I
Speaker 5:  Mean I feel like if Elon was gonna be wild, he would introduce tiered pricing.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. There gold
Speaker 7:  Checkbooks. Oh my God, that's what I want
Speaker 5:  Checkmarks.
Speaker 7:  And like just go all
Speaker 9:  The way that could happen. That could happen. I mean I think we're
Speaker 9:  undervaluing the algorithmic boosting aspect of this. And we're also
Speaker 9:  vowing a unique aspect of Twitter's a social network, which is that a very,
Speaker 9:  very small percent of the user base produces the vast majority
Speaker 9:  of the content. And if you fall into that bucket, which is all of us, everyone
Speaker 9:  in media, celebrities, the Scott Galloways of the world, et cetera, you
Speaker 9:  are absolutely going to pay for this because otherwise your reach is gonna
Speaker 9:  be on day one reduced. So it's not even that you're in a separate
Speaker 9:  line, it's that you're in another line where you keep getting pushed to the
Speaker 9:  back of the line, the regular line, two steps forward.
Speaker 5:  I dunno if you've ever been to the airport before of
Speaker 6:  Well
Speaker 9:  At least you move forward in that line. I have precheck. I'm just
Speaker 9:  saying like I have precheck and I I see your analogy, but it's almost like
Speaker 9:  if you're in the other line, you just keep getting pushed back. It's not
Speaker 9:  even that you're in another line. So I, I do think the people who produce
Speaker 9:  the most content on Twitter will pay for this.
Speaker 6:  The but the, the part of this that makes me agree with Kranz is I I would
Speaker 6:  be more inclined to pay if it were divorced from the blue check.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Because now what the blue check becomes, there's a certain world in
Speaker 6:  which the blue check becomes like a symbol of your thirstiness that says
Speaker 6:  not only do I care about Twitter, I care so much about you reading
Speaker 6:  my sick ass tweets that I'm gonna pay money to get in front of you.
Speaker 7:  Like that's exactly what it becomes.
Speaker 6:  All the people who made fun of Ben Smith for his like ridiculous promoted
Speaker 6:  tweets promoting SE four, like this is now that at scale
Speaker 6:  it's, it's you promoting your own tweets and that's, that's what it's gonna
Speaker 6:  look like.
Speaker 9:  Yeah, sure. But like this is what verification at Twitter was originally
Speaker 9:  designed to be like what Musk is doing is actually how Twitter has always
Speaker 9:  wanted verification to work. Which is that it's actually just to say you
Speaker 9:  are who you say you are and now it's linked to a credit card. So
Speaker 9:  obviously people can fake that it's, and that will happen. It's not But I'm
Speaker 9:  just saying like this is what that I mean Yes. That is what it is. It's,
Speaker 9:  we
Speaker 7:  Have an identity layer. No, it's not because it is now requiring, like I,
Speaker 7:  I know I saw one guy who's like a journalist in Africa and he was saying,
Speaker 7:  I need this because I am regularly arrested for my tweets. I'm regularly
Speaker 7:  like stalked for this stuff. I can't afford the $8 a month
Speaker 7:  or whatever it's gonna be in my country. So now I'm screwed.
Speaker 7:  And like those people are still going to be affected by this
Speaker 7:  and Oh yeah. Are they gonna, I don't think they're going to, but I think
Speaker 7:  like, I think like this is not just pay to be verified,
Speaker 7:  this is pay to be verified, get all of this stuff and pay for everybody in
Speaker 7:  the world to know that you pay for this. And I think that's really
Speaker 7:  silly. Like I want that check to go away as
Speaker 7:  soon as possible. I don't want a single person to think that I pay for twitter.com.
Speaker 9:  No one has invented a way to actually identify users on social media
Speaker 9:  at scale in a way that works yet. And I think credit card linking to accounts
Speaker 9:  is the best thing that we, that anyone could do in the given like right
Speaker 9:  now. Yeah. I'm sure something will be invented that's better than that. And
Speaker 9:  I hear you on the paid thing. I'm, I've heard that blue is so rushed that
Speaker 9:  it's only gonna be in English and only in like a few markets when it comes
Speaker 9:  out, which is a huge fail, right? Yeah. That's a huge fail for the
Speaker 9:  kind of people that you just talked about. And hopefully over time must lets
Speaker 9:  journalists and people who work at nonprofits and activists be able to have
Speaker 9:  it for free. I think that would be a good thing. I'm sure they're considering
Speaker 9:  it. I'm just saying as an identity layer that is actually what
Speaker 9:  verification was supposed to be. Twitter has just been so inept at actually
Speaker 9:  enforcing this over the last decade that it's become this like
Speaker 9:  elite class. Like you have to have a social media manager contact at
Speaker 9:  Twitter to be able to get it thing That was never what it was intended
Speaker 9:  to be. So it's actually returning verification to what it originally was
Speaker 9:  supposed to be, which is just, I am who I say I am,
Speaker 7:  But like in the worst way possible. Sure. Under the musk, which
Speaker 7:  is Yeah. Like it's a terrible way to do it. Well
Speaker 5:  So I just wanna be very clear about one thing, criticism of
Speaker 5:  the Musk administration of Twitter is in no way the
Speaker 5:  same as praise for any other previous management of Twitter.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. Yeah. I'm so glad you said that.
Speaker 5:  Deeply mismanaged company for a decade or more,
Speaker 7:  Right? Terribly managed.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. You can hold two things as truth. You cannot like the way Musk is doing
Speaker 9:  things. And you can also acknowledge that Twitter has been a spectacularly
Speaker 9:  mismanaged company and everyone at the company will privately acknowledge
Speaker 9:  that.
Speaker 7:  Yep. Like it's wild that it's taken this long to figure out the
Speaker 7:  verification thing for years. Everybody's like, how do we do it? And it's
Speaker 7:  like, I mean
Speaker 9:  They put the program on pause for years where they were just like, Screw
Speaker 9:  it, we're not gonna verify anyone else cuz this is such a mess and we don't
Speaker 9:  even know how to like implement this at scale. And then they would still
Speaker 9:  sneak people in. Like if a Twitter employee had a contact and everyone would
Speaker 9:  get mad. I mean it's a, it's a disaster.
Speaker 5:  So here's a question. I don't pay enough attention, but I think I know the
Speaker 5:  answer. No one's mad at the blue checks on Instagram. Right? Right.
Speaker 5:  No one's mad at the, they're at Twitter. Like YouTube has effectively
Speaker 5:  blue checks. No one's mad at them. Right. No one's mad at the blue checks
Speaker 5:  on TikTok. Right. It's just Twitter.
Speaker 9:  Right. Cause we're all deeply insecure cynics on Twitter.
Speaker 7:  I think it's more because Twitter had like, I think we wanna be
Speaker 7:  cautious and remember that a lot of this blue checks like anger
Speaker 7:  came from right wing people who were upset that Trump was being de platformed
Speaker 7:  and felt that he was, he and other right wing commentators were being
Speaker 7:  de platformed at the like to prop up the blue
Speaker 7:  checks and that these other people should be up there. But the reason they
Speaker 7:  were deed was because they were sharing misinformation and saying like
Speaker 7:  they were instructions. Yeah. Like that's the big, like
Speaker 7:  that's the big part of this that's like an undercurrent of this entire thing
Speaker 7:  that I think a lot of people are really mindful of and they, they
Speaker 7:  know that like the blue check discourse always came from this
Speaker 7:  really
Speaker 5:  The mainstream media. Yeah. In a
Speaker 9:  Way. Cause that's what it literally has been. So if you actually see, excuse
Speaker 5:  Me, we are the Renegade Media sermon. Well we're, this podcast exists on
Speaker 5:  a fringe, not fringes of American democracy. That's
Speaker 9:  Right. You
Speaker 5:  Can't silence us and if you try, we'll come for you
Speaker 5:  somehow if but with weed. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Laser bg.
Speaker 9:  I'm just saying like, Alex, if you, I I agree with you that that's how
Speaker 9:  obviously how check marks have been viewed. If, if it becomes something that
Speaker 9:  isn't regulated to a certain class by proxy of who you know, but something
Speaker 9:  literally anyone can just pay for, is that not actually a good thing for
Speaker 9:  what the check mark represents long-term?
Speaker 7:  I think that's good. I think like making it accessible and
Speaker 7:  more understandable and comprehensible is great. I think tying that to money
Speaker 7:  and is, is dumb. I think you can have
Speaker 7:  Twitter, blue, great service, you wanna pay for that. Great verification
Speaker 7:  should be independent of that because verification should never be
Speaker 7:  about whether or not you're paying for the service.
Speaker 5:  So what you're, you, I think there's a little bit of a heat, a heated agreement
Speaker 5:  going on. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Right. We're furiously agreeing with each other about
Speaker 5:  Two, like two different things. Alex said there's two Alexs
Speaker 7:  You gotta go crayons and Heath.
Speaker 5:  God dammit. Okay. Heath said verification is a, is a
Speaker 5:  quality signal for Twitter. Yeah. That's the important part. I think this
Speaker 5:  is the thing that maybe Elon and David Sachs and David, Jason Calcan, all
Speaker 5:  these people are working on like get, they're lost in the poison of the the
Speaker 5:  blue check mind, right? Yeah. Which is, it's good for the Twitter
Speaker 5:  community to know that LeBron James is LeBron James
Speaker 5:  on Twitter. Right? Right. Like that's his account. It's really him. They've
Speaker 5:  done something to verify that it's him and that blue check means it's him
Speaker 5:  and not a fraud. Right. And across the Twitter ecosystem that is good.
Speaker 5:  Yes. You know that wonderful presidents the president, you know the White
Speaker 5:  House is the White House, You know that Chuck Todd is Chuck Todd. I was just
Speaker 5:  on Chuck Todd podcast. So that's, he's on my mind. Hey Chuck, that
Speaker 5:  you shouldn't charge the people for that. That's a value you are providing
Speaker 5:  to the end user of Twitter. Right. To say these people are who they say they
Speaker 5:  are. You can trust this information. Yes. Adding capitalism
Speaker 5:  to that does not necessarily accomplish that goal. Correct.
Speaker 5:  In a way that you need that goal to be accomplished. And he's already said
Speaker 5:  we're gonna start giving politicians and other quote public figures an additional
Speaker 5:  label that they already have to serve that purpose.
Speaker 7:  A blue check maybe it'll
Speaker 5:  Be pink. That's a check plus. Yeah. Right. And I think they just, that's
Speaker 5:  a gold check. They just like hate the media and they're like, the media should
Speaker 5:  pay us. The flip side of that is, as he pointed out,
Speaker 5:  we make all the content on Twitter, like the people not, we
Speaker 5:  immediately, like the people, the users of Twitter make all the stuff. And
Speaker 5:  I cannot think of another social platform that charges
Speaker 5:  its users to have good experiences in that way. Like
Speaker 5:  yeah, YouTube is not out there being like, Hey Mark, he brownley,
Speaker 5:  would you like to pay us a little bit more money to have a not garbage experience
Speaker 5:  on YouTube? They're much more like, Hey, we found additional ways
Speaker 5:  for you to make money tick. Like YouTube shorts now
Speaker 5:  has an ad split that is more lucrative for you than TikTok
Speaker 5:  cuz we need to keep you here and not have you go to TikTok, which
Speaker 5:  only as a creator fund. Right. And TikTok immediately responded to that by
Speaker 5:  saying, we're gonna roll out better monetization than this creator fund because
Speaker 5:  that is the competition that you need for users. You need to pay them more
Speaker 5:  money. Yeah. You need to pay your creators more money. Elon has said that
Speaker 5:  this $8 a month fee will somehow create a fund to pay creators.
Speaker 5:  The math on it is bad. It's,
Speaker 5:  it's horrible. At $8 a month you get all 400,000 people, which you won't
Speaker 5:  get. But assuming you get all 400 those people, it's like what? 35, 30
Speaker 5:  2 million a year? It's nothing.
Speaker 9:  I think it's gonna be dramatically more than the current 400,000 that opt
Speaker 9:  into this because of the network effects of people realizing that they're
Speaker 9:  getting gated in, in the algorithm because of, and
Speaker 9:  because of like a simple thing like default tab placement matters
Speaker 9:  a lot in these experiences and the verified notifications
Speaker 9:  experience is literally gonna be first when you open notifications on Twitter.
Speaker 9:  Why
Speaker 5:  Do you
Speaker 7:  Think they're gonna do that and not just leave the platform for one that
Speaker 7:  doesn't charge them $8? Where
Speaker 9:  Are they gonna go? I mean I've always like, I mean everyone's always writing
Speaker 9:  and saying like when a platform goes through a moment like this, oh people
Speaker 9:  are gonna go. And right now it's masked on whatever these network effects
Speaker 9:  are really hard to rebuild. Twitter's had over a decade of this
Speaker 9:  and I just don't see the, the current creator class of Twitter,
Speaker 9:  which is that, you know,
Speaker 7:  I mean we saw it with Tumblr. Like Tumblr I think is our best exam. I know
Speaker 7:  I bring it up a lot, but it is our best example here. They said we're gonna
Speaker 7:  get rid of boobies. I mean they really said we're gonna get rid of nudity.
Speaker 7:  We don't want any nudity on the website. And that included,
Speaker 5:  Verizon says, no boobs.
Speaker 7:  And that included no female presenting nipples. That was a really
Speaker 7:  big one. That was in like their, their announcement on it and they lost over
Speaker 7:  a third of their people like, like over a third of their audience just said,
Speaker 7:  Okay, I'm out. And some of them went to Twitter and some of 'em went to TikTok
Speaker 7:  and a lot of 'em went to Discord and some of 'em went to Pillow Fort. But
Speaker 7:  they did say, I don't want to be a part of this. And I think
Speaker 7:  we're gonna see that on Twitter too. And maybe those people will go
Speaker 7:  to Mastodon hysterical, maybe they'll go to Tumblr,
Speaker 7:  not likely. But I think they are gonna go and look at other
Speaker 7:  avenues cuz it's like, well why should I stay here and be charged
Speaker 7:  for this experience that oftentimes I hate when I can go to TikTok
Speaker 7:  for free when I can go to Mastodon and have
Speaker 7:  1212 people talk to me. Yeah. But for
Speaker 5:  Free. And then TikTok will happily serve me good tweets of people just
Speaker 5:  on a green screen in front of a good tweet
Speaker 7:  Pointing out and saying, Look, this is good.
Speaker 9:  I hear you Kranz, I don't think there's anything that replaces Twitter for
Speaker 9:  the people who are addicted to it. There's nothing that has the same network
Speaker 9:  effects, the same potential reach that you can have a tweet that can get
Speaker 9:  15 million impressions in three days or
Speaker 9:  2 million because you know, like you just, you can't get that TikTok Yeah.
Speaker 9:  If you like videos, if you can, if you make videos, but for text
Speaker 9:  and for news, there's nothing that can replace Twitter that it currently
Speaker 9:  exists.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I'm, I'm with Heath here and I think the, the reality
Speaker 6:  of Twitter is that Twitter costing $8 will not be in like the 10
Speaker 6:  worst things about Twitter. And like
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And we're all still here, right? Like it's, it's, there was a minute where
Speaker 6:  it was like, you're gonna be able to pay to make it better and now it's,
Speaker 6:  you're gonna be able to pay and not make it worse. And I think that is a
Speaker 6:  really odd way of thinking about the platform, but like,
Speaker 7:  Is that precheck
Speaker 6:  Line think it's gonna
Speaker 5:  Work the precheck line? Look, let's say
Speaker 7:  I love to keep my shoes on.
Speaker 5:  I'm just, again, just the math here is, so the math is so revealing.
Speaker 5:  Let's say they get 10 x the users they have for the
Speaker 5:  current verified products. So 400,000, they gets
Speaker 5:  4 million people decide to pay $8 a month for Twitter.
Speaker 5:  They will make 384 million a year. Twitter makes a billion
Speaker 5:  dollars a quarter. Like
Speaker 9:  Eli, he doesn't care about the economic
Speaker 7:  He has to, Right? Like he has to pay down a billion dollars
Speaker 7:  a year.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. But, but I don't think Blue is about making money. I think it's the
Speaker 9:  identity problem. It's how do we somehow verify the identity
Speaker 9:  of people. And the only way, again I come back to that's people have
Speaker 9:  decided is to do a credit card. And I think there's a plenty of like
Speaker 9:  fair criticism of what happens to people who are trying to anonymously
Speaker 9:  speak out, get information out. A lot of the ways that Twitter really took
Speaker 9:  off, say in the Arab Spring, how does that happen in an environment like
Speaker 9:  this where you need to have, it doesn't, a proven real identity tied to a
Speaker 9:  credit card. It doesn't or it's regulated to that bottom half of the service,
Speaker 9:  Right? That's not getting the same level of reach and it's up to the check
Speaker 9:  marks to go down, find it, bring it up into the checkmarked environment,
Speaker 9:  which is just like futurist and horrible. But I, I, I think
Speaker 9:  I do think there's going to be, you know, at least that identity
Speaker 9:  layer that is not about making money, but is just about
Speaker 9:  making Twitter a place where you know who you're seeing
Speaker 7:  If you pay for it.
Speaker 9:  And I don't think he really cares about it being if you pay for it. And I
Speaker 9:  don't think he cares about it being, I think he thinks advertising is gonna
Speaker 9:  remain the biggest part of the company's revenue even though advertisers
Speaker 9:  certainly.
Speaker 7:  Well let's, let's talk about that. Advertise. Yes. Oh my God,
Speaker 5:  Are we ready for this? Let's talk about the thesis of Welcome to Hell Eli.
Speaker 7:  How's that going for him?
Speaker 5:  So there's a, a good piece in Rolling Stone, that one up. Just be
Speaker 5:  before we started taping like the right wingers are already starting to turn
Speaker 5:  on Elon because he had a meeting with CMOs. He like
Speaker 5:  had an open letter to advertisers, said it's not gonna become a hellscape.
Speaker 5:  He had a meeting with a bunch of civil society groups, promised them that
Speaker 5:  he wouldn't change the rules before they
Speaker 7:  Listening
Speaker 5:  Tour a listening tour. And you know, the, his new right wing
Speaker 5:  fans who are quote unquote, you know, for free speech people, which
Speaker 5:  is really just like the N-word club is here. You know, like
Speaker 5:  they're pissed at him already, you know, and and there's just a variety of
Speaker 5:  figures who are saying we were promised free speech and now you're talking
Speaker 5:  to you know, the Anti-Defamation league and why would you do that? That has
Speaker 5:  nothing to do with free speech. And I think he's caught in this place where
Speaker 5:  Alex, I think you've talked to some advertisers, I have talked to some advertising
Speaker 5:  folks. There's just a lot of skepticism that this
Speaker 5:  will remain a good platform for advertising. And what I mean by that
Speaker 5:  specifically is they don't want to be near bad content.
Speaker 5:  They never have, they care a lot about brand safety.
Speaker 5:  This is why YouTube has apocalypses over the years. Yeah, right. YouTube
Speaker 5:  gets a little outta control, the moderation gets a little haywire, the community
Speaker 5:  goes a little haywire and the advertisers all walk away and this is a cycle
Speaker 5:  that plays out on YouTube kind of over and over again.
Speaker 5:  This is a cycle that's playing out on Twitter kind of for the first time
Speaker 5:  in this way where the advertisers say like the ipg, which is one of the biggest
Speaker 5:  holding companies of ad agencies is saying we recommend that you paused.
Speaker 5:  GM has paused at spend, I think partially a tweak Tesla
Speaker 5:  like maybe more than partially Tesla.
Speaker 7:  Like all those car companies,
Speaker 9:  There's a legitimate concern that he literally has dozens of Tesla employees
Speaker 9:  inside Twitter right now. And why would you, why would I put my brand campaigns
Speaker 9:  and my spending and all that stuff on a platform that you have access to
Speaker 9:  when you run Tesla? I don't think there's gonna be any auto dealers on Twitter
Speaker 9:  for a while.
Speaker 5:  I mean that part's really funny. Tesla has historically never done any marketing.
Speaker 5:  He has no idea how advertising works, right?
Speaker 9:  Yeah. Twitter. Twitter is Tesla's marketing like you Like that's the thing.
Speaker 9:  Like he bought his marketing org right? It's just funny, like
Speaker 5:  That's what it is. He now has a customer, like the marketers
Speaker 5:  are Twitter's customers. That's where your billion dollars a quarter comes
Speaker 5:  from. Yeah. Is ad agencies and CMOs and he
Speaker 5:  is, I think enlisted Jason Cal Canis who started
Speaker 5:  Weblog Zinc and Gadget, like loved Jason, very sincere guy,
Speaker 5:  but he's the face of the advertising organization Now for these marketers
Speaker 5:  that's a lot like he's a new person, they don't trust him and they
Speaker 7:  Don't, doesn't have a title.
Speaker 5:  I don't know if you've seen the text to Elon. They think that he's gonna
Speaker 5:  do what Elon tells him to do. Maybe there's evidence for that
Speaker 5:  and maybe there's not fall in a Jason's one who sent the
Speaker 5:  get your blades out boys text to Elon in regards to sharpen your blades.
Speaker 5:  Right. That's the, that it's just this cast of
Speaker 5:  characters and if you think that marketing is stupid and Tesla doesn't need
Speaker 5:  to do it and you go to the CMO of a GM or the
Speaker 5:  CMO of a Ford and you're like, Give me some money. Yeah. So you can compete
Speaker 5:  on my platform against my own tweets. They're like,
Speaker 5:  Yeah, we don't trust you. And if you go to Proctor and Gamble
Speaker 5:  and they wanna sell Tide or whatever you wanna sell
Speaker 5:  and you're like, and also we've decided to let 10% more
Speaker 5:  racism back on the platform. They're just like, no. Right.
Speaker 5:  And so he's got this poll out that's like should advertisers support free
Speaker 5:  speech or political correctness? And it's like, dude, it's their money.
Speaker 5:  They can pay for whatever they want. That's the free
Speaker 5:  speech.
Speaker 5:  It's just utter like that piece of it, to me it's like such a blind
Speaker 5:  spot for him that he's got customers now.
Speaker 6:  And unlike Twitter's users, those customers have a million places
Speaker 6:  to go. Yeah. Like if, if you want to advertise on social
Speaker 6:  platforms, your options are are limitless. And there are a bunch of
Speaker 6:  companies out there who will very happily take the money that you're taking
Speaker 6:  away from Twitter right now. So I think like all the network, but
Speaker 5:  Facebook would love some incremental ad dollars. They would be very happy
Speaker 5:  to make a little bit more money than they've been making.
Speaker 6:  Snapchat's still a thing. They, they have ads.
Speaker 5:  Definitely what I've heard is that people, you know, the
Speaker 5:  advertiser class thinks Twitter is fun. It's like, it's like the
Speaker 5:  most live environment. Yeah. So if you do the thing, you make the launch,
Speaker 5:  it's where everyone goes to see if any they got any traction but they're
Speaker 5:  like, we don't need it.
Speaker 7:  It's like the smallest part of a lot of these big agencies spend. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  When it comes to social media, this is like at the very bottom of their thing
Speaker 7:  and they're like, oh yeah, okay we'll throw a hundred K to a quick campaign,
Speaker 7:  do some promoted tweets. So I'm really, really curious to
Speaker 7:  see how much this like I'm gonna be focused on, on blue and solving
Speaker 7:  this identity problem is going to at the cost
Speaker 7:  of like, I'm going to make all of these advertisers feel comfortable so I
Speaker 7:  can get their billions of dollars so I can make my billion dollar. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Marketing. Yeah. I just think the idea that Elon has already
Speaker 5:  pissed off some of his most vocal hard
Speaker 5:  right. Ultra-conservative influencer supporters because he has to promise
Speaker 5:  the advertisers and like civil groups Yeah. That he can't change
Speaker 5:  the rules too much is fast. Like he's gotta pull
Speaker 5:  that bandaid right after the midterms and be like, here are the new rules.
Speaker 7:  And I'm really curious also how much, how much of Twitter's
Speaker 7:  ad money was coming from car companies. Because like car companies are
Speaker 7:  a big advertising market, right? Like they spend a lot of money.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. My understanding is the, the top spenders are
Speaker 9:  the streamers or the hbos, the Disneys, the companies that are doing
Speaker 9:  big brand campaigns around stuff
Speaker 5:  Like that.
Speaker 7:  And we saw this week that they're also thinking like they're very conscious
Speaker 7:  of like not Iger, Bob Chape, the new CEO of
Speaker 7:  Disney has been making rounds with all of the, the conservative like
Speaker 7:  senators and congressmen assuming that the midterms is gonna go their
Speaker 7:  way so that he doesn't get hurt and whatever comes next. So that
Speaker 7:  Disney doesn't once again become at the focal point of like what's happening
Speaker 7:  in the world. You guys suck. So it's gonna be really, really interesting
Speaker 7:  to see what happens with that. Plus with Twitter like this, the whole brand
Speaker 7:  safety thing is you're now having two very different concepts of what brand
Speaker 7:  safety does.
Speaker 5:  I do look forward to a conception of freedom of speech in America where the
Speaker 5:  government forces Disney to buy ads on Twitter next to racist content. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Like you can just, there's a bill coming, like Ted Cruz is like, I gotta
Speaker 5:  work this out. That's what's I'm going in the lab. Yeah. Here's my new freedom
Speaker 5:  of speech Bill Disney is required to buy ads on Twitter
Speaker 7:  And it's gonna be like what? What Supreme Court's gonna do it and then
Speaker 7:  we're gonna just have the same conversation in four years.
Speaker 5:  By the way, everyone should read Addie's piece about free speech in two 30.
Speaker 5:  That's our like big midterm story.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, he's great.
Speaker 9:  I I would be curious to hear you guys react to this. So something Elon talked
Speaker 9:  about internally on his, his first week at Twitter is starlink in the
Speaker 9:  potential of using starlink to deliver Twitter to countries where
Speaker 9:  I believe the readout of the meeting was something like they discussed how
Speaker 9:  they would literally need to shoot down satellites and that's the only way
Speaker 9:  that
Speaker 7:  Did he not talk to Zuck who had this exact same plan like
Speaker 7:  six years
Speaker 5:  Ago Zuck had a plane, Google had balloons.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. And I, I just, I'm curious about that and what you guys think about
Speaker 9:  that because obviously Musk is heavily compromised in China.
Speaker 9:  You know, Twitter employees are already wondering, is he gonna build a localized
Speaker 9:  Chinese Twitter that has, you know, he says he is
Speaker 9:  going have free speech but also abide by local laws. What does that look
Speaker 9:  like in a place like China? It looks like Doyon the sister app to
Speaker 9:  it looks very different, but also like starlink, what if he just like
Speaker 9:  starts trying to like beam Twitter to countries
Speaker 9:  that do not have anything near the US Constitution via starlink?
Speaker 5:  I mean he can and he can't, right? I mean right now he
Speaker 5:  won't let starlink do that. Like when you install a starlink receiver in
Speaker 5:  a country that's not supported, it's just GPS is out. Like, and that's why
Speaker 5:  they had to enable it in Ukraine in all these other places. So he's gotta
Speaker 5:  change that decision. I think that decision is hard to change because he
Speaker 5:  needs like SpaceX to be able to be
Speaker 5:  somewhat neutral cuz it flies over every country and then he's
Speaker 5:  gotta ship Teslas everywhere. You're right that he's compromised in China,
Speaker 5:  but he's compromised in China by is that he needs to sell a lot of Teslas
Speaker 5:  there and he makes Teslas there. So if he's beaming Twitter
Speaker 5:  to Chinese consumers using Starling, they're just gonna
Speaker 5:  shut down his Tesla factory the way they,
Speaker 7:  They're just gonna take those Teslas and now there'll be a lot of cool cop
Speaker 7:  cars in China with Tesla logo.
Speaker 7:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  But at the same time, I absolutely believe he will try this like
Speaker 6:  with, with a hundred percent certainty this will be a thing that happens
Speaker 6:  because, because what we're, what we've been watching since this started
Speaker 6:  in April is Elon Musk like speed running the history of social media
Speaker 6:  and and one of the steps along the way is trying to bring your
Speaker 6:  app to other people who can't otherwise get it through weird means of
Speaker 6:  the internet. Like it's just a thing you're required to do. Google tried
Speaker 6:  it, Facebook tried it didn't work, but it's, it's like, it's one of the steps
Speaker 6:  you have to fail on before you get to like building a payments network. And
Speaker 6:  he'll eventually land on like vertical video and turning Twitter into a music
Speaker 6:  app like everybody else does. But like this is the path
Speaker 9:  It's gonna be delivering groceries and
Speaker 6:  That's exactly right.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. Yeah. I mean it's amazing because like Mark
Speaker 9:  Zuckerberg, it took him almost three years to meet with like the
Speaker 9:  ADL and like all of these like activist groups and human rights groups
Speaker 9:  and like Musk did it like two days ago, right? He's like a week into the
Speaker 9:  company and he's already like doing the Zuck like I'm gonna clean this up
Speaker 9:  tour Zuck. By the way, I wish he would've actually answered my question when
Speaker 9:  I asked him for advice for Musk, cuz he would've probably said like,
Speaker 9:  Don't do this,
Speaker 9:  trust me, welcome to hell. Right. But yeah, I
Speaker 9:  I I I think the next shoot a drop is who he actually
Speaker 9:  installs permanently in some of these key roles
Speaker 9:  because all these people we've been talking about, David Sachs, Jason call
Speaker 9:  Canis, they're, they're temporary, they're not gonna be working there fulltime.
Speaker 9:  So who are the people that he either elevates internally, brings in from
Speaker 9:  other companies, et cetera. I think that's the next,
Speaker 6:  Is there any sense of who the like leading candidate for that would be so
Speaker 6:  far? Like who's the, who's the betting favorite? Well,
Speaker 9:  Cavan, the former head of product to Paraag fired in
Speaker 9:  May has been in the building for the last week. So
Speaker 9:  there's rumors he may come back. The optics are really,
Speaker 5:  He tweeted that he's not actively involved. He applied to someone and said,
Speaker 5:  but who knows? Well
Speaker 9:  The optics are rough because if you used to work at Twitter under the former
Speaker 9:  regime and you come in now as Elon has kind of brutally
Speaker 9:  fired the current regime, how does that work with people who have,
Speaker 9:  feel certain ways about that? Right? Like it's just, it's a tough thing to
Speaker 9:  be like a former person and come in That said, there are like 16 former heads
Speaker 9:  of product, so I'm sure one of them is up for the job.
Speaker 9:  The problem is, is you've gotta find someone who, like a, wants to work at
Speaker 9:  a private company that's like Musk's fourth company doesn't wanna work
Speaker 9:  in big tech or wants to leave and also wants to deal with cleaning up
Speaker 9:  and fixing Twitter. It's just, and working for Musk. Like there's a, that's
Speaker 9:  a short list I think
Speaker 7:  Right now I can't imagine he pays like really well for this
Speaker 7:  role either. I, I feel like he's the kind of guy who's like, you know what
Speaker 7:  you're working for Musk.
Speaker 5:  Well, so at Tesla he pays really well cuz he pays in Tesla stock and he
Speaker 5:  doesn't have that anymore.
Speaker 7:  I don't want that Twitter stock.
Speaker 9:  They actually switched to Cash grants recently too for a lot of people
Speaker 9:  because of the economy. They, he started paying out cash awards
Speaker 9:  cashed out. So I do think like, hey, if he's like, hey, I mean he's told
Speaker 9:  investors I know this, that he wants to take Twitter public again in like
Speaker 9:  three to five years. So if that's the pitch, come in, fix this, take it back
Speaker 9:  out with me. You'll have whatever, half a percent of the company when it
Speaker 9:  goes out, we're gonna make it a hundred billion dollar company. I'm Eon Musk,
Speaker 9:  let's go. There may be some people who would bite at that. I think he has
Speaker 9:  a lot of supporters obviously, so I just, I'm not sure who
Speaker 9:  it's gonna be right now. Like I said, he has almost 90 direct reports right
Speaker 9:  now.
Speaker 5:  That's amazing. I mean honestly there, there's parts that's like where you
Speaker 5:  just have to, you just have to give it to him.
Speaker 7:  Doesn't he have 20 direct reports at Tesla? Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I
Speaker 9:  Mean something like that. So what
Speaker 7:  Does his phone look like right now? I
Speaker 9:  Can't imagine, does
Speaker 7:  He just set on fire? Like does he keep it like in ice at all times
Speaker 7:  so he can use it like
Speaker 9:  It's just the Twitter icon just on the home screen
Speaker 5:  Mean I talk to a lot of CEOs, I'm like, what's your structure? What's your
Speaker 5:  ING decision? I definitely know a CEO is like, how does he get it all done?
Speaker 9:  I think he literally just like barely sleeps. I think he three sleeps like
Speaker 9:  three to four hours a night. Like he was tweeting at like 5:00 AM the other
Speaker 9:  day. And like, like how in bananas this all is, is like Twitter employees
Speaker 9:  are glued to like the Elon Jet Twitter account to like, that tracks where
Speaker 9:  his jet takes off and lands to like see is he coming to the our office next.
Speaker 9:  Like it's, it's just an insane, I mean who knows, like we're all Lima may
Speaker 9:  come in and be running. Wow,
Speaker 5:  That's
Speaker 9:  Enough. And a and a
Speaker 5:  See ya. It was good to see you Alex. All
Speaker 9:  Right. Sorry guys. I gotta go. I gotta go check in with my husband
Speaker 5:  And wife. See you guys. See you brother. All right. That's, that's
Speaker 5:  how you know it's over. We gotta take a break. We'll right back. Talk
Speaker 5:  about the Smart Hub. We're right back.
Speaker 5:  All right, we're back. We're back. That's enough. We're
Speaker 5:  just gonna put that aside. We're
Speaker 7:  Gonna talk about what really matters.
Speaker 5:  There you go. I'm tired. There you go. We're gonna talk about
Speaker 5:  gadgets and standards and parties
Speaker 5:  in Amsterdam. Were just, doors are locking and unlocking left and right.
Speaker 5:  It's matter. Launch day. This is a big deal. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Wait, I'm sorry, can I just pause real fast? Alex, I just want to acknowledge
Speaker 6:  the matter pun that you just made that I think completely missed. No, I didn't
Speaker 6:  miss it and I just want you to know it. It was very good. Thank you. It was
Speaker 6:  very good. I liked it very much and I just want you to know that I see you
Speaker 7:  And I appreciate, I like, I feel like I need to have a limit on how many
Speaker 7:  times I can do that. Pun in this, in this next 45 minutes.
Speaker 7:  It's,
Speaker 6:  It's one and you, you did it and congratulations, you used,
Speaker 7:  You have to call me out if I do it again. I'm gonna try really, really hard
Speaker 7:  not to.
Speaker 5:  My strategy with puns is that you just ignore the bullies that go away
Speaker 5:  and puns are verbal bullies.
Speaker 5:  That's what I got for you. No matter launch day it did. What's going on?
Speaker 7:  Okay, so, So Matter launched over 190
Speaker 7:  Smart Home devices are now certified by Matter. But I think the big thing
Speaker 7:  was that we also heard a lot about what's coming next for
Speaker 7:  matter and, and we're starting to see a lot of these other products say,
Speaker 7:  Hey, yeah, now we're gonna be on matter. Nano Leaf was one of the big ones
Speaker 7:  that just announced that they're gonna finally put out a bunch of matter
Speaker 7:  products. They'd not done it before this. They'd had some thread light bulbs.
Speaker 7:  I have one, it's lovely, but it doesn't have matter. And so now it's gonna
Speaker 7:  have, if you go and buy the new ones, they will have thread and matter
Speaker 7:  in them. Another one was Eve's Eve
Speaker 7:  is like a big company, really works closely with Apple Home Kit
Speaker 7:  and it's finally getting matter. Yeah, that's really exciting. I, I was
Speaker 7:  noticing a lot of these products were ones that were like kind of exclusively
Speaker 7:  Home Kit before this. Yeah. And, and now they're gonna be everywhere. And
Speaker 7:  that's exciting because Home Kit smart gadgets I feel are
Speaker 7:  better.
Speaker 5:  Yes, I agree. So, I mean, the interesting underlying piece of matter is that
Speaker 5:  it is basically home kit. Yeah. So Apple, the, you know, there's a real
Speaker 5:  experience with all this where you just, it's like you just wish everyone
Speaker 5:  would cut to the end. Yeah. Like two years before the end.
Speaker 5:  And so, you know, Amazon had its own ecosystem and Google had its own
Speaker 5:  ecosystem and Apple had its own ecosystem and you're like, Why don't you
Speaker 5:  all just make a thing that works together? And they're like, No, because
Speaker 5:  we would like to fully dominate your life in every way possible.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. We wanna destroy your
Speaker 5:  Credit card. And then like five years later, here they are. They're very
Speaker 5:  proud of their new standard that they all made together because they realize
Speaker 5:  this was stupid. Yeah. So I don't want take them very happy. They did.
Speaker 5:  It matters. Great.
Speaker 7:  It took,
Speaker 5:  Yeah, it took a long time.
Speaker 7:  It took a long time. It shouldn't have taken this long. It kept getting delayed.
Speaker 7:  It was supposed to take about what, in like 2021 I think. Yeah. Like it,
Speaker 7:  it kept getting delayed. It was kind of obnoxious that it took this long.
Speaker 7:  Especially because a lot of this stuff could already work together. You could
Speaker 7:  go and get HomeBridge, you could go and get these other software products
Speaker 7:  and just make this shit work together and be friends.
Speaker 7:  And the companies were like, No, no, no, no, no. Wait, wait. We're gonna
Speaker 7:  get thread and then we're gonna have our new standard took.
Speaker 5:  But the reason it's Homecare devices first is because it's Apple's credit.
Speaker 5:  A lot of what matter is is Home Kit. Yeah. Like Apple
Speaker 5:  basically gave away the store on the Home Kit standard
Speaker 5:  and said, Here you use everyone, Use Home Kit. It's secure. It's good. It's
Speaker 5:  what we will approve Apple to make a smart home device. You wanna be on the
Speaker 5:  iPhone, you wanna be in the control panel on the iPhone. So
Speaker 5:  everyone Apple saying we're gonna let it be home Kit. Cuz that's what we'll
Speaker 5:  approve. Big step for Apple.
Speaker 7:  Huge
Speaker 5:  Step for Apple. Imagine they like,
Speaker 7:  They don't play nice.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Like whoever at Apple got back to their house, they closed to the door.
Speaker 5:  They're like, I hope I did the right thing. You know, like that. Does that
Speaker 5:  kind of move for them? So I You're Eve is like a big home kit company. People
Speaker 5:  are like their stuff. Nale
Speaker 7:  Nale.
Speaker 5:  They were,
Speaker 7:  They do the cool like light panels. Yeah. That you always see in
Speaker 7:  every single battle station photo on Reddit. Yeah. Every guy is like, Yeah
Speaker 7:  I got my new, my new
Speaker 5:  Computer streamers have an leaf that, that's great. But like nano leaf flights
Speaker 5:  are great cuz they're, they, they have been on thread for a while. So if
Speaker 5:  you had like a home pod mini and a nano leaf flight
Speaker 7:  Just works.
Speaker 5:  It just works. And it's like instantaneous in a way that the best wifi
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Setups are not instantaneous.
Speaker 7:  I think one of the big ones here for me was Phillips Hugh Bridge is
Speaker 7:  going to have a software update to support matter. That's really, really
Speaker 7:  nice because Phillips Hugh Bridge I think is probably one of the ones that
Speaker 7:  the majority of people, if you do do smart home, you dip your toe in.
Speaker 7:  That's like one of the first things you do. You go and you buy the cool lights,
Speaker 7:  you spend $40 per light bulb and you feel really proud about it until somebody
Speaker 7:  asks you how much you spent per light bulb. Yeah. And you do the math in
Speaker 7:  your head.
Speaker 6:  That one is kind of funny to me because like in theory what
Speaker 6:  matter does is obviate the need for things like the hub
Speaker 6:  bridge. Yeah. Like the whole reason for matter is so that we don't have to
Speaker 6:  plug in a million hub bridges to our homes. And to me that's like a perfect
Speaker 6:  example, right? Like in in the best possible world, Phillips have come out
Speaker 6:  and say all of our lights now support matter, control them however you want.
Speaker 6:  Happy days are here again. But instead this is like, this is the launch of
Speaker 6:  matter, but it's actually like one step in the right direction
Speaker 6:  instead of like a solved
Speaker 7:  Problem once. Right. Well cause they don't have a lot of those, those light
Speaker 7:  bulbs. They don't have the the capa like they don't have the hardware in
Speaker 7:  them to support this. They they have to.
Speaker 6:  Right. Because the bridge is, the bridge does all of the actual
Speaker 7:  Work, bridges all the work. So I, I'm really excited to never use the Phillips
Speaker 7:  Hue light app ever again. Just a terrifically
Speaker 7:  terrible app.
Speaker 6:  That app is trash.
Speaker 7:  And I'm really excited and every couple of years they're like, we redid it
Speaker 7:  and it's the same but a slightly d
Speaker 5:  This is why I end up, this is why I have a raspberry pie. Yeah. Right.
Speaker 5:  Just,
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Home fridge makes everything better.
Speaker 5:  It's so this, this, I'm excited for matter just to get, I mean I love this.
Speaker 5:  It's like a tomagotchi that runs my thermostat. Yeah. Like I have to
Speaker 5:  feed and care for it and I'm like, if I don't like check it every day, it'll
Speaker 5:  buy like it's my little lineage pet. Give
Speaker 7:  It a little
Speaker 5:  Pet and I know if it's working or not. Because we can, we can set the
Speaker 5:  thermostat on our phones without using the Nest app. It's the whole game.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I'm excited to, I mean I'm like, I'm,
Speaker 5:  I think bittersweet. Like I might send it off to college. Aww. And
Speaker 5:  now we're gonna have matter instead. But it's, it's that thing where, because
Speaker 5:  I have a Nest thermostat, I need to have middleware in my house,
Speaker 5:  extremely brittle self-install middleware in my house
Speaker 5:  to just make it convenient. And that's what the HU lights have been for so
Speaker 5:  long. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Well I mean I, there's like more bits
Speaker 5:  and bobs here that need to come out. Like I'm just hesitant to
Speaker 5:  say on this podcast of all podcasts the word thread border router
Speaker 5:  And this is like, this is where it belongs. That's where that vocabulary
Speaker 5:  belongs. Yeah. Yes. And like what needs to happen is
Speaker 5:  every router, every wifi router needs to have a thread radio in
Speaker 5:  it so that they're all thread border routers.
Speaker 6:  Is this when we should litigate the difference between matter over wifi and
Speaker 6:  matter over thread and how they're actually different things and and matter
Speaker 6:  is actually an umbrella term that describes several different things. Yes.
Speaker 5:  Yes. I think this is,
Speaker 6:  I
Speaker 5:  Is hesitant and it's like
Speaker 6:  I don't want to, David
Speaker 5:  Just man into
Speaker 6:  The
Speaker 5:  Is an umbrella. You
Speaker 6:  Did it. I would like to leave, I hate this. I'm
Speaker 5:  Sorry. Yeah. Matters. The control standard. It's the how everything
Speaker 5:  talks to each other standard.
Speaker 7:  But it uses a bunch of different technologies
Speaker 5:  They can operate in. The big move is that it uses
Speaker 5:  IP instead of some other, I mean this stuff is so wonky. They've been talking
Speaker 5:  about it for years. Yeah. And it's like, so you guys, after five
Speaker 5:  years of argument, you decided to use IP packets
Speaker 5:  instead of some other weirdo riff and they're like, I would've
Speaker 7:  Was just shocking. Yeah. Just shocking. We are gonna see some other new
Speaker 7:  technology coming to matter. They're gonna start supporting garage door
Speaker 7:  controllers, which could be fun. Electronic gates.
Speaker 7:  That
Speaker 5:  One's fun. That's all just doors. You described two different kinds of doors.
Speaker 7:  They're just doing doors,
Speaker 5:  Doors, big doors set at Hope. They're,
Speaker 7:  They're gonna do doors. You're gonna soon be able to open and close your
Speaker 7:  door without having to have Home Bridge installed. Which is really exciting.
Speaker 5:  Dream my garage openers home already.
Speaker 7:  But I think they're one that's kind of like interesting is the ambient,
Speaker 7:  the tiniest
Speaker 6:  Doors be around now. And I'm like, what if I just never had to open a door
Speaker 6:  again? What if all my doors were just magically open,
Speaker 7:  Needed them to, they open, it's great. Woo.
Speaker 5:  I
Speaker 6:  Could carry two beverages at the same
Speaker 5:  Time. Doesn't matter. Door committee is like, all right, next we're doing
Speaker 5:  big doors and after that I don't want to hear it Tom. We're not doing medium
Speaker 5:  doors, we're going straight to small doors.
Speaker 7:  Tiny. The tiny like the little fairy
Speaker 5:  Doors, medium doors suck it. Right.
Speaker 5:  Ambient something.
Speaker 7:  But I think, I think the big one is gonna be the, the ambient motion and
Speaker 7:  presence sensing. Okay. Because that's a weird technology that like Matter
Speaker 7:  itself is a whole bunch of different standards spread all around, right?
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Like, like links has, we're gonna bounce the wifi
Speaker 7:  off of you to know exactly where you are in your house at all times. Which
Speaker 7:  is both awesome and terrifying. Yeah. And then you also have like
Speaker 7:  the weird ultrasound sensing in the motion detecting in cameras and stuff.
Speaker 7:  So all of that is gonna soon come into matter soon. I say
Speaker 7:  soon it is still matter. It still could be like four years from
Speaker 7:  now when we finally get this. But,
Speaker 5:  But the dream here is that you can buy all these different
Speaker 5:  kinds of devices. Yeah. And it doesn't matter if you're a Google Home person
Speaker 5:  or
Speaker 7:  A home Care doesn't matter at all.
Speaker 5:  Oh my god Alex, I'm trying so hard
Speaker 6:  Here. I gave you one Alex this
Speaker 5:  One, this is why it was delayed. Like they just kept getting
Speaker 5:  sidetracked by their own wordplay. They're
Speaker 7:  Like, these puns are so good.
Speaker 5:  They're like we gotta get back to work. Someone in the background was like,
Speaker 5:  none of this matters.
Speaker 7:  Do you think they have like a big sign? It's like absolutely no puns beyond
Speaker 7:  this point just no like instant termination.
Speaker 5:  It's work time.
Speaker 5:  Start writing that spec.
Speaker 5:  The problem with that is all the like you can make it taken by motion
Speaker 5:  sensors from any company and door locks from any company and like cobble
Speaker 5:  together your own security system. But if people wanna buy is
Speaker 5:  like complete integrated products. So like is Ring gonna
Speaker 5:  fully participate or are they gonna hold back some features for their
Speaker 5:  proprietary riff? Right. Like but
Speaker 7:  I mean probably Yeah
Speaker 5:  But
Speaker 6:  Isn't the goal of Matter to make that a false dichotomy that
Speaker 6:  like what we have now is an integrated ecosystem no matter
Speaker 6:  what you buy that. Like in theory what should happen now is
Speaker 6:  I can control, I have all of my controllers work and all I have to do
Speaker 6:  is attach something to my network once and it talks to all of my devices
Speaker 6:  through all of my devices. And that's so like the thing Ring has done, which
Speaker 6:  is like build itself a beautiful little wall of garden in theory eventually
Speaker 6:  becomes like redundant and unnecessary. And to me what's super exciting
Speaker 6:  about that is you get to a future where the bar for building this stuff
Speaker 6:  is super, super, super low. Because right now if you wanna build like an
Speaker 6:  actually competitive smart home thing, even if it's just like a dumb little
Speaker 6:  like water sensor. Yeah. It's so much work and you have to build so
Speaker 6:  much new software every single time. And a lot of them choose Alexa because
Speaker 6:  Alexa has made that development easier than most. But then you only get one
Speaker 6:  slower of the market. And then if you wanna do Home Kit, that's a whole separate
Speaker 6:  thing. So a lot of companies are just giving up because like it's not worth,
Speaker 6:  it's not worth the development work to get into this ecosystem. But if you
Speaker 6:  can say like build it once and it will work for everywhere. It's like, it's
Speaker 6:  like building a a web app and you can just like people can have it. That
Speaker 6:  becomes kind of amazing. And I don't know like Matter is not gonna be there
Speaker 6:  in the first iteration but like that's gotta be where this is headed and
Speaker 6:  it's supposed to be where this is headed.
Speaker 7:  I think Neil was saying that like, like a web app. What if the web app gives
Speaker 7:  you way different features than the app that you install on your phone? Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Like Ring wants you to open their apps so they can sell you more ring cameras.
Speaker 5:  Like I have Ring it says like you have an order, you open it and then
Speaker 5:  you like go to the home screen. It's like have you thought about buying more
Speaker 5:  cameras? Right. Like they want, they do want you in their apps in some way.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  But now I don't have to Open Rings app. This is the beauty of Matter.
Speaker 5:  I
Speaker 6:  Don't ever have to use the Philips app or the Ring app ever again as long
Speaker 6:  as I
Speaker 5:  Can. But that desire is not gonna go away. Right. Like the business model
Speaker 5:  for these companies cannot be, you sell a water sensor once and you walk
Speaker 5:  away.
Speaker 7:  I think like the example is, so the Phillips HU app, Terrible garbage
Speaker 7:  hate it, The worst thing in the world. But what it does really cool that
Speaker 7:  I can't do on the Apple Home app is make all my lights mimic
Speaker 7:  candlelight. Yeah. Like I wanna sit at and read a book and pretend
Speaker 7:  like I have a roaring fire in my home. I
Speaker 6:  Can, I love when all my lights flicker
Speaker 7:  All the time. It's great. It makes total sense. I play a little jazz, have
Speaker 7:  a little cocktail. It's really, it's a nice moment. Alice
Speaker 5:  Just hammered me like make flicker. Yeah
Speaker 7:  Flicker faster. It's great.
Speaker 7:  But you can't do that with the home app. Like, and and I don't
Speaker 7:  see them changing that anytime soon. And so if I wanna
Speaker 7:  do that I have to go and go there and get through all those ads for other
Speaker 7:  HU lights that I don't need.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I think that this is what watching this play out is gonna be what
Speaker 5:  features do these companies hold back for their weirdo riffs? Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yes. And what features are the commodity features? And I we, we have no idea
Speaker 5:  but you can see it play out across
Speaker 5:  every other standard. Like AirPods are technically Bluetooth
Speaker 7:  Technically,
Speaker 5:  But Yeah. But Apple is special Bluetooth. It's better
Speaker 5:  than the Bluetooth everybody else gets So Nas, BBC negative. It's rare that
Speaker 5:  we see a new standard launch.
Speaker 7:  Well it's gonna go, there's an, there's an optimistic side to this. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  And I think that David was touching on that earlier in that you're still,
Speaker 7:  if you just wanna go and buy a cheap sensor and plug it into your house
Speaker 7:  and you don't need fancy features now you can just go do that.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. You wanna go buy a cheap light and you don't care if it does
Speaker 7:  candlelight great. You can just go do that.
Speaker 7:  So those, those premium ones are still gonna be there to say hey give
Speaker 7:  me extra money and use my annoying app. And you get cooler new
Speaker 7:  features. But for the vast majority of people they can just opt outta that
Speaker 7:  and just be like, I just want lights that turn on when I get home.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I'm I, yeah, I don't
Speaker 6:  Wanna think of my house as an ecosystem of hardware and software. Like
Speaker 6:  my house is just my house. Like when I need a light I would like to buy a
Speaker 6:  light. Yeah. Like and and we've ended up in this place where it's like every
Speaker 6:  time like the
Speaker 5:  The,
Speaker 6:  I always joke with my wife that like anytime she changes anything it inevitably
Speaker 6:  spirals into changing everything. Right? It's like we get a new rug and then
Speaker 6:  it's like oh well now the bedspread doesn't work and then we paint the walls
Speaker 6:  and now I'm tearing down the bathroom and it's all because we got a new fucking
Speaker 6:  rug. And that's what the smart home is like now it's like you find
Speaker 6:  one thing that is cool and you suddenly have to rip every wire out of your
Speaker 6:  walls and replace it just so it all works with your old stuff
Speaker 6:  and matter it in theory obviates that for regular people
Speaker 6:  like me who do not wanna deal with
Speaker 5:  It. So I've been thinking about this a lot in the context of maybe we'll
Speaker 5:  move, like maybe we're gonna have a different house. And I'm like the only
Speaker 5:  way to ethically sell my home is
Speaker 5:  to just run away to not even tell
Speaker 5:  people that there is a smart home stuff in it.
Speaker 5:  Cuz if you start, you have to be like, all right, here's the first thing
Speaker 5:  you need to do. There's 500 things in this house
Speaker 5:  that think the wifi is named whatever the wifi is named.
Speaker 5:  So you've gotta just, here you're gonna need a 40 foot ladder
Speaker 5:  and there's a floodlight on the roof and you've gotta go press a tiny button
Speaker 5:  on the side of it while holding your phone. It's like no,
Speaker 5:  actually what I should do is just bail and be like, if you're interested
Speaker 5:  in that floodlight, just like every other home in America, you're gonna discover
Speaker 5:  what happened to the floodlight on your own.
Speaker 7:  You can have a fun
Speaker 5:  Adventure. I can't be putting on this like you can't put this amount of responsibility
Speaker 5:  in someone else. There's a tiny tomagotchi in utility room
Speaker 5:  if it makes the thermostat work,
Speaker 6:  If you don't feed it, the house will burn down.
Speaker 5:  You can't give this responsibility to someone. All you can do
Speaker 5:  is like pack your bags and just walk off into the night and
Speaker 7:  Be like, lose my number.
Speaker 5:  Exactly.
Speaker 7:  Realtor calls just hang up. Yeah
Speaker 5:  Baby matter makes us better cuz all the stuff will just like still work together.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And it won't be like, here's a collection of apps
Speaker 5:  that runs the garage door. I hope you're
Speaker 5:  okay with this.
Speaker 7:  Well you're gonna have to wait because that's not coming yet. Yeah. It won't
Speaker 7:  be supported by that
Speaker 5:  Until matter supports garage
Speaker 7:  Doors. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Right.
Speaker 7:  Ethically
Speaker 5:  It's gonna be great. We're gonna have to keep living in the woods. Last one
Speaker 5:  just on matter, which is really cool Level locks or really cool the company
Speaker 5:  level. They've had a secret thread radio and then the,
Speaker 7:  That's the, that's the coolest thing in the world. Yeah. I I I love
Speaker 7:  when somebody's like secretly we've been planning for this all along.
Speaker 7:  Surprise. Yeah. You're just like,
Speaker 5:  Oh what was the one Google Smart Hunt thing where secretly at in microphone
Speaker 5:  all the time and it was, was that was the wrong thing to do. I'm sure. Do
Speaker 5:  you remember this? It was like one of the Google security system things and
Speaker 5:  they were like, it's had a microphone the whole time and everyone was like,
Speaker 5:  no that's the wrong choice for you to
Speaker 7:  Make Nest home
Speaker 5:  Security. Yes. The Nest Home security hub had a microphone in it and Google
Speaker 5:  was like surprise And everyone was like bad surprise, poor
Speaker 7:  Surprise. Take it out. Nobody wants
Speaker 5:  That. But we've a secret thread radio that makes our locks more compatible
Speaker 5:  with more things. Great.
Speaker 7:  Yeah and and level actually those locks look like real locks.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Which would probably be nice cuz part of the problem with most smart
Speaker 7:  locks is super hackable actually you have a cool little hacking tool
Speaker 7:  you can just like say hello, I'm in your house now.
Speaker 7:  So it's really nice.
Speaker 5:  I gotta go to my house.
Speaker 5:  I'll, I'll see you guys later do the, have fun with the third segment.
Speaker 5:  All right, we'll have you have to race Alex.
Speaker 7:  I know I'm gonna be like surprise Eli.
Speaker 5:  Hello.
Speaker 7:  I found the tomagotchi. Take it out the wall. Enjoy your
Speaker 7:  thermostat.
Speaker 5:  You get up. Can you go push that button on the roof that changes the wifi
Speaker 5:  network for the floodlight. We'll have much more modern news. By the
Speaker 5:  way, if I could be anywhere it would be in Amsterdam with Jen
Speaker 5:  and Thomas while they play with smart home gadgets.
Speaker 7:  It just sounds like a
Speaker 5:  Dream situation. Wonderful
Speaker 7:  Time. Absolutely.
Speaker 5:  Two of the coolest people on our team,
Speaker 7:  Super
Speaker 5:  Jealous and they are just turning lights on and off in Amsterdam
Speaker 5:  like at the fastest rainbows.
Speaker 7:  They're living the life we all wanna
Speaker 5:  Live and they're both the biggest smart hundred. So we'll have lots from
Speaker 5:  them on the site. Check it out. Okay, we'll take a break. Quick tour
Speaker 5:  through some gadgets show. We'll be right back.
Speaker 5:  Okay, we're back. Should we talk about the Apple TV
Speaker 5:  and what's going on with that? Or should we start talk about Amazon music?
Speaker 6:  Let's do Amazon first. Yeah cause this was, this was like the sneaky big
Speaker 6:  story of the week to me and I'm still surprised.
Speaker 5:  One of the most popular stories on our site to
Speaker 6:  Be Yeah,
Speaker 7:  Yeah. People really like to read about Amazon
Speaker 6:  Music and really hate the new Amazon music.
Speaker 7:  Really, really hate
Speaker 6:  It. Not all of them but some of them.
Speaker 7:  I mean they basically turned Amazon music into Pandora.
Speaker 5:  Well like a combos of Pandora and Spotify's free tier, like much
Speaker 5:  more Spotify's free tier than Pandora. So we had Steve Boom
Speaker 5:  who's the VP of Amazon Music on decoder. They had a big announcement, Amazon,
Speaker 5:  the bundle of Amazon music that came free with Prime, which is not free
Speaker 5:  at all. It's just a, it's just a, that we've chosen
Speaker 5:  to use together. Yes. This expensive thing came with a thing that is not
Speaker 5:  free, but it came with the thing
Speaker 7:  You pay for this already.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It's funny how they're like, this comes free with Prime and it's like,
Speaker 5:  it's nothing about, this is free. So Amazon music, the music service that
Speaker 5:  is included in your Amazon Prime subscription used to have
Speaker 5:  only 2 million tracks. Yeah. But it basically worked
Speaker 5:  like any other premium music service. Like you put songs, you could make
Speaker 5:  a playlist, you could whatever. Just the way that you thought Apple
Speaker 5:  Music or Spotify Premium worked, they have now changed it so that
Speaker 5:  it has a hundred million tracks, which is effectively the major
Speaker 5:  label catalogs like all of the popular music in America.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And you can pick, you can ask for one song at a time. You can like
Speaker 5:  be like, play this one Taylor Swift song to Alexa. It'll play that song.
Speaker 6:  No, not even. So thi this is where it kind of falls apart. So the way
Speaker 6:  it works basically is you're just in shuffle mode all the time. Like Pandora,
Speaker 6:  if you go to midnights by Taylor Swift and you hit play, whatever song you
Speaker 6:  click on, it will just shuffle songs from that album. It won't start with
Speaker 6:  the one that you picked. Maybe it will by accident but it won't, it'll just
Speaker 6:  shuffle through the album. If you pick an artist, it'll shuffle through the
Speaker 6:  artist. If you pick a playlist, it'll shuffle through the playlist. My favorite
Speaker 6:  thing that has happened so far is like you people release singles and they,
Speaker 6:  they look on these services like albums with one song. You
Speaker 6:  go to that album, I thought this was gonna be like a loophole. I was like
Speaker 6:  oh it'll shuffle the album but there's only one song so I win. You click
Speaker 6:  on it and it just plays a completely different song.
Speaker 5:  It's
Speaker 6:  Super jarring And, and this is the thing is like it does functionally work
Speaker 6:  like Pandora or in a lot of ways like Spotify is freeze here you
Speaker 6:  get a limited number of skips. You're mostly designed to be using
Speaker 6:  it as sort of background music. It's very much like a put it on
Speaker 6:  at the beginning of the party and don't touch it for six hours kind of music
Speaker 6:  experience. Can
Speaker 7:  You blacklist songs? Like if I wanna listen to cats
Speaker 7:  and be like I don't wanna hear Mr. Musto, I just, I
Speaker 7:  want everything else from Cats.
Speaker 6:  First of all, ski shakes, the Rail cat is the only good song from cats. But
Speaker 6:  we don't need
Speaker 5:  To my show. Right. Not
Speaker 7:  Memories.
Speaker 5:  I need this to stop. Right. We did, we've made
Speaker 5:  weed jokes. Alex said Lima twice
Speaker 7:  Other Alex
Speaker 5:  This is over.
Speaker 6:  Fair
Speaker 5:  Enough. Putting my foot down
Speaker 6:  And and the funny thing about this is this like as a music streaming
Speaker 6:  strategy, perfectly valid, right? This is like a thing a lot of folks do.
Speaker 6:  It's i it it is just how some systems work I think
Speaker 6:  as far as I can understand it is, it is basically cheaper
Speaker 6:  to run a service like this where you can't play the song you choose, you
Speaker 6:  just sort of get music as opposed to giving people like True on demand.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Click the song and play the song music makes perfect sense. The
Speaker 6:  problem is it's a total 180 in how it works from what
Speaker 6:  Amazon music used to be. Which like you I said is smaller library but
Speaker 6:  basically total access and I should say the new Amazon music has
Speaker 6:  a set of playlists that it calls all access playlists and those
Speaker 6:  you can interact with however you want. And those are like, you know, big
Speaker 6:  hits and some stuff like that. So it's, it's both confusing and a
Speaker 6:  total change from what people who are using this are used to. So my my
Speaker 6:  guess would be if you've never used Apple Music before and you open it up
Speaker 6:  and you're like oh tight all the music is here, I'm gonna like throw on a
Speaker 6:  drive playlist while, while I'm on my commute this morning. Like that's a
Speaker 6:  great experience. But for people who have like curated their own playlists
Speaker 6:  in Apple Music that now don't work the way they expected or can't go
Speaker 6:  listen to the music they had found there or what some people are saying,
Speaker 6:  they've bought music that Amazon has now put behind the paywall
Speaker 6:  and won't give them that kind of on-demand access to like I can see why you'd
Speaker 6:  be pissed. They basically just like upended the whole experience for you
Speaker 6:  for something that I think a lot of people weren't really asking for.
Speaker 5:  Well two things. One, you said Apple Music there twice when you met Amazon
Speaker 5:  Music. But I think the listeners will
Speaker 6:  Forget this didn't mean Amazon Music.
Speaker 5:  I'm sorry. That's fine. We'll get over it. Or will we?
Speaker 6:  It's the one that doesn't have Zalo, that's all I know.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Two, in talking to Steve Boom, you know the Amazon
Speaker 5:  music has been really targeted at the bottom 80% of
Speaker 5:  music consumers. Yeah. Which is fascinating, right? Like they're like this
Speaker 5:  is the thing when you ask Alexa for a song, it just needs to play the song
Speaker 5:  and most people don't spend a lot of money on music. So we're going to
Speaker 5:  go here, we're gonna find the 80% of people who don't spend a lot of money
Speaker 5:  in music and make the product for them and it's gonna be bundled with Prime
Speaker 5:  so they just use it.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Yeah. I thought it was really interesting that he said to you that
Speaker 6:  there's like a giant subset of people who will never spend $10 a month on
Speaker 6:  music. Cuz my impression was always that like all these companies assumed
Speaker 6:  eventually everyone would do it. That it is like such a demonstrably good
Speaker 6:  deal for people who listen to music that eventually it would get everybody.
Speaker 6:  But he's like no there is clearly a maximum of people who will do that and
Speaker 6:  word after everybody else. I just thought that was really interesting.
Speaker 7:  Oh I'm one of those 80% I have Apple Music and that's just because I get
Speaker 7:  it through one of my like I think my phone plan otherwise I'd be like, I'm
Speaker 7:  not gonna pay for music, I'll just pirate it. I mean I
Speaker 7:  will just listen on YouTube,
Speaker 5:  Fire up to Plex server, let's do this thing. Yeah, I mean
Speaker 5:  that, I think if you make that assumption, you're like these people don't
Speaker 5:  care very much.
Speaker 7:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Right. And so we can just like change the terms of the deal and
Speaker 5:  like people, I think there's an assumption that people are just like wandering
Speaker 5:  at me, like play some music Alexa and Alexa's like here's some stuff and
Speaker 5:  that's the end of it. And the reality is that some people
Speaker 5:  were actually very particular about their use of this service inside
Speaker 5:  of 2 million tracks. And now that has changed and they're mad.
Speaker 7:  Do they get that back? If they pay more? They do. Right? Because
Speaker 5:  There's the premium service. Yeah. Yeah. And I think they're equally mad
Speaker 5:  about being upsold.
Speaker 7:  Yeah,
Speaker 5:  We'll
Speaker 7:  See, it's Twitter blue all over again.
Speaker 5:  Everything is Twitter blue.
Speaker 7:  It all goes
Speaker 5:  Back to Twitter. You get a blue check mark if you pay for non shuffle playing
Speaker 5:  Amazon Music, Chris Waltz review the Apple TV 4k, it's great. It's an Apple
Speaker 5:  tv. They took out the fan, it's a little lighter. The chip is really fast,
Speaker 5:  unnecessarily fast. The expensive one has thread. I just am
Speaker 5:  bringing it up because there's a new TV feature that is going to
Speaker 5:  make me upgrade my TVs between Matter and
Speaker 5:  QMS V R on TVs. It's like I gotta upgrade, I gotta get new locks.
Speaker 5:  I get new lights. I gotta, you
Speaker 7:  Gotta get the TV that supports v r.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So it's called, it's not out yet. So the new Apple TV supports something
Speaker 5:  called qms, V R R I don't know what the QMS stands for
Speaker 5:  and I refuse to google it. No, that's not true.
Speaker 7:  I was like, I'm Googling it. Quick media switching.
Speaker 5:  So there's a, the new Apple TV has something called QMS vr which is quick
Speaker 5:  media switching variable refresh rate. So variable refresh rate as you know,
Speaker 5:  can the just like promotion on your phone, the TVs can swing from
Speaker 5:  24 hertz to 120.
Speaker 7:  It's always gonna give you what looks nicest to
Speaker 5:  Your eye. Yep. It's gonna match the content dynamically. It's not gonna blink
Speaker 5:  out to black. And then QMS is quick media switching. So I think you just
Speaker 5:  sent the, the thing you're playing can send a flag and it can switch the
Speaker 5:  vrr really fast. Right. The Apple TV supports it. There are no TVs that support
Speaker 5:  it yet. Which is hilarious cuz there are tons of TVs that support VR r. This
Speaker 5:  seems like it should be, but a software update away. But the
Speaker 5:  TV manufacturers continue to be TV manufacturers.
Speaker 7:  Oh they're gonna make you
Speaker 5:  Tv.
Speaker 6:  I literally don't think you could've described a feature that sounds less
Speaker 6:  interesting and worth upgrading. My tv
Speaker 5:  I'm gonna upgrade my TV to this so fast.
Speaker 6:  Okay, so you know how you're
Speaker 5:  Watching tv Want the TV to blink out to black. I don't want it to happen.
Speaker 7:  Well you could wait. You could also go and if your, if your TV already supports
Speaker 7:  Vrr, somebody will absolutely find a hack. Yeah. In Hack
Speaker 7:  qms on
Speaker 5:  There. And I'm saying that the community of Twitter followers that I have
Speaker 5:  built up is like, crap, I've gotta upgrade my tv
Speaker 5:  so you're my people but this is the reason I'm gonna upgrade my Apple tv.
Speaker 5:  It's the reason I'm finally gonna buy a new TV and then matters. How
Speaker 6:  Many times a day would you say the refresh rate changes on your television
Speaker 6:  in the eye? Let's talk this
Speaker 5:  Through. It's not the refresh rate, it's the, it's the match content. So
Speaker 5:  you can't run the interface in like Doby vision at one 20 and then
Speaker 5:  go watch Netflix 24 standard sdr. You can't run
Speaker 5:  the interface at like Doby Vision one 20 and then open Netflix
Speaker 5:  and SDR 24 Hertz without like an htm. I refresh
Speaker 5:  and an HTMI refresh
Speaker 1:  To be aware of bad news.
Speaker 5:  We gotta end the show.
Speaker 1:  No, no. So I I am one of your people
Speaker 1:  Eli and I was just telling David earlier, I want to
Speaker 1:  change my tv. There's a limitation to qr.
Speaker 1:  It only works for changing refresh rates without a
Speaker 1:  the black screen. It does not work. Going from SDR to
Speaker 1:  HDR or different versions of Adobe or
Speaker 1:  HDR 10 plus.
Speaker 5:  I can't, I can't abide my I know find me to QMS VR
Speaker 5:  office. We're going there right now.
Speaker 1:  Very frustrating
Speaker 5:  Is the H D M I building in the shape of a giant h Find it on Google
Speaker 5:  Maps. Let's go there. Everyone looked for the H on Google Maps.
Speaker 5:  Well that sucks. Now I'm not buying etv. You had your chance lg.
Speaker 7:  He's gonna be an lg.
Speaker 6:  I feel vindicated somehow I feel like I won this fight.
Speaker 7:  I still want it.
Speaker 6:  I
Speaker 7:  Do. I'm still gonna,
Speaker 5:  I just wanna buy any tv.
Speaker 7:  I know. Mine's five years old. I'm ready. It's time. Yeah
Speaker 6:  Mine's, I will say that reading
Speaker 5:  Garbage tv,
Speaker 7:  How to get a new
Speaker 6:  TV reading Chris's review and he, he keeps talking about how much unnecessary
Speaker 6:  power there is inside of this box. All I can think after spending months
Speaker 6:  sitting here, like begging my bro TV to load the app that I'm
Speaker 6:  trying to load is like I will take unlimited power from my set top
Speaker 6:  box. Like I, I would like six to seven times more power than I need from
Speaker 6:  my set top box because it's just, it is the worst. Like if my worst
Speaker 6:  problem was that the screen flickered every once in a while, that'd be great.
Speaker 6:  Now it's like I open the HBO Max app and four outta six
Speaker 6:  times. It's just like ah, I'm gonna crash your television.
Speaker 5:  I bought a smart projector last year and like over the course
Speaker 5:  of this summer, it's like what if I didn't run Android? Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Like what if I just like coughed and sneezed and was
Speaker 5:  like here's why. Here's parts of this interface, the
Speaker 7:  Media attack process.
Speaker 6:  My TV is tired. My literally acts like it's tired.
Speaker 6:  It's just like, alright, give a minute. Like yeah, I'll search for that for
Speaker 6:  you. But like hold on.
Speaker 5:  Hey Roku, 4K sticks are 25 bucks for Black Friday. I really? Yeah.
Speaker 6:  But then I have to plug a Roku into my Roku tv. I like on principle,
Speaker 6:  on principle I cannot do that. But I will buy an Apple TV that is
Speaker 6:  unnecessarily powerful and expensive and plug it in into my Roku tv. Like
Speaker 6:  yeah I will,
Speaker 7:  I'm ready. Can you bypass that? Because I know with Roku it always like presents
Speaker 7:  you the menu. Can you bypass that?
Speaker 6:  I have to open my Roku. Yeah. The data with like I can do that with like
Speaker 6:  great spite and anger. Like every time I open my Roku menu I can say no,
Speaker 6:  no Roku to my Apple TV and then I'll feel like I've accomplished something.
Speaker 5:  You know there's a chart at Apple there. It's like we've got this many a
Speaker 5:  15 s out in the world under TVs. We're about to become a gaming powerhouse.
Speaker 5:  And then like Tim Click is like, but I hate video games. And that's
Speaker 5:  where that conversation, that conversation's gonna hit that brick wall every
Speaker 5:  time. That's why the Apple TVs unnecessarily powerful cause they think it's
Speaker 5:  a game console. Yes. And if they can just get enough
Speaker 5:  eighteens underneath,
Speaker 7:  Nobody tell them nobody to tell them. I want my unnecessarily powerful
Speaker 7:  set top box. Yeah. On it. Yeah. I don't want
Speaker 7:  Roku so like just nobody tells him cook about this. We're all buying it for
Speaker 7:  the games, Tim. It's the only reason it's
Speaker 5:  All gonna happen. Speaking last little bit of streaming news, Netflix
Speaker 5:  ads plan came out today it's $7 a month and sign
Speaker 5:  up for it doesn't work on the Apple TV at launch,
Speaker 7:  Doesn't work on the Apple TV at launch. A surprising number, a
Speaker 7:  surprising amount of content doesn't work. And you get a
Speaker 7:  big padlock sign and then when you click it's like,
Speaker 7:  Hey, we noticed you clicked on this movie you wanted to watch. Would you
Speaker 7:  like to give us money? So that's why it doesn't work on Apple tv because
Speaker 5:  No, I
Speaker 7:  Mean that's
Speaker 5:  What I, No, Netflix gave a statement to nine to five Mac and they
Speaker 5:  said it's coming.
Speaker 7:  Okay, it's coming. Once they figure out how to get around the 30%,
Speaker 5:  Well or they're just gonna remove the the tout to actually pay money.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, we'll see. But it doesn't wear your launch. I, you know, I'm assuming
Speaker 5:  that
Speaker 7:  They're gonna email
Speaker 5:  You. They're gonna email,
Speaker 7:  It'll be fine.
Speaker 5:  They're gonna get a big fight. But it's out. Now you can read Jay
Speaker 5:  wrote about, Yeah
Speaker 7:  Jay Jay wrote about it. He, he tried it out for a few hours and it seems
Speaker 7:  to be just digital advertising. It's like Hulu and stuff where there's no
Speaker 7:  rhyme or reason to win. The advertisements will pop up. So when there are
Speaker 7:  those natural breaks, instead of it being there, it's gonna be like mid-sentence.
Speaker 7:  I love, Would you like to buy some Tide pods? Oh my God, it's gonna be great.
Speaker 7:  Exciting. There's still a lot to figure out there. They should probably look
Speaker 7:  to broadcast television because they figured out this whole advertising thing
Speaker 7:  decades ago. But he seems to like it overall. He's like yeah
Speaker 7:  if you, if you don't wanna be paying as much.
Speaker 5:  Oh yeah. So on the Netflix app, on iOS devices
Speaker 5:  like phones, it just basically says you need an
Speaker 5:  ad free plan. It doesn't let you buy it. Yeah, well they'll do that on the
Speaker 5:  tv I'm sure they just have to like get through some weird app. It doesn't
Speaker 5:  work on older Chromecast either.
Speaker 7:  Right. And it's not gonna work on probably a lot of your older Rokus too.
Speaker 7:  David, I'm sorry, does it work on yours? You have to test it out over
Speaker 7:  it.
Speaker 6:  Just roll. Give me like 45 minutes for the Netflix app to load. And I'll
Speaker 6:  tell you
Speaker 5:  Also the video quality is locked at seven 20 p and there's no offline
Speaker 5:  downloads. I don't know, I
Speaker 6:  Think are, are you, this strikes me as a fairly clear
Speaker 6:  way for Netflix to get people in and then try to get them to upgrade, which
Speaker 6:  I guess I underestimated the extent to which it was
Speaker 6:  gonna be that like this is not like just as good but with ads,
Speaker 6:  this is worse. Netflix for,
Speaker 7:  You can't even watch Arrested Development. None of Arrested
Speaker 6:  Development. What I'm saying like it's, it's, it's very clear that this Netflix
Speaker 6:  is looking at this like a gateway drug to a fully paid Netflix plan hundred.
Speaker 6:  Like a real swing at advertising, right?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, no I, well I don't know. I was gonna be really stru about that
Speaker 5:  but I've, I've in five seconds tone my opinion down.
Speaker 5:  So the comparison I was gonna make is if you're gonna do that then you might
Speaker 5:  as well do Spotify free and actually just make it free and let the ads pay
Speaker 5:  for the
Speaker 6:  Free shuffle Netflix
Speaker 5:  Shuffle Netflix. Like why not? You
Speaker 7:  Know, like what are you watching today? You find
Speaker 5:  Out. But Spotify free is really important to Spotify. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  it is the most important part of their product. It is the thing they give
Speaker 5:  away and everybody has it and it is designed to make you start to pay for
Speaker 5:  Spotify and it's the top of the funnel. So they care a lot about
Speaker 5:  Spotify free. It's the thing they make. Netflix got dragged kicking
Speaker 5:  and streaming to Netflix with ads, right? Yeah. Like they fair kind of don't
Speaker 5:  wanna make it. They've had to, they've reduced the price. It's still $7 so
Speaker 5:  you still have to pay for it. And then you get these ads and the ads are
Speaker 5:  where the money is supposed to come from cuz Netflix has this theoretically
Speaker 5:  huge audience. So they're, I think they're just kind of stuck in the middle.
Speaker 5:  Like they haven't built the Let's capture everyone and get
Speaker 5:  them to pay us cuz it's still not free. Gotta get $7 a month outta
Speaker 5:  people and they haven't built the, this is worth $7 a month and you have
Speaker 5:  to watch ads.
Speaker 7:  They've got a lot of contracts they have to get through too. So, So J's piece
Speaker 7:  noted that some of the stuff that's not available now is gonna be available
Speaker 7:  later. And that's just because like they have to go back to these people
Speaker 7:  and be like, Hey, we signed a deal with you that we would just stream this
Speaker 7:  movie now we wanna put ads on it. Yeah. Can we do that without giving
Speaker 7:  you more money? And I don't think they can,
Speaker 5:  I just think they should have done a free with ads tier in addition to this
Speaker 5:  one. Yeah. Like if you did free with ads and then you did $7
Speaker 5:  with like some ads and maybe 10 80 p like
Speaker 7:  Full efforts like free with this, with this limited library. Yeah. And
Speaker 7:  then $7 with the whole library in ads and maybe that's
Speaker 7:  the plan. And so we're all gonna be really delighted when that happens because
Speaker 7:  it'll be an improvement from this. I wouldn't, I
Speaker 6:  Mean we that out, we all paid a crap ton of money for cable subscriptions
Speaker 6:  that still had a lot of ads. So like I, I don't know that money plus ads
Speaker 6:  is all that shocking of behavior. Yeah, that's true. But it
Speaker 6:  would be interesting to see Netflix be like, okay, you can get it for free
Speaker 6:  but every hour it's gonna be 30 minutes of ads. Are you ready for this?
Speaker 6:  Like, here we
Speaker 5:  Go. I feel compelled at this time to disclose. We made a Netflix show.
Speaker 5:  It's very good. It's called The Future of, I'm hopelessly biased in favor
Speaker 5:  of it. I think you should watch it no matter what your plan. Also
Speaker 5:  Comcast is an investor in the Fox media or parent
Speaker 5:  company. You know, I don't care what Peacock does at this time, but they
Speaker 5:  exist and they run a competitive streaming service.
Speaker 7:  Should we, I feel like that's a good segue to talk about Comcast.
Speaker 5:  Just in general.
Speaker 7:  Just in general. No, they, they have their own rival to Roku
Speaker 7:  speaking of, and they said a while back they announced that they in charter
Speaker 7:  were gonna be partnering together and doing their own hardware ecosystem
Speaker 7:  and they finally have a name for it and it's called Zuma. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  And it's the exact same name that they already were using for a software
Speaker 7:  suite. So that's kind of of interesting. I, I don't know, I think it's
Speaker 7:  interesting mainly because of Roku and, and how this is really a play for
Speaker 7:  that super cheap set top box because a lot of people have Roku TVs and these
Speaker 7:  aging TVs and they are not going to go and pay a thousand dollars
Speaker 7:  to have qms V R R and instead they're just gonna be like, I
Speaker 7:  want a cheap set top box to play me the things and Charter and
Speaker 7:  Comcast are like, we'll do it and it'll be called Zoomo.
Speaker 7:  I'm just that name.
Speaker 6:  When I moved into my current house, we, we signed up for Comcast and they
Speaker 6:  literally sent me a set top box, which back then was called
Speaker 6:  Flex and I believe their flex program is now what's turning into zoomo
Speaker 6:  for free. And I literally was like, I don't want it. I have set top boxes,
Speaker 6:  I'm good. And he was just like, ah, we'll send you one. Like it, I think
Speaker 6:  you're right that it's it's they want to be in this platform
Speaker 6:  game so badly. They've been trying this for years. Like nobody
Speaker 6:  has tried more times with less success than Comcast
Speaker 6:  to build Yeah. A real like set top box empire.
Speaker 7:  It's really interesting because they do have this obsession with hardware
Speaker 7:  and that that no, no other kind of companies do they all, they
Speaker 7:  always want to own all of that hardware in your house and make you pay a
Speaker 7:  leasing fee for it.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Remember when the X one was gonna be like the super computer of set
Speaker 6:  top boxes and then everybody was like, the X one costs like six times too
Speaker 6:  much money. Comcast Yeah, please leave me alone. I do not want your cable
Speaker 6:  box.
Speaker 7:  Like I think they're, they're addicted if anything to that
Speaker 7:  leasing revenue stream and they're trying everything. They're trying their
Speaker 7:  damn desk to keep ahold of it as they lose all these other elements of like
Speaker 7:  cable is going away, cable is, you know, everybody says 10 years from now
Speaker 7:  cable's gonna be dead and where is that gonna leave them with
Speaker 7:  internet? And then ideally these set top boxes that they will charge you
Speaker 7:  an arm and a leg for each month.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I mean, and just like looking at the, the home screen on my Roku, right?
Speaker 6:  Like I I I turn on my television and right next to all of my apps,
Speaker 6:  there's just a big ass ad on the right side and like, you know, who would
Speaker 6:  like to be the one selling that ad is every media company on planet. Yep.
Speaker 6:  So like it makes a lot of sense to me that that's a really competitive space
Speaker 6:  and for Comcast, like as it gets harder and harder to sell people cable
Speaker 6:  subscriptions, like owning the box where people look at their television
Speaker 6:  is going to be a lucrative space. Right. Like Roku has continued to prove
Speaker 6:  that and it's, it's gonna keep working for any company that can actually
Speaker 6:  figure out how to pull this off. What's crazy to me is how few
Speaker 6:  have actually been able to like, it's been a long time since there was
Speaker 6:  an interesting new player in this space and like I certainly don't think
Speaker 6:  Zoomo is gonna change that. Yeah. But like, I guess kudos to Comcast
Speaker 6:  for, I mean I think continuing to bang its head against this particular,
Speaker 5:  I think you guys have done an excellent job laying out the strategic case
Speaker 5:  for Comcast to make this product fine. They called it Zuma
Speaker 5:  with an ex
Speaker 5:  like z u o. Like
Speaker 6:  This is the important part. This
Speaker 7:  Is this. Yeah. That's the whole name.
Speaker 5:  They, they, we live in a world where people do
Speaker 5:  not really understand the difference between Roku and Hulu. Like, it's my
Speaker 5:  favorite question that I've ever gotten from like the family. Like what is
Speaker 5:  the differe? And they're like Zoomo on our X Class
Speaker 5:  TVs running on Xfinity. It's like playing
Speaker 7:  The software because it also has software and the software is called
Speaker 7:  Zoomo play. So you gotta open the Sumo Play app on your zoomo.
Speaker 7:  No
Speaker 5:  Thank you. I I just don't
Speaker 6:  Anything can I, can I propose something to you that I think is gonna slightly
Speaker 6:  blow your mind? Yeah. Yeah. This name is a tremendous improvement
Speaker 6:  over the streaming box that Comcast launched last year.
Speaker 6:  Which which was spelled uppercase X, lowercase, i,
Speaker 6:  uppercase o, lowercase and lowercase e.
Speaker 5:  No. Is it,
Speaker 6:  Is it the, this is a real thing that happened.
Speaker 7:  How do you say
Speaker 6:  That? Is it and and all of the headlines you will find about this thing
Speaker 6:  are about how I literally don't know how to pronounce the name. It's very
Speaker 6:  good. This was Comcast last try. So Zoomo is, we're moving in the right
Speaker 6:  direction.
Speaker 7:  So does Comcast just have a room and they've got an X and they've got a
Speaker 7:  whole bunch of vowels and they're just like, throw 'em at the wall. That's
Speaker 6:  The name. Just like, it's like the refrigerator magnets, they just like whip
Speaker 6:  'em at the refrigerator. I'm like, ah, there
Speaker 7:  It's gotta have the X in. There's
Speaker 5:  Transformative, it's Z one. But then they saw that with an X, I don't know
Speaker 5:  man. Oh
Speaker 6:  Z one could be
Speaker 5:  Good. At the end of the day, Comcast is sad that they used to have two businesses.
Speaker 5:  They sold cable television and in access. Yeah. And one business is
Speaker 5:  going away and it's not the internet access business. So they, they're like,
Speaker 5:  what can we do to get back in the TV business, give
Speaker 7:  Us
Speaker 5:  Some monies And they're like, here's what we're gonna do. Army of Consultants
Speaker 5:  come up with a name and Army of consultants was like, we drank a lot of tequila,
Speaker 5:  we're going with Z one. Oh zoomo, let's go with Sumo.
Speaker 5:  It's bad, right? There's other stuff going on in the site. We were just like
Speaker 5:  way over. It's like six hours of Verge cast at this point. I mean we
Speaker 5:  love you all. Yeah, but honestly I can't think about Elon Musk anymore. I
Speaker 5:  just can't. I can't do it. The site is great. Lots of coverage on the site.
Speaker 5:  We had like a really fun day on the site just today between
Speaker 5:  Elon, the amount of short posts, Thomas and Jen at the matter thing. We
Speaker 5:  had the big decoder investigation. What's going on in the fcc, which
Speaker 5:  is real fun
Speaker 6:  Versus is back.
Speaker 5:  Oh versus is back. Yeah, V did her first verses great on smart watches. It's
Speaker 5:  great. Just kind of like an incredible week on the old verge.com. So we gotta
Speaker 5:  check it out, you know, Tweeted us. I'm at reckless. I mean for you
Speaker 5:  can we gotta add comments to quick posts. It's
Speaker 5:  like as fast as we can between us. Again, I'm at reckless. Alex is
Speaker 5:  Alex X Trans. David is at Pierce on Twitter. The platform
Speaker 5:  that we once loved. Well actually no one,
Speaker 6:  Everyone pay $8 a month and you can tweet me and think certain Eli as much
Speaker 6:  and he's obligated to read them.
Speaker 5:  Well not shout out to Addie's. Big piece on the first amendment this week,
Speaker 5:  which I think is really important. Maybe one of the most important things
Speaker 5:  published. Please go read that back on Wednesday. McKenna and Addie are gonna
Speaker 5:  talk about that piece. That's gonna be a good one. Indeed. And then you can
Speaker 5:  call us eight six six
Speaker 5:  Verge 11. 8 6 6
Speaker 5:  8 3 7 4 3 1. David, we'll listen to everything that you say
Speaker 6:  For $8 a month for
Speaker 5:  Eight, but I'll pay you $8. I will say that I stole this from Elon. Anytime
Speaker 5:  anyone criticizes me on Twitter now I'm just like $8. It's great. I encourage
Speaker 5:  you to try with your friends, but I think I have
Speaker 6:  To give you $8 a month and then, And then you get to yell at me on the Vergecast
Speaker 6:  hotline. I think that's how that works.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, yeah. David will pay $8. If you call this number, please call this
Speaker 5:  number eight six six vi 11. David will give you $8. We
Speaker 5:  call it. That's it. That's where our fast tracker.
Speaker 1:  And that's a wrap for Vergecast this week. Thanks for listening. If you enjoy
Speaker 1:  the show, subscribe in the podcast app of your choice or tele friend. You
Speaker 1:  can send us feedback at vergecast@theverge.com. The show is
Speaker 1:  produced by me, Liam James, and our senior audio director, Andrew Marino.
Speaker 1:  This episode was edited and mixed by Amanda Rose
Speaker 1:  Smith. Our editorial director is Brooke Miners and our executive producer
Speaker 1:  is Eleanor Donovan. The Verge Cast is a production of the Verge and Box
Speaker 1:  Media podcast network. And that's it. We'll see you next week.