# Transcript
ID: f6cad320-4485-11ed-a774-e34325a5e317
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: What does music feel like in the metaverse?
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-6292116121960471253/-6507944458415321396/s93290-US-1368s-1664957735.mp3
Description: The Verge's David Pierce dives into the world of virtual concerts in digital spaces like Roblox and Fortnite. Is this the future of live music?
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we'd love to hear from you.
We are conducting a short audience survey to help plan for our future and hear from you. To participate, head to vox.com/podsurvey, and thank you!
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (5 ads detected)
Speaker 3:  Welcome to the Vergecast, the flagship podcast of Screens Within
Speaker 3:  Screens Within Screens. I'm your friend, David Pierce, and this is
Speaker 3:  the third and last episode of our mini series about the future of music.
Speaker 3:  And for this episode, I wanna talk about live music, but not the live
Speaker 3:  music you're probably thinking
Speaker 3:  of. If you wanna know what the concert of the future looks like, we have
Speaker 3:  to go back to April 23rd, 2020, and then we
Speaker 3:  have to
Speaker 3:  go into Fortnite. It's 7:00 PM Eastern Thursday night, and
Speaker 3:  the Battle Royal game suddenly turns into this huge concert
Speaker 3:  arena with a big stage right in the middle of the water. There's a round
Speaker 3:  screen above the stage with lots of avatars gathered around it. It looks
Speaker 3:  like a concert, but then as the music builds right before the
Speaker 3:  show starts, things start to change. There's no musician
Speaker 3:  avatar that appears on the screen. Instead, this big orb
Speaker 3:  thing with glowing lights and speakers, kind of like you'd
Speaker 3:  mashed all the gear you need to put on a concert into a
Speaker 3:  ball just starts floating in from the sky
Speaker 3:  and then a huge like hundred feet tall
Speaker 3:  animated Travis Scott appears on stage.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, yeah, yeah. Gone on you with the roll Young Flame here in
Speaker 4:  Ome,
Speaker 3:  He spends the next few minutes stomping all over the island in
Speaker 3:  Fortnite, playing old and new songs. At one point he lights
Speaker 3:  everything on fire and then at another point he takes
Speaker 3:  the whole crowd underwater. It all sounds insane to say out
Speaker 3:  loud, but it was so cool. And then after about nine
Speaker 3:  minutes it was over.
Speaker 3:  You really can't overstate how big a deal that first Travis Scott
Speaker 3:  concert was. More than 12 million people watched that
Speaker 3:  first show, and more than 27 million saw it in one of
Speaker 3:  the five showings over the course of that weekend. Fortnite described it
Speaker 3:  kind of like a concert tour with different dates depending on where you
Speaker 3:  lived, and over the course of that weekend, Fortnite players could also get
Speaker 3:  Travis Scott emotes and gear to play the game with as well. Travis Scott
Speaker 3:  wasn't the first artist to play a concert in a digital space. That's actually
Speaker 3:  been a thing for a long time. I remember back in 2006 when Duran
Speaker 3:  Duran was playing a concert inside a bunch of colored cubes in
Speaker 3:  Second Life, which now sounds like a very old sentence to say out loud, but
Speaker 3:  it was cool.
Speaker 3:  Scott wasn't even the first to play in Fortnite, but the spectacle
Speaker 3:  of the show and the huge number of fans that showed up and the
Speaker 3:  overwhelming response that it created was a real moment in the
Speaker 3:  music industry. It caused a lot of people to start asking, What does
Speaker 3:  music in the metaverse look like? Oh, actually
Speaker 3:  a quick point on the word metaverse here. That word you probably
Speaker 3:  already know really doesn't mean anything. Meta means it to be
Speaker 3:  like vr, digital spaces where nobody has legs, but
Speaker 3:  we all sit in meetings all day. I guess some people think about it as what
Speaker 3:  we've seen in books like Snow Crash and Ready Player One, these super
Speaker 3:  immersive digital worlds we might all live in in the future, but I
Speaker 3:  would argue the Metaverse is also Fortnite and Roblox and Minecraft, and
Speaker 3:  basically any digital place where people hang out together in real
Speaker 3:  time, the tech doesn't matter really, at least for our purposes. The
Speaker 3:  idea is that it's people being together in digital spaces. That's the
Speaker 3:  metaverse that we care about.
Speaker 3:  So back to the question, what does music look like in the Metaverse?
Speaker 3:  One of the people asking that question was CBI de Gogo Jack, who was
Speaker 3:  then the head of music business development at Spotify. He's a long-time
Speaker 3:  music industry guy and is permanently looking for new ways for artists
Speaker 3:  to grow and make money.
Speaker 5:  I've been increasingly obsessed with artists,
Speaker 5:  artist success artists and fan connection and
Speaker 5:  enabling all of that. You know, my role at Interscope Records
Speaker 5:  was about finding more opportunity for artists to make more money
Speaker 5:  through the label. When I moved over to Spotify, it was a really similar
Speaker 5:  thing. How can Spotify make more revenue that we can then pass through
Speaker 5:  to musicians and how can we create emerging artist
Speaker 5:  programs or increasing artist equity programs, and how can we make sure that
Speaker 5:  those are really present in the world?
Speaker 3:  The spoiler ending to Kari's story is that he's now the head of music
Speaker 3:  partnerships at Roblox working on bringing more artists and music onto
Speaker 3:  the platform. So you could safely say he bought the whole music in the
Speaker 3:  Metaverse idea. I buy it too, honestly, The Metaverse is this
Speaker 3:  unknown new, messy thing where nobody knows the rules
Speaker 3:  or how it's supposed to work, but there's something to the live music thing.
Speaker 3:  It feels big and connective and exciting, and there's
Speaker 3:  clearly something that works for people on an emotional level. Here's how
Speaker 3:  C explained it.
Speaker 5:  I recently ran across a concept called reality
Speaker 5:  privilege. Reality privilege. Essentially it means that if
Speaker 5:  you live in an interesting place and you
Speaker 5:  have an interesting cohort of friends, but the truth is
Speaker 5:  that most people don't live in very interesting places
Speaker 5:  with very interesting cohorts of friends. Or even if they do,
Speaker 5:  they make real connections in digital spaces. So
Speaker 5:  I think that's a lot of the catalysts and the driver and the
Speaker 5:  appeal of a lot of what's happening across
Speaker 5:  Roblox and platforms like Roblox. I think from a concert
Speaker 5:  perspective, it's a concert, but it's a concert. Plus you
Speaker 5:  get to hear music, but you get to have unicorn
Speaker 5:  wings or something and you get to climb up
Speaker 5:  on Charlie Xcx and you get to share the stage with her and
Speaker 5:  it's more interesting or more interactive than
Speaker 5:  you know, a physical environment could be. So it it becomes
Speaker 5:  a whole different medium or event in its own way.
Speaker 3:  The most important thing to understand here, I think, is that there's
Speaker 3:  way less distance between a real life interaction and a digital
Speaker 3:  interaction than there once was. This is one of those things that if you're
Speaker 3:  under like 25, it sounds super obvious and if you're
Speaker 3:  over about 40, it sounds totally preposterous, but hanging out
Speaker 3:  in video games that's hanging out, it counts, it's real.
Speaker 3:  And going to a concert in Roblox and jumping up and down on the virtual
Speaker 3:  stage and meeting the artist's avatar after the show,
Speaker 3:  if that's not all the way as cool and memorable as seeing it in the real
Speaker 3:  world, it's a lot closer than you might think. I really do remember
Speaker 3:  that Travis Scott show as vividly as a lot of IL concerts
Speaker 3:  I've seen in the past. And like CBI said, it also opens up these
Speaker 3:  kinds of experiences to lots of new people. He mentioned one recent
Speaker 3:  event in Roblox, an album listening party with the artist, soccer mommy as
Speaker 3:  the kind of thing most people never get to be part of, but that are suddenly
Speaker 3:  available to millions of people all over the world.
Speaker 5:  She gave her fans an opportunity to hang out with her virtually. And you
Speaker 5:  know, there's a lot of these moments where these fans would geek
Speaker 5:  out and they would type in chat like, I can't believe that I got to meet
Speaker 5:  soccer. Mommy.
Speaker 3:  This is the thing about Metaverse music I think is so interesting in the
Speaker 3:  real world, there are only so many ways you can put on a concert or
Speaker 3:  music experience, big stage, lots of light a screen.
Speaker 3:  There's cool stuff you can do, but the boundaries are pretty clear
Speaker 3:  and pretty aggressive, especially when you have to tear the whole thing down
Speaker 3:  and do it again somewhere else the next day In digital spaces, you get to
Speaker 3:  kind of start over and rethink the whole idea,
Speaker 3:  but should you, We'll get to that in one second,
Speaker 3:  but first we're gonna take a quick break.
Speaker 3:  Welcome back. When you ask the question, what should a Metaverse
Speaker 3:  concert look like? The most important thing to know is that nobody
Speaker 3:  knows anything, and there's been a lot of experimenting over the last few
Speaker 3:  years. The DJ Marshmallow, who I think actually does get the
Speaker 3:  credit as the first Fortnight concert ever played a pretty
Speaker 3:  traditional looking concert. Yo,
Speaker 7:  What is up Fortnite? What's up? Pleasant part. My name is
Speaker 7:  Marshmallows.
Speaker 3:  There were some animated dancers on top of the stage, but it was still a
Speaker 3:  stage and some lights and some screens. Though I guess in the audience you
Speaker 3:  could fly during the concert, so that was definitely new. I
Speaker 7:  Want everybody to fly with me right now. Who's ready to fly? Let's go.
Speaker 3:  Last year, lil Nas X played a concert in Roblox that was a lot like the
Speaker 3:  Travis Scott show, a big cowboy hat wearing lil Nas dancing
Speaker 3:  around lots of different backgrounds.
Speaker 6:  21
Speaker 3:  Pilots did one that I thought was particularly cool. They had this Choose
Speaker 3:  your own Adventure concert and the crowd would vote after each song to
Speaker 3:  decide what they heard next, and
Speaker 8:  This next song is called The Outside.
Speaker 3:  There was also a cool Phoebe Bridgers concert in Minecraft where
Speaker 3:  she showed up playing on an old CRT TV while her blocky avatar
Speaker 3:  ran around the virtual stage
Speaker 9:  From Got Bored.
Speaker 3:  All of these, again sound sort of ridiculous to hear, but they're fun. They
Speaker 3:  work, they feel like concerts.
Speaker 3:  A couple of weeks ago, the Chainsmokers did a concert in Roblox that was
Speaker 3:  one of the platform's more epic productions.
Speaker 3:  The shtick of the event was that the Chainsmokers were on a plane late to
Speaker 3:  a music festival and all of a sudden the plane flew into a vortex at the
Speaker 3:  Bermuda Triangle. Somehow this leads to deciding the best idea
Speaker 3:  is just to have a concert on the wing of a plane instead, which
Speaker 3:  you know, sure, they played for about 20 minutes. Again, also going
Speaker 3:  underwater and through a city and all over the place.
Speaker 3:  The dominant aesthetic of these shows, I would say is larger
Speaker 3:  than life avatars playing in slightly other worldly places
Speaker 3:  while dozens or hundreds or thousands of game avatars
Speaker 3:  bounce and fly around. The bouncing is always my
Speaker 3:  favorite part.
Speaker 10:  All everybody,
Speaker 3:  It's like one giant mosh pit, everybody just jumping on each other's heads,
Speaker 3:  but without all the bruises and torn clothes back
Speaker 11:  Home to you
Speaker 3:  Often there's also some kind of mini game you can play during the concert
Speaker 3:  or some item to collect or some related fun thing
Speaker 3:  to do while the music plays. But like I said, this is all still
Speaker 3:  really early and most of the Metaverse concerts we've seen have been
Speaker 3:  huge, complicated one off productions. It's like making a
Speaker 3:  massively complicated music video or like a video game every time
Speaker 3:  you want to do anything, which just won't be possible for most artists. So
Speaker 3:  how do you make Metaverse music that scales? That's one thing I talked a
Speaker 3:  lot about with Connell Burn, the CEO of iHeart Media's digital audio group.
Speaker 12:  Anywhere we can show up as a widely distributed audio company that is
Speaker 12:  digital, that is my purview.
Speaker 3:  IHeart is this radio giant. They've made some big moves
Speaker 3:  into podcasting and music streaming over the last few years and
Speaker 3:  recently went kind of all in on the Metaverse Con told me he's
Speaker 3:  convinced that there's something big going on here, but he sees the space
Speaker 3:  a little differently than some others.
Speaker 12:  We don't think actually that at least right now, the
Speaker 12:  event Travis Scott type avatar driven
Speaker 12:  concerts are scalable. I think anyone would agree with that. That's
Speaker 12:  okay. By the way, if it's a one off, I think it's a little can be
Speaker 12:  a little confusing to fans on that platform. That's not
Speaker 12:  what we wanted to do. We wanted to build a place that was predictable,
Speaker 12:  natively integrated into the platform you were on, and a place like
Speaker 12:  you felt like was persistent. You could come back every day or once a month.
Speaker 12:  It's up to you trying to land somewhere in that spectrum.
Speaker 3:  IHeart recently opened a concert venue called iHeart Land in both
Speaker 3:  Fortnite and Roblox. They have events planned over the next year
Speaker 3:  and it actually looks like a concert venue sort of
Speaker 3:  In Fortnite for instance. It's an island, a heart shaped one, obviously with
Speaker 3:  a complex of buildings on it. Right in the middle there's a big stage with
Speaker 3:  a big Red State Farm logo on top of it because the whole thing is sponsored
Speaker 3:  by State Farm and there's a sort of complex around the stage with
Speaker 3:  four buildings that each have a mini game inside. There's one called Speed
Speaker 3:  of Sound, one called Leap of Faith. The games all sound and play
Speaker 3:  pretty much exactly like fall guys. There are a bunch of other
Speaker 3:  buildings around that are mostly just for show and apparently for some hardcore
Speaker 3:  game that's coming later off to one side. There's a dedicated
Speaker 3:  screenshot area, which is like a red carpet with lots of corporate logos
Speaker 3:  where you can take a picture of your avatar to say that you were there. But
Speaker 3:  obviously the stage is the thing. Here's how Atlas Creative, the company
Speaker 3:  that developed it for iHeart described the process in a YouTube video.
Speaker 13:  We started by making a massive frame for the video player that is big enough
Speaker 13:  to be seen across the island on top of the screen. We sculpted State Farm's
Speaker 13:  logo by kit bashing over 1000 different shapes together to form the letters.
Speaker 13:  This was a very difficult process, but it turned out amazing.
Speaker 3:  It all sounds very branded and it is, but so a real life
Speaker 3:  concerts, so I'll roll with it. The first concert at I Heartland was Charlie
Speaker 3:  Po and it was way less exciting than the Travis Scott show.
Speaker 3:  It happened a couple of weeks ago in Fortnite, and basically all that happened
Speaker 3:  was we stood there and bopped around as a pre-recorded Charlie
Speaker 3:  Poth concert played on the big screen.
Speaker 3:  You can see how this is way more repeatable. It's just a video file playing
Speaker 3:  on a screen inside of a game, but there are still some unique things about
Speaker 3:  it, as Con told me that he thinks make it feel like more than just a video.
Speaker 12:  So first of all, even in that 2D video, Charlie put is calling out the
Speaker 12:  Fortnite audience that he is playing to. Not a big thing, but that's a thing
Speaker 12:  he's aware of the platform he's on. The second thing is there's a bunch
Speaker 12:  of gameplay leading up to the actual concert itself. Trivia
Speaker 12:  with and by Charlie put himself, there is a bunch
Speaker 12:  of mini games that we've built in I Heartland and Fortnite. You'll see the
Speaker 12:  same in Roblox, that players are totally encouraged
Speaker 12:  to break away from the show and go, just do that if they want to. There
Speaker 12:  is a whole commerce of being able to collect and spend
Speaker 12:  currency soft, iHeart currency as you see fit. So it's this
Speaker 12:  blend of, okay, I'm here for what is a quote unquote traditional media
Speaker 12:  2D show, but you've clearly blended this a bunch with the platform
Speaker 12:  that you're on. That thoughtfulness was super important to us.
Speaker 3:  There are two things in there that I heard from a lot of people about music
Speaker 3:  in the Metaverse. One that it's really important that the artists
Speaker 3:  actually address and seem to understand where they are. It's like the
Speaker 3:  musicians who play a different city every night yelling, Hello Chicago, and
Speaker 3:  you see this a lot in the metaverse too. Artists saying, Hey, it's a Roblox,
Speaker 3:  or Fortnite or Minecraft,
Speaker 7:  IHeart Land. How are y'all feeling tonight? Yo, what is up
Speaker 7:  Fortnite? What's up Pleasant Park? What's up Roblox? What's up Roblox?
Speaker 7:  How you guys doing
Speaker 3:  Today? What's, and two, it's really important that there's more to do than
Speaker 3:  just the concert. Everybody is starting to develop mini games and build
Speaker 3:  side quests and give people things to do that feel native to the
Speaker 3:  platform that they're on. One underrated thing about a Metaverse concert,
Speaker 3:  and I know this sounds weird, is that the sound never gets worse.
Speaker 3:  You can run off to play a game or just go wander around for a bit and it's
Speaker 3:  still gonna sound like you're in the perfect position right between the speakers.
Speaker 3:  I heard a lot about skew morphism from the people I talked to about Metaverse
Speaker 3:  concerts. Skew morphism is basically the idea of taking something new
Speaker 3:  and recreating an old thing that feels familiar in the new space.
Speaker 3:  Computer desktops that looked like desks or the old Apple Notes app that
Speaker 3:  looked exactly like a yellow legal pad that's skew morphism, and right
Speaker 3:  now, sch morphism isn't actually a bad idea. Many people who come to
Speaker 3:  these concerts are new to the platforms that they're hosted on and often
Speaker 3:  new to the whole concept of the metaphors. So giving them a concert that
Speaker 3:  feels like a concert is a good idea and Roblox is K
Speaker 3:  told me. It kind of helps artists figure out what to do too, but
Speaker 3:  eventually you get to move on to the bigger, cooler, more
Speaker 3:  platform native stuff.
Speaker 5:  When you first introduce a concert into these environments, you want
Speaker 5:  the camera on the camera phone to make a shutter sound. Even though there's
Speaker 5:  no shutter in the digital camera, you're training people to
Speaker 5:  expect some aspects of what they've seen in real life or
Speaker 5:  what they've experienced in physical world. You're training them to experience
Speaker 5:  that in a digital sphere. But once people become accustomed to
Speaker 5:  what's possible in a Roblox concert, then we can
Speaker 5:  stretch what's possible in a Roblox concert. You can have it on the wing
Speaker 5:  of a plane or underwater, but there's Fire
Speaker 3:  IHeart's Tunnel burden was a little more conservative on the subject, but
Speaker 3:  I think feels kind of the same way.
Speaker 12:  We're trying to land in the middle of that spectrum where it's a
Speaker 12:  2D video on a large state farm park theater
Speaker 12:  screen, but it's also totally entrenched in all the
Speaker 12:  tropes and memes and gameplay of the platform that you're on as well.
Speaker 3:  One way I've come to think about this moment we're in is like the early
Speaker 3:  days of film. Back then a lot of movies were just filmed versions of
Speaker 3:  plays, but eventually everyone learned and developed a new
Speaker 3:  vocabulary, How things Cut, where people go, how cameras move,
Speaker 3:  all that kind of stuff. And I think we're gonna get the same thing here.
Speaker 3:  It'll be a real life concert in a digital space for a while
Speaker 3:  before we start to figure out what new and better things make sense
Speaker 3:  that never made sense or were even possible before. Maybe it's underwater
Speaker 3:  concerts, maybe it's mini games that move to the beat of the song. Maybe
Speaker 3:  it's something else we haven't even figured out yet. A big part of what's
Speaker 3:  left to figure out is how to make these things feel more like a
Speaker 3:  community and more interactive. The future of entertainment in general
Speaker 3:  is making the audience feel like they're part of the experience, not just
Speaker 3:  handed a finished product to look at. Some artists are hanging out in
Speaker 3:  digital platforms now doing live meet and greets through a computer. Others
Speaker 3:  are building permanent places for fans to just be together and talk to
Speaker 3:  each other and, oh God, there's merch everywhere. Everyone
Speaker 3:  involved is very excited about all the digital merch they're gonna try to
Speaker 3:  sell you. It's coming for you. I'm pretty skeptical of a lot of things
Speaker 3:  about the Metaverse and I definitely don't think I want to live my
Speaker 3:  whole life in a digital place, but there is something here, something that
Speaker 3:  feels exciting and immersive and big about bringing live
Speaker 3:  music to these digital spaces. I'd still rather go see my favorite
Speaker 3:  band's I l, but you know what? As of two weeks ago, I'd never seen
Speaker 3:  Charlie put live, and now I, along with millions of other people
Speaker 3:  have and I got to fly around and raise cars during the show.
Speaker 3:  Not a bad concert, you ask me.
Speaker 2:  That's
Speaker 3:  It for the Verge Cast. Thank you so much for listening. This is the last
Speaker 3:  in our three episode series about the future of music and I would love to
Speaker 3:  know what you think of the series. Send us an email at vergecast@theverge.com
Speaker 3:  or hit up the Vergecast hotline at 8 6 6 Verge one
Speaker 3:  one, and tell us all your thoughts on the future of music. The show is produced
Speaker 3:  by Andrew Marino and Liam James Nori Donovan is our executive producer
Speaker 3:  and Brook Mins is our editorial director of Audio. The Vergecast is a
Speaker 3:  verge production and part of the Fox Media Podcast network. If you have
Speaker 3:  thoughts, feedback, feelings, or want to meet me for a show in the Metaverse,
Speaker 3:  you can always email vergecast@theverge.com. We'll be back on Wednesday
Speaker 3:  and Friday with all kinds of tech news. See then rock and roll