# Transcript
ID: 58e161f0-3086-11ed-aead-ed7250182a0e
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Apple’s iPhone 14 event: the biggest announcements and our first impressions
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/5374532678525021052/-2862701319656645452/s93290-US-4573s-1662758816.mp3
Description: Apple held their annual hardware event on their campus, debuting new iPhones, new Watches, and new AirPods. Nilay Patel, David Pierce, and Alex Cranz discuss everything that happened at the "Far Out" event, first impressions of the products, and their expectations for Apple in the next year.
Speaker 1:  Today on the verge cast, the whole team does a deep dive on Bo's new,
Speaker 1:  quiet comfort earbuds too. I'm just kidding. We're gonna talk
Speaker 1:  about apple the whole time. Everything that was announced and our first impressions
Speaker 1:  that's coming up right after this
Speaker 1:  with no fees or minimums banking with capital one is the easiest
Speaker 1:  decision in the history of decisions. Even easier than deciding to listen
Speaker 1:  to another episode of your favorite podcast with no overdraft fees.
Speaker 1:  Is it even a decision that's banking reimagine what's in your wallet
Speaker 1:  term supply. See capital one.com/bank capital one, a
Speaker 1:  member FDIC,
Speaker 3:  Teens use Instagram to explore and connect. That's why we
Speaker 3:  build features that can help teens see less sensitive content
Speaker 3:  interact in positive ways and spend time on Instagram, intentionally,
Speaker 3:  and tools that help parents support them in building a safe Instagram
Speaker 3:  experience because we're committed to building a community where everyone
Speaker 3:  feels supported. Explore more than 30 tools that can help teens
Speaker 3:  have a positive experience on Instagram at
Speaker 3:  instagram.com/safety.
Speaker 4:  Good morning. Hello.
Speaker 5:  Welcome to the flagship podcast crash
Speaker 5:  detection, which you need, or no one will know that you've been in a car
Speaker 6:  Crash or a plane crash, a boat crash.
Speaker 5:  I'm Nelia I'm your friend. David Pierce is here.
Speaker 7:  Hi. I am in our San Francisco office where I have been since
Speaker 7:  like 11 days ago. That's I live here now. Oh,
Speaker 5:  Don't even complain about being in one place for a long time. Alex
Speaker 5:  Crans is here.
Speaker 6:  I have not left my house in two months.
Speaker 5:  Very jealous. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Neely. Can you just run us through your travel schedule for the last like
Speaker 7:  96 hours? I just find it deeply hilarious. And I'd like you to tell everybody
Speaker 5:  One thing I don't recommend is being at lax three times in three days.
Speaker 5:  No, I was like, ah, I just live at lax. Now. This is where I'm at. I know
Speaker 5:  all the people I like said load the concession stand version. It
Speaker 5:  was great. So I have had five flights in seven days, basically. Oof.
Speaker 5:  So I flew home to do a panel with the Mount
Speaker 5:  pleasant community group, a better Mount pleasant about Foxcon. That was
Speaker 5:  really fun. It was great to be home. My dad was there. Nerve-wracking then
Speaker 5:  I flew to LA for the first day of the code conference. Then I went
Speaker 5:  to San Francisco for apple. Then I flew back to LA the next day.
Speaker 5:  And then a day later I flew home. So it's just been a ride. I was
Speaker 5:  at the point where I left some clothes in a hotel room because I knew I was
Speaker 5:  gonna come back to the hotel room and I was like, I just live here. Now
Speaker 7:  You had two simultaneous hotel rooms in two different
Speaker 5:  Cities. S that's. I was like, I don't even
Speaker 5:  know what's going on in my life, but it's great. The joke I made to David
Speaker 5:  was like, I think people think that's what my job is always like, so I
Speaker 5:  can't complain too much to be like, I'm chasing Tim cook around the state
Speaker 5:  of California. Like it was great. It was fun. It was exciting. Code
Speaker 5:  was great. The apple event was fun. We're gonna talk about all of those things.
Speaker 5:  Really. This is gonna be an apple themed version,
Speaker 5:  cuz it many things happened with apple this last week, iPhone
Speaker 5:  14 event, there was the new iPhone 14, which is really the iPhone 13
Speaker 5:  iPhone 14 plus the pro models pro max, lots of
Speaker 5:  camera stuff, apple watch series eight, apple watch ultra.
Speaker 5:  I mean there's there a lot going on new AirPods, near AirPods pro and then
Speaker 5:  that evening we all went on separate planes.
Speaker 5:  I will hasten to add to the co conference where Tim cook spoke on
Speaker 5:  a panel with Johnny ive and Lauren Powell jobs with the legacy of two jobs
Speaker 5:  with the care SU Fisher, which was incredible in many ways. So just a lot
Speaker 5:  going on in that day, but a ton of news just from the apple event, let's
Speaker 5:  start there. Do you wanna start with, we should start with the phones. So
Speaker 8:  Let's take a look at the new iPhone.
Speaker 7:  So the basic rundown is there's four phones. There's the iPhone 14,
Speaker 7:  which like you said is basically the iPhone 13. There's the iPhone 14 plus,
Speaker 7:  which is the exact same thing as the iPhone 14, but instead of a 6.1 inch
Speaker 7:  screen, it has a 6.7 inch screen. And then there's the iPhone pro and
Speaker 7:  Promax, which have all kinds of interesting stuff in them.
Speaker 5:  The dynamic island. Yes.
Speaker 9:  So now when you receive an alert, the dynamic island expands to
Speaker 9:  notify
Speaker 7:  You. So I tweeted yesterday on Thursday saying the Vergecast is
Speaker 7:  gonna be a little late. And also if you have any questions that you, if like
Speaker 7:  anything you want us to talk about on the Vergecast let me know. And solidly
Speaker 7:  half of the responses I got were basically to the tune of like, are we really
Speaker 7:  gonna let them get away with calling it the dynamic island? Like we're just
Speaker 7:  gonna do this.
Speaker 5:  So they they're already running the ads. I watched the bills Rams game last
Speaker 5:  night. And like every other ad was a dynamic island ad.
Speaker 6:  What, what would they call it though? But if they didn't call it that just
Speaker 6:  a toggle switch,
Speaker 7:  Anything else?
Speaker 5:  So I think the name is great. I've come around on the fact that like, if
Speaker 5:  you were a company, the size of apple, apple has been very
Speaker 5:  conservative recently, right? Like it's, I mean, it's a huge company,
Speaker 5:  global scale politics, regulators, data
Speaker 5:  centers, and like they're cons. They are now just because of who they are.
Speaker 5:  They're a conservative company, right? Every now and again, apple is the
Speaker 5:  only company of that scale. That's like dynamic island. Let's do it. I
Speaker 6:  Mean, there's like a history of really stupid names for really cool
Speaker 6:  user interfaces, right? Like there's the hamburger, there's the
Speaker 6:  meatballs
Speaker 5:  Straight up. We call it a mess. Everyone all day long is like, let me get
Speaker 5:  my mouse and wait, just let that slide. I don't know. The dynamic island
Speaker 5:  is gonna stay.
Speaker 6:  It'll just be island.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Look, I think it's a fun name. They had to call it something. Do
Speaker 7:  You think there was a meeting at apple where somebody was like, what if we
Speaker 7:  call it the touch bar? That's basically what it is. Right? And then like
Speaker 7:  somebody from the Mac team just came sprinting into the room. It's like,
Speaker 7:  no, we can't do that. It's not allowed.
Speaker 5:  I think what will almost certainly end up happening is that diehard Mac fans
Speaker 5:  will call it the dynamic island. And then the billions upon billions of people
Speaker 5:  who buy the phone will like emergent behavior, some other name for it. And
Speaker 5:  that will be the name that everyone calls it. And then we'll be, our comments
Speaker 5:  will be full of pedantic arguments about actually calling it pedantic or
Speaker 5:  actually calling it the dynamic island or not trust me, like I live through
Speaker 5:  the OSX wars. Yeah. And like, it's gonna be bad. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It's not gonna be great.
Speaker 7:  The technology of it is super cool though. It's super cool technology.
Speaker 5:  So that's where I'm like of both minds. Really. So the basic idea, right?
Speaker 5:  So they, they moved the notch down to a pill. It's the camera,
Speaker 5:  the true F sensor, the proximity sensor. They're actually two different spots.
Speaker 5:  So there's screening above them. So there's no more notch and there's screen
Speaker 5:  in between them and what the island does. Is it just like blacks out
Speaker 5:  more of that area to put indicators to the left and
Speaker 5:  right. Of the, of the pill shaped notches. Yeah. Yeah. Cutouts.
Speaker 5:  It's great. And so that part is interesting. Right? You're gonna take this
Speaker 5:  thing where the screen, where the screen is always blacked out and you're
Speaker 5:  actually gonna lean into it and black out more of the screen. Yeah. Cool.
Speaker 5:  Like very few companies will do that. Very few companies will tell their
Speaker 5:  developers to support such a thing and actually get their developers, do
Speaker 5:  it very apple in that way. You know, someone spent hours upon hours
Speaker 5:  doing the little bounce animations and they look great. But like
Speaker 5:  in use, David used it as well, too. The right. Really what you're getting
Speaker 5:  is like, when you place some music, you get music indicators. When you have
Speaker 5:  a timer going, you get timer indicators. The voice memo was one is really
Speaker 5:  cool. Like legitimately my favorite, one of the thing, cuz you get the little,
Speaker 5:  you get the little sound waves. Yeah. A love of sound waves. They showed
Speaker 5:  a bunch of other stuff, right? Lyft, like if you call a lift, it'll tell
Speaker 5:  you how long the lift will be. You get your sports scores, sports scores.
Speaker 5:  So they're all connected to the, the phone's widget system. So the
Speaker 5:  kind of like the way I have been thinking about this or these are like minimized
Speaker 5:  widgets.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. That's basically right. Are we
Speaker 5:  Gonna call 'em widgets? The widget? Yeah. The widget notch
Speaker 5:  notch. Which
Speaker 7:  Notch? Which there it is. We got it in one. But wait, you,
Speaker 7:  you say that you say that like it's a bad thing. That feels like a good thing,
Speaker 5:  But it's like, how many widgets do you want to minimize? Yeah. And
Speaker 5:  I was, I've been making the list in my head and it's like actually vanishingly
Speaker 5:  few. Oh
Speaker 7:  That's interesting. I feel exactly the opposite. I really like, there are
Speaker 7:  so many things that my phone
Speaker 7:  knows that I wish it had quicker ways to tell me. Right. One of them
Speaker 7:  is like, is my alarm set? This is like a spoiler alert for the
Speaker 7:  iOS 16 review that I'm writing for next week. Is that like, there's
Speaker 7:  just a ton of things that apple used to require you. It's like, if I want
Speaker 7:  to know if I, one easy example I always give is like, if you're a person
Speaker 7:  who uses like a habit tracker app and you open up the app every time you
Speaker 7:  wanna like log that you a glass of water. Right. That's too many steps.
Speaker 7:  And so for little things like that, or like who won the Yankee
Speaker 7:  game, like apple is like slowly pulling that out of apps and into like
Speaker 7:  the front of the phone and with iOS 16 on the lock screen, it's
Speaker 7:  pulling all that stuff even further to the front of the phone. And I feel
Speaker 7:  like the dynamic island is the kind of thing where it's just like, now it's
Speaker 7:  even more there. And for me there's like the question of, am I gonna wanna
Speaker 7:  see these things like 24 hours a day? I don't know.
Speaker 7:  And do I wanna see a tiny moving wave form all the time. I'm listening to
Speaker 7:  music. I also don't know, but there is a lot of like little tiny bits of
Speaker 7:  information that I'd like to have throughout the day that feel like they
Speaker 7:  fit there perfectly.
Speaker 6:  They're super contextual. Right? Cause like, I, I haven't gotten to play
Speaker 6:  with them. I've only seen like y'all's videos and the videos that apple
Speaker 6:  played, but they're contextual. So it's not like that waveform for the music
Speaker 6:  is always there. You still have to like interact to make it happen.
Speaker 5:  No. And there's a little bit of a delay. So if you open the music app and
Speaker 5:  stop the music and then go at the island is there and then it shrinks back
Speaker 5:  down to the notch
Speaker 6:  Like island get outta here. What are you doing?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. You can't. So like actually to David's point, like one of the things
Speaker 5:  that surprised me about it is it's the sort of like
Speaker 5:  user flow of it is more complicated than you would expect.
Speaker 5:  Yes. And I think in one particular way backwards, just having used, I
Speaker 5:  mean, we haven't gotten, we gotta like review the phone. Right. But so to,
Speaker 5:  to get it, you've gotta like open an app and do something. Right. You gotta
Speaker 5:  like start playing music. You gotta set a timer. Now you could do that from
Speaker 5:  like maybe a lock screen widget or something else or from Siri, but you gotta
Speaker 5:  like do something and like mostly you're gonna do it.
Speaker 5:  You're gonna open it up and do something. Yeah. Right. So then you close
Speaker 5:  the app and the thing flies into the widget. If you've got two things going
Speaker 5:  at once, there's a cool animation. The island breaks actually into two islands.
Speaker 5:  They haven't addressed that naming wise. It's
Speaker 7:  The archipelago.
Speaker 5:  That's great. So like you, but you gotta like do stuff. Right. And then
Speaker 5:  here's the thing. If you watch the ads, you watch the video, this is the
Speaker 5:  thing that really trip me up. You would think that if you tap on the island,
Speaker 5:  it opens the widget. Yes. Right? That is not the case. When you tap on it,
Speaker 5:  it opens the app. No. And when you, if you want the widget, you gotta
Speaker 5:  hold down. And that to me is totally backwards.
Speaker 7:  I've come around to your side of this. When you first mentioned that as we
Speaker 7:  were standing there at the hands on, like the second you touched it, that
Speaker 7:  was your instinct. And I didn't necessarily agree cuz like, as it
Speaker 7:  is with widgets, you hit, you tap the widget and it opens the app. So on
Speaker 7:  the one hand you would think that's expected behavior, but like it does,
Speaker 7:  it breaks the exact flow you're talking about. It should go like island to
Speaker 7:  widget, to app. And instead you have to like long press. I think, I think
Speaker 7:  you're totally right. And I bet apple changes
Speaker 5:  That. Yeah. It just seems, it seems totally backwards to
Speaker 6:  Me. Like when I press it, I expect it to have a quick contextual thing.
Speaker 6:  So I can do my thing without having to wait for the whole animation.
Speaker 7:  Right. I wanna pause the music.
Speaker 5:  I would just say that if you have the functional equivalent of a right
Speaker 5:  click in your ads, you should rethink that. Right?
Speaker 5:  Like that's what a long press on a phone is. It's a right click. Yeah. Right.
Speaker 5:  And it's undiscoverable by most people like a year from now,
Speaker 5:  someone's gonna make a TikTok video. That's like top 10 feature of the iPhone
Speaker 5:  you didn't know about. And they're gonna be like, did you know? You could
Speaker 5:  long press and the camera to open more. And it's like, they're gonna get
Speaker 5:  a million views. That's ideas for free. Just start making that video now
Speaker 5:  TikTok
Speaker 7:  And run it in one year.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Just like book it. Right. You wanna avoid burnout? You book your
Speaker 5:  content now. So like that's that flow is just
Speaker 5:  messy to me and I'm sure they'll tweak it. Or maybe they'll give you a switch.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. There's a million ways to solve. It's not like a deal breaker by any
Speaker 5:  sense. But the earlier part of the flow where you gotta go do something to
Speaker 5:  get it. Like David, what you're talking about is like, there's a bunch of
Speaker 5:  apps on my phone where I just want them to kind of like flow data to me.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Or like give me a control for the one thing. And control center does
Speaker 5:  that for some of those apps, doesn't do it for other apps, lock screen, widgets,
Speaker 5:  do it for some apps, not for other apps. And now you just have like 10 ways
Speaker 5:  to do that thing. Then it just, the island
Speaker 5:  creates another. But there's no like send this to the island,
Speaker 5:  but
Speaker 7:  That's true. There's no like step one island move. You can do you
Speaker 7:  have to like do the stuff and then leave
Speaker 6:  What would be a step one island? Because like, it makes sense to me that
Speaker 6:  I have to open the music app or the voice memo app. It looks like
Speaker 6:  the, the phone call one just pops up when you get a phone call.
Speaker 6:  And that makes sense. But like where are those cases? You want it to pop
Speaker 6:  up without
Speaker 5:  Interacting? Well, I think those are in apps. Like I'm not playing fantasy
Speaker 5:  football this year. I believe David is with our staff, which is gonna cause
Speaker 5:  a whole mutiny. But fantasy football happens on Sunday.
Speaker 5:  Like those apps should just start on Sunday afternoon and
Speaker 5:  populate the island and tell you how that's going. And like maybe that's
Speaker 5:  to come. I think that would be a great feature to build. And just right now,
Speaker 5:  like, you know, the, what the ad and the video promises you
Speaker 5:  is like this like constant animation of activity
Speaker 5:  and at least so far as we've used it, you gotta like do stuff
Speaker 7:  First. Yeah. Well, and there, there is like what, what you just described
Speaker 7:  is in an interesting way, like a low touch notification system,
Speaker 7:  which I could actually kind of get behind. It's like, what if your
Speaker 7:  dynamic island was like the ticker at the bottom of a news TV show?
Speaker 7:  Like, I don't know if that's a good idea or a terrible idea, but it's like,
Speaker 7:  there's a version of this that turns into something like that. And I think,
Speaker 7:  but
Speaker 6:  Isn't that a notification? Well,
Speaker 7:  That's what I mean. Right. But like, what if it didn't like buzz your phone
Speaker 7:  or come up over top of what you were already doing. It just sort of like
Speaker 7:  appears in there that it's like, what if it just says like touchdown and
Speaker 7:  then goes away? That's all I,
Speaker 5:  Yeah, there's just an, like we have to get it. We have to use it. We have
Speaker 5:  to feel it out. I'm basing this off of 45 frenzied minutes of hands on time
Speaker 5:  and a handful of conversations. But it's rare that there's any
Speaker 5:  distance between apple showing software and an ad and then what it is. And
Speaker 5:  here, there just felt like a lot of distance actually. Yeah. Cause they keep
Speaker 5:  showing you the expanded widget view in those ads. Yeah. And that you actually
Speaker 5:  have to know how to get those. Right. And like that to me is the first one
Speaker 5:  is like, if you're gonna show people that expanded view, it should be really
Speaker 5:  easy to get those because that's like the promise of the whole thing
Speaker 5:  is you, you kind of get these like that area, like minimized,
Speaker 5:  widgets, that area populates itself automatically with useful minimized
Speaker 5:  widgets that quickly get you to controls. But right now you tap on you just
Speaker 5:  like bomb into the app.
Speaker 6:  How excited were people at Steve do theater
Speaker 6:  about the dynamic island? Because I at home was very excited. That was the
Speaker 6:  thing people called me and were like, what phone should I get? And I was
Speaker 6:  like, get this one. Cause you get the dynamic island. And they're like, why,
Speaker 6:  why do I, what are you talking about, Alex? I'm hanging up now. Were people
Speaker 6:  excited?
Speaker 5:  I mean, there was a room full of like press people and YouTubers. Like of
Speaker 5:  course we are all excited. We're like, this is the thing we have to point
Speaker 5:  a camera.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. But I think it's like when you're in that room, everybody has the,
Speaker 6:  some feature that they're like, okay, I gotta go check out the camera. Or
Speaker 6:  like the year was slow motion camera. Everybody was like, oh,
Speaker 5:  So the, the fight here was the, the island and the apple watch ultra
Speaker 5:  and like the poor iPhone 14, the, the people
Speaker 5:  tasked with like showing off the iPhone 14 were like, would you wanna see
Speaker 5:  this one? So
Speaker 6:  13? And everyone's like, but with a new name
Speaker 5:  And they're like, this one, it comes in a slightly different color. And everyone's
Speaker 5:  like, I took one picture. I'm good. Like moving on. But
Speaker 7:  I do think there was something to actually like touching the thing
Speaker 7:  in a, in a funny way, cuz it's like, it makes for a great onscreen
Speaker 7:  demo cuz and, and like apple immediately got a bunch of credit from people
Speaker 7:  for like leaning into the notch. And I think it's like sort of
Speaker 7:  funny that apple is getting credit for that now because apple has always
Speaker 7:  done that. Like disagree when, when the notch first came out, apple made
Speaker 7:  all this noise to developers who were using the full
Speaker 7:  frame screen in their screenshots. And apple was like, absolutely not. The
Speaker 7:  notch has to be everywhere. Like normalized. The notch was like Apple's
Speaker 7:  thing for a long time. Apple
Speaker 6:  Was really bad about pushing like their own
Speaker 6:  software design was often scared of the notch. Right? Like, like,
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Oh, that's definitely true. And it largely tried to pretend it didn't
Speaker 7:  exist, but like,
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I think they were really messy with the notch for years. And this is
Speaker 6:  like, I think the software choice they made here was really smart and
Speaker 6:  good. Even if some elements of it like having to long
Speaker 6:  press to open it is really stupid.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. No, I think that's right. And to turn it into software was very clever.
Speaker 7:  I think I, I totally agree with
Speaker 6:  That. Yeah. Like, like that was like, oh wow, Apple's doing it right.
Speaker 7:  It just feels nifty. Like there was just something about you just, you just
Speaker 7:  press on the thing and it like bubbles around, it feels alive in a very cool
Speaker 7:  way.
Speaker 6:  Like you made an Instagram video and I kept watching it while I was working
Speaker 6:  on my dynamic island piece. Just the clip of like the island
Speaker 6:  itself. I was just like, this is just neat. Like that just looks fun.
Speaker 7:  It is. And I think like, I, I just love this thing that apple is doing where
Speaker 7:  it's like, what if your phone, wasn't just like a large collection of apps
Speaker 7:  on a home screen that you do things with. So like anything that feels
Speaker 7:  livelier than that makes me very happy. And this is like, like I, I agree
Speaker 7:  with ni that there's gonna be a bunch of decisions developers have to make.
Speaker 7:  And I've talked to a couple of developers in the last few days who are very
Speaker 7:  confused about what they're going to do in their apps with this stuff,
Speaker 7:  because there's a lot of things you can do and like no expected behavior
Speaker 7:  for it. So folks are gonna take a while to figure this out, but I think it's
Speaker 7:  gonna be the kind of space people are gonna play with.
Speaker 6:  Do you use this in a weather app and like carrot right now will send you
Speaker 6:  a notification if it's about to rain. Is that gonna now pop up on
Speaker 6:  the, the dynamic island? The notch?
Speaker 5:  I think the answer is no, I think those are still notifications. Like again,
Speaker 5:  I think the way to think about this stuff right now is minimized widgets.
Speaker 6:  I think widgets are themselves kind of notifications, right? Like, like
Speaker 6:  Apple's been using notifications as widgets to some extent for a long
Speaker 6:  time. And then they just keep like changing the name of
Speaker 6:  notifications and tweaking the functionality to be like, here's a new, fresh
Speaker 6:  type of notification. It's called widget. Here's a newer, fresher type of
Speaker 6:  notification. It's called the dynamic island.
Speaker 7:  Well, yeah, this is where like live activities figures in too, cuz it's all,
Speaker 7:  there's now this like wild spectrum of rectangles. You can put on your
Speaker 7:  phone and they all do slightly different versions of sort of the same thing.
Speaker 5:  So as you've been playing with Iowa 16, that seems like the most important
Speaker 5:  new part of the whole operating system
Speaker 7:  Live activities.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So that's the new kind of widget where if you are following
Speaker 5:  sports on ESPN, it'll like live, populate the score. Yep.
Speaker 5:  That to me is like ages ago, Josh Polski wrote in Apple's world.
Speaker 5:  It's always 72 and sunny because the weather app, wouldn't just tell you
Speaker 5:  the temperature. And it's like, they finally got all the way there. Right?
Speaker 5:  They like finally got all the way to apps can actually write to the screen
Speaker 5:  in these things called live activity, widgets
Speaker 7:  Almost all the way there. They're still slightly afraid of their developers
Speaker 7:  in that sense. But it's, it's, it's pretty close. And I think it's a huge,
Speaker 7:  huge, I mean the thing that you can't interact with widgets still
Speaker 7:  drives me insane. Right? Like widgets are still functionally like app shortcuts.
Speaker 7:  So that to me is like the last real thing that I want where it's like,
Speaker 7:  it can write to the icon, but I can't talk back to it without opening the
Speaker 7:  app. That's the one move apple still has not made. And
Speaker 7:  dynamic island stuff seems like it could have done more of that
Speaker 7:  too. And instead they're just like, even they still want you to go to the
Speaker 7:  app. Like part of me wonders how much of this is that like apple knows
Speaker 7:  developers want you to open their app. And so apple is petrified of anything
Speaker 7:  that is going to like meaningfully depreciate. The amount of time people
Speaker 7:  spend opening apps.
Speaker 5:  Oh interesting. Yeah. We'll see, like we gotta get the thing again.
Speaker 5:  We're basing this off of a vanishingly small amount of time. And by the way,
Speaker 5:  this event was wild first event in the Steve jobs theater in three years,
Speaker 5:  we were still watching a video, which was weird. I think it's time to let
Speaker 5:  that go. Apple loves it. Cuz the video streams and it travels and people
Speaker 5:  cut it up and like if you're playing to the internet, it's better, but there's
Speaker 5:  still something lost. It's also way harder to life log a video.
Speaker 7:  It just moves so fast.
Speaker 5:  No one ever takes a breath. Yeah. They should just put like breaths and applause
Speaker 5:  breaks and time for people to walk on and off the stage, back in the video,
Speaker 5:  maybe I'll be happy. It doesn't matter. We're there for the hands on. We're
Speaker 5:  there to talk to people. But it was, it was just the, you know, full theater,
Speaker 5:  the big crowded rush in the room, everyone running around
Speaker 5:  that part of it was great.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, it was. And it was the, like the energy was super high. And we talked
Speaker 7:  about this at, at WWDC too. There is just like, again, it's a very self-selecting
Speaker 7:  group of people who come to these things. So it's like people who are predisposed
Speaker 7:  to be excited about new technology, I would say. But yeah, there was still
Speaker 7:  this like first day of school energy again where it's like, people are
Speaker 7:  just like pumped to be back excited to be able to like see things and try
Speaker 7:  them and run around and talk to people. And folks are folks who are amped
Speaker 7:  to be back doing this kind of stuff, which was, which was very fun.
Speaker 5:  We've done like 25 minutes on the island.
Speaker 7:  I'm good with that. That feels right. Right. Like the iPhone 14, it's an
Speaker 7:  iPhone. The end. Let's talk more about the dynamic island. Well
Speaker 5:  The, the dynamic island is connect to the rest of the iPhone 14 pro of which
Speaker 5:  the two other notable features are the always on display, which
Speaker 5:  welcome apple, you know, apple claims, you know that
Speaker 5:  they did a lot of work, that they got the refresh rate down to one Hertz.
Speaker 5:  They have a new kind of L PTO O led display that
Speaker 5:  allows lower power. They could have done it before. They're waiting to invent
Speaker 5:  the things they needed to invent. You can just believe whatever. Well, you
Speaker 5:  just take whatever you want out of that and believe what you need to believe
Speaker 5:  to make this okay. But they're they finally have shifted and always on display
Speaker 5:  it. Doesn't, it's strange. Like it's more widgets, right?
Speaker 5:  Like why is the display always honest to show you more widgets and
Speaker 5:  show you more status information. They do really cool things with it. Here's
Speaker 5:  my favorite one. So when the display goes to, it's like low power state,
Speaker 5:  you know, in Iowa 16, they're doing the cool thing where the, they can cut
Speaker 5:  out faces and put them over the clock. When they go to the low power
Speaker 5:  mode, they reverse it. So the clock fades up over the face. And then when
Speaker 5:  you tap on the screen goes, the face comes back in front of it. It's neat.
Speaker 5:  That's
Speaker 7:  Cool.
Speaker 5:  They're doing all this like image management stuff for the wallpapers.
Speaker 5:  So when it goes into that super dim, low power mode, they actually preserve
Speaker 5:  skin tones and colors in, in different ways. So like they're doing a bunch
Speaker 5:  of apple stuff, you know, that maybe other companies are doing too. And just
Speaker 5:  don't talk about as reverently as apple talks about, but they're doing a
Speaker 5:  bunch of apple stuff,
Speaker 6:  But how long has it been since Samsung? Didn't always on
Speaker 6:  display five years,
Speaker 7:  Maybe longer. Like it's, they've had Android phones have had this forever.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Yeah. Cuz you, if you have an Oola display, you can just like cut the
Speaker 5:  power and the pixels stay static, but Apple's doing it with like some amount
Speaker 5:  of color. Like I think the very first, always on Oola displays actually went
Speaker 5:  to black and white, right.
Speaker 6:  The date and the time that's
Speaker 5:  It? Yeah. So app Apple's doing far more than that. So I think they, they
Speaker 5:  waited to some extent to just like do far more than that, but really you
Speaker 5:  tap on the thing, the display lights all the way up and you get it's interactive
Speaker 5:  again. If it's in your pocket or upside down, it goes totally off.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. They do seem to be really leaning into the idea that if you don't wanna
Speaker 7:  look at your phone, flip it over that that is like a, an unexpected societal
Speaker 7:  behavior. Now that it's like your phone is going to sort of always be staring
Speaker 7:  at you and if you don't want that, put it away. Which I very
Speaker 7:  much appreciate like as a, as a flip the phone over on the table person,
Speaker 7:  I very much appreciate that.
Speaker 6:  It kind of reminds me of, did you guys watch Halton catch fire,
Speaker 6:  best show ever made. And there's this whole thing where one of 'em becomes
Speaker 6:  a VC. Whenever she sits down, she has one of those leg, Jager lake tray
Speaker 6:  watches that like just flips over. And when she flips it over, she's like,
Speaker 6:  I will listen now because I'm not paying attention to the time. It's
Speaker 7:  Like, oh, okay. Now I care about you.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. It was the best thing in the world. And Apple's like, we see this,
Speaker 6:  we love it. You can do this too. Everyone should have this power move.
Speaker 6:  Just be like, now I care about you. I flipped my phone over.
Speaker 5:  Okay. So that's always on display. We should talk about the camera,
Speaker 10:  A 48 mega pixel camera with a quad pixel
Speaker 10:  sensor features our second generation sensor shift OIS
Speaker 10:  and 100%
Speaker 7:  Focus pixels.
Speaker 5:  The camera's pretty interesting. And then in some ways like, right,
Speaker 5:  it's still gonna deliver you 12 mega pixel photos. So it's a 48
Speaker 5:  megapixel sensor in the pro they're pixel bidding it in standard
Speaker 5:  mode. So you, you know, they're gonna use four pixels
Speaker 5:  to generate one. Can you
Speaker 7:  Explain what pixel bidding is? It's one of those things that I like, I'm
Speaker 7:  like 35% sure. I understand what pixel bidding is. Can you explain what pixel
Speaker 7:  bidding is?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So you've got 48. I mean imagine a grid. The actually
Speaker 5:  the pixel pattern on this is probably not a grid. They said they have a new
Speaker 5:  pixel pattern on the sensor and they had to like tweak their algorithms.
Speaker 5:  So I don't know what the pattern is, but just for the purposes of this, imagine
Speaker 5:  a grid. And so what you could do is use every single pixel
Speaker 5:  as a pixel represented in a photo and you can do that
Speaker 5:  in pro and you generate a 57 megabyte follow
Speaker 7:  Per,
Speaker 5:  So you can all the data back out of the thing. Wow. That's not useful
Speaker 5:  for most people, especially at those file sizes. And
Speaker 5:  most people sharing Instagram anyway. So what apple and everyone else with
Speaker 5:  big sensors do is actually say, we're gonna use four of those
Speaker 5:  pixels to collect all the light we can and then sample them down
Speaker 5:  to one pixel. So you've been the pixel and that's how you end up with a 12
Speaker 5:  megapixel photo out of 48 megapixel sensor.
Speaker 6:  So it's not just cropping, like when you're using a
Speaker 6:  DSLR.
Speaker 5:  Well ho hold on your friend.
Speaker 5:  So like that's the standard wide camera mode, right?
Speaker 5:  So, you know, on the iPhone 14, they say they they've made the pixels on
Speaker 5:  the 12 mega pixel sensor, slightly bigger to collect more light. At some
Speaker 5:  point you just like run into the limit of doing that at scale. And it's better
Speaker 5:  to just have more individual pixels and sample and combine them to get more
Speaker 5:  light. Fair enough. Cool. So that's like the standard wide camera, one X
Speaker 5:  mode then Alex, the two X mode, they are
Speaker 5:  cropping the sensor. And they're saying, because the sensor's so big
Speaker 5:  that at the crop, it's still a true two X zoom,
Speaker 5:  which is a huge claim.
Speaker 7:  Yes. Yeah. Do we buy that? I feel like I am trained to think that's just
Speaker 7:  cropping.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Our video producer here and was like outside and like I heard him
Speaker 5:  like hiss when they said this, like
Speaker 5:  I know, we'll see. Right. We gotta get the thing, but they're saying that
Speaker 5:  they can do that move too. Which some other phones do, some of their phones
Speaker 5:  don't right. Like we're figuring out what to do with the, he,
Speaker 5:  the huge sensors on these phones. We're not, we're not firing out 96 megapixel
Speaker 5:  images to people. Everyone is cropping and bidding in different ways. Then
Speaker 5:  the last thing you can do is the action mode that they've added to the video
Speaker 5:  camera, where they use the whole sensor and then they do that
Speaker 5:  dynamic cropping. Right? So they like pick an object in the frame. They're
Speaker 5:  gonna hold that steady and they're gonna move the frame around it inside
Speaker 5:  of the sensor area, which again, we have to
Speaker 7:  See, and that's what they're using to stabilize motion. And I actually think
Speaker 7:  if that's as good as it looked in that demo where it was like the sort of
Speaker 7:  camera running behind a runner and on the left it's ultra shaky and on the
Speaker 7:  right, it was super still, if that's that good, that's gonna be like
Speaker 7:  a gigantic improvement for a lot of people who make video.
Speaker 7:  Cuz it's the kind of thing that is like everybody buys these wacky gimbles
Speaker 7:  and does all kinds of crazy stuff. And if that is like an even like B plus
Speaker 7:  solved problem, now that's a really big deal. But it is also the kind of
Speaker 7:  thing that we have seen in the past is really hard to do without all that
Speaker 7:  like hideous warping and really ugly artifacting as people
Speaker 7:  move. Like I'm, that's one thing I'm very curious to see the test result
Speaker 7:  of.
Speaker 6:  Well, that's like a problem that Sony's face too, right? Like, cuz they've
Speaker 6:  tried to do that kind of stuff with video and
Speaker 6:  it always, you get that warping motion and it's really hard to do. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  It's super hard.
Speaker 5:  So we'll see. And they've brought that same mode to the FN 14, which has
Speaker 5:  a regular 12 megapixel sensor. So we'll see if they're even
Speaker 5:  different. Right. Cuz they're still shooting 4k video, which is only the
Speaker 5:  same area on the sensor. We, we just kind of don't know, but
Speaker 5:  yeah, they're, they're using the 48 megapixel sensor on the pro
Speaker 5:  in like several different ways. Like there are modes that it
Speaker 5:  goes into. One is the like pixel bend. It's actually just
Speaker 5:  a gigantic 12 megapixel sensor. The other is the
Speaker 5:  crop. We cut it down and we're using 12 megapixels out of the
Speaker 5:  middle. The other way is this like action mode. And then that you can switch
Speaker 5:  it in prayer on just like use it as a 48 mega sensor, which will generate
Speaker 5:  gigantic images of which we will have to like look at and see if you
Speaker 5:  lose anything by not pixelating them.
Speaker 6:  So they're really like, these are all, I mean, I don't know about phones
Speaker 6:  as much, but these are all methodologies that like Sony's been using for
Speaker 6:  years and it's DSLRs to like,
Speaker 5:  Oh this it's and Samsung. Yeah. And like everybody, like apple
Speaker 5:  is two years, three years behind
Speaker 5:  the let's put a big sensor and use it in funky ways. Trend.
Speaker 5:  Certainly the, you know, like the S phones have had this for a while.
Speaker 5:  Huawei phones have done this for a while. Like, like the trend is you
Speaker 5:  can only make the pixel so big or pack them so densely before you start
Speaker 5:  introducing errors or bad pixels. So you're, you're better move
Speaker 5:  is to pack in more pixels and then, and then bin them.
Speaker 5:  And that's like what we've been seeing across the industry. So Apple's like
Speaker 5:  coming to it. We have to see what sensor they're using. Right. They have
Speaker 5:  traditional use Sony sensors. We don't know if they're still using a, like,
Speaker 5:  there's a million things you gotta figure out. But it's funny cuz it's like
Speaker 5:  now known like I know what to go review it against and how to review it
Speaker 5:  because they're late. But it seems like they, they are doing at least a couple
Speaker 5:  more interesting things.
Speaker 6:  All right. I'm gonna ask you a question as that. I get from my mom
Speaker 6:  every year. She's asked me this question every year for the last seven years
Speaker 6:  and I hate it. And so I wanna pass on the pain to someone else, which
Speaker 6:  will be better for her to take photos, this phone or her
Speaker 6:  digital camera from 2003,
Speaker 5:  The phone that, that answers. What are you talking about?
Speaker 5:  That, that answer is like five years outta date.
Speaker 6:  I just needed this, this so I can send it to her to maybe finally
Speaker 6:  get her to stop using that digital camera. Is
Speaker 7:  She recording onto like mini VHS's?
Speaker 6:  No, she's got like, she's got like a CF card in it and
Speaker 6:  it's a crappy, like it's like a cannon point and shoot from
Speaker 6:  2003.
Speaker 5:  Right. That thing has like a, like a posted, like not even a posted, it has
Speaker 5:  like a quarter inch sensor. Yeah. And has a slow lens. And she probably
Speaker 5:  zooms with the slow lens and makes it even slower
Speaker 5:  rights. Like throw that like go to her house and was like throw it away and
Speaker 5:  just like leave an iPhone 12 in its place. And the iPhone 12 will be massively
Speaker 5:  superior to this thing.
Speaker 6:  No, I have to, I have to give her this, this audio clip.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. What's your mom's name? I can address her directly. Phyllis Phyllis,
Speaker 5:  let me talk to you. Settle in, throw away your camera
Speaker 5:  and buy any modern cell phone. It will be faster and better for you
Speaker 5:  and you'll be able to more easily share photos with your daughter.
Speaker 6:  Thank you. There it is. It's like little postage stamps.
Speaker 7:  That's another thing apple did actually is put in faster aperture lenses
Speaker 7:  into, I think all four of the phones. Oh really? I could be wrong. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  But I'm pretty sure every lens is faster. And that's another one of those
Speaker 7:  things that is like the kind of thing. Most people don't notice, but just
Speaker 7:  like instantly makes all of your photos slightly better. I'm very excited
Speaker 7:  about
Speaker 5:  That. And then they added, I think they did this just to troll me. I gotta
Speaker 5:  be honest with you. I'm pretty sure they did this just to troll me. They
Speaker 5:  were like, remember deep fusion and they literally showed a picture of a
Speaker 5:  person wearing a sweater. Yes.
Speaker 6:  That was just all for
Speaker 7:  You. Sweater mode.
Speaker 5:  What are we doing? And they're like, we've moved deep fusion
Speaker 5:  earlier in the process of taking the photo.
Speaker 6:  Oh sure.
Speaker 5:  And now we are calling that the photonic engine.
Speaker 5:  Sure. Like, sure. Here's this thing that
Speaker 5:  no one understood anyway, like, do you remember when they're like deep fusion
Speaker 5:  is here and they rolled it out? Yeah. And you're like, what does it do
Speaker 6:  Sweaters.
Speaker 5:  But it like, perceptively does very little and maybe it's, maybe it's doing
Speaker 5:  a lot and it's generating like a 5% change and that's very apple to make
Speaker 5:  a big hype about it. But you know, but like this is like they moved it early
Speaker 5:  in the process. And then the claim is that all these cameras
Speaker 5:  will perform better in low light because deep fusion is earlier in the process.
Speaker 5:  Okay. So it's up to two X better on the front camera in low
Speaker 5:  light against what? By the way, unspecified.
Speaker 5:  So it's up to two X better on the front camera, the telephoto
Speaker 5:  and the main camera. And apparently it's up to three X better
Speaker 5:  on the ultra one
Speaker 7:  Up to three X. Better. Not it's not necessarily three it's
Speaker 5:  Just but against what last year's phone, the first iPhone. Who
Speaker 5:  knows. Do
Speaker 7:  You think they're comparing it to Phyllis's digital camera? Yeah. Phyllis
Speaker 7:  is just out there shooting.
Speaker 5:  We have a cannon L SD 400
Speaker 5:  and it's up to three X. Better than that. Boom.
Speaker 6:  Buy it.
Speaker 5:  I had a cannon L SD 400. That camera. That camera got me through a
Speaker 5:  lot of nights at the bar. That's actually why you bought those cameras. You're
Speaker 5:  like one day someone will spill a beer fully on this. It'll be fine. That'll
Speaker 5:  be fine. Yep. Yeah. And then they added some video features, right? So the
Speaker 5:  cinematic mode can add 4k 30 and 4k 24.
Speaker 5:  I tried to test this out. I will tell you that cinematic mode does
Speaker 5:  not like being in a room with hundreds of faces. It
Speaker 5:  just lost its mind. Like again, true. Tremendously
Speaker 5:  unfair, right? Yeah. But it was like who, who, who should be blurry? I don't
Speaker 5:  know. I'm freaking out. So we'll try it again when I get a review
Speaker 6:  Because it just focuses like on one face. It's like facial.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And I tried to blurry it out. So it just like couldn't decide who I
Speaker 5:  cared about. You know, like yeah. Which of these people should be in focus.
Speaker 5:  So
Speaker 6:  Was it like the visual representation of smart homes having to decide who,
Speaker 6:  who to listen to when you, they adjust the, the temperature,
Speaker 5:  Just it just, and the poor person in the demo was like, it's not gonna work.
Speaker 5:  You
Speaker 6:  Like don't
Speaker 5:  Even try. I mean, look, I, I think the pro is great. I'm excited to review
Speaker 5:  it. I'm excited like orders right now. I'm sure people are gonna, regardless
Speaker 5:  of whatever review says, I, the thing to me though is I'm, I'm just
Speaker 5:  watching our gift that we clipped out of the video and it's like, they show
Speaker 5:  the big widget a lot.
Speaker 7:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And it's actually not the, it's not the user flow that you would expect
Speaker 5:  in, in using it. And that's the cool part, right? Like you've got the
Speaker 5:  airplane app. Boy, do I have thoughts about airplane app design?
Speaker 5:  Like airlines, if you're listening, like I've been on a lot of different
Speaker 5:  airlines in the past couple days, all of them are bad. You got
Speaker 6:  Feelings,
Speaker 5:  But like the cool one, right? We, you, you got your flight coming and you
Speaker 5:  like it opens and it shows you the plane flying over the thing and estimated
Speaker 5:  time like that stuff is amazing. And it's not actually what happens.
Speaker 5:  Like you tap on it. It's gonna kick you into an app. So I think that's the
Speaker 5:  flow that needs to get figured out.
Speaker 7:  You want the dynamic island to just show your plane flying from one end
Speaker 7:  of the island to the other.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Well I just, it's neat that that's what they're showing like. Yeah. That's
Speaker 5:  the cool part about this is you got these little minimized widgets and you
Speaker 5:  tap 'em you get the big widget and they look really cool. Right? Yep. And
Speaker 5:  like there's a reason they're showing it. They're not showing you bouncing
Speaker 5:  into the American airlines app, which
Speaker 5:  is just one of the worst experiences you can have
Speaker 5:  as a human being. They're like, no, here's a cool animation that shows you
Speaker 5:  what you need right away. And like, I think they'll, I think they'll get
Speaker 5:  there or they'll give you, they'll give me a switch real
Speaker 7:  Quick before you take a break. One more question on this. I, I was debating
Speaker 7:  this with somebody the other day. And I'm curious what you guys think. Do
Speaker 7:  you think people know like the average iPhone user, that
Speaker 7:  you can even long press on stuff to find more information because
Speaker 7:  like the not at all the edit message thing is coming in in messages
Speaker 7:  and that's underneath a long press. And like apple is increasingly doing
Speaker 7:  more and more of these features and putting them under long presses. And
Speaker 7:  my stance is basically like, as soon as you do that, you assume 95% of your
Speaker 7:  users are never gonna find it. But I've talked to people who were like, no
Speaker 7:  people know,
Speaker 5:  No, they had 3d touch. Remember they had pressure sensitive screens and they
Speaker 5:  were useless and they threw 'em away. Yeah. This is the company that still
Speaker 5:  will not ship a multi button mouse. Right. Because they,
Speaker 5:  at their core believed that everything should be on the surface of the interface.
Speaker 5:  And then the phone is like, right. Clicks for days. Like all,
Speaker 5:  all this is is right. Clicking. Yeah. Right. Like at a very basic level,
Speaker 5:  they've added right. Clicks to the phone. And it's cool if you are like,
Speaker 5:  my mouse has 10 buttons. Like I love an alternative click,
Speaker 5:  but most people like will never find it. Yeah. I think that's right. I think
Speaker 5:  a lot of the, the dynamic they should have called it, the dynamic notch,
Speaker 5:  I think they wanted to get away from the word notch. And so here we are at
Speaker 5:  island, I think all of the island stuff is right.
Speaker 5:  Clicks in like the, they, they just need to flip that around. We haven't
Speaker 5:  talked about this other phone at all. We should we take a break and talk
Speaker 5:  about the other phone? Who cares? We're gonna take a break. We're gonna have
Speaker 5:  that argument in the background.
Speaker 5:  We'll be right back.
Speaker 11:  Hi, I'm Kara Swisher for decades. I've covered Silicon valley, Washington
Speaker 11:  and Hollywood making sense of those worlds by talking directly to the people
Speaker 11:  who shaped them. Elon Musk, Barack Obama, Tony Fauci,
Speaker 11:  Kim Kardashian. I've had the pleasure of grilling them all.
Speaker 11:  Now I'm launching a new show called the Joe Rogan experience with Kara
Speaker 11:  Swisher. Just kidding. It's actually called on with Kara
Speaker 11:  Swisher. And let me tell you, it is on no holds barred
Speaker 11:  on the tough questions or on my opinions on with Kara Swisher
Speaker 11:  launches September 26th from New York magazine and the V media podcast
Speaker 11:  network, just look for on with Kara Swisher in your podcast app
Speaker 11:  and hit, follow or subscribe.
Speaker 12:  The Iowa lottery was out there saying on a regular basis, Hey folks, check
Speaker 12:  your ticket. Somebody's got 16 million bucks and it was sort of this mystery.
Speaker 12:  Why hasn't anyone come forward?
Speaker 13:  I'm Phoebe judge host of the podcast, criminal, true
Speaker 13:  stories about people who've done wrong. Been wronged or gotten caught somewhere
Speaker 13:  in the middle, told by people who know them best like a man
Speaker 13:  who successfully figured out how to negotiate with his father's kidnappers.
Speaker 13:  After some trial and error,
Speaker 14:  They were just like for that price, we won't even tell you where he's buried.
Speaker 13:  And a 12 year old who solved a family mystery.
Speaker 15:  There were three little fingerprints. And I remember in junior da
Speaker 15:  camp, I was like, oh, fingerprints. This is definitely some evidence. Then
Speaker 15:  we can find whoever broke into my grandmother's house,
Speaker 13:  Discover the unexpected side of true crime.
Speaker 16:  There were no security alarms whatsoever. The file
Speaker 16:  cabinets were not even locked. So that gave us enough information
Speaker 16:  to plan the actual break in, listen
Speaker 13:  To criminal. Now, wherever you get your podcasts,
Speaker 5:  All right, we're back. We have to talk to the FN 14 plus, which is a very
Speaker 5:  minor improvement over the 13.
Speaker 17:  IPhone 14 also has an updated internal design that
Speaker 17:  improves thermal performance, which is great for staying in the action
Speaker 17:  longer
Speaker 5:  Processor from last year's pro the a 15 bionic cool
Speaker 5:  minor upgrades to the cameras. Cool. Faster it lenses. Mostly
Speaker 5:  the photonic engine, extra sweater mode, super sweater mode. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Super sweater mode. And, oh, we, we didn't talk about this before at all.
Speaker 5:  It's got the satellite thing. Yep.
Speaker 15:  Which is a subscription, right?
Speaker 5:  Well, they get it free for two years and
Speaker 15:  Then you have to pay for it
Speaker 5:  And then you have to pay for it or buy a new phone, buy a new phone and get
Speaker 5:  it
Speaker 7:  For free. Can we actually talk about this? Because I have been trying to
Speaker 7:  decide since this event, whether or not this is
Speaker 7:  actually cool because it's one of those things that like, one of the themes
Speaker 7:  of the apple event was the apocalypse is coming slash you are going
Speaker 7:  to get lost in the woods. Very soon.
Speaker 5:  You're gonna be in a car crash and a computer should know about
Speaker 7:  It. Yeah. Like, like, but like it's coming, it's like, it's next week. You're
Speaker 7:  gonna get in a car crash. Apple. Can't tell you how it knows, but it knows.
Speaker 7:  Can
Speaker 5:  I just, can we talk about the one weirdest piece of staging at this whole
Speaker 5:  event? Sure. Utterly bizarre. So first of all, lots of car
Speaker 5:  crashes at the apple
Speaker 7:  Event. So many,
Speaker 5:  Every product introduction was accompanied by a video of a car crash
Speaker 5:  straight up. And then they would say something like, we hope you never have
Speaker 5:  to use this feature. And it's like, shit, me too. Like,
Speaker 7:  And then you started running around asking executives how many cars they
Speaker 7:  crashed and nobody would answer your question,
Speaker 5:  But okay. But here's the weirdest one in the apple watch I went talk about,
Speaker 5:  they were like, here's a bunch of letters that people have written to Tim
Speaker 5:  cook about how the apple watch like saved
Speaker 7:  Their life.
Speaker 18:  I placed my apple watch on his wrist and I couldn't believe my eyes,
Speaker 18:  an atrial fibrillation notification popped up holy
Speaker 18:  cow.
Speaker 5:  And they got the actual people to read the letters, like recreate the letters.
Speaker 5:  And it was like very moving, right. People are like, and it's the stuff that
Speaker 5:  you would expect. My heart started racing. My friends' heart started racing.
Speaker 5:  I went to the doctor. They were like, thank God you're
Speaker 7:  Here. There was also a guy who had a bear in his house just to like, it was
Speaker 7:  a wide spectrum of things,
Speaker 5:  But like familiar in the scheme of the apple watch shape of
Speaker 5:  my life. Except maybe for the bear. Then there's a woman who was like,
Speaker 5:  I was in a plane crash and I came to and like,
Speaker 5:  I pushed a button and I watched and what I called and it was like, but they,
Speaker 5:  because it was a recreation, they had her sitting in a crashed plane.
Speaker 5:  And I was like, did you take a plane crash survivor? And be like,
Speaker 5:  sit in. We built a crashed plane for you to sit in for
Speaker 5:  our a, like, it was just a bizarre, like that's
Speaker 5:  too much.
Speaker 7:  Or the guy who was like, I almost got crushed by the trash compactor,
Speaker 7:  in my garbage truck, standing there reading it into his garbage truck. It's
Speaker 7:  like, it's like, man,
Speaker 5:  That one made sense. Cause the garbage truck was like functional.
Speaker 5:  Right? He was like back at work at his, with his truck. This was like, they
Speaker 5:  had to make a plane crash. Well, there's two choices here. Someone
Speaker 5:  built a plane crash and they had a physical plane crash set or
Speaker 5:  you know, the crack apple TV production company. It was like, sit on the
Speaker 5:  screen screen. We're not gonna tell you what happens. And they matted in
Speaker 5:  a plane crash.
Speaker 5:  Like either way. It's like someone had to make a plane crash
Speaker 5:  for this poor woman to sit in. We're far away from satellite connectivity.
Speaker 5:  I just, it jumped out to me so immediately. Yeah. Like you took a plane
Speaker 5:  crash provider and like, I need you to sit in this plane crash and tell me
Speaker 5:  how to watch save your life. I can't even imagine what that day of shooting
Speaker 5:  was like. Let's just talk about that for the rest of the show. This is just
Speaker 5:  very traumatic
Speaker 7:  For a
Speaker 5:  Person. Oh, well she seemed happy. Who knows? So this is like the theme as
Speaker 5:  David was talking about, right? The watch can attack a car crash. The phone
Speaker 5:  can detect a car crash. If you're lost somewhere, you can
Speaker 5:  hold up your phone and connect. We think we've learned the company's globe
Speaker 5:  star.
Speaker 7:  Oh, interesting.
Speaker 5:  In our, in our preview episode, we're saying there was, there's a big spectrum
Speaker 5:  of ways that phone can connect to a satellite. One is cell
Speaker 5:  towers in space, full connectivity. There's a bunch of companies doing that,
Speaker 5:  like link and others. Another is star link, which is basically
Speaker 5:  cell towers in space. They're doing that with T-Mobile in slightly different
Speaker 5:  way. And then all the way down the line is very low data transmission in
Speaker 5:  emergencies and apple went with very low data transmission in emergencies.
Speaker 5:  So you can only send text messages in an emergency and
Speaker 5:  that's it. And you can only really send text messages. I understand it to
Speaker 5:  emergency services,
Speaker 7:  Right? It's yeah, it is. It's the equivalent of like the thing when you don't
Speaker 7:  have any service, but you can call 9 1 1. It's like that's, that's essentially
Speaker 7:  what it's just sort of expanding out. And there was a line in
Speaker 7:  it where he was basically like, we've done a bunch of work to
Speaker 7:  shrink the size of a message down to a third of its normal size,
Speaker 7:  which is already like a hilarious thing. Because the text message is like
Speaker 7:  not a large thing. And he was like, so you can send a message in as little
Speaker 7:  as 15 seconds. And it's like, wait.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And you need perfect line of sight, the satellite. So Starlink eat
Speaker 5:  your heart out, right? Yeah. This isn't a tree might be in
Speaker 5:  the way it's the phone puts up UI. That's like, here's the satellite
Speaker 5:  point, your phone directly at the satellite, holding it up in
Speaker 5:  the air. And then effectively the UI is like Clippy for
Speaker 5:  emergencies
Speaker 6:  That feels like not super productive. And like you have to text someone.
Speaker 5:  Right. So the idea, so when I say it's Clippy for emergencies, they're like,
Speaker 5:  we've built this system of common messages and applies
Speaker 5:  you might want to send, which I think is how they're doing some of the compression.
Speaker 5:  Right? They're like they, they have known messages and they can yeah.
Speaker 5:  Send codes instead of the messages. So it's like even an accident, like,
Speaker 5:  do you need help? And you like push one and like go. And then if the emergency
Speaker 5:  service provider that's near you doesn't accept text messages.
Speaker 5:  They have relay stations where people receive your text messages
Speaker 5:  and call the emergency services for you.
Speaker 6:  Okay. Cuz that was the part like generally speaking, when you don't
Speaker 6:  have connectivity, it's because you're in a more rural place where emergency
Speaker 6:  services probably are not as often technical, technologically advanced.
Speaker 6:  So the likelihood of like them having the ability to receive your
Speaker 6:  text messages in Abilene, Texas small.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So we don't know. So I've seen a lot of reports that Apple's partner
Speaker 5:  with globe star for this, even some reports on how much they've paid
Speaker 5:  globe star to do this. Right? Like we gotta confirm all those
Speaker 5:  details of how it works. But like who sits in the relay center? Is it
Speaker 5:  open question? I think, is it apple? Does apple staff a bunch of relay centers
Speaker 5:  or is it like GlobeStar, they're in a contract and they say they're apple
Speaker 5:  like lots of details there, but fundamentally it's, you're in an accident.
Speaker 5:  You don't have connectivity in the middle of nowhere. If you can point your
Speaker 5:  phone at the right spot in the sky, you can have a sort of scripted
Speaker 5:  conversation that gets you help.
Speaker 6:  Does it only activate if you're in an accident? Like if the bear
Speaker 6:  is in your house, how do you,
Speaker 5:  I don't think there's any situation which you buy an iPhone 14
Speaker 5:  just in case in your off the grid house, a bear
Speaker 5:  enters. And then you pointed at the sky to text
Speaker 5:  emergency services.
Speaker 7:  Bear here. Well,
Speaker 6:  No that's so I, I was just like, how do you activate? How do you activate
Speaker 6:  that emergency thing? The use case you're talking about is somebody's in
Speaker 6:  a crash and apple talked a lot about like, well, we can detect crashes now,
Speaker 6:  but when are the situations where you aren't in a crash, but you
Speaker 6:  do need emergency services
Speaker 5:  And you can just hold on that button on your phone, just like now. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  I believe it's a, it's not connected to the like crash
Speaker 7:  detection and stuff. That it is a separate thing.
Speaker 6:  Okay. So it's just like an individual thing and you can be like help.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Yeah. So like when you, you know, right now, if you like, hold the
Speaker 5:  two buttons down on your phone, you can like go to emergency mode.
Speaker 6:  I learn new things about my phone every day on the verge cast.
Speaker 5:  Here are your choices. When you want to turn your phone, if you hold the,
Speaker 5:  the volume in this, the power button down and you can turn the phone off,
Speaker 5:  you can get your medical ID or you can do an SOS. Right. And like picking
Speaker 5:  the wrong one at the wrong time. Seems very
Speaker 7:  Fraught, which is also how babies like to call 9 1 1
Speaker 7:  by pressing all the buttons on your phone and then seeing what happens.
Speaker 7:  But no, the, the thing that's interesting to me about this is like investing
Speaker 7:  in all the satellite stuff for like the watch ultra, which we're gonna talk
Speaker 7:  about. Makes a lot of sense to me because it's, it is like a group of people
Speaker 7:  who need this stuff and know that they need it are likely to buy these
Speaker 7:  devices. Right. This is the kind of thing that I would assume the earth
Speaker 7:  shattering. Majority of iPhone users will never once experience
Speaker 7:  in the entire time that they had this phone. So it was surprising to me that
Speaker 7:  this was like a thing that not only did apple building to the phone and,
Speaker 7:  and all, all of the models of the phone. Right. But like spend a lot
Speaker 7:  of time telling us about in launching the phone. And so the, the like galaxy
Speaker 7:  brand version of this is like, okay, what is this? The like one version of,
Speaker 7:  and it's like, okay, is apple eventually gonna do? I was talking to somebody
Speaker 7:  who was like, their big theory is eventually apple is gonna like obviate
Speaker 7:  all the carriers by doing its own fully satellite based infrastructure.
Speaker 5:  Apple loves the carriers. Now the carrier, like that is a
Speaker 5:  lucrative relationship. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. The carriers pay for all the ads for iPhones. It's a perfect setup.
Speaker 7:  But then if it's not that though, then like, what is the
Speaker 7:  five year plan here that makes this relevant to more than this teeny
Speaker 7:  tiny fraction of iPhone users? Or does there just not need to be one?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I don't think there was one. I think this was just like, this is a
Speaker 6:  cool feature. There's not a lot going on with the iPhone 14. This is a way
Speaker 6:  to differentiate it from the iPhone 13. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  They said that big technical achievement here is they got the antennas to
Speaker 5:  switch to the satellite bands. So they didn't have to add a bulky plastic
Speaker 5:  content. Like there's obviously a lot of technical work here that has been
Speaker 5:  done, but the future is cell towers in
Speaker 5:  space. Yeah. Right. And actually Elon, God bless Elon tweeted. Like
Speaker 5:  of course I've talked to the iPhone team. They're very smart. And it's like,
Speaker 5:  sure, you have, so who knows what you've done? Self-driving taxis will be
Speaker 5:  roaming the streets of America tomorrow
Speaker 7:  Two years ago. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Like, sure. But he's like turning a Starling satellite into a cell
Speaker 5:  tower space is not the end goal. And that's where that's the state of the
Speaker 5:  art right now is a cell tower space. So I, I think there's probably a lot
Speaker 5:  of work to be done here, but right now what you've got is like Clippy for
Speaker 5:  emergencies,
Speaker 7:  Which is fine. And it does seem to be true that apple
Speaker 7:  is leaning harder into this thing that it is like the apple
Speaker 7:  watch can save your life. Like, I it's very clear that that like means
Speaker 7:  something to apple. And they're like, not only is this like a hell of a marketing
Speaker 7:  scheme, but they seem to actually buy this theory that this
Speaker 7:  is meaningful to people in that way.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And Nicole wrote about it on the site. Like a lot of the message here
Speaker 5:  is like unsupported by research fear
Speaker 5:  Moning yes. But dressed up, right? Like the apple
Speaker 5:  watch can monitor temperature, but they can't make medical claims. Cause
Speaker 5:  it's not cleared by the FDA. So who knows the apple watch can monitor
Speaker 5:  your blood oxygen, but it's not cleared by the FDA. So who knows, like a
Speaker 5:  lot of the heart detection stuff that they've done study in
Speaker 5:  2020 found led to nothing but caused a burden
Speaker 5:  in interpreting in additional testing in the healthcare system. That's not
Speaker 5:  discounting the fact that people have had their lives saved by the apple
Speaker 5:  watch, but they're, they're leaning into it in a way that they have to connect
Speaker 5:  it to reality at the end, right.
Speaker 7:  Life saving at scale is a very different thing.
Speaker 5:  So we start with the watches. We have not talked about the iPhone 14 plus,
Speaker 5:  should we talk about it?
Speaker 7:  No, that feels right. We just, just that moment we talked about the iPhone
Speaker 7:  14 plus exactly. As much as we should. I will say, I do think a lot of people
Speaker 7:  are gonna buy the iPhone 14 plus. Oh yeah. This is the NELI Patel big, cheap
Speaker 7:  screen theory. Right? Like it's cheaper than the other big one and
Speaker 7:  it's big and it's the exact same phone as the F and 14, like
Speaker 6:  Great, very convenient that they're putting it out and they're not doing
Speaker 6:  a mini this year.
Speaker 5:  I'm telling you ever you can. Wh all you want
Speaker 6:  They're they're just trying to like feed your theory. Alison
Speaker 6:  will back me up on this. If she's on the show again, they're just, they're,
Speaker 6:  they're feeding your theory that people love big phones, but that's because
Speaker 6:  they don't offer 'em at the same time.
Speaker 5:  Oh, I see what you mean. No, no, no. They offered both at the same time and
Speaker 5:  people still bought the big ones so much. They got rid of the little one.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Apple famous for putting out products that people don't want. Just
Speaker 7:  despite Eli. That would say that, that happens a lot.
Speaker 5:  I will, we got there in like a lot of people there had listened to our episode
Speaker 5:  and they're like, so you want a TV? Huh? He's like, sure. Do. I'm just
Speaker 5:  telling you big cheap screens always win the difference in price between
Speaker 5:  the little pro and the big plus is a hundred bucks. And like in
Speaker 5:  any rational universe you would upgrade and get the dynamic island and the
Speaker 5:  better camera and the all the, and everyone's gonna buy the plus instead.
Speaker 5:  Yep. Without, without question,
Speaker 7:  Which one are you guys gonna buy?
Speaker 5:  The pro max?
Speaker 6:  I, I already got the pro
Speaker 7:  Big or little, little,
Speaker 6:  All
Speaker 5:  Right. We said we, weren't gonna talk about the plus. And here we are, we
Speaker 5:  should talk about the watches.
Speaker 19:  This is the new apple watch series eight. It
Speaker 19:  features a big brilliant, always on display with narrow borders that push
Speaker 19:  the screen right to the
Speaker 5:  Edge. So speaking big cheap screens, apple watch eight
Speaker 5:  huge screen. People are gonna upgrade just to get the, the big screen. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Added a temperature sensor. They can do cycle tracking, which is really interesting.
Speaker 5:  A lot of apps have done this over time. They can, they can only
Speaker 5:  retroactively tell you an ovulation is they can't predict it, which is
Speaker 5:  just another one of those like apples making claims, right. At
Speaker 5:  the limit of the claims they can make. Yeah. But they can't go farther,
Speaker 5:  which is interesting. Obviously, crash detection. God only knows if you
Speaker 5:  were in a car crash and a computer doesn't know about it. Apple is mad at
Speaker 5:  you, by the way. They've also fundamentally invented on star. Like
Speaker 5:  I went to code and I saw GM executives. Like they just invented OnStar and
Speaker 5:  they're like, we had an all hands and we were like, they just invented OnStar,
Speaker 5:  but the eight looks good. I think a lot of people are gonna upgrade it. Same
Speaker 5:  basic chip. Right? Like not a lot of additional features and the eight just
Speaker 5:  big screen. I
Speaker 6:  Think the, the, the period and ovulation tracking is kind of a big
Speaker 6:  deal for them because they've been notoriously super far behind
Speaker 6:  there. Yeah. For years and years and years and years. And this is like one
Speaker 6:  of the biggest, like places in wearable space.
Speaker 5:  Well, the interesting thing though, to, you know, just looking at how they
Speaker 5:  talked about it, you have to wear it while you're asleep. Yes.
Speaker 5:  Which is, you know, they're just gonna have to initiate a new user behavior.
Speaker 5:  Also tempera tracking the risk, kind of like dicey another piece of the Nicole
Speaker 5:  article that you, which is great. So we'll see. They've, it's good that they
Speaker 5:  did it. It's cool. I think a lot of people find it useful. I'm just saying
Speaker 5:  as a person who had a baby, you, if you're trying to make a baby, you, you
Speaker 5:  need to know ahead of time.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Yeah. No, I think, I think it's like, I think this is like, I don't
Speaker 6:  think this is necessarily like gonna be useful. I just think it's like interesting
Speaker 6:  that apple is finally doing it and doing this catch up. Yeah. And I would
Speaker 6:  suspect those temperature sensors are not just gonna be used for this, cuz
Speaker 6:  there's been so much space talk in the wearable space of using temperature
Speaker 6:  sensors to predict illness. And they, FDA
Speaker 6:  will be like, you absolutely cannot say that right now. And so I think that's
Speaker 6:  like series nine or something.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. They're they are oceans of peer reviewed studies away from making
Speaker 5:  the claims they want to make. Yeah. Which is again, they're making the claims
Speaker 5:  they can,
Speaker 7:  Which is one of the weird things. Like we're, we're used to these companies
Speaker 7:  like massively over promising all the stuff that they can do. And with a
Speaker 7:  lot of this stuff, it's a totally different dance where there's like, there's
Speaker 7:  the stuff. And I've heard this from a lot of wearable companies where they're
Speaker 7:  like, we see things, we can't tell you what they are, but we're
Speaker 7:  very confident about them, but we can't legally say a certain set of words
Speaker 7:  in a row about what things actually do. But if you buy one and it's useful
Speaker 7:  to you for that reason, terrific. And you just come outta that conversation
Speaker 7:  and be like, what
Speaker 6:  That's called government regulation, working as intended. Yeah. Cause
Speaker 6:  it's keeping these companies from over promising because otherwise like apple
Speaker 6:  would be like, we can predict when the baby is coming and you'd be like,
Speaker 6:  what?
Speaker 7:  A hundred percent. Yeah. We're gonna save your life for sure. Apple
Speaker 7:  a hundred
Speaker 5:  Percent again. And the fact you have to wear it overnight. Like I am not
Speaker 5:  the right person to review this product, but no. Well I think again, this
Speaker 5:  is like a reveal, like people are gonna get, here's what we know.
Speaker 5:  They're gonna sum millions with them. And I think we're gonna very quickly
Speaker 5:  learn how accurate the thing is. Cause people are gonna talk about it.
Speaker 5:  So that's the eight, I think people just for those reasons, big screen, big,
Speaker 5:  big, cheap screen. That's the upgrade. Yep. Everyone's gonna do it. The SES
Speaker 5:  really boring. They just added color to the back. And now we gotta talk with
Speaker 5:  the ultra.
Speaker 19:  This is apple watch ultra a completely new
Speaker 19:  design reimagined with extraordinary new capabilities that
Speaker 19:  expand the ways you can use apple watch.
Speaker 5:  I'm gonna buy an ultra it's $800. Yeah. Why am I buying ultra? I
Speaker 5:  don't know, like the most extreme sport I do as I throw max in the
Speaker 5:  pool
Speaker 6:  For divine was like, he called me and he's like, I'm buying the ultra. He's
Speaker 6:  like a watch guy. And I was like, you're a watch guy. Why, why do you want
Speaker 6:  the ultra? And he's like the tooling on it. I was like, I'm hanging up on
Speaker 6:  you right now.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, no that's right. It, the buttons are great. The, the digital
Speaker 5:  crown is finally nerded.
Speaker 7:  It's finally nerded.
Speaker 5:  It's a whole thing. Like the way to describe the design of this thing is
Speaker 5:  nerded. There. Isn't another word
Speaker 7:  I will say though. Apple did a pretty good job of this. This thing is enormous.
Speaker 7:  Like do not get it twisted. It is enormous to the point
Speaker 7:  where like you can, you could see from across the room,
Speaker 7:  which apple executive had an ultra on versus a different apple watch,
Speaker 7:  like unbelievably noticeable
Speaker 5:  At the start of the event, they were all wearing the regular apple watches.
Speaker 5:  That's right. It was announced. They all put on the big
Speaker 7:  Watches because it was that noticeable. Like you can, you can run around
Speaker 7:  with an iPhone 14 and no, one's gonna notice because it's just an iPhone.
Speaker 7:  Right. Like, but the, the ultra is, it's a big boy, but
Speaker 7:  it it's pretty light. I will say, like I putting it on. I expected it to
Speaker 7:  just like my hand to just like go down and make a dent in the floor
Speaker 7:  based on how big it is. But it's actually like, it felt pretty
Speaker 7:  wearable in that sense. It's still bigger than I want on my wrist. And bigger
Speaker 7:  than I think a lot of people are gonna want on their wrist. But like, if
Speaker 7:  you're used to wearing the like dump truck of a garment, watch on your wrist,
Speaker 7:  like this will actually feel probably better on your wrist than a lot of
Speaker 7:  those would be my guess. Well,
Speaker 6:  And I do think it like hits that chart of people who are like
Speaker 6:  the garment folks and then also the Elis and my friends, folks who like,
Speaker 6:  just want a big watch. Right? Like big watches have always been a thing they're
Speaker 6:  very like fashionable for, for most guys. I think it's like, yeah, I
Speaker 6:  wanna have a 49 millimeter. Totally behemoth on my wrist. Whereas I'm
Speaker 6:  crying over here saying no, like, but the thing do that,
Speaker 7:  You bring up the thing I've been wondering about like, right. I mean, it's,
Speaker 7:  it's enormous, but the, that point about like who apple is trying to
Speaker 7:  go after here, I think is, is exactly right. And is going to be very
Speaker 7:  complicated and yes, Thomas ER, wrote a really good story for us about this,
Speaker 7:  about whether apple can do to garment, what it once did to Nokia,
Speaker 7:  which is basically just like iterated out of existence. Yeah. And
Speaker 7:  what's interesting now is that the ultra basically seems to be
Speaker 7:  from a sort of like hyper adventurer athlete perspective,
Speaker 7:  like a mile wide and an inch deep. Right? Like it does a lot of things. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  But if you're, it'll, it'll do scuba stuff, but if you like really seriously
Speaker 7:  scuba, it won't do enough. It it'll do a lot of like mountaineering stuff.
Speaker 7:  But if you're a really serious Mountaineer Mountaineer one who mountaineers
Speaker 7:  sure. It won't be enough. And so I think trying
Speaker 7:  to get this overlap of like, how do you, can it do enough other stuff
Speaker 7:  to make up for the sort of ultra specific stuff it doesn't do
Speaker 7:  seems to be the pitch apple is trying to make on this one and seems
Speaker 7:  very complicated because in all, each of those little tiny niches are people
Speaker 7:  willing to spend an awful lot of money, but who have a really high bar for
Speaker 7:  the features that they want and V song and our team has been writing about
Speaker 7:  this for weeks that like to try to be all things to all people in this sense
Speaker 7:  is borderline impossible. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It's funny. The only customization on the watch is what band you get it with?
Speaker 5:  Like there's a running band, a mountaineering band and a
Speaker 5:  scuba band. And it's like, that's, those are your choices. By the way, the
Speaker 5:  bands are totally interchangeable. The existing bands, I might have horrified
Speaker 5:  some people, but just like clipping on my like Amazon camera band.
Speaker 6:  Well, that was a rumor beforehand. Is that it wasn't gonna work with the,
Speaker 6:  the old
Speaker 5:  Bands? No, that's totally worked. It was the first thing I did. And they,
Speaker 5:  everyone was like, stop that. And I was like, no, I'm still doing this, but
Speaker 5:  the, you know, the scuba thing, apple, isn't making that app. Right. They're
Speaker 5:  going out to like a dive computer company. Right. And they're letting them
Speaker 5:  make the app, which is crazy. Right? Like apple, that's usually sort of thing.
Speaker 5:  Apple just like Sherlock away. But they're like, we actually need the
Speaker 5:  credibility with this audience that the trusted name is
Speaker 5:  gonna build this app for this watch. They did not do that with mountaineering
Speaker 5:  or ultra marathoning or this other stuff. And in fact, the watch when you
Speaker 5:  use it is basically the same, right. It's big square display. It looks
Speaker 5:  like it has a really big lip around the display and it basically does
Speaker 5:  not. Yeah,
Speaker 7:  No, it, it actually, you almost wanted to have more cause you, you just,
Speaker 7:  you're it sort of your finger sort of slides off the edge of it in a way
Speaker 7:  that like, if I'm just running and want to deal with, I actually want it
Speaker 7:  to sort of trap at the edges. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And just like the thing's gonna be out in the world, like you assume the
Speaker 5:  face is gonna get scratched. If it doesn't have more of a lip, but so like
Speaker 5:  it, it looks different in person and it plays different in
Speaker 5:  person than it does on the videos. But the button, the big orange clicky
Speaker 5:  button is great. Right. And it's customizable, which is a big
Speaker 5:  first for apple can drop you into whatever the thing where you roll the crown.
Speaker 5:  And it turns to display red. This is neat. Like
Speaker 5:  I'm sold, I'm done. I'm buying the thing.
Speaker 6:  Like I saw that and I was like, do I need it? No. Do I want it now?
Speaker 6:  Yes. Just night mode.
Speaker 5:  But other than that, like the app model is the same. Right? Like it hasn't
Speaker 5:  gotten more powerful. We can't do more things.
Speaker 7:  There's a new face. That's the there's new watch face. It's
Speaker 5:  Complicated, new face.
Speaker 7:  There's so much stuff on that. Watch face it's nuts.
Speaker 6:  Does it like, look, feel more expensive than the regular
Speaker 6:  watch
Speaker 5:  Hundred percent like, cause
Speaker 6:  I wonder if like maybe that they aren't going after
Speaker 6:  that garment crowd, but they are going after those people who buy
Speaker 6:  expensive watches and wanna look like have nice expensive watches on their
Speaker 6:  wrist. And most of them also get like generally
Speaker 6:  speaking, when you're getting a really expensive watch, it's got a diving
Speaker 6:  computer on it or it's got like your flight computer
Speaker 6:  because secretly you're a pilot in 1942. Like
Speaker 6:  it's, it's got all of that stuff. And I wonder if that's actually the crowd
Speaker 6:  it's going after instead of people who run a lot in the
Speaker 6:  wilderness.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I mean, it looks real fancy
Speaker 5:  and I love it.
Speaker 5:  I dunno what to tell you.
Speaker 6:  You're like, yes. It's for me.
Speaker 5:  It's yeah. I'm gonna buy, I'm gonna pay too much money for this thing and
Speaker 5:  use one 10th of its, you know what I mean? Use it for, I'm gonna use it for
Speaker 5:  two factor codes. There you go. The most extreme two factor codes that have
Speaker 5:  entered been generated by any risk computer in the world,
Speaker 6:  Climb a mountain, be like,
Speaker 5:  Yes. Okay. I'm logging into my Gmail and no one else's people,
Speaker 5:  apple watch ultra,
Speaker 7:  All I could think during the event was how excited you must be, that there
Speaker 7:  are now bit more speakers so that you can just be running around walkie talking
Speaker 7:  with Becky all day.
Speaker 5:  And I said, 80 decibel siren. You can do anything.
Speaker 5:  So yeah. So we have people on our staff that are gonna review this thing
Speaker 5:  appropriately. Thomas Ricker is one of them V is another.
Speaker 5:  So we'll, we'll, we'll push on it in that front. But like the astonishing
Speaker 5:  thing to me is that apple has not just across the board here.
Speaker 5:  Right? They didn't show anything else you could do
Speaker 5:  with a phone or a watch. Like the apps are all
Speaker 5:  basically the same. There are the dynamic island is fun, but
Speaker 5:  it's widgets. The cameras are improved, but they're still the same cameras.
Speaker 5:  Like there was not, a lot of here are useful
Speaker 5:  features. The way that, you know, for years, every
Speaker 5:  iPhone event has added like meaningful daily interaction features
Speaker 5:  to people. And so even the ultra, I'm sure there, like I said, I'm
Speaker 5:  by one, I'm not I'm the sucker. Like it looks really cool.
Speaker 5:  And I'm sure people who are actually ultra marathoners or explorers, apple
Speaker 5:  juice in the word explorers, which was great. It's like, what if they exploring
Speaker 6:  What is there
Speaker 5:  Space like on the one hand there's satellites everywhere. And we can see
Speaker 5:  anything on the other hand explores like old school Magellan is buying this
Speaker 5:  watch, but it's just like, I'm sure those people are interested in the features,
Speaker 5:  but they're in a market where they're much more fully featured products.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So it's just like, I, I'm still waiting on the turn for the watch
Speaker 5:  where it becomes a risk computer instead of like an ever
Speaker 5:  larger, more complicated piece of hardware
Speaker 7:  Design. Same. And we've, I mean, we've talked about this on the show too,
Speaker 7:  that I think like with more screen, more battery and
Speaker 7:  essentially like more stuff you can do on it as a result,
Speaker 7:  there's more you could do there. And I wonder why
Speaker 7:  apple is not necessarily pushing on some of that stuff.
Speaker 6:  I feel it's the battery I'm like just straight up. It's the battery. Like
Speaker 6:  until battery tech changes, they can only fit so much battery in
Speaker 6:  this thing. In which case, like you have to then have a
Speaker 6:  processor that doesn't suck enough. Like destroy the battery. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I will say the screen is now so big that you can
Speaker 5:  open the keyboard and like kind of type with two
Speaker 5:  thumbs on it. Almost
Speaker 7:  The swipey typing kind of works.
Speaker 5:  You
Speaker 7:  Can, you can swipe type like
Speaker 6:  The writing typing. I do that all the time on mine. I mean it's like short
Speaker 6:  sentences. I don't,
Speaker 5:  Oh, that's all Siri for me. And then no one knows what I'm trying to say
Speaker 5:  to them. Oh yeah.
Speaker 7:  That's a nightmare. And now with iOS 16 and I think probably on watch
Speaker 7:  last nine, you can dictate emojis. So now you can be running
Speaker 7:  up a mountain, yelling hard emoji, thumbs up emoji,
Speaker 7:  dead emoji into your watch, which is just a life I'm very ready
Speaker 7:  for.
Speaker 6:  I'm just gonna be like dancing lady, emoji, dancing, lady emoji,
Speaker 7:  Plane crash, emoji, bear, emoji, house emoji, plane,
Speaker 5:  Crash emoji. There's a bear in my plane
Speaker 5:  crash.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, look they're so far ahead of everybody else. Like sun Apache was at
Speaker 5:  code on stage running a pixel, watch an unannounced pixel watch. He was very,
Speaker 5:  and I was so mad. I wasn't there like, but he was, he wore with white pants
Speaker 5:  so people would notice it. Right. And I was like, well, the old school blogger
Speaker 5:  me, like runs to get a zoom lens and is like stalking
Speaker 5:  him backstage. And like all the reporters there, like didn't do it like mark
Speaker 5:  Erman caught it to his credit. But the, the end gadget in me, like the old
Speaker 5:  school end gadget in me is like, I'm in the hallway, I've got
Speaker 5:  a 200 millimeter lens. Like student's not leaving here until I have
Speaker 5:  a photo of the pixel watch. But like, you know, you can see what it is.
Speaker 5:  It's a circular watch. It's gonna have a bunch of Fitbit features in it.
Speaker 5:  And they're they're they are competing with the apple watch
Speaker 5:  series five. Yeah. Like just a fundamental level. There are three generations
Speaker 5:  behind apple is and apple. So like it's, these complaints are
Speaker 5:  minor on the edges, right? Like I wish
Speaker 5:  they would make it more powerful, like, but this is more powerful than anything.
Speaker 5:  But it's just weird that like, you know, the theme here is like, you're gonna
Speaker 5:  be in a car crash, not look at all of the things you can do with your
Speaker 5:  phone. Like it's apple is just like starting to assume those things.
Speaker 5:  And
Speaker 6:  It's like, what if we also saved your life?
Speaker 5:  Right. They're going to places where they're adding
Speaker 5:  features, where they're, they are themselves even saying,
Speaker 5:  we hope you never use these features.
Speaker 7:  Well, and it's just like, apple is also sort of simultaneously on
Speaker 7:  this, like reset your relationship with technology. And let's
Speaker 7:  talk about screen time and focus modes. And like let's help you disconnect
Speaker 7:  and not feel so reliant on your screens. And it's like, you know, what would
Speaker 7:  help is make those interactions easier on the watch? So I don't even have
Speaker 7:  to get my phone out at all. I can just like, leave it flip down on the table.
Speaker 7:  And that's just like, some of that is already in there and you can do it
Speaker 7:  if you want, but either apple doesn't think it's an interesting selling point
Speaker 7:  for people or it just doesn't have any new ideas about how that
Speaker 7:  stuff is supposed to work.
Speaker 5:  All right. We need to take a break. Yes
Speaker 7:  We do.
Speaker 5:  I will quickly. Here's everything you need to about the AirPods pro. They
Speaker 5:  are largely the same. They have a slightly new driver. They have an H two
Speaker 5:  chip. They are still running Bluetooth and they do not do lossless and they
Speaker 5:  have a little loop in the case for lanyard.
Speaker 6:  But they, they, they do two times the noise canceling. What?
Speaker 6:  That, whatever that means.
Speaker 5:  Well, I think that one is the previous generation. I think that one you can
Speaker 5:  safely assume
Speaker 7:  I will say I tried them. I spent like five minutes wearing a pair
Speaker 7:  in, in the hands on. And the noise canceling is like good,
Speaker 7:  but not great. Like all noise canceling. Like it does the job, but it's not
Speaker 7:  incredible. But the, the pass through continues to amaze me,
Speaker 7:  like how good it is at passing through. I've used a lot of these
Speaker 7:  headphones now. And like, that's the one place where apple is just like leaps
Speaker 7:  and bounces above everybody.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. By the way, the, the setup for the hands on, they had people with
Speaker 5:  boxes of AirPods pro. Yeah. Yeah. And then so people would
Speaker 5:  try them on and then you would like put 'em away and like a fresh one would
Speaker 5:  be delivered to the room.
Speaker 7:  It's
Speaker 5:  Wild. Like lots of people with lots of boxes of AirPods
Speaker 6:  Pro. So what you're saying is there's gonna be a really good opportunity
Speaker 6:  to buy refurbished AirPods
Speaker 5:  Pros, just go to the apple store on campus.
Speaker 7:  If you want the AirPods that have been and marque brown Lee's ears, that
Speaker 7:  is a thing you can probably accomplish
Speaker 5:  Sell 'em as an NFT. Let's do it all. We'll take the break
Speaker 5:  right back.
Speaker 13:  You know, I wonder do you think that we should all try to spend a
Speaker 13:  little time thinking about a good prank that we could pull?
Speaker 20:  I think it would be a good idea. In fact, if you, if
Speaker 20:  you turn around right now, you'll see that I'm in the studio.
Speaker 13:  This is love is a podcast about people doing incredible things
Speaker 13:  like a woman who moves across the country to work with her hero
Speaker 13:  prince, a man on his way to dinner, who finds a baby
Speaker 13:  on a subway platform, an entire town in Northern
Speaker 13:  Italy that tries to stay quiet at the same time
Speaker 13:  to protect a rare and beautiful sound. And in one of my
Speaker 13:  favorite episodes, a man puts on enormous fake feat and makes
Speaker 13:  tracks up and down the beach, fooling his neighbors for decades.
Speaker 20:  It's the stuff that makes life worth living.
Speaker 13:  I'm Phoebe judge, listen to new episodes of this is love
Speaker 13:  wherever you get your podcasts.
Speaker 5:  Okay? So that was the apple event. Obviously we gotta get all the stuff we
Speaker 5:  gotta review. We gotta talk about it more. We have to experience the island.
Speaker 5:  The other thing that happened on the same day was Tim cook came to code along
Speaker 5:  with Johnny ive and Lauren Powell jobs. And I will just tell you this brief
Speaker 5:  story about what it's like being in the room
Speaker 5:  versus what it's like watching on a stream. And you could have paid to watch
Speaker 5:  a stream Cod virtual tickets. So on stage, very
Speaker 5:  notably Johnny I've sat on one chair with Warren Malcho in the middle
Speaker 5:  and Tim cook sat and another chair. Right? And, and trip MC just had
Speaker 5:  his book after Steve about the differences between those two
Speaker 5:  was just reported that his contract with his new firm love from
Speaker 5:  is not apple in the room. They all, they
Speaker 5:  both had like entourages and they did not sit near each other
Speaker 5:  and they did not talk to each other. Oh, wow. I noticed that. And so like,
Speaker 5:  I'm watching trip. Mickle like clock this cuz he's there.
Speaker 5:  And it was just like a really that part of that dynamic. Like they didn't
Speaker 5:  really talk to each other. They talked about Steve. They were there to talk
Speaker 5:  about Steve. And that was very touching. Right? And like, I believe
Speaker 5:  that the value Steve instilled in apple are still present at apple.
Speaker 5:  Just the way that all three of them talked about it and talked about him
Speaker 5:  and their effect on him. Steve was the first guest at what
Speaker 5:  was then called all things D with Walton, Kara. And so Kara, this was Kara
Speaker 5:  Swisher's final code, the last session. And she teared up at the end, which
Speaker 5:  is remarkable for Kara Swisher. So all that was very poignant.
Speaker 5:  Then we got to the questions.
Speaker 5:  So I asked a question, which, you know,
Speaker 5:  you kind of know you're not gonna get answer sometimes, but I was like, look,
Speaker 5:  you guys all said, Steve would've hated social media and the business they
Speaker 5:  call these apps all run on your phone. What are you gonna do? People buy
Speaker 5:  the phones to run Instagram and TikTok. Like if you didn't have Instagram
Speaker 5:  and TikTok on your phone, like people would buy Android phones. And he is
Speaker 5:  like, yeah, you know, we have screen time. Like that was basically his answer.
Speaker 5:  Didn't he say, I'm not a TikTok expert. Wasn't that right? So then I asked
Speaker 5:  cuz the theme of code was everyone down the line being like TikTok is
Speaker 5:  dangerous. Like Scott, like we should ban it math. Softner who's the
Speaker 5:  CEO of actual Springer, huge media company that UNS political. These are
Speaker 5:  things like it should be ban every democracy. It's just Chinese influence.
Speaker 5:  He's on the board of Netflix. I think there might be, there might be some
Speaker 5:  other motive there. You know, Evan Spiegel was on stage right before
Speaker 5:  he was like, we gotta compete with them, but they're under CFIUS review.
Speaker 5:  And like the United States government kicked like this whole thing. And then
Speaker 5:  Tim is like, I'm not a TikTok expert. And Casey Newton is there and he's
Speaker 5:  like, apple has perfect data about TikTok. Yep.
Speaker 5:  Right. It's the most popular app on their phone. They can see every purchase
Speaker 5:  that's made in the app. They get a cut of all those purchases. Like actually
Speaker 5:  he's definitely a TikTok expert. Like this is the thing that people
Speaker 5:  are using their phones for apple is, but they don't want to talk about it.
Speaker 5:  So whatever, but ask the question. Great. Then the quant hunt
Speaker 5:  who is on the sort of revenue side of Fox media straight
Speaker 5:  up asked about RCS. Not me. Love it. Right. I was like
Speaker 5:  joking with Alex Heath. Like I should ask about RCS, but like I don't think
Speaker 5:  you'd answer the question, right? Yeah. So I try to ask like earthier question,
Speaker 5:  but anyway, qu asked the question, like, you know, Apple's all about connecting
Speaker 5:  people and equality and all this stuff. Like why don't you support RCS? My
Speaker 5:  Android funds are green bubbles. And Tim said, I mean, he,
Speaker 5:  he got like icy. Yeah. He said, I don't hear our
Speaker 5:  customers saying we should put a lot of energy into it, which is hilarious
Speaker 5:  because no customers ask them to put energy into the dynamic island.
Speaker 5:  Right? No customers, like, here's what you do, ship bad keyboards for five
Speaker 5:  years. But this is his answer. Great. And then solo says, well, you know,
Speaker 5:  but there's videos. I wanna send my mom that she can't get. And he was like,
Speaker 5:  buy your mom an iPhone that was like ice cold. And it was very funny. The,
Speaker 5:  the room laughed really hard. Like it was funny. It was obviously telling
Speaker 5:  a joke, but it's where apple is. Right. And like, I will tell you the
Speaker 5:  story we read about that is neck and neck with the iPhone hands on, right?
Speaker 5:  Like the interest in green bubbles and blue bubbles is
Speaker 5:  experienced by lots of people. And so apple being like no one wants,
Speaker 5:  this is actually inaccurate because people are experiencing
Speaker 5:  the reality of some of my friends are green bubbles and some of my friends
Speaker 5:  are blue bubbles and some of these videos are lower resolution. So there's
Speaker 5:  a lot of pretending that this isn't important to people by apple, by
Speaker 5:  tech people, RCS is not important. What is important
Speaker 5:  is communicating with people. What is important is encrypted. End-to-end
Speaker 5:  encrypted messaging by default on your phone. And like,
Speaker 5:  if you're just gonna exclude a huge portion of phones
Speaker 5:  from that by default, like you, I think you should account
Speaker 7:  For it. Well, and I guess I I'm of two minds about this I've because on the
Speaker 7:  one hand, I think if you're Tim cook, you can accurately
Speaker 7:  say you're more supportive of open
Speaker 7:  messaging than pretty much any other messaging app. Like WhatsApp doesn't
Speaker 7:  fall back to SMS. You're just hosed. If you're not using WhatsApp. Right?
Speaker 7:  Like that just, yeah, that just is what it is. There is no system, there
Speaker 7:  is no open system inside of WhatsApp. So even the fact that apple like
Speaker 7:  does a crappy job of supporting an open system is like one order
Speaker 7:  of magnitude, better than most other messaging apps. So on that level. Great.
Speaker 7:  I do think it seems impossible to me that this is not something
Speaker 7:  users have expressed for exactly the reason you're describing. I think the
Speaker 7:  like green bubble versus blue bubble thing is like
Speaker 7:  as its own thing, totally overblown. Like I actually don't think that matters
Speaker 7:  that much at all. It's the thing where my messages don't reliably
Speaker 7:  go through. And when I try to send my wife a picture,
Speaker 7:  it comes through as this teeny tiny little thumbnail sized
Speaker 7:  thing that looks like crap. And it's like, I don't
Speaker 7:  care about whether it's RCS or if apple just like does a better
Speaker 7:  job of supporting MMS. Like the, the underneath part of it
Speaker 7:  is not nearly as interesting as the fact that like the only way I can share
Speaker 7:  a photo with my wife is to upload it to Google photos. And you should actually,
Speaker 7:  if you're apple well, but
Speaker 5:  You could use signal or WhatsApp. Like, but I mean like there is that argument
Speaker 5:  floating out there.
Speaker 7:  Sure. But this is, this is my point. Like she doesn't use those things. Like
Speaker 7:  she uses text messaging and, and this should work. Like we have a
Speaker 7:  standard through which this works and if apple is gonna support it at all,
Speaker 7:  it should at least do the bare minimum to make it work. Functionally,
Speaker 6:  Tim, Tim cook was being like pretty honest that like when he said, buy
Speaker 6:  your mom an app, an apple phone, right. He has zero incentive
Speaker 6:  to, to wanna put RCS, why should he make that interconnectivity
Speaker 6:  easier for anyone? Like, why should he, he shouldn't, if, if you're running
Speaker 6:  a business, there's no reason to do that.
Speaker 5:  And we know from various lawsuits and discovery that they
Speaker 5:  have thought about putting iMessage in Android and they didn't because the
Speaker 5:  answer is then people would buy their kids, cheap Android phones instead
Speaker 5:  of giving them their old phones and upgrading, which is exactly just
Speaker 7:  Callous math. It is their main lock in engine. Like it really, really is
Speaker 5:  In the United States. We'll qualify it in the United States. It's definitely
Speaker 5:  main lock in and they know that teenagers bully each other into buying iPhones
Speaker 5:  because they have green bubbles. This is a real thing that happens. So yeah,
Speaker 5:  it's it was a, it was a moment like the whole, the whole Steve jobs thing,
Speaker 5:  Laurie Powell jobs announced to Steve jobs archive, which you can go to,
Speaker 5:  it's gonna share a bunch of emails and videos of Steve that you maybe haven't
Speaker 5:  seen before. Like that moment was great. And then it ended with buyer, your
Speaker 5:  mom and iPhone, which again, it was sharp, but it was still a joke.
Speaker 5:  But I think it was a very revealing joke.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. It's it was hard to come out of that thinking this will ever happen.
Speaker 5:  He was basically like, we're not gonna fucking do RCS. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Like he was, he was pretty clearly like, we're not doing this. Like,
Speaker 6:  this is a bad line of
Speaker 5:  Questions, but, but like Amy Klobuchar, like floating around the wings being
Speaker 5:  like, yeah, you are, you know, she was there. She talked about the whole
Speaker 5:  thing. So was code. We have lots of coverage of the stuff I'm excited for
Speaker 5:  reviews. I think the dynamic island will reveal itself to us and do
Speaker 5:  time through usage. I'm excited by this camera. So that's all coming up.
Speaker 5:  We gotta run and we've gone way over here as you people have demanded
Speaker 5:  by the way. Thank you for people who sent nice notes to Liam. I really appreciate
Speaker 5:  it. That was very nice of you. Please keep doing that.
Speaker 7:  Also, if you have apple questions, call the Vergecast hotline. It's eight,
Speaker 7:  six verge one one, and ask us all your apple questions. I think in two
Speaker 7:  Wednesdays, we're gonna do a bunch of Q and a about apple stuff. So if you
Speaker 7:  have burning questions, call 'em in. All
Speaker 5:  Right. That's it. That's Vergecast you can tweet at us. I'm at reckless Alex's
Speaker 5:  Alex crayons. David is at Pierce. We love hearing from you. Call the number,
Speaker 5:  write us notes only nice notes to Liam. We'll see you next week. Rock roll.
Speaker 1:  And that's a wrap for Vergecast this week. We'd love to hear from you. Shoot
Speaker 1:  us an email at vergecast@theverge.com. The Vergecast is a
Speaker 1:  production of the verge and the box media podcast network. The show is produced
Speaker 1:  by me, Liam, James, and our senior audio director. Andrew Marino,
Speaker 1:  our editorial director is Brooke. That's it. We'll see you next
Speaker 1:  week.