# Transcript
ID: b15e7de0-a67f-11ec-a1cf-b7e312e1d9d1
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: We reviewed the Mac Studio, the Studio Display, the iPhone SE, and the iPad Air
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/546322891291838131/7805117081990755149/s93290-US-5538s-1647581256.mp3
Description: Nilay Patel, Alex Cranz, Monica Chin, Allison Johnson, and Dan Seifert discuss The Verge's reviews of the Apple products announced last week: the new iPhone SE, iPad Air, Mac Studio, and Studio Display.
Speaker 1:  This week on the verge cast, Alex Cranz Dan Seaford, Alison Johnson
Speaker 1:  and Monica chin. During the show, we talk about all the apple reviews, the
Speaker 1:  iPhone se the Mac studio, the studio display and the iPad air. That's coming
Speaker 1:  up on the virtual test. Now we all have unique lives. Whether you invested
Speaker 1:  in crypto for the first time, this year own an up and coming small business,
Speaker 1:  or are raising rambunctious twins. Luckily, TurboTax live has
Speaker 1:  experts who can answer your tax questions, walk you through the whole process
Speaker 1:  or do your taxes for you from start to finish. No matter your unique
Speaker 1:  situation to TurboTax live experts and interesting life
Speaker 1:  can mean an even greater refund. Visit turbotax.com to
Speaker 1:  learn more. You do your thing. They've got your taxes, Intuit,
Speaker 1:  TurboTax live good news. You reached your Q1 benchmarks. Now you still
Speaker 1:  have three more queues. When you look out into the sea of CRMs, it can look
Speaker 1:  extremely blue, but HubSpot is here to give your company a more human approach.
Speaker 1:  It's a CRM platform. That's easy to use aligns all of your teams seamlessly
Speaker 1:  and delivers a better experience for your customers. So your business is
Speaker 1:  like a friendly neighbor and not some forceful sales company that will stop
Speaker 1:  at nothing to close deal. Learn how to grow better by connecting your people,
Speaker 1:  your customers, and your business@hubspot.com.
Speaker 1:  Hello, and welcome to the Vergecast flagship podcast,
Speaker 1:  bad charts. And so I wanted to start in a high, and then I was like,
Speaker 1:  what's in my heart. And it's chart crime, which is my new
Speaker 1:  favorite phrase.
Speaker 3:  There's a lot of
Speaker 1:  Them. I'm afraid of the light out screens. This here
Speaker 3:  I am so excited for this very specific podcast.
Speaker 1:  It's this one that's going to get off the rails. Pumped dancy for this here.
Speaker 1:  How are you
Speaker 4:  Doing?
Speaker 1:  Alison is here housing. Hello. A little bit later. Monica is going to join
Speaker 1:  us cause it's apple review week.
Speaker 4:  It is it's been apple review week. It's
Speaker 1:  Been an apple review
Speaker 3:  For a week.
Speaker 1:  Alison reviewed the iPhone se Monica review the Mac
Speaker 1:  studio, which I reviewed the studio display. It's
Speaker 1:  we read both things at the same time, but I was focused on displaying. She
Speaker 1:  was focused on and then Dan reviewed the iPad, the iPad air. So lots of apple
Speaker 1:  stuff. There's some other stuff we should talk about. But like Alex
Speaker 1:  said, this, this podcast is going to get wild. Cause
Speaker 1:  there's good parts and there's bad parts and there's medium parts. We're
Speaker 1:  going to laugh. We're going to cry. It's
Speaker 4:  The full spectrum.
Speaker 1:  There's going to be some very oblique references to Dieter jokes. It's gonna
Speaker 1:  be great. Let's start with the iPhone. Alison, your V the
Speaker 1:  iPhone se it feels like there's a lot to say. And it also
Speaker 1:  nothing to say. It's a very nice phone.
Speaker 5:  That's the thing it's like, it's still what the iPhone se has
Speaker 5:  been. It is a very inexpensive way to get into
Speaker 5:  Apple's ecosystem. You get, so it starts at
Speaker 5:  4 29. You get, you know, the newest processor and
Speaker 5:  the eight 15, but it's kind of just a lot of the same of
Speaker 5:  what the iPhone se has offered in the past. There's I mean, there's five
Speaker 5:  G now, which you know, where am I excited?
Speaker 5:  But yeah, it's still, it's still a really solid, like,
Speaker 5:  amazing mid-range phone. But I think at this point, this is
Speaker 5:  just kind of like my whole takeaway and the review is
Speaker 5:  a 4.7 inch screen is just not cutting it. And
Speaker 5:  I say this as a person who loves small phones
Speaker 5:  dearly, they're wonderful.
Speaker 3:  I'm with you.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And it's, it's like such a joy to put this phone
Speaker 5:  in my coat pocket and have that moment where I'm like, oh, is the phone in
Speaker 5:  my pocket? I'm like, yes, it is. It was just really small.
Speaker 5:  But it just, it feels really cramped. And it's those
Speaker 5:  bezels really it's like the aspect ratio of the
Speaker 5:  screen. And there's a lot of real estate taken up by the chunky bezzles.
Speaker 5:  It's an iPhone eight design, which was put out to
Speaker 5:  pasture quite awhile ago, except for the iPhone se
Speaker 3:  They had kept the size of the phone, like the out the external size of the
Speaker 3:  phone, but gotten rid of the bezels and just made it all screen. Would
Speaker 3:  you have liked it more?
Speaker 5:  I definitely would've liked him more, but then it's like, what does the iPhone
Speaker 5:  mini and then that's a philosophical
Speaker 5:  question you have to ask
Speaker 1:  You say it's an iPhone eight design. I just want to come. Isn't it more like
Speaker 1:  an iPhone six design, right? This basic
Speaker 1:  designer floating around for a very long time.
Speaker 5:  I have my original S
Speaker 1:  E that's like the iPhone five.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Yeah. It's it goes back. It is a throwback. Yeah. I don't
Speaker 5:  know. It's not the worst. You have the home button still, which some
Speaker 5:  people really want and they don't want face ID. And
Speaker 5:  that iPhone se will give you that you can get the latest
Speaker 5:  performance. You get a great phone, you get to keep your touch
Speaker 5:  ID. So it like, if that's you, then this
Speaker 5:  is your phone. And it's awesome.
Speaker 1:  Sorry. I was talking to our friend Joanna Sarnath wall street journal. And
Speaker 1:  she went through the same review week that we did. And she was like, he don't
Speaker 1:  understand for wall street journal readers. The iPhone
Speaker 1:  se is the Superbowl. Like, this is what they want.
Speaker 1:  This is what they care about the most. She was like, I can't screw up the
Speaker 1:  sec review. This is it. Like they don't, they, they love
Speaker 1:  the home button. They want a great camera. They don't
Speaker 1:  want to mess with what they know. This is like the phone for them.
Speaker 1:  I think it's fascinating. Right? Like our audience is very much like what
Speaker 1:  is the latest and great. I mean, if you're listening to this show, you were
Speaker 1:  very interested in things like phone specifications, at least I
Speaker 1:  believe you are. And I just think that's like, you know, Apple's product
Speaker 1:  line is so big. That's like basically every $50 price point or I guess now
Speaker 1:  in the 5g era at every $70 price point, apple
Speaker 1:  has a phone for you. And this one just like holding down the low end.
Speaker 1:  But then I just looking at their pricing, you can get an iPhone
Speaker 1:  11, which is kind of like a dramatically better phone
Speaker 1:  with a bigger screen, for what, 70 bucks
Speaker 1:  more it's 4 99. And it's like, I would just get that.
Speaker 1:  Like, you can get 128 gig version of iPhone 11 for five forty nine, but
Speaker 3:  Would you have 5g?
Speaker 4:  You, you wouldn't have 5g. But I think that there's something to be said
Speaker 4:  about like how most iPhone se buyers are actually buying their
Speaker 4:  phone and they're not rolling up to apple.com and ordering it there.
Speaker 4:  And they're probably not really ordering it or buying it from the apple store.
Speaker 4:  They're probably buying it through a carrier. And the carrier is like, it's
Speaker 4:  $11 a month for the, and then like into tiniest print, it's $11 a
Speaker 4:  month. And then it says for the rest of your life, but like in the tiniest
Speaker 4:  print. Okay.
Speaker 1:  And then they put you on a 5g plan and that grant is more expensive, even
Speaker 1:  though you don't need it,
Speaker 4:  But what they're not looking at like, oh, this one is 600 or $500
Speaker 4:  versus 430. They're like, this is $11 a month. It's like really cheap.
Speaker 4:  It has all the stuff that I'm familiar with. That's why I'm buying it. But
Speaker 4:  like, I, I really also feel like the reason people buy the se the
Speaker 4:  marketing line says they love the home button and it's familiar, but the
Speaker 4:  real line is it's cheap. And that is why it is sell itself. It is
Speaker 4:  purely because it's cheap. If apple made a cheap iPhone
Speaker 4:  mini or iPhone 11 design, that was just
Speaker 4:  $400 or $430. That's the one people would buy
Speaker 4:  if it was cheap, it's just because it's cheap. That's the reality of it.
Speaker 3:  Here's my question. iPhone se comes out if they did an
Speaker 3:  iPhone X S E extra L a large iPhone
Speaker 3:  se same price, giant screen. Would that sell
Speaker 3:  more?
Speaker 1:  Yes.
Speaker 4:  You could tell by just how poor the iPhone mini sales have been. People always
Speaker 4:  choose the bigger screen at the same price. They choose the bigger screen.
Speaker 3:  That's the thing I poke at is what, if this is get a little galaxy
Speaker 3:  brain, what if the reason people don't
Speaker 3:  buy the mini and buy the se is because the se is small,
Speaker 3:  but also cheap. And the people who want a small
Speaker 3:  phone also do not care about specs.
Speaker 4:  Well, I think all the people that want a small phone, right? For tech blogs,
Speaker 4:  but that's the entire market.
Speaker 4:  I mean like, Alison, not to put you too much on the spot here, but
Speaker 4:  like, you like small phones, which is fair and cool. But what phone do you
Speaker 4:  own?
Speaker 7:  That's an iPhone 11.
Speaker 4:  So like,
Speaker 3:  It was the smallest phone you could get. Yeah,
Speaker 1:  That's right Dan. Huh?
Speaker 1:  What now, counselor?
Speaker 3:  I'm just excited to have somebody on the verge cast today who also likes
Speaker 3:  small phones. Yeah, it does. I have been bullied so
Speaker 3:  often by large phone takes unfair.
Speaker 1:  We have a lot of small phone proponents on our staff, but I will just offer
Speaker 1:  you this counterpoint. Yes. My mother was a
Speaker 1:  devout Steve jobs fan. Like
Speaker 1:  this woman read the biography when it came out and called me in tears.
Speaker 1:  And she was like, after he left, all the designs went bad and these phones
Speaker 1:  are ugly. And so she wanted to give up her leg
Speaker 1:  last, Steve jobs, iPhone five.
Speaker 5:  I love her.
Speaker 1:  So she held onto for our city, the tiny phone. And then it was time to finally
Speaker 1:  give up the phone could not, was not operative anymore.
Speaker 1:  And we went to the store and she was like, I just want a small one. All these
Speaker 1:  phones are too big. They ruined it. Like, this is the conversation I'm having
Speaker 1:  in the middle of the pandemic in an apple store. She's like after Steve
Speaker 1:  jobs died, like I can't be here with you.
Speaker 1:  And I was like, no, you don't understand the font size on your phone is out
Speaker 1:  of control. This display scaling on your phone is
Speaker 1:  like, it's tiny screen, huge letters. Like you're reading one word
Speaker 1:  at a time. So I bought her the pro max
Speaker 1:  and it's great. And now she is never going back.
Speaker 1:  She's like, this is the best phone I've ever had. Right. Because it's
Speaker 1:  gigantic. And if I could buy her that mid range, like
Speaker 1:  Samsung makes a thousand phones like this, the mid range phone with a
Speaker 1:  huge screen. And that's like their sweet spot. And I feel like apple doesn't
Speaker 1:  have that things. We ended up in this weird conversation with the iPhone
Speaker 1:  mini. But if they had that thing, it would be by far and
Speaker 1:  away, the best selling. That's what the 11, the
Speaker 1:  XR was That weirdo phone that they made.
Speaker 4:  I mean, you could look at this, like the history of the iPhone, the iPhone
Speaker 4:  sales didn't really skyrocket until the six plus came out.
Speaker 4:  Apple finally came out with a big screen, iPhone and sales took off. And
Speaker 4:  then the screen has gotten progressively bigger cross the line until they
Speaker 4:  introduced the mini, which no one bought
Speaker 1:  We've gotten, we've gotten so far away. See,
Speaker 1:  see Alex, he's you called it. You're like, this is going to go sideways the
Speaker 1:  se itself house. And tell us about the phone.
Speaker 5:  It's nice. I mean, it really flies. Like there's
Speaker 5:  nothing oil. There's very little that I feel like I
Speaker 5:  can't do on it that I can do on a thousand dollar phone, which has been
Speaker 5:  the case with the se then it's, that's just kind of,
Speaker 5:  it's trick is like, this is less than $500 and it does an amazing
Speaker 5:  job. If you look at it purely like in the mid range
Speaker 5:  class, like across Android to it, you know, it gives
Speaker 5:  you IP 67 rating got wireless charging. It's not
Speaker 5:  MagSafe, but you get the cheap charging and that
Speaker 5:  processor it's immediately stand out. It's sort of,
Speaker 5:  it would, it would be a no brainer to me if this
Speaker 5:  screen was a little more modern, but yeah, I
Speaker 5:  just found myself, like, not that the iPhone se
Speaker 5:  owners probably going to be doing a lot of gaming, but I'd put
Speaker 5:  tension impact on there. And you're just, your sons are over so much
Speaker 5:  on the skinny. I was like peeking around, like, where's
Speaker 5:  my, oh, okay.
Speaker 4:  I thought it was really interesting the way you put it in your review that
Speaker 4:  like just the modern web and modern apps are just not designed for
Speaker 4:  16 by nine, 4.7 inch screen anymore. And that's where everything
Speaker 4:  starts feeling cramped, the gaming example, but like, think about your email
Speaker 4:  app. Like you see what two emails on a screen before you have to start scrolling
Speaker 4:  or, you know, other, other applications that are very standard in like
Speaker 4:  everyday applications are all taking advantage of the
Speaker 4:  wider aspect ratio, the taller screens, because there's more real estate
Speaker 4:  there to play with. And when you don't have that, especially if you're used
Speaker 4:  to it, when you go back to like, like maybe if you know the se buyer or someone
Speaker 4:  who's never had it, they're not used to it. They're known, know what they're
Speaker 4:  missing, but if you're used to it and you try to go back to that, it is like
Speaker 4:  a jarring experience. And I think that's really what came through in your
Speaker 4:  review.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Yeah. I think if you're, if you're coming from an se and it's
Speaker 5:  just time to get a new phone and you want to get this one
Speaker 5:  because you want to hang on to it for the next five or six years, like do
Speaker 5:  it, you will be so happy. But
Speaker 5:  yeah, I can't, I can't envision coming from a bigger screen
Speaker 5:  and going to back to the 4.7 inch because
Speaker 5:  everything is so tiny. I'm like, I'm doing my duo lingo and
Speaker 5:  I'm like, I can't read the words I need to,
Speaker 5:  I need some kind of new glasses. I don't know. Also getting old.
Speaker 3:  What was the battery life like on it? Cause I think that was like a big question,
Speaker 3:  mark, coming into this.
Speaker 5:  I thought it was fine. Yeah. The previous
Speaker 5:  model battery life was a little iffy. It was a, a
Speaker 5:  little dodging. I think whether you could get through a full day
Speaker 5:  of kind of moderate use in my experience, a
Speaker 5:  moderate day, I could get to the end of the day. And I still had enough in
Speaker 5:  the tank to get into some of the next day too. So it
Speaker 5:  definitely, it feels like an improvement to me. I think it's a
Speaker 5:  heavy user. And that was
Speaker 3:  Like with 5g on and doing its thing.
Speaker 5:  Yes. Which 5g is questionable where I live,
Speaker 5:  but
Speaker 3:  No millimeter wave.
Speaker 1:  I want to come back to the thing you said about five or six years. So it
Speaker 1:  has an, a 15 in it, which is Apple's highest and
Speaker 1:  iPhone chip. It does not have an M one L TriNet. It has
Speaker 1:  a 15 in it. Maybe it
Speaker 4:  Should,
Speaker 1:  But what this thing needs is 48. GPU's,
Speaker 1:  that's got 15 in it, which, you know, for
Speaker 1:  a $430 fund is pretty remarkable. And that's, I think
Speaker 1:  that's an, Apple's really good at software updates over time, much better
Speaker 1:  than any Android phone vendor. So that's where, okay.
Speaker 1:  Five or six years, or this phone sounds really reasonable. And that's why
Speaker 1:  you put the really high-end chip in there because you're expecting
Speaker 1:  people to hold onto it for a long time. But I was just put that right next
Speaker 1:  to what you're saying about the screen, which is already feel small
Speaker 1:  for the current state of web in apps, six years from now,
Speaker 1:  like this trend is not slowing down like six years from now
Speaker 1:  who knows, like every developer could be assuming that your phone
Speaker 1:  unfolds to become a much larger screen,
Speaker 1:  which is right. And like, I don't know that's going to happen, but you just
Speaker 1:  see the trend line is when we make fancy features on the
Speaker 1:  website, right. We like test them out. And we T we, we know the, most of
Speaker 1:  our readers are mobile, but we just sort of assume they have big phones because
Speaker 1:  that's what the data tells us. And so you just keep this trend
Speaker 1:  going, and it's like, soon, you will not be able to read the web
Speaker 1:  on your tiny phone. The processor will be there. And maybe the, you
Speaker 1:  know, the mobile network speed will be there, but you're just going to get
Speaker 1:  completely left behind by the screen size. This is the first time I've thought
Speaker 1:  about that with an iPhone.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And I felt so I, so I dug out
Speaker 5:  the 2016 iPhone se I put iOS 15 on it,
Speaker 5:  which worked. And, but I was going through something on
Speaker 5:  Instagram and I was trying to light something
Speaker 5:  that someone like damn to me. And I physically couldn't. It was
Speaker 5:  like a real estate that I needed to be hitting on this
Speaker 5:  green, just like didn't exist. And it was sort of like,
Speaker 5:  yeah, this is what this is maybe going to come to in five
Speaker 5:  years when you're on your 4.7 inch screen, and everybody else
Speaker 5:  has the folding, whatever. And it just kind of
Speaker 5:  sucks. It's like, that is the really cool thing about this phone is you think,
Speaker 5:  keep it for so long. And it's this
Speaker 5:  2016 se is running iOS 15
Speaker 5:  fine, but it's, it's like the modern web
Speaker 5:  has been as Dawn. So
Speaker 1:  Let's talk about the camera real quick. It's got the single camera, no nightmare,
Speaker 1:  which seems like a real miss to me.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And it's, it just seems to be a choice on
Speaker 5:  Apple's part, because I can't imagine that the processors,
Speaker 5:  there are other phones with this processor that have night mode that
Speaker 5:  kind of stinks. There's, there's a lot of mid-range phones on
Speaker 5:  Android that have perfectly decent night modes and
Speaker 5:  cost about the same amount of money have less fancy processors.
Speaker 5:  So that, that sticks out a little bit. It is the same
Speaker 5:  camera hardware as the previous generation, still a
Speaker 5:  single camera, which doesn't bother me a lot. I think
Speaker 5:  people probably aren't buying it for the camera, or they're not
Speaker 5:  super interested in, in an ultra wide or
Speaker 5:  kind of messing with a lot of settings. Maybe, maybe you are, but
Speaker 5:  what you do get is pretty good. I mean, it's an iPhone camera it's
Speaker 5:  it does what it does very well. And video recording is
Speaker 5:  very good, especially in the mid-range class.
Speaker 1:  Do you think it's on par with the iPhone 11, for example,
Speaker 5:  It's pretty close. Yeah. I think that, I think the night mode is
Speaker 5:  I do, I do. In fact,
Speaker 1:  The 11 is when I stopped using my RX 100 as much. That's that's and I know
Speaker 1:  that's the fun you have. So that's like the comparison making, when the 11
Speaker 1:  came out, I noticed that I slowly stopped using my RX 100, as much
Speaker 1:  as I had been, other than the tennis looked horrible. So that's probably
Speaker 1:  like embedded in my brain. So this is like, goes back to the
Speaker 1:  thing about the wall street journal audience, like the update, you can bring
Speaker 1:  an audience it's like, the camera is way better and you don't have to think
Speaker 1:  about it or you can zoom. Right. Cause
Speaker 1:  that, that breaks people's brains that you can zoom in an iPhone, but it
Speaker 1:  makes the image quality worse, like significantly worse in digital zoom.
Speaker 1:  And that to me is just like adding Nymo to this would have effectively been
Speaker 1:  free. It would have blown every other mid-range phone out of the
Speaker 1:  water and everyone could have seen that they got something
Speaker 1:  cool. And it just seems like such an odd feature omission.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I, I can't figure it out. And there's sort of like a
Speaker 5:  theory. If you look at the product cycle, it was four
Speaker 5:  years between the first two versions of those phone and then
Speaker 5:  two years. So this has made me like the S
Speaker 5:  eight S is one theory on it. But
Speaker 5:  like maybe in another two years, we're going to get, you know, that, that
Speaker 5:  more, a bigger screen you're going to get,
Speaker 3:  Could they do it as a software update? Like, could we, could they just
Speaker 3:  announce it when they announced all the other iPhones and be like, and by
Speaker 3:  the way, this one's getting mode,
Speaker 1:  Are you, you D when iOS 16 comes out,
Speaker 1:  Like we've added, who knows?
Speaker 5:  That would be great. I don't know, write to your Senator
Speaker 1:  Right. To your Senator. And okay. I want to end this by complaining with
Speaker 1:  the New York times, which I've been
Speaker 1:  quietly vibrating in the background ready to do so I don't understand what's
Speaker 1:  going on at the times, review I'm certain the person who had served you is
Speaker 1:  lovely. The New York times has fully decided
Speaker 1:  that people should not care about their smartphone cameras. Like they
Speaker 1:  just don't think many people care about better pictures. So they wrote this
Speaker 1:  review of, of the se. And I just want to read this line to you
Speaker 1:  and you tell me what you think. Cause I think it is bonkers.
Speaker 1:  So it's all the stuff you probably want. This one or $30 phone. If you meet
Speaker 1:  this, any of these criteria, you don't care about features like ultra Fest
Speaker 1:  cellular fine. You correctly recognize that smartphone technology has been
Speaker 1:  around for so long. You should be paying less for it. Fine. And then there's
Speaker 1:  this line. You don't care about what the number of camera lenses or
Speaker 1:  pixels on a screen, tell your friends and colleagues about your
Speaker 1:  wealth. And I'm just like, yeah. I mean, okay. Maybe I
Speaker 1:  just want to flex like my ranger over keys in the club
Speaker 1:  with my iPhone, that anybody can buy. I'm
Speaker 1:  sure. That's just who I've been. But like the number of lenses it's
Speaker 1:  like that helps you take better pictures. And
Speaker 1:  like all anybody cares about these phones anymore is like the
Speaker 1:  cameras. It's like, when we do reviews, what are all the questions we get
Speaker 1:  our cameras and maybe that's our audience at Southwestern, all journalists.
Speaker 1:  And other times, I just don't understand this approach to this review.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It's kind of news to me. If like multiple cameras on a
Speaker 5:  phone is a status thing. There's a lot of
Speaker 5:  fun. I have a lot of cameras. I don't know.
Speaker 4:  I'm only carrying that Nokia nine preview around,
Speaker 4:  it's got six camera lenses on the back.
Speaker 3:  That's the last time a phone was considered one like a
Speaker 3:  status symbol, right? Like 20 14, 20 15, when
Speaker 3:  they're like, we're making these phones for billionaires. And then we stop.
Speaker 4:  I, I think there's something about like folding phones, folding phones, when
Speaker 4:  people see that, that it's different. They like,
Speaker 1:  That's just the form factor. Eventually. I'll be like, I'm just telling you
Speaker 1:  it. And I haven't rolled up in the, in a one time. But if you roll up in
Speaker 1:  the club and you're like, I haven't, I phone 13, bro, like
Speaker 1:  shit is not gonna work.
Speaker 3:  You don't have a broken iPhone 13 pro because the bouncer will
Speaker 3:  throw into the ground.
Speaker 1:  Like I have the fanciest Toyota Camry that has ever been.
Speaker 5:  So yeah, it's not hard. I mean, mid-range funds will just
Speaker 5:  like pack on my camera lenses, like have a
Speaker 5:  macro lens on my phone. Like that's not really gonna get you
Speaker 5:  anywhere special.
Speaker 1:  Well, yeah, for whatever reason, the fact that the times is decided that
Speaker 1:  good photos, it's not a thing that fund buyers should care about. It just
Speaker 1:  breaks my brain completely. And then the idea that the number of lenses
Speaker 1:  are signifier of wealth. And that is the only reason you should care about
Speaker 1:  the number of lenses is just like, no, one's rolling
Speaker 1:  up with a light show, camera
Speaker 1:  96 lens.
Speaker 4:  I'm just, I just looked at the back of my iPhone and now I'm very confident
Speaker 4:  in my family's hereditary wealth for the next few generations.
Speaker 1:  I honestly think like apple should at my request is like add night
Speaker 1:  mode to the camera. The people who buy this phone will probably be
Speaker 1:  happier if they take better photos in low light.
Speaker 5:  Absolutely.
Speaker 1:  That's like the main thing that is confounding to people. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. That's a little one. I don't get, I don't buy any good
Speaker 5:  explanation from apple. Just put night load on it. I'll
Speaker 5:  start a campaign. I'll start a letter writing campaign.
Speaker 1:  Can I, can I tell you what the time said about photography? That's
Speaker 4:  My favorite list.
Speaker 1:  They said you can always just use the flash.
Speaker 5:  Oh,
Speaker 1:  Just you're technically true. You can and make
Speaker 1:  everything into some sort of bizarre nineties Cobra, snake, photo shoot.
Speaker 1:  That is a choice you have, you can make your children look like they are
Speaker 1:  completely strung out at any moment of the day
Speaker 1:  by shooting photos of them, especially your led flash on an
Speaker 1:  iPhone. Anyway, that is confounding. I just want to complain about it because
Speaker 1:  I can't let it go.
Speaker 4:  I just want to clarify you can't always use the flash because like the iPhone
Speaker 4:  has auto or off on the flash. So the iPhone decides whether you can use the
Speaker 4:  flash or not.
Speaker 3:  Well, you put it in video mode
Speaker 4:  And then, and then you just have the light on
Speaker 1:  The
Speaker 4:  Flashlight and then you take a picture.
Speaker 1:  What you wanna do is you want to switch. You're already behind the curve.
Speaker 1:  Camera two it's 10 80 P video mode. It
Speaker 4:  Does 4k.
Speaker 1:  It does 4k
Speaker 4:  That's. What's so baffling about it. It records 4k video. That's better than
Speaker 4:  like basically any Android phone you can buy, but they didn't put night mode
Speaker 4:  in it.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Utterly baffling. I love it. And also, because this is like
Speaker 1:  full on 4k 60. Yes.
Speaker 1:  In the base storage is what? 32 gigs for C4. Okay. So you can
Speaker 1:  record 10 minutes, 4k 6,000.
Speaker 1:  That's great. I love it. All right. That's the iPhone se
Speaker 1:  I will complain about the New York times more at a later date. Rest is
Speaker 1:  short. I can do it at the drop,
Speaker 1:  but Alison, thank you so much. It was a great review. You were just saying
Speaker 1:  there's another Samsung phone, like a mid-range Samsung phone. That's worth
Speaker 1:  comparing to us, right? That's on the side now.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Samsung just announced a 53 5 gene,
Speaker 5:  which is a 52 5g last year mid-ranged
Speaker 5:  phone and about 500 bucks. I, I thought it was really the
Speaker 5:  best bet for that price range on Android.
Speaker 5:  So they announced the newest version. It is
Speaker 5:  $50 cheaper, which puts it in just under the
Speaker 5:  iPhone se at the 128 gigabyte
Speaker 5:  storage level. So wonder if they're doing a
Speaker 5:  little like undercutting there.
Speaker 4:  How big is the screen?
Speaker 5:  It's much bigger. It's a 6.5 inch. I
Speaker 5:  believe it.
Speaker 4:  An iPhone se
Speaker 5:  You could fit several iPhone se than to it,
Speaker 5:  but it's, it's the closest thing I think to in
Speaker 5:  there, they're getting there on the software updates to their
Speaker 5:  promising four years of Android OS updates
Speaker 5:  in their five years of security updates. So I feel like Samsung
Speaker 5:  is like slowly chipping away at what was just
Speaker 5:  kind of like a Guinea for the iPhone. Se was like, you're going to get all
Speaker 5:  these years. And software updates is super cheap and it
Speaker 5:  is, you know, built really well. So that's one to watch. I'm really
Speaker 5:  interested in trying it out and word on the street also
Speaker 5:  is that it does not have millimeter wave just like the iPhone se
Speaker 5:  and will also be sold at Verizon
Speaker 5:  Because our nightmare is over.
Speaker 1:  Oh, Allison, before you go, do you have a, do you have like an Iran update
Speaker 1:  for every time you're on. I'm like I got to ask there's one person who cares
Speaker 1:  about Iran. As much as me. It's Allison.
Speaker 5:  I have no update. I
Speaker 5:  do. We have a fourth wireless carrier in this country.
Speaker 5:  No.
Speaker 1:  Alright. Just
Speaker 1:  around the clock dish network, four years ago, dish network promises store.
Speaker 3:  We're going to do an emergency verge cast. When Iran finally happens,
Speaker 1:  We should
Speaker 3:  Absolutely.
Speaker 1:  The project Genesis Genesis Vergecast it's Jenna
Speaker 1:  five says by the way that we're going to be onto like the six G hype cycle
Speaker 1:  by the time, you know, it's going to be very depressing. All right,
Speaker 1:  Alison, thank you so much for joining the show. We'll be right back with
Speaker 1:  Monica Chen. Talk about this Mac studio.
Speaker 1:  People think unusual circumstances mean complicated taxes, but for
Speaker 1:  TurboTax live experts. That's what makes things interesting.
Speaker 1:  We all have unique lives, whether you're invested in crypto for the first
Speaker 1:  time, this year on an up and coming small business or raising rambunctious
Speaker 1:  twins. Luckily TurboTax live has experts who can answer your tax questions,
Speaker 1:  walk you through the whole process or do your taxes for you from start to
Speaker 1:  finish. They help you get every deduction you deserve, no matter your unique
Speaker 1:  situation. And you can talk to a TurboTax live expert through your phone
Speaker 1:  or computer without leaving your house. TurboTax live experts are here to
Speaker 1:  help you however you need. And if you need an extra hand, hand your taxes
Speaker 1:  off to them and they'll do it all for you. So TurboTax live exports and
Speaker 1:  interesting life can mean an even greater refund. Visit turbotax.com to
Speaker 1:  learn more. You do your thing. They've got your taxes, Intuit TurboTax
Speaker 1:  live it's 2007 and people are hustling. Two roommates need some
Speaker 1:  cash. They start renting an air mattress in their apartment. Strangers stay
Speaker 1:  with them. Those roommates earn some extra spending money. And Airbnb is
Speaker 1:  born. You know what happened? Next? That little tech company exploded with
Speaker 1:  rentals available in more than 100,000 cities. But one of those cities was
Speaker 1:  prepared to go to battle on behalf of renters and hotels to keep Airbnb
Speaker 1:  at bay business wars from wonder is a podcast that looks at the world's biggest
Speaker 1:  company rivals their new season, Airbnb versus New York city examines. How
Speaker 1:  that struggle became a symbol for the tug of war between startups and regulators.
Speaker 1:  It started as a clever way to earn a little extra cash, quickly transformed
Speaker 1:  into something a lot more complicated. She'll get into impact the housing
Speaker 1:  and rental markets. When New York city officials decided to curb the expansion
Speaker 1:  of Airbnb into their city, the tech giant refused to back down and that's
Speaker 1:  when things aren't really interesting. Listen to business wars on apple podcasts,
Speaker 1:  Amazon music, or you can listen. Ad-free by joining Wondery plus in the
Speaker 1:  Wondery app.
Speaker 1:  We're back. Monica chin is here. Hey Monica. Hello. It's good to see
Speaker 1:  you. I feel like we've been talking every minute of the day for the past
Speaker 1:  week about these reviews. So Monica got the
Speaker 1:   ultra max studio and the studio display
Speaker 1:  with a nano texture coating. And then I had the M
Speaker 1:  one max max studio and the regular studio display with the regular coding.
Speaker 1:  And I mostly just had benchmarks and then gave the computer to Monica. So
Speaker 1:  she did all the computer review stuff along with our amazing video and
Speaker 1:  art teams. And I mostly just see all the, with webcams. So
Speaker 1:  let's start with the computers. It
Speaker 1:  seems Monica like apple has pulled off a chip design
Speaker 1:  dream with this MUN ultra and then package it in a computer that everyone
Speaker 1:  seems to be very happy with.
Speaker 9:  Yep. That's pretty much right. Basically, you know, for years
Speaker 9:  and years and years people, various companies have been trying to take two
Speaker 9:  GPU's and make them into one GPU. And
Speaker 9:  it's, you know, usually you just put two GPU's or two
Speaker 9:  chips on one board and you put it in the system and then you
Speaker 9:  basically say the software has to figure out how to make those
Speaker 9:  two GPU's work together. And that's really difficult to
Speaker 9:  automate because they really need to be in sync with each other. Like if
Speaker 9:  they're, if one of them is not rendering things, when it's supposed
Speaker 9:  to, it can throw everything off. So usually what programs do is they just
Speaker 9:  have the two GPU's like do separate things. So Apple's
Speaker 9:  taken two M one maxes. They've used this technique called ultra fusion
Speaker 9:  to put them into one GPU. But the difference here and what
Speaker 9:  we haven't seen done successfully at this scale before is that
Speaker 9:  they are actually presenting themselves as one chip. So, so like a
Speaker 9:  software we'll see them as one chip and it will just give them a
Speaker 9:  task and they will do the task and divide it between themselves. So the software
Speaker 9:  doesn't have to do anything. You, the user do not have to do anything manually.
Speaker 9:  It, they just work as one chip. There's a 2.5 terabytes of data
Speaker 9:  like going between them or that that's the bandwidth that it supports. So
Speaker 9:  these things are able to talk to each other and to Macko S
Speaker 9:  at like a speed that we just have not seen before. And that's like a
Speaker 9:  crazy amount of power that they've put in this thing.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I would say that the clarification I make, I think I'm pretty sure
Speaker 1:  Macalester is helping a lot here. Like the, you know,
Speaker 1:  the promise of all apple things that is on the hardware and the software.
Speaker 1:  So it seems like, yep, they've done this ultra fusion chip
Speaker 1:  design technique, which she talked about a bit last
Speaker 1:  week. Right? They've assembled the chips in this way. That seems to be more
Speaker 1:  prevalent, but they've actually pulled it off. And then between the
Speaker 1:  chip and the operating system application
Speaker 1:  like Adobe premiere, which is always the one that comes up when we do these
Speaker 1:  reviews does not need to be, it's just
Speaker 1:  seamless for it.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. You didn't have to like actually do anything. Cause I know a lot of
Speaker 3:  times when you do these kinds of things, you have to tinker, right. Like
Speaker 3:  to get, sometimes somebody will see it. One program will be like, oh
Speaker 3:  yeah, I see these, this, these two things is one. And sometimes you'll have
Speaker 3:  to spend 40 hours downloading drivers and installing them. And this just
Speaker 3:  like you turned on premier and premier, I was like, oh, Hey, cool. You have
Speaker 3:  the new, like, did you have to update premiere? Did you have to do, like,
Speaker 9:  We were never asked to do anything that like, I would have thought we
Speaker 9:  did not have to do on the Maxim machine. You don't have to divide anything
Speaker 9:  manually.
Speaker 3:  You didn't have to like reach out to Adobe and be like, send me a special
Speaker 3:  updated version
Speaker 9:  For a dual GBU set up. No, we did not. That's
Speaker 3:  Cool. That is super cool.
Speaker 9:  It worked out of the
Speaker 3:  Box. That is really awesome.
Speaker 1:  I mean, that's the dream. Every other time we've done a
Speaker 1:  pro review of a Mac and we've done the game. And
Speaker 1:  Monica, you mentioned this scenario view, like we've just like give the thing
Speaker 1:  to people. And then they like complain. Like it doesn't
Speaker 1:  seem faster. Or in particular creative
Speaker 1:  cloud is like not updated. And it's usually like apple wacky
Speaker 1:  GPU ideas. And no one else gives a shit.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. I mean, it was real. It's really interesting. Like I honestly think,
Speaker 9:  you know, we have all these benchmarks, whatever. I think the most telling
Speaker 9:  thing is you watch the Mac pro review where we gave this device to
Speaker 9:  like all kinds of podcast people and music, people, and artists, and
Speaker 9:  they all use it across the board. They're all like, this is not any faster.
Speaker 9:  And we gave this studio to our art
Speaker 9:  director, our illustrator, our audio engineer, people like that,
Speaker 9:  every single one of them used it for like five minutes, said this is so fast
Speaker 9:  that the reactions were just opposite ends of the scale.
Speaker 3:  Was that the ultra or the
Speaker 9:  Max that was the ultra.
Speaker 3:  And that's like the super high end.
Speaker 1:  So that, that ultra that you had was the 20 core CPU with
Speaker 1:  64 GPU cores. Yup. The fascinating thing about all
Speaker 1:  of this is these cores are the same across the M one line,
Speaker 1:  right? So when we do benchmarks and we do like single threaded
Speaker 1:  CPU tasks, you can buy that
Speaker 1:  $8,000 computer. But if you have a single threaded or a single core
Speaker 1:  task, it's as fast as like the Mac book air.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. I mean that we would really need a revolution in architecture and see
Speaker 9:  those increased, which, you know, we might very well get, but those are what
Speaker 9:  we were expecting here.
Speaker 1:  I mean, the thing about this computer to me and this came up in the
Speaker 1:  review is the chip is fast, but it is
Speaker 1:  consistently, the ultra is two X as
Speaker 1:  fast as the max, which is already a very fast chip on the
Speaker 1:  benchmark,
Speaker 9:  But in the multi-core benchmarks like sedimentary, multi poorer and geek
Speaker 9:  bench, multi court, you know, that's, and that's what you'd expect that has
Speaker 9:  twice the course, you know, it's going to do it, but it, you know, it is
Speaker 9:  impressive that, you know, apple got that right. And it was
Speaker 9:  delivering the twice, the cores of w core twice
Speaker 9:  the score on the multi-core benchmarks that as opposed to, in terms of like
Speaker 9:  real world tasks that we'd ran, we were not seeing that. Like we were not
Speaker 9:  always seeing double the scores on tomb Raider. We were not seeing double
Speaker 9:  the scores on like huge or bench for premiere reputed venture after effects.
Speaker 9:  So, which I think just underscores that, you know, these are systems
Speaker 9:  and these are software. And you know, if you're not using a
Speaker 9:  software that doesn't effectively scale to every available
Speaker 9:  core or, you know, effectively utilize all that GPU
Speaker 9:  power, you're not necessarily going to be seeing that benefit. But the
Speaker 9:  ultra was a little bit faster than the max. That was the impression that
Speaker 9:  we got from the various professionals who use this for us. It was like
Speaker 9:  noticeably faster for them, but it was not either, they didn't
Speaker 9:  feel it was twice as fast or the max is already so fast that like
Speaker 9:  having that time is not like super, did not like change their lives.
Speaker 4:  It seems like a lot of the folks that you were working with were coming from
Speaker 4:  Intel based machines, right? Like their everyday I know Becca is daily drivers,
Speaker 4:  the old Mac pro
Speaker 1:  The old Macro-Pro $14,000 computer that we
Speaker 1:  bought
Speaker 4:  $17,000 Mac pro it's a
Speaker 4:  crusty old crusty two year old machine of ours that
Speaker 4:  we spent a salary on.
Speaker 4:  She works on that, which is Intel base. I know Andrew works on an Intel based
Speaker 4:  machine. Alex Castro, the illustrator, he works on an Intel-based
Speaker 4:  PC that he was comparing us. So they were seeing these huge
Speaker 4:  advantage advantages coming to this desktop form factor that they had not
Speaker 4:  seen before. But I just wonder how much of that was because they were moving
Speaker 4:  from Intel to apple Silicon now. And like, there, there
Speaker 4:  might be like diminishing returns between the max and the ultra, you
Speaker 4:  know, because the big leap is going from Intel to apple
Speaker 4:  Silicon. Right.
Speaker 1:  Dan, I think that point is like, well taken, although I'm not sure.
Speaker 1:  This is what I think about. Apple's wacky GPU ideas. Part of the
Speaker 1:  jump to apple. Silicon was all these, all these apps. When
Speaker 1:  they move to apple, Silicon, they started using metal. They started actually
Speaker 1:  taking advantage of the GPU's and then the GPS were not
Speaker 1:  wacky old AMD GPU's or wacky, Intel
Speaker 1:  integrated GPU's are like reasonably good. It's a
Speaker 9:  Little kooky AMD shifts. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Almost like, what do you got? And he was like, I know it's a weird shit.
Speaker 1:  Like, so like, I feel like the chips themselves are more powerful.
Speaker 1:  Then now what you're seeing is Apple's approach to
Speaker 1:  GPU's beyond just the wacky parts is no longer this like wacky
Speaker 1:  idea that they're just going to throw more like GPU
Speaker 1:  chips at the problem. They're just gonna make the GPU itself
Speaker 1:  bigger and addressed as a single device, and
Speaker 1:  then figure out how to distribute across courts. And I think that that feels
Speaker 1:  scalable. Like that's why you see that the two X and the benchmarks.
Speaker 3:  Well, it's scalable in a really a way that's gotta to be super frustrating
Speaker 3:  for AMD and Nvidia because notoriously
Speaker 3:  GPU makers do not like to talk about they don't they're like, they're
Speaker 3:  not course. We don't talk about threads. We talk about compute units or where
Speaker 3:  they make up some other word,
Speaker 1:  The chip industry doing weird graphs.
Speaker 3:  That's crazy.
Speaker 9:  It's more seen that before,
Speaker 3:  But Nvidia and AMD are like very particular about this. If you try to say,
Speaker 3:  oh, this has got 56 or 64, they're going to be like, no, no, no. That doesn't
Speaker 3:  matter. Nvidia in particular is like, that doesn't matter. And apple is saying,
Speaker 3:  no, actually these do matter. Here are really measurable differences.
Speaker 3:  When you bolt twice, the number of GPU cores on you're going to
Speaker 3:  see, you know, close to twice the performance and
Speaker 3:  that's gotta be a little scary for the GPU industry, right? Like
Speaker 3:  somebody is kind of calling them out.
Speaker 9:  I mean, another thing not to overlook here is that Adobe has, at this point
Speaker 9:  had like two years to get its shit
Speaker 9:  together. When it comes to making its programs run really well
Speaker 9:  on apple devices. And that like prior to
Speaker 9:   being released, we had been saying for years, like all
Speaker 9:  these apple products are really good. The cruise three doesn't run well on
Speaker 9:  them. It's full of bugs. Like on our Mac purview, it was like breaking everyone's
Speaker 9:  plugins. Now we have a bunch of these programs that
Speaker 9:  are professionals we're using have been made and optimized to
Speaker 9:  run on the M one chip. And that allowed, I
Speaker 9:  think these devices to unlock potential in those
Speaker 9:  programs that like previous apple machines just haven't been able to
Speaker 9:  do because the software hasn't been focused on that area for awhile.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I will say that the Adobes, the big stuff has
Speaker 1:  moved over. Right? So parts of premiere parts of
Speaker 1:  after effects, parts of Photoshop that like 90% of
Speaker 1:  that stuff is optimized. There were the you're mentioning Puget bench.
Speaker 1:  People don't know here's your benches basically like they're a systems vendor,
Speaker 1:  but they sell a bunch of benchmarking plugins so that then they can sell
Speaker 1:  you a faster machine to make their benchmarks go higher. It's a great business
Speaker 1:  model. Some of the best marketing I've ever seen, but they're
Speaker 1:  plugins that run these benchmarks in Adobe programs are basically just like
Speaker 1:  automations. Right? You download a bunch of assets. You like run the
Speaker 1:  plugin at times. How fast
Speaker 9:  Actually really fun to watch it. Cause it takes control of your mouse for
Speaker 9:  like half an hour. It just plays around in premiere. And you can just watch
Speaker 9:  and try to figure out what it's doing. It's like making, it's like throwing
Speaker 9:  like effects on the pictures, like making them all green for no reason.
Speaker 9:  And then it gives you a number of the end. It's really?
Speaker 1:  Yeah. And it's like, we're going to run a GPU heavy effect. And it's like,
Speaker 1:  what we're going to do is take this video clip and make it look ridiculous,
Speaker 1:  like, right. It's just like nuts
Speaker 9:  For all the colors. It's like, oh yes. As one does
Speaker 1:  Like you do. But it was like Photoshop or it was Photoshop that
Speaker 1:  we couldn't run the benchmark because that part of Photoshop was not
Speaker 1:  available on apple Silicon yet. Right. Right. And there's like, there are
Speaker 1:  these weird corner cases where the transition is complete, but to your point,
Speaker 1:  it is mostly complete. And it's mostly pretty good. I think
Speaker 1:  the question about, do you get the  ultra? Like if you know, you need this
Speaker 1:  computer, which I think now our entire video team fully in their heart
Speaker 1:  believes they need this computer. Right. You're probably good enough right
Speaker 1:  now with the max. Right. That's like basically what we saw.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. So no one who we talked to thought that the max was inadequate
Speaker 9:  for their workflows, but you know, they would have all chosen to be on the
Speaker 9:  ultra if they could. I think Alice Castro illustrator said something to me
Speaker 9:  that was like, yeah, like the max would be great for my work. I think if
Speaker 9:  I really wanted to take it to the next level, I'd want to be on the ultra
Speaker 1:  Alex, just like drafting the email to request a, your computer. I know all
Speaker 1:  this
Speaker 10:  Art we could have if you just gave me an
Speaker 1:  Ultra wandering the halls.
Speaker 9:  I think like, you know, if you're someone who really needs every last ounce
Speaker 9:  speeding yet what some people do and some people do want to pay for that,
Speaker 9:  then, you know, the ultra will be like a millisecond faster on,
Speaker 9:  on various things that you're doing, which does add up in your, in your workflow.
Speaker 9:  But no one was using the maximum is like, oh, this is slow. Like the max
Speaker 9:  is also like very, very fast.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Well, so the ultra is twice as expensive. So I would just connect this
Speaker 1:  to our iPhone, a C conversation, which we were just having Monica, which
Speaker 1:  is like, the thing will last a long time. So I think a good, like a good
Speaker 1:  question is how long do you expect to keep this computer?
Speaker 1:  If it's a long time, then having the
Speaker 1:  performance had removed, the ultra might well be worth it. As things get
Speaker 1:  more demanding. If you're running some sort of
Speaker 1:  tax scheme and you're just like flipping computers every two years, I've
Speaker 1:  never run anything.
Speaker 4:  I mean, studios like studios do flip computers every couple of years, right?
Speaker 1:  Tax schemes,
Speaker 4:  They run the tax scheme. But like, they're the ones that are going to buy
Speaker 4:  the alternate, right? Like if you're doing a production, maybe
Speaker 4:  are, you know, Vox, media produces Netflix shows.
Speaker 4:  Maybe those teams really want these ultras because they
Speaker 4:  have a lot of production work to do. But if you're a consumer like
Speaker 4:  us and you're doing, and even if you're doing like heavy consumer work,
Speaker 4:  like I, I mean, Monica, this was the point you made, right at the top of
Speaker 4:  your review, I could run thousands of Google docs on this all day long and
Speaker 4:  never hit the ceiling of it. Right. So like, I, I think that
Speaker 4:  the, the, the ultra consumer or the ultra purchaser is very
Speaker 4:  distinct and like knows what they want and what they need out of it. And
Speaker 4:  then like, if you just want like a killer desktop computer
Speaker 4:  just by the max and load up on storage and Ram and save that $2,000
Speaker 4:  for those other things that you're gonna need to pay for.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. The other thing about longevity that it is worth, you know, is going
Speaker 9:  to matter. It's not going to, to some people is going to matter a lot to
Speaker 9:  other people is that it's not modular. Like the Mac pro was,
Speaker 9:  so you aren't going to be upgrading the Ram or the storage,
Speaker 4:  But you could plug a display into it.
Speaker 1:  Any keyboard you want
Speaker 3:  There is that that's, that's like, they've still got to announce the Mac
Speaker 3:  pro they've still got to show that off. So I guess we're not going to have
Speaker 3:  to listen to more talk about the alter when it comes out and they're just
Speaker 3:  going to be like, yeah, it's got that. But also
Speaker 3:  modularity, like, is that the plan?
Speaker 1:  That means they're gonna have to figure out like PCI,
Speaker 4:  Just how does PCI extension work in the M one world is going to be a fascinating
Speaker 4:  thing to see?
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I don't know the answer to that question. I also, I think that's, what's
Speaker 1:  left for the Mac pro though. I mean, they were very clear. There's no more
Speaker 1:  chips, but there's a Mac pro coming
Speaker 4:  Well, there's wheels there's you can't get wheels for the studio.
Speaker 1:  Well, so they've got to do internal expansion. They might move that to M
Speaker 1:  to N they were clear. There's no more M one chips coming.
Speaker 1:  Or, and this is my, this is my idea. They could go back to wacky
Speaker 1:  GPU ideas in the Mac pro
Speaker 9:  Just start stacking ultras on top of each other. And Evelyn gets out,
Speaker 4:  What did they sold? And one ultras on a PCI card that
Speaker 4:  you could click in. So you could just keep running more and more and one
Speaker 4:  ultras and like more and more GPU code.
Speaker 1:  No, no, you think I'm crazy, but this is what I'm suggesting that
Speaker 1:  they're going to do, like wacky afterburner card setups,
Speaker 1:  where they sell a physical piece of hardware that effectively accelerates
Speaker 1:  one program, which is what the afterburner card does for final cut
Speaker 1:  pro there's all kinds of like, all that stuff remains wide open.
Speaker 3:  What if they let you update the storage and the ramp?
Speaker 3:  What if that's the Mac
Speaker 1:  You're never going to get the Ram because the Ram is unified memory architecture.
Speaker 1:  That is the bet. And then when we talk about the jump to apple,
Speaker 1:  Silicon, like some huge
Speaker 1:  undefined acceleration for all these pro apps is
Speaker 1:  that the video cards have access to just heaps of Ram.
Speaker 1:  And the CPU is have access to Ram fast enough to run a video card.
Speaker 1:  Right. Which is like an inversion of how things, th they're each
Speaker 1:  getting the thing the other kind of system used to have, but it's just one
Speaker 1:  huge pool of memory. And like, I know we, you know, we had our apple
Speaker 1:  briefing and I was like, okay, like on the Mac book air with eight gigs of
Speaker 1:  Ram people run out of memory, what happens on Alex Castro is like, I need
Speaker 1:  to justify this ultra, like here's
Speaker 1:  129 gigabyte file. And then I think it will be interesting.
Speaker 1:  So it's like, I don't think that we've seen that like play out in
Speaker 1:  computing that Apple's big Uma bet. Obviously we've seen it play out on iPhones
Speaker 1:  and iPads because they have unified memory, but we haven't seen it play out
Speaker 1:  on these systems. And we certainly didn't see that play out in prem machines
Speaker 1:  that potentially needs to last for a long time. But Monica, this was the
Speaker 1:  con like when you were listing pros and cons, the cons is you buy it and
Speaker 1:  that's it like you get what you get.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. What you get that doesn't necessarily matter to everyone. But for some
Speaker 9:  people in this crowd, it certainly is going to matter, especially with, to
Speaker 9:  your point. This thing is so expensive. You people are going to buy it, wanting
Speaker 9:  to last, wanting it to last for a long time. And I think that is, you know,
Speaker 9:  it's always the story with apple. Like you can upgrade apple stuff, but as
Speaker 9:  you're getting into this price range in this market, I do think that is something
Speaker 9:  to consider.
Speaker 1:  I would not buy this on one max with 32 gigs of Ram.
Speaker 3:  I immediately bought it.
Speaker 1:  Did you realize
Speaker 9:  You kinds of people?
Speaker 3:  I bought it like they hadn't even finished the, the, the,
Speaker 3:  the, the keynote. And I was like, refreshing the thing. Cause I'm on a
Speaker 3:  2016 MacBook pro that when I do a zoom call, I
Speaker 3:  can't open a spreadsheet. So like,
Speaker 4:  I think 32 gigabytes of Ram, it's going to be like perfectly
Speaker 4:  adequate for someone who is like, my budget is $2,000 for a desktop. That's
Speaker 4:  going to last five plus years. I think it's totally going to be perfectly
Speaker 4:  adequate. If you're going to be running the premiere pros and whatnot,
Speaker 4:  then like, maybe you want to upgrade that Ram, but it's not an inexpensive
Speaker 4:  upgrade. It's what four, $800 to go to 64 gigs. It's
Speaker 4:  huge.
Speaker 3:  Apple is so excited because for years, the
Speaker 3:  horrible thing about buying a computer from apple
Speaker 3:  was the Ram markup. And now you cannot escape it
Speaker 3:  like before you could be like, okay, I'll buy it. And then I'll go upgrade
Speaker 3:  by Ram for a reasonable price. And now it's like, Nope, I guess I'm going
Speaker 3:  to pay $200 for 24 gigabytes, more Ram or whatever.
Speaker 3:  So this is they're living the dream.
Speaker 1:  I just looked at this. And so I, when I bought my 16 inch MacBook pro I bought
Speaker 1:  the MUN pro because I was like, battery life is all I really care about.
Speaker 1:  And we, in our testing, we discovered the max had lower battery life. And
Speaker 1:  I realized that I, I thought I had like bought 64 grand, but I bought 32.
Speaker 1:  So I don't even know what I'm talking about. My own computer. I bought my
Speaker 1:  own money.
Speaker 3:  I'm just going to be like out of, out of capacity. And about a
Speaker 3:  year DLI, we're all going to be crying. They're 32 gigabytes of Ram.
Speaker 1:  Well, I just think for consumer use, right? And like, I would say that
Speaker 1:  I'm a professional user of Google docs. Like I'm a pro slack user,
Speaker 1:  but
Speaker 9:  If they ever make a Google docs specific Mack, I
Speaker 9:  will, I'm going to have a great time with that review.
Speaker 1:  And they're like, our world-class chip team has added
Speaker 4:  We're joking, but I have a browser window open right now that has eight Google
Speaker 4:  docs open in it right now. And that's just for,
Speaker 1:  That's fine. If they make one, if they're like, we've added a
Speaker 1:  dedicated 12 core processor for
Speaker 1:  accelerates Chrome. And like I'm buying that computer.
Speaker 9:  I will be like Alex and I will be ordering it on my phone before the keynote
Speaker 9:  is over keynote, over
Speaker 4:  There's someone we know that might, you know, work on a certain product line
Speaker 4:  and a certain company that we could pitch a Google
Speaker 4:  doc specific hardware to.
Speaker 9:  And it'll be like the back next to you. And I'll just have all you guys lined
Speaker 9:  up to interview one by one and bet your Google docs experience and how much
Speaker 9:  faster it was in your,
Speaker 1:  I get a 20 minute video. They're just moving. Like, so here's my Google,
Speaker 1:  the hugs experience
Speaker 9:  Tabbing through. I don't really like to open file and recent. And you know,
Speaker 9:  that's a lot slower on this machine
Speaker 1:  And that would be just 20 minutes with me bitching. About every time I started
Speaker 1:  a new Google doc, it goes to my personal Gmail account. And not my, not my
Speaker 1:  work one, all I'm saying is this, you America texture. Like we still don't
Speaker 1:  know it's going to play out in desktop computing. And I would just always
Speaker 1:  buy the most Ram. I think that's been the rule for 20
Speaker 1:  years that buying more memory for your computer as a,
Speaker 1:  almost a more useful upgrade than the processor itself.
Speaker 4:  Sure. But to Alex's point that could have been done at any point that you
Speaker 4:  owned the computer and now it's like, okay, well I'm shelling out two grand
Speaker 4:  for the base model of this computer. Five 12 gigabyte is actually a
Speaker 4:  bigger concern. I have then 32 gigs of Ram. Like I would
Speaker 4:  fill that up with media.
Speaker 9:  That is not enough. Yeah. So
Speaker 4:  I, you, you need, you probably want to upgrade the storage,
Speaker 1:  But you can buy more storage. This isn't a ports galore,
Speaker 1:  man. Just stick an SD card in the front. I get
Speaker 4:  It. But like, who wants to do that
Speaker 1:  Right now? Every Mac accessory maker in the world is like, here's what we're
Speaker 1:  going to do. We're going to make a little wedge of a hard drive and we're
Speaker 1:  gonna put it right under the top. And instead of more ports on it, but
Speaker 9:  That takes up a port that you could be using for
Speaker 4:  More than other display.
Speaker 1:  We'll add more.
Speaker 9:  If I want to connect five displays to this thing and just have them on the
Speaker 9:  wall. I can't, I got every port counts.
Speaker 1:  Monica. One thing that did not pan out is apple
Speaker 1:  compared to the ultra to the 30, 90 on a series of
Speaker 1:  charts. I don't know why
Speaker 9:  They had like relative performance on the Y axis. You know, that very
Speaker 9:  useful word that we all know what that means. Okay.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, we definitely, and they would definitely tell us which benchmarks they
Speaker 1:  were running, which they refused to do, but you didn't find that to be the
Speaker 1:  case at all, that it could run with the,
Speaker 9:  No, I could not, did not replicate that in the GP benchmarks, we ran our
Speaker 9:  editor TC has a three 90 at home. He ran a geek
Speaker 9:  bench compute for us. It just absolutely demolished
Speaker 9:  the MRL tra like, and what ultra didn't even get like half of its
Speaker 9:  score. There have been some like back in like October,
Speaker 9:  there were some issues with geek bench in apple, but geek bench has had like
Speaker 9:  a lot of time to fix that issue. And also these were not like cookie scores
Speaker 9:  that I would not expect to get. Like this is like, I think it's just a
Speaker 9:  lot worse.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. So Haim and I looked now that we have our
Speaker 1:  results from benchmarks, the 30 nineties, like twice as powerful and various
Speaker 1:  benchmarks as the ultra, depending on the benchmark,
Speaker 1:  depending on the test. And so Haim and I went back and looked at those weird
Speaker 1:  apple graphs. Okay. So the Y axis is relative
Speaker 1:  performance and the X axis has power in Watts.
Speaker 1:  So the Y axis already is like just confusing. And maybe they're
Speaker 1:  just re you know, they're, they're just moving other numbers. Like
Speaker 1:  they're just turning each geek bench scores into zero to 100, like, I don't
Speaker 1:  know what they're doing. It's just,
Speaker 9:  It makes total sense to do in charts, you know, just move, move numbers around.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Just convert them into a different set of units for no reason. But
Speaker 1:  here's the thing. The 30, 90 line on that chart
Speaker 1:  stops at 320 Watts. And the
Speaker 1:  30 90 has a standard TDP
Speaker 1:  of 350 Watts and can spike to 400.
Speaker 1:  So they just stopped the line in 320 months.
Speaker 1:  And we're like, oh, that's why like, there's just more line.
Speaker 1:  That's the graph. Like the relative performance,
Speaker 1:  Y axis goes up to 200, but the 30 90 line
Speaker 1:  can go to 400. If you just keep letting it
Speaker 1:  go.
Speaker 9:  How utterly useful
Speaker 1:  I have complained about these charts so much. They, I mean, apple is
Speaker 1:  deeply aware of how I feel about the chart.
Speaker 9:  This is not going to shock anyone also, but the gaming, the frame rates
Speaker 9:  we were seeing in games were not at all close. So we always offered a 30,
Speaker 9:  90 either.
Speaker 1:  Can you talk about this? A lot of our comments were about shadow the tomb
Speaker 1:  Raider, which is not optimized for apple Silicon, but it's like the only
Speaker 1:  benchmark that we have across multiple systems.
Speaker 9:  It is a standard benchmark that everyone runs into the very GPU heavy
Speaker 9:  game. It has been out for, you know, quite a few years
Speaker 9:  now. Like it's not like it's this brand new game that, you know,
Speaker 9:  apple hasn't figured how to run. I mean, it is a game that like a graphically
Speaker 9:  powerful computer we would expect it would be able to run.
Speaker 3:  It's one of the first games with Ray tracing. Like it was one of the first
Speaker 3:  things we used for, for benchmarking, for Ray tracing, like shadow
Speaker 3:  shadow of the tomb. Raider is a very good benchmark
Speaker 3:  process product. And it's like, it's like that. And
Speaker 3:  civilization that's, which if you're going to benchmark across apple
Speaker 3:  and windows, that's kind of it because
Speaker 3:  apple does not care about gaming will never care about gaming. I'm sorry.
Speaker 3:  I'm sorry. But they just don't care. And they're never going to care
Speaker 3:  about, you know, trends, excuse me, PC gaming. They're never gonna care about
Speaker 3:  transferring PC gaming. They're never going to, and, and those companies
Speaker 3:  are never going to modify their software to make it run better on
Speaker 3:  an M one. I mean, they might,
Speaker 1:  If apple was smart, they would go and they would pay the developer of shadow
Speaker 1:  tomb, Raider to optimize it for apple Silicon, just to end this
Speaker 3:  Just, yeah, just, just, and in this, like, and it's also funny that they
Speaker 3:  compared it to 30 90, when Macko S can't
Speaker 3:  even really use Nvidia GPU's anymore. Like they
Speaker 3:  got rid of Kuda support years ago. Yeah,
Speaker 1:  That's true. But like, that's what they're comparing is because that's the
Speaker 1:  best one on the PC side. I understand. Here's the, here's the thing I
Speaker 1:  understand where they are compared to 30, 90, all they're saying is for
Speaker 1:  200 Watts, less power, we can like run with the big
Speaker 1:  dogs. Right? That's what they're trying to say.
Speaker 9:  So this, and last year when they compare it to the 30 80, and that also turned
Speaker 9:  out to be not really necessarily a true,
Speaker 1:  I could. Why walk into that fight? The thing
Speaker 1:  is historic. And the thing is that massive victory in ship
Speaker 1:  design, the performance is out of control. People love it. And you're like,
Speaker 1:  here's this graph that's going to make you mad at us and then not be
Speaker 1:  true. Like, what are you doing?
Speaker 9:  And just to be, to clarify on what was the frame rates we were getting from
Speaker 9:  the ultra, we're still like, you know, well, above 60. So it's
Speaker 9:  not like, like this couldn't run the game. Like the frame rates were clearly
Speaker 9:  good. The issue is that there's still stutter
Speaker 9:  going on in the game. Like it was still like, even when it was running, like
Speaker 9:  over a hundred frames per second, like the wrist, it was still hiccupping
Speaker 9:  all the time, which I think just goes to show like, you know, this is not
Speaker 9:  a gaming PC. No, one's gonna buy it for games. We understand that like games
Speaker 9:  aren't optimized for it. We understand that. But you know, in terms of comparing
Speaker 9:  graphics power to the graphics power that other machines have,
Speaker 9:  like, that's a number we get, we're gonna use.
Speaker 1:  If you can find us a game that runs an apple, Silicon and
Speaker 1:  windows that is graphically intensive, that has a built-in benchmark.
Speaker 9:  Don't say like world of Warcraft. Cause I'm not going to,
Speaker 9:  sorry. I'm not doing
Speaker 1:  I, if you can find us that test, we'll run it. But this is what we got, I
Speaker 1:  think is basically the answer. So I just want to start, I'm going to start
Speaker 1:  at the high before he go to the low that's what I was trying to deepen. It
Speaker 1:  was like, we're going to build up his historic computer
Speaker 1:  deeply disappointing display. I don't know what's
Speaker 1:  going on with this display. So apple announced the Mac studio. They announced
Speaker 1:  the studio display the cancel the 27 inch iMac.
Speaker 1:  Everyone is like, okay, here's what they're doing. They're reselling this
Speaker 1:  way from the 27 inch iMac, which is the only 5k display apart from
Speaker 1:  the, I would say much hated LG ultra-fine 5k. People do not
Speaker 1:  like that display. So here it is. It's in a case you can plug it into this
Speaker 1:  thing or place sort of the iMac profile. There is, I would say
Speaker 1:  just an inordinate amount of chatter about whether apple will do another
Speaker 1:  iMac pro or another 20 S I don't know what's going to happen. These are the
Speaker 1:  computers as cell now. So we get the display apples, like the
Speaker 1:  displays 5k display. It's beautiful. They don't make a lot of claims about
Speaker 1:  the display itself for reasons that we'll get into in a moment, but they
Speaker 1:  make a huge claim about it's video conferencing
Speaker 1:  capability, right? It's got a three mic array. It's got six
Speaker 1:  speakers. It's got a 12 megapixel camera. That
Speaker 1:  is the same camera as the iPad
Speaker 3:  Camera Nila.
Speaker 1:  And that's kind of a 13 chip, which is the same chip as the iPhone 11. We
Speaker 1:  were just talking about that. I was like, this is the, this is the phone
Speaker 1:  that made me stop using my RX 100. So I'm expecting to be blown away.
Speaker 1:  And I will say, this is probably not fair to apple. It's not fair to the
Speaker 1:  Opal team. But what I was expecting was we there's that start-up
Speaker 1:  Opal, that cameras are either camera. That's a $400 standalone camera.
Speaker 1:  It's called the Opal C1. It is the same camera
Speaker 1:  module is the original pixel and a little Intel chip
Speaker 1:  that does computational photography in the webcam is great, which is
Speaker 1:  great. I bought one for our CEO, cause I was like, you gotta stop doing all
Speaker 1:  hands on this whole company on your Mac book air. Right? So the thing's
Speaker 1:  great. So I'm expecting that apple is going to do computational photography
Speaker 1:  at smartphone level On this display.
Speaker 3:  Did you get that thing
Speaker 1:  Is garbage. Like
Speaker 9:  It's so, so bad.
Speaker 1:  I mean, it's so bad.
Speaker 9:  It's really ridiculous to look at
Speaker 1:  It's I don't know what's wrong with it. I honestly can't tell you. It's a
Speaker 1:  12 megapixel sensor and an a series processor
Speaker 1:  five years, a half a decade of experience will
Speaker 1:  tell you that apple is good at those two components, making good photos
Speaker 1:  in a series processor that's Apple's stuff. They know how to
Speaker 1:  do anything. It's like put those together and make photos that are better
Speaker 1:  than any Android phone. And the thing is garbage.
Speaker 3:  I have a theory. Yeah. I've got a theory. It's a really bad theory.
Speaker 3:  So I was looking, I was looking at, you know, the lovely video, everybody,
Speaker 3:  please go watch it. There's a really great comparison shot. And it's Neil
Speaker 3:  and like four different cameras at once. There are no
Speaker 3:  shadows, right? Like contrast does not exist on this thing. I think they
Speaker 3:  used cardboard cutouts of people for all of their testing.
Speaker 3:  So they never had to actually like mimic real world,
Speaker 3:  like contrast in what people actually see.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I don't know, man. We took briefings, you know, and
Speaker 1:  they were saying they were on these cameras and the briefings. It did not
Speaker 1:  look this bad. I got home. I plugged the thing in, I plugged it into the
Speaker 1:  Mac studio that I had. I plugged it into my Mac book. Pro Monica had
Speaker 1:  one, she plugged into one like, woo. It just looks
Speaker 1:  bad. Like Joanna stern compared it to her Blackberry
Speaker 1:  10 years ago,
Speaker 4:  It does some weird stuff too. Right? So like part of the pitch is that it
Speaker 4:  supports center stage, which is the auto framing type of feature that
Speaker 4:  they debuted on the iPads already. And it's kind of whack when
Speaker 4:  it does that, which is, it's kind of a weird thing to put on a monitor where
Speaker 4:  you're sitting still anyways, but it has that feature. It's got portrait
Speaker 4:  mode with an M one computer. So if you've got a Mac studio or you got an
Speaker 4:  M one Mac book, you can do portrait mode on there. But like it's a
Speaker 4:  12 megapixel camera, which has a very wide field of view from
Speaker 4:  12 megapixels. You can pull a 4k video feed out of because that's enough
Speaker 4:  resolution for 4k, but this camera never gives you the
Speaker 4:  full 4k. If you turn off center stage it like,
Speaker 4:  it's a very cropped in view of that field of view.
Speaker 4:  And it's still 10 ADP. It's very low quality. It's very strange.
Speaker 3:  You think they cheaped out on the Ram and
Speaker 1:  In the studio display
Speaker 4:  And they didn't get the upgrade when they were buying. And then I got, should've
Speaker 4:  gotten a 64.
Speaker 1:  Oh, well, let me just finish this. And then we can, we can, I don't know,
Speaker 1:  what's wrong with this thing. So all week I am sending basically
Speaker 1:  selfies of myself in various lighting conditions to apple, which is a
Speaker 1:  weird thing to do. I'm like, here I am in my basement again, like, Hey, like
Speaker 1:  here I am in the office, like comparing it. You know, we, we
Speaker 1:  got, there's some friends of the verge out there who review products. So
Speaker 1:  like some, a little back channel opens up. Then we're also like this crazy,
Speaker 1:  again, more selfies of myself sent to more people this past week than I've
Speaker 1:  ever been comfortable living.
Speaker 1:  And Apple's like, we're looking into it. You know, it's all very sincere.
Speaker 1:  I ran a full SIS diagnose. Actually Monica ran it for me. We sent that
Speaker 1:  over because I didn't have the machine anymore because I was back home and
Speaker 1:  it was in the office. But we sent that to apple. We checked all the
Speaker 1:  firmwares. We updated the soft it's all the same. So finally
Speaker 1:  last night apple says, and Dan and I were joking. Like I could have written
Speaker 1:  this line the first day
Speaker 9:  And just pre recorded in the video. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Like I didn't need to wait until the last minute. Like, we've seen the
Speaker 1:  thing. It's not behaving as we expected a future software update. We'll fix
Speaker 1:  it. Okay. Sure. I w I don't know, like maybe it
Speaker 1:  will the rule, and this has been our rule from the
Speaker 1:  beginning of the verge, dating back to art and gadget days, like whatever
Speaker 1:  is, we've been burned too many times where people promise you a software
Speaker 1:  updates and you review what's in the box because you can never count on the
Speaker 1:  software update coming, and you never know what it's actually going to fix.
Speaker 1:  So I asked, when is it coming? What will it fix no answers. So I don't
Speaker 1:  know if they can fix it. I don't know if they, they should fix it. Now that
Speaker 1:  the reviews are out. There's like noise in the world that this is a last
Speaker 1:  minute bug. And actually isn't, who knows? I don't know. But the thing looks
Speaker 1:  like a potato. Like, that's, that's what I got for you.
Speaker 9:  Biggest impression was that I would take a lot of, I was like hanging out
Speaker 9:  with the person who made our video Becca this entire week. And we would
Speaker 9:  often be taking these meetings together. When we were talking about this
Speaker 9:  review, it would be like me and Becca trying to get in the frame and center
Speaker 9:  stage would just lose its mind. Like it could not figure out what to focus
Speaker 9:  on. It was like swooping back and forth, like, like, like a
Speaker 9:  remote, like VR amusement park rides. Like it just like, it
Speaker 9:  could not figure out where everyone was telling us, turn it off, because
Speaker 9:  it was so distracting, like that kept going in and out.
Speaker 1:  So it keeps them moving around. I was trying to record my little update last
Speaker 1:  night with center stage on. And I was like, I can't like, this is just not
Speaker 1:  working. Like, it's just like flying the room anyway.
Speaker 1:  So we were not the only people who ran into problems. The camera at Joanna
Speaker 1:  ran into these problems, got the same statement. Sean Gruber ran into these
Speaker 1:  problems, got the same statement. He actually called it the center stage
Speaker 1:  stuff. I was so distracted by how bad the camera was. I was like, I can't
Speaker 1:  even, I can't even think about anything else. Like I'm not looking at your
Speaker 1:  center stage right now. I will say the microphone is great.
Speaker 1:  It is like really good. The speakers, I don't know if two
Speaker 1:  speakers and a stereo pair that are like 18 inches apart can produce spacial
Speaker 1:  audio. I don't even know spatial. Audio is like a real
Speaker 1:  thing that is worth it.
Speaker 3:  That is a lot of what's happening right now on this podcast.
Speaker 1:  Did I try to have the experience of Jimmy page sneaking up behind me with
Speaker 1:  a guitar with this computer? Like yes. Did it have, like,
Speaker 1:  it was, I surprised I was with this speakers do sound
Speaker 1:  good. I just, you know how I feel about audio processing and then the display
Speaker 1:  itself is just like, this panel is from 2014, man.
Speaker 3:  It is impeccably calibrated.
Speaker 1:  It is impeccably. Calibrated is very bright. Dan's theory,
Speaker 1:  about 600 nits versus 500 nits is it's in a different case and it has fans
Speaker 1:  so they can run the backlight LEDs brighter. Right.
Speaker 4:  It doesn't have a whole computer in there soaking up making heat so they
Speaker 4:  could that's that's my theory, at least.
Speaker 1:  Right. But in your day-to-day use, are you running this thing into full 600?
Speaker 1:  And it's like, like maybe like, are you going to see it? Like, I don't know,
Speaker 1:  but then it's just a single led backlight. And I went and I was like,
Speaker 1:  just like looking around. I was like $3,379 TVs
Speaker 1:  with full array, local dimming. Now
Speaker 3:  You guys all took offense at this, but I actually kind of like it.
Speaker 3:  And that's because I want to, all of this is dumb reason. I said the reason
Speaker 3:  I know,
Speaker 4:  So Alex is coming out as a dark, dark grays
Speaker 4:  enthusiast.
Speaker 3:  I am, I love my dark grays.
Speaker 3:  I love my all ed. I adore my OLED. The thing I
Speaker 3:  cannot stand about 99% of back led TVs is they
Speaker 3:  cannot mimic like, even really good tons of, yeah. The
Speaker 3:  bloom, the bloom just distracts me, irritates me. And so I would rather
Speaker 3:  have screen wide bloom where I don't have to think about it.
Speaker 3:  The bloom and little spots
Speaker 9:  Everything's blooming. So you just get used to it.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Like that for me, I was like, you know what? I don't hate
Speaker 3:  that. But also I watch like, I'd be using it in a big
Speaker 3:  room anyway, with a lot of tea, with a lot of light. So it's not
Speaker 3:  going to hit me as hard as somebody who's like sitting in the darkness,
Speaker 3:  trying to use this thing. It will suck.
Speaker 9:  Like I will say I've never seen two displays look more different than seeing
Speaker 9:  the XDR next to this one, the pro display XTR next? This one in like a
Speaker 9:  dark, our dark office. Like, it was just, it was like,
Speaker 9:  basically like literally night and day. Like there was one like very bright,
Speaker 9:  dark gray, and one that is actually black.
Speaker 3:  I do think the thing that provided the most irritation from when I,
Speaker 3:  because I went and looked at it with, with Monica, I brought in all my really
Speaker 3:  stupid little nerdy patterns. And I was like, let's talk to patterns.
Speaker 3:  And Monica was like, it was fast. I said, it just like that. Monica was like
Speaker 3:  very, very polite and was like, sure.
Speaker 3:  But, but before that, Monica had to like wipe the entire thing
Speaker 3:  down repeatedly because you had the, the nano texture, right?
Speaker 9:  Every two seconds, we had to wipe it down because you, your,
Speaker 9:  your hand comes within like 10 feet of this thing. And it gets a fingerprint
Speaker 9:  on it.
Speaker 3:  Magnet for handle ELLs,
Speaker 9:  Which we sort of, you know, that obviously was a problem for us because we
Speaker 9:  were carrying a sing around everywhere. I don't know how much of a problem
Speaker 9:  that is for like the average person. Just go to like, have it on a desk.
Speaker 9:  Like, I don't know how often they're going to be touching their display,
Speaker 9:  but
Speaker 1:  When they're going to move, they're going to adjust the, if
Speaker 9:  You adjust the angle, you will have to probably have to wipe it. You
Speaker 3:  Will need to wear gloves.
Speaker 1:  I'm Alex here, weird ideas went backwards side.
Speaker 1:  I kind of by the orient, like blooming and LCD TV is bad. Like
Speaker 1:  this is what great IPS LCD has looked like
Speaker 1:  since 2014. I mean, they started shipping. I'm
Speaker 1:  looking at a 2015 iMac right now with the same panel in it.
Speaker 1:  It is exactly the same. Right? You can get the QT or led that cam on.
Speaker 1:  It has on his desk.
Speaker 3:  It's in the, it was in the office. And I went and looked at it, stunning,
Speaker 3:  gorgeous. I cannot wait to read the review.
Speaker 4:  Excellent.
Speaker 1:  But cheaper than this thing,
Speaker 1:  you can save the money and you can buy a webcam that doesn't
Speaker 1:  insult your friends and colleagues.
Speaker 3:  I spend for like, okay, it's $1,300,
Speaker 3:  $1,600. So for a hundred dollars more
Speaker 1:  To get a better display,
Speaker 3:  I don't know. It's more, you get the QD OLED and you get the Opal.
Speaker 3:  And then you've got a good webcam and a really, really good
Speaker 3:  display that you can probably presumably touch without needing
Speaker 3:  gloves.
Speaker 4:  I am going to be the, the reason to buy the apple
Speaker 4:  display argument is because of its stupid 5k resolution though. But to
Speaker 4:  like me last point, like you've had that since 2014, like, like the, like
Speaker 4:  the person who wants the 5k display is not interested in the QD Allah, because
Speaker 4:  it is a 1440 P panel that doesn't scale macro S nicely. And it doesn't have
Speaker 4:  pixel perfect icons and all this other stuff, which is like a thing that
Speaker 4:  a lot of creatives and developers care deeply
Speaker 4:  about. They want that sharp resolution. If you're coding all day long, you're
Speaker 4:  looking at little texts, sharp resolution matters a lot more than refresh
Speaker 4:  rates.
Speaker 3:  Theoretically, everyone in this room should want the 5k because all we do
Speaker 3:  is look at texts all day.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I mean, but, but unless you play games in the evening, like then, then
Speaker 4:  you know, you want the refresh rates, right. And you want the contrast, or
Speaker 4:  if you're using your monitor to watch movies or whatever it is, then, then
Speaker 4:  the QTL it'll be fantastic. But like, you could have
Speaker 4:  gotten that experience for seven years now, or however long it's been. I
Speaker 4:  don't know how to count. Is it eight years? Maybe it's eight years since
Speaker 4:  2014 now. And we're not seeing any advancement on this end. Like it's a
Speaker 4:  $1,600 display. I feel like we could excuse the fact that the
Speaker 4:  panel was old. If it was $800, like, we'd be like, all right, whatever,
Speaker 4:  that's the apple tax that you're paying and you get the speakers and the
Speaker 4:  microphone and a terrible webcam, but it's is like $1,600. When I look at
Speaker 4:  like $1,600 displays, I'm looking at 5k two K
Speaker 4:  panels from LG that are ultra wide with, you know, DCI P
Speaker 4:  three gamuts and everything like that, that are like 40 inches. That's
Speaker 4:  a $1,600 display. Like they just kind of blow this
Speaker 4:  away. When it comes to like an actual monitor experience,
Speaker 3:  This is going to end up being like the home pod, the original home pod. So
Speaker 3:  if we wait a year, it'll probably like half in price,
Speaker 9:  Put out a tiny one.
Speaker 13:  They will cancel this one. And they will put out a 15 inch USBC
Speaker 13:  display,
Speaker 9:  Hold it in your Palm. And like,
Speaker 1:  Yeah. It's to me, it's you can't have HDR without local dimming.
Speaker 1:  If you just like played out in your head to do HDR, you need some parts of
Speaker 1:  the screen that are way brighter than others. So you can't just ramp the
Speaker 1:  whole backlight. You need to selectively light up parts of the display.
Speaker 1:  So you can have HDR that local living. There's no clubbing save no HDR. Now
Speaker 1:  this thing's just like out of the running. Like I do keep coming back to
Speaker 1:  the fact that the cheapest TVs now have
Speaker 1:  full array. Backlights full rate, local Demi backlights with HDR.
Speaker 1:  And maybe you could still use the panel, but why not innovate on
Speaker 1:  the backlight, which is like a totally possible thing to do.
Speaker 1:  And they did not do that
Speaker 3:  For the same price you could go get for around the same price, a
Speaker 3:  48 inch LG all led with
Speaker 3:  120 Hertz refresh rate, the absolute best
Speaker 3:  color. And,
Speaker 1:  But you would only get that 4k resolution and you'd run it.
Speaker 4:  And also it's a 48 inch screen on your desk. And I can tell you, that's not
Speaker 4:  a fun time.
Speaker 3:  Don't do it so much TV.
Speaker 1:  I personally cannot really see refresh rates beyond 60 Hertz. This is
Speaker 1:  actually like deep Dieter and he's to talk about all the time. Like he was
Speaker 1:  really, he could see the refresh rates. I
Speaker 9:  Absolutely can.
Speaker 1:  And I see HDR in color. And like,
Speaker 1:  I dunno, maybe that's just a thing like you're one or the other you're left-handed
Speaker 1:  or right-handed. But to me, it's way more important to have the HTR in that.
Speaker 1:  And the backlight then refresh rates. I know we have tons of people in our
Speaker 1:  audience, Monica who can see it.
Speaker 4:  It's a, it's a constant argument in, in our slack as to like, how could you
Speaker 4:  buy a 60 Hertz monitor? I will say that like for a monitor where your inputs
Speaker 4:  are detached, you've got your mouse, your keyboard, or your track pad or
Speaker 4:  whatever. I do not see as big of a different, I'm looking at 120 Hertz monitor
Speaker 4:  right now. And I really only use it ever for work. And if I turn it to 60
Speaker 4:  Hertz, I really don't notice much of a difference. You do notice a difference
Speaker 4:  in gaming because everything's a little bit smoother there. And I definitely
Speaker 4:  notice it on a lot of touchscreen devices. And we'll probably talk about
Speaker 4:  this with the iPad, but if I'm directly manipulating things and I'm
Speaker 4:  actually reading texts, as I'm scrolling it with my finger, I noticed that
Speaker 4:  120 Hertz, because I can still read the text as I do it. Whereas a 60 Hertz
Speaker 4:  screen will we'll blur it out or get choppy. So it really depends on your
Speaker 4:  use cases, whether faster refresh rates make sense for your,
Speaker 4:  your needs. But I think anybody could probably tell to your point in your
Speaker 4:  life, the difference between an HDR and a non HDR screen, most
Speaker 4:  likely, regardless of what you're doing.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I don't know, man. I don't know what's going on this display. I
Speaker 1:  dunno. I had $1,600. I don't know why buying a stand that allows you to adjust
Speaker 1:  the height is another $400.
Speaker 4:  And the best part is if you make the wrong choice, when you buy it, you're
Speaker 1:  Stuck. You're screwed. If you
Speaker 9:  Have the max, do you can plug five of them in,
Speaker 1:  You can plug five, which is obviously important. And then in a
Speaker 1:  dark room, you would have just a source of blinding light,
Speaker 14:  Five gray panels.
Speaker 1:  People have been talking about like perfect blacks on displays since at least
Speaker 1:  2007. Like that's when I went to CS and pioneer would have us
Speaker 1:  in for their curl plasma demos, where they'd show
Speaker 1:  you that all the other ones had gray backlights and the Kurose. I swear,
Speaker 1:  we still have the curl plasma, man. You light that thing up. The Hotmail
Speaker 1:  lights in our house, dim
Speaker 1:  is an experience.
Speaker 4:  75 pounds.
Speaker 1:  It's yeah, it's just, it's in another room and every now and again, I go
Speaker 1:  and like lovingly gaze at it. We have to turn it on it,
Speaker 1:  but I'm never throwing it away. It was like the first expensive TV I ever
Speaker 1:  bought and weird keeping it until we're dead.
Speaker 15:  So the whole neighborhood,
Speaker 1:  But perfect black gloves.
Speaker 1:  But that's like since 2007, we've been chasing after this and a
Speaker 1:  $1,600 site from apple, which in every other category where it makes the
Speaker 1:  displays makes the best one. It's utterly bonkers
Speaker 1:  to me. Yeah. We'll see. We'll see if they can fix this webcam.
Speaker 1:  And maybe that will change things dramatically.
Speaker 3:  It'll also fix the black lights who knows
Speaker 1:  He'll feel the software update to follow local. To me. That'd be incredible.
Speaker 1:  All right. We started talking about this iPad. Monica, thank you so much.
Speaker 1:  Thank you. We're going to take a quick break. We'll be right back
Speaker 1:  Running business a lot like running a pirate ship. You got your eyes on the
Speaker 1:  prize and entire crew to coordinate. Luckily in the business world, there's
Speaker 1:  a lot fewer sea monsters to navigate and a lot more HubSpot. HubSpot is an
Speaker 1:  easy to use CRM platform that helps you grow your business. It seamlessly
Speaker 1:  connects your teams, grows your business and delivers a better experience
Speaker 1:  for your customers. It's a treasure map. The very clear X marks the spot
Speaker 1:  and the seat of sameness that is other CRM companies. HubSpot allows you
Speaker 1:  to customize your cruise experience, helping your company be a great partner
Speaker 1:  to your customers, connect your people, your customers, and your business.
Speaker 1:  It hubspot.com. Email. It's the tried and true method of
Speaker 1:  communication for just about everyone. But if you're a top company trying
Speaker 1:  to compete in today's business landscape, you need better than regular email.
Speaker 1:  You need a superpower kind of email for companies that's Mailgun by
Speaker 1:  cinch a platform it's straightforward and made great by world-class support
Speaker 1:  and incredibly powerful API APIs sending and tracking your transactional
Speaker 1:  and marketing messages with Mailgun is easy. And there's no room for excess,
Speaker 1:  either as it prevents fake signups and removes invalid email addresses from
Speaker 1:  your list quickly, plus Mailgun is proven. They empower leading brands
Speaker 1:  from all over the world to solve complex communications problems, their powerful
Speaker 1:  email API and intuitive email marketing solutions allow you to control your
Speaker 1:  entire email life cycle from the email testing stage through delivery and
Speaker 1:  their send time optimization capability automatically finds the ideal send
Speaker 1:  time for every recipient on your list and sends your message when they are
Speaker 1:  most likely to engage. Cinch delivers over
Speaker 1:  240 billion emails each year for businesses of all sizes and
Speaker 1:  fortune 50 brands to entrepreneurial startups. Discover why it's so easy
Speaker 1:  to build connected experiences. Start sending with Mailgun by cinch
Speaker 1:  today, visit mailgun.com to learn more.
Speaker 1:  All right, we're back. Actually, Monica is going to hang with us talking
Speaker 1:  about the Cypad, but Dan, you reviewed the iPad air. I did. I
Speaker 1:  will tell the audience that I specifically deleted the line air conclusion
Speaker 1:  where you're like, I have nothing to say about this computer. And I was like,
Speaker 1:  no, that's your job on me. I
Speaker 4:  Had this crisis of COVID.
Speaker 9:  I can put that in 99% of my reviews. I want to listen.
Speaker 4:  I will say that the fact that I had nothing really
Speaker 4:  to complain about with the iPad is a Testament to how good the iPad areas.
Speaker 4:  The iPad air is an excellent product and it is more excellent this year than
Speaker 4:  it was two years ago when they last refreshed it, it is closer to the
Speaker 4:  iPad pro experience than it's ever been before. And it's remarkable that
Speaker 4:  it does it for $600. Like when you think about the original iPad
Speaker 4:  came out in 2010 for 4 99, if you do the inflation
Speaker 4:  calculation or whatever, it's going to be way more than 4 99 in today's dollars.
Speaker 4:  This is giving you for $600. It's giving you basically
Speaker 4:  Apple's fastest iPad processor, that same amount of Ram, as you get in a
Speaker 4:  comparable storage, iPad pro it runs all the
Speaker 4:  same software and everything like that. So it really obviates the need for
Speaker 4:  the iPad pro for a lot of people. There's some reasons you might want the
Speaker 4:  iPad pro, but fewer and far between. And it's just like a
Speaker 4:  really great iPad. And I think the other question that you had when we were
Speaker 4:  editing this draft Nila is like, well, why don't you just buy the
Speaker 4:  $329 iPad if like they all run the same software and they all do the
Speaker 4:  same thing. And yes, that's true. The, the air is like, if you just want
Speaker 4:  a nicer experience, you want those nicer speakers. You want the nicer
Speaker 4:  build quality. You want the flexibility to work with the newer pencil to
Speaker 4:  work with the magic keyboard. If you really want to it's compatible with
Speaker 4:  all the same accessories as the last model. And you just want to be
Speaker 4:  able to have that iPad. That's going to last for five or six years. It's
Speaker 4:  got all the headroom and all the power that you could want. You're not going
Speaker 4:  to hit the limit of the power of this thing right now, but
Speaker 4:  it'll last for a really long time, just like the iPhone se, except that you're
Speaker 4:  not really making those same compromises you do on the iPhone se you're not
Speaker 4:  getting the old weird design. You're not getting a compromised
Speaker 4:  screen experience.
Speaker 1:  That's what the $329,
Speaker 4:  That's the $329. But the $329 iPad does use an
Speaker 4:  older processor and things like that. So you're, you're like, you know, getting
Speaker 4:  older,
Speaker 3:  Smaller bezels too, right?
Speaker 4:  Like, yeah, this is like the modern apple design ethos, right? It's got
Speaker 4:  that uniform bezels across the, across the screen. So it
Speaker 4:  feels exactly the same, whether you're using portrait or landscape, which
Speaker 4:  is really nice. That's like a, kind of like an iPad hallmark. I've
Speaker 4:  tested a lot of review, reviewed a lot of tablets. I've got the stack of
Speaker 4:  Samsung tablets here that I'm going to spend time with next, finally promise
Speaker 4:  you readers. We are working on them. We're not ignoring them. They do
Speaker 4:  not have that flexibility to work as comfortably in portrait and landscape
Speaker 4:  mode as the iPad does. And the iPad doesn't really well. And part of that
Speaker 4:  is because of it's aspect ratio. And part of it is because the bezels around
Speaker 4:  the screen are just all uniform. It doesn't really matter how you hold it.
Speaker 4:  So it gives you like all the best experiences that the iPad
Speaker 4:  offers for a price that is not a thousand dollars
Speaker 4:  or $1,500 when you add an accessories and things like that. So it's like
Speaker 4:  a really compelling type of tablet. If you're in the market for
Speaker 4:  this mid-size 10 inch 11 inch tablet, which is a really great
Speaker 4:  tablet experience,
Speaker 3:  Is the display better or worse than the Mac studio
Speaker 3:  display?
Speaker 4:  It's better because it's, it's, you know, it's, it's different.
Speaker 4:  I mean, like, I don't know, like it's, if we go and qualify it on all the
Speaker 4:  things that, the map that we just qualified, the Mac studio display on, right?
Speaker 4:  It doesn't have HDR. It maxes out at 500 minutes. So it doesn't have that
Speaker 4:  HDR mini led experience that you get on the 12.9 inch iPad or the
Speaker 4:  11 inch pro. So the 11 inch iPad pro does not have many led. So that's
Speaker 4:  kind of why the 11 inch iPad pro and the iPad air are so similar
Speaker 4:  because the screens are effectively the same, except for refresh rate.
Speaker 4:  Interesting. You said you don't get the HDR, you don't get
Speaker 4:  full array, local dimming or whatever. It's a, an LCD panel,
Speaker 4:  but it is, you know, a great colors. It's plenty of brightness for use
Speaker 4:  in any situation that I really couldn't encounter in my time with it.
Speaker 4:  And it's, you know, super responsive for touch and everything like that.
Speaker 4:  Like a typical iOS devices. So there's really very little to complain about
Speaker 4:  with the screen. It is only 60 Hertz and it doesn't have promotion. And so
Speaker 4:  for some folks who are, so we talked about this earlier, who, if you're
Speaker 4:  sensitive to
Speaker 3:  Neil, I would be fine. You would not.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I mean, like if you're sensitive to refresh rates, you might see a
Speaker 4:  smoother experience on the iPad pro because that does have the 120 Hertz
Speaker 4:  screen. I think a big misconception is that you need
Speaker 4:  the 120 Hertz screen for great stylist experience. And that's not really
Speaker 4:  the case at all. You can have just as good Silas experience on the iPad air.
Speaker 4:  So if you're drawing or writing notes, I take a lot of handwritten notes
Speaker 4:  on an iPad. I really didn't miss having 120 Hertz there.
Speaker 3:  The remarkable two has the best stylist experience out there
Speaker 3:  right now. And it has a refresh rate of like one.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, exactly. Like it's a wildly different technology there that your stack,
Speaker 4:  but if you're comparing the air and the pro and you're like, I want to buy
Speaker 4:  the pro because I use the stylist all the time. It's like, well, maybe you
Speaker 4:  don't really need the pro for your stylist work. There's a digital artist
Speaker 4:  on YouTube that I like a lot because I can't draw for anything. And he's
Speaker 4:  actually pretty good at it. He tests all the tablets and he does the comparisons
Speaker 4:  of like the stylist response in slow motion and like his
Speaker 4:  ultimate conclusion, his name is Brad Cobell. You can find him on YouTube,
Speaker 4:  but like his ultimate conclusion is usually that the, there really isn't
Speaker 4:  that much of a noticeable difference with the slower refresh rate. So the
Speaker 4:  reason that you would get the iPad pro are you get smoother scrolling when
Speaker 4:  you're interacting with it. Now, for me, what I use an iPad for is a lot
Speaker 4:  of reading static text, and I don't need smooth refresh
Speaker 4:  rates for that. Like, it's, it's just there. So like
Speaker 9:  All your pages to be really smooth when they're turning.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. You know, like I turned on the little page, turn animation and the
Speaker 4:  Kindle app, so I can see the page curl over, which I, to every single time,
Speaker 4:  like I turn it on every single time I viewed that at 120 Hertz,
Speaker 4:  but like, I really don't. So like when I was using the air, it like, I, I
Speaker 4:  have, I own an 11 inch pro that's my personal iPad. And like, I
Speaker 4:  didn't miss the pro screen at all. Like, I really didn't miss anything about
Speaker 4:  the pro. That was the weird part about it was, well,
Speaker 17:  You didn't miss face ID.
Speaker 4:  Oh, I'm sorry. That is, yeah. You got the Alex. That is like
Speaker 4:  the, the one experience difference that I think a
Speaker 4:  lot of people will experience between the pro and the air. The air has the
Speaker 4:  same touch ID system and its power button that they had on the 2020 models.
Speaker 4:  So you've got to rest your finger on the power button to unlock it. It works
Speaker 4:  very well. It recognizes your fingerprints very quickly. It's
Speaker 4:  just not nearly as intuitive and seamless as the pro where you just tap the
Speaker 4:  screen, it sees your face and you're in, right? Like it's, it's, it's like
Speaker 4:  you have to stop put your finger on the button, wait for it to do its thing.
Speaker 4:  If you're like, you know, unlocking your password manager or buying an app
Speaker 4:  or paying for something with apple pay, you got to stop, put your finger
Speaker 4:  on the button and I'm never holding it where my fingers near the button.
Speaker 4:  So I always have to like, do
Speaker 1:  You always have it in the keyboard case?
Speaker 4:  So I, for, you know, testing, I put it in the keyboard case. I think the
Speaker 4:  keyboard case is great, but I don't think that this is the right iPad to
Speaker 4:  buy. If you want to replace your laptop, because it's got a small screen.
Speaker 4:  And like, I mean, most of the time for, you know, I think what this is really
Speaker 4:  great at is that tablet experience, you are
Speaker 4:  holding it in your hands. You're sitting on your couch, you're lying in bed
Speaker 4:  or whatever. You're watching a movie, you're reading a book, you're reading
Speaker 4:  apple news or an article or something like that. And it gives you that nice
Speaker 4:  large screen that is still comfortable to hold. As soon as you try to go
Speaker 4:  into like a laptop work environment, you really run into the walls of
Speaker 4:  this really quickly in terms of like the size of the screen and the limitations
Speaker 4:  that iPad iOS puts on you for multi-tasking file management, all the things
Speaker 4:  that we've beaten to death for a couple of years now. And if you are
Speaker 4:  intending on like replacing your laptop, I strongly recommend you consider
Speaker 4:  just going whole hog out to the 13 inch model. But then you give up the tablet
Speaker 4:  experience because the 12.9 inch iPad, it's kind of a crummy tablet when
Speaker 4:  you take it out of its case. So that's kind of where I sit with it. It's
Speaker 4:  a really great tablet experience. And I don't really knock iOS. iPad was
Speaker 4:  all that hard for it's like lack of laptop experience in the review,
Speaker 4:  because I think a lot of people are going to experiences mostly as a tablet.
Speaker 1:  We'll see. I mean, I have an 11 inch pro, which I clearly
Speaker 1:  don't use enough cause I didn't even remember what kind of display it had.
Speaker 1:  The most used iPad in our house is my kids
Speaker 1:  $329 iPad, which runs exactly two apps, Disney
Speaker 1:  plus and YouTube kids. And one is the one I wanted to use. And the other
Speaker 1:  one is full of garbage. It's poisoning her mind. And that's the one that
Speaker 1:  she wants to use. We'll, we'll let the audience try and
Speaker 4:  Figure out
Speaker 1:  Which one's, which Disney plus. Right. But it's like, that's what
Speaker 1:  that thing is for. And it, the thing is trashed and it's fine. And then
Speaker 1:  I think most people, like if you've got the money to spend, you're going
Speaker 1:  to want the nicer one. This is just how companies price products and create
Speaker 1:  tiers. But then it's like, well, if I'm they're so
Speaker 1:  close in price, especially once you start factoring in the story.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. So my big complaint about the iPad era was that it still comes with
Speaker 4:  only 64 gigs of storage, which I think we talked about this last week, but
Speaker 4:  like my perception did not change throughout the process of the review. So
Speaker 4:  my review unit was at 256 gig model. I just kind of like cloned my
Speaker 4:  iCloud account onto it and loaded all my iPad apps that I use. And I'm
Speaker 4:  at 87 gigs. So 64 gigs right off the bat. It's like, no good for
Speaker 4:  me, someone who's had an iPad for a couple of years, doesn't rely on it for
Speaker 4:  like work stuff. I just kinda like use it as an iPad. I think if
Speaker 4:  apple had gone to 1 28 with this as a base, it would have been
Speaker 4:  great because the upgrade is $150 more and it goes all the way to
Speaker 4:  2 56 right away. And then you are like $50
Speaker 4:  away from the 1 28 gig iPad pro, which now you're like, oh, should I
Speaker 4:  just spend 50 bucks and give up that half that story?
Speaker 1:  This is, they did this on purpose. This is like Phil Schiller
Speaker 1:  and his pricing matrix. It's like, I'm going to torture them, torture them
Speaker 1:  and spending a little bit more money. Right? Like I think that all makes
Speaker 1:  sense. I, the one place I disagree with you and I don't travel as
Speaker 1:  nearly as much as I used to, the reason I bought the 11 inch iPad pro and
Speaker 1:  the keyboard case, which is a very expensive, tiny little laptop was it is
Speaker 1:  great for traveling. And it's especially great for airplanes because,
Speaker 1:  because I thought it was just like this endless single-tasking cannot be
Speaker 1:  broken. It doesn't try to use Gogo data the way that like your laptop
Speaker 1:  does.
Speaker 4:  I think in that scenario. And I agree with you because back when I commuted,
Speaker 4:  when that was like a regular thing for me, I use an iPad on the train every
Speaker 4:  single day. It had built in cellular connection and that was like my train
Speaker 4:  computer, or it's a great plane computer. And it's a great travel computer
Speaker 4:  because the, I think the boundaries of iPad S
Speaker 4:  really mesh nicely with the boundaries of that environment that you're in.
Speaker 4:  You're not going to be the most productive on a train. You're not gonna be
Speaker 4:  the most productive on a play. And you're going to bang out emails, write
Speaker 4:  documents, you know, one at a time, things like that. You're not bouncing
Speaker 4:  between tasks and things like that. You're not shuffling files around a lot
Speaker 4:  in those scenarios. And I think the limitations bipedal has, and, and frankly
Speaker 4:  for me, the limitations of chromo has worked really well in those environments.
Speaker 4:  And I can be as productive as I possibly can be with that device, but
Speaker 4:  it is not replacing my laptop because as soon as I get to wherever I'm
Speaker 4:  going, I'm not using the iPad anymore. I'm using my laptop or I'm
Speaker 4:  using a proper computer because it does give me that flexibility
Speaker 4:  where I'm in an environment that I can be more productive. So like the
Speaker 4:  keyboard case is excellent for that type of purpose. And I actually really
Speaker 4:  like typing on the magic keyboard, even though it's small. Like I weirdly
Speaker 4:  get very comfortable on it very quickly and, and I can type very well on
Speaker 4:  that. But like once I get to the office, the iPad staying in my
Speaker 4:  bag, cause I'm just using my laptop, which is even bigger and more comfortable
Speaker 4:  and I have more space and I'm more flexible there. So I, I don't think it
Speaker 4:  replaces my laptop. When you start to add all these things together though,
Speaker 4:  like 600 bucks for the air $300 for the
Speaker 4:  keyboard. If you want to get the pencil, now you're at a thousand dollars.
Speaker 4:  That's a Mac book air with the same processor, twice a store, four
Speaker 4:  times the storage.
Speaker 1:  Right. But it's not as much fun to use. I've I've, I've the reason I had
Speaker 1:  a 12 inch MacBook with the single port for the longest
Speaker 1:  time was cause it was just like the right size for an airplane. Sure.
Speaker 4:  But, but as soon as you got off that airplane, you weren't using that anymore.
Speaker 4:  Right?
Speaker 1:  Well, presumably I had, I had arrived at a destination where I was going
Speaker 1:  to talk to other people and not like immediately. So you see my laptop, like
Speaker 1:  that's like the saddest plane right in the world where we're different people
Speaker 1:  that have clearly, it's like, you know, here's what I do. I've I've arrived.
Speaker 1:  I'm going to go to my hotel room and set up my three displays rock
Speaker 1:  out. Like,
Speaker 9:  And without your Mac studio set up your five displays, a new TV.
Speaker 1:  Exactly. I brought my iMac with me. I don't
Speaker 1:  know. I don't remember what traveling is like. It was a different life. I
Speaker 1:  was a different person back then. So I've had air seems great. It
Speaker 1:  feels like if you need to buy an iPad right now that one's
Speaker 1:  fine, but we would probably expect new iPad pros
Speaker 1:  the end of the year. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  It's weird. If you're, if you've been paying attention to that rumor mill,
Speaker 4:  that's like they go back and forth every other week, new iPad pros are coming
Speaker 4:  this year. They're not coming this year. They will bring the million mini
Speaker 4:  led screen down to the elephant inch. Oh, they're not going to do that this
Speaker 4:  year. So it's like really hard to suss out whether we're going to see new
Speaker 4:  iPad pros is here. I will say that they released new iPad
Speaker 4:  pros last year, less spring-ish. And the
Speaker 4:  iPad pro is typically on an 18 to 24 month upgrade cycle per
Speaker 4:  history. So my money would be on early
Speaker 4:  20, 23 for an iPad pro, but the supply chain kind
Speaker 4:  of mix everything up. So you can't really predict all that easily anymore.
Speaker 4:  So I don't know. It's hard to say if you're buying today, I would say
Speaker 4:  the air should probably be your first choice. If you're looking for a great
Speaker 4:  iPad experience, make sure you can deal with that. 64 gigs of storage. If
Speaker 4:  not, then you're looking at upgrading the storage and then you're in this
Speaker 4:  world, weird world of, should I buy the pro or not? And frankly, I
Speaker 4:  don't know if I can help you too much there. You just gotta look into your
Speaker 4:  heart and decide which one is the better one for you.
Speaker 1:  If you want face ID it's is it face ID, right?
Speaker 4:  It could be the 120 Hertz. I don't think it's the four speakers. Like I couldn't
Speaker 4:  hear a difference between the two speakers on the air and the four speakers
Speaker 4:  on the pro non-significant difference there. It's definitely not the
Speaker 4:  0.1 inch larger screen. Cause it's 10.9. There's
Speaker 4:  11. Yeah. That's not it. And maybe it's,
Speaker 4:  you know, the, the 120 Hertz screen. I didn't, we even talk about this at
Speaker 4:  all. That air now has an optional 5g, but it's only six sub
Speaker 4:  six. It works. If you get 5g on the
Speaker 4:  pro it's millimeter wave, which great if you can find it, but
Speaker 4:  that 5g upgrade on the pro cost $200 and the 5g upgrade on this
Speaker 4:  kind of air costs 150. So you have to pay more for that millimeter wave that
Speaker 4:  you probably won't get.
Speaker 1:  You're just standing under a street corner with an 11 inch iPad pro
Speaker 4:  You get two extra, you get an extra camera in the back. So you're taking
Speaker 4:  pictures with your iPad and more meter with of, of the millimeter wave tower.
Speaker 1:  Everyone's like, look at that rich guy. That's staggering display every well
Speaker 1:  gets
Speaker 4:  So many cameras
Speaker 1:  From this extra camera and millimeter wave.
Speaker 1:  Who is that? And the
Speaker 9:  Keyboard case attached
Speaker 1:  Warren buffet.
Speaker 1:  All right. A couple of we're way over couple of notes,
Speaker 1:  universal control also hit Mac iOS, iOS, iPad, iOS
Speaker 1:  . So now you can just like scoot a mouse, like magic.
Speaker 4:  Very clever.
Speaker 1:  It is very cool. It works really well. If you've got an iPad and Mac,
Speaker 1:  although you have to upgrade your max Monterey, which yes you do. Th that's
Speaker 1:  how they get you. Also, the studio display requires Monterey, which is like
Speaker 1:  the monitor, but it's got a whole computer. Yeah. That's why I
Speaker 1:  definitely doesn't need
Speaker 1:  a very confusing, whatever two things I want to call out.
Speaker 1:  Mia Sato, our platforms and communities reporter, and the creators ask
Speaker 1:  big Vimeo story Sauvignon, pivoted away from being a YouTube competitor to
Speaker 1:  being like this B2B video provider. But now the creators and the
Speaker 1:  platforms are being asked to pay thousands of dollars for hosting fees.
Speaker 1:  They're not happy. That's a great story. You should read it. She also had
Speaker 1:  an incredible story about Ukrainian influencers who are on tick tock,
Speaker 1:  tick tock stuff like tussle, like business hustle
Speaker 1:  advice, and like workout tips. And now they're all like war correspondence.
Speaker 1:  It is remarkable. It's like a great verge story. It's about how people
Speaker 1:  dramatically changed the way they use the tools they have when circumstances
Speaker 1:  change. There's the way out. Great. You got to go read it. And then lastly,
Speaker 1:  this is just a fun one. Jason Snell, who used to be editor of Macworld magazine.
Speaker 1:  When the Mac studio was announced, I was like, this thing reminds me of this
Speaker 1:  idea for computer people have had for 20 years. So he wrote about it with
Speaker 1:  like all these pictures of old Mac magazines and like why people wanted Mac
Speaker 1:  something like a Mac studio. It was just a great story. It's called the Mac
Speaker 1:  studio Smith fulfillment. If you're in a computer history, it's really good
Speaker 1:  to go to this week. Matt Mullenweg. Who's the CEO of automatic that's company
Speaker 1:  that owns WordPress and Tumblr and day one in pocket casts.
Speaker 1:  Super interesting conversation. You can tweet at us. I'm at reckless.
Speaker 1:  Alex is Alex H Kranz. Dan is DCC for
Speaker 1:  Monica's NC squared, 96. Alison is Alison Joe
Speaker 1:  one. That's it? That's where Chester
Speaker 19:  Later