# Transcript
ID: 9eeda0b0-bd1c-11ec-ab72-3b8274bd4ba1
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Mark Zuckerberg’s big plans for AR glasses / Elon Musk offers to buy Twitter in takeover attempt
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/1922991724938814339/8443761330437407172/s93290-US-5817s-1650063852.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, Liz Lopatto, Alex Cranz, and Alex Heath discuss Elon Musk's offer to buy 100 percent of Twitter and what it could mean for the company.
Senior reporter Adi Robertson joins the show to discuss Elon's limited thoughts on content moderation and Alex Heath's scoop on Meta's plans for their AR glasses.
Speaker 1:  This week on the verge cast, Liz Lopatto, Addie Robertson and Alex
Speaker 1:  Heath joined the show. We talk about Elon Musk's offer to buy
Speaker 1:  Twitter. What that means, what would happen, what he is talking about. When
Speaker 1:  he talks about free speech, then Aussies had big soup on medicine tire AR
Speaker 1:  roadmap. We get into that. That's come up on the Vergecast. Now
Speaker 1:  Hello, and welcome to the Vergecast flagship podcast. The
Speaker 1:  first amendment or the only podcast that reads
Speaker 1:  it, I've read it. I assure you that I've read the first
Speaker 1:  amendment and the associated case law. Look, I'm all about free
Speaker 1:  speech here. And if anyone says I'm not they're censoring me anyway,
Speaker 1:  I'm Neil. I'm your friend Alex grants here.
Speaker 5:  I'm actually buying another social media network. So I too can be a
Speaker 5:  champion of free speech.
Speaker 1:  So that's what you need. Market competition, Alex, Heath, this here.
Speaker 6:  Hi, I am your fire, your one desire.
Speaker 6:  And it's been a long week.
Speaker 1:  The last night I was talking to Alex. He goes, I think I almost passed out
Speaker 1:  today. And I was like, what happened? He's like, I forgot to breathe. Which
Speaker 1:  is like a real thing you said to me, he was like, I was typing
Speaker 1:  so fast. I forgot to breathe. Liz Lopatto was here.
Speaker 7:  I bring with me tidings of Elan, as I think long time listeners. Now
Speaker 1:  The winds of Ilan have brought Liz back to us. Once again, the
Speaker 7:  Winds are changing.
Speaker 1:  So we got to talk about it and buy it. I mean,
Speaker 1:  Intel's next generation. I don't mean that at all. What I mean is that Elon
Speaker 1:  Musk threatened to buy Twitter this week. He blew up our entire publishing
Speaker 1:  schedule. We had so many great stories this week and suddenly our whole
Speaker 1:  site yesterday, I looked at the site and the entire top of it was the alumni
Speaker 1:  stories. So if you will recall, I think I was not on the show the
Speaker 1:  week this happened, but you
Speaker 5:  Are not
Speaker 1:  Many of you were here that week. I was trapped on a plane, I believe.
Speaker 5:  And I were just dropping curse words the whole time you were gone.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. Dad's out everybody party.
Speaker 1:  Well, trust me, the curse words are coming free. Speech. You can't, you
Speaker 1:  can't shut me down. What's the FCC going to do? Half of my personality is
Speaker 1:  the movie pump up the volume scene where he drives around in the Jeep
Speaker 1:  Wrangler. And the FCC tries to chase him down. That's Easily
Speaker 1:  half of my personality. So Elan
Speaker 1:  bought 9% of Twitter. He was offered a board seat.
Speaker 1:  They thought he had were tricking him from what we gather into like having
Speaker 1:  a fiduciary duty to the best interest of the shareholders and
Speaker 1:  a lockup provision that said he couldn't buy more than like almost 15% of
Speaker 1:  the company. He declined this. He gets away from it ever and wonders. What's
Speaker 1:  he going to do? He filed, he sends it out another letter saying I
Speaker 1:  offered to buy the whole thing for Liz's favorite number 54,
Speaker 1:  20 a share is his favorite number all for favorite
Speaker 1:  number, chaos ensues. He did an interview at
Speaker 1:  Ted, which was horrible. We'll talk about that later with Addy. Cause it
Speaker 1:  was all about content moderation. What? Just start at the
Speaker 1:  start. Alex, walk me through like what this
Speaker 1:  offer is you reported right out of the Twitter, all hands
Speaker 1:  yesterday, you reported a little bit on what the board was thinking. What's
Speaker 1:  going on here.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. So Elan is offering about
Speaker 6:  of 43 ish billion dollar and I guess
Speaker 6:  cash. We don't really know. And I guess that's the Elan of all. This is
Speaker 6:  that he says funding is secured
Speaker 6:  TBD. We'll see what that is. He says he has the assets to
Speaker 6:  buy Twitter and take it private at a nice takeout premium,
Speaker 6:  which is higher than when he started buying shares towards the beginning
Speaker 6:  of the year. And he notified Twitter of this
Speaker 6:  one evening this week, the next morning made it public and an sec
Speaker 6:  filing and a tweet just saying like I made an
Speaker 6:  offer Twitter quickly responded and was like, we're going
Speaker 6:  to review this. Obviously they have to, Twitter is not a founder
Speaker 6:  controlled company like Facebook or snap or
Speaker 6:  Google. And they can't just have one person be like,
Speaker 6:  not when stuff like this happens. So they had to
Speaker 6:  respond. And then the chaos that is
Speaker 6:  Elan continued to ensue throughout the day. And I
Speaker 6:  forgot to breathe at some point after that,
Speaker 5:  You're too busy. You couldn't breathe. You had to blog.
Speaker 1:  And what are you doing with breathing? You don't breathe on my dime
Speaker 1:  Alex, on your own time, when you
Speaker 1:  taking breaths, there was actually a moment yesterday when Keith were boy,
Speaker 1:  who's like a high-end VC was
Speaker 1:  like the woke Twitter employees are going to see what's coming to them
Speaker 1:  one time, Elan threatened to fire all of the interns at Tesla because they
Speaker 1:  were waiting in line for coffee. And it was like, what?
Speaker 1:  Why are you turning heel so deeply, right? That just like buy
Speaker 1:  another coffee machine.
Speaker 6:  Well, it was really like, you know, the phrase like reality
Speaker 6:  is stranger than fiction or something like that. Like it was, it was focus
Speaker 6:  week for Twitter. So did employees had Monday off as a day of
Speaker 6:  rest. And that was when a lot of this started. And
Speaker 6:  then for the week they were supposed to take minimal meetings and be heads
Speaker 6:  down on projects. And the CEO then scheduled
Speaker 6:  an emergency all
Speaker 6:  hands.
Speaker 6:  Pretty interesting. And you know, had some Backstreet
Speaker 6:  boys playing. So yeah, it was a, it was the CFO's birthday, I think
Speaker 6:  when Elan made the bid as well. So you just,
Speaker 6:  you can't write this stuff.
Speaker 1:  The Backstreet boys line by the way is real. They open the meeting by playing
Speaker 1:  Backstreet boys, which is perfect. Like someone had to choose
Speaker 1:  like that's you have to make you don't just like hit the button in zoom.
Speaker 1:  That's like play some music you like now let's go with Backstreet. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  The first song was I say a little prayer and then they
Speaker 6:  jumped into, I want it that way.
Speaker 1:  Amazing.
Speaker 7:  I think we've all been saying little prayers ever since this, this offer
Speaker 7:  became public. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. So Liz, you are a noted Elan watcher. I believe you described
Speaker 1:  yourself as a sicko yesterday. That might've been the exact phrase you
Speaker 1:  used to walk us through the Ilan of this all.
Speaker 7:  Okay. Well I just want to say like, although he's got Morgan Stanley
Speaker 7:  advising him, he says that funding is contingent on
Speaker 7:  winning. And then if this seems familiar, it's because he doesn't have
Speaker 7:  funding lined up. And like during his Ted talk, he was like,
Speaker 7:  well, I don't, I don't, I could buy Twitter, but I don't want to which who
Speaker 7:  could blame him because he'd have to sell a bunch of Tesla shares and that
Speaker 7:  would make the Tesla people very unhappy. So the funding is
Speaker 7:  TBD. And if this were anybody else, I would say, this is not a
Speaker 7:  serious offer because serious offers have funding lined
Speaker 7:  up. But in Elan's case, it's impossible to tell what serious and
Speaker 7:  what some kind of joke, which is like, you know, Matt Levine has suggested
Speaker 7:  Twitter, come back to him with another price, which is the
Speaker 7:  other fund, internet number $69 a
Speaker 7:  share, Which, you know what I
Speaker 7:  like, I like, I like how he was thinking here, but you know, if you, if you
Speaker 7:  consider what he's doing, I got to say, like, I kind of feel
Speaker 7:  like he's just fucking with Twitter because the share price
Speaker 7:  is it, you know, it's, it's relatively low compared to where Twitter has
Speaker 7:  been trading since like last year. Like I think it was in the
Speaker 7:  sixties in October and then the seventies, like a year
Speaker 7:  ago. So like relatively recently, the, the share price was
Speaker 7:  trading at more than a lot more than what he's offering. Well, the
Speaker 7:  other thing that I noticed about shares because the secret of shares is like,
Speaker 7:  they're just like feelings. Like this is just people putting money on like
Speaker 7:  their feelings. That's that's all the market is now. You're a trader.
Speaker 7:  I noticed that the shares were trading well
Speaker 7:  below where the offer was
Speaker 7:  all of yesterday, which means that the market doesn't believe it's real.
Speaker 7:  Now, if the market did believe it's real, it would be trading at the same
Speaker 7:  price or around the price of the offer. And if they thought there was going
Speaker 7:  to be somebody else jumping in, like for instance, Disney, they would be
Speaker 7:  trading above the offer. So you can look at that and you can say,
Speaker 7:  oh, these people are familiar with Elon Musk. They're aware that sometimes
Speaker 7:  when he says he was taking a company private, he's just
Speaker 7:  kidding.
Speaker 1:  Let's we gotta talk about that specific line of Elon in a minute.
Speaker 1:  But real quickly is I think most people are vaguely
Speaker 1:  aware that you can offer to buy a company, but there's like a lot of steps
Speaker 1:  before the company is actually yours. So what's the process here that Elon
Speaker 1:  would have to go through.
Speaker 7:  So I, the first, this is a hostile bid. So that's that in and of itself
Speaker 7:  is unusual. Ordinarily one works with companies management to
Speaker 7:  like come together with a thing that will be acceptable to
Speaker 7:  major shareholders. And this is not what's happening here. This is Ilan is
Speaker 7:  like, I got a bid. So Twitter has to think about it. They have like a whole
Speaker 7:  fiduciary duty. The board is going to be thinking about it, but I, if
Speaker 7:  I'm Ilan right now, I'm out here pressuring shareholders to pressure the
Speaker 7:  board. So I'm calling them. I'm saying things like in that script that we
Speaker 7:  all saw that was filed with the sec where it's like, this is my best and
Speaker 7:  final offer. And I, you know what, I'm going to sell all my
Speaker 7:  shares if it doesn't work, which in Elan's case is like a little bit like,
Speaker 7:  Hmm, okay, this is, this is hard ball. This is like some Carl Icahn shit
Speaker 7:  we got going on here. And he loved because he created a premium by getting
Speaker 7:  into the stock, by having his ownership announced, which is the sort of thing
Speaker 7:  that you associate actually with corporate Raiders. Like that's also what
Speaker 7:  happens with Carl Icahn gets into a stock. So Twitter's board has to think
Speaker 7:  this through, like, just because I'm a, I'm a lady who is like, maybe
Speaker 7:  not particularly privy to this stuff. I think it's going to be
Speaker 7:  like, I don't think that the board is going to say yes to
Speaker 7:  this. Just speaking as somebody who doesn't know anybody on the board or
Speaker 7:  doesn't have any connections to the board. I feel like if I were on the board,
Speaker 7:  I'd be like, no, but what's interesting. Here is now the company is
Speaker 7:  in place. So there could potentially be another bidder. The market doesn't
Speaker 7:  totally believe it. But if I'm a tech company and I ever wanted to acquire
Speaker 7:  a Twitter, like now's the moment. Because one of the things that the board
Speaker 7:  can do is come back with somebody else's better offer and say, sorry, Elan.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. So Alex, you were tracking a little bit of this yesterday.
Speaker 1:  Twitter's management and board is kind of an interesting spot, right? Jack
Speaker 1:  Dorsey left. He basically said my hand selected
Speaker 1:  successors progra wall as CEO and my hand selected
Speaker 1:  chairman of the board is this guy, Brett Taylor. And he's like, these are
Speaker 1:  my guys. I picked him. I love him. They're Jack skies. They were, I,
Speaker 1:  you can't like if someone came to your job and was like,
Speaker 1:  we think you've been doing a really bad job, so we're just gonna take it
Speaker 1:  from here. Like it's, I don't think it's instinctual for you to be like,
Speaker 1:  I agree with you. And I have trapping accepted this job. I
Speaker 1:  will in fact recede into the distance and let you destroy whatever it is.
Speaker 1:  I was supposed to be in charge of like, especially for a young
Speaker 1:  CEO who has no name, otherwise, like, that's just
Speaker 1:  like, you're done, right? Like you're, you might as well just ride off into
Speaker 1:  the sunset, like your career kind of stops there. So
Speaker 1:  what were you hearing yesterday, Alex?
Speaker 6:  Well, I think every, I mean, obviously I think Liz is right. The
Speaker 6:  board doesn't want to do this. I think that was the tone of the all hands
Speaker 6:  with employees was Prague was, you know, I think employees
Speaker 6:  were because Prague and the leadership had not
Speaker 6:  directly addressed Ilan besides
Speaker 6:  Pirog tweeting when he decided not to join the board and
Speaker 6:  saying distractions are ahead. Foreboding kind of what was to come employees
Speaker 6:  were expecting. I think at this emergency all hands to kind of get some more
Speaker 6:  clarity about where the company was leaning, what the timeline was going
Speaker 6:  to look like here, because this could be a protracted messy thing, especially
Speaker 6:  if they have to run an official bidding process. And these large
Speaker 6:  companies take time to reviews the review of these deals.
Speaker 6:  So, you know, that's not really what happened. And Pirog was like, look for
Speaker 6:  legal reasons. I can't really say, but I can just say that we're
Speaker 6:  following a rigorous process. Yada, yada, everything was obviously very
Speaker 6:  lawyered. They knew it was going to leak like almost in real
Speaker 6:  time. It wasn't quite in real time, but we got ours up like
Speaker 6:  right when it ended. So our, our story on it. So yeah,
Speaker 6:  it was, I would say there was a sense of resistance,
Speaker 6:  but from Pirog he said something about how, you know, we're not going to
Speaker 6:  be held hostage. And, you know, basically saying that
Speaker 6:  like it's too early to speculate about what it would look like if we were
Speaker 6:  taken private, because there's big implications for employees in that, you
Speaker 6:  know, if that happens, because what happens to their stock
Speaker 6:  options, there were questions about layoffs, which is something I was actually
Speaker 6:  hearing before this meeting was the moment Elon announced his interest. I
Speaker 6:  had like three Twitter employees to be like, there's going to be layoffs.
Speaker 1:  Like, absolutely.
Speaker 6:  Like Twitter is fairly bloated relative to
Speaker 6:  the money it makes and it's tech peers. So those are the
Speaker 6:  questions on people's minds, which to me says, people think that this is,
Speaker 6:  you know, the rank and file thinks this is probably happening no matter what,
Speaker 6:  at least like there's going to be a messy, maybe bad outcome for
Speaker 6:  them from this. And so in that way, you know, there's a,
Speaker 6:  maybe a fear that management at Twitter has kind of lost faith. You
Speaker 6:  know, that the employees have lost faith in them to a degree, a little bit.
Speaker 6:  One was like, are we just going to be letting any billionaire who wants a
Speaker 6:  board seat? Give them a board seat. Are we going to just like, do this for
Speaker 6:  everyone now who asks
Speaker 5:  They got enough money, right.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And it's an interesting time for Elan to be doing this because Jack
Speaker 6:  is on the board for like another month or so before the next board votes
Speaker 6:  on the new board seats. And so, I don't know, you know, my favorite conspiracy
Speaker 6:  theory here is that Jack and Ilan are aligned on this. And this is Jack
Speaker 6:  Sweet revenge on Elliot management, which was the last active
Speaker 6:  investor that came into Twitter and really kind
Speaker 6:  of led to Jack stepping aside and naming Pirog last November.
Speaker 1:  Walk us through that. There's a lot of detail to explore there
Speaker 7:  Before you walk us through it. We need to have the succession theme play
Speaker 7:  because this is like very like, this is a very
Speaker 7:  succession theme moment here.
Speaker 6:  Oh my God. I had a very senior former Twitter person be like text me right
Speaker 6:  before Elan walked out on stage at Ted and be like, I have money on Jack
Speaker 6:  walking out with him on stage attack, which is like,
Speaker 6:  yeah, that's, that's better than whatever the next
Speaker 5:  Jack wanted to take the company private awhile ago. Didn't he?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. So I had done some reporting a couple of years ago that, you know,
Speaker 6:  the last time Twitter ran a formal sales process was
Speaker 6:  around 2016. And that was when Salesforce and Disney were the two kind of
Speaker 6:  lead suitors and Bob Iger and mark Benioff have talked publicly about
Speaker 6:  that. There were two other players who didn't get as far apple and
Speaker 6:  Google that were looking at IQ at apple and Sundar at Google.
Speaker 6:  And there were also some offers informally to take the company
Speaker 6:  private at the time. And this was when Twitter's valuation was like 10 billion.
Speaker 6:  And it was just really, almost struggling more than it has been
Speaker 6:  since, which is like hard to think about. So I had heard from
Speaker 6:  someone kind of directly involved in those talks that Jack was in favor of
Speaker 6:  taking the company private at that time. And it makes sense because Twitter
Speaker 6:  has just, when you have these quarterly expectations in the
Speaker 6:  market and your comp to Facebook, which has just been this unstoppable
Speaker 6:  growth juggernaut for over a decade and even like
Speaker 6:  snap snap is added like a hundred more, a hundred million more users than
Speaker 6:  Twitter. And it's like four years younger as a company and been public
Speaker 6:  way less. So Twitter is just really struggled relative to its
Speaker 6:  peer set. And it could probably use the insulation that going private
Speaker 6:  would provide it right where like they can actually go heads down and focus
Speaker 6:  on just not these near term quarterly benchmarks they need to meet,
Speaker 6:  but like really, really, you know, reinvent the product and Jack and
Speaker 6:  Elan saw eye to eye on that. You know, they both talk about open
Speaker 6:  sourcing the algorithm, which God we got to get into that because that makes
Speaker 6:  absolutely no sense. None, you know, opening up the algorithms cause that'll
Speaker 6:  solve everything and, you know, crypto
Speaker 6:  decentralization putting, making it a protocol again, going back to the
Speaker 6:  Tweety days when like all these clients were sat on top of
Speaker 6:  Twitter and invented, you know, the best parts of Twitter. And I
Speaker 6:  could see there's an argument to be made that Jack maybe wants this in the
Speaker 6:  background. And the fact that Elon is doing this while Jack is still on the
Speaker 6:  board and still has about 2%. It's like the timing of that. Very interesting.
Speaker 1:  So Jack had a tweet a couple of weeks ago now where he was
Speaker 1:  like, I now realize that centralizing all internet
Speaker 1:  services was a mistake and I am to blame. And then someone was like, well
Speaker 1:  fix it. He was like, I'm working on it. And I've just been thinking about
Speaker 1:  that, that little interaction in this context a lot, because
Speaker 1:  he, Twitter has this program called blue sky, which
Speaker 1:  has been moving in an absolutely glacial pace, which is
Speaker 1:  designed to decentralize Twitter and turn it into a protocol. When I
Speaker 1:  say a glacial pace, I mean every six months, they're like, we've
Speaker 1:  hired one more person. We're up to four.
Speaker 6:  They recently announced. So it's actually a separate legal entity. It's like
Speaker 6:  a nonprofit that Twitter funds, they're not the only funder and Jack is on
Speaker 6:  the board of blue sky. And he's about to leave the board of Twitter and he
Speaker 6:  just joined blue sky interesting note, but continuing the line.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. It just put the it's the heaven, you know, I feel about vaporware.
Speaker 1:  You can tell me you're going to do shit all day long. Right? You have to
Speaker 1:  do it. And they've, they've not shipped a single line of code. They've
Speaker 1:  shipped a white paper and a bunch of press releases about people they've
Speaker 1:  hired.
Speaker 7:  Well, you know, Jack is very into crypto, so that's like kind of standard
Speaker 7:  in that world. Although in fairness, I should say he's a
Speaker 7:  Bitcoin maxi and not into crypto per se so much as he's just
Speaker 7:  into Bitcoin.
Speaker 1:  Great. He's the one who's beefing with Chris Dixon about Andreessen Horowitz
Speaker 1:  being just like another, like a VC front for web three. And
Speaker 1:  he's like, Bitcoin is the alpha and the omega at web three is just another
Speaker 1:  way for VCs Tony internet. Like that's Jack very
Speaker 1:  publicly beefing with the people who are funding web three.
Speaker 1:  However you wanted to find next to that is Ilan who, who just
Speaker 1:  loves Twitter. Like the man just loves Twitter. Lizzie mentioned Matt Levine
Speaker 1:  earlier in it. He's a columnist for Bloomberg
Speaker 1:  in one of his columns, I think earlier last week, maybe he was
Speaker 1:  like, if you're really rich and you play a video game all the time, you're
Speaker 1:  going to have ideas about the video game and that is Ilan and Twitter,
Speaker 1:  right? Like it's a video game that he constantly plays and stuff like
Speaker 1:  open up the algorithm. Like that's the sort of idea you might have about
Speaker 1:  it. Like I have a million ideas on how to fix Madden NFL. Like I, every
Speaker 1:  day I can just generate a list and there's like, what I think should happen
Speaker 1:  and reality of that game and how it is architected. And
Speaker 1:  so if you think, you know, I can just buy it and open source Twitter or buy
Speaker 1:  it and turn it into a protocol. The technical effort to do
Speaker 1:  that is extraordinarily high. The company is
Speaker 1:  already trying to do some of that stuff and hasn't done any of it. And all
Speaker 1:  the employees are pissed off and thinking about leaving or we're worried
Speaker 1:  about being laid off. Like, I don't know how you go from here to there. And
Speaker 1:  Ilan hasn't really laid it out.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I mean, there was a pretty senior Twitter person who I saw a tweet
Speaker 6:  in response to someone saying like, what will you do if Elan takes over?
Speaker 6:  And is I, and she was like, well, you know, I hope he likes working at a
Speaker 6:  company with no employees. Like she was like the head of like machine
Speaker 6:  learning or something. So yeah, open sourcing the algorithm. Can we talk
Speaker 6:  about this? Because you know, I actually, I just did a story a couple of
Speaker 6:  weeks ago about Facebook. It took them six months to try to figure
Speaker 6:  out what went wrong with the newsfeed algorithm. This is the people
Speaker 6:  who directly work on the newsfeed literally did not
Speaker 6:  know what broke for months. And they are still dissecting
Speaker 6:  it. Like I've heard from people who work on these kinds of algorithms that
Speaker 6:  these social media companies, they don't really know how they
Speaker 6:  work fully. It's all, it's like a Pandora's box that once you
Speaker 6:  open these things have millions of signals. And the idea that
Speaker 6:  like, it's this one algorithm that everyone can just like look at and
Speaker 6:  dissect and know all of its inputs and
Speaker 6:  outputs. The whole point of this is that it's different for every single
Speaker 6:  person. These algorithms are really just like a reflection of like
Speaker 6:  your most carnal desires. Like they
Speaker 6:  are a distorted mirror of you and your worst impulses.
Speaker 5:  Well, a lot of them, but I mean, it's, Twitter's though like Twitter. I always
Speaker 5:  envisioned as having the most
Speaker 5:  simplistic
Speaker 9:  Envision about Twitter
Speaker 6:  Because
Speaker 5:  Like, this is not Tik talk that like
Speaker 5:  knows I like skiing before I did. This is like pretty
Speaker 5:  simple
Speaker 6:  As someone who woke up this morning and was seeing tweets from 17 hours ago
Speaker 6:  at the top of my feet and had to switch to chronological. Cause I was like,
Speaker 6:  I saw this yesterday and have that experience on a daily basis. You're
Speaker 6:  right. That's what our algorithm is. Not really that good at mind reading,
Speaker 6:  but my point is just that the algorithm is different for every single
Speaker 6:  person. And I think we're fooling ourselves to say that like millions
Speaker 6:  of people care or want to know the innards of like the
Speaker 6:  feed that is giving them information.
Speaker 5:  I don't think millions, but one of these algorithms being open source
Speaker 5:  is a fascinating thing because we don't really have one now to my
Speaker 5:  knowledge and, and, and having those researchers and those people
Speaker 5:  in the open source community, having access and starting to tweak with these
Speaker 5:  things and deal with them is really interesting. I
Speaker 5:  think for Twitter itself, it makes zero sense and as
Speaker 5:  super stupid, but like, I think 90% of Twitter's business
Speaker 5:  is kind of stupid. Like it's not a company that's making a lot of
Speaker 5:  money. It's not a company that's building subscribers, everything about this.
Speaker 5:  It's just like a billionaire kind of shit posting his
Speaker 5:  way into notoriety with a company that he can afford to
Speaker 5:  do it with.
Speaker 7:  I also don't know that like the algorithm is the problem with
Speaker 7:  Twitter. Like I just, I just want to be super real
Speaker 7:  about like what Twitter is. It's like an all
Speaker 7:  versus all hostiles zone where
Speaker 7:  like, you know, roving gangs of people
Speaker 7:  form and like it.
Speaker 7:  So I'm going to compare it to four Chan in a very limited way, which
Speaker 7:  is that it is,
Speaker 5:  This is
Speaker 7:  Getting good. It is a nexus of internet culture from which a lot of internet
Speaker 7:  culture comes, but it is also a very hostile
Speaker 7:  environment. And now the mechanics of it work differently from four Chan,
Speaker 7:  like in ways that are like maybe not worth discussing right at this very
Speaker 7:  moment. But in terms of like users, it's a relatively
Speaker 7:  small base compared to like most of the other social
Speaker 7:  media platforms, but it has this like outsized
Speaker 7:  hold on the public's imagination, a of all, because every
Speaker 7:  journalist is like addled by Twitter. Cause we're all there. Cause
Speaker 7:  that's like what we do instead of like RSS feeds
Speaker 7:  because Google reader doesn't exist anymore. So Google, thank
Speaker 7:  you. This is your fault.
Speaker 1:  RSS feeds. I, it would not be the virtuous. If I didn't remind that RSS feed
Speaker 1:  still exist, there are many independent RSS readers over there and I'm counting
Speaker 1:  on Google to be the sole shepherd or the open internet was always a mistake.
Speaker 1:  That's it? Just my little digression, the act.
Speaker 7:  So there's that. But also like we have these 24 hour cable
Speaker 7:  news networks that like need to like put stuff on
Speaker 7:  television. And so what do they do? They open up Twitter, they read tweets
Speaker 7:  out loud and like, that's like a segment.
Speaker 1:  And as somebody who has a cable news contract, I feel comfortable
Speaker 1:  saying the majority of mainstream cable news is a podcast to people
Speaker 1:  reading tweets. And then like, I'm not saying that's not
Speaker 1:  our podcast. Like it's not like the harshest criticism in the world.
Speaker 1:  Like we're talking about one guy who tweets a lot. We've been doing it for
Speaker 1:  26 minutes. So like maybe that's all news now.
Speaker 1:  But the point about like what Twitter is, whether it has a
Speaker 1:  ranking algorithm or not, the problem is actually expressed
Speaker 1:  in whether the ranking algorithm for Twitter is it's product or
Speaker 1:  not. Facebook's product is a ranking algorithm. Take talks.
Speaker 1:  Product is a ranking algorithm, right? Google's product
Speaker 1:  is the world's most successful ranking algorithm. You
Speaker 1:  express some interest to one of these platforms and they
Speaker 1:  have a huge data set of all the other people. YouTube has a huge data set
Speaker 1:  of all the other people have contributed content and then they show it to
Speaker 1:  you, Twitter, you log in as a new user and it's like, the
Speaker 1:  worst shit in the world is going to immediately start happening to you. And
Speaker 1:  maybe you will find NBA Twitter, or maybe you will distract
Speaker 1:  yourself with media, Twitter. Like maybe you will find some pocket of
Speaker 1:  film Twitter. That's great. But at any moment, as Liz
Speaker 1:  said, that angriest hoards of people might find you or the
Speaker 1:  worst possible thing that could happen to you, your tweet will go viral and
Speaker 1:  like Fox news will write about you. Like the worst possible
Speaker 1:  things could happen to you at any moment. On the Twitter platform,
Speaker 6:  I had a tweet go viral about Ilan and the day of
Speaker 6:  the week of focus and the day of arrest, then the timing of it all. And it
Speaker 6:  was just, it was that persona. It was just like his bot
Speaker 6:  farms and his like, you know, people calling me an idiot and all
Speaker 6:  these things saying, I don't understand things. Like I got like
Speaker 6:  unsolicited, like hate mail. So it's
Speaker 6:  like just for a tweet. And that was because it was about Elan, the guy trying
Speaker 6:  to take Twitter, we should know like Elon has a like massive
Speaker 6:  bot army that follows him on Twitter and amplifies and it
Speaker 6:  attacks his critics. And he said that he wants to get rid of bots. But
Speaker 6:  like, it's just very ironic to me that that's the
Speaker 6:  case that like this, this one individual has that
Speaker 5:  Well, like I think a lot of people fail to understand that
Speaker 5:  Ilan success at this point that his current success is
Speaker 5:  kind of based on Twitter and this like this fandom he's
Speaker 5:  created around himself that centralized on Twitter. Right.
Speaker 1:  I think Elan might feel that way. And I think we might feel that way. I'm
Speaker 1:  not entirely like, I don't know the conversion rate between
Speaker 1:  having a bot army and lots of followers on Twitter to Tesla sales.
Speaker 1:  Right. And Tessa has apparently like inelastic demand. Like you can price
Speaker 1:  a Tesla at any number or produce any number of Teslas and all of them will
Speaker 1:  sell. Like they can't, every Tesla they make at any price will sell out.
Speaker 1:  Right. What does that have to do with the Twitter army?
Speaker 7:  I'm like dying here because like I have been covering Elon
Speaker 7:  Musk for a very long time and like, yeah, like
Speaker 7:  welcome to tweeting about Elon Musk. Like those aren't all bots. Like some
Speaker 7:  of those are just people who can't spell very well. You discover
Speaker 7:  if you reply to them. So Tesla is the original meme stock.
Speaker 7:  And like one of the things that was going on with Tesla
Speaker 7:  shares, you know, in 20 16, 20 17, 20 18
Speaker 7:  is like Elon Musk can make the shares go up by tweeting positive things about
Speaker 7:  Tesla. And like he's been disclosed and their company filings as being like
Speaker 7:  a source of legitimate information, like his Twitter account. Isn't there
Speaker 7:  a legitimate source of information about the stock. I take your point. And
Speaker 7:  you lie about like, being a little cautious about wanting to say that like
Speaker 7:  he's built his army on Twitter, but like I kind of think he has. And like
Speaker 7:  he is maybe the most important financial influencer currently
Speaker 7:  going, like he can send cryptocurrency up and down just by tweeting about
Speaker 7:  it, you know? Yeah. There was the brief period where he, Tesla was accepting
Speaker 7:  Bitcoin and that made Bitcoin go up. And then Tesla like stopped accepting
Speaker 7:  Bitcoin and Bitcoin went down and like he used tweeted about dose and dose
Speaker 7:  has gone up. So I do think that there's something very real here and it's
Speaker 7:  because so many finance people are on Twitter. Like I don't, you
Speaker 7:  gotta, you gotta, you gotta want to be on finance Twitter. I'll be real with
Speaker 7:  you. Slotted penny stock guys that hate you. But like, there is a very real
Speaker 7:  community like tweets show up on the Bloomberg terminal. And so that's
Speaker 7:  another reason why Twitter is so powerful. Like all of these communities,
Speaker 7:  like it's just, it's like the most hardcore people in any
Speaker 7:  given community are all on Twitter together. And so Elon Musk like
Speaker 7:  Twitter is really a source of power for him. Because
Speaker 7:  again, he can, he can really move real world
Speaker 7:  stocks by, by tweeting about them. And like, if you remember the game
Speaker 7:  stop thing in January, 2020, there are a bunch of people who
Speaker 7:  made a lot of money, but realizing that an Elon Musk tweet was the top and
Speaker 7:  immediately selling as soon as they saw it, you
Speaker 7:  know,
Speaker 1:  I'm not saying it's, I'm not saying it's zero. I'm saying it's not a hundred.
Speaker 1:  And we don't, there's no way of knowing, right? Like what is
Speaker 1:  the conversion rate between an Ilan tweet and people mind, like,
Speaker 1:  I don't know, that would be an amazing PhD thesis. Someone should do it.
Speaker 1:  And then we'll write about it. Like, I would love to know that information
Speaker 7:  If you're an economist,
Speaker 1:  By the way, by throwing the game software, this reminds me this, the next
Speaker 1:  hour is just gonna be talking about tweets that went viral and how bad it
Speaker 1:  was. Like I did like the most in the light
Speaker 1:  tweet during the whole GameStop fiasco and Robin hood was
Speaker 1:  stopping sales. And I was like, here's a screenshot of the
Speaker 1:  terms of service. Like this is what happens when everyone just hits agree
Speaker 1:  without reading it. And then like the hordes descended on me that I was
Speaker 1:  not being sympathetic to the, to the retail investor. And I was like, no,
Speaker 1:  I'm just in my bag. Like, this is what I talked about. Like every day is
Speaker 1:  terms of service agreements. Like I had nothing to
Speaker 1:  say, anyhow, my broader
Speaker 1:  point is like, Elon loves the service. When Addy comes on, we're going to
Speaker 1:  talk about whether it's a town square or any of that
Speaker 1:  noise. But the core of the problem, like we keep kind of
Speaker 1:  dancing around. It was just say it out loud. Twitter needs to grow in order
Speaker 1:  to grow, it needs to be much more consumer friendly. It needs
Speaker 1:  to be a much friendlier environment to just sign up for it. You want to
Speaker 1:  get a hundred million users, which is what we're all supposed to do in his
Speaker 1:  tenure. As CEO, you cannot, you cannot
Speaker 1:  have this experience with Twitter for initiate a hundred million new people
Speaker 1:  who want to use your service every day. That's not how tic Tucker that's
Speaker 1:  how YouTube grow. That's how snap is growing. Those are friendly,
Speaker 1:  meaningfully safer environments than Twitter. But then the thing that
Speaker 1:  makes Twitter valuable is just like the state of nature
Speaker 1:  for nerds, right? We're like life is bloody and short
Speaker 1:  on Twitter, but if you're a nerd, it's where you want to be. Right. And like,
Speaker 1:  I don't like fucking, can you
Speaker 1:  sell nature red in tooth and claw to a hundred million more people? Like,
Speaker 1:  I don't know the answer to that question.
Speaker 5:  I don't think we can because people keep comparing Twitter
Speaker 5:  to Facebook or to snap or whatever.
Speaker 5:  But really its main comparison is tumbler.
Speaker 5:  Like it's a place, it's a place it's like developing fans and
Speaker 5:  fandoms. And whether that's an Elan fandom or a TV show
Speaker 5:  fandom or movies, or you know, tech, a lot of us are in
Speaker 5:  that fandom. It, it it's building like a fandom. It's building like a community
Speaker 5:  of like weirdos who want to talk about this stuff. Facebook is
Speaker 5:  not super great at that. Snap is not super great at
Speaker 5:  that. Tumblr was I guess, okay. At it,
Speaker 5:  Twitter is really good at it. And that's like, but that's also like a small
Speaker 5:  market. Those weird obsessives. I say that as one, those weird
Speaker 5:  obsessives, like that's a small group of people. I don't think Twitter,
Speaker 5:  like, unless it fundamentally changes its approach and how it
Speaker 5:  operates. It's never going to move out of that. And I don't think it
Speaker 5:  necessarily
Speaker 5:  should.
Speaker 1:  I'm curious your view here. Right? You've got a company that had an activist
Speaker 1:  investor. They kicked out the founder CEO. They brought in the new CEO. He
Speaker 1:  said, we're going to grow it. There's one way to grow it, which is to make
Speaker 1:  it friendlier and to explore, expose more of the good things to more
Speaker 1:  people and get them to sign up and engage. Then you've got Ilan who wants
Speaker 1:  to open-source the algorithm, which implies the algorithm is important. And
Speaker 1:  we have all been talking to the algorithm is like not what Twitter is, power
Speaker 1:  users care about and it is bad. So you can open source it all
Speaker 1:  day, right? Like the ranking algorithm on Twitter shows you tweets from 17
Speaker 1:  hours ago or whatever, like the product isn't good. But somewhere in
Speaker 1:  there is, I mean, that's the story of Twitter whip sawing
Speaker 1:  between not having a chronological or doing the home
Speaker 1:  feed by default and making you hit 15 buttons
Speaker 1:  to click back to chronological recently and then walking that back. Cause
Speaker 1:  all our power users like that dynamic between the people who make Twitter,
Speaker 1:  what it is and the people it needs to attract the
Speaker 1:  service are radically different, have radically different needs. That's been
Speaker 1:  the motivating dynamic of Twitter, I think maybe the whole time. And I don't
Speaker 1:  see it. I don't actually know where the company is on that perspective
Speaker 1:  now. And I don't know if Ellen's going to knock it off that path, whatever
Speaker 1:  it is
Speaker 6:  Funny. You asked me that I did an interview with Twitter, new product leadership
Speaker 6:  team about three weeks ago, talking about this. And before
Speaker 6:  Ilan came in, they were addressing, hoping to address a law
Speaker 6:  under a full-time CEO for the first time in years. And we should know
Speaker 6:  like the reason Twitter has been so stagnant as a product is because Jack
Speaker 6:  let it run by committee. Cause he was part-time and only weighed in on things
Speaker 6:  he cared about. And so it was just this like imagine humping like
Speaker 6:  Twitter being run by like 12 executives who need to like figure out
Speaker 6:  their little fiefdoms. It didn't get anywhere right now.
Speaker 6:  They, they are trying to reignite it and also
Speaker 6:  turn it back a little bit to the early days, which I think is the answer
Speaker 6:  here. If we were like up until 2015, Twitter was there were, there
Speaker 6:  was a VC fund that was literally just investing in Twitter
Speaker 6:  clients. Like there was a whole economy. People
Speaker 6:  thought that Twitter was going to be this platform. And the
Speaker 6:  best features of Twitter were invented by developers who were building on
Speaker 6:  top of Twitter. And then we remember when they pulled the API out from everyone,
Speaker 6:  when they realized we've got to bring everyone into our client because we
Speaker 6:  need to sell advertising, we're going to start gating our new features to
Speaker 6:  our client. And they slowly choked the life out of the tweet, decks, the
Speaker 6:  Tweenies et cetera. I was just talking to their head of the guy, the
Speaker 6:  lead guy. That's trying to bring the API back to those early days,
Speaker 6:  like a few weeks ago. So they were wanting to, and then in the background
Speaker 6:  they eventually want to just put it on like a decentralized protocol where
Speaker 6:  Twitter is one of the platforms that then has
Speaker 6:  clients on top of it. Right? So they want to like really abstract this
Speaker 6:  and turn it into like a, a protocol for others to build on similar
Speaker 6:  to email, similar to RSS. And that's a
Speaker 6:  unique point of view in the world. Facebook snap, all these
Speaker 6:  other social media companies, they're becoming like their own silos, their
Speaker 6:  own super apps, trying to pull all the interactions into their
Speaker 6:  client. So that's the opportunity. I think Twitter has to do something unique
Speaker 6:  in the world and also kind of it aligns with the public nature of
Speaker 6:  Twitter. And also they're just finally starting to look into
Speaker 6:  subscriptions, which has been like, everyone's been saying, and Elon was
Speaker 6:  saying this, he would want the company to do subscriptions and to charge
Speaker 6:  its highest users. I guess maybe not him. Maybe he gets a special
Speaker 6:  discount there, but you know, charge these accounts
Speaker 6:  that use these as their main marketing, you know, Tesla doesn't spend
Speaker 6:  anything on marketing because Elan has a Twitter account with 80 million
Speaker 6:  users, Twitter to Elan is worth billions of dollars a
Speaker 6:  year and they could be charging for that kind of stuff.
Speaker 6:  And you know, like I pay for Twitter blue because I want to change my app
Speaker 6:  icon. And I'm like, it doesn't really do anything. They put nuzzle in
Speaker 6:  it like, cool. Like they're going to bring, edit tweet to it. Cool. But like
Speaker 6:  they just haven't really, they're starting to show signs of willingness to
Speaker 6:  experiment again, but they haven't really leaned into it fully, but they
Speaker 6:  were in the process before Elan came in. So it's like, they didn't get the
Speaker 6:  chance to really try. So it's like, it's just kind of sad in
Speaker 6:  that way that now everyone's like been derailed by this because they were
Speaker 6:  really trying to turn the ship around and they had this gun to their head,
Speaker 6:  which was this growth target that their activist investor gave them.
Speaker 1:  I feel bad for the new CEO. Right. Like, yeah. Can you imagine getting that
Speaker 1:  job and being all excited and then he had a baby he's
Speaker 6:  Supposed to be on parental leave.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. And he made this like, I think extremely cool public
Speaker 1:  declaration that even after taking the new job as a CEO, he was going on
Speaker 1:  leave to like set an example. That leaves should be like, I love that. I
Speaker 1:  love this dude. Probably come on decoder. He's not going to do it. I don't,
Speaker 1:  I don't think I'm getting any Twitter executives for a while, but Elan you
Speaker 1:  are invited. Come on, decoder. Let's let's talk. But I
Speaker 1:  just, I feel bad for that guy in particular. Like, I don't know if his vision
Speaker 1:  was right out. If it was going to work, it seems very clear. He was never,
Speaker 1:  he's never going to get the shot to do whatever he wanted for even her appearance.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I agree. And now what is the best outcome of
Speaker 6:  this? I mean, it's that Elan potentially
Speaker 6:  backs out. I mean, I don't want to, like, he backs out the stock
Speaker 6:  tanks. Maybe they get some other passive investor in there and morale is
Speaker 6:  destroyed and people's options are underwater or Elon
Speaker 6:  does take it private and then people quit and mass, like, those are
Speaker 6:  kind of the two options right now, which is like not a good sign
Speaker 5:  Stock tank if he backs out, like, cause it hasn't
Speaker 5:  changed. It didn't change when he, he announced he was going to buy
Speaker 5:  it.
Speaker 6:  Well, there's still his premium in there from when he first disclosed his
Speaker 6:  steak, it would go, it would go 30 or below for
Speaker 1:  Sure.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. So Alex, I think that those are two possible
Speaker 7:  outcomes. I do not think that they are the only possible outcomes. And
Speaker 7:  again, the reason I don't think so is because now Twitter is in play and
Speaker 7:  it is an incredibly influential service for all that. It
Speaker 7:  is like all versus all fighting and like
Speaker 7:  very unpleasant. If you have more than about 2000
Speaker 7:  followers, because whoever controls, Twitter
Speaker 7:  controls a lot of what happens on cable news.
Speaker 7:  And like to some degree, you know,
Speaker 7:  buying Twitter, like there was this comparison that I saw on, on
Speaker 7:  Twitter, but about, you know, Bezos
Speaker 7:  buying the Washington post and Musk buying Twitter. And
Speaker 7:  like they are actually pretty comparable. Like the Washington post, I think
Speaker 7:  Bezos has been a great steward of, but with Twitter, what you're
Speaker 7:  controlling is essentially the comments section for the entire internet.
Speaker 7:  And that's really powerful. So, you know, if
Speaker 7:  I'm at another tech company, I'm like calling my
Speaker 7:  lawyers to see what I can buy without triggering antitrust.
Speaker 1:  This was the mark Cuban tweet.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Because like that, like that actually is a
Speaker 7:  very, very powerful tool for marketing, for culture making for all of those
Speaker 7:  things. And I think that there are probably people out there who are interested
Speaker 7:  in the, in it. And like at this point, you know, if you're the board, maybe
Speaker 7:  you're looking for a white Knight. So like we might see another
Speaker 7:  player emerge.
Speaker 6:  Oh no, you're totally right.
Speaker 1:  I would not discount the power if you go for some of this, like if you're
Speaker 1:  one of those players, you get to put one over on Ilan.
Speaker 1:  Like there's more interest in that than I think you would
Speaker 1:  imagine.
Speaker 6:  No, I guarantee you if, if the year was 2015 and antitrust
Speaker 6:  scrutiny had not reached what it was, mark Zuckerberg has a blank check right
Speaker 6:  now. Like absolutely like what he did for WhatsApp. He put this
Speaker 6:  like, like Zuck multiple on it. That made no
Speaker 6:  sense. Like he did for Instagram. Like he's done for all the deals he cares
Speaker 6:  about. He'd buy Twitter for a hundred billion dollar
Speaker 1:  If he could get it. Right. But he's also just a rich guy. Like why isn't
Speaker 1:  he just staking someone else to do it? There's a lot of that out
Speaker 1:  there. Right? Like you actually didn't who doesn't. We never got to this,
Speaker 1:  but you know who doesn't have all the cash to this is Elon Musk.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. It does not know. He he's, he's not liquid. And he's already got a
Speaker 7:  bunch of loans against his shares.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Tesla shares. Maybe he'll just like, I don't know. So advertising the
Speaker 1:  side of space, X rockets, like raise funds. We've gone way over on the
Speaker 1:  segment list. Thank you so much. I imagine you're going to be back to talk
Speaker 1:  about this a few times over the next few.
Speaker 7:  Listen, I, you know, I got relaxed, right? Like after 2018,
Speaker 7:  like things calm down and I was like, okay, okay. Like I don't have to, like,
Speaker 7:  I don't have to constantly pay attention to Ilan. I can take the alerts off
Speaker 7:  his tweets and now I regret it because the Ilan cycle has
Speaker 7:  started again. So I'm sure we're going to be talking about this
Speaker 7:  again,
Speaker 1:  Liz, every now and again, I would get text messages from, it was like in
Speaker 1:  the  of early on cycles, usually like he's e-learning
Speaker 1:  again. And like the Elon Musk war room would spin up in slack.
Speaker 1:  Like here we are. That's great. All right. We
Speaker 1:  gotta take a break. Addie Robertson is going to come and join us to talk
Speaker 1:  about content moderation because that's another whole side of this. Thank
Speaker 1:  you, Liz. We'll be right
Speaker 1:  back.
Speaker 10:  You listened to this show weekend and week out because, well, we'd like
Speaker 10:  to think we offer sharp unfiltered insights into the biggest stories in
Speaker 10:  tech, business and politics. We also understand that your time is
Speaker 10:  valuable and we want you to apply the lessons that you hear on this
Speaker 10:  podcast.
Speaker 1:  We're back. Eddie Robertson is here. Hey Eddie. Hey, so
Speaker 1:  Alex's house. Heath is still here and Alex trans. So Addie we've been talking
Speaker 1:  about Ilan and Twitter. Of course, we just have Liz on. We must be
Speaker 1:  talking to the mechanics of the deal. What would happen? Twitter is a company
Speaker 1:  I wanted you on you and I spent an awful lot of time in our live segment,
Speaker 1:  content moderation and free speech and all the stuff Elan seems
Speaker 1:  very motivated to somehow change how Twitter
Speaker 1:  moderates and yesterday, I don't know if this was by
Speaker 1:  coincidence or by design or just the pure,
Speaker 1:  chaotic energy of the universe. He was onstage at Ted. You might
Speaker 1:  remember Ted, Ted, Pete, once influential conference for big
Speaker 1:  thoughts. We all, we all signed up for a free stream of
Speaker 1:  Ted yesterday because Elan was going to be there. And we like
Speaker 1:  sat through what appeared to be like a ninth grade social studies course
Speaker 1:  on a manual con and John Stuart mill. Like I literally read John cert melanose
Speaker 1:  in ninth grade. And Ted was like, have you heard, have you heard of John
Speaker 1:  Stuart mill? Like, I don't know what's going on there. It was like, you should
Speaker 1:  read it. It's foundations of Western liberalism were contained in John
Speaker 1:  Stuart mill, but I don't know why the Ted audience needed to know that information.
Speaker 1:  Anyway. So Chris Anderson, who is the head of Ted sat
Speaker 1:  down for an interview with Elan, I would describe that interview is
Speaker 1:  embarrassingly stupid, just on both ends. Like it was just real
Speaker 1:  bad, but we did learn some bits and bobs about
Speaker 1:  what Elon thinks and given just our history and covering it. I think
Speaker 1:  there's some challenges that so Eddie, you want to walk through what we think
Speaker 1:  we learned about Elan's approach to content moderation on Twitter?
Speaker 12:  Yeah. So there is very
Speaker 12:  long string of dumb things that were said that I am sure that maybe we'll
Speaker 12:  get into in more detail, but basically Elon Musks
Speaker 12:  says, okay, we understand that we want this to be a platform for global
Speaker 12:  free speech, but we know that you're going to have to follow laws. And we
Speaker 12:  think basically Twitter should just follow the laws of countries,
Speaker 12:  which implies sort of that ears. They're supposed to be just like
Speaker 12:  a first amendment Twitter. But at the same time, he also is really
Speaker 12:  mad about bots and spam. So he wants to get rid of bots because
Speaker 12:  bots are not part of free speech, mostly because he's mad about
Speaker 12:  cryptocurrency Schilling. I, it seems like. And
Speaker 12:  then at the same time, he's very worried about the idea that there's an
Speaker 12:  opaque algorithm that is demoting or promoting tweets in
Speaker 12:  ways that are not visible, which is one of those things that
Speaker 12:  it was a big meme and sort of conservative circles several years ago that
Speaker 12:  the idea that there was shadow banning quote unquote, that was making it
Speaker 12:  harder to search for things. But I'm not entirely certain what
Speaker 12:  he's referring to in this particular case, because Twitter tends
Speaker 12:  to be kind of upfront about telling people when they're banned and about
Speaker 12:  telling people like they to Russian
Speaker 12:  news outlet, like state news outlet, information and tweets, but they were
Speaker 12:  just like, yes, we're going to do this. We're telling you about this thing
Speaker 12:  proactively. So I'm, it feels like he's responding to a bunch of
Speaker 12:  things that are a little bit weird and
Speaker 12:  confusing and not actually the speech challenges
Speaker 12:  that Twitter faces.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Let's start with opensource algorithm. Cause we were just talking about
Speaker 1:  it in the previous section a little bit, all these platforms have done
Speaker 1:  things to try to be more transparent. The thing that occurs to me in
Speaker 1:  just listening to people blather on about opensource source
Speaker 1:  algorithms and Ilan was like, we'll just put it on GitHub and people can
Speaker 1:  leave comments that has no connection
Speaker 1:  to being transparent about what happens to an individual tweet,
Speaker 1:  right? Like if you are, if you think you can derive what happened to your
Speaker 1:  tweet from the code being on get hub, you are the
Speaker 1:  single best computer scientists in the history of the world, right? Like
Speaker 1:  there's no way, like, I don't know how you would do that. Well, you want
Speaker 1:  as a button on every tweet that says this was down ranked or
Speaker 1:  up ranked or your, I dunno, your army of
Speaker 1:  Tesla, people was busy watching a baseball game today. So they didn't like,
Speaker 1:  you want some of that information or like Jack was mad at you when he turned
Speaker 1:  down the big knob in his office and said, Elan's reach, right. Like that's
Speaker 1:  the thing you're actually, after the code might tell you that those buttons
Speaker 1:  and knobs exist, but they will not actually tell you how they're used. So
Speaker 1:  just like from the jump, there's this massive discrepancy in the
Speaker 1:  outcome you want and the solution proposed.
Speaker 12:  Yes. It also does not mention really how, I guess you leave a comment on
Speaker 12:  GitHub and then there's just an army of moderators that will check and be
Speaker 12:  like, okay. So all the tweets that we moderated based on this turns
Speaker 12:  out, we should have done that differently. Like it doesn't, the appeals
Speaker 12:  process is also a huge part of how Twitter works and why it's
Speaker 12:  frustrating when it's frustrating. And he, we didn't really learn much about
Speaker 12:  that.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. So that's open source algorithm, which I feel like we can just
Speaker 1:  dispense with. Although I will say that when pressed in this interview on
Speaker 1:  any specific Elan returned to the idea of open
Speaker 1:  source algorithm is a, was like his happy place. Like
Speaker 1:  here's this very, I mean, just embarrassingly stupid
Speaker 1:  exchange. This is my I'm just going to, I'm going to end up repeating this
Speaker 1:  until I die. So Chris Anderson is like, here's the
Speaker 1:  challenge. I'm just quoting Chris Anderson. It's a nuanced difference between
Speaker 1:  different things. There's incitement to violence. That's a no, if it's
Speaker 1:  illegal, which I would just say implies that there are some,
Speaker 1:  some form of legal incitement to violence, which if you can
Speaker 1:  discover, like let me know. Cause is that just like, let's do
Speaker 1:  swords. And like, it's like, I
Speaker 1:  dunno,
Speaker 1:  Whatever. So there's incitements to violence. That's a no, if it's
Speaker 1:  illegal, there's hate speech. Which some forms of hate
Speaker 1:  speech are fine. I hate spinach,
Speaker 13:  Which
Speaker 1:  Like, I just like echoing through my head. Like you didn't
Speaker 1:  prepare, you don't know what you're talking about. All right. So then here's
Speaker 1:  the example. Ilan says, spinach is delicious. If it's sauteed in cream sauce,
Speaker 1:  this is all hack actually happened. Then Chris Anderson says, let's say I
Speaker 1:  tweet, I hate politician X. The next tweet is I wish politician X wasn't
Speaker 1:  alive. And then he qualifies this. Some of them said, this is about Putin
Speaker 1:  right now. So that's legitimate speech there. Just like
Speaker 1:  UN like if you're like, you know what if it's about that guy or some of us
Speaker 1:  have said it that's obviously, like I said it. So that's obviously cool.
Speaker 1:  Who knows? And then another tweet is I wish politician X wasn't a
Speaker 1:  lad alive with a picture of their head over with a gun Gunsight over at plus
Speaker 1:  her address. At some point, someone has to make a decision as to which of
Speaker 1:  those is not okay. Ken, an algorithm do that. The answer to that question
Speaker 1:  is fucking of course not.
Speaker 12:  I also like to point out none of that is hate
Speaker 12:  speech. Well, not even
Speaker 12:  forget whether it's legal or not. None of that actually is what people who
Speaker 12:  hate, who are like upset about hate speech say is
Speaker 12:  hate.
Speaker 1:  I hate spinach. Some sun hate speeches. Okay.
Speaker 1:  I,
Speaker 12:  I hate, spinaches actually closer to hates. I don't want
Speaker 12:  this politician
Speaker 12:  dead.
Speaker 1:  So I was just wondering if you asked
Speaker 1:  any four people, you know, like the four of us or like four of your
Speaker 1:  friends to make determinations on how to rank those things as
Speaker 1:  acceptable Arctic social speech, we would all disagree. That is the nature
Speaker 1:  of these debates. So can an algorithm do that? I was like, I dunno,
Speaker 1:  man, probably not
Speaker 13:  Just based
Speaker 1:  On what I know about human nature. So he says, surely you need some human
Speaker 1:  judgment. That point fine. He is minorly rescued himself.
Speaker 1:  Elan's response to this is just in my view. Twitter
Speaker 1:  should match the laws of the country. That's it? That's his
Speaker 1:  answer. And he's like, there's an obligation to that. But going beyond
Speaker 1:  that and having it be unclear, who's making what changes to where having
Speaker 1:  tweets, mysteriously promoted, demoted having a black box algorithm, promotes
Speaker 1:  some things, not other things. I think this can be quite dangerous. None
Speaker 1:  of that is an answer to I've given you three tweets, which one is unacceptable,
Speaker 1:  by the way, what's the deal with spinach and like the whole conversation
Speaker 1:  is here's something that appears to be a hard question. Anyone
Speaker 1:  saying open the algorithm up in some way. And I just don't see the
Speaker 1:  connection between the two Addie. I'm wondering if you do.
Speaker 12:  I don't either. It feels, this is a thing that it feels like a bunch of
Speaker 12:  people doing policy. I hear it mostly with anti-trust and speech where it's
Speaker 12:  like, oh, well, okay. So what's the problem with moderation it's that these
Speaker 12:  companies are too big, which is like, okay, fair. These are problems, but
Speaker 12:  there's you can't just like fix one thing in tech
Speaker 12:  and platforms and everything else gets fixed with it. This all
Speaker 12:  just seems there's so many nonsequitors in that interview.
Speaker 12:  It really, it was extremely frustrating.
Speaker 1:  Give me my favorite one. I'm sorry. This whole thing was so
Speaker 1:  stupid. So Ilan says obviously Twitter or any form is bound by the laws of
Speaker 1:  the country that operates in. So obviously there are some limitations in
Speaker 1:  three speech in the United States. He says, obviously there's some limitations
Speaker 1:  in Twitter. I have to abide by those rules. And then Chris Anderson follows
Speaker 1:  up. So you can incite people to violence, like direct incitement of violence.
Speaker 1:  You can't do the equivalent of crying fire in a movie theater, for example,
Speaker 1:  and Ilan responds with it. That is a crime. It should be a
Speaker 1:  crime. Now I will tell you that you can walk into
Speaker 1:  any theater in America and yell fire. And it is not a
Speaker 1:  crime definitely should not be a crime.
Speaker 1:  There's a long history of that. People who say that kind of immediately
Speaker 1:  out themselves as having no idea what's going on at a, you want to kind of
Speaker 1:  explain, I could try, but I'll just start crying.
Speaker 12:  I'm the, they're actually very, very good explanations
Speaker 12:  online. The Atlantic's that are really fantastic. One, but the long story
Speaker 12:  short is there has never been a case about whether there was a crowded theater
Speaker 12:  in some guy cried fire. It was a metaphor that was used in a
Speaker 12:  case, a Supreme court case. That was what was,
Speaker 12:  what was it about? It was about draft speech, right?
Speaker 1:  Yes. It was world war, one husband or two people in our,
Speaker 1:  her as a husband or wife. But two people were distributing leaflets in the
Speaker 1:  run up to world war. One saying, you should disobey the draft because war
Speaker 1:  is bad. They were socialists. And the government arrested them. And the
Speaker 1:  Supreme court said, that's cool that you can limit their speech in that way,
Speaker 1:  because they are creating a clear and present dangerous United States of
Speaker 1:  America,
Speaker 12:  Which was like shouting fire in a crowded theater
Speaker 1:  With the metaphor is like, certainly there are some limits and that was the
Speaker 1:  metaphor.
Speaker 12:  And then this was later overturned if I remember correctly. And so not only
Speaker 12:  was it not a thing that happened, it was a metaphor for a thing that
Speaker 12:  wasn't even that is at this point no longer even current.
Speaker 1:  Yes. So that shank was overturned in part by what's it
Speaker 1:  Brandenburg? Yeah. It's Brandenburg, Ohio. I don't remember that
Speaker 1:  case. It's about Brandenburg was a guy he talked to Ohio was mad at him.
Speaker 1:  I don't know. But they out clear and present danger, which is where that
Speaker 1:  phrase comes from. They threw out the whole case and they replaced it and
Speaker 1:  said, the government cannot punish inflammatory speech unless it directly
Speaker 1:  incites or produces imminent lawless action.
Speaker 1:  And that's it like, that's the thing, the government. So if you are
Speaker 1:  like, I want everyone to write, let's do
Speaker 1:  swords right now against the guy
Speaker 1:  is like, you're directing people towards imminent lawless action. The government
Speaker 1:  can stop that speech,
Speaker 5:  Right?
Speaker 1:  This has that's the limit of the first amendment. So all this other stuff
Speaker 1:  is not like Twitter would just have to let it go. If they're going to be
Speaker 1:  restricted by the first amendment
Speaker 6:  Also clear and present danger is a great Harrison Ford film,
Speaker 5:  Wonderful movie,
Speaker 6:  But also the U S of this is fascinating
Speaker 6:  because like most actual American based social media companies, the
Speaker 6:  vast majority of Twitter's users are not in the United States.
Speaker 6:  And the promise of Twitter is that someone in one country can
Speaker 6:  talk and tweet to someone in another. So either you're going to
Speaker 6:  geo lock Twitter and it's ad tech stack, and it's
Speaker 6:  everything to every country you operate in, or
Speaker 6:  you have to pick some balance of the U S
Speaker 6:  constitution, what the EU wants, what India wants, which is
Speaker 6:  increasingly less democratic. And China's just like,
Speaker 6:  no, you can't be here. Right? So like, how do you navigate all that? And
Speaker 6:  if you're going to abide by the laws of the country, you operate
Speaker 6:  in this, every platform is tied up in this right now because you
Speaker 6:  can't really do it. You can't like, like Facebook
Speaker 6:  has this problem all the time. And I just don't see
Speaker 6:  Ian really wrestling with that in the interview. It wasn't brought up at
Speaker 6:  all.
Speaker 12:  So the funny thing is, Twitter has done that in the Twitter, had to deal
Speaker 12:  with this with hate speech in Germany and France around 2012. And its solution
Speaker 12:  was withholding tweets, which is that you can be a Nazi
Speaker 12:  on Twitter and post Nazi stuff. But in Germany, you won't get to see the
Speaker 12:  Nazi tweets. They will be basically as geo locked.
Speaker 12:  And Elon seems to have given this much less thought than everyone at
Speaker 12:  Twitter,
Speaker 1:  Shocker.
Speaker 5:  I'm just kind of shocked that he announced, like when he said he
Speaker 5:  wanted to buy this company, it was to protect free speech. And then he
Speaker 5:  immediately goes to this Ted talk and says, oh yeah, yeah, yeah. I'll just
Speaker 5:  listen to the, the, the laws of the whatever country and like, okay.
Speaker 5:  But those are not the same thing.
Speaker 1:  Okay. So I sort of understand that argument. I will say, I have a sympathy
Speaker 1:  towards that argument in this specific way, these
Speaker 1:  companies are all pretty big. This is I think, where the fuzziness or the
Speaker 1:  antitrust comes along. So if you're like, there's only four companies
Speaker 1:  that really have it locked in social media, their moderation. I don't know
Speaker 1:  that I agree with all this, but this is my sympathy. Facebook's moderation
Speaker 1:  decisions are opaque to me. There's no process. It doesn't
Speaker 1:  feel fair. Twitter's moderate, whatever it is, it would be
Speaker 1:  better if our elected representatives were voting on speech
Speaker 1:  regulations, right? Like that's, that's where you're going. You're saying,
Speaker 1:  I believe in free speech, I'd rather have the government issue, speech
Speaker 1:  regulations than these companies that I hate and are really big. And I can't
Speaker 1:  switch away from, I would put, I understand that
Speaker 1:  argument. It is also
Speaker 1:  crazy to be like, what I would like is for the United States
Speaker 1:  to throw away the first amendment and start issuing government
Speaker 1:  speech regulations.
Speaker 12:  It's also the very, the U S ness of it comes up again, because there are
Speaker 12:  just, there are a bunch of countries where if you value any kind of free
Speaker 12:  expression, they are not following those rules. Like you just, you cannot
Speaker 12:  possibly say I value free expression. And I believe that we need to operate
Speaker 12:  according to these two, like China's regulations,
Speaker 1:  Right? So this is, I've been trying to describe the mental
Speaker 1:  flip that you need to make if you're based in the United States. So
Speaker 1:  in the United States, your baseline perspective is that you can
Speaker 1:  say anything you want in the first amendment,
Speaker 1:  prohibits the government from doing all that X, Y, and Z, right?
Speaker 1:  So you're like in a permissive structure and all like
Speaker 1:  let's do, swords is illegal and that's child pornography is
Speaker 1:  illegal. Even make a tortured argument that the expansion
Speaker 1:  of copyright law makes some kind of expression illegal. And the government
Speaker 1:  has created a private whatever. That's just me. I'm going to leave that alone.
Speaker 1:  I'm defamation law, right? It's like, there's an explosion in defamation
Speaker 1:  law cases. We're getting more letters than ever for our coverage. Okay. But
Speaker 1:  that's still a permissive structure. There's a small list of things that
Speaker 1:  might reasonably chill your speech. Otherwise, it's a free for all. You go
Speaker 1:  to a company like outset, or you go to a country like outside, like
Speaker 1:  India. It is actually the absolute
Speaker 1:  flip where it's a restricted culture. And there's a smallest of things you
Speaker 1:  are able to say. And that those countries have demanded
Speaker 1:  that social media companies like Twitter and Facebook have offices. There
Speaker 1:  have employees there. The Indian government has sent the police to
Speaker 1:  Twitter's offices because Twitter was labeling tweets
Speaker 1:  from the BJP party as manipulated information. They're
Speaker 1:  calling out lies from the government and the police showed up at their office.
Speaker 1:  That is a restrictive culture. So if you're based in the U S and you're like,
Speaker 1:  it should be the laws of the country. Your entire framework is the
Speaker 1:  permissive framework of speech United States, and almost everywhere else.
Speaker 1:  It is a restrictive culture where there's mostly, mostly, you cannot
Speaker 1:  do things. And I don't know that you want us thought about it. Ilan is
Speaker 1:  not from this country. He grew up in another country with a different attitude
Speaker 1:  towards speech, South Africa. He obviously has huge factories in
Speaker 1:  China, in Germany. It's just unclear why he hasn't thought
Speaker 1:  any of that through.
Speaker 5:  He did think it through. And I think he was saying one thing in his
Speaker 5:  sec, filing to like drum up support
Speaker 5:  from, from his, his base fandom. And then another thing
Speaker 5:  in this Ted talk, like I think he various cognizant of the fact
Speaker 5:  that he can't have it both ways, but he can say I'm a
Speaker 5:  champion of free speech. Cause what's the, like the sec can just be like,
Speaker 5:  no, you're not like they're not going to do that. Like, like we're all
Speaker 5:  sitting there. Like nobody, you D like, that's, doesn't make sense. And he's
Speaker 5:  like, oh yeah, yeah, I know. But I'm a champion of free speech. Like, that's
Speaker 5:  just always is kind of like modus operandi, right? Like he's always kind
Speaker 5:  of like,
Speaker 12:  Was always, also did this, like Dick Costolo was in
Speaker 12:  2012 or 2011 was late. Twitter's were the free speech wing of the free speech
Speaker 12:  party. And at the same time, yes. We also know that we have to follow the
Speaker 12:  laws of these countries and operate because we're a company. So it's totally
Speaker 12:  not a unique thing. But the interview was just, and I'm to be clear,
Speaker 12:  blaming Chris Anderson for this, it was an atrocious interview.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I mean, it was extra, just embarrassing. So let's end here, which I
Speaker 1:  think is the hardest problem in the first amendment debate. And this was
Speaker 1:  handled very poorly. So we were talking about hate speech earlier. I will
Speaker 1:  just tell everyone hate speech is not illegal in the United States of
Speaker 1:  America. Various states have tried to pass these laws. The Supreme court
Speaker 1:  has mostly struck them down. You can just do some hate speech. People think
Speaker 1:  it's illegal because it feels right for it to be illegal because the social
Speaker 1:  platforms themselves have decided they don't want hate speech on their
Speaker 1:  platforms. You know, it's really hard to do. If you hate speech on your platform,
Speaker 1:  sell advertising. So they have like a business imperative, they have a
Speaker 1:  consumer imperative. So the social platforms are decided, this is unacceptable.
Speaker 1:  You know, norms in society have decided that being outright
Speaker 1:  racist is unacceptable, but there's no log in hate speech. United States.
Speaker 1:  There's just a bunch of social conditioning, then Ilan going on and on
Speaker 1:  about spam and spam bots, commercial speeches,
Speaker 1:  protected speech. So if you think about your physical mailbox, where the
Speaker 1:  United States postal service delivers your mail, the government cannot
Speaker 1:  proactively filter out junk mail.
Speaker 5:  It should,
Speaker 1:  You might want it to, there are laws in the books that enable you to opt
Speaker 1:  out of it or to be on a, do not mail list or do not call list. But you,
Speaker 1:  the individual citizen have to like proactively say
Speaker 1:  it. The government cannot make that decision for you because it's a, it's
Speaker 1:  a prior strand speech, right? This is crazy. This also applies to
Speaker 1:  email. There's a law called the canned spam act. You can see if it was
Speaker 1:  effective, but the government basically is like commercial emailers have
Speaker 1:  to provide these tags. They have to give you an opt out. They have to give
Speaker 1:  you a button that says unsubscribe me, but they can't block it. And in
Speaker 1:  fact, the thing that has walked it most effectively, email monopoly. This
Speaker 1:  is what Sarah, John will tell you that like Gmail is and email monopoly.
Speaker 1:  And that has been more effective at spam than any government
Speaker 1:  regulation. Take that for what you will, but that's because the first amendment
Speaker 1:  prohibits the government from doing it. So then Elon is like, the top priority
Speaker 1:  I have is limiting spammers and scam bots and bot armies on Twitter. They
Speaker 1:  make the product worse. I agree with him. But if you're limiting yourself
Speaker 1:  to I'm following the law of the country, you're kind of immediately in a
Speaker 1:  pretzel of logic, right? Addy.
Speaker 12:  Yes. And it's, again, just one of those things where it feels like there
Speaker 12:  is a specific thing that he just doesn't want the site to
Speaker 12:  do. And then he's trying to build this consistent framework around
Speaker 12:  it. And it's, that's very difficult to do when it seems like what he
Speaker 12:  has is just sort of a hobby horse that he doesn't want Twitter to do a thing
Speaker 12:  that feels like it's political censorship, but
Speaker 12:  hasn't, can't just like come out and say things that he's actually upset
Speaker 12:  that they're doing. And so it makes up this very broad, like it has to follow
Speaker 12:  the law kind of framework
Speaker 5:  Wouldn't getting rid of all the bots also affect him
Speaker 5:  because of his army of bots. Yeah. Like that seems bad for him.
Speaker 12:  I mean, bod is also a weird term. Like I assume that like, there were a
Speaker 12:  bunch of art bots on Twitter. There are a bunch of really fantastic things.
Speaker 12:  I think he's just mad at the ones that pretend to be him and sell crypto.
Speaker 1:  Right. So w like, how do you make that distinct distinction? Like, here's
Speaker 1:  like another problem no algorithm can solve. Like, how do you decide
Speaker 1:  between one of the bots that sneakerheads use to know when there's a
Speaker 1:  sneaker drop? That's like, obviously sending a lots and lots of tweets to
Speaker 1:  lots and lots of people at any given moment. And the crypto spam bots are
Speaker 1:  applied at Ilan everyday. Like maybe a person could do it, but like the
Speaker 1:  signals you actually get are very low. The verge automatically tweets every
Speaker 1:  story that's a bot, is that allowed, like these are very fine
Speaker 1:  distinctions and saying, I'm just going to get rid of spam bots, I think
Speaker 1:  is like one of the more challenging aspects of Twitter, because some of the
Speaker 1:  best parts of Twitter are automated or there aren't projects. There's a bot
Speaker 1:  that every time we change the tagline and image in our masthead, there's
Speaker 1:  actually two bots. Every time we change those things, it's just tweets what
Speaker 1:  they are. I love that bot someone just made it for us to be, well, two people
Speaker 1:  just made them for us. Are they illegal under Elon law? Like, I don't know.
Speaker 1:  The, you should know the answers to these questions before you propose these
Speaker 1:  kinds of things.
Speaker 12:  We're just, I wish just all talk about our favorite Twitter bots. Now I
Speaker 12:  have a bot that tweets random words on dark souls. You died
Speaker 12:  screens.
Speaker 1:  It's pretty good. My favorite bot is called schemer. It just, it just
Speaker 1:  comes up with color schemes and gives them insane names
Speaker 6:  Students. Next week, we need you to read chapter three of the free speech
Speaker 6:  century. Come back with your questions. I feel like
Speaker 6:  we've, I feel like if we say free speech again, and this podcast that
Speaker 6:  will combust.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. We shouldn't take a break. This interview
Speaker 1:  sucked and everyone should feel
Speaker 1:  bad.
Speaker 1:  I mean, it is like directly as I, as I'm saying it
Speaker 1:  like as a person who interviews people about
Speaker 1:  their ideas every week, like if your
Speaker 1:  approach is, I think Twitter's moderation is bad, such that it is a threat
Speaker 1:  to civilization, which is more or less what he wants that yesterday, right?
Speaker 1:  This is a civilizational catastrophe editor. You got to really interrogate
Speaker 1:  that. And you got to really be prepared to answer those questions. And if
Speaker 1:  you think that the first amendment is the correct set of rules,
Speaker 1:  like you're going to run into every other country in the world that thinks
Speaker 1:  differently that you are trying to sell Teslas in. And that's just like a
Speaker 1:  bad dynamic for you. All right, we're gonna take a break. We're gonna come
Speaker 1:  back. We're gonna talk about gadgets, Gadgets for your face. We'll be
Speaker 1:  right
Speaker 1:  back.
Speaker 15:  Hi, I'm Zach Beecham and I cover global politics and democracy for
Speaker 15:  Vox. I'm currently hosting a special four-part series in the Vox
Speaker 15:  conversations feed called the war in Ukraine explained each
Speaker 15:  episode. I sit down with an expert to unpack a different dimension of this
Speaker 15:  generation defining conflict. The series is designed to give you a top
Speaker 15:  to bottom understanding of the Ukraine war, starting from the very beginning
Speaker 15:  to what it could mean for the future, not only of Europe, but the entire
Speaker 15:  world. In part one, I spoke with political scientists and scholar of Russian
Speaker 15:  politics, Yoshiko Herrera about why Putin invaded Ukraine in the first
Speaker 15:  place. And part two, I spoke with Tufts university professor and sanctions
Speaker 15:  expert, Dan Drezner on the unprecedented economic warfare being waged
Speaker 15:  by Western countries on Russia, in retaliation for the attack. And this
Speaker 15:  week for part three of speaking with nuclear policy expert, Jeff Lewis about
Speaker 15:  the risks that this war escalates to a nuclear exchange and what
Speaker 15:  we can do to prevent them listen and subscribe to Fox conversations
Speaker 15:  today, to hear the whole
Speaker 15:  series.
Speaker 1:  Alright, we are back at a and Mr. Heath are still with us.
Speaker 1:  Let's talk about gadgets, Alex, in the midst of all this, you published
Speaker 1:  a huge scoop this week. You have the entire Metta AR
Speaker 1:  roadmap. What the company formerly known as Facebook wants to do for computers
Speaker 1:  on your face. It seems challenging. It does seem like bet the company
Speaker 1:  walk us through it.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. So everyone remembers that pretty wild video that
Speaker 6:  mark Zuckerberg shot last
Speaker 6:  fall. October-ish when he announced the rebrand to Metta,
Speaker 6:  here's a AR you know, chess game on a table, and you're
Speaker 6:  playing with a hologram, you know, the classic stuff that we've seen in these,
Speaker 6:  these demos on stage. Yeah. Mark fenced with a
Speaker 6:  hologram let's do
Speaker 1:  Shorts. See it all comes back to doing stories.
Speaker 6:  It's all connected. What is the, what
Speaker 6:  is free speech in the metaverse? Oh boy.
Speaker 6:  And the holy grail device. He's called around all this
Speaker 6:  as AR glasses, which we've talked about a lot on this show. I
Speaker 6:  imagine most of our listeners know the distinctions between VR and AR.
Speaker 6:  So I won't explain that right now, but yeah, I set out to answer the question.
Speaker 6:  How soon are these things actually coming? What are they going to look like?
Speaker 6:  And what is the long-term commitment to this as a product category, it turns
Speaker 6:  out it's a pretty, long-term big commitment. So they have three
Speaker 6:  generations of full AR glasses. They're called Nazare
Speaker 6:  it's sucker Berg's pet project. And he's got thousands of people working
Speaker 6:  on them, spending billions of dollars. And the first version is coming in
Speaker 6:  2024, it's going to be an early adopter developer gear
Speaker 6:  device. They're going to sell like low tens of thousands of them. The bill
Speaker 6:  of materials on these classes is in the thousands of dollars. So
Speaker 6:  they have to figure out how to subsidize that, which is going to be challenging.
Speaker 6:  The battery life is like four hours. So they're mostly going to be used
Speaker 6:  indoors, but a pretty impressive field of you. Some
Speaker 6:  pretty impressive specs, honestly, custom silicone custom wave
Speaker 6:  guides, the best of the best and you know, no
Speaker 6:  expense spared. And that's what we're getting from the company. Literally
Speaker 6:  investing the most with like a founder led just
Speaker 6:  insane fervor behind it. That's what's coming
Speaker 6:  with that. And then they have another version two years later, and another
Speaker 6:  version two years later, and there's another device coming in 2024,
Speaker 6:  another pair of glasses that has like a smaller heads up display.
Speaker 6:  That's more Google glass. Like that's more kind of notifications.
Speaker 6:  And the distinction that one's called hyper Nova, they all have these, like
Speaker 6:  the main air glasses are a Ryan, the smart glasses with the little
Speaker 6:  display or hyper Nova. And the distinction is
Speaker 6:  that hyper Nova will be, you know, still needing a phone
Speaker 6:  to work. So, but it's the idea is to lessen the dependence
Speaker 6:  on the phone and the main air glasses do not need a phone to
Speaker 6:  work. They'll have a little phone like device. It's not a phone
Speaker 6:  though that will offload wireless li some of the compute.
Speaker 6:  So it doesn't literally burn your face, which we've
Speaker 6:  also talked about on the ship that's what's coming and what Mehta has
Speaker 6:  up its sleeve that I think a lot of people will be surprised by when this
Speaker 6:  ships is this a neural interface. I guess we
Speaker 6:  could call it mind reading technology. They don't want to call it that because
Speaker 6:  it's not reading your mind, but
Speaker 12:  It's kind of
Speaker 6:  Reading. I know, I know, I know Addie will explain this cause she's actually
Speaker 6:  tried it, but you know, everyone, they bought this company called
Speaker 6:  control labs in 2019 for like a billion dollars. It was like
Speaker 6:  12 people pre product launch. One of those classic, like funny
Speaker 6:  Zuck, multiple acquisitions. And that is kind of the, the
Speaker 6:  key that unlocks all this from an input perspective, because how do you
Speaker 6:  control glasses on your face? They obviously don't have a touch
Speaker 6:  screen. You're not going to have a mouse with you. You're not going to have
Speaker 6:  a keyboard. You know, what, how do you do that? And so it's this
Speaker 6:  armband wristband that lets you kind of have a Phantom limb
Speaker 6:  to type and control them. So that's at a high level. What is coming on
Speaker 6:  the AR side for Metta
Speaker 5:  Is the idea here though, that like you can put on this wristband and
Speaker 5:  not lift your hands up and look like a dill weed while you're manipulating
Speaker 5:  things that nobody else can see.
Speaker 6:  How do you want us to explain?
Speaker 12:  Yes. So they're magic leap and
Speaker 12:  Hola lens to different extents, but kind of similar. You use optical tracking
Speaker 12:  there's cameras in front of you. It can kind of pick up your hands
Speaker 12:  and then you gesture and it's like minority report. And the minority
Speaker 12:  report interface is both. You look weird cause you're gesturing to stuff.
Speaker 12:  Nobody else can see. But also it's really tiring because you're lifting
Speaker 12:  your hands constantly. And you have to be in a situation where you know
Speaker 12:  that you like it's inside your field of view. You also just it's
Speaker 12:  tiring because you're moving your actual hands around a bunch and you have
Speaker 12:  to use these graphical interfaces that rely on you grabbing and
Speaker 12:  pulling if you want. But the way that this works
Speaker 12:  is that you put on this wrist band and it reads the
Speaker 12:  signals that are going down your arm down like
Speaker 12:  the neurons there that are telling your hands how to move
Speaker 12:  basically. So it can act like a
Speaker 12:  hand tracker that just doesn't need a camera because it can kind of detect,
Speaker 12:  okay, you want to move your index finger, but it can also
Speaker 12:  detect intention. Like the way that
Speaker 12:  they tell people to start learning how to do this is that you put the
Speaker 12:  armband on and you move your finger. Like you make a fist and
Speaker 12:  your virtual hand reflects this because you're telling your
Speaker 12:  arm, I want to make a fist. Then you put your hand on something hard and
Speaker 12:  flat where you can't move it, but you tell your arm to make a
Speaker 12:  fist. And it does the same thing because you
Speaker 12:  are sending the instructions to, through your neural
Speaker 12:  system, through your arm to say, I want to make a fist. And it doesn't
Speaker 12:  matter that your actual hand isn't doing it.
Speaker 5:  So this is like the same tech that you're seeing with like a
Speaker 5:  lot of arm prosthetics, right?
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 12:  It's really, it's a thing that does a lot of the same work as
Speaker 12:  brain interfaces like Neuralink. Okay. I shouldn't say neural link. Cause
Speaker 12:  neuro link is like, I don't even know what's going on with it completely,
Speaker 12:  but there are a bunch of brain interfaces. And the idea is that they're
Speaker 12:  supposed to mimic the way that your brain sends signals to your
Speaker 12:  limbs. These are really good. If you don't have a working
Speaker 12:  limb there at all, there is not really a super
Speaker 12:  great reason. Why, if you have a functional limb, you
Speaker 12:  should try to go straight to like Jack into your brain
Speaker 12:  to do a thing that you could just tell your arm to do. It's like,
Speaker 12:  I can't remember if I'm stealing this analogy from the
Speaker 12:  actual, from like control labs, but it's
Speaker 12:  like saying I want to write a command. And instead of using
Speaker 12:  JavaScript or something, you learn binary code and go and like write in
Speaker 12:  binary code
Speaker 1:  Once I kind of understand why you'd want to do that for an AR interface
Speaker 1:  though. Right? You're seeing something no one else can see. And you're just
Speaker 1:  like hit that button and the button gets hit. Like that would rule.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. So hyper Nova the heads up display glasses that are more minimal and
Speaker 6:  use a phone. That's the ideas like really fast texting, really
Speaker 6:  like responding to notifications without needing to talk without needing
Speaker 6:  to gesture. That's potentially going to be pretty cool. And Addy, like
Speaker 6:  everyone I've talked to, who's tried the prototype. That's kind of more recent
Speaker 6:  that Matta has. It's based on this as it's like one of the coolest tech demos
Speaker 6:  they've ever tried and that it could be like pay for everything. If it
Speaker 6:  works at scale, what do you think? Cause you, you tried it. How do you,
Speaker 6:  what do you agree? There are not,
Speaker 12:  I think literally the only thing I've ever tried tech wise
Speaker 12:  that felt more cool and magical is the Oculus
Speaker 12:  rift, which ironically is also a Facebook now.
Speaker 12:  I, everything I like, no, I think it's incredible because the, yeah, the
Speaker 12:  thing I'm getting at is that it feels like mind control
Speaker 12:  to an extent, like it's not putting a thing literally in your brain,
Speaker 12:  but it's letting you just feel like you're gesturing using your hand, but
Speaker 12:  your hand is not necessarily moving. And your hand isn't necessarily
Speaker 12:  using a thing where you have to have a one-to-one I'm pressing this
Speaker 12:  button. It's like to some extent it can kind of learn
Speaker 12:  from the way that you are thinking that it
Speaker 12:  can match up. When I make this brain pattern, I want this thing
Speaker 12:  to happen. And if you blend that with a bunch of really
Speaker 12:  advanced sort of predictive artificial intelligence systems, you can end
Speaker 12:  up getting these really interesting, smart, like control
Speaker 12:  systems that are super
Speaker 12:  different from anything that you've tried ever. In theory. Again, the thing
Speaker 12:  I tried is a very, it was a 2019 demo. It was very early, it was basically
Speaker 12:  playing pong, but it was super fun.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And like, so what's going to happen is med is going to Trojan horse
Speaker 6:  this into smartwatch that is coming first this year,
Speaker 6:  without this technology that I reported on last year, it'll have a detachable
Speaker 6:  display with two cameras, like a little detachable GoPro on your
Speaker 6:  wrist, which is
Speaker 5:  Dick Tracy. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  That's
Speaker 1:  A classic Metta idea. That's not going
Speaker 6:  To succeed. So the idea is like, get people use to a smartwatch from Metta,
Speaker 6:  by the way, like the name change very much like motivated by all this hardware
Speaker 6:  coming because they know that like the Facebook glasses, people in the U
Speaker 6:  S are not going to buy. Right? So like the metal watch. And then by
Speaker 6:  2024, when the glasses come out, they ship one with
Speaker 6:  control, abs tech and it syncs with the glasses and
Speaker 6:  apple. I don't like apples scared of this. I've heard because of,
Speaker 6:  they think it's going to have privacy concerns obviously, and people are
Speaker 6:  going to think it's weird and too intimate. And so apple is very scared
Speaker 6:  of this space. Snap. I just scooped bought a similar, it
Speaker 6:  wasn't doing EMG. It was doing a different version of this that you wear
Speaker 6:  on your head. But another BCI company called next mind
Speaker 6:  and they want to hook that up to their spectacles down the road. So everyone's
Speaker 6:  trying to like with maybe the exception of apple come up with this
Speaker 6:  brain BCI interface for these classes,
Speaker 5:  Apple scared of it because these other companies are relying on
Speaker 5:  like algorithms and stuff. Because I mean, this technology itself is not
Speaker 5:  new. We're seeing it a lot in the accessibility space. Like
Speaker 5:  it's used for people who are paraplegic and need to control computers and
Speaker 5:  stuff. It's used for people with residual limbs. Like it's
Speaker 5:  not new technology. And I don't think there's privacy concerns about people
Speaker 5:  being able to pick up a can of soda in real life.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Apple may come around to it. They've been hesitant, the apple headset
Speaker 6:  that's coming that I think they'll probably still announce by the end of
Speaker 6:  the year, has this ring that they've worked on that has like touch on it.
Speaker 6:  That's like their input. So people are finding all these ways that they can
Speaker 6:  try to control these glasses. But it sounds like has crack something with
Speaker 6:  control labs that maybe will put them ahead. They're on input.
Speaker 1:  You know, it's funny because you know, apple is sort of like reverse engineered
Speaker 1:  the Steve jobs magic. If you like, whenever they do a new category, the
Speaker 1:  watch was like this, the Sterling example of this they're like, what we
Speaker 1:  invented was a new input device. First. It was the mess. Then it was the
Speaker 1:  touch screen. And then it was the digital crown. And you're like,
Speaker 1:  what are you talking about? And so like
Speaker 1:  Crown for such like apple, like
Speaker 1:  for a long time, it was all in I'm like what you need to enter a new category
Speaker 1:  is like a big idea about input devices. So if they
Speaker 1:  do glasses and they haven't like, they
Speaker 1:  don't drop some big idea about input devices, they will actually be really
Speaker 1:  out of form for them. Maybe it maybe it's this ring, but it just strange
Speaker 1:  that they wouldn't be chasing that as hard as anything.
Speaker 6:  I mean, the continuum of these devices is that the glasses are coming
Speaker 6:  later. Metal will probably be first with like something that
Speaker 6:  is like at least consumer like usable, like
Speaker 6:  snaps, not even selling their AR spectacles because they're so expensive.
Speaker 5:  Apples is like a developer kit, right?
Speaker 6:  No, the apple headset's going to be consumer. I mean, it's going to cost
Speaker 6:  a lot of money, but the glasses Apple's not close on
Speaker 6:  really. So like the continuum will be these high-end mixed reality headsets,
Speaker 6:  that sheet into AR by mixing high resolution
Speaker 6:  video pass through with AR effects. So that's what Matt is going to do with
Speaker 6:  Cambridge headset coming out later this year, Apple's going to do.
Speaker 6:  And then later on that continuum, sooner for Matta is glasses
Speaker 6:  that are designed to not fully immerse you and
Speaker 6:  Zach's thesis for this is like presence. It's like, you
Speaker 6:  know, holodeck like holograms of people
Speaker 6:  around you, which like it's supposed to be meant in D w mostly
Speaker 6:  worn indoors, the battery life's like four hours Nila. Does this sound
Speaker 6:  appealing to you? Would you spend, would you spend like
Speaker 6:  $1,500, let's say conservatively on something
Speaker 6:  that, you know, needs a wireless thing in your pocket, an
Speaker 6:  arm band that reads your mind essentially control with your mind that
Speaker 6:  you,
Speaker 1:  It gets me about all that, right? If it's primarily designed for indoors,
Speaker 1:  like, I don't know why it need a strap, a bunch of extra shit to my body
Speaker 1:  to make that go
Speaker 6:  Cause of input. Cause well, cause of computing and I
Speaker 1:  Don't need the processing on my body. I don't, you know, like maybe the arm
Speaker 1:  band, but like I don't need a battery pack. Like if you're telling me this
Speaker 1:  is mostly, so I sit,
Speaker 6:  It's not battery, it's
Speaker 1:  Not battery. Okay. Mostly I'm sitting in my chair in my office. And like
Speaker 1:  you pop up in a hologram. Yes.
Speaker 6:  Yes.
Speaker 1:  That's it. That's the whole game. Yeah. I, I dunno, man.
Speaker 6:  I mean, for V1 V2, maybe like you can take it outdoors with you and has more
Speaker 6:  battery life. It's going have better optics, lighter design. The first version
Speaker 6:  is going to weigh a hundred grams, which is about four X, the weight of regular
Speaker 6:  regular glasses. You're not going to, wouldn't want to wear these for long.
Speaker 5:  People are going to be fee ears.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And what I wanted to suggest with the story is like, this is all very
Speaker 6:  expensive. He's spending over 10 million a year on this. He's literally bet
Speaker 6:  the company on this and it's going to take like they're, they're they're
Speaker 6:  modeling that they may be selling tens of millions of smart glasses
Speaker 6:  collectively between the Ray-Bans between the cheaper hyper Nova
Speaker 6:  glasses between the full AR glasses. That's all of them by like 20,
Speaker 6:  28, like maybe tens of millions. And I'm just like, I don't know how
Speaker 6:  much leash they have.
Speaker 5:  I mean, we've, we've talked a lot about AR and in the success of AR and there's
Speaker 5:  like two big things. One, have they resolved the deal we'd faster.
Speaker 5:  Will you look like a deal we'd wearing 'em into? Have they resolved the fact
Speaker 5:  that there was zero killer app? Because the best killer app is a privacy
Speaker 5:  nightmare?
Speaker 6:  Well, they haven't been invented yet. Like there's not the pro like the opening
Speaker 6:  of this story. It's like these glasses that they showed in this video,
Speaker 6:  like it's not based on any running code. It was all unity prototypes.
Speaker 6:  There's not a wearable prototype internally of the one yet. It's like a
Speaker 6:  stationary desk board. And like, they're hoping to have their wearable
Speaker 6:  prototype internally by the end of the year. Meanwhile, Zuck has literally
Speaker 6:  bet the company on this concept and they do not have a working wearable
Speaker 6:  prototype. So like the guts are incredible. I mean, I got like,
Speaker 6:  there's, there's no company that that's like that. And
Speaker 6:  we can talk about the motivations. I mean, I put in the story, it's like
Speaker 6:  Facebook and it's always like apple and Google that are always over them.
Speaker 6:  And this is their chance, Zack, thanks to gal from under them. And also just
Speaker 6:  like be seen as innovative and cool again, you know, like, cause Turkish,
Speaker 6:  the traditional social media, stuff's not anymore. Then they can't buy.
Speaker 1:  Look, I am very sympathetic to the idea that Facebook will become or
Speaker 1:  Metta will become the next great hardware platform that will break
Speaker 1:  the dominance of the two phone plans. Like that sounds
Speaker 1:  great. But you're saying the first one is going to connect to your phone
Speaker 1:  and like apple is going to have a competitive product right next to it. And
Speaker 1:  like the idea that you're gonna spend $10 million a year to turn into pebble
Speaker 1:  smartwatches, because apple will not let you send a text message
Speaker 1:  in response to a notification on their phone is ridiculous.
Speaker 1:  Like I hear that story and it's like, the first thing you're gonna do is
Speaker 1:  quickly reply to notifications and it's connected to your phone. Like Apple's
Speaker 1:  just going to turn off the notification API for everybody and be like, yeah,
Speaker 1:  the watch can do it in our glasses. Can do it. Everything else is a security
Speaker 1:  problem. We're very sorry.
Speaker 6:  I am so fascinated by antitrust. Like potentially making apple have to
Speaker 6:  open up here, but they're not going to want Metta to be anywhere near their
Speaker 6:  glasses. And like they're unmet as glasses to be anywhere near their phone.
Speaker 6:  Right. And so how do you you're right. How do you navigate that?
Speaker 5:  I mean, this just sounds like a perfect setup for the usual kind of like
Speaker 5:  apple playbook, Facebook, Medis, excuse me. Will come
Speaker 5:  in. They'll do this will be like, this is really cool, but not super
Speaker 5:  viable. They'll do it. What, till 20, 26 or whatever. And then apple will
Speaker 5:  be like, we figured out AR look at, look at what. Now you
Speaker 5:  can use your mind to control things from your apple, watch on your
Speaker 5:  new glasses that we sold you. Isn't it great. Like they're just going to
Speaker 5:  let Facebook, excuse me, Mehta, figure out all of the
Speaker 5:  like hard parts. And then
Speaker 6:  It's classic apple. It's classic apple. They love to skip the messy middle
Speaker 6:  of new computing. Right. And like quest has been that up until
Speaker 6:  quest two and they finally, there were more quest, two sold last year, the
Speaker 6:  next boxes. So like that thing is hitting meaningful scale and the next version
Speaker 6:  will have eye tracking, which will make the avatars like super cool and immersive.
Speaker 6:  So it's only going to get like dramatically better. Apple's watched all that.
Speaker 6:  They'd been secretly buying things. They'd been building experimenting
Speaker 6:  prototypes. They're going to come out with this super high-end luxury. Like
Speaker 6:  state-of-the-art with all their M two chips, sensors, LIDAR and
Speaker 6:  skip a year basically of where Mehta has been tech, not like from the
Speaker 6:  technology standpoint and have like not dealt with all that messy
Speaker 6:  stuff that got up to now. And I think they're going to do the same thing
Speaker 6:  with glasses. I think mark wants to be out there with them to show that
Speaker 6:  they're the leader, but Apple's going to wait and probably come out. And
Speaker 6:  like, I guess my thesis here is that if Meta's is coming out with their first
Speaker 6:  classes by 2024, I wouldn't expect Apple's until at least 2026.
Speaker 12:  It's bizarre that we have not mentioned Google in this because Google is
Speaker 12:  the only one of these companies that is actually currently selling a
Speaker 12:  commercialized AR headset. They also own the
Speaker 12:  company that made the predecessor to control labs project, which did not
Speaker 12:  work very well, but was the same idea was a commercial product like
Speaker 12:  five years before control labs existed. And we are
Speaker 12:  totally not talking about them because it seems like it's not even necessarily
Speaker 12:  clear they're doing anything.
Speaker 1:  They probably forgot like sooner if I just forgot that he even has any of
Speaker 1:  this right.
Speaker 5:  Of these three companies, Google has the worst track record for
Speaker 5:  shipping hardware that people actually want to buy.
Speaker 6:  Well, the problem with Google is focus. It's focus and they have
Speaker 6:  the resources. They have the money, they have the assets, they have the best
Speaker 6:  machine learning. They have maps with like, which is such a key asset for
Speaker 6:  glasses. They have like, they literally have the world mapped, which is like
Speaker 6:  something that it has to figure out. And that assistant, they have the most
Speaker 6:  impressive visual assistant that can like just see something and
Speaker 6:  identify it. It's incredible with classes, right? Like search on your
Speaker 6:  face. They have that. The problem is, is that they don't have like a
Speaker 6:  founder like mark, who is like pushing them to like
Speaker 6:  focus everything on this. And they have a million things going on. They have
Speaker 6:  all this like regulatory scrutiny. They have all these big business lines,
Speaker 6:  all this optionality. And I, you know, I did a story for us about they're
Speaker 6:  doing this. High-end they're also working on a high-end mixed reality headset.
Speaker 6:  They've Al they have all of the big tech guys have all kind of decided the
Speaker 6:  high-end mixed reality is like, that's the near term. They have a glasses
Speaker 6:  project. They bought north, which was like making smart glasses. They're
Speaker 6:  working on something up in Canada. It'll work with a phone I'm
Speaker 6:  told. And, but like, I just don't see the passion there from Google
Speaker 6:  yet. I don't see the focus. And I see where talent goes and all the
Speaker 6:  talent, either going to Metta or apple right now and back and
Speaker 6:  forth.
Speaker 1:  The thing that you mentioned, the founder thing get mark is a founder of
Speaker 1:  Facebook. I think Tim cook is very focused on his legacy at apple. And he
Speaker 1:  has been saying for years that health and AR will be his twin
Speaker 1:  legacies. And you can see how he's going to combine all of that.
Speaker 6:  Yep. I repeat this all the time, but AR is literally the only
Speaker 6:  thing that apple and Mehta agree on. Like the only thing that they agree
Speaker 6:  that is going to be big. So, I mean, we'll
Speaker 6:  see.
Speaker 1:  Well, let's talk about the actual Metta glasses for a minute. Cause Addie
Speaker 1:  you've tried on virtually every one of these products.
Speaker 12:  I'm not tried on there. I've not tried on snaps thing, but I try
Speaker 12:  to.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, but so like between the two of you, there isn't a face computer in
Speaker 1:  the world that we haven't, we haven't strapped on here. So these
Speaker 1:  glasses here's Ms. RA the full AR experience. And does doc wants 3d
Speaker 1:  graphics, large field of view, socially acceptable design, which by the way,
Speaker 1:  mark soccer, where he's like, I need a socially acceptable design. That's
Speaker 1:  a pretty broad remit coming out of duck, like
Speaker 12:  Full
Speaker 1:  Sunscreen face, like whatever you want socially acceptable, but sign.
Speaker 1:  But whatever the team is hoping for a 70 degree field of view,
Speaker 1:  maybe that'll happen. And won't, they look like the Superman glasses when
Speaker 1:  he was Clark. Kent is what Alex right here. And they are really heavy. Now
Speaker 1:  we have talked on the show a lot about just like the stack of problems for
Speaker 1:  AR glasses, right? You've got a display problem. You've got a
Speaker 1:  camera problem. You've got a processing problem. You've got a battery
Speaker 1:  problem. Where is this sitting in the current state of the art? Do you think
Speaker 1:  Alex,
Speaker 6:  It's pretty advanced. You know, a lot of the people I've talked to for this
Speaker 6:  story. It was like, this is actually a pretty impressive like tax spec that
Speaker 6:  is in search of a compelling use case because the software side of this is
Speaker 6:  still being built. They actually just decided the OSTP route. They want to
Speaker 6:  take like in December, basically just
Speaker 1:  Fuchsia, which is
Speaker 6:  Hilarious. No, no, no. They, so they killed, they killed the future approach.
Speaker 6:  So they were going to do fuchsia. They were doing a microkernel like this
Speaker 6:  show,
Speaker 1:  They were still using Google glasses. They just went to Android.
Speaker 6:  They're using the open fork of Android. And that's the same thing that powers
Speaker 6:  the quest. So there'll be able to share like apple libraries and stuff. So
Speaker 6:  they may be able to bring some of the developer ecosystem over, but they
Speaker 6:  were wanting to do a microkernel like fully custom
Speaker 6:  OS. And they decided that won't ship in time for 20, 24, basically.
Speaker 6:  So like this is like do or die. And like, I just, the software
Speaker 6:  side of it is the biggest question, mark. They do not have the platform,
Speaker 6:  DNA developer DNA that apple does. And developers are
Speaker 6:  very wary of Facebook dating back to Farmville. And
Speaker 6:  when FameBit pulled the plug on all these developers, Oculus
Speaker 1:  Is sort of salsa in this problem.
Speaker 6:  Right. They, they have, they have they've, they've got very meaningful, you
Speaker 6:  know, they're buying everything that's doing, going really well. But yeah,
Speaker 6:  they do have developers that are doing well there. But
Speaker 6:  the software side is the biggest question mark by far. And like, how do you
Speaker 6:  build a holographic Kodak to use with messenger where it works, where like
Speaker 6:  on your phone, you can see the hologram, you know, or someone didn't
Speaker 6:  like, cause the idea is like they've got these social apps that like they
Speaker 6:  could use with the glasses where like, I don't need the glasses to like call
Speaker 6:  you on your glasses. Right. And like that's the real unlock. And that's,
Speaker 6:  that's a hard problem that they're still very early on
Speaker 1:  Adding the displays here, Alex is reporting their costly custom wave guides
Speaker 1:  and micro led projectors. I'm still just so
Speaker 1:  skeptical of all of these display ideas.
Speaker 12:  That just sounds like what? Every, like everybody has custom wave guides
Speaker 12:  and everybody okay. Projection tech is like complicated, but it just
Speaker 12:  depends on, it depends on how good the white cards.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I mean, snaps were for the spectacles. They were accustomed, but they
Speaker 6:  were working with wave optics on them. And then they just bought wave optics
Speaker 6:  for half a billion dollars when they decided they wanted to own that.
Speaker 6:  But Metta is like, they're, I mean, they're building everything fully
Speaker 6:  like custom because they've decided they have to go that route, which is
Speaker 6:  what apple has shown is kind of the best way forward with like wearable.
Speaker 1:  Right. But I'm saying you're like everyone's in on high-end mixed reality
Speaker 1:  and right. And I think the reason for that is like
Speaker 1:  to really do the glasses. You have to invent a radically new kind of display
Speaker 1:  tech and costly custom way of guides in micro led projectors. Like maybe
Speaker 1:  they're going to do the best job of that, but that's still as near as I can
Speaker 1:  say, that's still pretty much in the pocket of where everybody is right now.
Speaker 12:  So just a really broad term. You could, it's such a weird, messy, new
Speaker 12:  technology that there could be a really good version of that. That's very
Speaker 12:  thin and very interesting and has really good optics,
Speaker 12:  but it doesn't necessarily tell me a bunch about how
Speaker 12:  good the system currently is. Like magically. I think magic
Speaker 12:  leap too. At this point, it has some of the best stuff that I've seen and
Speaker 12:  tried with some limitations. And I don't know how this would stack
Speaker 12:  up to that. They have at this point, a pretty solid field of view
Speaker 6:  Magically two 70 field of view. Isn't it?
Speaker 1:  Magic leap two is 70 diagonal degrees field of view.
Speaker 12:  Yeah. It's, they've started shipping them to like small partners
Speaker 5:  Or the meta headset's going to be, cause you've mentioned in your piece that
Speaker 5:  they're going to be 70 field of you. Is that also diagonal? Are we talking
Speaker 5:  about
Speaker 6:  No, that's what the hope that they had. That's the hope that they had, and
Speaker 6:  I don't think they're going to get there because then they're probably going
Speaker 6:  for like a color richness and a resolution that's
Speaker 6:  very, mark wants very crisp, like vivid
Speaker 6:  holograms, like you to feel like you can you're someone's almost there.
Speaker 5:  You're looking at through a porthole on a boat
Speaker 6:  Like these glasses have eye tracking
Speaker 12:  Chicken leaps holograms at this point are pretty dear pretty
Speaker 12:  solid, but also in the package that very much does not
Speaker 12:  look normal. They basically just acknowledged. He had look, there's
Speaker 12:  going to be weird, big sunglasses. That's what we're doing. This
Speaker 12:  is what serves our user base. So they have kind of
Speaker 12:  different prerogatives and different requirements.
Speaker 6:  And the metal glasses will have eye tracking, which we consumers have not
Speaker 6:  experienced yet. They will starting later this year with the new quest and
Speaker 6:  apple. But like that, that changes the game. I did this demo of a
Speaker 6:  contact lens where it used my eye movement to like do the
Speaker 6:  input and like go around the dial and select the directions. And like
Speaker 6:  that stuff is wild. Like eye tracking com is going
Speaker 6:  to be very cool and it makes your avatar follow your face and your where
Speaker 6:  you're looking and all that. So they will have that magic leap to does not
Speaker 6:  have that. So I do think from a spec perspective, these will be the best
Speaker 6:  when they come out, but they're going to be expensive and they're going to
Speaker 6:  be for early adopters and they're not going to sell that much.
Speaker 12:  I'm curious what the early adopter thing is going to is going to do because
Speaker 12:  like glass tried that. And I think that's kind of one of the reasons why
Speaker 12:  people hated glass so much because it was seen as this thing that you had
Speaker 12:  these very small groups of super rich, early
Speaker 12:  adopter guys trying out, and they looked like jerks and you hated
Speaker 12:  them
Speaker 5:  Glass holes, like what are we going to call these? Are these guys also going
Speaker 5:  to be called glass holes?
Speaker 1:  Well, the idea is that you won't know like glass was, I mean, this is my
Speaker 1:  favorite. So to start my class so many times glass looks so intense and it
Speaker 1:  came with so much hype in that moment of hype that like
Speaker 1:  I went to the Indy 500 wearing Google glass. And like
Speaker 1:  people were like falling out of trailers in the infield and be like, can
Speaker 1:  you see through clothes? And like, that was the thing that would have sold
Speaker 1:  what Google glass looked like to people like they were heartbroken when I
Speaker 1:  was like, no, I can not see through clothes at best. It like
Speaker 1:  lightly buzzes and takes a two megapixel photo,
Speaker 1:  like reach up to it. Like that's what it does. But I think you have to make
Speaker 1:  them look really normal, right? That's like, that's where everyone is headed
Speaker 1:  with these. They have to look
Speaker 6:  And to be clear, the first version of these there, there's going to be no
Speaker 6:  mistaking that you're doing have normal classes.
Speaker 6:  So like,
Speaker 1:  Well, this is a great story. We're obviously tracking this very closely.
Speaker 1:  I'm I mean, this is the next generation of gadgets, right? Like
Speaker 1:  It's like folding phones and this and my, you know, one of my big
Speaker 1:  theses is that display technology drives the generations of
Speaker 1:  gadgets. Like if you can predict this way, technology can predict the shape
Speaker 1:  of things. And that will like folding phones. Is that thing. I imagine Apple's
Speaker 1:  working in one of those too, right? Like it's just about that time for that
Speaker 1:  to hit the mainstream and right next to it is can we make the display that
Speaker 1:  goes into your face? And I'm, I'm very curious to see how this plays out,
Speaker 6:  Which will happen first Elan, making Twitter a
Speaker 6:  bastion of free speech or really good displays for our
Speaker 6:  face
Speaker 1:  To face displays. I gotta be honest with
Speaker 5:  You.
Speaker 1:  All right. We have gone spectacularly over time. I appreciate all of you.
Speaker 1:  I appreciate all of you for listening to us. You can tweet at
Speaker 1:  us. I'm very confident that you'll and bots. We tweeting us this
Speaker 1:  week. Alex is Alex H Kranz. The other Alex is Alex
Speaker 1:  Heath. It's good. It worked out. Addie is at the Dexter hierarchy. Liz is
Speaker 1:  Ms. Lopatto and reckless on Twitter is a fun week on
Speaker 1:  the virtual icon actually Corrine our new senior security reporter had a
Speaker 1:  big story on why crypto bridges are where all the hacks are. So if
Speaker 1:  you've been watching all these crypto hacks, like he has a deep dive into
Speaker 1:  like why it's happening and the structure that creates it. And then on decoder,
Speaker 1:  we had more crypto Chris Dixon, who is a Forbes, just called them the number
Speaker 1:  one VC in the world. He's the big web three VC. He and I got into it. And
Speaker 1:  whether any of that stuff is real, it was a really fun conversation. I'm
Speaker 1:  just going to tell the virtuous audiences now next week on decoder on
Speaker 1:  Tuesday, Alan Young, the guy who was in charge of the Fox on
Speaker 1:  project in Wisconsin asked us to be under coder.
Speaker 1:  Oh wow. And it was nuts. At one point I was like, what's in the
Speaker 1:  dome. And he's like, I gotta be honest with you. I think the dome should
Speaker 1:  have been bigger. And it was like, yes.
Speaker 17:  When he's right. He's right.
Speaker 1:  I was like, yeah, I agree with you. I can't, I find no fault in any, if anyone
Speaker 1:  tells me don't shoot bigger, I'm in it. I agree. It was just a
Speaker 1:  Bunker's conversation. He has a book. I don't know why he has to be in the
Speaker 1:  show, but he has a book that's coming out. That's on Tuesday and declutter.
Speaker 1:  All right, that's
Speaker 1:  it.