# Transcript
ID: 6de53380-c25c-11ec-bdeb-13be7b465b76
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Sonos' new budget soundbar / CNN Plus is shutting down / Netflix loses subscribers for the first time in over a decade
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-4491168858000929356/8417832864323893021/s93290-US-4784s-1650641232.mp3
Description: David Pierce rejoins The Vergecast with Nilay Patel and Alex Cranz. The crew discuss Netflix losing subscribers for the first time in over a decade, CNN Plus shutting down only a month after it launched, and a whole lot more.
Verge editor Chris Welch joins the show to discuss Sonos' new budget soundbar that is set to release in June.
Speaker 1:  This week on the Vergecast David Pierce joins the show for the first time.
Speaker 1:  It's one of its new hosts. We talk about what's going on with Netflix, losing
Speaker 1:  subscribers, CNN plus shutting down. We do a little bit of a gadget scoop
Speaker 1:  about sus. And of course we talk about Elon and Twitter. That's coming up
Speaker 1:  on the broadcast. Now,
Speaker 2:  Everyday customers rely on the internet for information needed to make life
Speaker 2:  decisions big and small from booking a dream vacation to picking out a new
Speaker 2:  pair of shoes, no matter what they're searching for, they need the right
Speaker 2:  information in that moment of intent to confidently take the next step in
Speaker 2:  their journey. But when they're searching for info about your business, are
Speaker 2:  you sure they're finding exactly what they need, because if they can't find
Speaker 2:  it from you, they'll find it from someone else. Yext puts you back in control
Speaker 2:  by consolidating and managing all of your businesses information to make
Speaker 2:  it easy, to find everywhere on search engines, websites, apps, chatbots,
Speaker 2:  and voice assistants. The AIX platform provides accurate timely answers to
Speaker 2:  questions across the entire customer journey from discovery to conversion,
Speaker 2:  to support and beyond. Plus you'll gain rich insights about what your users
Speaker 2:  are looking for. That helps you create and deliver new and better. Content.
Speaker 2:  Implementation is easy and businesses who use the X to drive more transactions,
Speaker 2:  reduce the number of support tickets and deliver an overall better customer
Speaker 2:  experience. Take control of your business information and make sure it's
Speaker 2:  discoverable by everyone everywhere you need it to be, to learn more, go
Speaker 2:  to E X t.com.
Speaker 3:  Support for this episode comes from Salesforce. Did you know that pivot is
Speaker 3:  now on Salesforce, plus it. Salesforce is new streaming service
Speaker 3:  where you can now stream award-winning original series live
Speaker 3:  experiences and virtual learning with Salesforce. Plus
Speaker 3:  business leaders can tap into the latest engaging, inspirational
Speaker 3:  stories and get thought leadership and expert advice on demand.
Speaker 3:  Join for free and watch new business series like pivot on demand at
Speaker 3:  salesforce.com/plus
Speaker 1:  Hello and welcome to our chest. The flagship podcast, the
Speaker 1:  90 scale of Dube streaming services, a joke, which I
Speaker 1:  started five years ago, but as newly relevant today,
Speaker 1:  that's the virtuous. I'm your friend Nila. Alex cranes is here.
Speaker 5:  I am really excited about talking about Quimbee today.
Speaker 1:  This is all we do is we talk about Quimbee. Please rotate your phone.
Speaker 5:  Rotate. As you can hear this better.
Speaker 1:  We have a big announcement, very exciting news, new
Speaker 1:  host of the Vergecast new member of the verge staff. David Pierce
Speaker 1:  is here.
Speaker 2:  Hello? I'm your friend who will always share his Netflix password.
Speaker 2:  Always no questions.
Speaker 1:  I asked, no matter what you can VPN into my house.
Speaker 2:  And when we break up and you keep ruining my Netflix recommendations, I will
Speaker 2:  not take away your access because I'm just that good. A person.
Speaker 1:  It's funny. Cause I want to take away Max's access. Cause she's really ruining
Speaker 1:  my recommendation. That's huge problem. It's the children. Once they're in
Speaker 1:  there, Netflix has no idea what
Speaker 5:  Cocoa Mellon.
Speaker 1:  Now it's all cocoa Mellon. Liam are pretty
Speaker 1:  strong. The virtuous in creating the producer of decoder, both worked on
Speaker 1:  a kid show called Gabby's dollhouse, which is great. And max likes it and
Speaker 1:  I'm happy to support those two. I just don't need in my
Speaker 1:  recommendations.
Speaker 2:  I've always thought Netflix needed a button. That's just like a regret button
Speaker 2:  where you're like, I should never have watched this. I'm so sorry. Please
Speaker 2:  take this out of my recommendations forever. They were
Speaker 5:  Supposed to give us one. We were supposed to get like a forget button.
Speaker 1:  Okay. I want to talk about that in a minute. First of all, I just want to
Speaker 1:  point out David was like employee one at the verge in 2010. True. You've
Speaker 1:  been on a journey through the wilderness and now you're back.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, it was just, I was just looking for you, looking for love and looking
Speaker 2:  from your mind. It's all it was
Speaker 1:  For here.
Speaker 2:  No, it's, it's both very weird and very good to be back. It kind of feels
Speaker 2:  like no time has passed. It also feels like it has been a literal eternity
Speaker 2:  since I have done a Vergecast
Speaker 1:  Yeah, you were on stage with us at the 10 year event with Joanna. But I think
Speaker 1:  the last time was like seven years ago. Formally that you did have her chance
Speaker 1:  with us.
Speaker 2:  Yes. Still mercifully. The only time anyone has made me cry on a podcast.
Speaker 2:  So, which is a thing that I would very much like to
Speaker 1:  Welcome back, David, we've got a new goal for you, buddy. If
Speaker 1:  we don't get to tears the next 90 minutes, I don't know what we're doing
Speaker 1:  here.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Listen, if CNN plus can't do it to me. Nothing can.
Speaker 1:  So that's so let's talk about the news. David's here. Everybody welcomed
Speaker 1:  him. You can tweet at him. He's at Pierce. It's great. It's great to have
Speaker 1:  you here. We're very excited. We've got big plans to expand the show with
Speaker 1:  David. You're going to see him on the site in a bunch of ways. It's going
Speaker 1:  to be fun. All right. So talk about streaming and really what I want to talk
Speaker 1:  about is not CNN plus or Netflix losing subscribers. I want to talk about
Speaker 1:  this very simple idea that you just brought up, which is you should, every
Speaker 1:  streaming app should have a button that's like play, but
Speaker 1:  don't count it.
Speaker 2:  Yes. I call it the, I feel bad about this button.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Don't put this in your data.
Speaker 2:  I want it for Spotify. I want it for everything. Like I want to listen to
Speaker 2:  this thing or watch this thing, but please don't tell anyone. I don't
Speaker 2:  remember that. I did it like it it's I would use it all the time. That's
Speaker 2:  all I want.
Speaker 5:  And Cognito mode basically.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. This show ain't a hit that play, but don't pretend that this was, I
Speaker 1:  did this, right. This is how I feel about moon night. I'm watching
Speaker 1:  that shit. But I don't think that this is a good show
Speaker 1:  that anyone should be watching,
Speaker 2:  Right? Yeah. I don't want you to hold this injury in your viewership metrics.
Speaker 2:  I don't want you to use it to decide how much money you're going to pay Oscar,
Speaker 2:  Isaac, like this sucks. And I want you to know it, but I am going to watch
Speaker 2:  it.
Speaker 1:  If ever Disney plus releases metrics on new night, I'm just going to follow
Speaker 1:  they're on me. But minus one, I didn't, I
Speaker 1:  didn't do that willingly. It was just Wednesday and nothing else was happening.
Speaker 1:  I feel very badly about that. We're going to have Charles Pulliam Moore,
Speaker 1:  our new TV critic on the show soon to talk about all the start-up shows.
Speaker 1:  And I really just want to talk to him and brunette the whole time. So don't
Speaker 1:  tell him he thinks he's coming on to soccer about super pumped and we crashed
Speaker 1:  and all that. It's just our me being like, why did they
Speaker 1:  make an ABC TV movie from the nineties on
Speaker 1:  Disney was like, that is the level of quality of the show. I'm sure there
Speaker 1:  are Moonlight fans out there and I encourage you to tweet.
Speaker 2:  I have not watched Moonlight. And now it's a really, it's a hell of a sales
Speaker 2:  pitch. You just did. I cannot wait. I mean,
Speaker 1:  It gets so bad. It has the production quality of remember see quest
Speaker 1:  DSV
Speaker 1:  kids are right in that pocket
Speaker 5:  And also has a talking dolphin. It's wild. How similar they are.
Speaker 1:  It's like what's going on with anyway, the
Speaker 1:  actual streaming services. We're going to talk about what sort of Netflix,
Speaker 1:  because Netflix is a juggernaut. It's I think
Speaker 1:  it's going to be fine, but they just saw subscribers for the first time in
Speaker 1:  over a decade, they announced they're going to do an advertising tier
Speaker 1:  and they are going to crack down on sharing Netflix accounts, the
Speaker 1:  same password across households. That's a lot of change. And I would say
Speaker 1:  people lost their minds.
Speaker 2:  Yes.
Speaker 1:  When all this happened.
Speaker 2:  So I would say my big take on this is that two of those three things
Speaker 2:  you just said are super, super interesting. I think the fact that Netflix
Speaker 2:  lost 200,000 subscribers in a quarter is like a small thing
Speaker 2:  worth noting, but not ultimately like the harbinger of anything.
Speaker 2:  Long-term everything changes. Like there are
Speaker 2:  only so many humans in the world who will ever subscribe to Netflix. Like
Speaker 2:  those numbers are going to go up and down a little more than they have. That
Speaker 2:  does not strike me as all that. Interesting. I think the ad future of Netflix
Speaker 2:  is fascinating. And I think the password thing is going to be super interesting.
Speaker 2:  And it was really incredible to watch the response to this because
Speaker 2:  everybody went from Netflix is the juggernaut. It's the future of TV too.
Speaker 2:  Like in the course of one earnings release, being like, well, Netflix is
Speaker 2:  over.
Speaker 1:  So I have to, I have to do this closures, Vox media as a company, we all
Speaker 1:  work at it. NBC, which owns peacock, which streaming service NBC is a
Speaker 1:  minority investor in Fox media, which we all work at that soundbite,
Speaker 1:  Comcast, Comcast doesn't like, doesn't like us. So there should have closure.
Speaker 1:  The verge is making a Netflix show. It's actually coming out soon. It's gonna
Speaker 1:  be really exciting. I'm the VP of that show. Vox media
Speaker 1:  as a company makes shows for all these streaming services. There's a show
Speaker 1:  on CNN plus, which we're going to talk about. There's a lot. The Vox is show
Speaker 1:  Netflix. Like all the things you can think of, but our show is our show and
Speaker 1:  we get to say whatever we want. I just make the disclosures. That's the disclosure
Speaker 1:  part. You can't tell me I didn't.
Speaker 5:  You did it. That was great.
Speaker 1:  I wear it like moon night wears the suit
Speaker 1:  All throughout moon night. There's just like wear the suit. And he's like,
Speaker 1:  no, it's like, that's your whole job.
Speaker 5:  That's the one thing we want to see from you. How do we segue that back to
Speaker 5:  Netflix? The one thing we want to see from them is more subscribers.
Speaker 1:  Yes. So you want it. So Netflix loses 200,000 subscribers. There's some
Speaker 1:  underlying data stuff to think about there because they
Speaker 1:  left Russia. So they hadn't left the Russian market and
Speaker 1:  maybe they would have ticked up slightly. But it doesn't matter because net,
Speaker 1:  they lost 200,000 subscribers. They are focused on
Speaker 1:  that subscriber loss, particularly in north America, which is a big, big
Speaker 1:  deal, right? This is the market that's saturated and they are attributing
Speaker 1:  it to look. There's a lot of competition. Now there is Disney plus there
Speaker 1:  is apple TV plus apple TV. Plus just won an Oscar. Their shows are
Speaker 1:  really good. Everyone like severance, there is HBO max, which we should talk
Speaker 1:  about because now it's part of discovery and they're going undergoing changes.
Speaker 1:  But HBO, max has the Batman
Speaker 5:  Scribe,
Speaker 1:  But like that's HBO, max, like they've got the big
Speaker 1:  catalog of HBO stuff.
Speaker 5:  They've got like the whole Turner collection. They've got like all the old
Speaker 5:  movies that nobody else has.
Speaker 1:  You can watch pump up the volume on HBO, max, whenever you want. And
Speaker 1:  then, you know, the Batman was a sensation in theaters and it quickly hit
Speaker 1:  the streaming service and then everyone watched it again and it had another
Speaker 1:  cycle, like that's real competition regardless of the corporate
Speaker 1:  chaos of 18 T and Warner media and discovery
Speaker 1:  like they're executing.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Well, and it's an interesting thing because I was thinking about this
Speaker 2:  in the course of prepping for this, that like, I almost couldn't describe
Speaker 2:  to you what Netflix is the streaming service for anymore. Cause
Speaker 2:  it's like HBO is starting to lock down the sort of really like
Speaker 2:  blockbustery prestige stuff more and more Disney is the
Speaker 2:  place you go that has all of the stuff that like your kids want to watch.
Speaker 2:  And it's like the family friendly one that has all the Marvel and star wars
Speaker 2:  like that pitch is easy. A peacock is where do you go to watch
Speaker 2:  the office paramount plus exists?
Speaker 1:  No apparent my is going to have top gun Mavericks.
Speaker 2:  Okay. There you go. So there's a tail switch and I'm kind of at a point where
Speaker 2:  like Netflix, his big thing is just that it's Netflix, right? Like it is,
Speaker 2:  it is just the one everybody already has and that's
Speaker 2:  super powerful, but it does seem like we're getting to a point now where
Speaker 2:  like, if I have subscription fatigue, like how long is the list of things
Speaker 2:  that are like dragging people back to Netflix every single day anymore. And
Speaker 2:  it feels like that list is getting shorter.
Speaker 5:  This is what Netflix has been scared of for years though. Right? Like they
Speaker 5:  started losing their catalog. They started losing friends in the office and
Speaker 5:  star Trek and everything else. And those went to smaller, serve smaller services.
Speaker 5:  And so they've been terrified of this. That's why they've been investing.
Speaker 5:  They've been trying to build this catalog. And I honestly think that this
Speaker 5:  is all because they screwed up because they're like, we know, we know we
Speaker 5:  got to build a catalog. We got to do like apple TV. We've got to make like
Speaker 5:  a reason for people to come here. But instead of everybody else who goes
Speaker 5:  and like figures out what shows people want to watch and make them
Speaker 5:  Netflix was like, we're going to use an algorithm to figure out how
Speaker 5:  to like, min-max this shit. And that's how we're going to make
Speaker 5:  content. And now everybody's like, but it's all boring and
Speaker 5:  bad and blahzay
Speaker 2:  Because the algorithm told them the thing to do is go all in on like niche,
Speaker 2:  weird dating shows. Yeah. Which I've watched all of them,
Speaker 5:  The international selections. Incredible. But it's mainly through like partnerships
Speaker 5:  with other, other channels. And then there's like, all the American stuff
Speaker 5:  is like stuff that canceled after two seasons.
Speaker 1:  When I say people went crazy because Netflix lost 200,000 subscribers,
Speaker 1:  like literally got all the way to, this is the end of prestige TV.
Speaker 1:  Right. Like, and it was like, what are you talking about? Right. Like they
Speaker 1:  were sort of not making it when they were making it. It was like house of
Speaker 1:  cards. And it was like one specific era. But what isn't Netflix like
Speaker 1:  very famous for. It's like two seasons or a thing that a
Speaker 1:  small, very dedicated crew fans likes and then cutting
Speaker 1:  it and then moving on. Right. And like we've heard from TV
Speaker 1:  executives over the years or like Netflix isn't promote our work the way
Speaker 1:  the other streamers do that is in contrast to
Speaker 1:  a lot of TV. People saying Netflix is the best to work for it. Cause they'll
Speaker 1:  cut you a check in and get out of your way. Which I always think of that
Speaker 1:  is like a blessing and a curse. Like it's a lot of smart, creative people
Speaker 1:  without an editor. And then as an editor, you know, I have a very specific
Speaker 1:  feeling about that, which is like, everybody needs an editor. It's like,
Speaker 1:  there's a lot of just like bloat in the middle of Netflix shows
Speaker 2:  One. It sounds like even now Netflix is aware of that. Like
Speaker 2:  I think it was Matthew Ball was tweeting about this earlier after the, the
Speaker 2:  news came out, that Netflix is aware of the thing that
Speaker 2:  you're describing and is kind of 18 months into a plan
Speaker 2:  to fix some of that where they're like, and they've been saying, we need
Speaker 2:  to reinvest in, in quality over quantity, which is like a very funny thing
Speaker 2:  for somebody like Netflix to say, it's like, well, yeah, we all could have
Speaker 2:  told you that that was going to be the case, but they just made it so much
Speaker 2:  stuff for so long that I think they were
Speaker 2:  maybe later than they needed to be to realizing like, oh, what we actually
Speaker 2:  need is a handful of really good, really sticky, really
Speaker 2:  long lasting things. And the problem is they're halfway into the
Speaker 2:  process of making some of that stuff and making that stuff is really, really,
Speaker 2:  really hard. Like they made squid games. Everybody's like, cool. But like
Speaker 2:  there's not 80 more seasons of squid game that people are gonna watch.
Speaker 1:  Oh, they're going to now they're gonna find a way
Speaker 5:  Pushback on that idea that they're, they're redoing things. Cause they aren't
Speaker 5:  like they just, this week got rid of their head of animation. That was one
Speaker 5:  of the places where they were really standing out and they were really competing
Speaker 5:  and, and starting to like take all these really cool creators from Disney
Speaker 5:  and cartoon network and, and building up this thing under this guy, Phil
Speaker 5:  Renda, who had started at cartoon network, he found like adventure
Speaker 5:  time, which kicked off this huge animation Renaissance. And like
Speaker 5:  they were building a new animation Renaissance at Netflix. And then they're
Speaker 5:  like, no, we're going to fire that guy and like cancel everything. Oh, you
Speaker 5:  wanted bone. We've been trying to make it for 25 years. Nevermind. You're
Speaker 5:  not getting it. And he was one of those rare people that was actually thinking
Speaker 5:  about, okay, what is good content? How do we make good content? I will not
Speaker 5:  just listen to the algorithm and they get rid of him. And like, that seems
Speaker 5:  very, very stupid.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. But I, I don't ever really know how to evaluate those things.
Speaker 1:  Right. Like how big was the audience for that? Netflix won't give us the
Speaker 1:  numbers. Maybe they're spending a lot of money in animation. No one was watching
Speaker 1:  it. Or they were spending a lot of money on animation and a very small
Speaker 1:  number of very loyal people were watching it and tweeting a lot. And that
Speaker 1:  just like skews our perception of everything. One of the core problems with
Speaker 1:  all of these services is that they're utterly opaque in a way
Speaker 1:  that I don't know, broadcast TV and cable TV all had Nielsen.
Speaker 1:  So we could, we had some way of measuring something.
Speaker 1:  Even if Nielsen wasn't perfect.
Speaker 5:  That's going to change soon. Right? Because like all of these, all of these
Speaker 5:  people are also pivoting to advertising and you can't do advertising
Speaker 5:  without metrics. Like nobody's, I mean, I hope they do try. I
Speaker 5:  hope they go the tumbler route and like just have the worst ads on all the
Speaker 5:  Netflix shows like that would bring me personally joy. But at some point
Speaker 5:  we're going to have to get metrics because like, who's going to want to,
Speaker 5:  like, they're going to say, oh yeah, everybody watches, squid gains. Did
Speaker 5:  everybody watch squid games? Are you just telling us that? Cause you can
Speaker 5:  do that, but you can't do that to the advertisers.
Speaker 1:  Well, so now Netflix has started releasing some numbers. They've got a website
Speaker 1:  now, you know, the it's like total engagement or
Speaker 1:  something like some number that no one else uses. So you can't measure it.
Speaker 1:  Exactly. But the thing you're saying about advertising and the password
Speaker 1:  sharing thing is really interesting because it connects directly to it. David
Speaker 1:  was saying about, you kind of run out of people in United States. Yeah. You
Speaker 1:  sort of have any sort of haven't right. They've got 200 million people
Speaker 1:  around the world more or less.
Speaker 2:  It's like two 20. Yeah,
Speaker 1:  Yeah. 220 something accounts, 220 million. So many accounts around the world.
Speaker 1:  There's more people than that in United States. So you haven't like maxed
Speaker 1:  it out yet. There's a billions of people in the world. And like, you know,
Speaker 1:  the hyperbolic headline of maybe this is as big as any streaming service
Speaker 1:  and get like, or you can do a lot of things. So one thing we can do
Speaker 1:  is eliminate password sharing. And the way that they have hinted
Speaker 1:  at doing is they won't just cut you off. They'll tell the
Speaker 1:  person whose password you're sharing. Hey, you could just
Speaker 1:  pay some more money to support your friends or your ex
Speaker 1:  or whoever it is.
Speaker 5:  I'm going to do that.
Speaker 1:  Right. So like, I'm going to get the note about my parents And
Speaker 1:  I'm like, yeah, just pay the money for mom and dad. So like they will
Speaker 1:  attract some revenue in that way. Then if you're like, I'm not going to pay
Speaker 1:  for my ex, I'm going to cut them off. You'll what they'll drop down to
Speaker 1:  is a lower ad supported tier. So then Netflix will
Speaker 1:  retain you on a cheaper tier or maybe even a
Speaker 1:  free ad supported tier and say, you still have Netflix. We
Speaker 1:  didn't take it away from you. Right. We just put some ads in it.
Speaker 5:  Is it going to be like punishment? Like if you don't pay, you have to move
Speaker 5:  to ads.
Speaker 1:  Well, no. Cause like maybe you're like, I just don't want Netflix, but what
Speaker 1:  they're not going to do is like penalize everyone. They're going to like
Speaker 1:  have these off-ramps into either more money or ads. And
Speaker 1:  that like increases your number of users, which is like very,
Speaker 1:  very clever way of doing
Speaker 2:  It is I am fascinated by what the like copywriting
Speaker 2:  meetings are going to be like for how they tell your parents and my
Speaker 2:  exes, what just happened. It's like
Speaker 2:  Nila decided he doesn't want to pay for you anymore. He
Speaker 2:  doesn't love you enough to pay for your Netflix profile. So here's some ads
Speaker 2:  thanked me like,
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I mean, and they've got to find ways to solve it. People will travel.
Speaker 1:  So like, if you're traveling out of your house, like they'll, they'll do
Speaker 1:  this stuff that quite frankly, all the live TV services have done, like
Speaker 1:  YouTube TV has figured this out. Hulu has pretended to figure it out. But
Speaker 1:  Hulu is just like, are you somewhere else? Go to jail wherever you are. If
Speaker 1:  you're not in your home, this is probably jail of some kind that you should
Speaker 1:  be in. So all these services have these like geolocation restrictions, but
Speaker 1:  the idea that they will initiate new people and advertising, they've got
Speaker 1:  a ramp with password sharing into, here's a soft landing on
Speaker 1:  the ad supported here that you're not paying for. And if you want to pay,
Speaker 1:  you can still pay for the new thing. They've got to execute all of
Speaker 1:  that. But that's actually how you end up growing your business. You add
Speaker 1:  pricing tiers, right? You make a cheaper one and a more expensive one. Like
Speaker 1:  every, you know, there's an, there's an iPhone at every $50 price point that
Speaker 1:  you can think of. Cause it's like, do you have some money? You should spend
Speaker 1:  it. And right now Netflix is like, to your point, David, like, they've
Speaker 1:  just acted like the default. Yeah. Your first $15 in your streaming budget
Speaker 1:  goes to Netflix. And I think that might be,
Speaker 2:  I kind of think so. I, I, if I had to pick one as the default right now,
Speaker 2:  I think it's probably a Disney plus. Like if, if you're only going to get
Speaker 2:  one streaming service, it feels increasingly to me, like the answer is Disney.
Speaker 2:  Plus
Speaker 5:  You have small children in your
Speaker 2:  Home. I don't, but I know a lot of people who do so it's possible that I'm
Speaker 2:  very biased. I also think that's what HBO max is after and has a real shot
Speaker 2:  at pulling off with the whole discovery thing.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I was going to say like HBO, max would be where my, like
Speaker 1:  That's where my first money would go.
Speaker 5:  And like if it fixed its app for God, I refuse to have it be my
Speaker 5:  only one with its terrible app.
Speaker 1:  I think there was a secret update to the HBO max app. There
Speaker 5:  Was it now does a BombBomb like, like Netflix.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. It has the weird circle spinner. And I think the purple got darker
Speaker 1:  And they didn't say anything about it. So I'm just, I'm just there being
Speaker 1:  like, is that purple? Darker? Should I read into this? And then the app
Speaker 1:  is like ever so slightly slower and I'm like, maybe it's not an update, but
Speaker 1:  then it's like, boom, it's like, it's different.
Speaker 5:  And these are just like, don't actually test things before they push them
Speaker 5:  live. I think we are the test subjects. They just push it live and I'm like,
Speaker 5:  did anybody complain? No, no. Keep going, keep going, keep
Speaker 1:  Going. They should just let me in there. Let me design here.
Speaker 5:  But do you really think that like Netflix is actually going to add subscribers
Speaker 5:  because they think of this bonkers number of like a hundred million
Speaker 5:  people or a hundred million subscriptions are being lost to,
Speaker 5:  to password sharing. Do you really think they're going to claim all of those
Speaker 5:  back or is the company
Speaker 1:  That's the same number as like the recording industry being like, we would
Speaker 1:  have made 50 million more dollars last year, if not for piracy. And it's
Speaker 1:  like, no, I definitely wouldn't have listened to anything. Sorry.
Speaker 1:  Like I definitely like ripped all of my friend's CDs and I wasn't like
Speaker 1:  ,
Speaker 5:  I think we're also reaching this point where I'm seeing more and more people
Speaker 5:  say, how do you use bit torrent? Like I'm seeing like this increase in like
Speaker 5:  interest in piracy. I'm seeing this increase in like interest in not
Speaker 5:  paying for the shit
Speaker 1:  Spoken like a true Nvidia shield on her. I
Speaker 5:  Right. I love my Plex. Very legally acquired
Speaker 5:  materials on it. But like, I just really don't think
Speaker 5:  that they're these, all these people, these hundred million households or
Speaker 5:  whatever are going to be like, okay, well there's a cheaper version now I'm
Speaker 5:  going to go get it.
Speaker 1:  But I think you can point to that and saying, we'll get some percentage of
Speaker 1:  them. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I guess they will. They'll get their 200,000 back.
Speaker 1:  Yes. I mean, that's a very small percentage, a hundred million people.
Speaker 2:  I think. I mean, to me, the, the ad thing is much more
Speaker 2:  about like other countries outside the S than it is the U S and like
Speaker 2:  there's some like me layer, right? Not everyone in America has Netflix already,
Speaker 2:  so there's some gain to be had there. But I think like the, the thing that
Speaker 2:  I've heard over and over about India for instance, is that like Netflix is
Speaker 2:  just too expensive in India. And people have cable subscriptions that are
Speaker 2:  not very expensive, that they're not eager to cancel. And so Netflix just
Speaker 2:  has not been able to make the same pitch in countries like that, that it
Speaker 2:  has here, which is like, we have tons of stuff to watch and we're cheaper
Speaker 2:  than cable. Like that is actually not how it works in India, but something
Speaker 2:  like additive, which is like a cheaper free Netflix
Speaker 2:  or not free, but a cheaper ad supported Netflix is going to be
Speaker 2:  much more compelling to people in countries like that. Where $20 a month
Speaker 2:  for Netflix seems ludicrous. But half that plus ads
Speaker 2:  or a quarter of that plus ads might be a lot more compelling. So that's
Speaker 2:  like, I think the, the sort of fail gracefully into ads thing is really interesting,
Speaker 2:  but my sense is the people who would pay for Netflix
Speaker 2:  at what it costs now and the people who want it with ads are like more
Speaker 2:  separate groups of people than, than maybe I had been thinking. Yeah,
Speaker 1:  Yeah. We actually have a pitch in, from an Indian reporter about why Netflix
Speaker 1:  failed in any of that. I'm very excited to read when it comes in.
Speaker 2:  That's exciting. I look forward to my theory being totally wrong when that
Speaker 2:  sort of anxious. So that'd be great.
Speaker 1:  I think that market is particularly interesting for a wide variety of reasons
Speaker 1:  at the end of the day, though, what I think the real cause of this like day
Speaker 1:  long freak out about Netflix is because this market is now competitive
Speaker 1:  and everyone has forgotten what super competitive tech markets look like.
Speaker 1:  Like you have a lot of choices and you can bail and spend your money somewhere
Speaker 1:  else. And a lot of people looked at Netflix this past quarter and
Speaker 1:  bailed and like most of these companies do not have that experience,
Speaker 1:  right. Like, no, one's like, you know what, I'm going to do an Android phone
Speaker 1:  today. I think on the show, sometimes we pretend that
Speaker 1:  right. But like every, I mean we do earnings every quarter and every quarter
Speaker 1:  it's like apple had another record quarter or like Amazon is like once
Speaker 1:  again, an Amazon number of Kindles were so, and they're like, what does that
Speaker 1:  mean? And they're like the most Kendall's compared to the number of
Speaker 1:  Kindles previously sold compared to the number of Kindles that I imagined.
Speaker 1:  And it's like, that's so not a number, but it sounds great. And the other
Speaker 1:  numbers going up and like, we just haven't seen any of the big tech
Speaker 1:  companies take a hit in such a long time that when they do it
Speaker 1:  feels like something is over as opposed to just how markets work,
Speaker 1:  like people left and came back.
Speaker 2:  I think that's right. Well, and I also think it's clearly the end of one
Speaker 2:  phase of this industry for companies like Netflix too, which is basically
Speaker 2:  just the throw money at the problem phase. Right. And yeah, even going back,
Speaker 2:  Netflix basically was able to throw money at the problem and keep
Speaker 2:  growing like crazy forever. And if there's one thing we know investors in
Speaker 2:  particular, like it's a hilarious amounts of money being spent in service
Speaker 2:  of hilarious amounts of growth. And now Netflix is saying, we need to
Speaker 2:  spend less on dumb stuff and be a little more prudent about how we
Speaker 2:  spend our money. And investors are saying, well, that freaks
Speaker 2:  us out because, because like the, the freewheeling era of streaming
Speaker 2:  growing is just, is just not going to keep being this
Speaker 2:  freewheeling. Like, as they got bigger, as they start to make a real dent
Speaker 2:  in the cable industry, it was always going to happen like this. And I think
Speaker 2:  Netflix just, unfortunately for Netflix gets to be kind of the first through
Speaker 2:  the gate of like, this is a real industry now.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I mean, the phone companies is uncompetitive as that market
Speaker 1:  is right at and T and Verizon and T-Mobile track their
Speaker 1:  churn amongst each other and they carefully manage their prices. So that
Speaker 1:  they're all the same all the time. Anyway,
Speaker 5:  Now we're going to have a quad opoly. What's the streaming one. How
Speaker 5:  many are there
Speaker 1:  Streaming is just like this like super competitive market. Like, I don't
Speaker 1:  think it is a four-sided race between Netflix and
Speaker 1:  HBO, max and Disney plus and peacock. Like there's a lot of
Speaker 1:  entrance and there's a lot of ways to spend your money.
Speaker 1:  And like, some of them are just gonna fail and some of them are going to
Speaker 1:  succeed and some of them are just trade subscribers. Like, like, I think
Speaker 1:  it's actually relatively cool that unlike a cable or
Speaker 1:  your phone service, like you can just quit these apps like month to month.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Is there anything else out there like that? Like I, I subscribed to
Speaker 2:  Showtime for a month so that I could watch super pumped and yellow jackets
Speaker 2:  and I have two more episodes of yellow jackets. And when I'm done with them,
Speaker 2:  I'm going to cancel them until another season of those shows comes out. And
Speaker 2:  it's such an unusual mechanic that like,
Speaker 2:  I can just, anyone who's paying attention can just do that with
Speaker 2:  five different services, five times a year. And you end up saving yourself
Speaker 2:  a bunch of money and it's going to make their numbers chaos all the time.
Speaker 2:  It's so unlike anything else I can think of
Speaker 5:  Man, if only they had some sort of like hard copy
Speaker 5:  version of these things that you could just buy for a lot more money
Speaker 5:  and oh, that would be wild.
Speaker 1:  That'd be great. I
Speaker 2:  Don't even know what you're talking about. That seems crazy.
Speaker 1:  And then you would have them and you wouldn't be like renting them anyway.
Speaker 1:  So that's Netflix. I suspect Netflix will be fine.
Speaker 2:  Stranger things is coming. So Netflix is going to be fine.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Stranger things is coming. All those people will come back.
Speaker 5:  Sweet games got renewed.
Speaker 2:  Everybody dies again.
Speaker 5:  They're just going to resurrect everybody who knows.
Speaker 1:  Oh, it's just seemed like they need hits. Right. TV is a hits business. Netflix
Speaker 1:  needs more hits apple TV. Severance is a hit. Right. But we have no
Speaker 1:  idea if it's actually a hit,
Speaker 5:  It's a hit in the verge newsroom. That's it?
Speaker 2:  It's it's. I mean, it's the best. It should be a hit everywhere. If it's
Speaker 2:  not, I will, I will go to the grave telling people to watch severance, but
Speaker 2:  it does make me think, like, I wonder if the other half of the
Speaker 2:  strategy, which is basically like you need hits, but you also need sort of
Speaker 2:  the background, like turn off your brain television. And people have been
Speaker 2:  talking about that forever as like the thing Netflix didn't have. And Netflix
Speaker 2:  has invested really hard in that they have tons of house shows. They have
Speaker 2:  tons of food shows they have is this cake. They have all these different
Speaker 2:  kinds of like deliberately non prestige TV.
Speaker 2:  And I'm starting to wonder if that is actually the hook
Speaker 2:  to keep people that maybe a lot of people thought it was. And if we're going
Speaker 2:  to maybe get a swing away from that now,
Speaker 5:  Was it Netflix? They created the random button.
Speaker 1:  Yes they have. They have the shuffle,
Speaker 5:  The shuffle, like, yeah. They just invented TV channels.
Speaker 1:  The shuffle is great, but you need the, I watch this, but don't count it
Speaker 1:  button. Like that's actually way more important than the shuffle button.
Speaker 1:  The I'm so sorry. So we should, we should pivot to discovery because that
Speaker 1:  idea that you'll have all the background noise, big part of the discovery
Speaker 1:  strategy. Yep. They make a lot of that stuff. They have it
Speaker 1:  all. It's on discovery plus. And they just bought Warner
Speaker 1:  media Warner media on CNN,
Speaker 1:  CNN plus launched less than a month ago, under 80 and T
Speaker 1:  the story. So it goes is a discovery did not
Speaker 1:  want CNN plus to launch, but they were legally prohibited
Speaker 1:  from telling anyone at 18 T had a manage the business before the
Speaker 1:  deal.
Speaker 2:  So instead they had to talk very publicly about their pants.
Speaker 2:  It actually makes a lot of sense in retrospect, right? Cause they gave an
Speaker 2:  unusual number of interviews in the run-up to all of this happening. Being
Speaker 2:  like here is what we think the future should look like
Speaker 2:  just to no one in particular, just like standing outside the office and
Speaker 2:  screaming. Like here's what I think.
Speaker 1:  So the deal closes it's less than a month I'd ever seen him plus, and they
Speaker 1:  shut it down today. They said, it's going to be over on April 3rd. The thing
Speaker 1:  lasted 29, 23
Speaker 5:  Days,
Speaker 1:  23 days is today. But it's, you know, it's got like seven more.
Speaker 2:  It'll be like 31 by the time it dies.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. So a full month virtual virtuous listeners may know I'll reintroduce
Speaker 1:  everyone to this concept. Verizon was the first to doom
Speaker 1:  streaming services. They want you to think called go 90. It was so named
Speaker 1:  because when you watch a video on your phone, you're supposed to turn your
Speaker 1:  phone to landscape. Verizon. The phone company did not
Speaker 1:  think about portrait video when they watched their streaming service.
Speaker 1:  So they're like, everyone's gonna turn their phones, go 90, say launched
Speaker 1:  this weird mishmash of a YouTube competitor. And they bought a bunch of cheap
Speaker 1:  crap. If they called it go 90, they spent 80 billion or $80 million in this.
Speaker 1:  They said it was a bet, the company moment. And it just collapsed into
Speaker 1:  dust. We did an amazing story in video on it. Ben
Speaker 1:  popper, when he still worked here, that's how that was for us. And it's ready
Speaker 1:  to show you. It's sexy side
Speaker 1:  all time headline. It was nuts. The whole thing was nuts.
Speaker 1:  This thus was born to the go 90 scale of doom streaming services,
Speaker 1:  which goes from zero to 90. 90 is death when you've gone
Speaker 1:  90.
Speaker 2:  So Netflix is like a two. We would say
Speaker 1:  Netflix was for a long time, lived at one.
Speaker 2:  Okay,
Speaker 1:  Great. Every streaming service is doomed. That's like,
Speaker 1:  this is the underlying conceit of the whole thing. It's just like how close
Speaker 1:  to 90 are you? So Netflix for years it was like, was it one
Speaker 1:  YouTube? Is it one right? You're you're still doomed. Well, we're just
Speaker 1:  not anywhere close to yet. Right? Like nothing gets to zero. Cause
Speaker 1:  everyone, you know, time is relentless.
Speaker 1:  Death comes for us. All right. So Netflix and YouTube were always kind of
Speaker 1:  at one Quimbee started life at
Speaker 2:  80
Speaker 5:  And just quickly,
Speaker 1:  Quickly progressed itself
Speaker 2:  Tonight. I think 80 was generous as it turned
Speaker 5:  Out, very generous.
Speaker 1:  We, you know, we had a meeting with cats. He was very
Speaker 1:  convincing. So I, so CNN plus fastest
Speaker 1:  time to 90, it
Speaker 5:  Did a speed run
Speaker 2:  By a wide margin
Speaker 1:  Launched at 85 left us 23 days later at night,
Speaker 5:  It could be lasted like eight months and see it in plus couldn't last a
Speaker 5:  month.
Speaker 1:  So I encourage, if you have thoughts about where other streaming services
Speaker 1:  are on the go 90 scale of doom streaming services, you can tweet them at
Speaker 1:  me. I'm reckless. You can tweet them at David. He's a Pierce. Alex is illustrates
Speaker 1:  Krantz. Just let us know. Cause once you start thinking of these companies
Speaker 1:  in this way, you quickly realize like, oh, they're all on it.
Speaker 2:  We need a thing on the verge.com where you can make your own slider. Will
Speaker 2:  it give you a bunch of, you can put them on there.
Speaker 1:  So Paul Miller made one for us. It's still up. It's gone.
Speaker 1:  ninety.biz.
Speaker 2:  That's amazing.
Speaker 1:  It's not great. It's really not great. He refused to
Speaker 1:  label the chart, which isn't a real virtue. It's
Speaker 1:  still, it's still works. You can look at it. You can be like, oh, voodoo
Speaker 1:  that's oh, we're at 90. It's fun to do. We're
Speaker 1:  going to make another one. But right now, so I would put the things that
Speaker 1:  are closest to life. One, I would put ATRIO max at like a one, like
Speaker 1:  it's gonna survive. Netflix is like maybe at a
Speaker 1:  five now. Right? Like it had a bad quarter. They need to rejigger.
Speaker 1:  It's the first time they've moved off of that spot. Disney plus is looking
Speaker 1:  like a, you know, they've got actually challenges. They've got investors
Speaker 1:  worried about the reorg. We just had Julia Alexander on decoder.
Speaker 1:  Like they've had to pull off a lot of things. That's not a one that's also
Speaker 1:  looking like a five. So like, I just think this market is so hard and so
Speaker 1:  competitive. And they were all betting on endless growth and people signing
Speaker 1:  up for streaming. And what they're kind of getting is like, people have a
Speaker 1:  finite amount of money for entertainment and they're not just going to leave
Speaker 1:  these subscriptions on forever. They're just going to quit on you unless
Speaker 1:  you have something great to show them. And what you have is moon night. Well,
Speaker 1:  you better hope you have blue in the background because
Speaker 2:  That's well, and part of it is also, I think that the last two years
Speaker 2:  in retrospect kind of screwed them all because they all grew so fast.
Speaker 2:  And everybody's memory is so short that it was like, oh,
Speaker 2:  explosive growth for two years because no one went outside. That's the
Speaker 2:  future forever. And ever. And then you get a little bit of retrenchment
Speaker 2:  back to like where these companies would have
Speaker 2:  gone. If they had gone on a normal trajectory for the last couple of years
Speaker 2:  and people start to panic. So it's like the, the, the whip sighing of it,
Speaker 5:  200,000 people were the ones with lives. They've overturned.
Speaker 2:  They've have all gone outside now.
Speaker 1:  And the people who went to HBO, max, cause they wanted to watch a
Speaker 1:  square version of justice league black and white for
Speaker 2:  Nine hours.
Speaker 1:  The greatest money ATG has ever spent straight up the fact that at
Speaker 1:  and T paid for Zack Snyder to make a 43 black and
Speaker 1:  white version of justice league will go down in history as the best money
Speaker 1:  any phone company has ever spent. Like it's like
Speaker 1:  unbelievable that that happened. So CNN plus
Speaker 1:  discovery shuts it down. They have this meeting, the new guy who runs
Speaker 1:  CNN plus Chris Licht. He's a discovery guy because Jeff Zucker was pushed
Speaker 1:  out by Warner media. He said they had built a beautiful house, but
Speaker 1:  then this is a quote. Then the new owner came in and said, what a beautiful
Speaker 1:  house, but I need an apartment that doesn't take anything away from this
Speaker 1:  beautiful house you built. I am proud of you. And I am proud of this team,
Speaker 1:  but I am gutted by what this means for you. And what he means is burning
Speaker 1:  down your house.
Speaker 2:  You built such a good house.
Speaker 1:  I have no choice, but to torch it in discovery's whole
Speaker 1:  strategy is like basically bundling CNN plus into HBO,
Speaker 1:  max bundling, ATRIO max with discovery plus and
Speaker 1:  creating kind of David where you're talking about. She's like a super app
Speaker 1:  of content that is always on that has the first run movies that
Speaker 1:  has the kind of like background home shows
Speaker 1:  that has potentially live news. That's a cable bundle in
Speaker 1:  there. They want to make that.
Speaker 2:  And this is the thing that the discovery executives have been unusually forthcoming
Speaker 2:  about over the last few months. Like typically in a case like this, where
Speaker 2:  you have a big merger coming and it's, it's one of, it's two of the biggest
Speaker 2:  players in streaming. Everybody's kind of coy about what they're up to, right?
Speaker 2:  Like they don't usually have a lot of incentive to like roll out their grand
Speaker 2:  plan. But over and over discovered executives just kept getting up there
Speaker 2:  being like, we think bundling is the answer. We are going to
Speaker 2:  have one app and like mincing, no
Speaker 2:  words about it. They were like, yeah, we think the best future for discovery
Speaker 2:  plus and HBO max is if they are one thing and given the way this company
Speaker 2:  works, it will be called discovery. Plus HBO, max, CNN. It's like,
Speaker 2:  that will be the name of this app
Speaker 1:  Disco max plus.
Speaker 5:  It's interesting because for them bundling is like just a path to, to the
Speaker 5:  merging. And like Disney is over there. Disney's been bubbling for a while.
Speaker 5:  They've got Hulu and ESPN plus and everything together. And like they have
Speaker 5:  zero interest in combining all of those together.
Speaker 1:  So they do so in markets that are not the United States, Hulu is basically
Speaker 1:  integrated in Disney plus, which leads to very weird moments inside the Disney
Speaker 1:  plus app where it's like, whoa, that's a little spicy for Disney.
Speaker 1:  Plus
Speaker 5:  We call it also like stars plus and a lot of markets.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Cause they've got that. They've had another whole content arm. That's
Speaker 1:  international.
Speaker 5:  They're partially doing it in the United States at least because they want
Speaker 5:  everybody to still think of Disney as like for princesses and superheroes.
Speaker 5:  And they want Hulu to be for adults.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. But I'm saying if you leave the United States and you open Disney,
Speaker 1:  plus there's a real chance it's going, gonna be like Pam and Tommy is here.
Speaker 1:  That's weird. She's not a Disney princess.
Speaker 5:  She could be.
Speaker 1:  I remember she is at this point,
Speaker 5:  Aspirational,
Speaker 1:  But know Disney. The United States right now is like undergoing this massive
Speaker 1:  culture war attack that might be destroying that like they're in a tough
Speaker 1:  spot with that bundle, but they also sort of acquired
Speaker 1:  their way into that bundle. Like they launched the Hulu is like a part
Speaker 1:  ownership. They can't integrate it. Now they have more of its catalog. You
Speaker 1:  can see where they're going over time. ESPN is going to be its own thing.
Speaker 1:  Always. I think, anyway, this is all just shaking out. I feel bad for the
Speaker 1:  people at CNN, although they did cover their own streaming service
Speaker 1:  launch, just like a completely ridiculous way. Fair. I feel bad.
Speaker 1:  We should feel bad. They're laying people off. People are going to have to
Speaker 1:  find new jobs inside of that company. Or
Speaker 5:  400 people got laid off, I think.
Speaker 1:  Is that the number? So that's all bad, but 23 days
Speaker 1:  in just a catastrophe of corporate miscommunication.
Speaker 1:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Well, and that's the thing. And I think it's like, it's, it's important to
Speaker 2:  note here and it's kind of a bummer that this is the case that this isn't
Speaker 2:  actually really about the performance of CNN. Plus like if CNN plus has come
Speaker 2:  out and gotten 50 million subscribers in the first month, like we might be
Speaker 2:  having a different conversation, but we also might not be because like, even,
Speaker 2:  even in the course of making these announcements, they've been very clear
Speaker 2:  that like this was bad strategy. This goes against
Speaker 2:  what this newly combined company wants to do. And it basically
Speaker 2:  sounds like, like you were saying, they didn't want them to launch it at
Speaker 2:  all. Jason Kylar and the CNN team, like two middle fingers to
Speaker 2:  discovery decided to launch it anyway on the premise that if we've already
Speaker 2:  launched it, they can't possibly shut it down. And then they said, oh, watch
Speaker 2:  this and then shut it down. And so it's like, I don't know that it has anything
Speaker 2:  to do with the streaming service. It's this weird, like C-suite fight that
Speaker 2:  just spilled out into shutting down CNN plus, which is
Speaker 2:  crazy.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. In the middle of all this Jeff sucker who ran CNN
Speaker 1:  was one presumes. If he had launched it and was it
Speaker 1:  discovery, Warner media or whatever, it's called. Things may have gone
Speaker 1:  differently because he was just a personality. But he got run out of there
Speaker 1:  to like right
Speaker 2:  And discovered. It was also reportedly mad that he got run out the way that
Speaker 2:  he did like the whole process. They seem to do all this stuff before
Speaker 2:  they had new overlords and the new overlords were not fans.
Speaker 1:  Maybe I need to rename the chart to like the Jeff Zucker Memorial doing the
Speaker 1:  streaming service.
Speaker 1:  I'm going to say, we'd go 90 a pioneer in the field of doom streaming services.
Speaker 1:  Remember kids, when you watch a video go 90,
Speaker 1:  We should very quickly talk about like the other side of the streaming world,
Speaker 1:  which is podcasts that is undergoing change to Spotify as head
Speaker 1:  of podcasts left Courtney Holt. He was the one who brought
Speaker 1:  in Joe Rogan's and other deals notably signed the Obama deal,
Speaker 1:  a Bama leaving Spotify for another as yet unannounced deal. A
Speaker 1:  lot of those deals have not borne fruit, right. They, they bought themselves
Speaker 1:  a sort of, always on Joe Rogan noise machine. And
Speaker 1:  like, sometimes it's like louder and sometimes it's quieter, but it's always
Speaker 1:  on, there's just always a level of white noise coming out of the Joe Rogan
Speaker 1:  machine that they bought.
Speaker 5:  Have we gotten the Harry and Meghan podcasts that they bought?
Speaker 1:  No, but they, they like assigned people to it
Speaker 2:  And they make like one episode and then never again. And now supposedly they're
Speaker 2:  doing it for real.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Like our 12 media, their thing is going to do something. So the person
Speaker 1:  who signed all these deals is leaving. The Obama's are leaving and they're
Speaker 1:  opening up. They bought this tool called anchor, which is their like user
Speaker 1:  generated podcasting tool. Now anchors and let you start
Speaker 1:  uploading video podcasts ever in the United States and other markets. I would
Speaker 1:  just say that on the spectrum of companies that have figured out their
Speaker 1:  approach to content moderation, there's YouTube, which is like,
Speaker 1:  kind of figured it out still not great because content moderation is unsolved.
Speaker 1:  And then way over there across the ocean in a
Speaker 1:  volcano is Spotify being like, we don't know what we're doing.
Speaker 5:  We're a tech company,
Speaker 1:  The combo platter of unmoderated open podcasting and
Speaker 1:  unmoderated video is just going to open them up to a
Speaker 1:  world of chaos. So we will see how this goes.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. It's, it's going to be a mess. I will say. I think there's this really
Speaker 2:  interesting race happening right now where YouTube is pretty clearly investing
Speaker 2:  in like the audio experience based on the theory that a lot of
Speaker 2:  people want to watch podcasts. And a lot of people wanna listen to podcasts.
Speaker 2:  And I feel like, I think that's pretty clearly real and YouTube is trying
Speaker 2:  to solve how to transition into like an audio first
Speaker 2:  experience while Spotify is trying to figure out how to make video work.
Speaker 2:  And if I were a betting man, I would, I would push all of my
Speaker 2:  chips in the YouTube side of that fight. But I think spot, I
Speaker 2:  think this is the right thing for Spotify to do. I think the moderation is
Speaker 2:  gonna be a mess and Spotify is approach. It has an approach. It is chilling
Speaker 2:  in a volcano, but its approach is to chill in the volcano and hope you don't
Speaker 2:  notice. And to say, we think moderation is important and then
Speaker 2:  disappear into the wilderness.
Speaker 1:  Here's what I'll tell you again. I decoders a podcast with org charts. It's
Speaker 1:  like, that's the secret of Dakota. It's just me being like, what's your org
Speaker 1:  chart. And then like asking a lot of questions. YouTube is moderation. It's
Speaker 1:  run by the head of product, trust and safety at YouTube reports to
Speaker 1:  the head of product it's in the product organization. So unique arrangement
Speaker 1:  and all the tack, it's like 50, 50, you know, but like product is
Speaker 1:  like a meaningful place for that to live. That's on the roadmaps that is
Speaker 1:  literally baked into the product of YouTube, Spotify, trust and
Speaker 1:  safety reports to coms.
Speaker 1:  I don't know about that, man. It's just like one of those
Speaker 1:  things, like I can just tell you that maybe all the people are great, whatever,
Speaker 1:  but just that structure is like, you think this is a comms PR you think there's
Speaker 1:  a PR problem, not a product problem. And like, I can just tell you
Speaker 1:  that based on where you've put it.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And they very clearly do. And that's been their response even to Joe
Speaker 2:  Rogan, things like that. They see it sort of as a, as a hurdle to get past,
Speaker 2:  not as a problem to solve.
Speaker 1:  I was just like interesting that they're still chasing after it. And they
Speaker 1:  are the 800 pound gorilla in podcasting. They seem to
Speaker 1:  be driving a lot of things, but they true that they have not figured it out.
Speaker 2:  Definitely true. But the good news for them is I don't know that anyone has
Speaker 2:  like pot, the podcasting infrastructure across the whole internet is still
Speaker 2:  such a disaster that like Spotify should be better at it. But
Speaker 2:  I don't know that it's behind, which is so crazy.
Speaker 1:  Let's take this to say that if you're interested in podcasts, we have a paid
Speaker 1:  newsletter about the podcast industry called hotpot insider. She has a free
Speaker 1:  edition every week called, but you can just sign up for it. We just hired
Speaker 1:  a great new reporter for it is Ariel Shapiro. She's amazing. We're going
Speaker 1:  to be, you'll see her on the verge assay That shameless plug for our own
Speaker 1:  work is a good time to take a break. We get to talk about some guidance.
Speaker 1:  We'll be right back
Speaker 1:  Email. It's the tried and true method of communication for just about everyone.
Speaker 1:  But if you're a top company trying to compete in today's business landscape,
Speaker 1:  you need better than regular email. You need a superpower kind of email for
Speaker 1:  modern companies. That's Mailgun by cinch a platform it's straightforward
Speaker 1:  and made great by world-class support and incredibly powerful APIs
Speaker 1:  sending in tracking or transactional and marketing messages with Mailgun
Speaker 1:  is easy. And there's no room for excess, either as it prevents fake signups
Speaker 1:  and removes invalid email addresses from your list quickly, plus Mailgun
Speaker 1:  is proven. They empower leading brands from all over the world to solve complex
Speaker 1:  communications problems, their powerful email API and intuitive email marketing
Speaker 1:  solutions allow you to control your entire email life cycle from the email
Speaker 1:  testing stage through delivery and their send time optimization capability
Speaker 1:  automatically finds the ideal send time for every recipient on your list
Speaker 1:  and sends your message when they are most likely to engage. Cinch delivers
Speaker 1:  over 240 billion emails each year for businesses of all sizes
Speaker 1:  from fortune 50 brands to entrepreneurial startups. Discover why it's so
Speaker 1:  easy to build connected experiences. Start sending with Mailgun by
Speaker 1:  cinch today, visit mailgun.com to learn more.
Speaker 2:  By now you've probably heard of the recent surge in gas and grocery prices.
Speaker 2:  Statistically speaking this 7.9% inflation rate is the highest since
Speaker 2:  1982. So you may be looking to save money wherever you can. Well, good
Speaker 2:  RX is here to ease a bit of the stress on your wallet with good RX. You can
Speaker 2:  instantly compare prescription prices at pharmacies in your neighborhood
Speaker 2:  and find discounts that could save you up to 80%. It's free and easy to use
Speaker 2:  and works whether or not you have insurance. Even if you do have insurance,
Speaker 2:  good RX may actually beat your copay price. Check out good RX online or
Speaker 2:  in their app to find prescription savings at pharmacies such as CVS, Kroger,
Speaker 2:  Walgreens, Rite aid, Vons, Walmart, and more. So for simple, smart
Speaker 2:  savings on your prescriptions check. Good RX. Go to good
Speaker 2:  rx.com/verge. That's good.
Speaker 2:  rx.com/verge. Good RX is not insurance, but can be used in
Speaker 2:  place of insurance, Medicare and Medicaid in 2021. Good RX users saved
Speaker 2:  81% on retail prescription prices.
Speaker 1:  All right. We're back. Chris Welch has joined us. Hello
Speaker 8:  Everyone.
Speaker 1:  We just said 45 minutes of corporate streaming strategy. So it's time to
Speaker 1:  clear our pallets old-fashioned gadget scoop.
Speaker 1:  Chris is scooped a new soundbar from Sonus. Tell us what's going on.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, so I don't know what it's called just yet. That's the one thing they
Speaker 8:  can actually say for the announcement.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, I see a shit
Speaker 8:  That's similar to Patrick. Spence is just staring at the wall in his office.
Speaker 8:  Very
Speaker 1:  Frustrated. He's got a picture of you up on that wall.
Speaker 8:  So it's going to be their cheapest soundbar yet. Actually it's going to cost
Speaker 8:  $249 and it's smaller than the beam, which means it's pretty tiny. Cause
Speaker 8:  like seeing the beam in person is like, you just, it's a tiny little soundbar
Speaker 8:  and this one is four inches smaller. So it's got quite a few less drivers.
Speaker 8:  There's no Atmos, you know, there's no Mike's built in. So it's going to
Speaker 8:  be like a pretty rudimentary, just TBM music soundbar and it'll come out
Speaker 8:  sometime in June. I believe. So there are photos on the site, take a look.
Speaker 8:  So I think they're just going after that really cheap market, like videos
Speaker 8:  and you know, like Roku and TCL, soundbars and, and that's who they're really
Speaker 8:  going for with this.
Speaker 5:  I get taking out the microphones and a lot of the other processing and stuff.
Speaker 5:  Cause it doesn't do Atmos, but why go so small? Because
Speaker 5:  the whole point of speakers is the bigger, the better the sound couldn't
Speaker 5:  they do bigger speakers without jacking up the price. Oh
Speaker 8:  No. I think they just see this as like for pretty, fairly small TVs. Same
Speaker 8:  as the beam. So if you've got like a giant sixty-five or like 75 inch TV,
Speaker 8:  you go for the arch. If you've got something smaller, you go for one of these
Speaker 8:  two.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, because these are like 20, you have you're in the measurements.
Speaker 5:  550 millimeters width. And the beam two is 651.
Speaker 5:  That's like 25 inches. I definitely searched that guys. I do
Speaker 5:  not just switch between millimeters and inches. And my head is
Speaker 2:  To be very impressive. I
Speaker 5:  Was, I had to let everybody know, but yeah, that's like, that's a
Speaker 5:  tiny baby of a speaker.
Speaker 8:  It's a tiny little thing. And one of the things is as there's a new Mount
Speaker 8:  for there, so you can Mount it vertically. And so they think people are going
Speaker 8:  to like buy two of these, to use what the arch as like rear surrounds. And
Speaker 8:  if you look closely at the image, you'll see like the tweeters are like curved.
Speaker 8:  So like when you Mount it vertically, it might do a better job of like just
Speaker 8:  sending audio upwards toward the ceiling. Like something like a one SL or
Speaker 8:  one of those speakers. So if you want to spend $500,
Speaker 1:  Oh I see us again, bounce off the ceiling.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. On your surrounds.
Speaker 5:  So you would use these instead of like right now, if you're really
Speaker 5:  into building a 5.1 Sonos system, because you have all the money
Speaker 5:  in the world, you would do like two Sonos fives. Right.
Speaker 5:  And now you'll be able to do these much cheaper actually built for
Speaker 5:  movie audio.
Speaker 1:  Well, yeah, the best part of this entire Sonos thing is like anything you
Speaker 1:  can have like lamps, the surrounds cause they make the speaker lamps
Speaker 8:  Picture frames.
Speaker 1:  But this is like soon they're going after like the dorm room market or like
Speaker 1:  the second bedroom market here.
Speaker 2:  What is the state of that market right now? I feel like it's, it's been a
Speaker 2:  while since I bought a soundbar, but my impression of it is like, you can
Speaker 2:  get a pretty good soundbar at this point for not a lot of money. Like does
Speaker 2:  Sonos have a move here?
Speaker 8:  I mean, I think they want to have a move. I think busy was kind of own this
Speaker 8:  whole space for years and now they've got like Roku and you know, some other
Speaker 8:  companies like TCL coming in as well with like, you know, $99,
Speaker 8:  $150 soundbars and Sonos won't go quite that low. It seems like they're kind
Speaker 8:  of like apple in that they will only go so low for a product price, but two
Speaker 8:  50 for a Sono soundbar. Now it sounds like a pretty good gateway.
Speaker 2:  So it does definitely does have the shiny brand where like, I think if you
Speaker 2:  just, if you just show people a Vizio thing and a Sonos thing, they'll mostly
Speaker 2:  just assume the Sonos thing is better.
Speaker 1:  The vision thing is always really funny cause they will like the Vizio
Speaker 1:  soundbars are fine. They sound really good. Some of them great, but like
Speaker 1:  the classic one is like, you know, the long box with a big hump for the
Speaker 1:  subwoofer. Yep. Or like here's like half a dozen weird
Speaker 1:  little speakers with like the fiddly wires
Speaker 2:  And it sort of hangs off the edge of your TV stand. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  And then like people buy them. People have always bought those kids. Like,
Speaker 1:  but that's like we're Vizio. I think Sonos wants to be that sort of like
Speaker 1:  premium plug it in once we just assume that over time you
Speaker 1:  will have more money and have more rooms in your house. And we'll just follow
Speaker 1:  you along that chain.
Speaker 5:  I'm still going back to the fact that it doesn't have microphones. Cause
Speaker 5:  it seems like Sonos kind of finally abandoning, oh, we're going to be
Speaker 5:  the voice assistant hub in your home.
Speaker 8:  I don't know. I think like the other two do have like spelt in and also like
Speaker 8:  they make like the arch SL you can buy at Costco that like doesn't have Mike's
Speaker 8:  there just some people who like don't want
Speaker 5:  Right. That like, they, they make a lot of those now, but this is like a
Speaker 5:  new speaker from them. This is one of the first speakers I think we've seen
Speaker 5:  from them without these microphones. So it's like,
Speaker 1:  They make the one SL then make the ARCA. So they've been pretty clear. Like
Speaker 1:  some people do not want more microphones in their house
Speaker 1:  If you're, and I think they've also learned like, what do people do with
Speaker 1:  microphones? They ask for music. And so like, it's, it's actually kind of
Speaker 1:  like odd to have it in your sound bar. Maybe this one would have
Speaker 1:  worked, but like that's how you get the price down. The thing that really
Speaker 1:  gets me about this whole thing is we've also seen all these rumors that they're
Speaker 1:  hiring people for like a home theater. Oh, us.
Speaker 1:  Right. And they've put up job listings. They've been tweeting about
Speaker 1:  it. Some of their employees have been tweeting about it that like, this is
Speaker 1:  just a regular plug in a sandbar to your arc port off you go. There's
Speaker 1:  no operating system or anything. But that next big move from
Speaker 1:  Sonos has got to be either a streaming box,
Speaker 1:  a smart soundbar, or, you know, I'm going to say now the
Speaker 1:  TV, every company should make a TV.
Speaker 2:  Everyone should see the face. Chris is making right now. Like when you said
Speaker 2:  the O S Chris got like visibly excited,
Speaker 1:  Do you think it's really TV? I think it's really TV.
Speaker 8:  I don't want a TV. I just want a cheaper subwoofer man. And apparently are
Speaker 8:  working on that. The sub mini. And it would make sense to have that come
Speaker 8:  out with this at the same time. I think. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Because right now it's like $700 for a Sono sub
Speaker 5:  that's
Speaker 8:  Absurd.
Speaker 5:  It's really, really good. It sounds amazing.
Speaker 8:  $250 soundbar. Now you just have to buy a $700 of warfare to go with,
Speaker 1:  But there's a lot of people online that will find a ways to hack other subs.
Speaker 1:  And they're working with sense. Like you can there, I will just be
Speaker 1:  careful kids. Like you're going to break up that soldering iron. You're going
Speaker 1:  to disassemble a one Sonos, one SL or like
Speaker 1:  my Kia lamp to make her sub before. We're just like, be careful. I'm
Speaker 1:  just adding value. Save yourself. Yeah. But the idea that they need to expand
Speaker 1:  their market, I mean, this is kinda what we're saying, that this is a super
Speaker 1:  competitive market. They can make cheaper products and get a new base of
Speaker 1:  people. But at the end of the day, they're always plugging into somebody
Speaker 1:  else's TV. They're always at somebody else's mercy, somebody else's
Speaker 1:  streaming box. There's only one answer, man. Patrick, if you're listening,
Speaker 1:  make me that Ola TV,
Speaker 5:  It's going to be the box. It's going to be the streaming box.
Speaker 2:  It's going to be the box.
Speaker 1:  You think it's a box.
Speaker 2:  It's gotta be a box. Like a, I think Sonos has a lot to gain
Speaker 2:  from a future where you have dumb screens and smart boxes
Speaker 2:  and would be very interested in being those smart boxes. I
Speaker 2:  also think that is the correct future. Like stop selling me smart TVs,
Speaker 2:  sell me smart boxes and dumb screens. That will last me a decade. No,
Speaker 1:  One's going to sell you a dumb screen.
Speaker 2:  I know. And I would, I wish they would. And maybe Sonos will.
Speaker 5:  We want you to buy a new TV every time your screen gets too dumb.
Speaker 2:  Third Roku update. I have to buy a new television. It's fantastic. But no,
Speaker 2:  I also just think like if I'm Sonos, the TV
Speaker 2:  market is a mess, especially right now, and it's not going to
Speaker 2:  get better quickly. And like they could build
Speaker 2:  better home theater software without trying very hard, because most of it
Speaker 2:  is trash and Sonus has a pretty good track record of building good software
Speaker 2:  and then put it in a box and sell it to the same kinds of people who would
Speaker 2:  buy something like this. And that feels like Sona seems to just be
Speaker 2:  relentlessly pushing down in the market. And that feels like where it
Speaker 2:  thinks all its growth is. And I don't know that Neela has all led TV assaults
Speaker 2:  that
Speaker 1:  I let me make the opposite problem. We'll let crispy the judge. You ready?
Speaker 1:  Okay. Yeah. There's the opposite argument selling a box in a
Speaker 1:  market where Roku and Amazon will just give you one for
Speaker 1:  free. And they are already, the market leaders is
Speaker 1:  stupid, Right? Like you like blink at
Speaker 1:  Amazon. You're like, huh? I'm interested in bookstore. They're like, have
Speaker 1:  you heard about prime TV? Here's one.
Speaker 2:  That one just appears at your
Speaker 1:  Door. It's just like happened to you. Right? Roku. Like their entire business
Speaker 1:  is giving away that hardware for is cheapest possible and subsidizing with
Speaker 1:  ads and all this other stuff they want to do being in a business where you're
Speaker 1:  selling a box and you've got to make a new software experience. And you're
Speaker 1:  still just kind of at the end of the day, just like looking at your same
Speaker 1:  old TV. That's not like Sonus.
Speaker 1:  Sonus is like experience and like the
Speaker 1:  speakers. I, you know, I have a lot of Sonos speakers. I think they're great.
Speaker 1:  I think the company is great. I think it all works great, but they're not
Speaker 1:  the best sounding speakers you can get. Always.
Speaker 5:  No, they're actually not that great. Like I currently have a
Speaker 5:  5.1 Sonos system and almost every night I spend way
Speaker 5:  too much time trying to figure out what bookshelves, speakers, or
Speaker 5:  giant towers I'm going to get to replace it and move from like 5.1 to two,
Speaker 5:  because all the home theater nerds are like, you know what your speakers
Speaker 5:  suck. And I truly believe them. I like haven't heard
Speaker 5:  comparisons,
Speaker 1:  But like you're on the AVS.
Speaker 5:  Like convinced me, man. I'm like, no, I get it. I get it.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Like a, a great 2.1 system is better than a son. That's why for me,
Speaker 1:  like, I've been there.
Speaker 5:  I'm like, I'm there right now. The only reason I haven't done it is because
Speaker 5:  I have neighbors and I don't think they would be as excited about my new
Speaker 5:  speakers as I will be.
Speaker 1:  But what I'm saying is Sonos owns the brand in the best buy
Speaker 1:  of one of the best things you can buy that has a complete experience. It
Speaker 1:  makes you fancy and trying to sell, like trying to hock
Speaker 1:  some box at people. That's like, that's why he got to build the
Speaker 1:  TV and be like, this is the best TV you can get. Cause it has our brand on
Speaker 1:  it and it's got our software in it. And then you sell a lot of
Speaker 1:  those. And then he go to the atrium acts of the world. And like, you want
Speaker 1:  to be on our TV. Cause everyone likes you. You got to pass the money. No,
Speaker 5:  It's going to be a box. It's going to be a really, it's going to be the
Speaker 5:  Cabo was at Cabo. The HTMI for us. Well, we
Speaker 8:  Were promised,
Speaker 1:  But the Cabo has not pivoted to a, like a assistive tech for older people,
Speaker 1:  I think. Oh,
Speaker 2:  That's
Speaker 5:  Awesome.
Speaker 1:  I get an email from them every now and again, being like you can't wait to
Speaker 1:  show you. And I'm like, okay, if we can, I would love to see a software update
Speaker 1:  for the one I bought my mom. Look, I'm just saying, if you're going to build
Speaker 1:  that thing the way to package it, isn't a new kind of, isn't a TV people
Speaker 1:  like things. If you, if you send us some Android TV box with a skin on it,
Speaker 1:  like, come on, don't be doing that. All right,
Speaker 1:  Chris, you've heard the arguments. You're the judge. Which way do you
Speaker 1:  think it's going?
Speaker 8:  I don't know if it's a sound idea, but I go with the TV,
Speaker 1:  Gotta be the TV,
Speaker 8:  But first we'll come this in June. And then these headphones that they've
Speaker 8:  been working on for years apparently are taking quite a long time, hit the
Speaker 8:  market. So hopefully those will be,
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I'm no longer convinced. That's real. I think it's, it's just, I've
Speaker 2:  given up on. So, and I said, we're making headphones.
Speaker 8:  I think there are challenges there. Like how do you do handoff from like
Speaker 8:  headphones to a speaker to that phones have wifi. Like where do you go from
Speaker 8:  there? So I think there's a lot to figure out in terms of like that
Speaker 5:  Headphones always just seemed very stupid. Like that always just seemed like
Speaker 5:  a bad idea. It just from the beginning, it's like, we're going to do
Speaker 5:  we're in speakers. So we're going to go for tiny speakers on your ears.
Speaker 1:  No, this is like the Dyson story. Dyson's like we invented a fan. What things
Speaker 1:  suck or blow. We'll just make all of those things.
Speaker 1:  It's up to say like when Dyson was like, we're going to do a car, like they
Speaker 1:  quicker the, I was like, oh, the fan is not the most important part of
Speaker 1:  we're way up for taps guys. Fan powered cars are never
Speaker 5:  Just blowing across the highway.
Speaker 1:  Oh boy, this prototype is not what we thought was going to
Speaker 5:  Be loud.
Speaker 1:  It's like 500 air apps like it on the back of the tape. I said, it's
Speaker 5:  Going in circles.
Speaker 2:  Sounds amazing though. All
Speaker 1:  Right. So, which I think ended
Speaker 1:  in the only place, it could be a bunch of other gadget stuff. David, you
Speaker 1:  were really taken with a story still thinking about the civic
Speaker 1:  fans. I apologize, David, you were quite taken with this story about
Speaker 1:  LG leaving and how it benefited Samsung. I just
Speaker 2:  Think it was fascinating. So basically the thrust of the story was
Speaker 1:  This Allison Johnson story. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. She went to find out basically what happened to the
Speaker 2:  smartphone market after LG left and did a bunch of really
Speaker 2:  great reporting, found out a bunch virtual, really funny stuff, and essentially
Speaker 2:  got to the end of it. And it was like, well it was already a two horse race
Speaker 2:  and now it is still a two horse race. And
Speaker 2:  The thing that was so striking to me is like, it just made me realize like
Speaker 2:  those of us who cover phones, we think about it as this like big
Speaker 2:  teaming market, full of lots of companies. And you have the big guys, you
Speaker 2:  have the challengers and the actual like facts on the ground are that there
Speaker 2:  are apple and there are, is Samsung. And absolutely nobody else matters.
Speaker 2:  And they come and they go and everybody gets really excited about one
Speaker 2:  plus. And then nobody buys one plus phones and we all move on with our lives.
Speaker 2:  And it just it's, it's also really incredible hat to
Speaker 2:  me, how much of everything that happens in the Android market just accrues
Speaker 2:  to Samsung. Like it has just so decimated the rest of
Speaker 2:  that market, that anything that happens to anybody else, somehow a cruise
Speaker 2:  to Samsung. And it was just really eye-opening to read that story for me.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. It's fascinating. I mean, I like to blame carriers for this, right?
Speaker 1:  Like United States, like a carrier has to certify your phone. They've got
Speaker 1:  to approve it for the network they get in between you, but even in other
Speaker 1:  countries where there's theoretically more competition, I don't
Speaker 1:  know, kind of just a cruise to Samsung.
Speaker 2:  And all of a sudden it made me realize like Samsung has made a lot of noise
Speaker 2:  with its mid-range phones over the last couple of years. And this story really
Speaker 2:  sort of opened up why. And it's like, because Samsung realizes it's just
Speaker 2:  going to beat everyone out of the market as long as it has a phone at
Speaker 2:  the same price point. And so it's just going to have phones at every $10
Speaker 2:  from a billion-dollar foldable phone all the way down to 50
Speaker 2:  bucks. And that'll be that,
Speaker 1:  That will be that other little guys itself. We'll just talk about. And there's
Speaker 1:  a leak of the pixel. Watch we thinking it'll be next
Speaker 1:  month. That IO it's a circle.
Speaker 5:  It looks like the LG watch the really bad
Speaker 5:  LG watch from 2017. I hope that's not true.
Speaker 1:  I mean, I like it. It's got a very Google like that. Watch had already had
Speaker 1:  a very Google look to it. This watch has a very Google too. I liked that
Speaker 1:  they've added this crown every time I see a crown on a smart
Speaker 1:  watch. I think back to when apple announced the apple watch,
Speaker 5:  They invented it. You know,
Speaker 1:  We were told that the digital crown was the next grade and put method
Speaker 1:  on par with the mouse and touch screen.
Speaker 5:  You don't believe it.
Speaker 2:  You can twist it and press it.
Speaker 1:  Just go back and watch that. Something like that. Obviously they have a watch.
Speaker 1:  They've rebooted it since it's very successful. People love it.
Speaker 1:  I get it. But did you go back in time and watch that and be like, oh, this
Speaker 1:  is the definition of the words I hear and supply. Like you really believe
Speaker 1:  that you invented the mouse again. I think we'll see this watch, you know,
Speaker 1:  the big question for the pixel watch always we've been hearing rumors
Speaker 1:  forever is like, can they get
Speaker 1:  the battery life? And so like just general support
Speaker 1:  that the apple watch has rounded. They do have Fitbit now we'll see, right?
Speaker 1:  Like it's been a long time coming for Android. Smartwatches
Speaker 5:  Acquired enough stuff at this point. That be kind of sad if they can't get
Speaker 5:  it right. Or at least chase apples coattails
Speaker 5:  better.
Speaker 2:  Well, and I think they've realized that the thing that apple took a
Speaker 2:  long time to realize is like, it's tell me at the time it's
Speaker 2:  due like basic dumb assistant stuff. And it's health. Like
Speaker 2:  those seem to be the things that people want from their watches. And I feel
Speaker 2:  like Google is at least as well, positioned as apple to actually successfully
Speaker 2:  do some of those things. All the other crap. I don't care about like every
Speaker 2:  time I get an apple watch, I put a million apps on it and I never use them
Speaker 2:  ever. I just want it to do like four things. And I
Speaker 2:  feel like if I'm Google and I had a, I had a long talk with a Google
Speaker 2:  executive, like years ago now about this. And they're basically like, what?
Speaker 2:  Like if you were going to make a smart watch, what would you do? And I was
Speaker 2:  like less, like much, much less. And
Speaker 2:  I, I have no idea how this will land, but just from like, if they're going
Speaker 2:  to do the simpler thing, which is kind of the move with pixel
Speaker 2:  in general, I could be into it. I don't know, Chris, what do you think? You're,
Speaker 2:  you're into dumb smartwatches as much as I am, or at least once
Speaker 2:  we're
Speaker 8:  I once was a pebble person back in the day, but I've had the apple watch
Speaker 8:  for a few years. Obviously. I think, I mean, it sounds like a good recipe,
Speaker 8:  but like you said, with phones before, the only thing that stands in their
Speaker 8:  way at Samsung, like Sam Sam's watches business does really well. And I'm
Speaker 8:  not sure like how big that market is, the people who don't want a Samsung
Speaker 8:  watch and want the pixel so-called watch. We'll see. But yeah, I think if
Speaker 8:  they go big on Fitbit stuff, that'll be a hit
Speaker 2:  It's the galaxy watch any good? I have not used it ever.
Speaker 8:  Apparently it is. People
Speaker 2:  Seem to like it. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  No, the galaxy watches like really, really good. Yeah. Victoria
Speaker 5:  song reviews, all those watches and she's still like, this is the
Speaker 5:  best Android watch you can get. It looks like a real watch for the most part.
Speaker 5:  It's huge.
Speaker 1:  See,
Speaker 2:  This is the thing, This is the bar. Like my watch, it looks like a watch.
Speaker 2:  It tells me the time it's like,
Speaker 5:  That's the bar. You don't need a lot from your watch. I mean, I was just
Speaker 5:  looking at all the apps on my watch while you're, while you're talking about
Speaker 5:  all the apps we never use. Like when was the last time you used the walkie-talkie
Speaker 5:  app?
Speaker 1:  I use it every day. What you taught your kids
Speaker 5:  Only like when you want to inflict violence on family members,
Speaker 1:  Second, you have a child and then you spend all day in your house.
Speaker 1:  Raising said, child, the walkie talkie app starts to become like a
Speaker 1:  key parenting tool. And there's literally nothing funnier than
Speaker 1:  your wrist or opting with your wife going code brown.
Speaker 1:  That was like a hilarious part of the first two years of Max's life
Speaker 1:  All the time. Yeah. We use it all the time.
Speaker 2:  I feel like that's slightly less monstrous than the people who use the drop-in
Speaker 2:  features on like Alexa devices. But it's still pretty monstrous.
Speaker 5:  I showed my mom how to use it and I had to turn it off. Cause like nine o'clock
Speaker 5:  in the morning. I just heard Hulu from my watch.
Speaker 7:  And I'm like, Nope, Nope, we're ending this.
Speaker 1:  And you got to really limit it. I'm just saying kids or pets.
Speaker 1:  It's like you're co-parenting after a child or a bet bucks.
Speaker 1:  He comes in. And what I was gonna say is there's a new
Speaker 1:  book called after Steve it's by trip Mikel. He was at the wall street journal.
Speaker 1:  And I think now he's at the times and I it's coming out May 3rd, but I
Speaker 1:  actually have a galley and a huge trumpet chocolate. This book is Johnny
Speaker 1:  Ives doing the watch. And Apple's like
Speaker 1:  journey from like fashion object to fitness object with the
Speaker 1:  watch. This is gonna make everybody mad. Like everybody is going
Speaker 1:  to be mad, but it's great. And like the report, I would say there's like
Speaker 1:  very few sources for like Johnny Ives stood alone in his house. Thinking
Speaker 1:  about the watch.
Speaker 1:  You know what I mean? Once you read this book, you're like, oh, they all
Speaker 1:  talked to him.
Speaker 1:  I don't know if that's true. I'm not going to burn trip sources. I'm just
Speaker 1:  saying there's very few sources for Johnny Ives stood alone
Speaker 2:  Fair.
Speaker 1:  And it is utterly fascinating. The story about the
Speaker 1:  inside development of the watch, it is all contained in this book. So
Speaker 2:  I wrote a story when I first joined wired, after I left the
Speaker 2:  verge, the first big thing I wrote for wired was like, it was called the
Speaker 2:  secret history of the apple watch. And I wrote, I wrote the beginning of,
Speaker 2:  one of the paragraphs was apple decided to build a watch and only then set
Speaker 2:  out to figure out what it was for an apple was mad at me about that line
Speaker 2:  for like five years.
Speaker 2:  Cause he was the opposite of what they want to tell you to do. Right. But
Speaker 2:  they were just like somebody like Johnny rolled in one day and was like,
Speaker 2:  we're going to make a watch. And they were like, what's it gonna do? And
Speaker 2:  he was like, I don't know what it's going to be. 24 karat gold.
Speaker 1:  I, again, I can't, I cannot stress enough that if you're a virtuous listener,
Speaker 1:  you will, you will love this. It will make you mad. No matter what
Speaker 1:  side of this whole thing you're on. If you're an apple fan and you're not
Speaker 1:  apple fan, you love Johnny Ivy hate Johnny. It will make you
Speaker 1:  mad
Speaker 2:  Trips, a friend. We're going to have to find some way to get him to talk
Speaker 2:  to us about the book. Oh,
Speaker 1:  We should get him to come on
Speaker 2:  The show. Yeah. That'd be fun. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  The book is great. It is just when you read, like, I'm curious for you to
Speaker 1:  take when you read it, David, like, cause if you're a reporter and editor
Speaker 1:  and you read a book like this, like you cannot help but think about how it
Speaker 1:  was sourced.
Speaker 2:  Oh,
Speaker 1:  For sure. And there's a lot of moments in this book where like, was he in
Speaker 1:  the room? Like, it's great. I cannot recommend this book enough.
Speaker 1:  I had, I read it basically in like one and a half sittings, but like it's
Speaker 1:  all about the inside of the watch. And like the core problem is what do people
Speaker 1:  want from the watch? They want fitness stuff and they wanna tell the time
Speaker 1:  I hire, if you have a smart watch and you like live a two factor life, like
Speaker 1:  any corporation in America or like you should
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Morally putting your two factor app on your watch is great. It's a little
Speaker 1:  bit like you're a secret agent, but also at the most tedious corporate bullshit,
Speaker 1:  you ever done it and have more quick gadgets off
Speaker 1:  Google assistant was supposed to roll it to the galaxy watch for that is
Speaker 1:  not happening. We reviewed the playdate, which is a super cool little
Speaker 1:  panic with a handle.
Speaker 5:  It's so tiny
Speaker 1:  Game. That thing is, it seems awesome. It's very hard to get the Andrew Webster
Speaker 1:  loved it with his
Speaker 2:  Review. I'm so excited that it's good. So excited.
Speaker 5:  If you didn't order it, you have to wait a year.
Speaker 1:  The photos from the urine are amazing. The
Speaker 5:  Photos are incredible,
Speaker 1:  Intense, new Brin reference and the deck of this little yellow, different
Speaker 1:  love that great story. They're not camera batteries for weird Sony cameras
Speaker 1:  to charge a USB-C. That's a big deal. I just want to call that out. That's
Speaker 1:  like virtuous level stuff.
Speaker 5:  That's a big deal for me personally. And it's really upsetting that it took
Speaker 5:  this long.
Speaker 1:  All right, we're cruising over. We've got to take a break. We're gonna come
Speaker 1:  back and finish this lightning round. We'll be right back.
Speaker 9:  It's easy to get sloppy. When it comes to password security in the modern
Speaker 9:  workplace employees log in and out of countless websites,
Speaker 9:  programs and apps every day, maybe have used the same password
Speaker 9:  over and over, or maybe you prefer the super secure sticky note on
Speaker 9:  monitor solution. These small shortcuts can add up to a huge
Speaker 9:  gap in your company's security. The most common cause of corporate data
Speaker 9:  breaches isn't special hacking techniques or high-tech viruses.
Speaker 9:  It often comes down to weak or stolen passwords, but keeper security can
Speaker 9:  help protect your company's data. Their enterprise password management
Speaker 9:  platform enforces strong passwords and makes it easy for teams to
Speaker 9:  securely share credentials, keep locks down, login details,
Speaker 9:  infrastructure, credentials, confidential documents, and more than a
Speaker 9:  patented zero knowledge fault. Plus it takes less than an hour to
Speaker 9:  deploy. Get the best password manager for your business. Get
Speaker 9:  keeper get started by visiting keeper
Speaker 9:  security.com/vox.
Speaker 11:  You listened to this show weekend and week out because well, we'd like to
Speaker 11:  think we offer sharp unfiltered insights into the biggest stories in tech
Speaker 11:  business and politics. We also understand that your time is valuable
Speaker 11:  and we want you to apply the lessons that you hear on this podcast. So
Speaker 11:  what if you could get bite-sized snippets of the best content we have to
Speaker 11:  offer every week, while you're in luck? What a thrill,
Speaker 11:  because pivot and Salesforce are teaming up to
Speaker 11:  give you just that Salesforce has a new streaming service called Salesforce
Speaker 11:  plus, and they're helping to bring pivot on camera. That's right.
Speaker 11:  Salesforce plus will now be the exclusive home for visual highlights of
Speaker 11:  pivot showing for video segments each and every week. But it's not
Speaker 11:  just pivot Salesforce. Plus users can stream live experiences,
Speaker 11:  original series, virtual learning, and other programming to help your business
Speaker 11:  grow the award winning shows on the platform. Aluminate the future of technology
Speaker 11:  and the digital first work anywhere world and
Speaker 11:  Salesforce plus will inspire business leaders, including you to learn new
Speaker 11:  skills, pursue new career opportunities and drive change in the
Speaker 11:  world. Sign up today to watch pivot and more exclusive
Speaker 11:  content at salesforce.com/plus that's
Speaker 11:  salesforce.com/p L U S.
Speaker 1:  Okay. We're back. Chris waltz was still here. This lightning round continues.
Speaker 1:  This is not gonna be lightning round. I dunno. I dunno. I said it's later
Speaker 1:  on the next one is Elon Musk lays out funding for Twitter takeover. David
Speaker 1:  what's going on with our boy. So Lonnie,
Speaker 2:  I don't know. So the big question about Elon Musk's
Speaker 2:  takeover of Twitter has been what the hell is going on.
Speaker 2:  The other question is, does he actually have the money to do this right?
Speaker 2:  He wants to offer 43 billion and change.
Speaker 2:  And as we know about Elon Musk do, does not have a lot of cash on hand,
Speaker 2:  generally speaking, he like lives in a weird tiny trailer and all his money
Speaker 2:  is tied up in Tesla stock. And he's very excited about this fact. So the
Speaker 2:  question has been like, if in fact he wants to do this,
Speaker 2:  how is he going to do it? And so what happened on
Speaker 2:  Thursday was he, I think, amended an existing filing or
Speaker 2:  did a new filing with the sec paperwork with the sec,
Speaker 2:  basically explaining how he's going to come up with, I think 46 and a
Speaker 2:  half billion dollars that would let him finances purchase of Twitter.
Speaker 2:  He also said that Twitter has not responded to him and is
Speaker 2:  sort of, he's kind of angsty about the whole thing. But basically the
Speaker 2:  point is that I think Morgan Stanley has agreed to loan him
Speaker 2:  $25.5 billion. And Ilan says, he's going
Speaker 2:  to spend $21 billion of his own money. Again, we don't know exactly where
Speaker 2:  that's coming from or how he's going to get it, or what happens to Tesla
Speaker 2:  stock if he sells another $21 billion worth of it. But the theory
Speaker 2:  now is at least he, you know, funding secured, right? He like has
Speaker 2:  the money to buy Twitter.
Speaker 5:  If he secretly listened to his friend, Peter and
Speaker 5:  has just like a huge Roth IRA somewhere Just
Speaker 5:  enormous Roth IRA.
Speaker 1:  So what Alex is making reference to is Peter. Teal's started a Roth IRA when
Speaker 1:  he started PayPal and put all of his PayPal stock in a Roth IRA.
Speaker 5:  And he's so
Speaker 1:  Much accrues tax-free
Speaker 5:  For years is very good
Speaker 1:  As well. But You know, I know, I know people are outraged with the story
Speaker 1:  of billionaires, pay their taxes. If you have the foresight to be like, oh,
Speaker 1:  PayPal is gonna be a big deal when they put it in my Roth IRA,
Speaker 1:  like I dunno, like you're betting on yourself in a,
Speaker 1:  in a fairly serious way at that point. It's still very funny
Speaker 1:  now  to pay their taxes. I'm sorry. I don't mean like, but it's
Speaker 1:  still like good on ya, but you have to be the
Speaker 2:  Player, but also hate the game
Speaker 1:  It's like over the player was actually quite clever here, but the game is
Speaker 1:  rigged, right? It would be amazing if you're 21
Speaker 1:  off,
Speaker 5:  They're just incredible.
Speaker 1:  Anyhow, Twitter has the poison pill and it's actually very funny to see
Speaker 1:  all the time. People who didn't realize poison pills were a things. Speaking
Speaker 1:  of books, everyone should read barbarians at the gate, which is like one
Speaker 1:  of the great 1980s corporate like novel books ever
Speaker 1:  written is about the takeover of RJR Nabisco. It's like
Speaker 1:  nonfiction, but it's written like a novel. It's like this inspired many things
Speaker 1:  about our culture that it's just like working in the background. This was
Speaker 1:  just book, talk on the verge. Now I've had a number of my kids for books,
Speaker 1:  for you to read.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, there is, there was so much homework on the verge cast.
Speaker 2:  I don't know how to feel
Speaker 5:  Signed every week,
Speaker 2:  But what I can't figure out. I come to the end of this and it's like, okay.
Speaker 2:  He continues to do things that make it seem like he genuinely wants to buy
Speaker 2:  Twitter and is capable of buying Twitter. And this is not all like a hilarious
Speaker 2:  drugs joke, but I get to the end of this. And I'm like, is this, I don't
Speaker 2:  know like w with, with Elon Musk as with everything, I have no idea
Speaker 2:  how seriously to take anything that he does or says like, this seems
Speaker 2:  serious, but I have no idea.
Speaker 5:  I didn't actually answer the big question, which is where are the
Speaker 5:  billions coming from that you're going to do this. Are you going to tank
Speaker 5:  Tesla stock and sell a bunch to do this? Because like all he's done and said,
Speaker 5:  okay, instead of tanking, Tesla stock, by selling off 40
Speaker 5:  something billion dollars of stock, I'm not going to just do 21 billion.
Speaker 5:  Like he hasn't changed.
Speaker 1:  No, but I think that, have you ever tweeted about Tesla and your life?
Speaker 1:  There'll be fine. It'll just keep, keep buying the stock. Be like, oh, the
Speaker 1:  stocks were sale. We got to support Elan.
Speaker 1:  He doesn't exist in like the normal market dynamics.
Speaker 1:  I think, I think he's counting on that. I just think the Twitter board
Speaker 1:  appears to be somewhat at odds with itself, notably
Speaker 1:  checked or see just like liking and replying to tweets that Twitter shouldn't
Speaker 1:  be both. Like,
Speaker 1:  this is very,
Speaker 2:  And like on lighting the board on fire, every chance he gets.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. He's like the board has always been the problem. So we'll see, like
Speaker 1:  I said, like David said, the core question here is what's going on?
Speaker 1:  This has happened. So it's still happening. You say we are going to bring
Speaker 1:  back our newsletter this week in Elan written by Liz Lopatto.
Speaker 2:  I have a story from Liz on what is going on here, waiting for me to edit
Speaker 2:  when we're done for each casting here. So by the time people hear it, Liz
Speaker 2:  will have some good thoughts on the site. Cause the other thing that's going
Speaker 2:  on is there are, as you guys have talked about on the show, there are
Speaker 2:  in theory and increasingly in reality, other people who might be interested
Speaker 2:  in buying Twitter, who have very different ideas about what they
Speaker 2:  could do with Twitter, like Elan just wants to buy it. Cause like he thinks
Speaker 2:  it's hilarious and something, something free speech, but there are others
Speaker 2:  who are going to make like a much more real case that there's a lot of money
Speaker 2:  to be made from Twitter that is not currently making. So like it's all
Speaker 2:  these different parties bidding against each other for something that they
Speaker 2:  don't want for the same reasons. Like this is going to get messier before
Speaker 2:  it shakes out. I think one way or another
Speaker 1:  What's fascinating about all this is that Twitter itself rarely makes a case
Speaker 1:  where its own existence. And they've got a new CEO who's been tasked explicitly
Speaker 1:  with a growing it by a hundred million people. And we just came off the whole
Speaker 1:  streaming conversation. Like that's a hard hundred million people.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. They're not all just password chairs.
Speaker 1:  It would just be nice to Twitter, started making a positive case for what
Speaker 1:  it might do to grow as opposed to what it's doing now, which is like,
Speaker 1:  like a deer in headlights kind of situation. We'll see
Speaker 1:  other last few things where you gotta get outta here at Delta confirmed exploratory
Speaker 1:  Starling tests, which is really fascinating because they already getting
Speaker 1:  satellite internet from VSA, which actually quite fast now.
Speaker 1:  And Starlink is not compared to that. Well, you can just like, you can
Speaker 1:  stream movies on via sat,
Speaker 1:  but
Speaker 5:  They're going to get the Elan bump.
Speaker 1:  You have Dion bug, but Starlink is like about a hundred down. They
Speaker 1:  have a faster tier now, which is make me 500 down, but you got to support
Speaker 1:  whole plane with that. So I'm just curious how that's gonna work
Speaker 5:  Also at speed, like Starlink is like scared of trees
Speaker 5:  sometimes. It's like, how is it going to handle
Speaker 1:  No tree, no trees in the sky.
Speaker 1:  So let's say they've started the test. I think it's fascinating of all the
Speaker 1:  places started and could compete. It's like go, go in via sat, like yeah,
Speaker 1:  go get 'em.
Speaker 2:  Well, I would also think if I'm, if I'm one of the airlines, like I'm going
Speaker 2:  to be so excited to, you know, have, have talks, quote
Speaker 2:  unquote with anyone who could maybe drive the price down for some of these
Speaker 2:  other companies, like they're going to be so amped about
Speaker 2:  competition in this space where there has historically been like less than
Speaker 2:  none.
Speaker 1:  Well, so there are two companies there's go-go and VSI. They bought each
Speaker 1:  What happens in America. David, when there's two companies, we'd like to
Speaker 1:  get them down to one. That's really how we like these easy
Speaker 1:  Tesla earnings. They earned over 3 billion in profit. Even with its various
Speaker 1:  challenges with supply chain in China, all this stuff. So, you know, it's
Speaker 1:  doing
Speaker 2:  Fine. It's only 18 billion left.
Speaker 1:  I just got there. Net neutrality, actually the law in California. Now it
Speaker 1:  went to court. The court said, Nope, you can have a lot. This was actually
Speaker 1:  very funny. Just like legal procedure stuff. The FCC under Ajit
Speaker 1:  PI Donald Trump, they said Netta child is no longer the law. And
Speaker 1:  also we don't think the sec should add any authority to
Speaker 1:  pass these laws ever. So we no longer have the authority to do net neutrality
Speaker 1:  or not. We solved it. And then the states said,
Speaker 1:  well, we have net neutrality now. Then the carrier said, no,
Speaker 1:  that's traditionally authority left to the FCC. And all they had to say
Speaker 1:  was no, the FCC. They said they don't want it anymore. And that's how they
Speaker 1:  want it. This is true.
Speaker 2:  This is the Spiderman meme where
Speaker 1:  1000% too clever by half. Like, they're like, no, if you just hadn't
Speaker 1:  done this other part, you would have actually been able to preempt this.
Speaker 1:  But you did the other part cause you were greedy. And so now California net
Speaker 1:  neutrality is a lot of California. They could appeal to the Supreme court
Speaker 1:  who knows if they will. But the fact that it's a law in California, New York
Speaker 1:  state, there's always that meme of like nothing bad happened when a neutrality
Speaker 1:  went away except for the two states where it still exists and all the companies
Speaker 1:  have to deal with it. Yeah. That's my personal thing. All right. That's it.
Speaker 1:  We have all these things about amp, but I want to talk about amp.
Speaker 1:  I just want to talk about amp. I've done. I've done enough today. I will
Speaker 1:  tell you that Instagram is begging you to stop re
Speaker 1:  posting to talks, to reels, which is a very good first
Speaker 1:  David Pierce headline on our website.
Speaker 2:  Thank you. I try Adam. Moseri he's just, he just wants you to make things.
Speaker 2:  It's all he wants in the whole world,
Speaker 1:  But only for him, make them
Speaker 2:  For him. Send them to him directly.
Speaker 1:  Some things to call out. We did the decoder episode on young from Fox on.
Speaker 1:  I will tell you this. I've never gotten so many emails from a podcast
Speaker 1:  episode in my life and John Sanford, Josh Rosa, the number of people in
Speaker 1:  Wisconsin who still want to talk about that project. And they are just
Speaker 1:  emailing us, being like, thank you for pointing out that this is still nuts,
Speaker 1:  but go listen to that. Decoder
Speaker 2:  It's get upset.
Speaker 1:  The AI AK 5g conversation, truly just
Speaker 1:  bonkers. No idea what that means. Still don't know why he reached out.
Speaker 1:  He promises. He's gonna write another book with a answers in it. I don't
Speaker 1:  know if he's going to do that, but when he does, he promised he would come
Speaker 1:  back. So we we'll see. Yeah. It's a
Speaker 2:  Lot for glutton for punishment.
Speaker 1:  Mechanic. Kelly has a great story on a firm that has like an
Speaker 1:  influencer network that promise Republican candidates that can go viral,
Speaker 1:  bad company, same stuff. As everybody company didn't pay people, screaming
Speaker 1:  to people. Great story though. Great reporting from McKenna, just in comma
Speaker 1:  has a great story about the growth of
Speaker 1:  warehouses in inland, California. Just one of those, like
Speaker 1:  this is how the world works. Now you need warehouses everywhere for all this
Speaker 1:  delivery. Very cool. And then we have a huge feature from Amanda Chicago
Speaker 1:  Lewis. It's basically just a heist story. Like a caper story
Speaker 1:  about people who were hustling their way into PPE
Speaker 1:  contracts during the early pandemic. Just like a great read. Like
Speaker 1:  you got some time. You want a great yarn. This is a great story.
Speaker 1:  Okay. That's it. That's the verge cast. David Pearce's here. Everybody.
Speaker 2:  Glad to be here.
Speaker 1:  We went over as always. We got to bring this down. That's your job.
Speaker 2:  I have to reign in the Vergecast somehow
Speaker 5:  Shave like 40 minutes
Speaker 1:  Off, Chris. Thank you so much, buddy. Thank
Speaker 8:  You all. Have a good weekend, everybody and sorry, Patrick,
Speaker 1:  You can tweet at us. David is at Pierce. Alex is Alex H
Speaker 1:  Kranz. Chris is at Chris Welch. I'm at reckless
Speaker 1:  Dakota. Next week is the CEO of UI path, a company that
Speaker 1:  makes computers that use your computer. Oh, I did so
Speaker 1:  fascinating. And it's like multi-billion dollar business.
Speaker 1:  No, it's robotic process automation. My personal obsession. I'm so excited
Speaker 1:  about this episode.
Speaker 2:  Do you talk about domes at all?
Speaker 1:  You got to start asking all that you got to get back on domes and then we'll
Speaker 1:  be back next week, more virtual guest. That's it. I don't know.
Speaker 3:  This episode was sponsored by Salesforce. Salesforce plus is an
Speaker 3:  all new streaming service that includes live experiences, original
Speaker 3:  series podcasts, and other programming with Salesforce. Plus
Speaker 3:  business leaders can stream the latest and engaging inspirational
Speaker 3:  stories and access thought leadership and expert advice on demand.
Speaker 3:  Salesforce plus is available right now for those looking to be informed,
Speaker 3:  entertained, and inspired in the business space. Join for free and
Speaker 3:  watch great business series on demand at salesforce.com/plus.