# Transcript
ID: 1a028f10-7f2b-11ed-a15d-c7be979ddb61
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Livestreaming is back!
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/3439429057650173453/5832260088678485544/s93290-US-2286s-1671405811.mp3
Description: In the final episode on our series about creator economies, David Pierce is joined by producer Hadley Robinson to explore the world of livestreaming and its recent popularity across every social platform. Livestreaming is certainly not a new thing though, so why does it seem to be having a moment?
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (4 ads detected)
Speaker 1:  Welcome to the Vergecast, the flagship podcast of Stream snipers.
Speaker 1:  I'm your friend, David Pierce, and this is the third episode of our mini
Speaker 1:  series, looking at the business of being a Creator. I wanna start this
Speaker 1:  episode by telling you about a new nightly routine that I've developed.
Speaker 1:  TikTok has been the app that I look at right before bed for a
Speaker 1:  long time. Now, I really don't recommend this, by the way. It's really
Speaker 1:  aggressively too easy for just a quick TikTok scroll
Speaker 1:  to turn into like two hours of watching and me suddenly getting
Speaker 1:  too little sleep for no good reason. But I do it anyway. And recently,
Speaker 1:  the thing I found myself doing a lot is watching live streams. They show
Speaker 1:  up right in the for you feed in TikTok. And for a long time I would just
Speaker 1:  skip past them. But recently, for whatever reason, I found myself diving
Speaker 1:  in more and more. And let me tell you, friends, TikTok Live
Speaker 1:  is a weird, weird place. Last night for instance, I watched
Speaker 1:  a live that was just a girl standing on a beach talking about how
Speaker 1:  she was going to go in the water, but not actually going in the
Speaker 1:  water for so long that all of the viewers ended up getting annoyed by
Speaker 1:  her and this entire process. And yet there were like
Speaker 1:  18,000 of us watching. It's
Speaker 3:  Freaking storming out here guys. It's storming out here. And I just,
Speaker 1:  Oh, and the best part is I'm pretty sure like 98%
Speaker 1:  sure that the live was actually just a replay of a different
Speaker 1:  live from a few days ago, which some of the viewers said they had already
Speaker 1:  seen. It was insane. I also took some notes on other lives that I've
Speaker 1:  found over the last few weeks. There was the one that was just a long shot
Speaker 1:  of a pier with waves crashing over it. As the guy pointing the camera
Speaker 1:  told us it was about to be destroyed. Pier
Speaker 4:  Cam video from tomorrow will be interesting for sure. You're right Taylor,
Speaker 1:  As far as I can tell, never was watched it for a long time. Anyway, there
Speaker 1:  was one where a truck driver had mounted his phone to his windshield. So
Speaker 1:  I was just watching the view of the road as he drove. I watched that one
Speaker 1:  for a long time instead of sleeping for some reason. There was
Speaker 1:  another one that was just two students in anatomy class streaming themselves,
Speaker 1:  eating gummy candy and blatantly not paying attention
Speaker 1:  in anatomy
Speaker 1:  class,
Speaker 6:  The,
Speaker 1:  There was one that was one of those quarter machines in a casino where you
Speaker 1:  put in a quarter and try to knock a bunch of other quarters off the ledge.
Speaker 1:  That one is a staple of TikTok live. You find them everywhere.
Speaker 7:  We got a hundred bucks right here and 50 bucks right
Speaker 1:  There. Thank you. So is the interactive sleep stream where the creator is
Speaker 1:  just asleep and viewers can give gifts or send messages to play
Speaker 1:  certain songs or make stuff happen to try to wake them up.
Speaker 8:  Viewers join my livestream and minions wake me
Speaker 8:  up.
Speaker 1:  But my favorite one so far, I think was a still shot
Speaker 1:  from one of those huge car crushing machines in a junkyard.
Speaker 1:  I spent like a full hour watching this machine, pick up cars,
Speaker 1:  move them over, drop them in the crusher, crush them and move on.
Speaker 1:  It was awesome. And then over and over
Speaker 1:  and over in my feed over weeks at a time, I kept seeing this
Speaker 1:  one guy, his screen name is
Speaker 1:  the six shooter with the number six instead of the first s. And it seems
Speaker 1:  like almost every night he does the same live stream. It's just him
Speaker 1:  in a small gym with a few basketballs, a hoop and a rebounding machine.
Speaker 1:  And he spends a couple of hours sometimes trying to make
Speaker 1:  53 pointers in a row. I found
Speaker 1:  myself watching this stream night after night for hours with
Speaker 1:  hundreds or thousands of other people. We all cheer when he gets close to
Speaker 1:  50. We groan when he misses someone is always
Speaker 1:  counting in the chat. And if I'm being honest, sometimes we all just
Speaker 1:  collectively root for him to miss. It's both kind of boring if
Speaker 1:  I'm being honest. But also totally enthralling. And Seth McCoy,
Speaker 1:  who is the sixth shooter himself told me, I'm not the only one who feels
Speaker 1:  that way.
Speaker 9:  There's people in my comments that say, I don't even like watching basketball.
Speaker 9:  This is just therapeutic. So it's like a, I forget what the word is, but
Speaker 9:  like a ASMR type stuff.
Speaker 1:  Okay, let's back up quickly. Seth is a basketball player and a good one,
Speaker 1:  but he only started turning, shooting into content over the last couple
Speaker 1:  of years.
Speaker 9:  During Covid is when it all kind of started picking up. We're all at home,
Speaker 9:  we're not doing anything. I'm, I'm, I'm bored outta my mind. And my brother
Speaker 9:  walks in after seeing a lethal shooter video and lethal shooters, kind
Speaker 9:  of somebody that I look up to and I'm, and I'm, I'm seeing what he's doing
Speaker 9:  and, and I want to do stuff like that cuz I think I have the same types of
Speaker 9:  skill. And, and he's like, Seth, why aren't you doing this?
Speaker 9:  And I'm like, I'm like, what? What? What do you, what do you mean? He's like,
Speaker 9:  dude, dude. He's like, you're better than lethal shooter. Like you need,
Speaker 9:  you need to be doing what, what he's doing. That day we,
Speaker 9:  we made my Instagram account.
Speaker 1:  At first, Seth tried to do trick shotty stuff, which is another
Speaker 1:  staple of live platforms everywhere. He was shooting threes with shoes on
Speaker 1:  his hands or trying to make shots with tennis balls instead of basketballs.
Speaker 1:  He was also posting highlights of his own games and all that was doing
Speaker 1:  fine. Not great, but fine. But early on he had this
Speaker 1:  one goal. He didn't really know what he was doing, but he wanted to get enough
Speaker 1:  followers to go live.
Speaker 9:  The goal with, with lives is you have to get to a thousand followers. I didn't
Speaker 9:  know what I'd do. I didn't know if I'd just sit there and talk. I didn't
Speaker 9:  know what I'd do on lives. I had no plan. I, I just knew, okay, a thousand
Speaker 9:  followers means I get to go live. And I think with
Speaker 9:  me, with the personality that I have, I thought, okay, well if I get
Speaker 9:  to go live, people will understand who I am as a person,
Speaker 9:  understand what I'm doing it for rather than my videos.
Speaker 9:  Cuz my videos, I'm just trying to get attention my lives. I, I can
Speaker 9:  build community.
Speaker 1:  Early on he tried the sit in front of the camera and talk thing and
Speaker 1:  that also went okay, but talking into a camera when nobody can
Speaker 1:  talk back and even the chat is kind of delayed from what you're talking
Speaker 1:  about is just awkward. And as Seth kept telling me
Speaker 1:  this community feeling of the whole thing was the whole point that
Speaker 1:  he was after.
Speaker 9:  When I was younger, I told myself like, I would try to reach out to the bigger
Speaker 9:  pages and I would never get a response. And I told myself, if I ever had
Speaker 9:  a platform, I would use it to inspire. I want to inspire the younger
Speaker 9:  generation to love basketball as much as I do.
Speaker 1:  So Seth not really knowing exactly how any of this should work kept going
Speaker 1:  live. And he eventually started streaming some of his own basketball workouts.
Speaker 1:  And he had this goal, not so much for content, but just for himself. He wanted
Speaker 1:  to hit more than 105, three pointers in a row. Why
Speaker 1:  105? Because there was this super viral video of Steph
Speaker 1:  Curry hitting 105 in a
Speaker 1:  row. And so Seth, of course was like,
Speaker 1:  well, maybe I can beat that. And he became obsessed with trying
Speaker 1:  and he started streaming all of his attempts live. Oh,
Speaker 1:  and about the same time, he also figured out a crucial way to make
Speaker 1:  his live streams work.
Speaker 9:  One thing I figured out is lives that are horizontal
Speaker 9:  do horrible. So I had to flip it to Norm Normal. If
Speaker 9:  you're scrolling that, that's the normal view that you see. And I did that
Speaker 9:  and I, and I started shooting.
Speaker 1:  That's when things really took off. Seth started calling his lives things
Speaker 1:  like making 50 in a row and people started showing
Speaker 1:  up. One night I joined him, he
Speaker 1:  had 3,400 people watching and he told me he's getting more than a million
Speaker 1:  viewers a week on his lives at this point. But the question then
Speaker 1:  for him and really for anyone making stuff like this is so
Speaker 1:  what Seth has this audience, people like watching him and he
Speaker 1:  thinks there's a business here. But one thing he's been trying to figure
Speaker 1:  out is how exactly to monetize the streams himself.
Speaker 1:  Live is different from a lot of the ways people make and monetize content.
Speaker 1:  And it's a little messier. One way people have found is
Speaker 1:  just to basically ask viewers to give you stuff. There's things
Speaker 1:  like super thanks and super chat on YouTube and you can ask for tips on
Speaker 1:  certain platforms. And on TikTok there's gifts.
Speaker 9:  So I'm trying to turn around more and talk. I'm trying to, to help as many
Speaker 9:  people as possible. I'm playing around with the gifting now. I've done it
Speaker 9:  the last three lives. And you know how silly you sound when you
Speaker 9:  turn to the camera and say, let's get 50 donuts. Like
Speaker 9:  I sound so stupid. Like, I don't know, it's so silly.
Speaker 9:  But it all comes, comes down with with monetization.
Speaker 1:  The other thing he's planning is giveaways. He wants to work with brands,
Speaker 1:  especially basketball brands, to give away their stuff on his streams.
Speaker 1:  And he also started this thing called the Six Shooter Academy where you can
Speaker 1:  sign up to learn how to shoot like Seth. That's all part of the business.
Speaker 1:  But the thing that seems to get Seth most excited right now is all the people
Speaker 1:  who come on his streams and root for him to miss or comment things like
Speaker 1:  it's a loop when he makes too many in a row. Now Seth,
Speaker 1:  like any good creator, is trying to monetize the haters.
Speaker 9:  Now I'm trying to get my haters to, to interact. Hey, I'm trying to
Speaker 9:  hit 50 in a row, don't, don't join my live and don't make me miss. So
Speaker 9:  each gift is gonna be a sound like while I'm shooting or
Speaker 9:  strobe lights or just something that's a distraction to try to
Speaker 9:  make me miss
Speaker 1:  That explanation. And that combination of things actually hits a pretty broad
Speaker 1:  spectrum of the ways creators are monetizing their live streams. Giveaways
Speaker 1:  are a big one, really. Any kind of product marketing or live shopping is
Speaker 1:  growing in a huge way. But I think the most interesting other space is
Speaker 1:  this direct interaction. How do you get your fans and your haters
Speaker 1:  to pay for your lives indirectly or otherwise? The interactive sleep
Speaker 1:  idea, which Seth says was the inspiration for the sounds and strobe lights
Speaker 1:  that he's thinking about has big potential. I think you're gonna see that
Speaker 1:  lots of places. Some others have subscriptions. I don't know if you've ever
Speaker 1:  come across the lo-fi girl on YouTube for instance. Those are the channels
Speaker 1:  that stream never-ending live music that's great for studying or
Speaker 1:  working. It makes money through a monthly subscription that gives you loyalty
Speaker 1:  badges in the chat and custom emoji and some cool stuff on Discord
Speaker 1:  and even access to new videos ahead of time. But the most interesting
Speaker 1:  thing about all this is just that it like works.
Speaker 1:  Now Live has obviously been big
Speaker 1:  in gaming for a long time. Twitch got a lot of things right early on and
Speaker 1:  it's just fun and natural to watch someone else play video games that
Speaker 1:  just works. But there have been so
Speaker 1:  many other attempts to make other kinds of live happen through the
Speaker 1:  years. Remember when like Meerkat and Periscope were gonna be the next big
Speaker 1:  thing, but neither of those obviously turned into much of anything.
Speaker 1:  It felt for a lot of years that live streams were mostly just known
Speaker 1:  for streaming horrible things like shootings and live was
Speaker 1:  a content moderation problem much more than it was an actual revenue
Speaker 1:  stream or entertainment platform. But now YouTube Live
Speaker 1:  is growing fast both as a way for people to premier videos for everybody
Speaker 1:  at the same time and is an actual live streaming platform. Live
Speaker 1:  is one of the fastest growing things on TikTok and a huge business opportunity
Speaker 1:  for the platform. Twitch's just chatting section continues to grow. It's
Speaker 1:  a deeply weird and fun place to hang out on the internet. Live is a thing.
Speaker 1:  Now we're gonna take a break and then we're gonna get into how we
Speaker 1:  got to this moment and where the money really is in life.
Speaker 1:  We'll be right
Speaker 1:  back.
Speaker 1:  All right, we're back. Howley Robinson is here. Hi Hadley.
Speaker 11:  Hello.
Speaker 1:  You and I kind of divided and conquered on this particular subject.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, the first place we kind of sent you was to go figure out why
Speaker 1:  live is happening
Speaker 11:  Now. Right. So I think to, to get to where we are today, you
Speaker 11:  have to go back a little bit. I think webcams in the nineties are kind
Speaker 11:  of the starting point. Okay. Little fixed cameras that you might
Speaker 11:  put, I don't know, like at the top of a ski slope or there was a famous
Speaker 11:  one where they like just put it in front of a coffee maker.
Speaker 1:  I remember that.
Speaker 11:  Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  But also the vibe of that is not that different from the stuff that people
Speaker 1:  do now. Like it's amazing how little has changed. That's
Speaker 11:  What I was about to say. Yeah. But to really get a sense of the
Speaker 11:  trajectory of live streaming kind of as we know it today. I talked to
Speaker 11:  David Craig, he's a professor at USC Annenberg School
Speaker 11:  of Communications. And one of his areas of expertise is creator
Speaker 11:  culture. He told me we really have to start around 2007.
Speaker 12:  The earliest precursor of what we in the West think of as live streaming
Speaker 12:  was launched with justin.tv.
Speaker 11:  Each user had channels. They were encouraged to broadcast themselves just
Speaker 11:  doing whatever they do. Again, sounds familiar.
Speaker 11:  The original Justin, he would wear a webcam on
Speaker 11:  his hat and he had this like B backpack laptop
Speaker 11:  setup and he would just stream live continuously. They called it
Speaker 11:  Lifecasting back then,
Speaker 1:  Right? It was like the kind of make your own Truman show experience.
Speaker 11:  Yes, yes. And Professor Craig said it was a lot
Speaker 11:  of almost reality TV live
Speaker 12:  And it didn't quite work out. And it turns out reality shows
Speaker 12:  are much more interesting if they are edited and
Speaker 12:  there's a story and people were not ready at
Speaker 12:  that moment to tune in and just hang out and watch people living
Speaker 12:  out their lives online fair.
Speaker 11:  But they did settle into one area that was working well and that was
Speaker 11:  gaming. And when they saw that was working really well, they went all in,
Speaker 11:  made it Twitch in 2011,
Speaker 12:  They quickly discovered that there was this huge community
Speaker 12:  and very engaged community interested in watching people
Speaker 12:  playing online games. And not just for the purpose of learning
Speaker 12:  how to play the game or watching great game play, but
Speaker 12:  for a means of socialization as a way to hang out. It
Speaker 12:  was live streaming with a purpose.
Speaker 11:  So Twitch blew up, it had more than 3 million users per month
Speaker 11:  in the first year. Amazon bought it a few years later for a billion
Speaker 11:  dollars. And around this time everybody's also
Speaker 11:  getting a smartphone video capability. Connectivity is getting
Speaker 11:  better and other tech companies kind of start sniffing around the live
Speaker 11:  space. And this is what you were mentioning before, startups like
Speaker 11:  Me, cat Periscope, were drawing funding. Facebook Live
Speaker 11:  was becoming a thing.
Speaker 12:  The Meca era. Yes. In the case of Meca,
Speaker 12:  I think it was a, a consortium of different Hollywood companies that
Speaker 12:  invested in this but had no idea what made live streaming different from
Speaker 12:  broadcast television and didn't fully appreciate and understand how
Speaker 12:  to navigate that. Periscope, as we know, was purchased
Speaker 12:  alongside with Vine by Twitter. And one of the things that Periscope
Speaker 12:  could not get their head around was that the creators were the
Speaker 12:  core value of live streaming platforms. And that meant they needed
Speaker 12:  to pivot to a way to promote monetize
Speaker 12:  support, both financially and even
Speaker 12:  creatively and emotionally. The work that creators were doing on
Speaker 12:  Periscope, Periscope was rather treated just as
Speaker 12:  a added value proposition on the Twitter platform and
Speaker 12:  has now since disappeared.
Speaker 11:  These apps and platforms were never really able to scale up and they pretty
Speaker 11:  much either failed spectacularly or faded from view
Speaker 11:  over time.
Speaker 1:  So do we think we can kind of blame Twitch
Speaker 1:  for that quick rise where Twitch figured out this one thing, which is like,
Speaker 1:  people like to play games and then everybody else saw Twitch growing and
Speaker 1:  selling to Amazon and said, okay, let's, let's figure this out. And
Speaker 1:  tried to sort of make it bigger than that before it was ready to be bigger
Speaker 1:  for that. Like is it, can that whole boom sort of be traced back to Twitch,
Speaker 1:  do you think?
Speaker 11:  I mean it certainly works on the timeline that way. Amazon saw value
Speaker 11:  in Twitch and a lot of other places started to wonder if there was value
Speaker 11:  in other areas. And maybe it was, they didn't understand that
Speaker 11:  gaming was unique at the time and there was something more to it than just
Speaker 11:  straight, like going live from everywhere. You know, I, I think the point
Speaker 11:  of not really making it work for creators back then not
Speaker 11:  understanding it was kind of like about them and, and that like to spend
Speaker 11:  all this time cuz live takes a ton of time for creators, it should
Speaker 11:  kind of be worth their while.
Speaker 1:  That makes sense.
Speaker 11:  Okay. But I wanna kind of bump over to Asia and particularly China
Speaker 11:  at the time because live Stream was going in a different direction
Speaker 11:  there.
Speaker 11:  Livestreaming at this time in China is having a lot of success.
Speaker 11:  And it starts with online dating Professor Craig
Speaker 11:  assures me this is isn't porn, which is strictly prohibited.
Speaker 11:  So
Speaker 1:  This is not only fans before, only fans that we're talking about here.
Speaker 11:  Right? Okay. Right. You can't do that in China.
Speaker 12:  It was a visual representation of pretty
Speaker 12:  women who are able to then engage hundreds if not thousands of
Speaker 12:  men online through live streaming platforms to spend time with
Speaker 12:  them, to converse, to chat, to interact, to watch, to
Speaker 12:  sing, to discuss their day, to talk about
Speaker 12:  the world. You might use the analogy to the movie
Speaker 12:  her,
Speaker 11:  This is a little bit of a side, but there is like all this context going
Speaker 11:  on that like, women are moving to cities because there's a lot more economic
Speaker 11:  activity. A lot of the men are left behind. There's a lot of lonely people.
Speaker 11:  There's, everyone's got a phone basically live in
Speaker 11:  this context is really starting to work. And a lot of platforms there see
Speaker 11:  this. And every platform develops a live
Speaker 11:  feature
Speaker 11:  and soon a new thing starts happening on live. And that's
Speaker 11:  shopping. Hmm. It starts taking off in China around 2016.
Speaker 11:  And it's not just beauty products, it's also cars,
Speaker 11:  it's rockets. They're like selling everything in that time period in the
Speaker 11:  last like five or six years, it's just gotten huge. It's a 400
Speaker 11:  billion industry there.
Speaker 1:  So what does that look like? Like give me a, a sense of what like a live
Speaker 1:  shopping stream might look like. Is it, obviously everybody uses the sort
Speaker 1:  of QVC and home shopping network on the internet example
Speaker 1:  when they talk about this stuff. Is that kind of how it works? It's just
Speaker 1:  somebody being like, buy this and then there's a link on the side and you
Speaker 1:  can buy it and if you want it, you buy it and people do.
Speaker 11:  So yeah, it is a little like qvc, but it's kind of a chattier approach
Speaker 11:  where the host or seller answers questions about the
Speaker 11:  products and responds to people and it's all on
Speaker 11:  one app interface. So you can watch, you can ask questions and you can buy
Speaker 11:  the product right there. Sometimes these hosts are influencer type people
Speaker 11:  already who can open a channel and bring over their mass audience.
Speaker 11:  But sometimes companies or brands just pay their own staff or smaller
Speaker 11:  influencers to go live and sell these products.
Speaker 1:  I mean, and I guess to some extent that's not, that's a, an extension of
Speaker 1:  regular influencer culture, right? Like we, we've spent a long time with,
Speaker 1:  you know, Kim Kardashian saying, look at this shampoo, buy my shampoo. The
Speaker 1:  shopping stuff is just a more sort of interactive and in some ways
Speaker 1:  like honest version of that. So it, I guess it, it makes sense to me that
Speaker 1:  it's big, but honestly, what did you say, it's a 400 billion industry. That's
Speaker 1:  a crazy number.
Speaker 11:  Yeah. It's a huge, huge number. It's a number that
Speaker 11:  excites a lot of people in the
Speaker 11:  US because it seems like, I think people are, are
Speaker 11:  visualizing that kind of opportunity.
Speaker 1:  Okay. I want to come back to that. But first we need to take a break. We're
Speaker 1:  gonna come back in just a second and talk about live shopping coming for
Speaker 1:  America. We'll be right back.
Speaker 1:  All right, we're back. So, Hadley China is all in on
Speaker 1:  live shopping. Live shopping's a huge industry and at some point, I'm assuming
Speaker 1:  it sounds like someone in America went, what if we did that? But for
Speaker 1:  America, because this is how live streaming works. Okay.
Speaker 11:  There are a lot of people who think live shopping or commerce could be big
Speaker 11:  here too, as discussed earlier, you know, social platforms like TikTok
Speaker 11:  are getting in the game and offering tools to creators and helping them
Speaker 11:  monetize. But there's also a ton of startups. One consultant I talked to
Speaker 11:  told me that 80% of the cold calls she was getting earlier this year were
Speaker 11:  from live commerce startups. Wow. One of these
Speaker 11:  upstart live platforms is called not,
Speaker 14:  You know, one way to think about it's kind of like eBay meets Twitch.
Speaker 11:  That's Grant LaFontaine. He's the c e o and co-founder.
Speaker 11:  And the first time I went Onnot, I was watching this guy
Speaker 11:  wheel a shopping cart through a thrift store and basically picked things
Speaker 11:  off the rack, engage interest and communicate with people there
Speaker 11:  who were like interested in those jerseys over there. And then I flipped
Speaker 11:  to another one of a guy at home selling records. I saw one of
Speaker 11:  people unwrapping baseball cards. I dunno if you checked it out at all,
Speaker 11:  David.
Speaker 1:  I did. So it, you told me about this right. As my parents
Speaker 1:  sent me a big box of my old sports
Speaker 1:  cards. And so I just went and checked this out and it turns
Speaker 1:  out it's, it's kind of addicting. Like I haven't collected sports cards in
Speaker 1:  a long time. I just have this big box of them and now I'm, I'm kind of
Speaker 1:  back in like watching people open the packs and debate what's good and what
Speaker 1:  isn't and trying to find like the misprints cuz the misprints are always
Speaker 1:  more valuable. It, I have no interest in buying any of those things, but
Speaker 1:  like I, I found myself spending way more time watching them than I expected
Speaker 1:  to.
Speaker 11:  They started like as an e-commerce marketplace selling collectibles.
Speaker 11:  The first thing was Funko Pops, which I had never heard of, but are
Speaker 11:  these like big-headed action figures? Collectibles.
Speaker 1:  I was at Target the other day and I got to watch a mom and her son negotiate
Speaker 1:  whether he could buy one, two or three Funko pops for like
Speaker 1:  20 minutes. Like I did a whole lap around Target and came back to them still
Speaker 1:  negotiating about Funko Pops. So like, do not underestimate the power of
Speaker 1:  Funko Pops.
Speaker 11:  No way. I mean it's, yeah, it's propelled whatnot into a
Speaker 11:  huge business. Grant said he and his co-founder had kind of
Speaker 11:  started seeing people auctioning stuff off on YouTube and Instagram with
Speaker 11:  these really vibrant comment sections. Hmm. And so,
Speaker 11:  you know, they went from just kind of being like an e-commerce
Speaker 11:  site that's asynchronous is the word for not
Speaker 11:  live into deciding like, let's try a live thing. And so
Speaker 11:  they launched a live product and it went pretty
Speaker 14:  Well. I was the first person to go live two and a half hours. I sold like
Speaker 14:  120 Funko pops. And so if you're a seller and you
Speaker 14:  can see something in two hours where you can sell 120 items, which
Speaker 14:  would typically take you, I don't know, a couple months on eBay.
Speaker 14:  That's a compelling value proposition as a seller. Then we went to Pokemon
Speaker 14:  cards, sports cards, comic books. There's a lot in
Speaker 14:  between. But kind of fast forward to today, you know, we're probably selling
Speaker 14:  things in about 80 plus categories. We're about 350 people.
Speaker 14:  We've raised about half a billion dollars in venture capital funding. Wow.
Speaker 1:  You weren't kidding. Don't underestimate Funko Pops indeed.
Speaker 1:  Goodness.
Speaker 11:  Yeah.
Speaker 1:  You see a lot of the same like, watch me open Pokemon card packs
Speaker 1:  on YouTube and stuff like that, but there's no sort of obvious shopping thing
Speaker 1:  at the end of it. It sounds like what, what not did was say you wanna make
Speaker 1:  this thing people like watching you open Pokemon card packs. Let's give
Speaker 1:  you the tools to like sell and ship this stuff at the same time. Am I understanding
Speaker 1:  that right?
Speaker 11:  Yeah, and I mean if you, if you go onto whatnot, basically there's like
Speaker 11:  a column on the left where you can click all the items
Speaker 11:  that are kind of coming up and just buy them and you know, there's
Speaker 11:  also a vibrant comment section. So the person who's doing the selling is
Speaker 11:  responding to people's questions. I see the evidence is out there that
Speaker 11:  people are moving a lot of product when they're live.
Speaker 14:  It's an incredible sales channel and that is where some of, like the data
Speaker 14:  from China probably holds true. Who is it on
Speaker 14:  Singles Day this year? I think one of the guys sold like a billion dollars
Speaker 14:  worth of product in 24 hours. And it's otherworldly and
Speaker 14:  we're not close to that anywhere close to that in the United States yet.
Speaker 14:  But, but still, if you're, you know, the, the like for like comparison of
Speaker 14:  let's take a traditional search based marketplace and
Speaker 14:  compare it to, you know, livestream shopping and how much product you can
Speaker 14:  move per hour. Livestream shopping has a huge advantage there.
Speaker 11:  Grant told us that some sellers on whatnot are making tens of millions of
Speaker 11:  dollars per year. Wow. Which kind of feels like it's moving out of the creator
Speaker 11:  economy and into just very big business.
Speaker 1:  Yeah.
Speaker 11:  So back to David who, you know, was telling me about the history. He kind
Speaker 11:  of had had this one story about live shopping.
Speaker 12:  I once went to a event in
Speaker 12:  a, a beauty store in Hong Kong in
Speaker 12:  2017 where the creator was
Speaker 12:  live streaming simultaneously across five different
Speaker 12:  platforms and sold out the product from the French perfume
Speaker 12:  company in 40 minutes. The French seller was standing
Speaker 12:  next to me and said, we'll never go back to traditional advertising.
Speaker 1:  Okay. So that just made something click in my brain, which
Speaker 1:  is that what this actually does is make, it makes the advertising and it
Speaker 1:  makes the store the same thing. Right? Like it's, this stuff has all been
Speaker 1:  so sort of abstracted where like you have an influencer who is like, buy
Speaker 1:  this thing and then you have to click a link and you have to go to a thing
Speaker 1:  and you have to buy it. And there's, it's often hard to connect it back to
Speaker 1:  the influencers. It's like the podcast ads all telling you to like, you know,
Speaker 1:  put slash podcasts at the end of your thing. Whereas with this, it's just
Speaker 1:  like there is a person you care about and a product you might like and they
Speaker 1:  are one and the same. And so of, of of course it's going to
Speaker 1:  convert better and be faster and be more fun. And like everybody has an incentive
Speaker 1:  to be interesting and everybody has an incentive to sell you stuff. It's
Speaker 1:  kind of, it's like the most efficient vehicle we've ever
Speaker 1:  created to just sell people things from people that they like. That's kind
Speaker 1:  of wild. I had never really thought about it like
Speaker 11:  That. Yeah. Professor Craig was kind of pointing out that like the loss
Speaker 11:  of the 32nd advertising spot is just huge.
Speaker 11:  You know, the fact that we're all, a lot of people are streaming without
Speaker 11:  ads nowadays. Yeah. You know, it's harder for businesses to figure out how
Speaker 11:  to tell you what they've got and having people go live that is
Speaker 11:  advertising, you know, it's just in a different format may, you know, maybe
Speaker 11:  in a more effective format. Totally. The other thing that seems to be key
Speaker 11:  to live shopping and making it work and just key to live in general, I
Speaker 11:  mean we were talking about this earlier with, with Twitch is community grant
Speaker 11:  said a lot of the sellers on whatnot develop relationships with each
Speaker 11:  other. When I was researching this story, I listened to this one podcast
Speaker 11:  and it was two guys who met on whatnot and now host this podcast
Speaker 11:  together.
Speaker 14:  You know, when I think about collectors and enthusiasts, you're often not
Speaker 14:  buying the item for the item's sake. You're buying the item almost as an
Speaker 14:  excuse to sit there and talk with people who have a similar shared
Speaker 14:  interest as you. You know, the, the object is almost secondary to the
Speaker 14:  community and an excuse to have conversation around
Speaker 14:  things. And so when you think about that in
Speaker 14:  the live shopping experience, it's not really about the object, it's about
Speaker 14:  the experience around it. Are you talking with someone who's knowledgeable?
Speaker 14:  Are there other people in there who have this have the same interest? Is
Speaker 14:  it fun? And
Speaker 11:  This is a point a lot of experts kept making to me that shopping is
Speaker 11:  actually a social experience for many people. Like friends go shopping together,
Speaker 11:  they try things on, they ask each other how it looks and then
Speaker 11:  there's this other social component which is having a sales rep help you
Speaker 11:  and answer questions. And so the host of a livestream and the people in
Speaker 11:  the chat can kind of replicate that real world experience.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, I, I mean that that whole idea of community is something that
Speaker 1:  kind of came up. I think through both of our reporting on this a lot is
Speaker 1:  that so much of live is about
Speaker 1:  like minute to minute, second to second community building. Right. And in
Speaker 1:  a lot of ways it's much harder than just like posting a video and responding
Speaker 1:  to some of the comments in the comments, which is the thing a lot of creators
Speaker 1:  do. But on the other hand it also feels much cooler to
Speaker 1:  like ask a question and have them answer it directly to you as
Speaker 1:  it's going. And I think live when it works, I think brings people
Speaker 1:  so much closer that way. And there's even a thing, like, I just think back
Speaker 1:  to these girls I was watching sit in anatomy class, like the thing that combined
Speaker 1:  us all in that chat was not, we're all interested
Speaker 1:  in anatomy class or whatever, right? It was just, it's a bunch of people
Speaker 1:  who were like bored on TikTok at the same moment and there's like something
Speaker 1:  connecting about that. And then if you can add Funko Pops or Pokemon
Speaker 1:  cards or whatever on top of that, suddenly like I will be part of, of this
Speaker 1:  community and we'll talk about it together and I'll buy the thing and then
Speaker 1:  we can talk about the thing that I bought. And that actually totally tracks
Speaker 1:  for me that all of this is sort of in service of that feeling of community
Speaker 1:  for people. That's really interesting.
Speaker 11:  Yeah. And I mean that might be what was missing, you know, in me Cat
Speaker 11:  and Periscope that that they didn't see that that's really like you
Speaker 11:  have to build a a community space. That's why people want to go there.
Speaker 1:  Totally.
Speaker 11:  I think one interesting thing that David Craig pointed out in terms of the
Speaker 11:  difference between China and the US is that in the US we have kind of an
Speaker 11:  attachment to the retail experience.
Speaker 12:  China hasn't, didn't go through our 20th century
Speaker 12:  retail mall advertising culture that we are still
Speaker 12:  clinging to where we still want to keep the mom and pop shops alive or we
Speaker 12:  want to keep mall culture alive. They were very quick
Speaker 12:  and deft and adapted very quickly cuz there wasn't a lot of that
Speaker 12:  already to, to prevent it.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Like malls are dying and we're sad about it and most people in other
Speaker 1:  places are not sad about malls dying.
Speaker 11:  Right.
Speaker 1:  So then that makes me wonder like, are the malls so to speak, getting into
Speaker 1:  social shopping? Like I know this is a thing Amazon has experimented with
Speaker 1:  over time, but like is this the future of all of these big retail
Speaker 1:  companies too?
Speaker 11:  Oh man, this is a great segue because one thing that David Craig told
Speaker 11:  me is that Walmart is getting in the game.
Speaker 1:  Oh, well there you go. It's on now. Yeah. Okay.
Speaker 11:  They have set up a creator studio. You
Speaker 11:  can sign up, you can, you have to apply. But it seems like there's a very
Speaker 11:  low barrier to entry. You don't have to have any followers to start out,
Speaker 11:  which like, we'll see if it works. Cuz we were just talking about like,
Speaker 11:  like that community thing. But yeah, if you want to go and try and
Speaker 11:  sell Walmart products and take a cut, Hmm. Anybody can go and
Speaker 11:  try and do that.
Speaker 12:  All the big retailers have understood now that the future
Speaker 12:  of retail is in social commerce and are moving as quickly as
Speaker 12:  they can. Even though they aren't tech platforms, they are moving into
Speaker 12:  and becoming tech platforms, not just in response to Amazon, but
Speaker 12:  because they understand that people are walking in, you know, they're not
Speaker 12:  getting the traffic back the way they once did in the stores.
Speaker 11:  They're not gonna keep having traffic in their stores. I think we're moving
Speaker 11:  in a one way direction and I mean, that kind of brings me to one point that
Speaker 11:  a lot of people brought up with live and, and why it's having more of
Speaker 11:  a moment now in the US and it's because of the pandemic. Sure. I
Speaker 11:  think you see that with six shooter, right? Like he said, he started it
Speaker 11:  during the pandemic, he was bored, there was nothing else to do. People
Speaker 11:  were trying to figure out their time and he had, there's a big audience
Speaker 11:  of other people who are bored and wanna watch it. Right. And then retailers
Speaker 11:  are starting to see the need to up the online sales game, you know, and
Speaker 11:  then tech companies are starting to build tools for creators to, to do it
Speaker 11:  all. So I don't think you can overstate like the US might have needed a
Speaker 11:  little push into live and the pandemic kind of, kind of helped a little
Speaker 11:  bit.
Speaker 1:  Totally. Yeah. Well, and it makes me wonder if where we're headed now
Speaker 1:  is the Walmart side of things is one version of it, right? Where you say
Speaker 1:  basically we have the mall and you're gonna come
Speaker 1:  shop it on camera and people are gonna go along with you, right? Like, you're
Speaker 1:  the guy you were talking about on whatnot who's literally pushing a shopping
Speaker 1:  cart along. That's such an interesting version of live shopping. But then
Speaker 1:  there's another side of it that is basically all of these platforms are just
Speaker 1:  gonna sort of build in like buy now tools to their stuff. And so people
Speaker 1:  will just go live and like, if I hold up, I have a, I have a can of
Speaker 1:  seltzer here and like if I hold it up on camera, it's just gonna pop up and
Speaker 1:  go buy this seltzer. Right. Is it all of those things, do you think like,
Speaker 1:  I, I guess what I'm trying to figure out is like, do we end up with a bunch
Speaker 1:  of, you know, like shopping
Speaker 1:  creators or does shopping just come to all creators?
Speaker 11:  Yeah, it's really interesting because I think, I think the other thing is
Speaker 11:  like a creator and a seller is not necessarily always the same thing.
Speaker 11:  Creators are entertainers and some of them might do sales very well,
Speaker 11:  but when you're, when you're just a seller, you know what I mean? When you're
Speaker 11:  just there to like make the sale. I don't know if that's as enticing. Yeah.
Speaker 11:  You know, I I, I actually was flipping, I noticed that I had Amazon's live
Speaker 11:  shopping app on my, on my tv and so I was like, I'm just gonna check this
Speaker 11:  out. And I'm like, I don't care. I don't want any of this.
Speaker 11:  Like, I'm not going to a live channel
Speaker 11:  to just like randomly shop
Speaker 1:  Just having a person hold a thing up and be like, here is what it looks like
Speaker 1:  and how it feels is something, but that's not the sort of full
Speaker 1:  potential of live shopping. I think like that's the thing where it's like,
Speaker 1:  okay, this is a person that I either I know or I trust for some reason.
Speaker 1:  Like that stuff feels really powerful to me. And it's like that's, that stuff
Speaker 1:  starts to feel different when it's like, okay, I'm now sort of shopping with
Speaker 1:  the help of someone I care about and trust. Not there's a hand model
Speaker 1:  on my phone. Right. You know what I mean? And I think I, it's gonna be interesting
Speaker 1:  to see if these big retailers can figure out how to get some of that
Speaker 1:  magic of that first thing over time. Or if all of the
Speaker 1:  creator platforms will just figure out how to build buy buttons and they'll
Speaker 1:  kind of win that race from the other direction.
Speaker 11:  Right.
Speaker 1:  So now that we've both spent a lot of time in this world, are you, are you
Speaker 1:  as obsessed with live streams as I am or live shopping in general? Have you
Speaker 1:  bought anything on a live stream? Be honest,
Speaker 11:  I have not bought anything on a live stream. No.
Speaker 1:  No.
Speaker 11:  Okay. I have, I have been looking at many
Speaker 11:  more lives than I I ever did before. Like it's just one of those things
Speaker 11:  I was, I feel like I was scrolling past, but there's a lot of people doing
Speaker 11:  interesting stuff. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. This feeling like not only do I get to see somebody else's reality,
Speaker 1:  but in some small way shape it, I think is like
Speaker 1:  intoxicating to people. Yeah. Yeah. And I totally get that feeling. Even
Speaker 1:  just like the, this, this dumb girl I was talking about at the beginning,
Speaker 1:  who wouldn't go in the water. Like when she
Speaker 1:  eventually, like everybody got so mad at her on the stream,
Speaker 1:  she started being like, okay, fine. And then the stream was so proud of itself
Speaker 1:  for finally convincing her to do this. You're, you get to like be an avatar
Speaker 1:  in somebody else's world for a minute and there's something kind of amazing
Speaker 1:  about that.
Speaker 11:  Totally. I think that like, building in any kind of tension really works
Speaker 11:  for live streams. Is the wave gonna crash? Is she gonna
Speaker 11:  go in the water? Like, is he, he gonna miss all of those things? It's like
Speaker 11:  that's what keeps you on. Yep. You're waiting, you're there's
Speaker 11:  anticipation. Totally. And it takes a long time. It's real life, you know,
Speaker 11:  it's not edited and cut. So, and I found that watching a lot of
Speaker 11:  streams where I'm like, well, is he gonna actually fix the dire, I mean
Speaker 11:  the most Right. Mundane thing, but like, why am I still watching it, but
Speaker 11:  I like wanna see
Speaker 1:  It. Yeah. I used to think of that as, as a, as a bug of live streams that
Speaker 1:  it was so sort of inefficient in its use of time that it's like, if I just
Speaker 1:  wanna watch somebody fix the tire, like I'll just come back for the clip.
Speaker 1:  But no, it's actually, it feels real. It's like you, you are actually watching
Speaker 1:  somebody's life and this stuff takes time and there's something kind of powerful
Speaker 1:  about that. Totally. Just don't do it before bed. That's my
Speaker 11:  Takeaway. Okay. I think that's a, that's a good call. I'll need that advice.
Speaker 1:  All right. Well Hadley, thank you for joining me deep, deep down this
Speaker 1:  crazy rabbit hole of live streams. I also want you to know that as we've
Speaker 1:  been doing this, I did just go tonot.com and I am now watching
Speaker 1:  someone sell sports cards and all of a sudden I might buy one. This
Speaker 1:  is a real problem that I'm having. Wow. So we should go before I get, before
Speaker 1:  I spend a whole bunch of money that I don't have on trading
Speaker 11:  Cards. Yeah, good
Speaker 11:  call.
Speaker 11:  This episode was produced by David Pierce and Hadley Robinson. It
Speaker 11:  was mixed by Andrew Marino. Liam James is our lead producer, and
Speaker 11:  Brooke Min is our editorial director. The Vergecast is a Verge
Speaker 11:  production and part of the Vox Media podcast
Speaker 11:  network