# Transcript
ID: fa77e2a0-3bdf-11ed-a72e-278e72d98f43
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Apple Watch Ultra review: an aspirational debut
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-8915080539962859767/-4972488652980917559/s93290-US-4681s-1664006774.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, Alex Cranz, David Pierce, and Victoria Song discuss using the new Apple Watch Ultra, the next-gen GPUs, and a bunch of gadget news.
Future reading:
Apple Watch Ultra review
Apple AirPods Pro (second-gen) review: same look, better everything else
This RTX 4090 is so ridiculous it needs a ‘Dark Obelisk’ RGB support stick
Nvidia announces next-gen RTX 4090 and RTX 4080 GPUs
Nvidia says it built too many GPUs — expect sales while it works on something `new`
DJI's new smartphone gimbal aims to get you filming quicker than ever
Logitech’s G Cloud Gaming Handheld arrives in October for $349.99
ByteDance’s Pico 4 VR headset is a Meta Quest 2 competitor
Framework’s new Chromebook is upgradable and customizable
This new turntable can play music directly to a Sonos system
The PS Vita’s time is now, again
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we'd love to hear from you.
We are conducting a short audience survey to help plan for our future and hear from you. To participate, head to vox.com/podsurvey, and thank you!
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (14 ads detected)
Speaker 2:  Today on the Vergecast Victoria's song, joins the show for a deep dive on
Speaker 2:  the apple watch ultra. And for some reason, we let Alex talk about JPS. Again.
Speaker 2:  It's coming up right after this. That's the Vergecast coming up
Speaker 2:  now
Speaker 2:  Hello and welcome to our chest. The flagship podcast
Speaker 2:  of very large wrist wear.
Speaker 5:  Yeah,
Speaker 2:  It's good. Honestly, I didn't think about it too much beforehand. Anyway,
Speaker 2:  I'm your friend. Eli. David Pierce is here.
Speaker 6:  Hi, I have a small blast and I'm sad about it now, but we're gonna talk
Speaker 6:  about it. I have feelings.
Speaker 2:  Well get ready, Alex. Kranz is
Speaker 5:  Here. I once had a 50 millimeter watch, but I was also in third
Speaker 5:  grade. So it was just like comical.
Speaker 2:  Did he just look like flavor play?
Speaker 5:  There's a photo somewhere on the internet of me with it. It's incredible
Speaker 5:  little like Bob haircut. It's great.
Speaker 2:  And Victoria song is here. Hey back.
Speaker 7:  Hey, I am double resting the largest apple watch possible.
Speaker 7:  And the smallest ones simultaneously,
Speaker 2:  Are you like selectively deciding which one to deploy depending
Speaker 2:  on situation like I'm at the bank. Big
Speaker 2:  watch
Speaker 7:  I should, but I haven't. So I will now.
Speaker 2:  All right, well, we'll get into it because V just re reviewed the apple watch
Speaker 2:  ultra of which I spent. I don't know what my
Speaker 2:  contribution was. They sent me one too, and I also played with it, but V
Speaker 2:  actually reviewed it in the context of an actual review. I just tried to
Speaker 2:  avoid breaking my NDA. As I walked around the world with a giant watch.
Speaker 2:  Marist.
Speaker 6:  How successful were you? Actually, I actually wanna this about both of you,
Speaker 6:  because one of the things we heard from apple, like right off the bat, like
Speaker 6:  there was this story that they were telling us that like during the event,
Speaker 6:  as they announced the ultra, all the apple executives had to take off their
Speaker 6:  watches and put on ultras because otherwise they were so large. You'd be
Speaker 6:  able to tell. Yeah. Did you guys get caught out for wearing ultras
Speaker 6:  before you were supposed to
Speaker 2:  Like constantly?
Speaker 7:  Not at all?
Speaker 6:  No.
Speaker 2:  That's so
Speaker 7:  Funny. No, not at all. Which you would think people would notice it more
Speaker 7:  on me because I have really petite risks, but you know,
Speaker 7:  I went grocery shopping. I went to all these places, not a single person
Speaker 7:  clocked it on me. And when I went hiking with my friends, one of them
Speaker 7:  was just like, oh, is that the new series eight? And she's a non-techie so
Speaker 7:  yeah. Yeah. That's that's to be expected. I was like, no, you, he,
Speaker 7:  then it's an old,
Speaker 2:  Well, I will say so it happened to, and I live in the middle of nowhere at
Speaker 2:  like 20 yards away at a golf course. A dude came, which I think is
Speaker 2:  like, where dudes notice watches. Yes. Like that's a target rich
Speaker 2:  environment for watched dudes once the grocery store. And
Speaker 2:  then when I was getting my new booster, the pharmacist, like needle and
Speaker 2:  hand, right. Like shooting the stuff in the air, I was like, Ooh. And I was
Speaker 2:  like, let's one step at a time. I'll talk to you
Speaker 2:  about this afterwards. So yeah. I mean, I, maybe it's just like a, like a
Speaker 2:  dude's noticing, watch this thing, but I just it's so big.
Speaker 2:  Also what watch face were you using? V
Speaker 7:  I was switching between a bunch of them, but I was using the Wayfinder one
Speaker 7:  because that's the one that's exclusive to the ultra. Ah,
Speaker 2:  Well, we should say so, like I said, Victoria reviewed the apple watch. We've
Speaker 2:  got AirPods pro the second gen review to talk about. Although I think Chris
Speaker 2:  Welch is coming on the show to really get into it with that soon.
Speaker 2:  There's a bunch of GPU news. Talk about a little lightning round of gadgets.
Speaker 2:  So started with the apple watch review. So I was using the infograph
Speaker 2:  modular face, like the straight face I always use, which is
Speaker 2:  like pretty colorful and full of text. It's got like, I have my
Speaker 2:  calendar in the middle and it's got obviously the rings and whatever. And
Speaker 2:  that one just seemed like everyone could read it from five miles away.
Speaker 2:  Cause the screen is really big. Yeah. It it's like the main
Speaker 2:  thing. If you're not like an extreme sports athlete, what you're getting
Speaker 2:  out of this is basically infinite battery life and the screen
Speaker 2:  is gigantic.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. So the, the good baby boomer watch, Hey. Or
Speaker 7:  if you're like me and you have the world's worst eyesight. So like I go
Speaker 7:  into the accessibility settings and crank the text up to the
Speaker 7:  largest possible thing and everyone can just read my texts from my wrist.
Speaker 7:  It's bad, but I can read it. So that's great.
Speaker 7:  And yeah, that's all that matters. And texting's easier. No typos when I
Speaker 7:  use swipe to type on the ultra, whereas it's typo city everywhere else. So
Speaker 7:  there are benefits.
Speaker 2:  It's big enough that I could just push the letters. I wasn't even swiping.
Speaker 2:  I was just like, boo, boop. Like, this is just a keyboard that I'm
Speaker 2:  using on my wrist. I think it's in your review. Like this is as close to
Speaker 2:  like an iPhone on your wrist. Yeah. As you can get
Speaker 2:  without actually crossing over to it's a phone on your wrist,
Speaker 7:  Especially because the screen is flat.
Speaker 6:  The you, I, I know you have tried to do this many times and it's
Speaker 6:  borderline impossible, but like I still cannot wrap my head around how
Speaker 6:  big this thing actually is to wear all day. Because like you see all the
Speaker 6:  pictures everybody's wrists are different. And like, I think you
Speaker 6:  had the same experience I did in mine was much briefer, but like
Speaker 6:  picking it up and putting it on and being like, oh, this is lighter than
Speaker 6:  I expected. It doesn't feel monstrous, but like, it looks
Speaker 6:  humongous. And I feel like I'm like putting on my coat. I feel like it
Speaker 6:  would catch every single time. I feel like I would like scratch it on doorways
Speaker 6:  as I walk through. Like, I don't know how big is this thing
Speaker 7:  Actually. Well, David, I'm glad you asked because I had such
Speaker 7:  cognitive dissonance over the past week. I was like, am I getting ultra
Speaker 7:  pilled? Do I not understand what sizes anymore what's going
Speaker 7:  on? And the thing is is that this is a 49 millimeter
Speaker 7:  watch, but it's like, I would say it's the equivalent of a 50 to
Speaker 7:  51 millimeter round watch. But it gets to be small. Like
Speaker 7:  you can tell, I have spent like nights staring at the ceiling
Speaker 7:  thinking about the size because I
Speaker 5:  Was it's just like,
Speaker 7:  So the width is 44 mill. See, I can tell you the measurements off the
Speaker 7:  top of my head. I even bought digital calibers to help me because I was having,
Speaker 7:  like, I was having just such an existential crisis.
Speaker 7:  Cause I don't love big watches. And the, it, it is like
Speaker 7:  44 millimeters in terms of the width, which is the same as the
Speaker 7:  44 to 45 millimeter apple watches. Okay. Which is why, when you
Speaker 7:  look at it, it doesn't seem as humongous as a
Speaker 7:  49 millimeter watch should be. If this was a 49
Speaker 7:  millimeter round watch, it would look like a dinner plate. Yeah. On my wrist.
Speaker 7:  That makes sense. Now it just looks gigantic, but not like, wait,
Speaker 7:  oh my God, what are you doing? Gigantic.
Speaker 2:  I don't think I put this together. You're saying it's it's the same width
Speaker 2:  is the previous ones. But it's taller. Yes. The software has to have
Speaker 2:  scaled differently
Speaker 7:  Then. Yeah, it does. But when you put the
Speaker 7:  45 millimeter series eight next to the
Speaker 7:  49 millimeter series eight, you're just kind of like, oh, it's not that big.
Speaker 7:  But you know, at the same time, if you put the 40 or 41 millimeter watches
Speaker 7:  next to the 45 ones, you're like, oh, that's not that big. It's when you
Speaker 7:  put the, the smallest watches next to the largest one that you're like, oh,
Speaker 7:  this is honking huge. This is gigantic. This
Speaker 2:  Is
Speaker 7:  What the hell. It's the size of a fig Newton. That's what it is.
Speaker 5:  I was about to say, you, you, you were tweeting with like calibers and like
Speaker 5:  it's the size of a fig Newton, which is heavier a fig Newton
Speaker 5:  or the watch, the
Speaker 7:  Watch.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 7:  A fig Newton is not titanium. It's
Speaker 7:  it's
Speaker 5:  I mean, they're, they're hefty cookies
Speaker 2:  Also extremely limited connectivity on a few
Speaker 5:  Moon. Yeah, no, yeah. Really bad connectivity
Speaker 2:  Zig. The only,
Speaker 5:  It's almost none.
Speaker 6:  You can only swipe type on the fig Newton. It's a real problem.
Speaker 7:  I was just trying to find something that everyone could like go into their
Speaker 7:  house and be like, oh, this is what it is so that you don't have to like
Speaker 7:  memorize numbers.
Speaker 2:  I I'm excited for the people out there who are gonna put a fig Nuant on the
Speaker 2:  wrist. Just like for a day.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It's just to figure it out, like
Speaker 6:  Having a bag of flour to prepare for
Speaker 2:  Like the Palm team walked around with a block of wood to like, see what
Speaker 2:  a Palm pilot would look like. Like I'm just gotta fig Nuant to my wrist.
Speaker 2:  I'm just seeing if this is worth $800. That's the, the size of it is
Speaker 2:  something it's lighter than you think. I actually, I think it's too big and
Speaker 2:  I have bigger wrists than V V. It sounds like, like you are all tripled.
Speaker 2:  You're like, this is fine. This is what I'm doing. I
Speaker 7:  Really hate to admit it. But I was talking with Dan over slack and we're
Speaker 7:  like, are we ultra pilled? Are we okay? What's wrong? Because we're both
Speaker 7:  very firmly on the side. That smart watches are getting too big. And I still
Speaker 7:  believe that it's just, you know, I didn't realize how bad my eyesight has
Speaker 7:  gotten over the course of my life because I'm just like, wow, I can read
Speaker 7:  without squinting and putting it right directly in front of my face. And
Speaker 7:  that's yeah. Been a revelation. So like, there are are reasons to have a
Speaker 7:  bigger watch. Fashion is absolutely not one of them, but there are
Speaker 7:  reasons
Speaker 2:  MI Eli I'm shocked. You're a big watch guy though. I mean, I
Speaker 2:  do wear a larger watch when I, well, I buy the larger
Speaker 2:  apple Watchers, just still not a big watch on me. And then when I wear a
Speaker 2:  regular watch, I tend to buy big washes. But, but you think this is too big,
Speaker 2:  you know, it's inter it's the thing that he's talking about with the
Speaker 2:  screen. So I'm very much appreciate the screen is
Speaker 2:  bigger. I am like paranoid that if I was in an office
Speaker 2:  or out in the world, like everyone could read my texts. Like it's, I don't
Speaker 2:  need to turn up the font size all the way, but it's already at
Speaker 2:  its default. Just like big enough to, I think you can just comfortably read
Speaker 2:  it from far away. So like, you know, and you can just like change all the
Speaker 2:  settings. I've turned it all off. So it shows you the preview until you hold
Speaker 2:  it up. But there's like a, I think there's a real balance here between
Speaker 2:  how personal, the information that comes through on your wrist is
Speaker 2:  on a thing that's on display versus how big the screen is. And I,
Speaker 2:  you know, I just like have to use it to be comfortable like thinking,
Speaker 2:  oh, maybe one time the text will come through the settings won't work and
Speaker 2:  you'll just be able to read whatever summit. Cause my hand's on the table.
Speaker 5:  I'm just thinking of like celebrities at a basketball game, sitting court
Speaker 5:  side, and they get like a really spicy text from somebody.
Speaker 5:  And it's just photographed by everyone,
Speaker 2:  Everyone you're thinking of like Adam Levine being
Speaker 5:  Like, yeah, just that spicy text
Speaker 2:  Way with his apple watch
Speaker 5:  Courtside Lakers. I
Speaker 2:  Don't know. I, I know where your brain went immediately.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Immediately. Incredible.
Speaker 2:  Well, we won't quote the Adam Levine text. I will tell you that you should
Speaker 2:  read them cuz they're hilarious. They're
Speaker 5:  Very funny.
Speaker 2:  Flatly hilarious. And it's also not black. Yeah. So for $800, I
Speaker 2:  want a black one.
Speaker 5:  Oh, interesting. The colors part of the problem for
Speaker 2:  You. Yeah. I think it would like look smaller if it was black. Also I like
Speaker 2:  things that are black and it's you only can only get one color. Your choices
Speaker 2:  are what extremely loud color band do you want? And
Speaker 2:  I spent the day wearing the orange one. The that's the trail one, right?
Speaker 7:  That's the Alpine one. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And I was just walking around being like, I'm already paranoid. Everyone's
Speaker 2:  looking at this thing and now it's bright orange.
Speaker 5:  Like,
Speaker 2:  And I'm just in my house. I mean, but these
Speaker 2:  are like purely aesthetic concerns. I think the other thing for me, and I
Speaker 2:  don't know if you felt this way, that software is so much the
Speaker 2:  same and it really is just scaled up. And it's
Speaker 2:  surprising to me that I didn't even realize it wasn't scaled like perfectly
Speaker 2:  linearly that the screen is taller than it is wide on the series eight
Speaker 2:  because it it's so similar that unless you are paying attention, you would
Speaker 2:  not see it. That actually the screen is a different aspect ratio and the
Speaker 2:  software has changed its scaling because unless you're using one of the new
Speaker 2:  modes, the experience of this watch apart from the battery life, which is
Speaker 2:  phenomenal, is exactly the same.
Speaker 7:  That's kind of the story of all three of the apple watches this time
Speaker 7:  around is that the bulk of what makes them good is in watch a west
Speaker 7:  nine, which is it's a significant update compared to like watch USA. It was
Speaker 7:  just like, Hey, be more Zen. You're all stressed. But watch OS nine is an
Speaker 7:  actual update update. And it's just kind of
Speaker 7:  weird what they decided to include on what watch, but just
Speaker 7:  generally speaking, having used all of them, the software experience
Speaker 7:  is basically the same. So you're really only getting
Speaker 7:  the ultra for either aesthetic or durability
Speaker 7:  or battery reasons. And let's be real. Most, most people don't need
Speaker 7:  the durability, even though, you know, people are screaming that I need the
Speaker 7:  Sapphire crystal, most of you don't you, you just don't like
Speaker 7:  you don't
Speaker 5:  Well, I, I thought there was interesting. There's some stuff that's gate
Speaker 5:  kept to it. That seems really odd to be gate kept to it like the, the night
Speaker 5:  mode where it just goes completely red. Why is that only on
Speaker 5:  that watch and not the other ones. Do we have an answer to that?
Speaker 7:  I guess they're assuming that you're going to be in pitch black conditions
Speaker 7:  outside when you're on a trail and that might help you read more New
Speaker 7:  York city has so much light pollution that I didn't really get to try it
Speaker 7:  in pitch black settings just yet. I will in Iceland, but you know, I did
Speaker 7:  sit in a closet. I did turn the lights off.
Speaker 5:  Thank you.
Speaker 7:  And I did turn it on night mode and I was like, oh, okay. This is fine. I
Speaker 7:  feel like a gamer. That's cool. I guess it works. I don't know that
Speaker 7:  it's actually easier to read.
Speaker 5:  Somebody was tweeting about how like they were an astronomer and that mode
Speaker 5:  was gonna be really exciting for them because their eyes weren't gonna get,
Speaker 5:  like they wouldn't have to worry about the light change fluctuations. Like
Speaker 5:  they would with a regular watch.
Speaker 2:  Oh, I have an app on my phone called Skyview where you like, hold it up to
Speaker 2:  the sky and it shows you where the stars are and it has that red mode and
Speaker 2:  it rules.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Also that app is cool. If you can see stars and I
Speaker 7:  Have to try
Speaker 2:  It. Yeah. Yeah. It's a great
Speaker 5:  Idea. That seems dope.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. I'm gonna go chase the Northern lights next week in Iceland. So
Speaker 7:  I'll try it then and report back.
Speaker 5:  Does it only work with like pitch black
Speaker 5:  conditions?
Speaker 7:  I just don't think like if you're in a closet and you turn the lights off,
Speaker 7:  it's just like, anti-climactic, you're like, oh, it's red. That's
Speaker 7:  fine.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Like I really think it's gonna be for outdoor use that you really see the
Speaker 7:  difference. And I just, you know, there's fricking street lights on every
Speaker 7:  corner in New York. It's not
Speaker 2:  And no apple standard, apple watch owner is ever outside in the dark. No,
Speaker 2:  never
Speaker 5:  Happens. Never. I've never, never been outside in the dark. Like that was
Speaker 5:  the thing that kind of bumped me about about it was like, oh, I would use
Speaker 5:  that constantly because when I'm trying to, like, I wear my watch a
Speaker 5:  lot of times when I'm sleeping and the, the normal
Speaker 5:  modes are all too bright, like I've tried setting up a dark red and it's
Speaker 5:  just, this seems much better.
Speaker 2:  What's fascinating about this is it's not a feature of the watch. It is a
Speaker 2:  feature of the watch face.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  And you have to like, none of the other watch faces inherit this
Speaker 2:  mode. Right. Which is weird for this watch. You think they could just sort
Speaker 2:  of add it to everything, but it's just this one watch face, which you could
Speaker 2:  theoretically just bring to the other apple watches. Right. But
Speaker 2:  apple actually restricts watch face creation on the
Speaker 2:  apple washer. Some mystifying reason.
Speaker 5:  There's a color that I have the stainless steel gold watch.
Speaker 5:  And so I have a gold color, but I'm only allowed to use it on this
Speaker 5:  watch. Not any of the other watches I might have. And only in certain
Speaker 5:  watch faces other watch faces. It's like, no, you don't get gold. You can
Speaker 5:  get brown or you can get yellow. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  It's
Speaker 5:  Just the restrictions on watch faces is super weird at this point.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And then they opened up the Nike watch faces to all the watches this
Speaker 2:  time. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And the IME ones as well,
Speaker 2:  Looking at the IME, that's the one that like there's ones that I would
Speaker 2:  understand. Yeah. Like IES one is like, yeah, you gotta
Speaker 2:  buy one. You
Speaker 5:  Gotta spin the money.
Speaker 2:  Like, yeah. I can put a Gucci logo wallpaper on my phone
Speaker 2:  whenever I want. Like, I can be
Speaker 2:  that guy. Yeah. I'm a 40 year old Indian man. I can put a Gucci logo
Speaker 2:  wallpaper on my phone whenever I want it's in character. But
Speaker 2:  I just like, but it doesn't make it a Gucci phone kind of does. Whereas I
Speaker 2:  think like that, that makes sense with the it's weird, like what they allow
Speaker 2:  and what they, I think it just comes down to how they think about it as a
Speaker 2:  fashion object, as much as a, a tech object and
Speaker 2:  that dynamic is back and forth and it never really, it
Speaker 2:  hasn't really landed on in a thing that you can understand.
Speaker 6:  No, it's in that messy middle of like, they want to give you more stuff to
Speaker 6:  do, but not so much that you can make it ugly. It's like we talked about
Speaker 6:  this with the, the iOS 16 lock screens, to some extent almost right.
Speaker 6:  It's like they're caught between wanting people to customize things so that
Speaker 6:  they like them and doing things that are like aesthetically pleasing to the
Speaker 6:  12 designers at apple who make these things. And those two things turn out
Speaker 6:  to be further apart, I think, than they get credit for sometimes.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. He's just, but there's a spreadsheet somewhere like Tim cook has an
Speaker 2:  Excel spreadsheet. He has mini on files on his iPad
Speaker 5:  Is so many,
Speaker 2:  It's very confusing situation for him.
Speaker 2:  That's like a model of, if we allow everyone
Speaker 2:  to use the Imez apple watch, watch face, this is how many
Speaker 2:  fewer Imez apple watches. We, we will
Speaker 2:  sell from
Speaker 6:  Two, five.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Someone has done that. Math
Speaker 5:  To me now only 10 people are buying it. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Right. And then they've made that decision. And then at the same time they've
Speaker 2:  made a decision. That's like, if we let other people turn their watch faces
Speaker 2:  red, we will not sell apple. Watch ultras. Like apple is an
Speaker 2:  instinctual and you know, somewhat, somewhat, emotionally driven company,
Speaker 2:  but it's also a company that's run by Tim cook. And there's definitely a
Speaker 2:  spreadsheet in files app on an iPad somewhere. Yes. That's like, how do we
Speaker 2:  restrict some features to SEL more watches? And it's weird that the
Speaker 2:  extremely high end luxury watch face is like, screw it. Everyone can
Speaker 2:  have it. And the it's red is like,
Speaker 5:  No, no, you gotta pay for that.
Speaker 6:  I think that probably says a lot about what apple thinks sells
Speaker 6:  apple watches. Like I think, I think you could make a pretty strong case
Speaker 6:  that a lot more people want a red face than want on Herme face and are willing
Speaker 6:  to pay extra money for it at this point in the life of the apple
Speaker 6:  watch. But then the, the Nike one is a good example, right. Where that has
Speaker 6:  become so much like a sort of
Speaker 6:  mainstream piece of what people do with the apple watch that having like
Speaker 6:  a separate thing that is the Nike apple watch, I think stopped making sense
Speaker 6:  a long time ago. So actually bringing that to everybody tracks,
Speaker 7:  I think the, the red face is also just kind of like,
Speaker 7:  not only from like a fashion standpoint, it's to encourage athletes
Speaker 7:  who are like somewhere between middle intermediate, who
Speaker 7:  aspire to be, I don't know, DC Rainmaker are thinking of,
Speaker 7:  because the compass features like backtrack and Waypoint go all the way back
Speaker 7:  to the series six and you can even get them on the se. So there's like
Speaker 7:  a reason for athletes to actually save some money
Speaker 7:  and not go for the ultra because they have those features. So if you really
Speaker 7:  want people to get the ultra, you have to kind of limit
Speaker 7:  this red mode.
Speaker 5:  You're saying it's for nerds. You're saying it's for gadget
Speaker 5:  nerds who wanna be athletic, but don't really wanna be
Speaker 5:  athletic. Yes. Which is true. Like that's me that's I really want that red
Speaker 5:  face. I want it so bad, but go, I also see you're on
Speaker 2:  This spreadsheet. I know you're
Speaker 5:  One
Speaker 2:  Column of this spreadsheet. Just me things Alex will buy, how do we get
Speaker 2:  crayons dot XLS? It's
Speaker 6:  A long
Speaker 5:  Column. I'm one of those nerds that like, I, I want it because it seems like
Speaker 5:  a cool gadget feature, but I, I don't necessarily wanna pay $800 for
Speaker 5:  it and also have an iPhone on my wrist. Yeah. Or fig Newton, excuse
Speaker 5:  me.
Speaker 2:  Let's talk about those features. So, I mean, that's like the bulk of what
Speaker 2:  you reviewed. Right? They added all these sort of extreme sport features.
Speaker 2:  Even the you're supposed to pick when you buy it, which of the three bands
Speaker 2:  is the extreme adventure that you are in your soul. Right. Are you an ocean?
Speaker 2:  It's
Speaker 6:  Literally a choose your character in a video case.
Speaker 2:  Yes. Very much. It's like which Voltron lion are you? Are you the volcano
Speaker 2:  lion? Are you the ocean lion? Are you the forest
Speaker 2:  lion? I dunno their names.
Speaker 5:  You're the Alpine, right?
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I I'm. I think I'm the, well, I mean, in my heart, I'm the black
Speaker 2:  lion
Speaker 2:  don't need
Speaker 6:  That any further there.
Speaker 2:  Just
Speaker 6:  Leave that right there.
Speaker 2:  That's great. We can end the show here. No further analysis. So,
Speaker 2:  but I think in terms of the apple watch, apple thinks I'm the green
Speaker 2:  lion. So,
Speaker 7:  Well, it also thinks I'm the green lion, but I'm the runner lion. So I
Speaker 7:  was just kind of like, oh, I wanted the trail loop. Yeah. That's the one
Speaker 7:  I wanted. But you gave me the other two that I didn't want. And I understand
Speaker 7:  why, cuz those two are much more visually engaging, but
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Right. But, but that, but you're supposed to like pick like what, who
Speaker 2:  are you? And you like buy one? I, I immediately put my regular apple
Speaker 2:  watchband on the thing. It
Speaker 6:  Was fine. I just wanna say, I like it much better the other way where it's
Speaker 6:  like the sorting hat in Harry Potter, where like you go into an apple store
Speaker 6:  and you say, I would like an ultra. And like someone at apple decides
Speaker 6:  what kind of adventure you
Speaker 2:  Are. Yeah. Serious, like serious. Like all we're doing some
Speaker 2:  on device processing to figure out who you are. Did
Speaker 2:  you know? You loved the ocean. Yeah. Here you go. Like,
Speaker 6:  I love to run. And it's like, no, you don't. You'll never run
Speaker 6:  again.
Speaker 7:  I gotta say I wanted the trail loop because it is
Speaker 7:  the lightest thing that I have ever picked up as far as like
Speaker 7:  straps go. And in my head, I was like, okay, they're gonna give me the trail
Speaker 7:  loop. All I ever talk about is running. I'm insufferable about running.
Speaker 7:  And this is a big boy watch and I am a small girl. So
Speaker 7:  they're gonna give me the thing. That's gonna trick me into thinking that
Speaker 7:  this is lighter and better than it is. And I opened it up. I was like, I
Speaker 7:  got the orange one. Okay. I'm a
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Cuz you live in the mountains now I'm
Speaker 7:  A bio hazard. That's fine.
Speaker 2:  This is very bright. So let's talk about those modes. So like that's the
Speaker 2:  point of the watch down to like, here's what you can buy it with. It just
Speaker 2:  seems like your review of it was Apple's taking some baby steps,
Speaker 2:  but the garments of the world are safe for now.
Speaker 7:  Yes, absolutely. So I think the biggest emission is
Speaker 7:  the fact that, you know, they're saying explorers, adventurers,
Speaker 7:  this is the watch for you, but we won't give you offline maps or turn by
Speaker 7:  turn navigation. And it's sort of
Speaker 7:  like, Okay,
Speaker 7:  but why? Like I went to a mountain to like test out
Speaker 7:  the compass features over the weekend. And it was very much like me
Speaker 7:  and my buddies had zero cell signal and we had to
Speaker 7:  rely on a combination of the ultras
Speaker 7:  backtrack and the horrible Google maps that wouldn't
Speaker 7:  load and the horrible offline maps that just didn't make sense whatsoever
Speaker 7:  because trail maps never make sense when you look at them. And I was like,
Speaker 7:  oh, you know, if I had a garment, I could just condense all of that into
Speaker 7:  the garment and be fine and have turned by turn navigation. So
Speaker 7:  it would tell me where the F I'm supposed to go. This was just like,
Speaker 7:  I don't know, praying to the gods a little bit. And I was very happy that
Speaker 7:  I had backtrack on because they actually closed one of the gates that you
Speaker 7:  passed through early. So my friends and I were actually kind of stranded
Speaker 7:  and like we have to find an alternate route and we are not good at
Speaker 7:  this. So let's just use a combination of this and
Speaker 7:  look to find a way back to the part where it meets again. So that
Speaker 7:  was, I was really happy to have that. And I write that in my review, but
Speaker 7:  it's just baffling to me that you don't have offline
Speaker 7:  maps or turn by turn navigation, which is basically what puts garment
Speaker 7:  on the map for trail runners and hikers. So that's
Speaker 7:  omission number one that I'm baffled by. Yeah. And then what,
Speaker 6:  And it kind of seems like there's one of those in every category
Speaker 6:  apple is trying to do here. And this is like the thing I kept coming away
Speaker 6:  with from reading your review is basically like apple gets sort
Speaker 6:  of 60% of the way there with a bunch of different things, but never
Speaker 6:  fully completes the job. Like I've talked to a couple of people who are furious
Speaker 6:  that there's no recovery metrics in the, the workout stuff. And that's
Speaker 6:  a huge problem. And it's like for a giant number of people that is an instant
Speaker 6:  deal breaker. And it just feels like the list of those is long enough that
Speaker 6:  you kind of get to the end and it's like, is there anyone for whom this is
Speaker 6:  like actually correctly designed?
Speaker 7:  Yeah, I really do think it's for weekend warriors and it's for
Speaker 7:  intermediate people who are making the leap. So like an
Speaker 7:  example, again, running that I would give is someone who is very comfortable
Speaker 7:  running a 10 K probably has a half marathon under their belt and
Speaker 7:  is like looking at the, which we call it the
Speaker 7:  full marathon and going like, Hmm. Like that level
Speaker 7:  of person I think is who this is for, because you
Speaker 7:  don't want necessarily the garment like deluge
Speaker 7:  of clunky interface and 70,000 charts
Speaker 7:  and maps that you have to kind of sit and read what they mean. That type
Speaker 7:  of person, this is gonna be easier for you just because it's,
Speaker 7:  it's just, it just is. And then there are people who really like Excel
Speaker 7:  spreadsheets and tracking all of that stuff on their own. And then on top
Speaker 7:  of that just want, they don't wanna make a compromise between
Speaker 7:  a fitness watch and a smart watch. Right? So they're looking for, like,
Speaker 7:  I have seen readers comment on my reviews. Like God
Speaker 7:  I'm thinking of ditch and garment because I just need something that's smarter
Speaker 7:  because they're not out every single day doing
Speaker 7:  three hours of exercise. They're, they're backpacking on a weekend.
Speaker 7:  Those are the people who this is gonna be really great for.
Speaker 7:  But if you have people who are like, this is my 50th marathon, I
Speaker 7:  take training super seriously. Right. And if I'm a woman, I train
Speaker 7:  based on my cycle, like there are those athletes out there. This is not gonna
Speaker 7:  be enough for you. You need those recovery metrics. You need to understand
Speaker 7:  like where your, your physical strain is at. And you know, like
Speaker 7:  those recovery metrics are kind of, let's just say, take the accuracy with
Speaker 7:  the grain of salt, but those are the people who this is just not
Speaker 7:  gonna do enough for. So it's just a really
Speaker 7:  interesting, it's just interesting. And I, I attribute a lot of that to the
Speaker 7:  fact that this is their first attempt. I really think Darin should be like,
Speaker 7:  Ooh, we're cool for now next year. I think, I think it would be a
Speaker 7:  mistake for them not to see what Apple's doing and start
Speaker 7:  brainstorming. If they're not brainstorming, that's, that's a huge mistake.
Speaker 7:  But right now they're like, we're fine. Like that's how I
Speaker 7:  feel.
Speaker 5:  I just really wanna go back to, you said one of the, kind of the core audience
Speaker 5:  members for this is someone who really
Speaker 5:  loves spreadsheets and also really just
Speaker 5:  wants a watch. That looks nice. So is that just Tim cook?
Speaker 6:  That's literally just Tim cook.
Speaker 2:  That's
Speaker 5:  Just cook. Yeah. That's I love that. I love that. Tim's
Speaker 2:  Like, wait, no, I didn't. You mean people who train with spreadsheets?
Speaker 2:  Maybe
Speaker 5:  He does. He has spreadsheets for everything. I absolutely believe Tim has
Speaker 5:  a spreadsheet for his exercise workout. Like his exercise routine.
Speaker 2:  I tweeted a poll the other day to just because the thought came to me that
Speaker 2:  all the current tech CEOs have to be spreadsheet masterminds. Cuz they're
Speaker 2:  all. I mean just like look at 'em. Yeah. And I was like, who's the best
Speaker 2:  Excel power user. Is it cook Nadella, Piche or
Speaker 2:  Jeff Bezos. Who's no longer the CEO of Amazon, but you gotta put 'em on the
Speaker 2:  list and people like pick Nadella. Cause he runs Microsoft and I'm like,
Speaker 2:  no dude, it's Tim cook.
Speaker 5:  It's Tim cook.
Speaker 7:  It's cook. He's also
Speaker 2:  It's 1000%. He
Speaker 5:  Has never used numbers in his life.
Speaker 2:  He, Tim cook looks at numbers and he is like, get this out my face. He's
Speaker 2:  like,
Speaker 5:  How dare
Speaker 2:  He's
Speaker 6:  He like opens Excel and immediately just like pushes his mouse away. And
Speaker 6:  he's like, I will not be needing this.
Speaker 2:  He's got like the external number head on his, his hands go into
Speaker 2:  straight like sideways macro mode. Do you think he, Tim cook like
Speaker 2:  watches the Excel world championships? Yes.
Speaker 5:  A hundred percent.
Speaker 2:  Yeah man. You know when I was a code, I asked him this like big thinky question
Speaker 2:  about like whether the phone is, you know, like partially to blame for
Speaker 2:  social media, you know like philosophical. And he was like, no, we're fine.
Speaker 2:  I should have been like, do you watch the Excel world champ?
Speaker 6:  Who do you thinks gonna win this year, Tim?
Speaker 2:  Like, it's like you and me buddy. I know Johnny's here, but like you and
Speaker 2:  me eye to eye, he's super in it. He's streaming that shit.
Speaker 2:  And the next time I see him, 100% asking if he
Speaker 2:  watches the Excel world champ. I don't care where my career goes after that.
Speaker 2:  I just need to know the answer. But wait, the, you met people who train with
Speaker 2:  spreadsheets, right? Yeah. Like the people who play video games with
Speaker 7:  Spreadsheets. Yes. I, I know several of them. I am sometimes one of them,
Speaker 7:  myself. I go back and forth. It's it's just too. I have a whole
Speaker 7:  notion page with training info on there. It's sad.
Speaker 7:  Like I'm embarrassed for myself right now admitting it, but
Speaker 2:  Right. But then the garment can like send you CSV data. Right?
Speaker 2:  And the apple watch is just not built to do that.
Speaker 7:  So when I do my testing and I do comparisons, I'm old school
Speaker 7:  and I go spreadsheet, but I know there are smarter ways to do that
Speaker 7:  and to like export all your fitness data. So I'm not
Speaker 7:  the person to ask for that just because I like to be really, really hands
Speaker 7:  on with the data when I'm comparing and I'm anal retentive about the
Speaker 7:  columns and how they look, oh God, this is so embarrassing. But yeah,
Speaker 5:  That's
Speaker 2:  Welcome. This is fine. This is, this is normal. This is where you be. Are
Speaker 2:  your people?
Speaker 7:  Yeah. So like I just have a spreadsheet at home and it is psychotic looking
Speaker 7:  just like percent of change accuracy. And it doesn't,
Speaker 7:  I realized a long time ago that no one wants to read that in the review,
Speaker 7:  but for us assured I'm doing it and I've been doing it for
Speaker 7:  years.
Speaker 5:  I mean, people wanna read that there's an audience. You,
Speaker 7:  You don't wanna read like, okay. So on four different runs, it was off by
Speaker 7:  negative 0.2%. Like as these get more accurate, it gets
Speaker 7:  less relevant. That's the thing like six years ago when I was doing
Speaker 7:  it, I was like, the LG watch sport was super accurate.
Speaker 7:  And this LG watch style was off by zero point, like
Speaker 7:  2% and it's awful. And it was color coded and everything is so
Speaker 7:  sad. But yeah, like accuracy, it's
Speaker 7:  really interesting because accuracy and wearables is less relevant than
Speaker 7:  consistency. It it's just a thing that I came to after a long
Speaker 7:  time. You're if you're consistently inaccurate by the same margin, you can
Speaker 7:  still track your progress.
Speaker 2:  And the progress is the thing that matters most presumably. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  So it just seems like Garin has this advantage, right? Cuz it right now can
Speaker 2:  do more. It's got more metrics for fitness. It has offline
Speaker 2:  maps. It's built to be worn for the task, right? It's like task
Speaker 2:  specific in a way that wearing a garment is a general purpose. Smartwatch
Speaker 2:  doesn't really make any sense. Apple's bridging the gap. Do they have
Speaker 2:  to do more on the general purpose, smartwatch side? Or is it when you
Speaker 2:  push the button and turn on the I'm hiking mode or the I'm diving
Speaker 2:  the ocean mode, it needs to do more there to compete with those specialized
Speaker 2:  devices.
Speaker 7:  It needs to think a little bit harder about design in some, in some ways.
Speaker 7:  So like I love the action button, but the action button was built by
Speaker 7:  a general use company trying to pull in specialized people.
Speaker 7:  But the more I think about the action button, they left out a huge thing
Speaker 7:  with the action button here too, is that a lot of athletes use
Speaker 7:  physical controls to swipe through screens. And you would think that that
Speaker 7:  would be the case with the action button, but it's not, it's all like pause.
Speaker 7:  So like it's great. They thought about really hard about how to make a
Speaker 7:  more intuitive way to pause with physical controls, but they forgot
Speaker 7:  a more intuitive way to use buttons to scroll through
Speaker 7:  menus. Now that's something that, you know, everyone who uses a
Speaker 7:  garment is super used to. It's something they love. It
Speaker 7:  ensures with like, no doubt that if you wear
Speaker 7:  gloves, if your fingers are sweaty, if you're in the elements that you can
Speaker 7:  scroll to the menu that you need. So with apple, they added
Speaker 7:  the workout views, which freaking great. I love the new workout views, but
Speaker 7:  you're still having to scroll with the digital crown in order to view them
Speaker 7:  mid exercise. And that's just, I end up having to take like a
Speaker 7:  short walk break sometimes to, to scroll through it. And the digital crown
Speaker 7:  is bigger. It has grooves. It's more tactile. That's great. But it's not
Speaker 7:  the same thing as being able to press a button and scroll through your menus.
Speaker 7:  And I think that's a, that's a bit of a
Speaker 2:  Whiff. Would you say the digital crown is an input device on par with
Speaker 2:  the mouse and multi touch and
Speaker 2:  the multi-touch display. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Wow. It's just like, don't get me wrong. I
Speaker 7:  don't know
Speaker 8:  You, would you say it's as big a deal as, as the mouse
Speaker 2:  It's revolutionary?
Speaker 7:  No, I misunderstood what you were saying.
Speaker 2:  Cause I'm just saying when apple introduced digital crown, they were like
Speaker 2:  the mouse.
Speaker 7:  Oh no. In multitask. No,
Speaker 2:  No I, and now the digital crown,
Speaker 7:  No, I totally misunderstood. Is the action button there. The action
Speaker 7:  button is not there yet. I actually think the action button should be on
Speaker 7:  every single apple watch it shouldn't just be on the ultra, but
Speaker 7:  it's like David said, it's I wanna say 70% of the way there.
Speaker 7:  I'm super excited that there's a third physical control, which makes things
Speaker 7:  more accessible. But like keeping, it feels
Speaker 7:  like they were saying, you still have to use this digital crown. We made
Speaker 7:  grooves. So it's easier and more tactile for you to use, but really
Speaker 7:  cuz they want it to be the mouse. Cause they want that just the mouse of
Speaker 7:  the watch. But if you really listen to what athletes have been saying
Speaker 7:  online, and I've just been like going through all the comments and questions
Speaker 7:  and opinions, it's just, they wanted a button so that they could scroll
Speaker 7:  through stuff and they don't have it. Aw.
Speaker 2:  I'm shocked that you can't just assign it to open an app on the phone.
Speaker 6:  Yes. This is what I was gonna say. It's so nuts that it's not more customizable.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  You can pick like what six things, five things be like the, and it's apples
Speaker 7:  List, apples list.
Speaker 2:  It's like, you can turn on the it's like the stopwatch, the flashlight and
Speaker 2:  the workout app are
Speaker 7:  What you can do and dive and shortcuts, which, you know, shortcuts are so
Speaker 7:  clunky to program. But so you can do things like if
Speaker 7:  you're willing to go through the whole shortcuts app nonsense,
Speaker 7:  you can like press a button and it'll notify people at your next meeting
Speaker 7:  that you're running late. That's cool. Do much work for me.
Speaker 7:  It would be great if you could do other things. And I think that's coming,
Speaker 7:  you know, cuz there, there are certain, like I just wrote a how to on the
Speaker 7:  action button and there are certain settings in there that make me believe
Speaker 7:  that you'll be able to choose which app it triggers eventually. Oh interesting.
Speaker 7:  But I don't think like right now, like you go to the workout app, there's
Speaker 7:  a little button that says app and you press it. And it's the native workout
Speaker 7:  app. Cause none of the other developers have developed for this yet.
Speaker 7:  But I think in the future they will be. And that'll add some
Speaker 7:  customizability, but right now you have your choice between what apple says
Speaker 7:  you can choose. Like why won't you let me start a timer. Yeah. I
Speaker 7:  would love to start a talking with the action button. Right?
Speaker 2:  Why can't I open the home app or the remote app for the apple?
Speaker 2:  This is, you can tell where I used it. Yeah. Like these, like I make
Speaker 2:  spreadsheets down to the per like half a percent on how consistent the watches
Speaker 2:  are. And I'm like, I'd like to pause the TV. It's very important. Give me
Speaker 2:  the button that I can pause the TV with. I use my apple watch for two
Speaker 2:  factor off like important. Maybe anything. Let me just open
Speaker 2:  authenticator app. Like let me just do it. Why not? You know
Speaker 2:  like it's, that's like the one where you can see how you have to build
Speaker 2:  the entire system of APIs and hooks and blah, blah, blah, blah, blah. For
Speaker 2:  to fully enable it to be customized, but open arbitrary app.
Speaker 2:  I don't think you need to do much work to do it's baffling that they missed
Speaker 2:  that. But you can get there by writing a shortcut. No,
Speaker 2:  which shortcuts totally back
Speaker 6:  Shortcut is an answer to nothing. And there, there will come a time on this
Speaker 6:  podcast where I'm feeling spicy and give you like a 65 minute long rant
Speaker 2:  About I'm setting up the shortcut that notifies you, that you're doing a
Speaker 2:  bad job. And if I push the she's like text David like
Speaker 2:  work a little, little harder buddy, just
Speaker 6:  Like one second. No it's my overwhelming theory about shortcuts. Is
Speaker 6:  that shortcuts.
Speaker 5:  Please do it. Spa it
Speaker 5:  tearing the podcast is
Speaker 6:  You blew
Speaker 2:  Just like
Speaker 6:  You blew it. Yeah, no I'm I'm that's
Speaker 6:  the only good shortcuts idea I've ever heard in my entire life is my point
Speaker 6:  about shortcuts. Shortcuts is a terrible idea. And apple claims
Speaker 6:  it. Everything you don't like about all of your apple devices,
Speaker 6:  Apple's like, oh shortcuts. And that is not an answer to any of it
Speaker 6:  because it shortcuts is a terrible idea.
Speaker 5:  Either. Like just become a developer, but like not
Speaker 2:  Like a good one,
Speaker 5:  Like not a good developer, but just develop, come
Speaker 2:  On. And then there's like, there's a weird, especially in a watch, shortcuts
Speaker 2:  are particularly slow. So the shortcut you set up to open the app is
Speaker 2:  like, you might as well just open the app.
Speaker 7:  So there's a really funny thing cuz I was trying out every
Speaker 7:  single possible use case for the action button. And so I, I
Speaker 7:  dabbled with the shortcuts and I immediately remembered why I don't
Speaker 7:  normally, but you press shortcuts and you select which shortcuts you want.
Speaker 7:  There is one that says, quote, what is a shortcut? And
Speaker 7:  you can set the action button. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  That's my total one,
Speaker 7:  Something that says what is a shortcut? And then it's like, shortcuts are
Speaker 7:  blah, blah, blah. And here are three that you can try. So like one of them
Speaker 7:  that's
Speaker 6:  Literally Clippy. It's just Clipy
Speaker 7:  There was one of them that was just like, oh turn on theater mode. And I
Speaker 7:  was like, literally, so you want me to press it so that I open something
Speaker 7:  else so I can press something to do theater mode when I can just swipe
Speaker 7:  and hit theater mode. That's that was kind of
Speaker 7:  the, so, but
Speaker 2:  You want the shortcut? That's like, you know, I'm going out to do ocean
Speaker 2:  stuff,
Speaker 5:  Ocean stuff, me up watch.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And like, I gotta put my boat in
Speaker 2:  like lockdown mode and I've put all these smart home accessories in my
Speaker 2:  boat and right. As I dive elegantly into the
Speaker 2:  water, I reach over and click and then like all the shades and the
Speaker 2:  boat,
Speaker 5:  A very nice boat
Speaker 2:  In my calling music place.
Speaker 5:  See
Speaker 7:  That's the tech nerd side of it
Speaker 5:  Just
Speaker 2:  That's that's like the far expanse of what you want the shortcut for.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. I don't, you know, I don't know. I don't know that that's true. There's
Speaker 7:  a dive. The dive point is a lot more practical where
Speaker 7:  you press it and it starts your dive for you. You know which
Speaker 2:  No, but yeah, we just add that into the shortcut. Yeah. That's just part
Speaker 2:  of it. So you're like mid dive and you're like, shit, I forgot to prepare
Speaker 2:  for this. I'm already in the air. Kenny
Speaker 6:  G isn't playing yet.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I gotta hit the button. It starts dive mode on the
Speaker 2:  watch. It lights up the underwater speakers. It closes all the shades.
Speaker 2:  It probably turns down your thermostat.
Speaker 5:  It sets the timer to contact help. If you don't appear,
Speaker 2:  I don't know why this isn't in the ads. Why are they crashing cars? They
Speaker 2:  could be doing jazz ocean,
Speaker 7:  Zero people from the, the audience that they aspire
Speaker 7:  to buy this watch would buy this. Like, I mean,
Speaker 7:  when you like, you probably like NELA, you know this
Speaker 5:  Victoria's just like, absolutely not ne
Speaker 7:  No,
Speaker 5:  Your boat is not a thing.
Speaker 7:  It's like when you open the ultra box, we both got the hiking
Speaker 7:  version. Yeah. But you, you like open the box and there's pictures of
Speaker 7:  mountains on there and it's like, haha, you are a hiker
Speaker 7:  now. And I, I was looking at it. I was like, wow, this is extra. But
Speaker 7:  the people who are buying this are like, yes, I am a mountain year. No Mountaineer
Speaker 7:  is going, let me press this shortcut that
Speaker 7:  does this nonsense. That's super techy and nerdy. They're like,
Speaker 7:  oh, let me press this. Yeah, well,
Speaker 5:  No, the hiking one would lock your BMW that you've already cared with
Speaker 5:  your watch because it's ridiculous if you own a BMW because that's the hiker
Speaker 5:  that buys this. Yeah,
Speaker 7:  No it
Speaker 6:  Pops the tent on top of your Subaru. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  That one that one's like running a command team.
Speaker 5:  Subaru owners, student will never own an Applera.
Speaker 2:  I what's the connectivity situation on Subarus these days. Real good
Speaker 2:  Vergecast question right there. Real
Speaker 5:  Bad
Speaker 2:  Students have Bluetooth. Here's what
Speaker 5:  I'm saying. They got Bluetooth, but they they're still using their own like
Speaker 5:  custom built entertainment system software.
Speaker 5:  That's terrible.
Speaker 2:  Right? So what you want is like, you want like the middleware at your house,
Speaker 2:  that's connected to the like Rivian. So you run the shortcut and it
Speaker 2:  like locks your Rivian doors. Right. And like puts it into the, no, the
Speaker 2:  Rivian itself of these air suspension rooms. And
Speaker 5:  Like, this is where your hike is started. No, we'll call the cops if you're
Speaker 5:  not
Speaker 2:  Backing. And then the Rivian like auto drives itself to the bottom of the
Speaker 2:  trail. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  That's what I want.
Speaker 7:  Y'all are wild, but that is not,
Speaker 6:  I just can't stop hearing do subies have Bluetooth as the title of a
Speaker 6:  children's book that ne is gonna write
Speaker 5:  Here's
Speaker 2:  All the parts with Bluetooth do subies have Bluetooth and you
Speaker 2:  unfold. You open the garage. No. And there's like a cross track and it's
Speaker 2:  like, I do.
Speaker 7:  Wow. Okay.
Speaker 2:  Welcome to our show. But it's like this
Speaker 2:  all the
Speaker 7:  Time. See, you guys are a very specialized case. The majority of people who
Speaker 7:  are gonna buy the ultra are not that nerdy.
Speaker 7:  They're nerdy, but don't want to be, they're like going to a hike and
Speaker 7:  they're pressing the, the action button. And they're like, ah, I am disconnected
Speaker 7:  from the world yet. I have this giant honking computer on my wrist. It's
Speaker 7:  that? Like contradiction for the ultra it's.
Speaker 5:  So it's like people who glamp.
Speaker 7:  Yes. It's well, but they glamp.
Speaker 7:  But one level grungier than glamping. If that makes sense.
Speaker 7:  It's
Speaker 6:  People who buy really fancy looking expensive camping.
Speaker 7:  Yes. They buy
Speaker 6:  It's REI customers is basically what we're talking about. So right. Like
Speaker 2:  I was gonna say Yeti.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. It's there. Yeti REI. That's me. Patagonia
Speaker 7:  wears
Speaker 2:  See Alex holding up a Yeti right now. And I know that
Speaker 2:  as she dove into the ocean, she would want to lock down her smartphone.
Speaker 5:  I would, I would want my smart boat to just be like, just quiet
Speaker 5:  down.
Speaker 2:  Although Alex's smart boat would immediately start like pirating movies for
Speaker 2:  her smart boat flex.
Speaker 7:  Oh my God. I
Speaker 5:  Would and have its own server. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  She'd be like start background, ripping DVDs.
Speaker 5:  I need the next episode of she holds
Speaker 6:  Stack the underwater Plex projector turns on.
Speaker 2:  That's very good. I, I wanna say we've exhaustively covered
Speaker 2:  the apple watch ultra
Speaker 7:  Battery. We didn't talk battery
Speaker 2:  With this conversation. Oh,
Speaker 6:  Battery. Okay. We should talk about the battery real quick.
Speaker 7:  It's
Speaker 2:  Good. I was not able to kill it. So I went 56 hours before I
Speaker 2:  went like off the charger. Just line around the house. It's a
Speaker 6:  Lot of apple TV, remote usage in 56 hours. I would
Speaker 6:  assume
Speaker 2:  Furiously Watch. So like that's a horrible test. I was, I don't think it's
Speaker 2:  a basically not using it. It was on my wrist. Hadn't turned on any of the
Speaker 2:  workout modes. Hadn't used cell service, just some wifi. And then
Speaker 2:  I was actually gonna go and play golf where the person spotted me and I knew
Speaker 2:  I was gonna use the workout mode. So I was like, I gotta at least get this
Speaker 2:  thing back up. I had gone 56 hours. I was 14%. And I was like, I, I gotta
Speaker 2:  charge it. Cause I know it'll make it through this VU got to like 60
Speaker 7:  Hours. Yeah. Last night I got to 60 hours with no low power
Speaker 7:  mode on always on display on and several workouts,
Speaker 7:  like, well, several workouts, but a lot of them not GPS
Speaker 7:  related just only one of them was. So, you know, they're saying it
Speaker 7:  can get apple is super conservative with its battery estimate.
Speaker 7:  Cuz you know, they've been saying 18 hours for several watches now and it's
Speaker 7:  more than 18 hours. You're gonna get more than eight, 18 hours. So with the
Speaker 7:  ultra, when they said 36 hours, I was like, mm we're gonna get 48. And
Speaker 7:  generally, if you are working out and using cellular, you're gonna get
Speaker 7:  48 with regular usage. If you have a rest or recovery day or if you just
Speaker 7:  don't work out, which of large portion of people who buy this watch are not
Speaker 7:  people who give a dam about the fitness features whatsoever.
Speaker 7:  They care about the battery. Those people, you can get 60
Speaker 7:  hours without a low power mode enabled without
Speaker 7:  the special, further battery optimization feature that's
Speaker 7:  coming. It's it's insane. The battery life on this. When you
Speaker 7:  think about every other apple watch, that's been, it's the first true multi-day
Speaker 7:  battery that it's just multi-day battery. It's great. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  And I was incredibly impressed with it also, you know, it's interesting.
Speaker 2:  We, the last episode we talked about the iPhone always on display and how
Speaker 2:  much I think it is killing my iPhone. 14 pro battery turned
Speaker 5:  It off immediately is terrible.
Speaker 2:  I turned off now the battery like lasts forever. Yeah. This thing has
Speaker 2:  essentially that same always on display. Yeah. And it's just like just
Speaker 2:  cruising. It's obviously much smaller, but it's just cruising along for
Speaker 2:  hours and hours at a time. It's pretty impressive.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. It's it's I don't know. Like I feel like an always on display
Speaker 7:  is essential to a watch, but really unnecessary for a phone. That's just
Speaker 7:  how I feel. It's it's interesting cuz I thought I would like it
Speaker 7:  always on display on my phone and I was like, nah, I put it like face down
Speaker 7:  all the time anyway. So I don't need it. And I have a watch. It just makes
Speaker 7:  more sense than a watch.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  How did they test the battery on the watch? Like did they, because on the,
Speaker 5:  on the phone, on the laptop they usually do like a video rundown. Are they
Speaker 5:  just playing a tiny video on the watch? Is that what they do?
Speaker 7:  No, not at all.
Speaker 5:  I just really like the idea
Speaker 7:  Of that. I mean, I, I, in some cases I would like a benchmark
Speaker 7:  for like some sort of test I could run on the, the, on the
Speaker 7:  watch, but it's really, that's not useful to anyone at all. It's just
Speaker 7:  lifestyle usage that the, when you're testing the battery life, you have
Speaker 7:  to do okay. Daily smartwatch usage. Okay. Heavy GPS
Speaker 7:  usage and then heavy cellular. So
Speaker 5:  They average a bunch of different like use cases together after they
Speaker 7:  Get those. Yeah. So like usually when you get that's
Speaker 5:  Much less funny.
Speaker 7:  Well, duh, but when you get smart watch
Speaker 7:  battery estimates, there's usually a little asterisk in the fine print where
Speaker 7:  it's just like with about one hour of GPS usage
Speaker 7:  per day under these settings. And, and so like, that's
Speaker 7:  just generally the, the case for it. But apple, I think they take that and
Speaker 7:  then they like minus five hours from it just to, to cover
Speaker 7:  their butts, which is the exact opposite of what Samsung does. And
Speaker 7:  yeah. So they gave us a bunch of different battery estimates for
Speaker 7:  regular usage for absolute max usage and
Speaker 7:  then absolute max usage with low, with like it was with
Speaker 7:  LTE. That's what it was the low
Speaker 5:  Power. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  So it's like, they're saying, if you put low power boat on, you can get 60
Speaker 7:  hours. Well, I got 60 hours without low power mode, so I'm not
Speaker 7:  sure. I don't think there's enough time in the world within one week
Speaker 7:  to meet embargo, to see how long this thing would last with low
Speaker 7:  power battery mode on let alone the additional battery
Speaker 7:  optimization setting that's coming. So I, I, I would like
Speaker 7:  some time to just go, how long can I really
Speaker 7:  make this thing last? But that's different from how long can I make it
Speaker 7:  last within a triathlon. So it's supposed to be able to last
Speaker 7:  with low powered mode on an entire iron man, which is about 14 hours.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. So that's impressive, but still not at the level of a
Speaker 7:  course or a garment. That
Speaker 5:  Seems nice.
Speaker 2:  All right. We have take a break. We spent an hour with
Speaker 2:  really smart thoughts from V thank you on the apple watch and then whatever
Speaker 2:  we did,
Speaker 5:  We were also
Speaker 6:  Here's on his boat on
Speaker 2:  Our boat, also participated. I'm just thinking about my extremely
Speaker 2:  beautiful smart boat. That's great that his power entirely my shortcuts,
Speaker 2:  David, you're gonna have Chris Wal Sean to talk about the AirPods pro
Speaker 2:  gen two in some way. Yes.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. We're gonna do a, a deeper dive on that in the next couple weeks.
Speaker 6:  The short version of it seems to be, they are precisely AirPods pro
Speaker 6:  everything is slightly better. Noise cancellation seems to be potentially
Speaker 6:  substantially better, but not as good as the new bows ones, which seem to
Speaker 6:  be ridiculous, but we'll yeah. We'll, we'll get into that in a big way. In
Speaker 6:  a couple weeks, I think.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. The surprise hit of our second episode segment has been
Speaker 2:  putting Chris Welch in noisy environments and headphones. So we're just
Speaker 2:  gonna double down on that.
Speaker 6:  Some people really like it. Some people really
Speaker 2:  Hate it. So stay tuned for that. We'll talk more about the AirPods coming
Speaker 2:  up. We gonna take a break. We'll be right
Speaker 2:  back.
Speaker 9:  we're back V sticking with us. Thanks for hanging around V but
Speaker 9:  welcome to Alex. Crane's dark GPU zone.
Speaker 9:  Oh,
Speaker 7:  I've been here before. Yeah, you've been here. I've been here before. You've
Speaker 2:  Been here before. That's true. Alex and Victoria used to work together cuz
Speaker 2:  Meto. So she's, I don't know how Crans managed to recruit you
Speaker 2:  back into this situation, but
Speaker 7:  She was always assigning me stuff that I was like, why, why are you doing
Speaker 7:  this? And then she's like, because I know you're gonna have fun.
Speaker 7:  Sorry in advance.
Speaker 9:  So
Speaker 2:  That's great. That's perfect. That really tracks actually.
Speaker 2:  Okay. The reason I called it, the dark GPU zone is Invidia
Speaker 2:  had an event. They announced the RTX 40 90 and the 40, 80.
Speaker 2:  They're huge, et cetera. There's some metaverse stuff we should talk about.
Speaker 2:  Cause I did some metaverse noise in the middle of this keynote. Yeah, but
Speaker 2:  I just gonna, you, this headline, this RTX 40 90 is so ridiculous. It
Speaker 2:  needs a dark Oli RGB support stick. And
Speaker 2:  I purposefully just did not read the rest of that story so I can ask Alex,
Speaker 2:  what is going on?
Speaker 5:  So Nvidia announced they're 40 90, and they're 40, 80, the first of the new
Speaker 5:  40 series. This is the successor to the 30 series itself, the
Speaker 5:  successor to the 20 series, which is when they introduced rate tracing. So
Speaker 5:  like those two previous generations, the 40, 80, and the 40 90 have
Speaker 5:  rate tracing. Great. Like those two previous generations, they're
Speaker 5:  enormous. One of the companies that's making, one of those GPS is
Speaker 5:  GL and they're the ones that really
Speaker 5:  like RGB did up. They've also got like an anonymous
Speaker 5:  hacker thing going on with the, the box. If you look at the box,
Speaker 5:  there's just like a weird dude, like half a mass. So it's like a, some real,
Speaker 5:  real like fan of the opera situation here.
Speaker 2:  Fan milk. The opera. Yeah. It's fan of the opera across with V for vendetta.
Speaker 2:  That's the only way I can describe this look.
Speaker 6:  That's good actually. Yeah, that tracks.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And because these things are, they're big, they're honking huge. They put
Speaker 5:  out a lot of heat. A lot of 'em have, are gonna have a 3.5. Like they'll
Speaker 5:  take up 3.5 slots on the back of your computer. Good
Speaker 5:  Lord.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. It's huge. Like,
Speaker 5:  Ew, my 2080 does two slots and I was like, this is too
Speaker 5:  much. So this one is gonna take up nearly four slots,
Speaker 5:  which is gonna mean a lot less computers are gonna be able to
Speaker 5:  use it, which I personally am bummed about. Cuz I wanted to make a really
Speaker 5:  tiny computer and this will just never fit in it. But this
Speaker 5:  particular one decided that it also needed to have extra fans
Speaker 5:  and this stick and it's just a
Speaker 5:  big
Speaker 2:  And the stick just holds it up. Yes.
Speaker 5:  It's just, this is
Speaker 6:  Some like high tech thing. That's there to like augment the way that it
Speaker 6:  works. It's literally just a thing that holds it up. So it doesn't collapse
Speaker 6:  the rest of your computer
Speaker 5:  Because it's so heavy. Like the way, I mean, I don't know. The last time
Speaker 5:  you guys have built a computer, I love it. But you usually have
Speaker 5:  to like you plug it into the PCI slot. You usually put it pretty far
Speaker 5:  down because it takes up so many slots and you don't wanna like lose a bunch
Speaker 5:  of your other slots. So you have to plug it in pretty far down. And then
Speaker 5:  the only thing holding up a very heavy GPU
Speaker 5:  is the soldering from the P like the PCI slot.
Speaker 5:  And this guy is so heavy that they're like, eh, I don't know if the solderings
Speaker 5:  gonna hold it up. So we need to have a prop.
Speaker 2:  Incredible. So we made a stick and the, the stick itself
Speaker 2:  has RGB
Speaker 5:  Lights. Yeah. And the stick has RGB lights on it. Okay. So,
Speaker 5:  but the other ones, like the founder's edition, which is Invidia's one that
Speaker 5:  it made itself and is releasing does not have the stick. It's only the
Speaker 5:  GL. That's gonna have the big RGB stick.
Speaker 2:  Okay. I just wanna read you the caption,
Speaker 2:  which I know people think our fonts are hard to read, but this font is so
Speaker 2:  hard to read that I'm not a hundred percent sure what all, what it says.
Speaker 2:  My belief of what it says in the caption for this image
Speaker 2:  is 5g exclusive our RGB support
Speaker 2:  stick. And it's the 5g exclusive that really
Speaker 2:  sticks out to me. Oh, no idea what that
Speaker 2:  means. It might be SG exclusive. Maybe
Speaker 2:  it's hard. It's just hard to say unclear. It also might be AR
Speaker 2:  GB. What? None of that makes sense though.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. This thing is like one Bluetooth speaker away from being like the
Speaker 6:  exact center of all of Eli's interests, just right.
Speaker 5:  Party
Speaker 2:  Speaker. I did Sony put out a new party speaker this week. It's
Speaker 2:  $898. And literally the video opens with now with
Speaker 2:  six tweeters, which is
Speaker 2:  just probably so many
Speaker 2:  tweets.
Speaker 2:  I dunno what to
Speaker 5:  Tell still cheaper than any of these GPS.
Speaker 2:  They're like, I'll stick another one on there and make a video $900
Speaker 6:  As always our offer stands to the Sony party team. We will give you one full
Speaker 6:  hour of the first cast. Please come.
Speaker 2:  I Creighton has, has reached out on behalf of Dakota. We will, we will go
Speaker 2:  into it. I want to know how many, $900 party speakers do they sell.
Speaker 2:  That's how I feel about the RTX 40, 90. Yeah. Who is it
Speaker 2:  for?
Speaker 5:  So the 40 80 actually starts at about the same price as the
Speaker 5:  new Saudi speaker, but the 40 90 is gonna start at
Speaker 5:  $1,600. Wow.
Speaker 2:  That's crazy. This picture of theuse one where
Speaker 2:  it's just holding up an entire motherboard in like a T
Speaker 2:  shape is incredible. Like this is one of the biggest
Speaker 2:  graphic scars I've ever seen.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. It's
Speaker 2:  Wild. So what does it do? We, should we have not, we've talked about how
Speaker 2:  big it is and how silly that RGB lights are and whether or not it's a 5g
Speaker 2:  exclusive. It's
Speaker 5:  It's basically just like it's, it's, there's not any of the big, the, the
Speaker 5:  enormous jumps, like we saw with the, the 20, 80, where they finally introduced
Speaker 5:  rate tracing. I'm gonna make lots of people mad because I said that, but
Speaker 5:  it's true. There, there, most of the big jumps here are like, it's gonna
Speaker 5:  be just a lot faster. It's got better storage. It's using G
Speaker 5:  DDR six X memory, which is wicked
Speaker 5:  fast. I've been living in the Northeast too long, but it's just super,
Speaker 5:  super fast. But
Speaker 6:  Isn't there this ADA Lovelace thing that in videos, China say it's like a
Speaker 6:  whole new universe of how everyone thinks about everything.
Speaker 5:  Well, it's their, it's, it's their new architecture, right? Like they they've,
Speaker 5:  they've moved one architecture up. So, so they do kind of a talk, right?
Speaker 5:  Like CPU companies do. And this is, this is their new architecture.
Speaker 5:  But for most people, the practical experience is just gonna be it real
Speaker 5:  fast. Like, like for the major, the vast majority of people,
Speaker 5:  it's just gonna be a lot faster. And the
Speaker 5:  thing that got me really excited is gonna have native AV one support,
Speaker 5:  which is the big, like there's, HGC,
Speaker 5:  that's what most videos are like your phone, your iPhone will
Speaker 5:  record an ag VC. Most, most stuff does. AV. One
Speaker 5:  is an open source video Kodak that's really
Speaker 5:  popular, but it's kind of resource intensive. So it's not used as often as
Speaker 5:  maybe it could be. So this is gonna have native support, which we really
Speaker 5:  helpful for, for streamers and stuff. And anybody who is, for some reason,
Speaker 5:  I don't know, ripping enormous Blueray onto their
Speaker 5:  computer and wanting good playback. So
Speaker 5:  like that was the part that got me the most excited was the AV one support,
Speaker 5:  which is a very small part of the puzzle, but pretty exciting. Maybe apple
Speaker 5:  and other people will start adopting it and using it in their processors.
Speaker 2:  They're never gonna use an
Speaker 5:  They're never going to, they're
Speaker 2:  Never, ever, ever going to happen.
Speaker 5:  They, they they're like who.
Speaker 2:  And they said, they're all in, on their own GP Aion now, which does not require
Speaker 2:  support sticks.
Speaker 5:  Well, no, I think they can still support AV one. Like they can still support
Speaker 5:  this Kodak, but also apple, like, I don't think ever natively
Speaker 5:  supported, like they've always been butts about video codex and video
Speaker 5:  containers and supporting them and just, I'm still very upset
Speaker 2:  Except for E VC.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Except for HEC. They're like, we we're
Speaker 2:  On they're like, what about this one that you hate?
Speaker 5:  Everybody's gonna use it, send it to
Speaker 2:  Everyone. Actually protocol today had Inco protocol, had a piece about Google
Speaker 2:  coming up with its own new open competitor. It's Adobe vision and Atmos.
Speaker 2:  I saw that. And how, because of YouTube, they were able
Speaker 2:  to just force AV one into the world.
Speaker 6:  And now they're trying to do the same thing with basically HDR 10, right?
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. But they're, they're packing it, right. It's fast. Like this is nothing
Speaker 2:  to this video card. The other thing that was really interesting with the
Speaker 2:  Nvidia announcement to me, so RT for 90, 48. Great. That's what we covered.
Speaker 2:  That's like the consumer part, then there was this like hard gear down
Speaker 2:  shift into metaverse like enterprise metaverse
Speaker 2:  stuff, which is becoming an arms
Speaker 2:  race kind of between Nvidia and epic, which makes
Speaker 2:  unreal, so unreal is pushing really hard
Speaker 2:  into Hollywood. So all those new Disney
Speaker 2:  I'm assuming I know it was true of the Mandalorian, I'm assuming, and, or
Speaker 2:  as well shot on huge sound stages with micro L D screens
Speaker 2:  that are showing renders right out of unreal, which is
Speaker 2:  crazy to think about that's happening all over Hollywood. What was the
Speaker 2:  John F just did a whole movie in PR what movie am I thinking of?
Speaker 5:  Thinking of lion king. Yes.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Okay. I'll say that for real, Sean F did like all of the lion king,
Speaker 2:  like directed it in VR. Yeah. Right. So like, there's this big
Speaker 2:  push in Hollywood for that. And then there's something called the, I hate
Speaker 2:  this phrase. There's like enterprise metaverse stuff
Speaker 2:  where they showed Lowe's and other
Speaker 2:  companies like building what they call digital twins
Speaker 2:  of their stores. Yeah. And assembly lines and
Speaker 2:  factories. And then they're having AI try to optimize
Speaker 2:  the layouts of the stores or like the, how the factories work. And you can't
Speaker 2:  do that in real life. You need like an actual 3d model of the thing that
Speaker 2:  works in the same way. And so the, and video's just like pushing super hard
Speaker 2:  into the, the keynote's worth watching just for this part, cuz it's, it's
Speaker 2:  really boring on space. But on the other side you're like, oh, like they
Speaker 2:  can just go capture a whole video game in 3d. Like they can put their camera
Speaker 2:  in the middle of any video game and do volumetric capture the video game
Speaker 2:  and then reconstruct that as like a metaverse situation.
Speaker 6:  Well, and, and not only that, I mean, one of the things Jensen Wong, the
Speaker 6:  CEO of in video did a really good interview with Ben Thompson it's trajectory,
Speaker 6:  I guess like right after the keynote. And one of the things he was talking
Speaker 6:  about is cuz Ben brought up that, that like gear shift you're talking about.
Speaker 6:  And basically what Jensen said is like the future of
Speaker 6:  video games. But also all this other stuff you're talking about, the enterprise
Speaker 6:  universe, you know, know movie making all this stuff is about like
Speaker 6:  generative graphics and the idea that you can like build
Speaker 6:  as you go, it's not just about rendering something really fast at a really
Speaker 6:  high frame rate. You are changing the thing that it is on the fly.
Speaker 6:  Like that's what Minecraft is and Roblox is. And it's like, if we're gonna
Speaker 6:  get to the point where we have these like lifelike meta versus
Speaker 6:  like that is like, holy shit, the GPU
Speaker 6:  power we're gonna need in order to do that in a real way. And that was like,
Speaker 6:  he drew a much sort of straighter line between those two things than
Speaker 6:  I expected. Rich, I thought was really
Speaker 5:  Interesting. I mean, he's like very financially incentivized to off of course
Speaker 5:  that line, right? Like, like we saw NVIDIAs in the toilet. Well not
Speaker 5:  in the toilet, but it's way, way down stock. It's
Speaker 6:  Tough times price, right?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Yeah. And that's because they they've lost. Like they were being
Speaker 5:  propped up to kind of an like
Speaker 5:  absurd degree by cryptocurrency and everybody was
Speaker 5:  buying their, their GPUs to mine and that's gone and they still have a super
Speaker 5:  robust server business. They still have their, this consumer GPU business.
Speaker 5:  They still have their like straight to business GPU business,
Speaker 5:  but they need, they need people to be pumped about GPUs again.
Speaker 5:  Totally. And they're, they're specifically, they're big, super powerful,
Speaker 5:  super hot ones. Cause like these GPS sound really, really great, but they
Speaker 5:  are so far ahead of what you're getting in a PS five or an Xbox,
Speaker 5:  which is what most game developers are developing to. They're not game
Speaker 5:  developers do not develop to Invidia without
Speaker 5:  a lot of stuff going on in the background. Right? Like, like the game developers,
Speaker 5:  right. Go. And they have conversations with them, video and money sometimes
Speaker 5:  exchanges, hands it's it's, it's a wow, Alex, you know, they're
Speaker 5:  working together.
Speaker 6:  Sometimes there's a boat or fan,
Speaker 2:  No, wait a, we really rescue that. You're like, you
Speaker 2:  know, yeah. You just pay 'em to protect you a little bit. It's great. It
Speaker 2:  keeps you safe. It'd be a shame. If something happened to your video
Speaker 2:  game,
Speaker 5:  It's very telling that they're doing like Invidia has DLSS,
Speaker 5:  which is their own it's it's basically like a software
Speaker 5:  that makes the video games look prettier and you have to
Speaker 5:  work with the developers to make, this is like super over
Speaker 5:  oversimplification of DLSS. I'm so
Speaker 5:  sorry. My dog is snoring loudly and asleep. I
Speaker 5:  clue, but DLSS is, is this Invidia
Speaker 5:  software that is like exclusive to Nvidia AMD
Speaker 5:  has their own version of it. Intel's gonna have their own version of it.
Speaker 5:  It's using AI to, to basically upscale games and make games look a lot
Speaker 5:  prettier than they might out of the box, but it still has to be supported
Speaker 5:  by the game developers. And I think it's really telling that only 35 developers
Speaker 5:  are coming out of the box with the new 40 nineties
Speaker 5:  in the 40 eighties. So you're only gonna see 35 games have
Speaker 5:  that support. And that's because the real support, most of the money is
Speaker 5:  going to AMD and to the PS five and the
Speaker 5:  Xbox. So they kind of need bigger business.
Speaker 5:  They need more stuff and yeah. Saying, oh, you wanna
Speaker 5:  go and do like build the metaverse yeah. We're the
Speaker 5:  guys to come talk to. Yeah. Oh, you wanna, you wanna compete and build
Speaker 5:  your own giant mini L E D screen to render graphics on the fly
Speaker 5:  for shooting a movie. Yeah. Come talk to us. Like they need that. If they
Speaker 5:  wanna continue to advance compared to apple, who's just schooling
Speaker 5:  everybody in the GPU and CPU space right now.
Speaker 2:  It's also fascinating. Cuz the idea of you having a big GPU on your desk
Speaker 2:  might be going away is game streaming particularly comes to the foreground.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Well it, I mean, yeah, that was part of the AV one thing here is that they're
Speaker 5:  like, you wanna have the best stream. You wanna have the fastest, most efficient
Speaker 5:  stream and just look the coolest, get a big
Speaker 5:  3.5 slot thick GPU.
Speaker 5:  And if you can fit it in your computer and it won't break the motherboard,
Speaker 5:  it's gonna be a great time for you. Like I don't even think my computer could
Speaker 5:  fit it.
Speaker 2:  All right, David, what were you saying? And then we gotta take a break.
Speaker 6:  I was just gonna say it. I, it is interesting that there's this like huge
Speaker 6:  enterprise pivot for a lot of these companies. And it was, I was just thinking,
Speaker 6:  as I was reading about all this about, I believe it was a Bloomberg story
Speaker 6:  today about all the chief metaverse officers who are getting hired at these
Speaker 6:  companies. Yes. That story rules. It's fantastic. And, and it's
Speaker 6:  basically, these people are getting hired with these big lofty titles and
Speaker 6:  it's like figure out the metaverse and it's like, what the hell do these
Speaker 6:  people do all day? And I think if I'm a company like Invidia, like
Speaker 6:  all these companies are just throwing money at this in case it's like the
Speaker 6:  next big thing. And I think Invidia will not be the last company who just
Speaker 6:  like uses it in a lot of branding things to
Speaker 6:  try and make some money in the short run.
Speaker 2:  But I don't think this is just branding. I, they have built some real tech
Speaker 2:  here. That is fascinating. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  The omniverse thing is very cool.
Speaker 5:  Like they've had this tech for a while where, where they can go and, and,
Speaker 5:  and, and do this because they were originally marketing it to
Speaker 5:  streamers and to gamers. So you could take like the rats
Speaker 5:  screenshots of all time, by being able to move the cameras and stuff in the
Speaker 5:  games,
Speaker 2:  Someone there is someone in a videos like you have to make this real business.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. It's not just screenshots. And they came up with like hyper
Speaker 2:  optimizing a Lowe's layout with AI.
Speaker 5:  Like I cannot tell you how many cess that I went to where they're like, do
Speaker 5:  you wanna see how cool our screenshot camera system is now? And I'm like,
Speaker 5:  okay,
Speaker 2:  Sure. That's great. All we gotta take another break. We got a
Speaker 2:  little, let end, come in, stick around. We'll right
Speaker 2:  back
Speaker 2:  bought this immediately. Why? I don't know why I have
Speaker 2:  an Osmo already that I never use
Speaker 2:  here's. And I was like, oh, you know what? This one feature they added will
Speaker 2:  make me use it. I'm spending $180 on it.
Speaker 5:  Is it the telescope?
Speaker 2:  No, not the selfie stick. It has a magnet.
Speaker 6:  Oh God.
Speaker 2:  And so you put the little mat on your phone so you can pull the phone right
Speaker 2:  off it right away, which is big annoy. But then you clip it back on. It
Speaker 2:  runs a shortcut and it opens the app for you right away.
Speaker 2:  And I was like, oh, this is it. This is I'm gonna be gimbling for days.
Speaker 6:  If only you could launch that app.
Speaker 2:  Are you guys ready to see some of this smoothest, Instagram stories of all
Speaker 2:  time?
Speaker 6:  Oh my God.
Speaker 2:  Cause they're coming and you're gonna think to yourself, God, that boy is
Speaker 2:  smoothly.
Speaker 5:  It's so smooth. No, the
Speaker 5:  shortcut automatically doing stuff.
Speaker 6:  He did not enjoy that. Just now. I just want, I just wanted,
Speaker 2:  Who's just, its never coming on the
Speaker 2:  show.
Speaker 5:  A loud noise. That was a
Speaker 5:  lot.
Speaker 2:  I'm so sorry. That was mine somewhere else. Feel free to
Speaker 2:  go
Speaker 5:  Forward. I mean I'm super excited as I have been for a
Speaker 5:  while about the Logitech G cloud gaming handheld.
Speaker 2:  Oh yeah. It was announced this week.
Speaker 5:  Not excited about that name though. That name is it's very bad.
Speaker 5:  That's a bad name or the price. It's $349
Speaker 5:  and 99 cents, which is the same price as like a budget
Speaker 5:  phone. But I think this is still better than a budget phone for cloud
Speaker 5:  gaming.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. But it, it, I mean, it's the same price as a switch.
Speaker 5:  It's actually more expensive. It's $50, more expensive than a switch and
Speaker 5:  $50 cheaper than the cheapest steam deck you can get. Wow.
Speaker 2:  Okay. But you are excited about it. I'm
Speaker 5:  Still excited about it. I like, I think, I think the phone is a terrible
Speaker 5:  way to cloud game and if we want cloud gaming to be a real thing, there needs
Speaker 5:  to be real hardware to support it. And this is a great first if expensive,
Speaker 5:  poorly named step.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Just the idea that there is like going to be
Speaker 6:  real multi-company multi-platform
Speaker 6:  competition over handheld cloud gaming, I think is
Speaker 6:  very exciting. Cam Foxton on our team wrote a really good story this week.
Speaker 6:  About one a like the, I think the headline was the PSV time is now
Speaker 6:  again,
Speaker 5:  This time it'll
Speaker 6:  Work. And it's like on the one hand, like guy needs a hug. Like he's, he's
Speaker 6:  been through a lot with his PSV, but the other hand, like he's kind of right.
Speaker 6:  It kind of is
Speaker 2:  It's this its
Speaker 6:  Little tiny gaming consoles. Bring back the game. Boy,
Speaker 7:  My husband agree. My husband is such a PS Vita
Speaker 7:  fan. He like will be having dinner and then he'll just sign and
Speaker 7:  go. I miss the PS Vita. I don't
Speaker 7:  understand. I just don't understand. Yeah. He's just like, you don't
Speaker 7:  understand just
Speaker 5:  Eating a tomato being like
Speaker 7:  On a like random road trip. He'll be like, you know, I really miss my PS
Speaker 7:  Vita and it's just like, I don't understand it. I was, I showed him Cam's
Speaker 7:  article and he was like, I've written something like that before, too. I
Speaker 7:  understand.
Speaker 2:  So wait, the GCloud gaming hand, horrible name three 40 as
Speaker 2:  much as switch Ola. That's what I was thinking of.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, but less, less, you know, it's not an Ola display. It's an led
Speaker 5:  it's traditional led display. It's got a
Speaker 5:  Qualcomm snap dragons, seven 20 G
Speaker 5:  processor, four gigabytes of Ram. It's gonna have
Speaker 5:  64 gigabytes of storage in it. It's basically a Chromebook,
Speaker 5:  but for cloud gaming instead of cloud PC.
Speaker 2:  Right. So here's the line that really caught me. You can launch
Speaker 2:  Xbox cloud gaming, but it's just a progressive web
Speaker 2:  app. Yeah. I mean that's amazing, but
Speaker 6:  What yeah. What else do you need it to be? Well,
Speaker 5:  That's the way it's done on, on the steam deck now. Like I've got, I've got
Speaker 5:  the, I went through the whole process of setting up X cloud
Speaker 5:  gaming, whatever it's called on my steam deck. And it's just
Speaker 5:  a, it's just a website, but it works perfectly on,
Speaker 5:  on my little steam deck. Does it? So like why should they
Speaker 5:  reinvent the wheel for this as well? When they've got the app built
Speaker 2:  The web isn't dead, everybody. The
Speaker 5:  Web's here.
Speaker 2:  Here's the evidence, the verse.com and the
Speaker 2:  Xbox cloud gaming progressive would app.
Speaker 2:  The future is bright for the web. All right, David, what's yours.
Speaker 6:  I'm pretty excited about framework's new Chromebook frameworks.
Speaker 6:  This company we've covered a bunch that, that their whole thing is like super
Speaker 6:  upgradeable, super repairable laptops. And they made a, they made an
Speaker 6:  Intel based windows laptop that I think is like a little too expensive for
Speaker 6:  what it is, but people really like it. And I think they have like started
Speaker 6:  to actually deliver on the promise of making these things upgradeable. And
Speaker 6:  that's very cool. And now, now they have a Chromebook. And as we've talked
Speaker 6:  about, I was sad about the pixel books. So this made me feel a little better.
Speaker 6:  There's like new people doing interesting stuff with Chromebooks and it's
Speaker 6:  still super upgradeable. It looks nice. I think it's a thousand bucks,
Speaker 6:  which feels like a lot of money again, but you can choose all your ports.
Speaker 6:  You can choose like lots of things about how it works. You can choose the
Speaker 6:  Ram and the storage. And it's just like, I don't know. The tinkerer in me
Speaker 6:  is very excited about specking to death, a Chromebook,
Speaker 5:  But you'll still be using Chrome ass, which is I've come. I
Speaker 5:  like I love, but I think is super ugly and needs an
Speaker 5:  entire refresh.
Speaker 6:  Oh, I totally agree.
Speaker 2:  Here's what I tell you. Framework tweeted. Google is committed to a minimum
Speaker 2:  of eight years of updates, framework, laptop, Chromebook condition.
Speaker 6:  That's a, a long time
Speaker 2:  Google. Isn't committed to Google search for eight years. Like this is a
Speaker 2:  huge commitment to that. Look at any moment. They're like, fuck it. We're
Speaker 2:  shutting down search. Like it's time to sunset search. We're
Speaker 2:  very sorry that you relied on it. Here's do do YouTube
Speaker 2:  stories.
Speaker 6:  We're just maps now.
Speaker 2:  Like, well, I, I just like don't buy it. I
Speaker 2:  it's amazing how Google has like torched its brand in that way.
Speaker 6:  It really is. I mean, to be like eight years is like a ludicrously long time
Speaker 6:  for Google. But I feel like if you're gonna bet on anything betting on Google
Speaker 6:  Chrome to last a while is a, is a decent bet. I would say
Speaker 2:  I wouldn't, I wouldn't take that bet. Just telling
Speaker 2:  you, sorry.
Speaker 6:  Fair
Speaker 2:  Enough. Google's like we don't support Cordy keyboards anymore. We've looked
Speaker 2:  into it and they're dumb. It's over VI, do you have a lightning round
Speaker 2:  entry?
Speaker 7:  Is it a gadget or just a story that I like?
Speaker 6:  Just anything, something going on this week, you're into
Speaker 2:  Whatever you want. You've earned. You've earned it by being on the show today.
Speaker 7:  Well, if it's something I'm looking forward to, then it's
Speaker 7:  probably the pixel watch just because I am dying to know what
Speaker 7:  this thing is gonna be like. I've just been, it's just been haunting my
Speaker 7:  nightmares ever since it was announced
Speaker 2:  Nightmares.
Speaker 7:  Yes. Cuz where OS before where OS three was an absolute
Speaker 7:  nightmare that every single time a new where OS two watch was announced,
Speaker 7:  I just sat on my bed and cried. It was not, you know, that's an, that's an
Speaker 7:  exaggeration, but it was just gentle weeping. It was sad. It was
Speaker 7:  so sad. And you know, like, I don't know. I'm just so
Speaker 7:  curious as to what this thing is gonna be. Cuz Google
Speaker 7:  was at the forefront of wearables back in 2014, like Android wear was
Speaker 7:  first to the game and then they were like, meh, we
Speaker 7:  give up. And then they were like, oh no, smartwatches are popular
Speaker 7:  now. Oh. And then like in 2019 they
Speaker 7:  just started like building. They like bought a bunch of fossil
Speaker 7:  stuff. They were bought Fitbit and they were just kind of
Speaker 7:  like mulling it. And then Rick Olo comes out and I just remember being
Speaker 7:  there at the made by Google event in 2019, he's like ambient computing. And
Speaker 7:  I was like, are you gonna fix it? Are you gonna fix it? And then I
Speaker 7:  had to wait another like two years to get that Samsung. And I was like, you
Speaker 7:  kind of didn't fix. Okay, well I'll wait another year.
Speaker 7:  And then, and then I was like, oh it's it's it's you know, I
Speaker 7:  still see the promise kind of, you kind of made some progress. And then I
Speaker 7:  tested them on Blanc summit three. And I was like, oh no, the fragmentation
Speaker 7:  is still there. So there's just so much, I'm curious about with the
Speaker 7:  pixel watch. I really wanna get my hands on it and probably break my brain,
Speaker 7:  testing it, just comparing it to what Samsung's done with it. And
Speaker 7:  well it's coming soon, right? Yeah. It's haunting my dreams.
Speaker 7:  It's coming soon. October 6th. I'm just so
Speaker 7:  curious what they're doing with it.
Speaker 2:  I feel like in the abstract you described all of Google hardware. You did.
Speaker 2:  Yes. Right? Like if you just take out the words watch or like, did they fix
Speaker 2:  it? And then Rick Olo said some stuff and they bought some stuff and then
Speaker 2:  you waited a year and then Samsung did a thing and then Google didn't do
Speaker 2:  a thing. And then, oh my God, the fragmentation. And are I gonna do it? It's
Speaker 2:  like, I it's, it's all of it. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  That's Google. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  All right. My last one is Victrola put out an $800 turntable
Speaker 2:  to stream directly to Sonos, which is cool. They should have done this.
Speaker 2:  Like Sono should have done this. It's just funny. That's Victrola, which
Speaker 2:  is until recently, like one of those like zombie brands that you buy at target
Speaker 2:  for $99, like RCA biggest glow up for a zombie
Speaker 2:  brand that has ever
Speaker 6:  Occurred. Good for that
Speaker 2:  Guys. Like the $99. Like, you know those like
Speaker 2:  blue suitcases that have turntables in them step up to $800
Speaker 2:  stream clay sentence. Very good. All of us should be so
Speaker 2:  ambitious. That's it for
Speaker 2:  us, Victoria. Thank you so much for rendering us on the show. I feel like
Speaker 2:  it was mostly fun. Thank you.
Speaker 6:  It's literally the best we can hope for.
Speaker 2:  It's true. I'm blaming Alex. You can tweeted us. Well, moving back
Speaker 2:  on Wednesday, David, what's the hotline
Speaker 6:  Next Wednesday. We have a bunch of fun stuff. I did a whole story on scooters
Speaker 6:  because I can only stop myself from talking about scooters for so long. So
Speaker 6:  we're doing some scooter stuff. We have some other stuff, but the big thing
Speaker 6:  coming up is we're doing a whole episode about cybersecurity at the end of
Speaker 6:  October. And what we really want is for people to give us cybersecurity mysteries
Speaker 6:  we can solve on the Vergecast. Yeah. So if you have
Speaker 6:  big, small, weird, extra weird
Speaker 6:  call us and tell us about them. It's eight sixty six version one, call the
Speaker 6:  hotline. Also the next episode of the future music mini series is going up
Speaker 6:  on Monday, Ariel. Shapiro's doing it. It's awesome. Lots of fun stuff going
Speaker 6:  on.
Speaker 2:  All right. You can tweet at us. David is at Pierce.
Speaker 2:  Alex is Alex H Crans Victoria is Vic M song.
Speaker 2:  I'm reckless. We love hearing from you. Please keep sending in redesign feedback.
Speaker 2:  I love reading it. I'm trying to get back to everyone slowly but
Speaker 2:  surely. It's great to hear and I'm glad it's clicking with so
Speaker 2:  many people. We are gonna tweak it, but I'm glad it's like working. So that's
Speaker 2:  like great to hear that's
Speaker 2:  it.
Speaker 3:  And that's a wrap for Vergecast this week. Thanks for listening. If you enjoy
Speaker 3:  the show, subscribe in the podcast app of your choice or tell a friend, you
Speaker 3:  can send us feedback at vergecast@theverge.com. This show is produced
Speaker 3:  by me, Liam, James, and our senior audio director. Andrew Marino. This
Speaker 3:  episode was edited and mixed by Amanda Rose Smith. Our
Speaker 3:  editorial director is Brooke mins and our executive producer is
Speaker 3:  Eleanor Donovan. The verge cast is a production of the verge and box media
Speaker 3:  podcast network. And that's it. We'll see you next
Speaker 3:  week.