# Transcript
ID: be187990-d5d8-11ec-a29d-29edd006c127
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: How video game controllers got a lot more accessible
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-291990626248408925/-8900134253417922883/s93290-None-2123s-1652788693.mp3
Description: In the final chapter of our Vergecast “creators series,” Alex Cranz talks with Ben Heck, who has been modding game systems and controllers since the early 2000s, which led to his project creating single-handed video game controllers.
Alex also talks with Bryce Johnson, who is one of the inventors of the Xbox Adaptive Controller, the game controller designed for gamers with limited mobility.
Speaker 1:  This episode is brought to you by grain your
Speaker 1:  life from the shoes you wear to how you make your coffee is
Speaker 1:  fueled by recommendations, maybe from your favorite artists, your
Speaker 1:  sister-in-law or your friend. Who's so cool. It's actually kind of
Speaker 1:  intimidating. Grin is the leading influencer marketing
Speaker 1:  software that allows you to build relationships with creators directly.
Speaker 1:  It's used by top e-commerce brands like Allbirds, skims,
Speaker 1:  Warby Parker, and more find out how grim can help you grow
Speaker 1:  your friend. Watch the demo@grin.co that's.
Speaker 1:  G R I N dot C O.
Speaker 3:  Hey Rodney. It's Nila. We've got another special episode of our virtual
Speaker 3:  cast creators series coming up. What's up, Alex,
Speaker 4:  We're going to talk about controllers today.
Speaker 3:  Control. So this is the third episode. Yes, you did
Speaker 3:  keyboards.
Speaker 4:  We did keyboards.
Speaker 3:  You did track Pauls.
Speaker 4:  We did poopy
Speaker 3:  Floopy.
Speaker 4:  It talks about floopy
Speaker 3:  Today's controllers. What do you mean about controllers?
Speaker 4:  Well, I think the thing was for this final episode, we really wanted to talk
Speaker 4:  about a gadget where all the tinkerers, all the people, making these things
Speaker 4:  actually for once had a really big win in these bigger companies really
Speaker 4:  finally started to pay attention. And that led us to
Speaker 4:  controllers because right now, most of them aren't really
Speaker 4:  accessible unless you have like two hands with really solid dexterity.
Speaker 4:  And a lot of people have spent a lot of time modding those to make them more
Speaker 4:  accessible for other members of the gaming community.
Speaker 3:  What specifically do you mean by accessible?
Speaker 4:  I think that means like controllers that you can use with one hand or a
Speaker 4:  foot, or like putting all the joysticks on one side, there's even mods for
Speaker 4:  people with different levels of motor control. And so that kind of led me
Speaker 4:  to this one guy who's been doing this for 20 years and that's been
Speaker 4:  heck
Speaker 3:  So it's funny. I know Ben Ben is from Wisconsin, listen Madison
Speaker 3:  in my ancient logging history. We would always cover every Ben
Speaker 3:  Heckmont. I've actually been out to Madison to see Ben before. That's amazing.
Speaker 4:  And he, he was, he was a lot of fun to talk to about video game
Speaker 4:  controllers, but you know, this is also a success story. And
Speaker 4:  so the other half of this is we really wanted to talk to one of these big
Speaker 4:  companies. And we ended up talking with Bryce Johnson, who is one of the
Speaker 4:  creators of Microsoft's adaptive controller for the Xbox.
Speaker 3:  That adaptive controller is a big win. People love it. One of the things
Speaker 3:  that I think about all the time is people love the adaptive controller. Even
Speaker 3:  if they do have two hands and staring, cause it's just a, it's a cool controller.
Speaker 3:  That's great. And making things accessible. It makes them better for everybody.
Speaker 3:  So I am very excited for this episode. Take it away,
Speaker 3:  Alex,
Speaker 4:  A lot of the times when I hear game control mods, I think of people
Speaker 4:  cheating at call of duty by adding special triggers,
Speaker 5:  The controller and the rapid fire mods. It completely
Speaker 5:  transformed this gun.
Speaker 4:  Or I think of like that video of teen Timothy shallow may painting an Xbox
Speaker 4:  controller.
Speaker 6:  Oh, here's a red tiger. Started it today. Yesterday, finished it today.
Speaker 6:  It looks nice. It looks sexy.
Speaker 4:  And yeah, some of the controller modding is focused on cheating the system
Speaker 4:  or just being unique. But a lot of the people out there modern
Speaker 4:  controllers are doing it for a much cooler reason. Increasing the
Speaker 4:  accessibility of playing video games.
Speaker 7:  My name is Ikea and this is my one handed dual sense controller.
Speaker 8:  This video will review our PlayStation four red-handed controller for
Speaker 8:  accessible gaming device.
Speaker 9:  It's a hobby I've built and designed custom game controllers for people with
Speaker 9:  physical disabilities.
Speaker 4:  Video games have a very well-documented accessibility problem, but
Speaker 4:  that's starting to change and it's not because exact set
Speaker 4:  gaming companies have suddenly changed their minds. It's because of the community
Speaker 4:  being vocal and demanding changes. And when that fails
Speaker 4:  implementing their own,
Speaker 4:  That's what led me to Ben. Heck
Speaker 10:  Hello? I am Benjamin J heckendorn online. I go by Ben, heck
Speaker 10:  I've have a website. Ben, heck.com. I am a self-taught
Speaker 10:  electrical engineer and I've been doing video game related modding and
Speaker 10:  customized console's controllers, et cetera. Since the year 2000,
Speaker 4:  He was one of the first modern to really embrace building communities. Online,
Speaker 4:  back before social media was even a term in most of our vernacular.
Speaker 4:  I knew if I was going to talk to anyone about how this area has transformed
Speaker 4:  and what it takes to do it, it had to be Ben. So here's my conversation with
Speaker 4:  them.
Speaker 4:  What was your first controller that you modded?
Speaker 10:  Well, I started out modifying old game systems,
Speaker 10:  the Atari 2,600 from back in the seventies or like 1980. I
Speaker 10:  found one of those in like a junk drawer. And I was like, I think I could
Speaker 10:  make this portable. This was back in 2000. So I hacked it all up and
Speaker 10:  I made it into like somewhat compact unit,
Speaker 11:  A grand total of 57 wires, nine switches, three potentially auditors, three
Speaker 11:  resistors, two capacitors, and one voltage regulator have to be hand connected
Speaker 11:  to build a VCSP.
Speaker 10:  I had a geo cities website. I put it on there and then a
Speaker 10:  gaming. I think it was classic gaming.com put a link to it. And then
Speaker 10:  apparently I became sort of internet famous back then.
Speaker 4:  I mean, that was before YouTube social media even.
Speaker 10:  Yeah, that was 22 years ago.
Speaker 4:  So you've been doing it ever since. What I was really excited to talk to
Speaker 4:  you about is I think in my head, I usually think of
Speaker 4:  controller mods is like somebody painting a controller or maybe putting
Speaker 4:  little switches on the back so they can shoot faster in call of duty,
Speaker 4:  but you're actually doing stuff to make controllers more accessible for people.
Speaker 10:  Correct. So I became known as like, oh, this guy's modifying things. Or
Speaker 10:  like, oh, he made a portable X-Box 360 into a laptop or whatever. So
Speaker 10:  2006, this guy emails me and he's like, Hey, I
Speaker 10:  was in the second Iraq war. And when he was over there, you
Speaker 10:  know, he'd been wounded and he came back. He's like, I realize if I don't
Speaker 10:  have both my hands, I can't hold a controller because it requires both of
Speaker 10:  your hands. He's like, I want to play video games. Like this was a big part
Speaker 10:  of my life. So he's like, could you make me a controller? But he's like,
Speaker 10:  can you move everything? That'd be on one side of the controller and make
Speaker 10:  it so it's accessible just on one side. And I'm like, oh, okay. I'll, I'll
Speaker 10:  try that.
Speaker 12:  It says he can see, we have the left analog on the leg here. So
Speaker 12:  what you do is you move your arm left and right. To do that
Speaker 12:  motion. And then the right hand log stick is the same as it ever was
Speaker 10:  The original prototypes that I did. I think this was the Xbox 360 days.
Speaker 10:  Well, I think they were actually over-engineered because I was like laser
Speaker 10:  cutting panels and little. And he was like, oh, okay, this works.
Speaker 10:  And I can't remember if that was, that was the first time I did it. But
Speaker 10:  you know, there's two analog sticks. Right. And obviously that's a problem.
Speaker 10:  So one of the gags I came up with was you take the right hand analog
Speaker 10:  stick and you put it on the bottom of the controller and then you actuate
Speaker 10:  it against your leg.
Speaker 4:  Oh, that's cool.
Speaker 10:  This acts as a joystick for the movie, the controller against your leg acts
Speaker 10:  as the other analog axis of movement. And so that was something that I did
Speaker 10:  pretty early on because I was like, you know, how do you get both analogs?
Speaker 10:  Do it now. It is harder for people to learn because you're taking this
Speaker 10:  many tasks and putting them all into one hand, which does make it more difficult.
Speaker 10:  But the vast majority of people that I sell them to that
Speaker 10:  seems to work. I get a lot of feedback. It's like, Hey, now I can game again.
Speaker 10:  So that's kind of, that's where it started back in 2006,
Speaker 4:  You expanded it. You, you primarily, for a long time, there were mainly doing
Speaker 4:  X-Box 360 controllers, right? You weren't working on PlayStation or
Speaker 4:  Nintendo controllers.
Speaker 10:  Yes. So if you think about in 2006, if you take
Speaker 10:  apart your standard computer keyboard, not like a, a razor, but your standard
Speaker 10:  one, it's got those that's soak screen, conductive membrane. It's
Speaker 10:  basically two pieces of plastic. And then that's how the switches work.
Speaker 10:  That's what Sony uses. They've been using that for their controllers, for
Speaker 10:  the buttons since 1995. And it makes it really hard to modify like you
Speaker 10:  can't just go in there and like, oh, I'm going to solder to this point.
Speaker 10:  And that gives me that X button I'm going to solder to this point. That
Speaker 10:  gets me the square button. You can't do it very easily on a Sony controller.
Speaker 10:  Whereas in the Xbox you take it up. It's just a box standard green circuit
Speaker 10:  board. And it's filled with test points all over. It's like test point test
Speaker 10:  point, and you solder to those and boom, you get your button.
Speaker 4:  Oh, that's cool.
Speaker 10:  So that's why for the longest time, I only did X-Box was because it was
Speaker 10:  much, much easier to modify the controllers versus
Speaker 10:  PlayStation. Also, if you want to get into the weeds with it, always
Speaker 10:  Sony revises their controllers multiple times for generation, whereas
Speaker 10:  Microsoft might do it once. So not only is it places you control
Speaker 10:  are harder to modify, but it keeps changing as well. I think there was at
Speaker 10:  least three different versions for the PlayStation four, for instance. Whereas
Speaker 10:  X-Box had to over that same period,
Speaker 4:  It was like Microsoft conscious of like what you were doing.
Speaker 10:  Oh yeah. Actually Microsoft actually, every so often they'll send me a
Speaker 10:  whole box of like broken controllers just to scavenge parts from
Speaker 4:  That's. Cool. So how did that go from like one guy and
Speaker 4:  helping one guy to a little side hustle? Is it fair
Speaker 4:  to call it a side hustle? Is it a full hustle?
Speaker 10:  No, it is not the main thing that I do, but actually I just, I just, I
Speaker 10:  actually, I got to send them off today. Like I just did my taxes, like
Speaker 10:  2021. I built like 124 of them. It turns out.
Speaker 10:  So I, I built about two weeks for people, but one thing that helped us,
Speaker 10:  we had a, we had this forum on my website. We, it was the
Speaker 10:  Ben heck.com forum. And people would go on there like, oh, I want to
Speaker 10:  modify video game councils. I want to, you know, do this. And that was from
Speaker 10:  like 2004 to 2007 was probably the heyday of that.
Speaker 10:  So my website, Ben, heck.com already had a lot of good
Speaker 10:  SEO as far as like modifying things go because that's why, even though my
Speaker 10:  forums are dead, we there've been dead for a long time. I still keep them
Speaker 10:  up, but I keep the database and good. Nick
Speaker 4:  SEO is too good
Speaker 10:  For dry because there's still tons of legacy links from Google that still
Speaker 10:  go to that website. So I wanted to make sure it's still there. So it was
Speaker 10:  just, it was just web traffic back then. And I guess it still is. I don't
Speaker 10:  do any marketing people just come to my website and order this stuff.
Speaker 4:  YouTube Twitter, like when, when, when you started using these, cause you're
Speaker 4:  a fairly big presence on both that didn't kind of transform how
Speaker 4:  people were reaching out to you and, and kind of talking to you about accessibility
Speaker 4:  and controllers.
Speaker 10:  Not that I've noticed. I, well, a lot of people email me about it. That's
Speaker 10:  pretty common. So I, maybe they just go to my website because you know,
Speaker 10:  they'll email me and be like, oh, you know, I've got this particular thing
Speaker 10:  or I have also done all their modified controllers in the past. Like I've
Speaker 10:  done one for someone who had muscular dystrophy, which meant they basically
Speaker 10:  had trouble having the strength to necessarily use the controller. Another
Speaker 10:  thing I've come across is the size of people's hands.
Speaker 4:  I couldn't use the original one. I had to my I very tiny hands
Speaker 10:  And you're not alone. Like there's, there's one right now when I'm trading
Speaker 10:  emails with them, their, their main problem is they are having trouble
Speaker 10:  reaching the whole thing because yes, people have different size hands.
Speaker 10:  There's a lot of different things that can affect, you know, your ability
Speaker 10:  to game myself. I have, I'm like 50% color blind.
Speaker 10:  So when they started adding those options into games about 10 years ago,
Speaker 10:  I think like dice actually was one of the first ones to do it with bad company
Speaker 10:  too. I'm like, oh yes. Finally I can see the, the, my ally
Speaker 10:  markers in the snow maps because of the lines. I couldn't see the blue.
Speaker 10:  Right. I'm like, okay, this is something I can appreciate. And there's other
Speaker 10:  things, a lot of other much smell, almost everything is worse than that,
Speaker 10:  that can affect people. So it's kind of interesting to do that. Kind of
Speaker 10:  like, okay, what can I do? Even if it's just these controllers, which are,
Speaker 10:  it's not like it's some sort of science miracle, but it's kind of fun to
Speaker 10:  do problem solving with that. And right now what I'm doing is
Speaker 10:  actually I was working out just this morning, I'm working on ways to
Speaker 10:  improve the process so I can keep the prices
Speaker 10:  static. As other prices might change. Like during the,
Speaker 10:  like in 2020, I had a hard time like finding the controllers. So I
Speaker 10:  was having to go on eBay actually to get a lot of them or go to the
Speaker 10:  used game store once things reopened. And yeah, that was kind of a crap
Speaker 10:  shoot back then. And even like the filament at that time, like the
Speaker 10:  3d printer filament. So when people send me controllers for
Speaker 10:  repair, which, you know, obviously that they break after time and the number
Speaker 10:  one thing that goes wrong in stick drift, don't tell them, don't tell big
Speaker 10:  game industries. I had the spool of filament. It's like this
Speaker 10:  marble fake marble filament. I got at a festival in 2019
Speaker 10:  and I'm like, oh, wait a minute. I'm never going to use this. I'm not going
Speaker 10:  to print chess pieces or anything. Right. But then Amazon was like, oh,
Speaker 10:  we don't have any white filament. And I'm like, I guess I have to use this
Speaker 10:  white marble. So now when I get, if someone sends in a controller and I
Speaker 10:  see something that should have been a white, 3d printed piece, but it's
Speaker 10:  actually like this marble, which kind of looks like, you know, the white
Speaker 10:  gum that has like the specks of flavor in it. It kind of looks like that.
Speaker 10:  So if I see something on there with that color of film and I'm like, oh,
Speaker 10:  I made that the summer of 2020 it's it's like
Speaker 10:  an archeologist I could like rip it. It kind of reminds me of,
Speaker 4:  It gets a little bit of an artist's signature people. You can just see that
Speaker 4:  and be like, I did that. I know. And other people will now know. I love it.
Speaker 10:  Well, in the case of that filament, it was the signature of shortages or
Speaker 10:  whatever the problem was. Back then,
Speaker 4:  You mentioned earlier that Microsoft was, was always very enthusiastic about
Speaker 4:  you modifying these controllers and making a more accessible Microsoft
Speaker 4:  now is kind of embraced accessibility itself. And it started,
Speaker 4:  you know, it has this big cool accessibility controller. Yup.
Speaker 13:  For the Xbox adaptive controller, a gamer can gain with one hand
Speaker 13:  and one foot or one hand and their shoulder or even one
Speaker 13:  foot and their chin. And I can change it for the damned again.
Speaker 4:  Was there ever like evidence where they were like, oh yeah, we're working
Speaker 4:  on this because we see so much of the appetite there because of people like
Speaker 4:  you.
Speaker 10:  Well, they've never told me that directly. I know they knew of
Speaker 10:  my work. I don't know if it inspired them. And I actually did buy one of
Speaker 10:  their controllers to take a look at. And at the time they announced
Speaker 10:  that like, oh, I guess we're not going to build these anymore. But
Speaker 10:  an issue that people have with that, like people will email me and there's
Speaker 10:  like, Hey, I tried it, but it's this big box. And it has all
Speaker 10:  these like one eighth inch, three millimeter headphone jacks. So you're
Speaker 10:  like, okay, I've got this foot pedal, plug it in. That's going to
Speaker 10:  be the jump button. I've got this puff controller where you
Speaker 10:  use air, I'm going to plug it into here. So basically in order to use this
Speaker 10:  thing, you have to plug all this stuff into it. It looks like a giant, like
Speaker 10:  super squid with all these wires coming out of it. So the feedback I've
Speaker 10:  gotten from people is that, yeah, I think the thing is like 99 bucks, which
Speaker 10:  is actually a lot less than I charge for my modifications,
Speaker 10:  but they're like, yeah, but you can't just use this thing out of the box.
Speaker 10:  It's got like two big buttons on the front at everything else has to be
Speaker 10:  plugged back in. So at least for people with a specific situation of,
Speaker 10:  I only have one hand people buy the controller and then they don't realize
Speaker 10:  how much extra work you have to put into it. Or how many ad-ons Microsoft
Speaker 10:  also has this thing on your Xbox consoles. I think it's called assist
Speaker 10:  or Microsoft assist. So if you have like, you know, your
Speaker 10:  partner or your brother or sister or whatever, like let's say, okay, I'm
Speaker 10:  playing this game, but I have some sort of impairment. There's a certain
Speaker 10:  thing I have difficulty doing. Like this button, this button, Microsoft
Speaker 10:  actually has it where you can map certain functions of one controller
Speaker 10:  onto an assistant controller. So someone else can help you perform those
Speaker 10:  functions as well. And that's baked into the operating system of the
Speaker 10:  Xbox, which is pretty cool. That's
Speaker 4:  Very cool.
Speaker 10:  I think that's one of the things they thought with the, you know, the Microsoft
Speaker 10:  accessibility controller or whatever it's called is that, oh, you know,
Speaker 10:  this can let a person do certain things, but then someone else can do the
Speaker 10:  rest of it. So they, they made it very general purpose, but
Speaker 10:  that's also a negative because you have to add everything else to it. So,
Speaker 10:  yeah, I mean, I thought, oh, I guess, I guess we're not going to sell any
Speaker 10:  more of these mods anymore. And this was like three or four years ago. And
Speaker 10:  I guess not like last couple of years, I think I've sold more per year than
Speaker 10:  I did in the past even. Wow.
Speaker 4:  I guess my last big question for you is how have you seen these
Speaker 4:  big gaming companies? We talked about Microsoft, but, but
Speaker 4:  Sony, Nintendo, even some of these other ones like
Speaker 4:  steam and stuff, have they started to embrace accessibility? Have you started
Speaker 4:  to see them change in this last 22 years that you've
Speaker 4:  been doing this?
Speaker 10:  Well, I would say a lot more changes happened in the last 10 years. Even,
Speaker 10:  you know, you have like able gamers, they've been pushing for this for much
Speaker 10:  longer than 10 years, but it does seem like the industry is starting to,
Speaker 10:  well, not starting. Do they have that and implemented it more and more?
Speaker 10:  I mean, I'm surprised Sony hasn't done more with it. I mean, they sell way
Speaker 10:  more consoles and like, I'm not the only one who modifies controllers. You've
Speaker 10:  got like evil controllers and there's a couple other ones, you know, if
Speaker 10:  you have like, oh, like let's say you're Sony, Hey Sony, maybe make it.
Speaker 10:  So your controllers a little easier to mob a person of average soldering
Speaker 10:  skill who hasn't been doing it for like 35 years would probably
Speaker 10:  struggle with it. Anyway, what I would want to say with that is since
Speaker 10:  people are modifying controllers, maybe, Hey, there's things they could
Speaker 10:  do to make it easier. Yes. There's going to be people trying to cheat or
Speaker 10:  quick scope or whatever in call of duty. There's also people that want to
Speaker 10:  modify a controllers for altruistic purposes. So, you know,
Speaker 10:  without affecting anything, they could make things a little easier to modify
Speaker 10:  or, or fix. So, yeah, I guess that would be my, my, my plea.
Speaker 10:  And as I mentioned, except for like the Microsoft or in part X-Box, it's
Speaker 10:  actually gotten easier with the controllers. I don't think it was on purpose,
Speaker 10:  but it's been easier. Whereas Sony is, they've actually made the
Speaker 10:  controller the same way longer. The next box is like, oh, here's a silkscreen
Speaker 10:  circuit. And that's got the four face buttons, the four shoulder
Speaker 10:  buttons and the cross, they keep making it the same way over and over and
Speaker 10:  over. And it's very hard to mod because I can't solder to a piece of plastic,
Speaker 10:  the silkscreen circuit. So you've got to find the traces on the PCB.
Speaker 10:  The PCB has no test points. Oh, and the soak screen is black or blue, which
Speaker 10:  makes it even harder.
Speaker 4:  I'm just still continuously impressed. You've been doing this for over 22
Speaker 4:  years and you started putting it on your website to kind of creating
Speaker 4:  this industry, to getting people like even Microsoft noticing your
Speaker 4:  work and hopefully thinking about it. But thank you
Speaker 4:  so much for taking the time to chat today. Ben. No
Speaker 10:  Problem.
Speaker 4:  Okay. I bet you didn't expect. We'd be talking about PCBs in an
Speaker 4:  X-Box controller that long. Finn's got a wealth of knowledge about the game
Speaker 4:  controller space and about the unique challenges of building controllers
Speaker 4:  for a wide variety of people with different capabilities. After the
Speaker 4:  break, I'm going to talk to somebody else who knows this space,
Speaker 4:  particularly the X-Box accessibility space, Bryce
Speaker 4:  Johnson. He's one of the creators of Microsoft adaptive controller, which
Speaker 4:  was maybe the first controller from a major console maker intended to
Speaker 4:  actually address accessibility for a wide variety of people
Speaker 4:  stated
Speaker 1:  Thanks to grin for supporting this episode. So you and your
Speaker 1:  business have finally taken the leap into influencer marketing. It's going
Speaker 1:  great. And you're excited to connect with your audience in a powerful new
Speaker 1:  way, but you've noticed you're spending a lot of time on busy work checking
Speaker 1:  to see if the creator has gotten your product moving through a tangled web
Speaker 1:  of emails and DMS. And now you're wondering, Hey, did that
Speaker 1:  Instagram post they promised ever even go up influencer marketing
Speaker 1:  can be super effective, but not if it's a drain on your time. That's
Speaker 1:  where green comes in. Grim is the number one creator management platform.
Speaker 1:  It helps you find and recruit the perfect ambassadors for your brand and
Speaker 1:  streamlines the communication process. You can collect all creator content
Speaker 1:  in one, easy to find place and track your return on investment and
Speaker 1:  mealtime influencer marketing. Doesn't have to be complicated. Grim
Speaker 1:  makes it simple. So you can treat your creators like your brand revolves
Speaker 1:  around them because in the creator economy, it does
Speaker 1:  influence our marketing is easier with grant. Find out why I
Speaker 1:  glen.co that's, G R I n.co.
Speaker 4:  And we're back, we've talked to a lot of gadget bakers for this video
Speaker 4:  series about their efforts to make cool stuff that maybe,
Speaker 4:  maybe the big guys and gadgets will pay attention to Ben
Speaker 4:  and other game controller monitors have actually succeeded. Maybe
Speaker 4:  it's because I've been doing it longer. I'm not sure, but regardless in
Speaker 4:  2018, Microsoft introduced the adaptive controller
Speaker 4:  and finally gave first party choice for people looking to make an accessible
Speaker 4:  controller for playing video games, no waiting for a mater, no concerns
Speaker 4:  about voided warranties, just an easy financial transaction.
Speaker 4:  And that's because of Bryce Johnson and his colleagues at Microsoft, they
Speaker 4:  created the adaptive controller.
Speaker 14:  I've been at Microsoft a while working on accessibility, probably most of
Speaker 14:  my time here throughout X-Box and now hardware.
Speaker 4:  So let's talk to them about it.
Speaker 4:  You know, I think it's kind of interesting that you guys did this and
Speaker 4:  then Microsoft released it and really put a lot of marketing and, and other
Speaker 4:  things behind it, a lot of resources behind it, because kind of
Speaker 4:  prior to that, as far as like accessibility and gaming, it was primarily
Speaker 4:  up to people online, like just hacking together
Speaker 4:  things. Would you say that's kind of correct?
Speaker 14:  Oh yeah, for sure. And I mean, it's not like we didn't know or notice we
Speaker 14:  learned a lot from a lot of people and we had wonderful partners throughout
Speaker 14:  the journey. I think as you get into any type of accessibility
Speaker 14:  inclusion, you know, we talk a lot about it and being intentional and,
Speaker 14:  and we kind of dig into the weeds there with the community. So that, that
Speaker 14:  is super important to us. But to do that, you have to be part of the community.
Speaker 14:  So yeah, we were there, we were there when we saw it, but we, we saw folks
Speaker 14:  doing things and we, we, we learned
Speaker 4:  Was that primarily like in forums, was it on YouTube, was like, where, where
Speaker 4:  were you signing a lot of that community working on these things and thinking
Speaker 4:  about it. Cause I think most of the community did a very different kind of
Speaker 4:  approach to accessibility controllers versus what you guys did, but
Speaker 4:  I want to get into.
Speaker 14:  Yeah, absolutely. And I would say that like, definitely in the beginning
Speaker 14:  there was a lot of YouTube, you know, I'm thinking like my buddy
Speaker 14:  AIJ Ryan who goes by only use me feet. There's so many people to be
Speaker 14:  honest, you know, nomads, all these folks, there's, there's really just
Speaker 14:  tons of them. I wish I could just sit here and say them all for only course
Speaker 14:  parolee and can't believe I forgot Brawley.
Speaker 4:  I think a lot of the, the ones I had seen had primarily been created for
Speaker 4:  people who might have only one lamb or something like that.
Speaker 4:  But you, you really were working on something that was available for
Speaker 4:  people with a wide variety of different needs. What kind of led
Speaker 4:  you to trying to kind of do as much as you can for as many people as you
Speaker 4:  can.
Speaker 14:  I think that's the answer in way it's like we wanted to do as much as we
Speaker 14:  can for as many people as we can. And we had to investigate a
Speaker 14:  lot of solutions that were out there, understand who were they were optimized
Speaker 14:  for. I think the one thing that is tricky and I don't want to
Speaker 14:  say that it's, this is a golden rule or anything, but often when you optimize
Speaker 14:  for one disability, you're excluding from another, right.
Speaker 14:  You have to figure out the balance. Right. And so for us, it was always
Speaker 14:  this exercise and understanding the balance. And I will say
Speaker 14:  that, I think that, you know, we still have a lot to learn there in that
Speaker 14:  way. We still are learning to understand that balance, but we started, I
Speaker 14:  think we're in a place that you just described, right? We started with limb
Speaker 14:  different vets, you know, we moved on to quadriplegia. Cause that makes
Speaker 14:  sense. Cause that's where a lot of limb, different bets are also quadriplegics.
Speaker 14:  You know, we moved on to cerebral palsy and then, you know, we moved on
Speaker 14:  to muscular neuromuscular conditions. So while I think we do
Speaker 14:  really well for limb different folks and quadriplegics and even CP,
Speaker 14:  you know, I definitely recognize that we could do better for neuromuscular
Speaker 14:  folks. And that's, you know, we're always thinking about,
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I think it's, it's a real challenge because you do have just, you can't
Speaker 4:  build just w I mean, I think you guys are kind of coming close to that, but,
Speaker 4:  but you can't build just one thing for, for everybody.
Speaker 14:  Yeah. I mean, like I wanted big black buttons on the front of the controller,
Speaker 14:  you know, you can press it in any spot. The engineering team made it. So
Speaker 14:  it didn't wobble. It was fairly lightly pressed, but not too lightly pressed,
Speaker 14:  like the trick we did have these in the beginning, we had these a little
Speaker 14:  bit lighter to press, but the problem was is if you moved it, it would press
Speaker 14:  the button. So because it was so lightly finely tuned, but the
Speaker 14:  other thing about it, and I'm going to this might, you know, sorry to the
Speaker 14:  audio guy in advance, like you can hit these things, right? Like they're
Speaker 14:  meant to be hit for people who have, like, they don't have the, the
Speaker 14:  motor control and they have what they would call high tone so they can kind
Speaker 14:  of hit it. So that's just two different extreme uses, like the ability of
Speaker 14:  people who press to light and the ability of people who press too hard.
Speaker 14:  There's many spectrums like that, that we think about as we work on our
Speaker 14:  products. And I D I will come back to, we try to find the balance, but it
Speaker 14:  is always in the service of like human diversity. Right?
Speaker 4:  Well, that was really interesting about the community. And what I've really
Speaker 4:  seen from the community is, is for the most part, it's, it's, it's a lot
Speaker 4:  of mods and stuff. And I know a lot of people in the community specifically
Speaker 4:  appreciate Microsoft because you leave a lot of like
Speaker 4:  the pens on the board available. So people can really get in there and
Speaker 4:  mess around. Why did you go instead of
Speaker 4:  kind of doing just the most X-Box modded
Speaker 4:  mod, X-Box 360 controller, instead of doing that, you
Speaker 4:  created this, this almost joystick looking device, what kind
Speaker 4:  of led you from that very traditional
Speaker 4:  iconic look to this new one.
Speaker 14:  Yeah, that's a really good question. Let me kind of give you a bit of a
Speaker 14:  broader story around it. We knew that we needed to externalize
Speaker 14:  controls. So on the back of the controller, there's 19 ports that basically
Speaker 14:  have a switch input for every function on a game controller, plus two extras.
Speaker 14:  I'm actually sorry, generation nine controllers. They'll not only be one
Speaker 14:  extra. So if you want to have that share button, you can't. So
Speaker 14:  there's still a lot of options there. And so trying
Speaker 14:  to figure out how to externalize all those controls was, was
Speaker 14:  really tricky. And what allowed us to design a
Speaker 14:  form that was so different from a regular controller was
Speaker 14:  copilot. So we were working in a different direction. The original
Speaker 14:  hacks were in a different direction. And
Speaker 14:  co-pilot when we designed that as a feature, we've got that into like
Speaker 14:  production allowed us to like, use different forms because
Speaker 14:  you can always use a traditional controller alongside your
Speaker 14:  adaptive controller. You can use them at the same time. Can
Speaker 4:  You explain copilot
Speaker 14:  Copilot is the ability to take two controllers. So it could be an adaptive
Speaker 14:  controller or a regular traditional controller and tell the
Speaker 14:  Xbox or windows 10 PC that they're the same controller that
Speaker 14:  you really only have one controller. And for the adaptive controller, what
Speaker 14:  this allowed us to do is it allowed us to have this form, because if you
Speaker 14:  could use half the buttons on a regular controller, let's say you were limb
Speaker 14:  different. You could use the right half of a controller. We want you to
Speaker 14:  use the right half of a controller. We don't want you to go out and buy
Speaker 14:  stuff. We want you to use what you have. So the other thing too, for
Speaker 14:  copilot is some people don't even need the adaptive controller. They could
Speaker 14:  get what they need from two controllers. And we continue to look at that
Speaker 14:  as we develop the ecosystem, you know, the design for X-Box Horry
Speaker 14:  products that they put out, you can copilot their arcade, stick
Speaker 14:  with a controller. So in a sense, that's super powerful. If
Speaker 14:  you've looked into these hacks, you've seen people, it is about
Speaker 14:  modularizing control. You know, we always ask people to tell us
Speaker 14:  where you have movements so that we can put buttons there. We can put Joe
Speaker 14:  six there. I think a lot of times in the disability community, especially
Speaker 14:  in limited mobility community, we talk in terms of what people are missing,
Speaker 14:  but we don't focus on that. We focus on what people have,
Speaker 4:  Where do you think the community is going to go next? Like,
Speaker 4:  what are the next big goals in making gaming more
Speaker 4:  accessible
Speaker 14:  In terms of gaming? I think there's been a lot of people who've been talking
Speaker 14:  about this for a really long time, and that history should be honored. I
Speaker 14:  look at what gaming is doing, and I see them basically rocketing through
Speaker 14:  accessibility. You know, if you think about the internet, like the web was
Speaker 14:  designed to be accessible from the beginning, and we're still talking about
Speaker 14:  it, like 30 years later, like making web accessibility, we always have to
Speaker 14:  be kind of, sort of vigilant to make sure that we're intentionally, including
Speaker 14:  people, we're bringing people into the community. So we're where are we
Speaker 14:  going next? I think there's tons of stuff in game accessibility. That's
Speaker 14:  going on. Like, to be honest, after the adaptive controller, I did a lot
Speaker 14:  of game stuff. I then kind of sunk more into hardware stuff, and I
Speaker 14:  still kept basically in the gaming world. I actually I'm on a group
Speaker 14:  chat with like the folks from GA comp. And can I play that? And so
Speaker 14:  I'm still connected to that world. So it's, it's
Speaker 14:  really interesting to see how quickly that's developing, especially if
Speaker 14:  you know, the history of, of computing accessibility in general, like
Speaker 14:  human computer interaction in gaming is, is like human computer interaction
Speaker 14:  on extra hard, right? Put a gaming metaphor in there, right? There's so
Speaker 14:  many things that they're uncovering and addressing so quickly and
Speaker 14:  gaming accessibility. It's really quite impressive, but there is still a
Speaker 14:  huge way to go. I mean, even an inaccessible
Speaker 14:  website is somewhat more accessible than an accessible game. There's
Speaker 14:  really a lot of to go on and that's not to diminish any of the work that
Speaker 14:  anyone's done. There's been some incredible work throughout the community,
Speaker 14:  but, you know, that's just that aspect of it. Like, but I mean, as you think
Speaker 14:  about like, well, what is gaming, right. I think, you know, one of the
Speaker 14:  sad things, this will I'll date myself, as I know that the mixer
Speaker 14:  team did a lot of really great work on how to think about like how people
Speaker 14:  with disabilities stream. And when you think about like the fact that if
Speaker 14:  you can't get a nine to five job because of a disability or, or condition
Speaker 14:  that you have, you know, streaming can be a viable option to help supplement
Speaker 14:  your income, you know, it's, it's so it's, as we think about empowering
Speaker 14:  people with disabilities through gaming, there is, there's just so much
Speaker 14:  stuff that we can do.
Speaker 4:  Do you think that community of people creating these controllers,
Speaker 4:  doing these pretty extensive mods and stuff to make these more accessible,
Speaker 4:  is that going to go away as companies like Microsoft and
Speaker 4:  Horry kind of invest more in this community? Or do you think they're going
Speaker 4:  to continue?
Speaker 14:  No, because I think we try to service those people, right? Like
Speaker 14:  when we created the adaptive controller, we definitely had
Speaker 14:  a sense of like supporting makers because as we
Speaker 14:  talked about earlier, when you lean too much in one direction, you might
Speaker 14:  be excluding someone else. So for example, people ask why we don't include
Speaker 14:  joysticks with the adaptive controller, you know, and it's kind of like,
Speaker 14:  well, what joystick, like a joystick for like someone with cerebral palsy
Speaker 14:  who might use their feet or, or a tetrapolegic that needs something bigger,
Speaker 14:  or like a tiny joystick for someone with like a neuromuscular condition.
Speaker 14:  So you realize that as soon as you start, including all these parts in here,
Speaker 14:  parts that cost money, some people will use them and other people won't.
Speaker 14:  So it is actually crucially important for us to support that maker
Speaker 14:  community and to have those things out there. So in many ways, we've,
Speaker 14:  we've actually dug deeper into that. But at the same time, you know, we
Speaker 14:  recognize that people want to go buy a product, that they can kind of go
Speaker 14:  to a store and buy in and sort of use without having to like go into
Speaker 14:  their garage and build something, you know? So we're trying to figure out
Speaker 14:  all these things, right? Like how do you create products that can be
Speaker 14:  extended by the maker community, but can be purchased to the store and basically
Speaker 14:  taken home and used.
Speaker 4:  So what is next for Microsoft in this area?
Speaker 14:  So on May 10th, we announced the Microsoft adaptive accessories.
Speaker 14:  It's a suite of products, which basically includes an adaptive
Speaker 14:  mouse that can be extended by 3d printing tales
Speaker 14:  and things like that. That changed this mouse in many different forms. There
Speaker 14:  is the Microsoft adaptive hub, which is very similar to what the
Speaker 14:  Xbox adaptive controller is. And then there's the, the Microsoft
Speaker 14:  adaptive button. So this is very similar to our D pad. This comes in a number
Speaker 14:  of different ways. All the functions of these devices can be programmed,
Speaker 14:  not only with like to whatever button presses you on, but to macros and
Speaker 14:  things like that, to help you kind of increase your productivity. So the
Speaker 14:  top of this button can be 3d printed and designed to be
Speaker 14:  extended by the maker community and to kind of bridge that gap
Speaker 14:  between makers and consumers. We've partnered with Shapeways
Speaker 14:  so that people can basically go to Shapeways, pick the mods that they
Speaker 14:  want and just have Shapeways print them and then send them to them.
Speaker 14:  So you don't even have to have a 3d printer to basically go in and get
Speaker 14:  and take advantage of the community of people that will build mods for
Speaker 14:  this thing. So we have like joysticks for this button. We have Cheech sticks
Speaker 14:  for this button. We have all kinds of things, you know, more kind of
Speaker 14:  vertical things. Typically a lot of quadriplegics want a bigger joystick
Speaker 14:  to even press buttons, you know, because this kind of movement helps. So
Speaker 14:  we've created this system so that people on their PCs and it
Speaker 14:  also works on, on, on mobile phones to can basically create
Speaker 14:  what we did with the adaptive controller. Like that's a, I think one of
Speaker 14:  the things that we've learned in our inclusive design practice, that is
Speaker 14:  something that I think we need to dig in more to is that, you know, very
Speaker 14:  often in accessibility, we talk about what's wrong, but we really need to
Speaker 14:  also focus on what's right. You know, like with the adaptive controller,
Speaker 14:  I couldn't really articulate this until about, until the middle of the pandemic.
Speaker 14:  You know, we created the adaptive controller for veterans with limited mobility,
Speaker 14:  but we were inspired to do so to support their mental health because they
Speaker 14:  loved gaming, right. We were there to support what they love. So I think
Speaker 14:  a lot of what we talk about and inclusive design and accessibility can sometimes
Speaker 14:  be about the bad things, but we need to hold on and cling to the good thing
Speaker 14:  we need to hold on to why they're there.
Speaker 4:  I want to thank Bryce and Ben, both for coming on the show. A lot of the
Speaker 4:  times you can get, I don't know, a little despondent about what major tech
Speaker 4:  companies are doing versus the little guy too often. It feels like they buy
Speaker 4:  up the cool stuff only to kill it, or they sell their own products for so
Speaker 4:  cheap. The cool stuff can't survive, but here's an instance where
Speaker 4:  both are happy to co-exist and actually create really
Speaker 4:  important technology that makes playing video games a lot
Speaker 4:  more accessible for a lot more people. It gives you hope for
Speaker 4:  people like Colin and Phil lamp who created floopy to make open source
Speaker 4:  gadgets, a real viable thing, or Jacob Alexander, who
Speaker 4:  just wants you to use a better keyboard than the one. It issues you
Speaker 4:  great. See changes in the gadget world can happen. The adaptive
Speaker 4:  controller feels like proof of that. You just need to find a gadget you
Speaker 4:  love and find a community that loves it as much as you do.
Speaker 4:  If you have thoughts about this episode, you can hit me up at Alex H
Speaker 4:  Kranz on Twitter, or you can email
Speaker 4:  us@vergecastattheverge.com our regular Vergecast chat show.
Speaker 4:  We'll be back on Friday. This episode of the Vergecast is produced by me,
Speaker 4:  Alex Cranz lead producer, Liam, James, and see your audio director,
Speaker 4:  Andrew Marino. Okay. Stay classy.
Speaker 1:  This episode has been brought to you by grin. Top creators are
Speaker 1:  already using and loving your product. So why haven't you partnered with
Speaker 1:  them so they can share that love with their audience. Grin helps you bring
Speaker 1:  creators on board is the ultimate champions of your brand. You can
Speaker 1:  recruit ship sample products and track creator content. All in one
Speaker 1:  place. Grin is the number one influencer management platform,
Speaker 1:  helping e-commerce brands connect with their audience through the power of
Speaker 1:  creator partnerships. Find out how grin can help you grow your
Speaker 1:  brand. Watch the demo@grin.co that's, GRI
Speaker 1:  n.co.