# Transcript
ID: 8cb644a0-b71e-11ec-aba1-35bf1ec67789
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Elon Musk buys 9.2 percent of Twitter  / OnePlus 10 Pro review /  QD-OLED monitors and TVs
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/683067296408220127/3406515871051557014/s93290-US-4448s-1649408038.mp3
Description: Verge managing editor Alex Cranz leads this week's show with Dan Seifert, Liz Lopatto, and Allison Johnson to discuss Elon Musk buying stock in Twitter, Allison's review of the OnePlus 10 Pro, and the newest monitors and televisions in 2022.
Speaker 1:  Focus on the flight taxi, captain speaking, and welcome back for those of
Speaker 1:  you that are still with us. We do have a maintenance completed the problems
Speaker 1:  with the fixed for the ice detection system. We'll be texting out as soon
Speaker 1:  as we get topped off people here, they should be on momentarily.
Speaker 1:  Once I get in there, it's about an hour and five
Speaker 1:  minutes,
Speaker 2:  Alex, it's it lie. I am on a
Speaker 2:  plane that stuck on the runway because the ice detection
Speaker 2:  system is broken. I think it's a software. I think they just have to unplug
Speaker 2:  it and plug it back in, in any case, I won't be back in time to host the
Speaker 2:  verge cast. So you have to do it. Good luck. I
Speaker 2:  believe in you. It's been three weeks since apple said they would issue a
Speaker 2:  software update to fix the studio display webcam,
Speaker 2:  Godspeed.
Speaker 1:  Hello, and you are listening to the Vergecast the flagship
Speaker 1:  podcast of the edit button.
Speaker 2:  I'm your host for the day. Alex Cranz Nila
Speaker 2:  is clearly not here as you know, because you're hearing me talk,
Speaker 2:  but don't worry. We've got some great people here. We've got Dan Seaford
Speaker 2:  is here. Talk about phones. Hello?
Speaker 3:  We got Liz. Lopatto here to talk about edit buttons, right? Liz, that's it?
Speaker 3:  Nothing else happened.
Speaker 5:  I'm certainly not talking about Elon Musk again.
Speaker 3:  No, we are. We're definitely just going to be here to talk about the Twitter
Speaker 3:  at a button. That's the biggest news of the week. Nothing else happened this
Speaker 3:  week. Very, very quiet week. We've also got, Alison Johnson is
Speaker 3:  going to be on the show later today. We're going to talk about though the
Speaker 3:  one plus 10 pro, she reviewed it. That's going to be really
Speaker 3:  exciting, but first Liz how's Ilan doing
Speaker 5:  Well. I feel like Elan has made
Speaker 5:  some real strides for this shit posting community in
Speaker 5:  that, you know, he's now invited
Speaker 5:  himself to the Twitter board. So for those of you who haven't been
Speaker 5:  paying a ton of attention to Twitter, which I don't blame you, it's a
Speaker 5:  strange place. Elon Musk has been one of its
Speaker 5:  power users for quite some time, so much so that Jack Dorsey,
Speaker 5:  the former Twitter CEO has said that he's like the ideal Twitter
Speaker 5:  user, which I would just like you to ponder in silence for a second. Okay.
Speaker 3:  Well, all right. So the ideal of Twitter user should like
Speaker 3:  threatened people and promise subs and break federal
Speaker 3:  laws and break federal laws. And
Speaker 5:  Yeah, Well, listen, I, you know, long time
Speaker 5:  listeners will remember that I was at the Elon Musk defamation
Speaker 5:  trial for tweeting about how one of the guys
Speaker 5:  involved in the cave rescue in Thailand was a
Speaker 5:  pedophile. And in that sense, I suppose, Ilan
Speaker 5:  was ahead of the curve because now it seems like a lot of people are out
Speaker 5:  here calling each other pedophiles. So thanks
Speaker 5:  Elon. No, he, so he filed some paperwork
Speaker 5:  indicating that he bought, I think
Speaker 5:  9%, maybe
Speaker 5:  9.2% of
Speaker 5:  Twitter. He's been complaining about like free speech basically
Speaker 5:  saying that like too much stuff gets removed and
Speaker 5:  your friend and mine, Casey Newton, who is a pro sole
Speaker 5:  proprietor of his own newsletter has written a little bit
Speaker 5:  about something that stuck with me, which is that people actually seem
Speaker 5:  to like moderated platforms and Tik TOK
Speaker 5:  success is partially because of that. It's most moderated
Speaker 5:  platform. And it's also like Facebook's biggest competition and Twitter,
Speaker 3:  Like way kind of like Jake clear. A lot of us are on
Speaker 3:  Twitter. Everybody, everybody on this podcast is on Twitter. A lot of our
Speaker 3:  listeners are on Twitter. FA we are the minority. The
Speaker 3:  vast majority of the world is not on
Speaker 3:  Twitter and never has been
Speaker 5:  They're on something reasonable. There is some other reasonable platform
Speaker 5:  that is that for people who have like internet brain worms and
Speaker 5:  Godspeed to them,
Speaker 3:  I personally, I embrace my brain worms that, that I've gotten from using
Speaker 3:  Twitter all these years. What I don't get is like, did Elan do this?
Speaker 3:  Because he really wants to just bring shit posting into
Speaker 3:  the mainstream. Like, was this like an advocacy purchase on
Speaker 3:  his part? Or was he just like, I got money to burn
Speaker 5:  So long time Ilan followers will remember that he can be
Speaker 5:  somewhat whimsical in his use of money. So you may
Speaker 5:  remember he couldn't buy the onion, which he's a fan of. And so he created
Speaker 5:  his own sort of satirical thing called FID and
Speaker 5:  then pulled the plug on it, like right after it
Speaker 3:  Launched, just hit with a FID
Speaker 5:  That's right. You know, it's got this whole history with Twitter from, you
Speaker 5:  know, as sec violations from saying he was going to take Tesla,
Speaker 5:  private funding secured, except it wasn't. And, you know, threatening
Speaker 5:  journalists occasionally sometimes stealing means. And so as a
Speaker 5:  practical matter, you sort of start to wonder like, well, what does
Speaker 5:  this mean? And you know, Twitter spokesperson Adrian's and Maura
Speaker 5:  has said, the Twitter is committed to impartiality in development
Speaker 5:  enforcement of its policies and rules and the day-to-day operations and decisions
Speaker 5:  are made by Twitter management and employees. And I
Speaker 5:  will see, I will see,
Speaker 3:  I feel like I was seeing a lot on Twitter, various Twitter,
Speaker 3:  like higher ups kind of feeding the Elon
Speaker 3:  frenzy, like promising him in an edit button.
Speaker 5:  That's right. So you on of course is, is, is already
Speaker 5:  trolling on Twitter. And he has pulled to ask if
Speaker 5:  Twitter should add an edit button. And then the CEO of Twitter has said that
Speaker 5:  the poll will have important consequences. So it does suggest that
Speaker 5:  that there's like some sort of something going on. And then Twitter came
Speaker 5:  out later. It was like, by the way, we've already been working on the edit
Speaker 5:  button. This has nothing to do with Ilan. This is cloud
Speaker 5:  chasing all of that. Sure.
Speaker 5:  Say, you know, I it's, I do think it's interesting that the platforms like
Speaker 5:  top shit poster has the keys to the castle. And like he joined
Speaker 5:  the board as part of a standstill agreement saying that he isn't going to
Speaker 5:  buy more than I think 14% of
Speaker 5:  Twitter, which we'll see. I
Speaker 5:  mean, we already know that my guy kind of takes a dim view of some
Speaker 5:  of these agreements, especially with ones with the sec. So we'll see how
Speaker 5:  that works. But like, I also think that like part of what's fun
Speaker 5:  here, fun. I I'm sorry. Like I don't, I don't know,
Speaker 3:  Big air quotes on that fun.
Speaker 5:  Fun is that he's, he's managed to do this in such a way that he's also
Speaker 5:  managed to basically give a middle finger to the sec,
Speaker 5:  because this is like fun with corporate forums with Liz
Speaker 5:  Lopatto I
Speaker 3:  Love it. I'm here for it.
Speaker 5:  If you are an activist shareholder like per for instance, Elliott
Speaker 5:  capital management who got involved with Twitter last year and was part of
Speaker 5:  the reason why I think Jack Dorsey is no longer CEO and you've bought into
Speaker 5:  Twitter because you want to do some cool shareholder activism. You fill out
Speaker 5:  a form 13 D in which you disclose what your purpose
Speaker 5:  is. But if you're a large institutional investor
Speaker 5:  from like, I don't know, black rock or something
Speaker 5:  like that. And you're just like going to have like a passive
Speaker 5:  stake, you fill out a form 13
Speaker 5:  G and so Musk initially files a
Speaker 5:  13 G and then the same day he filed paperwork
Speaker 5:  to join the board. And like, I can't speak to like Elon Musk's
Speaker 5:  mind because I can't, I
Speaker 5:  don't know, like maybe that was an honest mistake should happens.
Speaker 5:  I do know that he has previously tweeted that the sec is an
Speaker 5:  acronym and the E stands for Elan's. I know that
Speaker 5:  he's gone on 60 minutes to inform us he doesn't respect the
Speaker 5:  sec. And like, he's certainly beefed with them about what he can and cannot
Speaker 5:  say on Twitter, because part of his settlement around the go private thing
Speaker 5:  was that he was gonna run material tweets by a Twitter
Speaker 5:  sitter, like a lawyer, you know, and then he didn't and the
Speaker 5:  sec went to court and then like, the judge was like, this is stupid. You
Speaker 5:  guys figure it out. And so that's, they've sort of been it's, it's been kind
Speaker 5:  of in a lull for whatever, you know, so I wrote about that. And then like,
Speaker 5:  after I wrote about it, he refiled with a form 13
Speaker 5:  D the activist form. And we saw when his
Speaker 5:  buys were, and it seems that the 13
Speaker 5:  G seemed to be late. And the 13 D
Speaker 5:  suggested it was very late. And so, but you
Speaker 5:  know, like again, like I don't, I don't know, lawyer stuff,
Speaker 3:  Like even just this week, we saw another instance of where like space
Speaker 3:  X guy has to go completely redo a permit
Speaker 3:  because they didn't do the paperwork right. Their first time. So it sounds
Speaker 3:  like a lot of his companies struggle with doing
Speaker 3:  paperwork appropriate in proper fashion,
Speaker 5:  You know? And again, like people are going to get mad, but I'm kind of sympathetic
Speaker 5:  to this. Cause I also have trouble with the DMV, but I mean, one of the things
Speaker 5:  that the, the amended filing proved as
Speaker 5:  our local favorite Matt Levine points out is that he definitely should've
Speaker 5:  filed earlier because that, that new filing
Speaker 5:  shows when he was buying each day. So he started buying at the end of January
Speaker 5:  and then had 5% by March 14th, at which point he should
Speaker 5:  have filed a form by like, I think March 24th. And then
Speaker 5:  when I'm buying and then later filed his form.
Speaker 3:  What I keep wondering is like Twitter for the most part has not been a
Speaker 3:  good buy, right? Like, it's that stock has just done
Speaker 3:  fine.
Speaker 6:  It's not a stock. You buy to make money.
Speaker 3:  Yes, no, this is not an investment. That's going to take you to the
Speaker 3:  moon. And yet, well, Ilan is now buying it.
Speaker 3:  And Elan has like a history of being able
Speaker 3:  to tap into the meme stocks. And this, it feels like he's
Speaker 3:  trying like, is this Elan wants an edit button? Or is this Elon
Speaker 3:  once billions through meme, stock manipulation or excuse
Speaker 3:  me, meme, stock savviness. I would never want to imply that someone
Speaker 3:  who's manipulating the market.
Speaker 5:  So here's the thing, as I think we all discovered with Tesla, which to
Speaker 5:  me is the original meme stock. There were a lot of people who trade on their
Speaker 5:  feelings. And I think that's maybe the most interesting part of
Speaker 5:  both cryptocurrency and the stock market is that like it's, it's
Speaker 5:  people are putting money on their feelings and I can watch it in real time.
Speaker 5:  And, you know, I love, I love that. And so there's a
Speaker 5:  possibility that he just bought into Twitter cause he likes Twitter and
Speaker 5:  that he, I don't know, billionaires have hobbies, just like the rest of us
Speaker 5:  and maybe their hobbies are different. Right. But what did happen is
Speaker 5:  that when he bought in and it was
Speaker 5:  announced that he had gotten, he'd gotten in the
Speaker 5:  shares, went up 27%, which I think was the biggest pop Twitter's had
Speaker 5:  since, since IPO, which is interesting because it is again getting absolutely
Speaker 5:  clobbered by Tik TOK and Facebook and so on. So,
Speaker 5:  okay. This, I think puts the sec in an interesting position because like
Speaker 5:  one of the things about Elon Musk brings to a company is a
Speaker 5:  shareholder value, which you can see when he sends the stock up
Speaker 5:  just by buying in. And the sec his job is to protect
Speaker 5:  shareholders. And so if you remove Musk from the
Speaker 5:  board, then potentially that hurts shareholder value and the stocks fall.
Speaker 5:  Right. Right. So if you're the sec, like, what do you do here? And like,
Speaker 5:  I, the answer is, I don't know, but I think we're going to find out,
Speaker 5:  but, but in the meantime, I do wonder if this means we're
Speaker 5:  going to see Twitter moving more towards crypto
Speaker 5:  because obviously one of the other things that Elon Musk can
Speaker 5:  influence by tweeting is the price of something like doge coin.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And he may remember he went on Saturday night, live and doge coin
Speaker 5:  promptly shit, the bed. So there's, there's just like a, sort of, a lot of
Speaker 5:  externalities here to keep track of.
Speaker 3:  So you're, you're saying that like Ilan could be going onto Twitter maybe
Speaker 3:  cause he likes it. Maybe because it's like billionaires have hobbies and
Speaker 3:  that's buying into large social media companies. Peter
Speaker 3:  keel did the exact same thing repeatedly and is made a lot of money off
Speaker 3:  of it. Like I guess that is a billionaire hobby.
Speaker 5:  Well, Peter teal in fairness got into Facebook early and
Speaker 5:  before it was public and made more money than God on that.
Speaker 5:  And this is Ilan coming in like real late and like
Speaker 5:  to kind of a failing platform that he happens to
Speaker 5:  like, is he going to make more money than God? I
Speaker 5:  don't know,
Speaker 6:  Liz, I want to ask, we talked a lot about the stock. I'm curious as to like
Speaker 6:  how much of Elon being on the board and like, how much does this,
Speaker 6:  can we expect this to influence Twitter's product? Like how much power does
Speaker 6:  he actually have by owning 9.2% and having a board
Speaker 6:  seat does like the CEO have to like,
Speaker 6:  do what Elon says now when it comes to like adding features
Speaker 6:  or, you know, whatever whim he might happen to have at the moment.
Speaker 5:  I think he's a really important shareholder at this point, right? Like you
Speaker 5:  don't have to do everything he says, but you do have to keep him pretty happy.
Speaker 5:  Because again, if Elon Musk exits the stock, then so do all the meme
Speaker 5:  investors. So, you know, that potentially hurts all the rest of your
Speaker 5:  investors. And so now, like this is like a question of like, what do you
Speaker 5:  do? What do you do to keep Ilan happy? Which is, I think why we're seeing
Speaker 5:  Twitter CEO helping him drill. Because obviously
Speaker 5:  like if Elon is having fun on twitter.com, then you
Speaker 5:  want to help him have fun on twitter.com in terms of product
Speaker 5:  decisions. I actually don't know the, the sort of the function of the board
Speaker 5:  is to be like, kind of like council of elders
Speaker 5:  or whatever. And like the CEO's like kind of boss
Speaker 5:  and that's not always true at companies, including Facebook where
Speaker 5:  like mark has special shares. So he's always in charge of
Speaker 5:  Facebook and everybody else can fuck off, but Twitter doesn't
Speaker 5:  have dual class shares like that. It's, it's
Speaker 5:  all the same thing. So there isn't really protection
Speaker 5:  for people who want to remain in control and not listen to
Speaker 5:  Elon on that level in terms of what the board does. Like a lot of
Speaker 5:  it is advisory. A lot of it is high level strategic stuff. And
Speaker 5:  I do think that having somebody in the room who actually
Speaker 5:  actively uses Twitter is probably a good thing because
Speaker 5:  as I think we've all discovered from like Twitter is like
Speaker 5:  decisions. Like a lot of people who work there just have no fucking clue
Speaker 5:  how the power users use it and mostly don't care. And so like,
Speaker 5:  you'll do you know, there was like that, that viral tweet about like users
Speaker 5:  try to get like Twitter to stop harassment and Twitter
Speaker 5:  being like, ah, yes, the star button is now a hard
Speaker 6:  Timeline goes sideways.
Speaker 5:  That's right. So
Speaker 5:  there is a world in which having Elon Musk on the board, I do think is a
Speaker 5:  net positive for Twitter, not least because
Speaker 5:  he is someone who has a lot of followers.
Speaker 5:  And one of the things about Twitter that I think is sort of terrible is like
Speaker 5:  the more followers you accrue and the better at the platform you are,
Speaker 5:  the more unpleasant the experience becomes, the more likely you are to have
Speaker 5:  people just like drive by hate iterating, you know? And
Speaker 5:  like
Speaker 3:  His notification tile must just be
Speaker 3:  awful. Like his notifications have like, as he looked at his notifications
Speaker 3:  and years,
Speaker 5:  Yes.
Speaker 6:  Responds, he replies all the time. It's like, how does he manage this?
Speaker 6:  Like I can't handle it. And I have a fraction of a fraction of that
Speaker 6:  following.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I just, I'm very curious how Elon is managing that many
Speaker 3:  followers as effectively as he does.
Speaker 6:  You would think he has better things to do, but apparently not.
Speaker 5:  I think this is fun for him. I think this is a hobby. And so like, and that
Speaker 5:  sounds like, I don't know that it's necessarily a bad thing that he's on
Speaker 5:  the board. And like the other thing that I'll note is that, you know,
Speaker 5:  as of like last may, consumers had lost
Speaker 5:  more than $2 million in cryptocurrency to scammers that were
Speaker 5:  impersonating Tesla and SpaceX, you know, CEO, Elon
Speaker 5:  Musk, right? The FTC announced that that like in, in that six month period,
Speaker 5:  people lost $2 million. There is an ongoing problem with people pretending
Speaker 5:  to be Elon Musk on Twitter to create scans
Speaker 5:  and take people's crypto. So, I mean, you know, having actual Elon
Speaker 5:  Musk on the board seems like there might be a little more impetus to do something
Speaker 5:  about that. Maybe because I imagine he's not super
Speaker 5:  fond of, of having scammers in his mentions all the time, pretending to be
Speaker 5:  him and like ripping off his fans.
Speaker 3:  Well, we've, we've talked about the product decisions and how he may or may
Speaker 3:  not affect that and stuff that the board is doing. But I think the big kind
Speaker 3:  of question is free speech, right? Like Ilan has a very different
Speaker 3:  approach to speech moderation online, then Twitter then than
Speaker 3:  most of the established social media platforms. How
Speaker 3:  much of that are we going to see? Are we going to see Twitter like slowly
Speaker 3:  transform on the moderation front?
Speaker 5:  We could. It's helpful to think. I think back to PayPal,
Speaker 5:  because one of the things that was true at PayPal is that they didn't do
Speaker 5:  a lot of confirmation of
Speaker 5:  customers and they lost a lot of money trying to acquire customers from scammers
Speaker 5:  because they just weren't doing the kinds of things that one
Speaker 5:  might do to avoid being scared.
Speaker 5:  Essentially there is a possibility that Elon is going
Speaker 5:  to be advocating for the wild, wild west, you know, with all
Speaker 5:  of this stuff. And like, again, like his first official comment on all of
Speaker 5:  this is oh, high law. Right,
Speaker 3:  Right. Yeah. Like this is just, he's having a good time. I mean, that's one
Speaker 3:  of the things that like, that's like the appeal of
Speaker 3:  Elan is that you never know when he's being serious. You never know if he's
Speaker 3:  doing this for like strategic reasons or not. And I know a lot of his detractors
Speaker 3:  would say, he's just a big showman. He doesn't actually have
Speaker 3:  any strategy behind it. I think even Peter teal has like
Speaker 3:  alluded to that in the past, but there
Speaker 3:  always seems to be a little strategy to what he's doing. Like he does, he
Speaker 3:  is a billionaire. He has accrued enormous amounts of
Speaker 3:  money.
Speaker 5:  Do you think the chaos is a strategy because it keeps people paying attention
Speaker 5:  to him. Right. I've been to a lot of events where he's
Speaker 5:  spoken and has said something that like people weren't planning for, I'm
Speaker 5:  thinking specifically of the neuro link where he was like, oh yeah, we're
Speaker 5:  in monkeys now. And one of his chief scientists was like, oh, I didn't know
Speaker 5:  that we were announcing that today. Okay.
Speaker 5:  You know, like it's, it keeps things exciting. It makes sure that people
Speaker 5:  are paying attention to him because he's unpredictable. He's not Tim cook.
Speaker 5:  You know, you kind of know what Tim, Cook's going to say before he gets on
Speaker 5:  the stage and it's going to be kind of boring. And like Elon Musk is definitely
Speaker 5:  not boring. So, you know, if
Speaker 5:  he's, if he's going to do like viral polling
Speaker 5:  and sort of like weirdo product
Speaker 5:  suggestions like that, that might suck for the CEO of
Speaker 5:  Twitter. I don't know how it's going to work out for us users. But
Speaker 5:  I do think that this is an interesting thing to just kind of keep an eye
Speaker 5:  on. And I think our, our, again, our friend Casey Newton wrote about this
Speaker 5:  quite well, you know, like it's, it's hard to predict Elon
Speaker 5:  Musk's next action either because that's a
Speaker 5:  strategic thing that he does or just because he's kind of flying by the
Speaker 5:  seat of his pants who can tell. And so I think right
Speaker 5:  now trying to be like, oh, well this means that Twitter is, is
Speaker 5:  not, is going to be free speech central. Or this means that Twitter is going
Speaker 5:  to make certain product decisions. Like, I don't think we get to know what
Speaker 5:  this means for awhile, because it's just
Speaker 5:  impossible to read this man's mind. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Like the, the button they were working on it, they didn't announce they were
Speaker 3:  working on it eons ago. It's like, this was pure,
Speaker 3:  just fun. Trolling just happened to be like nicely
Speaker 3:  timed. But I do still want to talk about the edit button because I personally
Speaker 3:  am terrified of an edit button on Twitter. Like I just keep thinking
Speaker 3:  of the platforms where you could edit and like, yeah.
Speaker 3:  Tumbler like Facebook. I think you can even kind of do it in the very, very
Speaker 3:  early days. And like, do we really want people to be able to go back and
Speaker 3:  edit what they say? And one like disrupt the
Speaker 3:  course of history to some respect, right? Like that's
Speaker 3:  really bad for historians and people looking back on this stuff for archival
Speaker 3:  purposes, but it's also like, you can make people say some really weird
Speaker 3:  stuff with an edit button. I assume.
Speaker 6:  I mean, there's a lot of like technical solutions to all those problems.
Speaker 6:  I mean, weather, whatever Twitter decide city, like they, they say that they're
Speaker 6:  rolling this out or we'll be testing it for Twitter blue users, which is
Speaker 6:  their paid subscription service. So yes, it looks like you're going to have
Speaker 6:  to pay to have this edit button. But I mean, they could do things like putting
Speaker 6:  a timer on it. So you can only edit within 90 seconds or something. A lot
Speaker 6:  of people are wanting to use edits for fixing typos. And right now the solution
Speaker 6:  is to delete the tweet. So like if it had a window that you could edit,
Speaker 6:  just like you can undo emails that you send in Gmail through, you can set
Speaker 6:  like various like 10, 15, 30 second windows, or maybe they could do like
Speaker 6:  a, a way to show, edit history, which I think how Facebook
Speaker 6:  handles it. I actually used Facebook in a long, long time, but like the,
Speaker 6:  the, if you make any edits, you can look at the history of it and see the
Speaker 6:  version of like what it was before and what it is. Now, those would kind
Speaker 6:  of like address a lot of those initial concerns about
Speaker 6:  somebody changing something that's part of the public record. But the other
Speaker 6:  part of the thing that Facebook, or excuse me, Twitter announced this week
Speaker 6:  is that like Twitter doesn't really care about historical records.
Speaker 6:  Like, you know, they, they announced this week that like,
Speaker 6:  when you delete a tweet, it's going to break every single embed of
Speaker 6:  that tweet, which historically did not happen. If a tweet was deleted and
Speaker 6:  it happened to be embedded in an article or another place using Twitter's
Speaker 6:  native end bed tools, you would be able to see what the text of that tweet
Speaker 6:  was. Now it's going to be gone. Like they're using some like hacky
Speaker 6:  JavaScript that you can kind of disable and get around it. But most
Speaker 6:  people aren't going to. So most people are just going to see a blank spot
Speaker 6:  there where a formerly deleted tweet. So like, I don't think
Speaker 6:  Twitter really thinks or cares that much about historical record. I think
Speaker 6:  it wants, it wants people to use it service more
Speaker 6:  ephemerally than, than archivally. So
Speaker 6:  it wants people to be uninhibited and, and speak their mind and share
Speaker 6:  things easily and not feel like it's going to live there forever for
Speaker 6:  them
Speaker 3:  Shit posters.
Speaker 6:  It wants shit posters, but like, why don't they, why doesn't it have a native
Speaker 6:  way to automatically delete your tweets? Like it, they don't serve that.
Speaker 6:  They don't have that feature. So I don't know. Twitter is a weird company
Speaker 6:  to try and figure out it's thinking behind.
Speaker 5:  So I got to say like, I
Speaker 5:  definitely feel like Elmo and the hell
Speaker 5:  fire here about the edit button. Like bring it on, like
Speaker 5:  don't like time limit it. Like don't, don't do anything reasonable
Speaker 5:  with it. Like this is already,
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  This is Twitter. Like it's already chaotic. It's a mess. Like
Speaker 5:  it's a place for like people to like, be absolutely wild
Speaker 5:  online. And it's like entering the arena. And like,
Speaker 5:  if that's, If that's what we're gonna do, let's
Speaker 5:  just, let's go all the way there. Like why the fuck not?
Speaker 3:  Yeah, just absolutely blow it up. Well, I think it's going to be
Speaker 3:  very interesting. Anyway, we kind of look at it like,
Speaker 3:  who knows is it going to become the, the shit posting Supreme?
Speaker 3:  We've said shit posting so many times on this podcast.
Speaker 6:  We are definitely hitting our quota of shit. Posting mentions.
Speaker 5:  This is what you get when you light doesn't show up. Nobody stops me from
Speaker 5:  swearing.
Speaker 3:  We're sorry. Neela is actually gonna have to come through and manually bleep
Speaker 3:  out every single one. That's what he's going to be doing on the
Speaker 3:  plane. Just bleeping them all out while cursing, probably us at the same
Speaker 3:  time. I feel sorry for the people sitting next to him on the plane. It's
Speaker 3:  going to be rough, but Liz, thank you so much for coming and
Speaker 3:  chatting.
Speaker 5:  It's my pleasure to be here. I always want to say hi, Liz
Speaker 3:  Is going to go. We're going to take a break. And when we get back, Alison
Speaker 3:  is going to be here. We're going to talk about the one plus 10 pro there's
Speaker 3:  a whole bunch of monitor reviews. There's some Samsung tablets. It's gonna
Speaker 3:  be
Speaker 3:  fun.
Speaker 3:  Alright, we are back with Alison. We're going to talk
Speaker 3:  about phones. You reviewed a big phone today.
Speaker 9:  I did, sir. All bank. Let's be honest,
Speaker 9:  physically.
Speaker 3:  There are no small phones anymore and there's no Nila. So we can talk about
Speaker 3:  how good small phones are. Dan is totally
Speaker 3:  outweighed here. We went small phone superiority.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I will. I will say that. Alison is the one who also reviewed the iPhone
Speaker 6:  se and her main thesis on that was, this screen is too
Speaker 6:  small. So I just want to like put that out there, but let's
Speaker 6:  talk about the OnePlus 10 player pro, which is a very different phone than
Speaker 6:  the se.
Speaker 9:  Yes. Okay. It's it's large, but I actually, for a big
Speaker 9:  phone, I like how it feels. It has that slightly
Speaker 9:  taller 20 to nine aspect ratio is
Speaker 9:  green. So it just feels like a little bit nicer in your
Speaker 9:  hand. And that there there's tons of things. I really
Speaker 9:  like about it, like personally, but it's really hard to
Speaker 9:  recommend and it just comes down to two things. It does
Speaker 9:  not work on a T and T five G and it
Speaker 9:  never will. Apparently
Speaker 3:  It's like the reverse of the original iPhone.
Speaker 9:  Right.
Speaker 3:  You can do only, not this carrier we'll work on Jenna five
Speaker 3:  SIS when it comes out.
Speaker 9:  Oh, that's the question. Isn't it?
Speaker 3:  That's like, I think a lot of people care. I think a lot of people want to
Speaker 3:  know
Speaker 9:  I'm going to start asking all the OEMs about Jennifer subsistency
Speaker 3:  Support unified says yeah.
Speaker 9:  With a straight face. Yeah. Yeah. So it's no, no 5g on
Speaker 9:  at and T it'll work. You can use LTE. And
Speaker 9:  it's worth saying that 5g on at T and T right now
Speaker 9:  is not that special, but it will get better over
Speaker 9:  the next few years. So that's where that's kind of a
Speaker 9:  major point against the 10 pro and
Speaker 9:  that in the camera system is fine, but it's
Speaker 9:  just not for a flagship phone. It's just not keeping
Speaker 9:  up kind of year on year with when you have the pixel
Speaker 9:  six pro right there or the galaxy
Speaker 9:  plus it kind of sucks to be like, yay. It's
Speaker 9:  just fine. It's okay.
Speaker 3:  I feel like for $900, your phone probably needs to be more than
Speaker 3:  fine.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. Yeah. I think so. What I
Speaker 3:  Thought was so funny was it like, you still really like this phone,
Speaker 3:  like it's not great, but what does, is it just
Speaker 3:  charm? Is there like a charm to the phone?
Speaker 9:  I think maybe I think it charmed me. Well, first of all, it's
Speaker 9:  green
Speaker 6:  Instant bonus points scored on the curve. Now
Speaker 9:  I put, I put a plus one right next to the
Speaker 9:  score because it's green
Speaker 9:  as no, it's pretty, it's like a shiny green to you.
Speaker 6:  We really missed an opportunity to make a OnePlus joke, but I'll leave
Speaker 6:  it.
Speaker 9:  Ah, Okay. I'll show myself out.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. It's like the, this kind of slender form factor. It
Speaker 9:  has this kind of like OnePlus mystique. I
Speaker 9:  feel like. And I don't know if it's just that I've been reviewing like a
Speaker 9:  thousand Samsung phones, but it just feels really
Speaker 9:  kind of league and grown up, you know, the
Speaker 9:  interface. There's not, there's not a thousand things
Speaker 9:  pre downloaded. It feels like a phone, a grownup
Speaker 9:  with you is not to be, yeah.
Speaker 6:  It's a departure from like what the pixels are doing now. Right? Like, like
Speaker 6:  the pixels, especially with Andrei 12 are very colorful and
Speaker 6:  bubbly and cartoony to an extent. And that is not
Speaker 6:  this, right. Like if you want a more suit and tie type of
Speaker 6:  experience,
Speaker 3:  That's what I want from my phone. Yes.
Speaker 9:  It makes you feel like a little more powerful. I'm like maybe I have my life
Speaker 9:  together. We're using this phone.
Speaker 3:  Do you pick it up? And you know what an IRA is
Speaker 3:  immediately.
Speaker 9:  And I know whether I have
Speaker 9:  one. That's a great
Speaker 9:  question. Yeah. It's Android 12, especially with
Speaker 9:  the pixel phones is kind of all about, you know, material
Speaker 9:  you and the colors that throughout the system
Speaker 9:  match your wallpaper and it's fun and it's quirky. And I like it when
Speaker 9:  I use the pixel six, but I picked up this phone in it. It
Speaker 9:  is, you can customize it for sure, but it's
Speaker 9:  still has like a little bit of a OnePlus flavor to
Speaker 9:  it. And honestly, I think I like it. I
Speaker 9:  think I like it a little better.
Speaker 6:  Just a
Speaker 3:  Little, a little more nice.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. It's fancy. I felt a little fancy using this
Speaker 9:  phone
Speaker 3:  A little top hat, little, little monocle and an IRA
Speaker 3:  like, wow, th this,
Speaker 9:  I opened an IRA and I walked with a spring in my
Speaker 9:  step.
Speaker 3:  It's still, it's, it's $900 and it's not as
Speaker 3:  good as the other phones in that, that range. Right? Like the
Speaker 3:  camera quality is not as good.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. And it it's one plus is still really leaning on
Speaker 9:  this Hasselblad kind of partnership they
Speaker 9:  introduced with the nine series last year. And
Speaker 9:  their line with that is that the color science
Speaker 9:  is informed and tuned by
Speaker 9:  Hasselblad, you know, legacy camera
Speaker 9:  maker.
Speaker 3:  But it is that sort of like how, what was the phone maker that was like,
Speaker 3:  yeah, we use like a, in our
Speaker 6:  Huawei had a, yeah. While I had a, like a partnership for a few years.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. So like Walway and like that, that whole partnership was kind of proven
Speaker 3:  to be a little bit of just PR smoke. Like it was just some
Speaker 3:  marketing speak is Hasselblad and one plus the same
Speaker 3:  way.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. They've kind of, they've made some illusions
Speaker 9:  to even down the road. It could mean that Hasselblad has
Speaker 9:  more of a hand in the design of the hardware,
Speaker 9:  which is, is more interesting.
Speaker 3:  Like, will they really, isn't a hassle, but it's like
Speaker 3:  medium format, big cameras.
Speaker 3:  And this is like, what not, this is a tiny
Speaker 3:  sensor
Speaker 9:  On
Speaker 3:  Your phone.
Speaker 9:  Maybe they'll go the Sony route and it'll be something you can like clamp
Speaker 9:  onto the back of a phone that is a medium format sensor,
Speaker 3:  Just a big old lens. Slap it on there.
Speaker 6:  Just to clarify for now the 10 pro, just like the nine
Speaker 6:  pro the hospital had partnership it mounts to
Speaker 6:  software interface slash features, maybe color
Speaker 6:  tuning. If we believe what they're saying and a logo on the back, right.
Speaker 6:  Like the, the they're not involved in the lens or the sensor or
Speaker 6:  anything on the hardware side of things.
Speaker 3:  Okay. But the color tuning are you seeing differences in it
Speaker 3:  versus like Samsung's aggressive thing
Speaker 9:  I get, I mean, I can see a difference between, but it's a really kind of
Speaker 9:  general, like, I can see what Samson's doing. I can see what
Speaker 9:  a pixel phone is doing. You know, a one plus
Speaker 9:  it's nice. I think the colors look nice. And I, I prefer it
Speaker 9:  over a Samsung. I just wouldn't go. As far as like, this
Speaker 9:  is Hasselblad color, you know, it doesn't just
Speaker 9:  scream at me. Like it's some kind of magic color
Speaker 9:  science. It's nice.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. What does Hasselblad color? Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I was going to say that's like, not like a, like, I feel like if you
Speaker 6:  speak to photographers, a lot of them will know like Canon color is very
Speaker 6:  famous and well known. And if you go back far enough, you got like
Speaker 6:  Kodak and Fuji and the film stocks have like their known
Speaker 6:  colors, but like it I've, I've been really
Speaker 6:  invested in photography for decades. And I could not describe hostile blood
Speaker 6:  color science to you. So
Speaker 9:  Yeah, that was my impression too. Someone get
Speaker 9:  Fujifilm color on a smartphone. That's
Speaker 9:  the, that's the phone all.
Speaker 3:  Why has Kodak been spending all of this time with terrible CES
Speaker 3:  booths and not making actually good products when they could be like Kodak
Speaker 3:  color?
Speaker 6:  Cause Kodak's barely a company at this point.
Speaker 3:  Like, yeah, exactly. Like this is very, just licensing right
Speaker 3:  there on the table. You'll get like $5 for every phone.
Speaker 3:  You'll see. You'll make $20 will be great. Like, come on, Kodak sign
Speaker 3:  OD.
Speaker 6:  So the one plus 10 pro is it's kind of a weird launch, right? Like we're
Speaker 6:  getting it late. It's like three months after it came out in
Speaker 6:  China, but we're getting it now finally in the us. And it's
Speaker 6:  only available through T-Mobile. Could you like kind of explain like what
Speaker 6:  they're doing with like the launch of this phone and like, does it feel like
Speaker 6:  this company is invested in this phone or like we should care about it? Like
Speaker 6:  it's just seems very weird to me.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. It's, you know, more than one person I think
Speaker 9:  has felt like the us launch, particularly as sort of an
Speaker 9:  afterthought for one, plus it launched in China in
Speaker 9:  January. There were a lot of, you know,
Speaker 9:  specs dribbling out ahead of that. So it
Speaker 9:  was very much a known quantity before it made it
Speaker 9:  here, aside from the price, which I think is pretty
Speaker 9:  good. It could have been worse 8 99
Speaker 6:  It's less than last year. Right? Like it's, it's, it's lower than the one
Speaker 6:  plus nine pro was last year, last year, obviously we had the one plus
Speaker 6:  nine non-pro that was even lower, but that was, you know,
Speaker 6:  lower tier features and things like that. Right,
Speaker 9:  Right. Yeah. And the, the 10 pro that, or the nine
Speaker 9:  pro that we got in the U S was the higher storage
Speaker 9:  capacity tier. So it was more expensive. This is sort
Speaker 9:  of like meets everything in the middle and it feels about right. But yeah,
Speaker 9:  it's sort of feels like a launch that has sort of
Speaker 9:  fallen flat and I wish there was more
Speaker 9:  exciting stuff to say about this phone. It's good. The charging, I
Speaker 9:  think we should like mention again because they get
Speaker 9:  that right. You know, it's 65 watt wired
Speaker 9:  charging and, and you get a charger in the
Speaker 9:  box
Speaker 6:  Comes
Speaker 3:  What I feel like that's the perfect segue to talk about the
Speaker 3:  Samsung tablets, because, because
Speaker 6:  You don't
Speaker 3:  Get a charge, like how are you charging the, these tablets that do not
Speaker 3:  include a charger in the box? Oh,
Speaker 6:  Well I've got one of those like hand crank things that you like
Speaker 6:  to run a flashlight and then I plugged it into a tablet. Yeah, no. So I
Speaker 6:  finally review the tab S eight family of
Speaker 6:  tablets. They will be live on the site tomorrow morning is from when we're
Speaker 6:  recording this. So you'll probably have seen them by the time you hear this.
Speaker 6:  But yeah. So Samsung has the tab, the tab eight plus the Tennessee
Speaker 6:  ultra, they are premium level tablets. They start at
Speaker 6:  $700 for the cheapest one. And the most expensive one is like
Speaker 6:  $1,500 before you even add things like a case or a
Speaker 6:  keyboard or anything like that. And none of them come with a charger in the
Speaker 6:  box, which I just think is an absurd thing for a product
Speaker 6:  of a that's price. And this type there's like, you know,
Speaker 6:  obviously Alison knows very well. We're kind of used to phones, not
Speaker 6:  coming with a charger in the box at this point, because you can always use
Speaker 6:  your phone's charger from before. That's the assumption is you have a phone
Speaker 6:  charge already and you can use it be from before. I don't really buy that
Speaker 6:  assumption. I think a lot of people just end up buying third party chargers
Speaker 6:  because yesterday's phone charger is not as powerful as today's phone
Speaker 6:  charger and doesn't charge your devices quickly. But that problem becomes
Speaker 6:  magnified on the tablets because there's so much bigger. So like, if all
Speaker 6:  you have is like this dinky five watt charger from your
Speaker 6:  phone, and you're trying to charge a thousand dollar tablet, it's going to
Speaker 6:  take like forever to charge the giant battery in this thing. And they
Speaker 6:  support up to 45 watt charging. But in order to do that, you have to
Speaker 6:  buy a separate charger. So not only are they expensive, but they also
Speaker 6:  kind of demand that you buy another charger. Okay.
Speaker 3:  I feel like if I opened the box and I pull out my
Speaker 3:  big thousand $1,500,
Speaker 3:  14.3 inch,
Speaker 6:  14.6,
Speaker 3:  14.6 inch tablet, that I've spent
Speaker 3:  $1,500 on and I pull it out of the box and I do
Speaker 3:  not see a charger I'm contacting Samsung. Cause I'm sure there's a
Speaker 3:  mistake.
Speaker 6:  I mean, I mean, that's what I did when w when I got the review units in,
Speaker 6:  I opened them up and I contacted Sandy. I was like, is this right? And they're
Speaker 6:  like, yeah, no, that's how it is. So, you know, it's a
Speaker 6:  bummer. You know, they, they have their reasons. I think the reason is fundamentally
Speaker 6:  profit margins, not the environment or anything green of that
Speaker 6:  sort, but going into this, you should know that you're not getting a charger
Speaker 6:  with it. That all said I've had the privilege of
Speaker 6:  reviewing a lot of Samsung tablets over the years. And
Speaker 6:  the general consensus, every single time is the
Speaker 6:  same old Android tablet story of like Android tablets are poorly
Speaker 6:  supported. They don't have optimized apps. They're not as good as the
Speaker 6:  iPad, so on and so forth. And
Speaker 6:  this time around that still is the case, but it's not like
Speaker 6:  the full story. And especially with the tab S eight and the S
Speaker 6:  eight plus, which are the lower, the less expensive ones. So they're like
Speaker 6:  $700 and $900.
Speaker 3:  You would actually want to
Speaker 6:  Buy the 11 inch model. And the 12.4 inch model, they are basically updates
Speaker 6:  to the tab S seven line from two years ago, if you happen to
Speaker 6:  have a Samsung phone, and you were like invested in the Samsung ecosystem,
Speaker 6:  you're a Samsung phone user. Maybe you've got an S 21 or 22, or
Speaker 6:  maybe even a fold. And you've got Samsung galaxy buds and things like that.
Speaker 6:  They're like a lot of things that make sense for you to buy a
Speaker 6:  Samsung tablet instead of an iPad now. So there's like
Speaker 6:  integrations where you can send your text messages from the tablet, just
Speaker 6:  like you would on the phone, or obviously any apps you buy on the phone are
Speaker 6:  going to be available on the tablet, which wouldn't happen if you were bought
Speaker 6:  an iPad, other integrations that like iPad and iPhone users are
Speaker 6:  familiar with, like the ability to turn on mobile hotspot on your phone,
Speaker 6:  right from the tablet is now available. So like, there's these kind
Speaker 6:  of like integrations that if you are bought into the Samsung family of
Speaker 6:  products, I can like squint and see the reason
Speaker 6:  why you would buy a Samsung tablet at this point,
Speaker 3:  Who those people are. Like I know in Korea, that
Speaker 3:  makes a lot of sense, because Samsung is just like the
Speaker 3:  number one phone in Korea
Speaker 6:  Phone companies in the U S that's cell phones, right. It is apple and
Speaker 6:  Samsung. So like, I think there are a lot of people in the U S who, who kind
Speaker 6:  of fall under that. They, they, they got a Samsung phone because
Speaker 6:  like second, most popular company, very few people want to buy pixels. And
Speaker 6:  very few people actually buy OnePlus phone. So, I mean, a lot of people own
Speaker 6:  Samsung phones. A lot of people will own Samsung earbuds to go with their
Speaker 6:  Samsung phones that don't have headphone jacks. So like, make sense. That
Speaker 6:  earbuds thing I should say is like very similar to Apple's
Speaker 6:  ability to switch your AirPods from your phone to your tablet
Speaker 6:  automatically Samsung basically adopted that feature for its own devices
Speaker 6:  now. So if you have Samsung galaxy buds and they're connected to your phone,
Speaker 6:  and then you go pick up your tablet and start playing music or a video on
Speaker 6:  that, it will automatically switch the audio over, which is like a great
Speaker 6:  convenient feature. When it works.
Speaker 3:  It never works. You word, it always
Speaker 3:  activates, like if I get a notification on my phone, it'll be like, oh, do
Speaker 3:  you want me to switch over? And I'm like, no, I don't want you to switch
Speaker 3:  over.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I mean, like even apple doesn't have that, like ironed out entirely.
Speaker 6:  I'm not gonna, I'm not going to try and say, like, anybody's really figured
Speaker 6:  that out completely, but it is a feature that I personally use all the time
Speaker 6:  between apple devices. It's nice to have it on the Samsung side of things.
Speaker 6:  It's nice to have those quality of life things, but like that only works.
Speaker 6:  If you have Samsung products, if you have a pixel phone, or if you have any
Speaker 6:  other Android phone, you lose out on like all of those integrations. And
Speaker 6:  so, like, it makes less sense to buy a Samsung tablet. At that
Speaker 6:  point, you start to lose a lot of those advantages. And then the conversation
Speaker 6:  becomes like, well, okay, maybe you should just buy an iPad because you're
Speaker 6:  going to lose these integrations. You're not going to get the benefits of
Speaker 6:  them. I personally think that the tab S eight is the most compelling of all
Speaker 6:  three, which is the smaller one because of the way that I use the tablet
Speaker 6:  is for like watching video and reading magazines and reading
Speaker 6:  books and stuff like that in a smaller size. It's much easier to do that
Speaker 6:  with if you are, you know, more into like maybe game
Speaker 6:  streaming, which is one thing that Android does do better than iOS, maybe
Speaker 6:  the larger screens would be more compelling to you, but I think most people
Speaker 6:  should probably stick to the tab or the tab of C plus. And let's
Speaker 6:  let the ultra let's let that bake for a few more years before we
Speaker 6:  start spending big bucks on that thing.
Speaker 3:  The one with a 14.6 inch screen,
Speaker 6:  It's a dazzling display. It's a lovely screen to look at.
Speaker 3:  But realistically, like I remember there was many, many years
Speaker 3:  ago, I think HP did an Android tablet that was like
Speaker 3:  17 inches.
Speaker 6:  Samsung had a 17 at Samsung Android tablet. They tried to pitch it as a kitchen
Speaker 6:  TV, and it came with like a built-in kickstand. And you're supposed to put
Speaker 6:  it in the kitchen and watch TV. Yes. But like, it wasn't even framed as like
Speaker 6:  a tablet so much unless outside the fact that it had a touch screen.
Speaker 6:  Whereas this is like very much like you buy it. It comes in the box, there's
Speaker 6:  no keyboard or anything. That's a $350 add-on, which
Speaker 3:  Is
Speaker 6:  A lot of money. And so it is a tablet first and foremost, and it
Speaker 6:  runs Android and it has like mobile software on
Speaker 6:  it. And my, my opinion of this, and I should say
Speaker 6:  always that a review is an opinion based on my experience using it is
Speaker 6:  that this is the size of a laptop. Especially once you have the
Speaker 6:  keyboard, it's a, it's as big as a laptop, it's as expensive as a premium
Speaker 6:  laptop. And so the expectations of it, of what you can do with it
Speaker 6:  should go up and are commensurate to what you expect from a laptop. And it
Speaker 6:  does not hit that because it runs into the limitations of being a mobile
Speaker 6:  operating system very quickly.
Speaker 3:  It starts at $1,500.
Speaker 6:  So it starts at 10 99 for the base model for just the
Speaker 6:  tablet and $350 for the keyboard. But you can spec up the
Speaker 6:  tablet with more storage too. I think in the neighborhood of 1500 bucks,
Speaker 6:  just for the, the tablet itself, the model that I reviewed was like $1,200.
Speaker 3:  And how many, how much storage did you get there?
Speaker 6:  The base model, I think is 128 gigs of storage.
Speaker 6:  It does have a micro SD card, so you can, you know, can upgrade the
Speaker 6:  storage.
Speaker 3:  I'm just going to throw this out there. You can get the USCIS R O G
Speaker 3:  flow Z 13, which is also
Speaker 3:  a very large tablet
Speaker 6:  For
Speaker 3:  $1,900. And it includes the case with the
Speaker 3:  keyboard, right? And a terabyte of
Speaker 3:  storage and Ram and windows. So it actually
Speaker 3:  works as a computer
Speaker 6:  Can run PC games.
Speaker 3:  It can rent, like I'm just,
Speaker 6:  Or if you look outside of tablets and just like what you could
Speaker 6:  spend money on, instead you get a Mac book air for a thousand bucks. You
Speaker 6:  can get a surface laptop for that price you could
Speaker 6:  get. I mean, I really think like, like the Seuss gaming tablet
Speaker 6:  is not going to satisfy the customer, looking at the Samsung tablets because
Speaker 6:  it's thicker, it's heavier. It's not smelt sweet and, and sleek and
Speaker 6:  stuff like that. But Microsoft surface pro devices certainly
Speaker 6:  are. And like the, the reason to buy this over a Microsoft surface
Speaker 6:  pro if like this is like the, the segment that you're playing in or
Speaker 6:  looking at, like, doesn't make it a lot of sense. It doesn't really add up
Speaker 6:  yet. And part of that is because you run into software limitations really
Speaker 6:  quickly, either the apps aren't like, I'll give you this example. We
Speaker 6:  use slack here at the verge. We rely on it. We use it day in and day out.
Speaker 6:  Slack does not have a tablet optimized app, which means that the Android
Speaker 6:  app for slack is stretched to cost 14.6
Speaker 6:  inches. And it's just like, it just like stretches it across. And you
Speaker 6:  got all your little tiny little names of your conversations on the
Speaker 6:  left side and nothing for the rest of the screen. And then you
Speaker 6:  click on it and you got like, I mean, it's absurd. And like, yeah, you can
Speaker 6:  use the split screen function. So you could say like, I've got slack in one
Speaker 6:  side and the browser and another, or whatever, or you could
Speaker 6:  switch to Samsung's Dex mode, which is like, they try to force a
Speaker 6:  desktop windowed mode onto Android.
Speaker 6:  And that works about as well as you would expect. They try to like, make
Speaker 6:  it feel like windows or Mac iOS, but it, it like, doesn't, you run into
Speaker 6:  issues really quickly. Like going back to slack, slack is now in like a little
Speaker 6:  window and you can't really easily adjust the text size. And
Speaker 6:  so scaling is all weird and wrong, or some apps just don't launch or like
Speaker 6:  window management is footsie. Like, it's, it's, it's good for like in a
Speaker 6:  pinch, if you need to do something with more windowing. But like, I could
Speaker 6:  not imagine I tried, I could not work on it all day long. Like it just like,
Speaker 6:  I hit too many frustrations.
Speaker 3:  Sorry. I just keep being like, who is this
Speaker 3:  for? Who is the person who is the decks
Speaker 3:  user? So obsessive, I want to talk to you,
Speaker 3:  like, are, do you, did you look at this
Speaker 3:  14.6 inch starting at a thousand
Speaker 3:  dollar tablet, 700 that cannot do any of the things
Speaker 3:  windows could do that could do iPad, iOS things
Speaker 3:  kind of similar, and you bought it like you, you
Speaker 3:  wanted this device
Speaker 6:  Look like people buy iPad pro 12.9 that are priced out to
Speaker 6:  $2,000. I don't know why. I mean, that's not me, but there
Speaker 6:  are people that buy that. But I think that
Speaker 3:  It's 12.9, like it's small. I can fit that in a bag.
Speaker 6:  And it's practically pocketable. The difference is there as obviously apple
Speaker 6:  has a much stronger ecosystem of software support for the iPad than Android
Speaker 6:  does. And like, that's just like a hard reality. And maybe you can
Speaker 6:  like thread that needle where like all the apps that you do care about, or
Speaker 6:  you can live entirely within Samsung's apps and you don't run into that problem,
Speaker 6:  but it really does not take long to find an issue with, you
Speaker 6:  know, or, or trying to run an app on, on an Android tablet that does not
Speaker 6:  work well on it. So there, there are people out there that like do that on
Speaker 6:  the iPad and maybe Samsung thinking they will do this for the tablet se
Speaker 6:  ultra. But what I really think is, is Samsung is doing its thing where
Speaker 6:  it is throwing ideas out into the market and seeing what
Speaker 6:  happens. And they are like, we've got this 14.6 inch led screen. It's
Speaker 6:  really cool. It's 120 Hertz. We want to put it in a product.
Speaker 6:  Let's just slap it onto a five millimeter thick tablet and see
Speaker 6:  what happens. And we'll charge a lot of money. Not a lot of people are going
Speaker 6:  to buy it, but we'll learn how they use it. And we'll tweak it over the next
Speaker 6:  generation in generation.
Speaker 3:  They kind of just made a cool laptop.
Speaker 6:  They do make laptops. It's a
Speaker 6:  Samsung we're talking about, they make everything.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. But, but a 14.6 old led display and a
Speaker 3:  laptop I'd, I'm like, all right,
Speaker 6:  If you are the product manager in charge of the galaxy tablet line, you
Speaker 6:  are like, screw them laptops or making a tablet. I got this screen,
Speaker 6:  we're using it.
Speaker 9:  Maybe it's aspirational. It's like you sell the
Speaker 9:  smaller tablets by being like, we have this big one. It's like the bottle
Speaker 9:  of wine.
Speaker 6:  I mean, that's certainly a part of it.
Speaker 3:  You see? You're like, oh man, I can't that's too much.
Speaker 9:  Well, I'll just go a couple steps down.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I mean, there might be part of it, but I also think that Samsung is
Speaker 6:  experimenting in public. They did it with the galaxy fold. It took three
Speaker 6:  to two and a half, three generations to really become a product that was
Speaker 6:  like, we can start to say like, oh wow. We're, we're really seeing the
Speaker 6:  usability of this. The first one, as everyone knows, went really
Speaker 6:  bad, really south really quickly. If you look at history of the galaxy
Speaker 6:  note, the first galaxy note was not that great. It was kind of big and
Speaker 6:  chunky and limited. And like it, it was made fun of at the time for having
Speaker 6:  a big screen, obviously Samsung understood that big screens were kind of
Speaker 6:  the future, but you look at every single galaxy note after that, it was
Speaker 6:  optimized to become smaller and easier to use and
Speaker 6:  have an even bigger display and so on and so forth. So like, this is the
Speaker 6:  way Samsung works. I'm not surprised by it. This is the first iteration around
Speaker 6:  this. I think in a couple of years, they're going to do it again. And maybe,
Speaker 6:  maybe they'll have improved the software somewhat. Maybe, you know, Google
Speaker 6:  keeps floating this idea that it cares about Android tablet software again.
Speaker 6:  And so maybe in a couple of years that will have materialized into something
Speaker 6:  more suburban
Speaker 3:  Because we invested a thousand dollars minimum in this tablet. And if you
Speaker 3:  wait three to four years, you'll really, that's what it
Speaker 3:  really kicks off.
Speaker 6:  No rule do not buy something today. Hoping you're getting something out of
Speaker 6:  it tomorrow. Like buy it for what it is today. And I, I don't think you should
Speaker 6:  buy this one yet.
Speaker 3:  The more Cardinal rule is never buy an Android tablet,
Speaker 3:  expecting Google to go and invest in Android.
Speaker 6:  That's why Samsung is in its position now, like Samsung built decks
Speaker 6:  specifically because Google was not investing in Android tablets.
Speaker 6:  And so like it had to build it on their own. And as a result, it's kind of
Speaker 6:  like this weird side project that gets not much attention every year. And
Speaker 6:  really the development on that has been really slow. But like that is a very
Speaker 6:  clear, obvious response to like Google doesn't care about Android tablets,
Speaker 6:  but we don't really have any other mobile operating systems around here.
Speaker 6:  Nobody wants to ties in tablets. So like, what are we going to do with it?
Speaker 6:  So
Speaker 3:  Somebody wants to Tyson tablet, there's like one, one TV
Speaker 3:  smart TV user that just loves Tizen. They actually can
Speaker 3:  explain the difference between it and Android.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Maybe,
Speaker 3:  Maybe
Speaker 6:  Anyways, to go back to it. Like, I think that the tab essay and the Tampa
Speaker 6:  state plus all do have their like place and like, I think they're too
Speaker 6:  expensive. I would love for Samsung to, to do something that's more competitive
Speaker 6:  on like the iPad air front, really like kind of the meat of the market of
Speaker 6:  like people who are buying tablets. But if they have, if they take what they
Speaker 6:  did here and move it down, markets, I think that like, they, they could have
Speaker 6:  a potential or like a good compelling story there. I just think the
Speaker 6:  ultra is, is needs more time. Well, we'll check in, in a couple of years,
Speaker 3:  Little, a little more time. And there was, there was one more big display
Speaker 3:  this week, which was a cam did a,
Speaker 3:  an, a review of the Alienware Alienware's new
Speaker 3:  QD Ola display.
Speaker 6:  You want to, you want to take a stab at naming that product name on, on the
Speaker 6:  microphone.
Speaker 3:  I'm not even going to try to do it from memory. This, the, the
Speaker 3:  very catchy Alienware, a w
Speaker 3:  34, 23 DW
Speaker 3:  rolls
Speaker 6:  Right off the tongue,
Speaker 3:  Like Dell. I will never understand why
Speaker 3:  they just refuse to give cool names to things like they give cool names.
Speaker 3:  It's called Alienware. And they're like, no, that's, as far as we hit Alienware,
Speaker 3:  that's as cool as you get everything else after that, it has to be like completely
Speaker 3:  forgettable. Like, I don't know how, like nobody's going to go in and
Speaker 3:  say, I want the a w 34, 23 D
Speaker 3:  w when they want to buy this thing. Right.
Speaker 6:  Okay. Well then what they'll say is I want that qto led screen. So like,
Speaker 6:  this is the first QD led on the market. I mean, we've seen a bunch of
Speaker 6:  announced. Sure. What bunch were announced at CES? This is technically the
Speaker 6:  first one that's arrived, even though if you try to buy it today, I think
Speaker 6:  cam was telling me that you will get it at the end of June. So they are like
Speaker 6:  massively ordered a little supply chains, but it shows there's probably a
Speaker 6:  high demand for it as well. But it's really interesting because qto led is
Speaker 6:  this new led technology that is supposed to solve a lot of the
Speaker 6:  traditional complaints of OLED. It's brighter. It's got better color
Speaker 6:  reproduction, it's got more things to help mitigate our
Speaker 6:  or extended longevity in lifespan and things like that. And it's very interesting
Speaker 6:  to see it deployed in a gaming display versus a TV.
Speaker 6:  And so if you are looking for the best gaming monitor
Speaker 6:  at the moment and are willing to wait two months to get it hard to recommend
Speaker 6:  anything else.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I like, I'm very excited about this thing. Honestly. I think
Speaker 3:  this is kind of one of the cooler things we've seen in monitor technology
Speaker 3:  in the last few years,
Speaker 6:  Really? The, the studio display webcam. Didn't do it for you.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I mean, you know, I really, I really wanted the webcam. That's not
Speaker 3:  a hard thing to do. Everybody should be like every monitor maker should be
Speaker 3:  putting a webcam in. This is like the easiest, lowest stakes
Speaker 3:  when you can have yeah.
Speaker 6:  To be fair. Dell did not. So the Alienware alphabet
Speaker 6:  soup does not come with a webcam. What I think is the real
Speaker 6:  difference and what is makes the, this Alienware monitor kind of
Speaker 6:  exciting. And the studio display kind of disappointing in many ways is
Speaker 6:  that apple did not innovate at all on the display side of things, which is
Speaker 6:  like the most important part of a monitor monitors, how it looks in the technology,
Speaker 6:  it uses to display photos and pictures and colors and things like that. And
Speaker 6:  they did not. It's exact same thing as what we've known for quite a
Speaker 6:  while. This is innovating on that. And this is a new
Speaker 6:  technology on how a screen is actually displaying things. And
Speaker 6:  like, it's got a fast refresh rate. So when you're gaming on it, it's very
Speaker 6:  smooth. It's got awesome color reproduction. It's got incredible viewing
Speaker 6:  angles. I think there's some pictures in cams review of like coming at it
Speaker 6:  from like 170 degrees from the side. And it's like
Speaker 6:  still full of saturation and like popping off the screen.
Speaker 6:  It's, it's, it's everything you know about your iPhone screen
Speaker 6:  on a 34 inch canvas, that's two feet from your face. And so
Speaker 6:  it's like really quite incredible when you're playing games on it. But even
Speaker 6:  if you're just like using it as like a standard monitor, we tested it with
Speaker 6:  both windows and Mac Mac, you might be hit or miss with the HDR modes,
Speaker 6:  but the refresh rate worked on a couple different Macs.
Speaker 3:  I see. I don't judge the monitor for this because I'm
Speaker 3:  using an LG monitor right now with HDR,
Speaker 3:  with my Mac studio. And Apple's HDR
Speaker 3:  mode is not,
Speaker 6:  I mean, to be fair windows, HDR is not
Speaker 3:  Like neither, neither company has figured out like what HDR means. And
Speaker 3:  even like, we're seeing that games too most, unless you're in film and TV,
Speaker 3:  HDR is like extremely hit or miss on whether or not it'll
Speaker 3:  just make a garbage out of their
Speaker 3:  display. Just like
Speaker 6:  I use an HDR monitor with my Mac and I have to have her off because when
Speaker 6:  I turned her on it just washes the whole,
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Everything just washes out. And sometimes we will, like when you play
Speaker 3:  a game, sometimes you'll be like, I'm going to turn on HDR mode and everything
Speaker 3:  just descends into darkness. And you're like, okay, I didn't actually need
Speaker 3:  it to be a candle lit scene. Like in, like, I think I feel like candles put
Speaker 3:  off more light than this display does. And so I think I'm not going to knock
Speaker 3:  it for that. I just cause also, I just think it's a really cool
Speaker 3:  looking monitor and I love that. Like somebody is actually caring about picture
Speaker 3:  quality and not just speed and a monitor that's meant for consumers
Speaker 3:  because there's a lot of people that like picture quality is usually very
Speaker 3:  expensive. Right.
Speaker 6:  And especially like when we're talking about gaming monitors, it's usually
Speaker 6:  the last thing on the list of things that they care about. Gaming
Speaker 6:  monitors, prioritize input time or input response. They
Speaker 6:  prioritize refresh rate, they prioritize size and they don't even really
Speaker 6:  prioritize resolution. Cause you know, most gaming monitors are 10 ADP or
Speaker 6:  1440 still. This one is still 1440. It's an ultra wide. So it's like
Speaker 6:  34, whatever by 1440. So it's not a 4k
Speaker 6:  monitor. It's not a 5k monitor at all. It's not that like super
Speaker 6:  sharp fidelity, but the colors are amazing. And the
Speaker 6:  gamuts that it covers are amazing. And that's what we are not used to seeing
Speaker 6:  in the gaming monitor world. And so like, it's a big step forward for that
Speaker 6:  in that it is giving you these incredible colors and visuals and
Speaker 6:  also being a really killer performer on games.
Speaker 3:  Like I just want an all led display. That's
Speaker 3:  fast, but also like high enough resolution that I don't see every
Speaker 3:  little pixel on my monitor when I'm looking at it. Like,
Speaker 3:  it feels like there should be a thing that people do.
Speaker 6:  I mean, you could do that. You could stick a 4k OLED TV on your desk. It's
Speaker 6:  just the enormous.
Speaker 3:  You still see the pixels because a 4k OLED TV like scoot
Speaker 3:  back. Yeah. Like way back. Like by, at
Speaker 3:  my, my, my corridor on my headphones, doesn't go that far. You have to get
Speaker 3:  a new headphones. Like I don't get it.
Speaker 3:  Well, that's the QD. Hold on. That's the
Speaker 3:  Alienware a w 34,
Speaker 3:  23 DW an absolutely terrible name
Speaker 3:  for a very, very cool monitor. We're going to take a break. And
Speaker 3:  when we're back, we're going to do a lightning round. There's a bunch of
Speaker 3:  smaller, smaller gadgets and technology news. Let's do it. Alison, are you
Speaker 3:  going to stick around? You want to do the lightning round with us? I'm in,
Speaker 3:  let's do it. All right. We'll be
Speaker 3:  back.
Speaker 3:  And were back with the lightening round. There's a lot
Speaker 3:  of stuff I'm going to, I'm going to start actually,
Speaker 3:  because that was not the only QD Allah display we saw this week,
Speaker 3:  or Like, I'm sorry. Nila is not here.
Speaker 3:  He's not here to like keep me from going on display tangents. There's
Speaker 3:  like, I have all the power right now and I'm going to use it.
Speaker 6:  I think he's going to be upset that he missed this because we're having some
Speaker 6:  really great display conversation.
Speaker 3:  Robinson, this is fun. And Samsung FA is showing off
Speaker 3:  it's its new QD OLED TV. We didn't go to CES where I think
Speaker 3:  some people saw it, but Chris Welch went out and saw the display and was
Speaker 3:  like, all right. Yeah, this is, this is legit. And he saw it in the TV
Speaker 3:  version and that means like Samsung and all these other plate people,
Speaker 3:  when they do these, these TV like displays like show
Speaker 3:  offs, they usually have a couple other TVs there and they always say, we're
Speaker 3:  not going to tell you what the TVs are. And they're very obviously like a
Speaker 3:  Sony and an LG display. And it's like, thank you for
Speaker 3:  putting a small piece of black tape over the Sony, but we know what it is.
Speaker 3:  And he got to go and he saw it like with the other TV is, and he's like,
Speaker 3:  oh no, this is, this is legit. This is very, very cool. And like, you
Speaker 3:  can see it. And 90% of people probably won't
Speaker 3:  care. And I'm like, I'm, I'm the
Speaker 3:  10%. So I'm like, yes,
Speaker 6:  These are a premium TVs. So like, you know, they're the higher end of the
Speaker 6:  market and like that, you know, person buying that is probably a little more
Speaker 6:  discerning. I think it's exciting that Samsung is finally playing in the
Speaker 6:  old led space on TVs. We known Samsung makes OLED screens for
Speaker 6:  phones, tablets, and laptops for very long time. But like we've not seen
Speaker 6:  them on TV. So it's exciting that they're here and they're this
Speaker 6:  good from what we can tell, obviously we'll be reviewing it and have more
Speaker 6:  final, you know, real world impressions later
Speaker 3:  Expensive too. Like you will not be
Speaker 3:  finding one of these,
Speaker 6:  This isn't, this isn't your black Friday thousand dollar Olin TV. Like you're
Speaker 6:  not going to find the deal on this.
Speaker 3:  Here's this isn't like the B the BX or the CX
Speaker 3:  when it goes on sale, this is your good pudding. This is the old school led
Speaker 3:  where you're absolutely gonna put some money into it.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. At least this year. I mean, give it a couple of generations and the
Speaker 6:  prices will certainly come down, but it's exciting. It's exciting that they're
Speaker 6:  here. It's exciting that effectively LG has been like the
Speaker 6:  only LG display I should say, which is their display
Speaker 6:  subsidiary or division has been like the only player in
Speaker 6:  consumer Owlette televisions, especially in the U S if you've got a Sony,
Speaker 6:  it's got an old LG panel, obviously the LGS have an LG OLED
Speaker 6:  panel. So now we've got like another option and
Speaker 6:  Competition. Competition's great.
Speaker 3:  It's great. Where's my E ink TV. That would be
Speaker 3:  terrible. That would be the ugliest
Speaker 6:  Monitors for you, Alex.
Speaker 3:  I know. And they're terrible. I tried to use one and I was
Speaker 3:  like, I couldn't even, I like open slack and I had it in dark mode. And so
Speaker 3:  it was just like all black on the screen. I couldn't see
Speaker 3:  anything. Like, I couldn't even refresh because I was like, I don't know
Speaker 3:  what's happening. Just darkness. Do not. I mean, you can try it.
Speaker 3:  I encourage everyone to try something once, but you'll do it once. And you'll
Speaker 3:  be like, yeah, she was right. That was bad.
Speaker 6:  The other Samsung thing that Chris got to see, it's the latest frame TV.
Speaker 6:  And I think like, to your point, Alex, like about most people not caring
Speaker 6:  about the QD OLED versus Olin debate, people love, the people love the frame.
Speaker 6:  Like the frame TV is like super popular. I think it like scratches an
Speaker 6:  itch that like people feel like they don't like
Speaker 6:  having, this is the reason that everyone has this idea of projectors being
Speaker 6:  so great. And I think we talked about this in the past because they don't
Speaker 6:  like a big black square on their wall that just sits there and takes
Speaker 6:  up space all the time. So Samsung solution is to make it display
Speaker 6:  art. And this year it's got a matte display so that it
Speaker 6:  actually looks more like art, as opposed to a screen. That's showing you
Speaker 6:  something, which is very cool. I think that's it. And Chris says, it's very
Speaker 6:  convincing. You have to like really get close to it to realize that it's
Speaker 6:  actually a screen that's emitting light as opposed to something that's
Speaker 6:  more, you know, passive
Speaker 3:  The sacrifice you're making. Cause like doing the mat display and stuff that,
Speaker 3:  that affects the quality of the display
Speaker 6:  In theory, Samsung claims it doesn't. But you know, again, we'll, we'll,
Speaker 6:  we'll be testing it out for sure.
Speaker 3:  Absolutely. Like everybody would be doing mat displays
Speaker 3:  if it didn't affect the quality. But I think for
Speaker 3:  90% of people that's enough. I'm I'm honestly, I'm
Speaker 3:  still kind of stunned that Samsung has this thing that sells
Speaker 3:  pretty well. It's very popular. People love it. It's very aspirational
Speaker 3:  technology and not a single other TV company has been like, man,
Speaker 3:  we should make like a TV that doesn't look
Speaker 3:  ugly, Like low
Speaker 3:  stakes. Like just make it look like a cool frame. And everybody's like,
Speaker 3:  no, we're just going to make the black square.
Speaker 6:  And the frame is not new. It's been out for like half a decade, at least.
Speaker 6:  So like, there's been, there's lots of time for other manufacturers to get
Speaker 6:  in this. I think, you know, it depends on the technology. They were aligned.
Speaker 6:  LG loves it's old TVs, right? Th that's like their premium flagship technology.
Speaker 6:  You can't leave a static image on an OLED TV. It will absolutely degrade
Speaker 6:  the panel. And then you'll have burn-in. So like Samsung is using LCDs and
Speaker 6:  many LEDs here that it can get away with that much
Speaker 6:  easier than say LG could, but you know, why isn't TCL doing it
Speaker 6:  or whatever the other brands,
Speaker 3:  I wonder what the power bill is. Like, maybe that's the reason, cause you've
Speaker 3:  got a TV on for just 24 7.
Speaker 6:  Well, they have, they have the sensor in there. Right? So like, it turns
Speaker 6:  off if nobody's in the room and then if someone's in the room, it comes on
Speaker 6:  and it's got the ambient light sensor and adjust it and all that stuff. I
Speaker 6:  think the, like if you look at the, like the, the power usage on them, I
Speaker 6:  think the maximum usage is like 60 Watts. It's not a ton. And so
Speaker 6:  like, that's like a light bulb was 20 years ago. So
Speaker 9:  Couldn't it be eating? Did we, Tara, did we come full
Speaker 9:  circle? But what if it was eating,
Speaker 6:  But what if it was eating?
Speaker 3:  It was like, you just roll an E ink. Like, like how the, the
Speaker 3:  LG rolling display. You just roll an E ink display in
Speaker 3:  front of it and like bam, beautiful black and white art.
Speaker 9:  Yep.
Speaker 3:  That's it. I, this I, that is a, somebody can take that idea. I'm
Speaker 3:  just put it out there in the
Speaker 6:  World by that.
Speaker 3:  Like I would buy that. I like, at least Alison sounded like she might almost
Speaker 3:  be
Speaker 9:  I've probably. Yeah, sure. I
Speaker 3:  Can get one or two customers.
Speaker 6:  I would want it to run the Kindle app.
Speaker 3:  Read
Speaker 6:  EBooks on my,
Speaker 3:  Just really enjoy it. I Alison what's what's the news that you love
Speaker 3:  today.
Speaker 9:  I was just really loving Andy Hawkins back to
Speaker 9:  the future jokes with this DeLorean
Speaker 9:  story. It's I don't understand cars. I don't follow the cars, but there's
Speaker 9:  a DeLorean. That's going to be an
Speaker 9:  electric vehicle in the future.
Speaker 9:  So they say it's sad. There's a very like dubious kind of
Speaker 9:  vibe to this article. They've promises
Speaker 9:  before.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. It'll presumably go 88 miles per
Speaker 3:  hour. It will presumably not run on
Speaker 3:  nuclear fuel that
Speaker 6:  Won't run on a blender. I
Speaker 3:  Mean, it will actually, depending on where you
Speaker 3:  live, it will be running on nuclear power because you're gonna have to charge
Speaker 3:  it and maybe you hear your power, so, oh my God.
Speaker 9:  But can you get to the future that way?
Speaker 3:  I do not think you can get to the future, but yeah. Doloria
Speaker 3:  like, is it a, this big like car company? They
Speaker 3:  didn't really make a whole lot of cars, right?
Speaker 6:  No, they have a very famous a fall from grace story. John
Speaker 6:  DeLorean had a lot of legal troubles, which eventually tanked his company.
Speaker 6:  And so they became iconic when, you know, back to the future, came out in
Speaker 6:  the mid eighties and doc brown turned to his old DeLorean into a time
Speaker 6:  machine.
Speaker 3:  I see one on the road. I still scream.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I mean, they're very rare.
Speaker 3:  It's like seeing a famous person. I know. I don't even
Speaker 3:  scream when I see a famous person. I'm just like, yeah.
Speaker 3:  Okay. Like I saw Emily blunt runtime in the street. I was like, oh yeah,
Speaker 3:  she's tall. And I, and I kept on, I see a DeLorean in the street. I'm like,
Speaker 3:  oh
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And there and there, you know, there's a whole lot of like community
Speaker 6:  of like restorers that keep them alive, but they are getting older and
Speaker 6:  the parts are becoming less and less available. So the odds of you seeing
Speaker 6:  an actual DeLorean on the road are becoming less and less, but this is like
Speaker 6:  a new car with the DeLorean brand. You
Speaker 6:  know, it's a new company, you know, so on and so forth.
Speaker 3:  So this is a lot like when somebody was like, we're going to launch a new
Speaker 3:  Atari console and we were like, oh yeah, good luck with that, buddy. When
Speaker 3:  you, when you, when you show us the console and we can play games on it,
Speaker 3:  we'll believe you.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. So they say August 18th, 20, 22, we
Speaker 6:  will see more. So like right now they've shown the left tail
Speaker 6:  light.
Speaker 3:  That's as much as the computer could render of the 3d
Speaker 3:  render, they couldn't finish the rest of the time for the
Speaker 3:  announcement.
Speaker 9:  You don't have a right tail light without a left tail light. So they're
Speaker 9:  off to a good start. I think.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. It looks like this might have a, a side view mirror,
Speaker 9:  At least one,
Speaker 3:  At least one or his brake lights. Like so, so when it's driving and it hits
Speaker 3:  the brakes, presumably you'll be able to see out of one, one tail light.
Speaker 3:  But yeah, this is probably we'll we'll maybe, maybe
Speaker 3:  August we'll see something for real. Maybe August. We'll see
Speaker 3:  yet another very obvious 3d render because it, it
Speaker 3:  wasn't an obvious 3d render. We would've seen more than the tail light.
Speaker 3:  Just throwing that out there. Just, just possibly,
Speaker 9:  Oh, mark my calendar. I'll check in and see how that's going. You work
Speaker 3:  With Andy on it. You guys,
Speaker 9:  I just, I just assigned myself that
Speaker 9:  one.
Speaker 3:  Dan, what's the big news that jumped out at you this week.
Speaker 6:  I want to just highlight Shawn Hollister had a, really a great piece
Speaker 6:  on logic techs. What he calls it, the magic mouse, but it's
Speaker 6:  like not apples magic mouse. Everyone knows Apple's magic mouse is the
Speaker 6:  one that you have to like flip it upside, upside down to charge it. And you
Speaker 6:  can't charge it while you're using it with logic techs, mouse.
Speaker 6:  That's actually been out for like five years, just charges
Speaker 6:  forever on its mousepad. And it's like a wireless mouse that wirelessly charges
Speaker 6:  on his mouse pad. And it's very, very cool. It's been popular for a long
Speaker 6:  time, but you know, there's always something cool out there that that's been
Speaker 6:  popular for a while, but it's really interesting.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. The magic mouse, the real appeal of the magic mouse Apple's
Speaker 3:  magic mouse is that you can scroll sideways, easily.
Speaker 6:  Timeline goes sideways.
Speaker 3:  That's it? Everything else is like terrible about it. Like the, the
Speaker 3:  ergonomics are awful. The fact that like you have, you can't use it when
Speaker 3:  you need a charge. It is mind numbingly stupid
Speaker 3:  by by 2022, but you can scroll
Speaker 3:  sideways. Can you scroll sideways with Sean's Logitech mouse?
Speaker 6:  You know, I, I suppose if you have the scrolly wheel, it's like
Speaker 6:  a very traditional gaming mouse is the thing it's like, it looks
Speaker 6:  like any other Logitech gaming mouse. It's just, you put this
Speaker 6:  special mouse pad under it and it automatically charges it, which is
Speaker 6:  like, you never have to plug the thing in and you have the freedom of wireless
Speaker 6:  control without the wires slowing you down. When you're, you
Speaker 6:  know, 360
Speaker 3:  Mousepad got to embrace the mouse in the pad,
Speaker 6:  You know, looking at it. I don't think it has a sideways scroll wheel,
Speaker 6:  but pro tip, if you hold the shift key and use the
Speaker 6:  regular scroll bar, it goes sideways. But yeah, that's a, it's a fun piece
Speaker 6:  that Sean talked to lodger tech. He like kinda got their like
Speaker 6:  perspective on it. They say it's very popular, which is not surprising. Gaming
Speaker 6:  mice have been very, very popular over the past couple of years. This is
Speaker 6:  one of them, but they like haven't iterated on it in five or six years. So
Speaker 6:  it's kind of just like sat there and done its thing and kept going.
Speaker 3:  I love it. I love it. All right. That's the show. If
Speaker 3:  you're listening to this, you should also be listening to the Dakota. There's
Speaker 3:  a great one. This week with Julia Alexander, former verge
Speaker 3:  employee now knows everything there is to know about streaming
Speaker 3:  and had a wonderful conversation with Nila. Super fun.
Speaker 3:  I'm Alex, Cranz at Alex H Kranz on Twitter. If you
Speaker 3:  want to get ahold of me, if you want to go yell at Nila and tell him never
Speaker 3:  to leave again, never to fly in an airplane again, Les, he misses another
Speaker 3:  show. You can get him at reckless. If you want to talk to Dan it's DC.
Speaker 3:  Siefert Alison is at Alison Joe one and Liz
Speaker 3:  is at miss Lopatto. That's the show. I'm not going to say
Speaker 3:  rock and roll cause I'm not Nikolai have fun
Speaker 6:  Later.
Speaker 6:  Y'all
Speaker 11:  This episode was sponsored by Salesforce, Salesforce, Blas as an
Speaker 11:  all new streaming service that includes live experiences, original
Speaker 11:  series podcasts, and other programming with Salesforce. Plus
Speaker 11:  business leaders can stream the latest and engaging inspirational
Speaker 11:  stories and access thought leadership and expert advice on
Speaker 11:  demand. Salesforce plus is available right now for those looking to be
Speaker 11:  informed, entertained, and inspired in the business space.
Speaker 11:  Join for free and watch great business series on demand at
Speaker 11:  salesforce.com/plus.