# Transcript
ID: 20ea0840-d804-11ec-a9af-19459eb12498
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Computex 2022 laptops, Elon vs Twitter bots, and Apple ‘testing’ foldable E Ink display
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-5462907138627117157/3279856820780632148/s93290-None-4860s-1653027208.mp3
Description: Nilay Patel, David Pierce, and Alex Cranz discuss the most interesting laptops announced this week at Computex 2022.
33:03 - Senior reporter Liz Lopatto returns to update us on Elon Musk's deal to buy to Twitter.
1:00:30 - Gadget rumors continue in segment three.
Speaker 1:  This week on the verge cast, we'll take you through the highlights of Computex.
Speaker 1:  Liz. Lopatto rejoins us for this week and Elan and Alex Cranz
Speaker 1:  loses her mind is eating, coming to the iPhone.
Speaker 1:  That's coming up right after this.
Speaker 3:  This episode of the Vergecast is brought to you by future. If you want to
Speaker 3:  get serious about your workout routine for the new year, I've got a great
Speaker 3:  idea team up with a personal fitness coach and build your own custom
Speaker 3:  workout on future. All levels. Welcome feature is an app that sets you up
Speaker 3:  with your own personal coach who will develop your routine and keep you accountable
Speaker 3:  every single day. Every month, you'll get unlimited training sessions and
Speaker 3:  workouts with your only coach for the same cost. As a single personal training
Speaker 3:  session. Get started right now with 50% off for your first three
Speaker 3:  months@tryfuture.com slash verge. Again,
Speaker 3:  that's tri future.com/verge.
Speaker 4:  Today's show is sponsored by you. Track you track is a powerful product management
Speaker 4:  system for all your groups, big and small. It can adapt not just to every
Speaker 4:  team, but to every team member it's flexible and easy for both tech
Speaker 4:  savvy and non-technical users across your entire organization.
Speaker 4:  There's tons of customization options, so you can create the perfect system
Speaker 4:  for your business, whatever your industry go to you, track.pro and get
Speaker 4:  started with you. Track for free. That's why O U T R a C
Speaker 4:  k.pro you track. It's easier than you think
Speaker 5:  Hello. Welcome to Vergecast the flagship podcast, free speech in
Speaker 5:  America,
Speaker 3:  Army
Speaker 5:  Or deals coverage. The problem with the tech industry right now
Speaker 5:  is like, we're going to talk about confidence. You want to talk about laptops,
Speaker 5:  but an equal amount of people are interested in the cool new laptops on
Speaker 5:  a coffee techs is the torture deal. Machinations of
Speaker 5:  Ilan buying Twitter, which means that we now run like a finance site.
Speaker 5:  We run like an M and a site. It's good. We've I've always thought
Speaker 5:  our futures, hardcore wall street coverage.
Speaker 3:  I know more about the sec now than I did a couple of weeks
Speaker 3:  ago.
Speaker 5:  I know more jokes that the SCCs name could stand for,
Speaker 5:  just cause of Ilan speed. Anyhow, there's a lot going on this week. It is
Speaker 5:  true. There's Computex. There's more on Twitter. We get a lightening round,
Speaker 5:  but I'm the lie. I'm your friend. David Pierce is here.
Speaker 4:  Hi, I'm your friend who will always just tell you to go
Speaker 4:  ahead and buy a MacBook air no matter what you want. I will just tell you
Speaker 4:  to buy a Mac.
Speaker 5:  Look at the end of the day, though. Really again, you know, there's new airs
Speaker 5:  coming out. This is like the worst time to tell people, buy back, look here.
Speaker 4:  Let's just buy a Mac quick air. It's fine.
Speaker 5:  It's just going to be fine. Fair enough. Alex. Creds is here and Alice is
Speaker 5:  going to run the whole show with us. How are you doing?
Speaker 3:  I'm going to be that person that tells you not to buy the MacBook air.
Speaker 5:  Just hold on.
Speaker 3:  Just wait.
Speaker 4:  Alex tells you to build your own PC
Speaker 3:  Yourself.
Speaker 5:  Those are actually like the two farthest ends of the traditional PC
Speaker 5:  spectrum. You understand? Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I also think they might be the only options. Like, I don't know that
Speaker 4:  there's anyone who exists between those two sides of the spectrum,
Speaker 3:  Hewlett Packard, the whole company.
Speaker 5:  Alright, there is a lot going on. Like I said, there's Computex this week.
Speaker 5:  So lots of copies. Next news. Liz is gonna come on. We're gonna talk about
Speaker 5:  Ilan and Twitter and where that deal is. And then I think
Speaker 5:  we're just going to spend about two hours talking about Amazon, adding a
Speaker 5:  USB-C port to the fire, seven tablet. Does that seem like us? Like we would
Speaker 5:  just, that's what we would land on for the last two hours of the show.
Speaker 4:  It is the thing in the rundown that made me go yes, as I was reading it.
Speaker 4:  So I don't know what to make of that, but here we are,
Speaker 5:  David, I think you put this rundown together. There's no project Jenna five
Speaker 5:  SIS news on here. Well, it's a real missed
Speaker 4:  It. It's
Speaker 5:  Our nation's fourth 5g network stumbles.
Speaker 4:  My favorite sort of running thing about the tech industry is
Speaker 4:  everybody's bad slides. And unfortunately there were no bad slides
Speaker 5:  To read.
Speaker 4:  There were no bad slides. And so, yeah, we're just, we're just stuck in Vegas
Speaker 4:  with no service ever.
Speaker 5:  I'm just going to look at my new favorite site, which is fierce wireless.com,
Speaker 5:  which is a hardcore trade publication for the wireless industry. I'll see.
Speaker 5:  Look here some news. I see. What were you doing, David? Did he know that
Speaker 5:  the new director of the national spectrum consortium is issued some comments
Speaker 5:  on RM
Speaker 3:  Or are they good comments, bad comments?
Speaker 4:  What they are is not important. It's just that they exist.
Speaker 5:  It's just, when you see the NSC, you don't think the national spectrum consortium
Speaker 5:  like no, actually the national security council would say anything about
Speaker 5:  This industry. Trade pub got into it. Anyway. They're confident that they
Speaker 5:  will accelerate the development of next generation. Technology is critical
Speaker 5:  to support us competitiveness in case you're wondering what the status of
Speaker 5:  is. That's good. I know all of our listeners are worried about the status
Speaker 5:  of RN. I think
Speaker 4:  They are.
Speaker 5:  David's like, you know, like we're spinning up these new episodes of Kyle Scott,
Speaker 5:  her mini series, where she's like, ploop Hadoop is gonna make you a track
Speaker 5:  ball. I'm going to do one. That's just like a deep
Speaker 5:  dive on over,
Speaker 4:  You know, that thing on the office. Where, where Ryan just opens up a word
Speaker 4:  document, writes a fake URL at the top and gives it to creed for his own
Speaker 4:  blog. We're going to give you a podcast. That's just for you.
Speaker 4:  It's going to be, it's going to be nine hours long and it is not going to
Speaker 4:  be, it's not going to be safe for the broader internet.
Speaker 5:  Andrew and I are going to get together or we're gonna make a cover song of
Speaker 5:  Iran by flock of seagulls, but about
Speaker 4:  Okay, that in it too,
Speaker 5:  All I'm saying is I'm obsessed with this wireless technology. I hope you
Speaker 5:  are too. If you work at the Orn association, leaky some
Speaker 5:  documents, that could be a way for us to become friends,
Speaker 5:  you and me together. All right, let's get out of the realm of the theoretical
Speaker 5:  and into the realm of the extremely real, which is hardcore windows, laptops,
Speaker 5:  David, your, this is a long list of
Speaker 5:  hardcore windows. Well, I guess there's a couple of Chromebooks in the mix.
Speaker 4:  This is the time
Speaker 5:  What's going on at Computex. Tell people what Computex is.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. So Computex is a huge, like truly
Speaker 4:  huge conference that happens every year in Taiwan.
Speaker 4:  And basically this week, I think along with CES is
Speaker 4:  probably the time when we get like the peak
Speaker 4:  into computers, like, like good old fashioned
Speaker 4:  computers. And like CES is like a TV and car show.
Speaker 4:  Computex is when people are just like 13 inch laptops, let's do
Speaker 4:  this. And then they just like throw them out of a truck at you. This year
Speaker 4:  was both like, I mean, to be honest, I don't know what I expect because
Speaker 4:  it's laptops like laptops, our laptops, our laptops. And we had that like
Speaker 4:  one cool phase a bunch of years ago where everybody tried to change things
Speaker 4:  and then nothing has really changed. And now there was a ton of news. There
Speaker 4:  are a bunch of new laptops, including a bunch of really good ones. And I
Speaker 4:  would say generally speaking, not a lot of like wild,
Speaker 4:  new ideas about laptops. So we basically have, you have companies like
Speaker 4:  Acer and a Seuss who are just out here launching every laptop they
Speaker 4:  can possibly think of. And the big upgrade this year is they're all going
Speaker 4:  from 11th generation Intel processors to 12th generation Intel processors,
Speaker 4:  which is a big deal, big performance, big battery. It's all very exciting.
Speaker 4:  It's also just the thing that happens every time. There's new
Speaker 4:  intelligent.
Speaker 3:  I mean, you say that nothing big happened, but it looks like
Speaker 3:  Acer has a laptop. That's going to have 3d content on it.
Speaker 3:  That seems very 2009
Speaker 5:  Laptop that'll make you dizzy. We are definitely in the
Speaker 5:  part of the tech hardware cycle where they
Speaker 5:  assume that people who are around for these ideas 10 years ago
Speaker 5:  are like have children or jobs,
Speaker 5:  you know? Like they're like you, they won't remember. And I was like, no,
Speaker 5:  we're still here, bro. Like, it's really true. I remember when you tried
Speaker 5:  to do stereoscopic display.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. But now they're burying it under more complicated terms.
Speaker 4:  I think the one for this one. So it's the, it's the Acer predator.
Speaker 4:  Helio's 300, which is an unbelievably great man for a laptop.
Speaker 5:  It is a great
Speaker 4:  Name. I'm super in on that. It's a 15.6 inch laptop
Speaker 4:  has a 4k display. And the, the description of
Speaker 4:  how, of what Acer did is it has a liquid crystal lenticular
Speaker 4:  lens, optically bonded on top of it. And it can toggle between 2d and
Speaker 4:  3d modes. Does that sound cool as hell? Yes. Does it mean
Speaker 4:  anything? Almost certainly not. And are you going to want to use it? No,
Speaker 4:  but it sounds rad. So I'm into it. I don't care.
Speaker 5:  So the lenticular lens is the thing that lets it send
Speaker 5:  images out in two different directions. That is a very familiar,
Speaker 5:  you've seen one of these before in your life. I think what they're doing
Speaker 5:  is they're when I say optically blocks, what they mean is our glue is really
Speaker 5:  cool.
Speaker 5:  It's fast. So they've glued it. They've laminated it very tightly to the
Speaker 5:  main display. And then they've got this additional time. Monica did a whole
Speaker 5:  writeup of this text, facial labs in like last year, like
Speaker 5:  almost exactly a year ago. She like went and like did the piece on
Speaker 5:  special labs and Acer the questions. She then was like, oh, this demo is
Speaker 5:  really cool. When are you going to ship it? What are people going to use
Speaker 5:  it for? And they were like 3d design, some answers.
Speaker 5:  She actually had only sent one to her, but it's very much like now they're
Speaker 5:  shipping one and they're, they're like 50 games appears
Speaker 4:  Like the, with the promise of more to come, which is one of those sentences
Speaker 4:  that you just hear like a want, want at the end of
Speaker 3:  51 games.
Speaker 4:  Exactly. But I think that's the thing with all of this and this is true of
Speaker 4:  like, there's a lot of this happening in the PC space right now where there's
Speaker 4:  stuff coming that you're like, oh, that's neat. And they're like, will it
Speaker 4:  change anything about how I do anything? No. It's like, I, that's how I felt
Speaker 4:  about the 360 hinges on laptops that have been coming around for forever.
Speaker 4:  You look at it and it's like, oh, that's cool. I can, you know, I can prop
Speaker 4:  it up like a tent. And that's like, sort of, it's neat in a, in a
Speaker 4:  way, but I have never once in my life, I think I would die of joy
Speaker 4:  if I like walked into Starbucks and somebody was using their Lenovo yoga
Speaker 4:  in tent mode, nothing, I would, I would shake their hand and ask them many
Speaker 4:  questions.
Speaker 5:  Do you remember when Lenova would like put on the icons of the modes in the
Speaker 5:  marketing? They'd be like, oh yeah, tent mode, wide mode and wide mode was
Speaker 5:  just like laying totally flat for no reason. Like flipped around mode. You
Speaker 5:  know, like they'd actually drawn icons for all of this. Here's my theory
Speaker 5:  about all of this. All of this is designed by people
Speaker 5:  who have cool jobs, you know, like you're a laptop designer. You
Speaker 5:  have like a stereotypically cool job. Like if you were cast in a
Speaker 5:  romcom and you're like, what's the cool job for your character in the wrong.
Speaker 5:  I'm like laptop designers, like on the list. Yup. It's right up there
Speaker 5:  with like print magazine editor who just circles things on the glass wall,
Speaker 5:  which is my dream. I've been doing this for 10 years. I've never circled
Speaker 5:  one thing on a glass wall. And
Speaker 4:  Have you carried a large binder full of loose leaf paper with all of the
Speaker 4:  magazine inside?
Speaker 5:  No. And every now and again, people ask me when I'm, if like, are you going
Speaker 5:  to leave early? Like you happy there? I'm like, well, I haven't circled anything
Speaker 5:  on a wall yet. So we've got a ways to go for. I've reached my
Speaker 5:  goals, but right. You have these serious stereotypical jobs. And so you imagine
Speaker 5:  these moments when like someone like takes their laptop and they put
Speaker 5:  it into tent mode or like, they're like, hang on, let
Speaker 5:  me push this button. And then like the building flies out of the front of
Speaker 5:  the laptop and spins around in 3d. And you're like, this is the
Speaker 5:  coolest, not only did I have a cool job, but I had a cool piece of
Speaker 5:  hardware that enables me to do my cool job in the coolest, possible way.
Speaker 5:  And then in real life, most people are like, my job is Excel.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And when I actually do 3d design, I need a very powerful computer.
Speaker 5:  That's plugged into the wall, which I think is how you get from that demo
Speaker 5:  to 50 games.
Speaker 4:  I think that's right. And that's fine and good for that device.
Speaker 3:  3d is actually the best thing to ever happen to Excel. Right?
Speaker 5:  If you, if you're one of the 3d Excel fans up there, can I, the
Speaker 3:  Numbers just flying at your face,
Speaker 5:  These tables really do pivot.
Speaker 5:  Can I just say this? We did the decoder episode with cat Norton,
Speaker 5:  miss Excel. And I was like, maybe the third piece of media she'd ever done,
Speaker 5:  but it wasn't. So we weren't first what he means and she's wonderful. And
Speaker 5:  she deserves all of her success, but that episode like went viral. And so
Speaker 5:  now, like months later, the financial times is writing stories
Speaker 5:  about Excel and tech talk because it is just sort of like bled its way
Speaker 5:  through the media
Speaker 5:  of like one of the most stuffy, just financial publications. It's like
Speaker 5:  Excel is on Tik TOK. You guys.
Speaker 4:  So the learning here is that Excel is like, they always say, you know, porn
Speaker 4:  drives new technology. Like, no, no, no it's actually Excel.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. One of the real theses of Dakota is like, every job is Excel. And if
Speaker 5:  I just spend an hour with you, you will admit to me when your job turns into.
Speaker 4:  But no, I think that the thing that was interesting to me about Computex
Speaker 4:  was exactly that thing that you just said, right? Where there's like all
Speaker 4:  these mifty things that everybody is perpetually working on. And we see this
Speaker 4:  to CES every year, two, there's like three bonkers new
Speaker 4:  ideas about how you can put a screen and a keyboard together.
Speaker 4:  And what it turns out, people actually want is just a laptop. But then you
Speaker 4:  get a couple of things. Like there was Acer has this new thing called the
Speaker 4:  spin seven, 14 that Monica on our team who has basically seen every
Speaker 4:  laptop that exists is super excited about. And it's basically just like,
Speaker 4:  they took a good Chromebook and made it nice looking,
Speaker 4:  which sounds like a relatively small thing, but it's not at all a small
Speaker 4:  thing. And like that's cool and exciting. And then you have like the HP
Speaker 4:  Spectre, which is, I think like for years now, one of the sort of go
Speaker 4:  to, if you're going to buy a windows laptop, it's like the XPS 13 and the
Speaker 4:  spectrum X 360, like just buy one of those. We'll be very happy.
Speaker 5:  Wait, I'm sorry. You think this computer looks good?
Speaker 3:  I mean, have you seen a normal Acer Chromebook? Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. But they're in there in the competition with a new hot look in HP
Speaker 5:  spectra Chromebook. Right. Which is like a, it's a, it's a thousand dollars,
Speaker 5:  but that thing looks great. I'm just looking at a picture of this. And I'm
Speaker 5:  telling you that on the bottom right corner of the display, there is a
Speaker 5:  giant HTMI sticker.
Speaker 3:  We gotta know
Speaker 5:  Like,
Speaker 4:  No you're, I will say you're actually missing the worst part, which is
Speaker 4:  that above the display on the left, it
Speaker 4:  says in, in teeny tiny little letters, it says
Speaker 4:  anti-microbial corn and gorilla glass at the very top left of the
Speaker 4:  screen.
Speaker 5:  This is like, they couldn't get the good stickers. So they took any
Speaker 5:  money, you know, like the HD my foundation was like, yeah, we got
Speaker 5:  20 bucks. So that got us a slot, you know? And it's like, it's the ad that
Speaker 5:  would normally be on like the back of the NASCAR, like underneath the
Speaker 5:  tailpipe, like that's the money? And they're like, no, no,
Speaker 5:  actually on this computer, you can have it right on the front.
Speaker 3:  No, everyone will know.
Speaker 5:  Also I can't believe this is true. That the HTMI sticker is
Speaker 5:  not on the same side of the computer as the HD of my parents.
Speaker 3:  It's just telling you it's exists.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, it has HTMI but a
Speaker 5:  Plug somewhere here is HTA,
Speaker 5:  look, I'm in the market for a new, so this is $750, which is expensive
Speaker 5:  for a Chromebook. But it is also true that the HP, the new HP one is like
Speaker 5:  floating at a thousand and above.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And this one, like the specs on this one are very good. It's like a
Speaker 4:  like high level, Current gen Intel processor, like good storage,
Speaker 4:  good Ram. Like it's just a good computer, which you can't say have a lot
Speaker 4:  of Chromebooks
Speaker 5:  As an HD. My port,
Speaker 3:  Not a lot of can say that.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And this one actually says it to you every time you look
Speaker 5:  at it, look, I'm in love with a high end powerful Chromebook. That looks
Speaker 5:  cool. So I'll put this on my little, my little Stu list, but it's going to
Speaker 5:  come with like the gorilla or what's the stuff the Google on. Can
Speaker 5:  I say the, the first one it talks about is the Rog Flo X 60 in the
Speaker 5:  Seuss. And what's actually the display. Isn't all. These
Speaker 5:  are fascinating. So we talked about the one that does a spatial 3d.
Speaker 5:  This one mini led display with 512 dimming zones. Mini
Speaker 5:  led is starting to come down. Right? The macro crows had them. Macro crows
Speaker 5:  are obviously a little bit more expensive. I think it's fascinating to see,
Speaker 5:  okay, this display styles coming down and then there's one with a
Speaker 5:  new Olin. There's like a inexpensive Ola display.
Speaker 4:  That's called the Acer swift three
Speaker 3:  Affordable. Owlette like $750,
Speaker 3:  800.
Speaker 5:  How big is that screen?
Speaker 4:  It's a 14 inch. It's 8 99. And substantially cheaper
Speaker 4:  than your average OLED laptop. And it looks really nice. And yeah,
Speaker 4:  that's one of the things like outside of all the wacky shit that
Speaker 4:  everybody is perpetually trying to do, like just give us better. Screens
Speaker 4:  seems like that's that one's actually happening. It's like make the processors
Speaker 4:  faster or make the screens better. Make the keyboards not horrible. Like
Speaker 4:  that is the recipe for a pretty good laptop.
Speaker 3:  The prices are interesting too, because for the longest time, like most laptops
Speaker 3:  sold were like under $500. Everybody just wants cheap 10 ADP,
Speaker 3:  15 inch display. Great. And now we've got a lot
Speaker 3:  of sub thousand dollar laptops with like high-end
Speaker 3:  monitors in them. And that's cool. Like an old ed for under a grand.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Would not have thought of that ever.
Speaker 5:  Can I, can I tell you this story? We, so we had the guy
Speaker 5:  Alan Young on decoder, the Fox son guy, then Josh Tris and I, a couple of
Speaker 5:  days after the episode, we took a call from a guy who's been in the display
Speaker 5:  industry for a long time. Cantankerous, older gentlemen. He was like
Speaker 5:  Fox homeless, always a lie. They're never building anything. I know all these
Speaker 5:  stories. We got to take this call. So getting a call and we're like expecting
Speaker 5:  to hear whatever it was. Good call. I'm not going to reveal everything he
Speaker 5:  said, but it was like old school display, manufacturing,
Speaker 5:  executive called to tell us I've been following your coverage. Here's some
Speaker 5:  things you missed, go chase it down. I know these guys. It was obvious to
Speaker 5:  everybody in the industry. They're not living in a factory. And then he's
Speaker 5:  like, I know people like OLEDs, and I know you like your
Speaker 5:  mini LEDs, but I'll see, these are just always going to win. You can always
Speaker 5:  just build them. They're getting better and faster. And I started laughing.
Speaker 5:  He's like, why are you laughing? I was like, my whole house has OLEDs in
Speaker 5:  many of them. There's four TVs in the house. Three of them are,
Speaker 5:  or one of them is plasma. There's two overheads. And my, you know, my laptop's
Speaker 5:  annuities. And he's like, how are you? I tell your readers,
Speaker 5:  don't buy the TVs I'm buying. It was just like
Speaker 6:  The harshest of broken I've ever.
Speaker 4:  The whole case is just, we're going to keep making LCDs.
Speaker 5:  He was like, plasma was a flash in the fucking pan. And you know, there's
Speaker 5:  all that stuff. They're never gonna get brighter. They're all going to die.
Speaker 5:  People are gonna realize it was a disaster LCDs. That's, that's always the
Speaker 5:  future. And I was like, you know, I got, I like, like my eligibility is like,
Speaker 5:  tell your readers, don't buy what you're buying.
Speaker 4:  Wow. See, this is the stuff that happens at trade shows. The, the, like it's
Speaker 4:  like some sharks and jets stuff. Like there's like no
Speaker 4:  lead crew walks into the bar that the LCD crew is already in. And then like
Speaker 4:  things get quiet. And there's, it's like, it's a scene. This is what happens
Speaker 4:  at Computex. Every year,
Speaker 5:  Every year coffee texts, there is a musical theater fight
Speaker 5:  between display manufacturers. They're
Speaker 4:  Just hammering TVs over each other's heads.
Speaker 5:  All right, let's talk about these two, this super bulky
Speaker 5:  Chromebook. I just think the fact that Chromebooks are, they're starting
Speaker 5:  to hit new form factors outside of the, we made a $300 one to throw in your
Speaker 5:  kid's classroom and get destroyed. So now they've got Acer
Speaker 5:  has got this Chromebook tab five 10, which has LTE, which is
Speaker 5:  fascinating for a Chromebook for many reasons. It's also just
Speaker 5:  like super rugged.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. The idea is basically like it's a, I think it's 400 bucks and it's
Speaker 4:  not a particularly like impressive looking for a
Speaker 4:  super powerful device. It's running on the Qualcomm Snapdragon seven C
Speaker 4:  chip, which is basically, this is designed to be a much more like mobile
Speaker 4:  thing and in their press release and stuff, Acer talks about it as like a
Speaker 4:  mobile, like video conferencing system.
Speaker 5:  So it's a mobile device running a Google operating
Speaker 5:  system with the cell radio. That's designed to
Speaker 5:  make calls
Speaker 4:  Kohan.
Speaker 5:  I'm just saying like they made a seven inch Android phone.
Speaker 4:  Yes.
Speaker 5:  But it runs chromo S
Speaker 3:  It's 10.1 inches.
Speaker 5:  So it's 10.1. Sorry. It has the exact same
Speaker 5:  aspect ratio. It was the nexus seven. And I assumed that it is exactly that
Speaker 5:  size in every picture,
Speaker 3:  Much larger pixels.
Speaker 4:  Well, and it's, it's weird that that others are doing this cause like Google,
Speaker 4:  as we talked about on the show is it has this very specific idea about what
Speaker 4:  criminal is for. Right. They see it as like an enterprise thing and an education
Speaker 4:  thing. And I, Frick Costello basically said exactly that to me. And they
Speaker 4:  think of Android as the mass consumer may and
Speaker 4:  thing. And also Android is so much better tuned
Speaker 4:  to like mobile systems. Like you can also make video
Speaker 4:  calls on your phone, which has LTE. Some of them even have a
Speaker 4:  stylist and a keyboard, like it's crazy. But yeah. So the, the
Speaker 4:  existence of this thing from Acer, I think is a,
Speaker 4:  nobody throws computers against the wall, like is her does.
Speaker 4:  So I sorta love it for that anyway, but also just the idea that everybody
Speaker 4:  is still out there experimenting even as Google is trying to like segment
Speaker 4:  chromo S into this teeny tiny little box is really interesting to me.
Speaker 3:  This is supposed to be the, the video Chromebook when it's
Speaker 3:  has a five megapixel webcam.
Speaker 5:  I mean, have you seen any apple webcam people crash shop in this room? Be
Speaker 5:  like, what? I've it's cheap. I can shoot a gun at it.
Speaker 3:  You could probably shoot a gun at this. And it would be okay,
Speaker 5:  So
Speaker 3:  Thick.
Speaker 5:  It's a chunk.
Speaker 3:  It's got a garage for the stylists.
Speaker 5:  I like the little pinstripe texture on the back. And then it's not that
Speaker 5:  I like it so much that I'd purchase it. I'm just saying it's better than
Speaker 5:  the normal thing.
Speaker 3:  It's very 2014. Yeah. It just looks like this would have
Speaker 3:  been super cool in 2014 and eight years later,
Speaker 3:  it just is existing.
Speaker 5:  Here's what it's like. We have LTE guys. You heard about the fourth
Speaker 5:  G the cranes. I gonna talk to you about the sort of chip situation, all of
Speaker 5:  these. But lastly, we should talk about their framework, which they, with
Speaker 5:  you dove into, this is a modular laptop that we've covered for a long time.
Speaker 5:  It seems like they're, they're living up to their promise in some ways.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. So the framework laptop launched a little over a year
Speaker 4:  ago and its whole thing is basically it's a relatively normal
Speaker 4:  laptop. Like not, no crazy ideas about laptops, no super new specs,
Speaker 4:  but it's whole thing is being modular and repairable and upgradable.
Speaker 4:  So their whole idea is you shouldn't have to buy a new laptop every time
Speaker 4:  you want a new laptop. And they came out this year with, they
Speaker 4:  call it a new framework laptop. But basically all it is is a
Speaker 4:  new main board. And it has the 12th generation Intel chip.
Speaker 4:  It's faster. It has all of this stuff. You can buy it in a new body if you
Speaker 4:  want, but you could also just slot it into your existing framework laptop.
Speaker 4:  And that is a really big deal framework made the same
Speaker 4:  promises that a million other companies have made over the years, right?
Speaker 4:  There's project Daraa Intel has done this a bunch of times, everybody has
Speaker 4:  tried to make watches or gadgets and everybody gives up on them immediately.
Speaker 4:  And framework at least is like out here doing the
Speaker 5:  Thing that made the one
Speaker 3:  It's different than like Alienware and MSI and what all those guys were doing
Speaker 3:  a couple of years ago where they were putting like  processors,
Speaker 3:  desktop processors into laptops. Like these are actual laptop processes.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Basically they're, they're taking the, like the Intel, you know, the
Speaker 4:  12th generation, the  and the ice Evans. And they'll just sell
Speaker 4:  you the main board and you just, you just stick it in where everything else
Speaker 4:  is and all the stuff that you can screw, all the parts in and out. They have
Speaker 4:  little ports for expansion stuffs. If you want an HTMI port, you put it in
Speaker 4:  ether, net, you put it in. It's just, it's a little box that you fill with
Speaker 4:  all the computer parts that you want. And it's kind of cool. Cause it's like,
Speaker 4:  it's a new computer, but it's also just like new parts for your old computer
Speaker 4:  that make it a new computer, which is just like wacky new paradigm of thinking
Speaker 4:  about how people buy computers that I think is very cool.
Speaker 3:  Old paradigm.
Speaker 4:  I mean fair.
Speaker 3:  There was the best laptop ever made. Did this,
Speaker 4:  The Motorola matrix,
Speaker 3:  The apple G three PowerBook Pismo
Speaker 5:  Pull the keyboard right off. Oh yeah. Yeah. This is a particularly
Speaker 5:  weird era of Johnny ive keyboards. Like we think that we live
Speaker 5:  through the butterfly era and that was really bad, but that's because all
Speaker 5:  of you are just too young to have lived through that era where he was like,
Speaker 5:  what if it was a tiny wafer of nothing and you could also
Speaker 5:  remove it completely resulting in this springy. His
Speaker 5:  keyboard made also, it will be slightly translucent. So remember that was
Speaker 5:  like, it was like translucent brown. But so when you pulled it off, you could
Speaker 5:  do the airport card. You could do Ram
Speaker 3:  And you could do the processor,
Speaker 5:  You could do the processor.
Speaker 3:  So other world computing. Right.
Speaker 5:  Okay. So some like other people did the processes. Yes.
Speaker 3:  Some other people made it so you could switch it out because I had that
Speaker 3:  laptop for like four or five. Like I had it for over 10 years because I just
Speaker 3:  replaced the, the old crummy T3 with a slightly less crabby,
Speaker 3:  G three and then a G4. And then the
Speaker 3:  internet started to exist in the computer died.
Speaker 5:  Did you have the moment of upgrading that
Speaker 5:  laptop where like starting up every time was like a little bit of an
Speaker 5:  adventure?
Speaker 3:  Yes.
Speaker 5:  Cause I had a, I had a G4 tower and I upgraded like all the
Speaker 5:  Ram and I swapped out the processor and the video card and by the end I'd
Speaker 5:  be like, I can't turn off my computer.
Speaker 3:  It might never
Speaker 5:  Turn on.
Speaker 3:  Like you just did never restarted it. If it restarted. You're like, well,
Speaker 3:  time to go buy a new laptop.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Like you look at the jar of change. We're like, I hope that there's
Speaker 5:  nothing there. So you get a max, it doesn't look exactly like Mac book pro
Speaker 5:  or metric error. Right.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And they're like, I think basically okay. With that idea, like
Speaker 4:  the, the, when I talked to, to Nerov the founder of framework a
Speaker 4:  while back, he was basically like we've the, the industry has gotten a lot
Speaker 4:  of things about laptops, right? Like we don't need to screw those things
Speaker 4:  up while we try to also do this other thing. Like let's just make a laptop
Speaker 4:  that is nice. And it looks nice. But also does these other things, which
Speaker 4:  I a hundred percent think is the right approach.
Speaker 5:  And they changed the, the top cover. Can you replace the top cover if you
Speaker 5:  have the old one too?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. So framework will actually sell you, they call it an upgrade kit. And
Speaker 4:  I think it's 580 bucks or something that is basically
Speaker 4:  the new main board and the top cover. And the big knock on the first version
Speaker 4:  was just that it felt kind of, I don't know, flaky, like it just didn't feel
Speaker 4:  like a particularly solid laptop, which is a possibility for something that
Speaker 4:  is basically just a bunch of pieces screwed together. Like they didn't do
Speaker 4:  any particularly impressive building. So
Speaker 4:  to have it be a little more rigid, like it just took them time. But the
Speaker 4:  idea is now they've like, I dunno, done something to the process. So the
Speaker 4:  top covers a little more rigid and they'll sell you that too, if you want.
Speaker 4:  Or you can just buy like the whole new package, which comes with that new
Speaker 4:  top.
Speaker 5:  Lots of new laptops, lots of new chips. The framework is interesting. Right?
Speaker 5:  It's a new, more powerful chip in the same cooling setup as the old one,
Speaker 5:  Alex, what should we be thinking about chips and all these new computers?
Speaker 3:  I mean, we sold these chips. Like what back in February, I think is when
Speaker 3:  they announced all of this stuff. So it was kind of like exciting to finally
Speaker 3:  see them in the things I think right now the other question is how good
Speaker 3:  actually are they right? Like how good are they doing on battery life? However,
Speaker 3:  everything else Acer historically is one of the first like folks out of the
Speaker 3:  gate with, with new processors and stuff. So these will be some of the first
Speaker 3:  ones
Speaker 4:  They'll try anything.
Speaker 3:  They'll try anything. I mean, that's the thing it's like Acer in particular
Speaker 3:  loves to just try anything. They love to do anything.
Speaker 3:  They're just like, let's see. Cause they have just such a huge business they
Speaker 3:  can afford to do this. They're like what? I think they're fourth now as far
Speaker 3:  as laptops go, but I think there's right now. It's just, there's a lot of
Speaker 3:  questions. We're seeing them in stuff. We're not seeing laptops that are
Speaker 3:  a lot thinner or a lot chunkier. We're not seeing big changes
Speaker 3:  in battery size. So there's definitely some questions to be had
Speaker 3:  about how much faster are they actually, how much better is the battery life,
Speaker 3:  but we have to actually get ahold of them and start testing them. I think,
Speaker 4:  Am I right in thinking that how that turns out is like
Speaker 4:  kind of huge and important for Intel? Because I feel like we're at this
Speaker 4:  moment now where, you know, AMT is doing really interesting stuff, Qualcomm
Speaker 4:  is coming along and it feels like Intel has been making noise about, you
Speaker 4:  know, we're, we're getting back to winning at this stuff and it feels like
Speaker 4:  the elderly stuff is coming out kind of slowly. And it feels like
Speaker 4:  how it turns out and how some of these reviews go feel like it's going to
Speaker 4:  be a really big deal.
Speaker 3:  I think they would like it to be a big deal. I don't know how big
Speaker 3:  a deal it is actually going to be. Right. Like I think Intel
Speaker 3:  has been so behind the curve for so long that it's just
Speaker 3:  like, we'll, I'll be like, oh my God, they caught up. But I think there's
Speaker 3:  a real question of, are they going to absolutely surpass? And I think we
Speaker 3:  saw that with the last generation, right? The 11th generation, we started
Speaker 3:  to see like, oh, they're doing good work here. They've caught up with
Speaker 3:  AMT. So ideally this is like, are they continuing to do it?
Speaker 3:  Was that just a flash in the pan? Or can they continue to stay ahead of AMD?
Speaker 5:  And they keep making this noise about using TSMC is a fab.
Speaker 5:  So if they can actually decouple their designs and make a five
Speaker 5:  nanometre design, which is like, I mean, like
Speaker 5:  if you're at Intel, that's what proposed to you like
Speaker 5:  decoupled design from manufacturing and make a five,
Speaker 5:  nine meter design for TSMC to make. Like, that is just so far outside of
Speaker 5:  the DNA of Intel. That like that company could just have like an allergic
Speaker 5:  reaction to this, this idea, but that's what they're threatening to do.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Like, I mean, they kind of have to right there, their foundries just
Speaker 3:  aren't capable of producing the chips that they need to produce to stay
Speaker 3:  competitive in the market. And they said, well, we're going to build our
Speaker 3:  Silicon sun valley or whatever. They're calling the thing in Ohio.
Speaker 5:  It's the Silicon Hartland
Speaker 3:  Skews me the Silicon Heartland. Like they said, they're going to do all of
Speaker 3:  this stuff, but that's still years away. And I think we're
Speaker 3:  kind of stuck in a spot for them where they're like, yeah, the really cool
Speaker 3:  stuff is coming. Like we kind of have it right now.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. We'll see. I think the answer is we'll see, especially if that Ohio
Speaker 5:  factory comes online, but great that what are we going to do when we test
Speaker 5:  these laptops, we're going to pick them up against a bunch of M series chips
Speaker 5:  and say, where's the performance versus the battery life. And I think the
Speaker 5:  battery life is actually more important.
Speaker 3:  I would a hundred like battery life is where everybody's
Speaker 3:  going. And they've all kind of started to change their philosophy on battery
Speaker 3:  life too. Right. Intel for years, their whole idea was we get through the
Speaker 3:  processes as quickly as possible. So we save you battery life. Cause we're
Speaker 3:  just doing it so fast. And then you realize that that's not actually like
Speaker 3:  that doesn't scale. Well, because you're using so much power to get it done
Speaker 3:  quickly that you're still sucking up the battery, which is where this whole
Speaker 3:  big little core thing came from where it's like, we're going to use these
Speaker 3:  really efficient core. So they're, they're really changing. Like not only
Speaker 3:  are they changing how they're like, okay, we're going to decouple.
Speaker 3:  We're not going to build the chips ourselves, but also our entire fundamental
Speaker 3:  philosophy of how we make chips go fast and save battery life. We're going
Speaker 3:  to change that too. So there's like a lot of stuff they've got to prove
Speaker 3:  consistently. I think they've proven it like once, but they have to repeatedly
Speaker 3:  prove that they can do this. And it's not just a one-off because Apple's
Speaker 3:  already doing it. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I was going to say, you say, we're going to put these things up against what
Speaker 4:  to M series max. And I feel like I, you know, I don't want to write reviews
Speaker 4:  before they get done, but I have an odd feeling. We know how those benchmarks
Speaker 4:  are going to go based on how this stuff has worked out relatively well.
Speaker 3:  I'm just lapping everybody else in the industry right now.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Like apple is just so far ahead at the moment. It's crazy. Like
Speaker 4:  I said, just buy a MacBook air.
Speaker 3:  Wait, please wait,
Speaker 4:  Get, don't buy a Mac book air now. But like in general I have
Speaker 3:  African six. Wait, at least until June six. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  That's a good call.
Speaker 5:  We got to take a break, was going to join us. We're talking about
Speaker 4:  Email. It's the tried and true method of communication for just
Speaker 4:  about everybody. But if you're a top company trying to compete in
Speaker 4:  today's business landscape, you need to be better than regular email. You
Speaker 4:  need a super powered kind of email for modern companies. That's Mailgun by
Speaker 4:  cinch a platform that's straightforward and made great by world-class support
Speaker 4:  and incredibly powerful APIs. Sending a tracking your transactional and marketing
Speaker 4:  messages with Mailgun by synch is easy and it prevents fake signups and
Speaker 4:  removes invalid email addresses from your list quickly. Plus Mailgun
Speaker 4:  by centuries proven they empower leading brands from all around the world
Speaker 4:  to solve complex communication problems. They're powerful email API
Speaker 4:  and intuitive email solutions allow you to control your entire email life
Speaker 4:  cycle from the email testing stage through delivery and their send
Speaker 4:  time optimization capability automatically finds the ideal send time for
Speaker 4:  every recipient on your list and send your message when they are most likely
Speaker 4:  to engage. Mailgun by cinch delivers over 240 billion emails each
Speaker 4:  year for businesses of all sizes from fortune 50 brands to entrepreneurial
Speaker 4:  startups, discover how easy it is to connect with your customers. Start sending
Speaker 4:  with Mailgun by cinch today, visit mailgun.com to learn more
Speaker 4:  prices are going up right now on basically everything. And if you're trying
Speaker 4:  to save some money on essentials, try good RX with codex. You can instantly
Speaker 4:  compare prescription prices at pharmacies in your neighborhood. You can find
Speaker 4:  discounts that could save you up to 80%. It's free and easy to use,
Speaker 4:  and good RX works. Whether or not you have insurance. And even if you do
Speaker 4:  have insurance, good RX may actually beat your copay price. You can check
Speaker 4:  good RX online or in their app. From there, you can find prescription savings
Speaker 4:  at pharmacies nationwide like CVS, Walgreens, Rite aid, Vaughn's
Speaker 4:  Walmart, and a bunch of others. Then take the money you've saved with good
Speaker 4:  RX and put it towards filling your tank or your shopping cart or anything
Speaker 4:  else. That's gotten pricey lately. So for simple, smart on your
Speaker 4:  prescriptions check, good RX go to good
Speaker 4:  rx.com/verge. That is good.
Speaker 4:  rx.com/verge. Good
Speaker 4:  rx.com/verge. Good RX is not insurance, but
Speaker 4:  can be used in place of insurance, Medicare and Medicaid in 2021.
Speaker 4:  Good RX users saved 81% on retail prescription prices.
Speaker 5:  We're back Liz. Lopatto welcome to the verge cast.
Speaker 8:  Hi, thanks for having me good to be back.
Speaker 5:  This is a segment that we are duty bound by law to call
Speaker 5:  this week and Ilan where we will be at some point in the future of
Speaker 5:  relaunching our newsletter that Liz started called this week in Elan.
Speaker 5:  We will take three verge reporters to support that newsletter. At this time,
Speaker 4:  I was saying to somebody earlier that I really liked the idea that this week
Speaker 4:  in Ilan is going to be way more than weekly. Like it just feels appropriate.
Speaker 4:  That that's what, that's how it's going to work
Speaker 8:  Our in Elan
Speaker 5:  This moment in Elan history, okay. Let's discuss where
Speaker 5:  Elon and Twitter are now. And then Elon has done and said
Speaker 5:  a number of other things this week that connect to this
Speaker 5:  deal. Don't connect to this deal, provided a provoked a
Speaker 5:  range of reactions. Well, let's start with the deal.
Speaker 8:  Well, I just want to be super clear is that the deal is still
Speaker 8:  happening no matter what Elon Musk says about it. Like, look, I think
Speaker 8:  you all know that I'm like a long time reader of Matt Levine. I've been reading
Speaker 8:  him since the financial crisis when he was a deal breaker.
Speaker 5:  Melamine is a columnist at Bloomberg.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, that's right. There's a thing that he said about this that I like can't
Speaker 8:  get out of my head, which is like, if you have to look at the contract for
Speaker 8:  the deal you've already lost. Yeah. And so I'm seeing all of these people
Speaker 8:  on Twitter who are like, oh, but he can't disparage Twitter. And it's like,
Speaker 8:  it's Elon Musk. He's going to do what he's going to do. The only entity that
Speaker 8:  can enforce the non-disparagement clause is his Twitter. And they seem
Speaker 8:  desperately to want to get this deal done. They've filed their proxy. They've
Speaker 8:  said multiple times, I think the deal is getting done. It's getting done
Speaker 8:  at this price. They're not renegotiating. And Ilan is just doing
Speaker 8:  whatever.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So let's just start chronologically this week.
Speaker 5:  There are many ways to come at this conversation. I feel as
Speaker 5:  though chronologically is the only one that will provide us
Speaker 5:  sanity. And even then it's kind of dicey.
Speaker 4:  That might be too high a bar.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. I don't, I don't think we're going to get to sanity. We can try. Let's
Speaker 8:  try. So for those of you who haven't been paying attention to the stock market
Speaker 8:  prices have been falling. It's been kind of ugly. And
Speaker 8:  so now the amount that Elan was
Speaker 8:  planning to pay for Twitter, which was 54 20 blaze.
Speaker 8:  It just seems high if you will.
Speaker 8:  So he's been tweeting a bunch of stuff about
Speaker 8:  bots on Twitter, and he's like
Speaker 8:  concerned that there might be too many fake spam bot accounts.
Speaker 8:  That might be as many as 20% of Twitter's users, that the deal can't
Speaker 8:  move forward until Twitter proves accuracy of its
Speaker 8:  actual estimate, which is like 5% I think. And I just want to pause
Speaker 8:  here and note that in normal
Speaker 8:  deals, these kinds of things get ironed out without me
Speaker 8:  watching in a process called due diligence, which
Speaker 8:  Elon Musk did not do on this deal
Speaker 5:  Declined to do. He actually said, I'm relying on Twitter's public statements.
Speaker 5:  He said, this publicly,
Speaker 8:  People just don't want to do due diligence. And I don't understand why, because
Speaker 8:  then they're like, oh, I was surprised by this thing. And it's like, you
Speaker 8:  didn't have to be surprised.
Speaker 5:  Well also I will just, this is more Matt Levine quoting, cause his
Speaker 5:  newsletter on this stuff is great. And it also keeps her finding Elon Musk
Speaker 5:  as his boss because he keeps trying to go on vacation and then something
Speaker 5:  happens. And he's like my boss, I must mean to write the column. It's a very
Speaker 5:  funny bit. But his point was Elan constantly and
Speaker 5:  consistently complaints about bots because Elan's mentions are a
Speaker 5:  disaster. He replied to me last
Speaker 5:  weekend. And then my mentions were a disaster of crypto spam. It was
Speaker 5:  like bizarre. So Elan is like deeply aware of the bot
Speaker 5:  issue. He thinks the number is high. Then he
Speaker 5:  says, I'm going to buy Twitter to fix the bot problems. And now his
Speaker 5:  excuses, I don't want to buy Twitter because I don't believe that their reporting
Speaker 5:  of bots is accurate. And so Twitter for years, like eight years or
Speaker 5:  something right in their quarterly reports. So like less than
Speaker 5:  5% of our monetized daily active users are bots,
Speaker 4:  Which they have said is not a perfect number. We should say, like they've
Speaker 4:  always said, they say something about like applying significant judgment
Speaker 4:  to it. Cause there's no way to like perfectly poll who is real
Speaker 4:  and who isn't under platform, but they're extremely educated guests over
Speaker 4:  and over and over again has been under 5% of users,
Speaker 5:  Less than 5%. But the number and Liz, this is like a weird
Speaker 5:  number right in the industry is monetized double daily active users,
Speaker 5:  which doesn't map. Like when you try to compare and contrast the size of
Speaker 5:  Twitter to any other platform, you kind of quickly realize
Speaker 5:  that no one else uses that number that you
Speaker 5:  can't compare dailies to monthly's because monthly's are always higher. More
Speaker 5:  people show up in a month. You can't compare data monetize well, dailies
Speaker 5:  to dailies on other platforms because Twitter is only counting monetized
Speaker 5:  dailies, which means if you're on Twitter, on other
Speaker 5:  platforms, you can't be, they can't serve you ads.
Speaker 5:  So you don't count. So it's just this one tiny group of users. Then they're
Speaker 5:  saying less than 5% for all we know Elan is like
Speaker 5:  using his own Homeworld Twitter client and he doesn't count, right? Like,
Speaker 5:  so there's just like this weird numerical problem where there's no light
Speaker 5:  to like comparison to anything. And then there's progress
Speaker 5:  while the new CEO, Twitter doing lengthy thoughtful threads about how they
Speaker 5:  calculate the thing to which Elon just replies with a
Speaker 5:  single poop emoji.
Speaker 8:  I listen, he understands how to use Twitter. This is more than we can say
Speaker 8:  for certain other technology moguls out here. You know, I will
Speaker 8:  say though, I just, I don't buy any of this shit around
Speaker 8:  bots. I don't buy any of it. I think this is a negotiating
Speaker 8:  tactic. And like, you know, Matt Levine came out and called
Speaker 8:  Elan a liar. And I think it's worth mentioning that Elan has directly lied
Speaker 8:  to us at the verge at least once. So like, it's not like this is out of
Speaker 8:  character for him to be, you know, disingenuous,
Speaker 8:  let's say
Speaker 5:  You should say what the lie is.
Speaker 8:  Do you remember? It was like a shadow Cain story. I'm sorry, this is going
Speaker 8:  to take a second. I'm going to need to bring the headline up. But we had
Speaker 8:  asked him some question about whether this rocket launch was
Speaker 8:  true and in our, in his DMS back when we talked
Speaker 8:  to him and he said, no, and then we corrected
Speaker 8:  our story, which we had gotten from other sources. And then we had to
Speaker 8:  correct our correction because our first story was right.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. That seems right.
Speaker 5:  Like, why do you think we changed our background policy? We just need to
Speaker 5:  attribute the things to people who say them.
Speaker 4:  So I have a question about this, that one of the things that I've been trying
Speaker 4:  to figure out is like, I think I buy all of that logic. Right. Which is that
Speaker 4:  none of the shit he's searching is actually about issues that
Speaker 4:  he has. And it's actually about him trying to get a lower price on Twitter.
Speaker 4:  That makes a certain amount of logical sense. But the part that I don't understand
Speaker 4:  is if that's what you're going to pick, why would you pick bots? Like why
Speaker 4:  it's such an odd hobby horse to use, to be like your
Speaker 4:  wedge in this fight? Like why would it be bots? Okay.
Speaker 3:  A lot of his followers, bots, like we've heard about Elan's bot
Speaker 3:  army, like they've inflated his like reach in a lot
Speaker 3:  of ways. Right. They've inflated as perceived. We reach. So like bots have
Speaker 3:  been good to Ilan. Like maybe they've been bad to his mentions, but they've
Speaker 3:  been good to him overall. So I was kind of surprised that he
Speaker 3:  is now anti bots.
Speaker 8:  I have a theory about this and it has to do with cryptocurrency spam. We
Speaker 8:  know that as of last year, Elon Musk, impersonators had
Speaker 8:  stolen more than $2 million in cryptocurrency.
Speaker 8:  It's just the, like a lot of these bots seem to be
Speaker 8:  crypto scammers. And for whatever reason, when they reply
Speaker 8:  to Elon Musk looking like Elon Musk with the name Elon
Speaker 8:  Musk, but without like actually being Elon Musk, people
Speaker 8:  really do think that there's some kind of crypto giveaway that
Speaker 8:  Elon is doing and click. Yeah. And I can certainly
Speaker 8:  imagine as Musk is like super protective
Speaker 8:  of his army of fans, that this is the kind of
Speaker 8:  thing where saying, Hey, bots are a real problem. And I really want to
Speaker 8:  deal with them is kind of for them, right? Like
Speaker 8:  they're the ones who get hurt. And they're also crucially the ones who
Speaker 8:  need to be reassured that he's on the level because I found the story that
Speaker 8:  Musk lied about. It's from December 1st, 2017
Speaker 8:  and the headline is Elon Musk told us he was sending a car to space then
Speaker 8:  said he totally made it up. And you may all remember that he did in fact
Speaker 8:  send a car to space.
Speaker 3:  He did,
Speaker 5:  Which ruled. I just want to put that out there. I know that was very controversial
Speaker 5:  at the time. The car in space was awesome.
Speaker 5:  We should just be clear about that.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. If I assign a car to space, I would tell everyone the truth about it
Speaker 4:  forever.
Speaker 5:  What are you learning about?
Speaker 8:  So, you know, like, I, I do think that like some degree of this is about
Speaker 8:  his fandom, which he like really does seem to care about a lot. And
Speaker 8:  like he needs to have a good
Speaker 8:  excuse for why he can back out of the Twitter deal. Not
Speaker 8:  for Twitter. Cause I don't think he gives a shit about Twitter, but for them.
Speaker 8:  So he's still the good guy.
Speaker 5:  He isn't a little narrative.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. And so like, like I think this is a transparent lie.
Speaker 8:  Like I think it's an obvious lie, but I also am not, I'm
Speaker 8:  not a member of the fan club.
Speaker 5:  Well, so this is all happening in the context of a number of things. So
Speaker 5:  as Liz pointed out, the stock market overall is down ever since he launched
Speaker 5:  the Twitter bid, Tesla stock is coming down, both because of the
Speaker 5:  market and because a huge part of his financing is tied to Tesla
Speaker 5:  stock. He's out there in the world trying to find other
Speaker 5:  people to finance the bid with him. Maybe he'll be successful. Maybe he
Speaker 5:  won't. I, if I had that amount of money, I wouldn't be like,
Speaker 5:  yeah, Twitter. That's where I'm going to get my return on investment. But
Speaker 5:  who knows?
Speaker 4:  In fact, a lot of very rich companies have made that particular
Speaker 4:  decision in the past not to buy Twitter.
Speaker 5:  It's true. Like, I don't know Bob. I was like, I don't know, like
Speaker 5:  we're not doing that. Like I think apple kicked the tires, Salesforce kick
Speaker 5:  the tires and Salesforce will buy anything. Seriously,
Speaker 5:  Let's check the fine. But it just seems like
Speaker 5:  that's, you know, I buy a lot of dumb stuff. And if you have that much money,
Speaker 5:  like a piece of Twitter might be how I think about one more
Speaker 5:  PS, five game that I'm not gonna play. You know? Like, I don't know that
Speaker 5:  much money, but you can, you can see how the thought process would scale.
Speaker 5:  But it's a lot of money that is depressing. His Tesla stock, as he
Speaker 5:  continues to basically take the freshmen core
Speaker 5:  curriculum of a liberal arts college on Twitter five in
Speaker 5:  person, which is like, it's just a thing he's doing, right? He,
Speaker 5:  he tweets some like asinine thing about what if there was a
Speaker 5:  more moderate party in the United States and literally Dan Drezner, this
Speaker 5:  is happening right now. Dan dresser, who was my political science
Speaker 5:  professor college. He says, I beg you to add a political
Speaker 5:  science expert to your tutors.
Speaker 8:  Let's see Jeff Bezos. If you were better at Twitter, this could be you.
Speaker 8:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It's like crazy. He's driving everybody insane. Every one of his
Speaker 5:  content moderation ideas, as I've said, his baby tweets for babies
Speaker 5:  Corrine wrote a great piece this week. Obviously there's an extraordinarily
Speaker 5:  tragic shooting in Buffalo on the big platform
Speaker 5:  side. Casey made this point in his newsletter. The big
Speaker 5:  platforms did like perfect content moderation of
Speaker 5:  the stream. Twitch had it down in two minutes. Facebook had
Speaker 5:  its sort of usual Facebook stumbles because it is
Speaker 5:  huge, but it started clamping it down. Right? I identify it. Twitter clients.
Speaker 5:  It like, it was a little platforms like streamable where
Speaker 5:  things got out of hand and they cause they don't have the resources that
Speaker 5:  are the, the teams or the scale. That's where it went. So the big
Speaker 5:  platforms, if you think about it, there was a bad guy. He livestreamed
Speaker 5:  the shooting, his horrific racist motivated shooting. He said he was going
Speaker 5:  to do it on discord. All of the stuff. When the platforms saw it within
Speaker 5:  minutes, they took action, which is a really hard thing to do. Twitter is
Speaker 5:  obviously doing it to Elan. Hasn't said a word about this, right? If Elan's
Speaker 5:  Elan's conception of what the content moderation standards
Speaker 5:  on Twitter are or should be, is all legal
Speaker 5:  speech. Then your first test case is the
Speaker 5:  video of the shooting, right? You've said, if people want
Speaker 5:  more tight content restrictions, they should pass a law. Otherwise I'm doing
Speaker 5:  the first amendment problematic for any number of reasons. This, this is
Speaker 5:  like core classes, education, but this video is legal
Speaker 5:  speech, right? It doesn't meet any of the exceptions.
Speaker 5:  It's just more Allotey. And like honestly, as an ad supported
Speaker 5:  business, like being a place where advertisers want to put their ads, leads
Speaker 5:  you to blocking this video immediately. Yep. This is just one of those spots
Speaker 5:  where like you have to be okay with it because you're okay with the first
Speaker 5:  amendment or you're saying, no, we have to take it down. In which case you
Speaker 5:  have left your principles behind. And
Speaker 5:  now you're saying we're going to make judgment calls.
Speaker 3:  That's why he's talking so much, right? Like, like that's why we're seeing
Speaker 3:  so many stupid inane tweets from him this week is
Speaker 3:  because like he's distracting us. Like, there's a very real
Speaker 3:  question everybody has for him is you want to buy Twitter. You want to
Speaker 3:  change how it moderates here is your first test case and he
Speaker 3:  is pointedly ignoring it. So by
Speaker 3:  like being like, I'm going to drop a poo emoji, I'm going to declare I'm
Speaker 3:  a Republican, which is a shock to absolutely no one. Like,
Speaker 5:  Did he move to Texas?
Speaker 3:  Like, come on. Like, you don't have that much money and not be, but whatever.
Speaker 3:  Like he's just doing all of this stuff to distract us from the fact
Speaker 3:  that he had this test case and he blew it,
Speaker 5:  Blow it. He just didn't say anything.
Speaker 3:  He didn't say anything because what he would have said, like if, if he held
Speaker 3:  his, his principles, quote, unquote of being like the first amendment
Speaker 3:  guy, the first amendment would require it to stay up.
Speaker 8:  I want to be clear. He said a number of things, but not actually about the
Speaker 8:  shooting, because he did talk about like content moderation again. And like
Speaker 8:  this time he was like, oh, you don't want to be manipulated by the algorithm.
Speaker 8:  You should get chronological feeds instead. And then he had
Speaker 8:  time for Matt Taibbi. So congratulations to Matt on that
Speaker 8:  about corporate regulation in California, there were images of a space X
Speaker 8:  launch. There was a Royal portrait of a king Louis, the
Speaker 8:  14th of France. And then he, the next day
Speaker 8:  decided it would be cool to talk a little bit more about the important of
Speaker 8:  open source code. So it's just, it's, it's a
Speaker 8:  lot of stuff to say, nothing that you could
Speaker 8:  engage with if you want, I guess, although I don't think anybody
Speaker 8:  here needs to have chronological tweets on Twitter, explain to them
Speaker 5:  If he's yours has existed for years, by the way you just push that button,
Speaker 8:  You know, it, it does feel disingenuous when you've come out as
Speaker 8:  like a free speech advocate, you have this very public test
Speaker 8:  case. And what you're tweeting about
Speaker 8:  is the algorithm. Like I would understand
Speaker 8:  this. If the algorithm you were tweeting about was the one that helps you
Speaker 8:  locate and take down this kind of content
Speaker 8:  maybe, but that's not what was going on.
Speaker 5:  There's a parallel here. And I feel all, all four of us have pride on our
Speaker 5:  best to avoid this. But like tic talking to you too, you are being
Speaker 5:  taken over by the Amber, heard Johnny Depp trial. Right.
Speaker 5:  And that I would, I would just call that like, this is
Speaker 5:  the algorithm sees demand. There's a lot of demand for it. And then
Speaker 5:  like the underlying materials and public domain, because it is just state
Speaker 5:  media, like the government is streaming the trial, so anyone can use it.
Speaker 5:  I mean, it's content creators can use it. So like there's, they're filling
Speaker 5:  this gaping amount of demand for this trial and all kinds of bad things are
Speaker 5:  happening. Like I think last feed had a great headline
Speaker 5:  today or yesterday that was like, I can't wait to watch the movie about how
Speaker 5:  we were all wrong about Amber heard. Yeah. Right. Like it's a spider,
Speaker 5:  like that's the bad algorithm like at play. Like you can see it happening
Speaker 5:  in real time. Like there's demand for this. People are filling it
Speaker 5:  because they will chase the, the YouTube algorithm or the Tech-Talk algorithm.
Speaker 5:  They actually have no idea what they're talking about people are watching
Speaker 5:  all of it. The algorithm sees even more demand. The cycle continues. There
Speaker 5:  is cat 10 barge at NBC news to the great piece about
Speaker 5:  an Elden ring video game streamer, who is pivoted to
Speaker 5:  Johnny Depp. Amber heard trial coverage, and his goal is it's
Speaker 5:  building his views. And he's like, when it's over, I'm going to pivot back
Speaker 5:  to Elgin and ring.
Speaker 4:  This is how you get in the partner program. That's what he was saying. He
Speaker 4:  was like, this is how I get enough views to get in. And then I can go back
Speaker 5:  And then I can go back. And now my video game content, we monetize. It's
Speaker 5:  like, that's just ice cold. Like that's the most cynical thing I've ever
Speaker 5:  heard. And if Elan's criticism of the algorithm was pointed at that,
Speaker 5:  it would make sense his Chris or the algorithm like Twitter is manipulating
Speaker 5:  you into only seeing the far left stuff that Twitter employees want you to
Speaker 5:  see at the same time that there is a
Speaker 5:  hard right. Racially motivated
Speaker 5:  shooting in our country, like in the state that I live at. And
Speaker 5:  like, I, that to me is it's not that we need Ilan to
Speaker 5:  talk about every mass shooting in the country or weigh in on every public
Speaker 5:  event. It's literally the thing that he wants to do would
Speaker 5:  materially change how Twitter responds to these events.
Speaker 5:  Right? And so like understanding of what he would do in this moment is actually
Speaker 5:  really crucial to understanding how serious his
Speaker 5:  free speech philosophy is. And I don't think that he wants to explain
Speaker 5:  that to anyone.
Speaker 8:  I feel like we already understand how serious this free speech philosophy
Speaker 8:  is. Am I wrong?
Speaker 5:  I dunno. You know, it's, it's so it's chaos. And I think
Speaker 5:  the character of Ilan is word chaotic than the person, the Vilan
Speaker 5:  right. That appears
Speaker 3:  Dude was fairly smart. Like how he set up this deal to begin
Speaker 3:  with a lot of the, the, the, the original machinations of this Twitter deal.
Speaker 3:  You're like, okay. I mean, however, I feel about you. This was like,
Speaker 3:  kind of cool and smart, and, and now it's spitting out because
Speaker 3:  he like his funding situation. He's like, we've
Speaker 3:  now had this horrible event happened that it's very pointedly pointed out.
Speaker 3:  I massive flaw in his philosophy for moderation. All of this stuff is
Speaker 3:  happening. And he's just like, I know what I'm going to do. Erect a billion
Speaker 3:  Straumann to distract you from all the things we actually need to be
Speaker 3:  talking about with this deal.
Speaker 4:  Well, and I think part of the reason, the second after me so much is that
Speaker 4:  there's like, the thing I have always struggled with is like the difference
Speaker 4:  between Elon Musk, like the person and at Elon Musk, the
Speaker 4:  Twitter personality, right? And at Elon Musk is just like a low stakes
Speaker 4:  shit poster. But like he doesn't, he mostly doesn't engage on
Speaker 4:  things that actually matter, except to just like, sort of talk shit in all
Speaker 4:  directions and, and like giggle as everyone freaks out. This is one
Speaker 4:  of those things that a is very high stakes B
Speaker 4:  matters to Elon Musk, the person who is theoretically gonna own Twitter and
Speaker 4:  will at some point and have to make a decision like this and see is going
Speaker 4:  to make an enormous number of people, incredibly angry, no matter what you
Speaker 4:  pick. And he does not actually tend to engage on
Speaker 4:  that kind of stuff directly all that often. But in this case, if he buys
Speaker 4:  Twitter, he's going to have to that's the, and that's why I feel like the
Speaker 4:  silence from him was so strong where it's like, I don't generally
Speaker 4:  care what CEOs have to say after events
Speaker 4:  like this. Right? Like I don't, I don't know that it helps anybody to like,
Speaker 4:  get thoughts and prayers from bill gates after the shooting in Buffalo. I
Speaker 4:  don't know if he did that. I'm not picking up bill gates specifically, but
Speaker 4:  in this case, it's like at some point someone is going to walk into a room
Speaker 4:  and say, Elon, what do we do? And he's going to have to decide,
Speaker 4:  and like, God help us. If he is like the person he is on Twitter.
Speaker 4:  But I think at some point you would want to see that actual person be
Speaker 4:  on Twitter rather than just whoever this character is. And it feels like
Speaker 4:  we're, we still haven't gotten any of that.
Speaker 8:  The other thing that I would just add to this is that like adding to that
Speaker 8:  specific kind of pressure is that it's very like at the front
Speaker 8:  of my mind that like moderation on YouTube at one point led to a mass shooting.
Speaker 8:  Like that's a real thing that really happened. And so like, this is
Speaker 8:  actually a very, very fraught area that
Speaker 8:  like, I don't know that Elon Musk
Speaker 8:  can weigh in on without making
Speaker 8:  things considerably worse.
Speaker 8:  Because again, like th think about who his followers
Speaker 8:  are. If he decides to criticize Twitter, taking down
Speaker 8:  links to this shooting, that seems gross and wrong, and a bunch
Speaker 8:  of people are going to be mad. But if he
Speaker 8:  says, Hey, I've reconsidered. You know, my thoughts about free
Speaker 8:  speech I've, I've got a more nuanced plan. Now that
Speaker 8:  potentially freaks out everybody who wanted to bring back Donald Trump to
Speaker 8:  the platform. And also like potentially like not for nothing
Speaker 8:  puts Twitter employees at actual physical risk.
Speaker 8:  So I just feel like it's a super ugly place to be. And like it's
Speaker 8:  when we talk about how difficult it is to moderate these platforms,
Speaker 8:  this is specifically the thing that we're talking about. And, you know, there
Speaker 8:  was that thread from the former Reddit CEO about how he was like
Speaker 8:  Eli, and you don't want this, like, this is going to break you. This is going
Speaker 8:  to be the worst thing you've ever you've ever seen. Like this was what he
Speaker 8:  meant.
Speaker 5:  The thing I'll add is this is like inside baseball, journalism.
Speaker 5:  But I think it's useful context here. We're good at this story
Speaker 5:  now, like the verge is good at it. And like, kind of the broader media is
Speaker 5:  good at it. Like the thing happens where, like, what are the platforms going
Speaker 5:  to do? We reach out to Tom's team at the platforms we hear
Speaker 5:  from the head of policy. We hear from the head of trust and
Speaker 5:  safety. They've made a decision. The decision has been like
Speaker 5:  reasonably disseminated to their teams. They tell us the
Speaker 5:  timeline on which they made the decision. This is how we know Twitch did
Speaker 5:  it in minutes. Like in one very abstract way. It's like an exchange of form
Speaker 5:  letters, right? We're like, what did you do? And here's what we did. And
Speaker 5:  it all, it all makes sense. And we've like, we've learned how to
Speaker 5:  communicate about content moderation between
Speaker 5:  professionals at like a pretty high level. And like that requires a comms
Speaker 5:  apparatus and a policy apparatus and a trust and safety team. And
Speaker 5:  then maybe they got it wrong. Maybe they didn't. But like whatever, we know
Speaker 5:  how to have the communication yuans companies don't have press
Speaker 5:  departments. They don't have comms. They don't like communicating about
Speaker 5:  what they're doing. He literally opened this by starting
Speaker 5:  online harassment campaign against Twitter's top lawyer, vagina. Got it.
Speaker 5:  Like just crazy. Like, it's like, it's not going to work if he takes over.
Speaker 5:  And he doesn't have that functionality because if you're running the town
Speaker 5:  square, the town square has to be accountable to people. And so
Speaker 5:  we should wrap this up, but like one of the funniest parts about this whole
Speaker 5:  week is that Twitter had an all hands this week and they
Speaker 5:  told staff that there's no such thing as a deal being on hold
Speaker 5:  Twitter, saying they want the deal to be completed on the agreed upon terms,
Speaker 5:  which by the way, they have a binding contract along rode to
Speaker 5:  Elan and said buying Twitter, which is like a crazy outcome. But the,
Speaker 5:  you know, Twitter's head lawyer who would make those decisions and do those
Speaker 5:  things are it's a good try. I got a, who is in charge of content policy.
Speaker 5:  So now he pissed off the lawyer, which is just one of those like classic
Speaker 5:  errors,
Speaker 5:  Like
Speaker 3:  How much of this Twitter deal is just Elan Musk,
Speaker 3:  his ego, getting away from it. Like how much of this is just hubris. We're
Speaker 3:  just watching like hubris happen.
Speaker 8:  I would say at least 95%.
Speaker 4:  I was going to say a little lower, but I think you're probably right. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I mean, it does seem like he thinks he can just chaos his way
Speaker 4:  into whatever he wants. And Twitter holds all the
Speaker 4:  actual cards here.
Speaker 8:  I will say that like one thing that I've been reflecting on for a while
Speaker 8:  now is that the reason why Elon Musk thinks he can do this is
Speaker 8:  because he's chaos his way into a lot of things. And out of a lot of
Speaker 8:  things, just without consequences or with
Speaker 8:  consequences that are so minimal for him, like for
Speaker 8:  instance, a $20 million fine from the sec
Speaker 8:  that, you know, it's a slap on the wrist. And so on some
Speaker 8:  level, I think he genuinely believes the laws of the
Speaker 8:  United States of America don't apply to him. And I am very interested
Speaker 8:  in finding out if he's right, because if that's true,
Speaker 8:  we have a problem.
Speaker 5:  We need to end the segment before our producer, Liam like literally jumps
Speaker 5:  through the zoom and chokes me out. He's been writing in all caps in red,
Speaker 5:  we're over in the dock. This is a real thing. That's happening.
Speaker 5:  The one thing I'll say two decisions out of the fifth circuit, which represents
Speaker 5:  taxes this week. One, they let the horrible Texas social
Speaker 5:  media bill go through, which is not being appeal to the Supreme court,
Speaker 5:  hilarious backstory to that. They weren't expecting to win that.
Speaker 5:  And now they have to find lawyers to argue their case in the Supreme court.
Speaker 5:  And they can't find any lawyers you want to. It's very funny. And then to
Speaker 5:  fifth circuit, same crazy ass, fifth circuit. You want to see some wild.
Speaker 5:  You want to see judges losing their minds. Fifth circuit. They reversed
Speaker 5:  an sec enforcement order this week saying that
Speaker 5:  administrative, the administrative state was not appropriate in this case,
Speaker 5:  which has a real, your Elan and your federal appellate
Speaker 5:  court is saying the sec, can't do stuff to you. Ooh. Ooh.
Speaker 5:  All right. We got to take a break, Liz. I'm sure we will have you back on
Speaker 5:  for this week in the Elan for many weeks to come. This is like the story
Speaker 5:  of the year. It's very entertaining for a variety of reasons.
Speaker 5:  Also. I think it might end with Twitter being gone no matter what
Speaker 5:  happens. That's my current prediction is that no matter what happens
Speaker 5:  at the end of this Twitter has gone. Like they might like Jack Dorsey might
Speaker 5:  be like, delete it. I'll do it on the blockchain. Like you never know. Like,
Speaker 5:  we'll see. All right. Thank you so much, Liz. Right?
Speaker 8:  Thanks guys.
Speaker 5:  We'll be right back with a lightning round.
Speaker 4:  Whether you want to gain a skillset to jumpstart your career, or you're just
Speaker 4:  looking for that sweet, sweet validation that comes from getting good at
Speaker 4:  something. Try code academy. Over 50 million. People have already
Speaker 4:  learned coding using code academy. That's because it not only teaches you
Speaker 4:  job ready skills, but also helps you build unique projects for your
Speaker 4:  portfolio and earn certificates and even prep for technical interviews.
Speaker 4:  If you're not sure where to start code academy can tailor career advice and
Speaker 4:  course recommendations based on your interests and what you're already good
Speaker 4:  at. Learn a cool new skill and get qualified for in demand jobs all at your
Speaker 4:  own pace. It doesn't matter if you're a newbie or just brushing up. You'll
Speaker 4:  be writing real working code in just a few minutes. With code academy, you
Speaker 4:  can learn coding languages like Python, HTML, JavaScript, and many
Speaker 4:  others. Join over 50 million people learning to code with code academy and
Speaker 4:  see where coding can take. You get 15% off your code academy pro membership.
Speaker 4:  When you go to code academy.com and use promo code verge, that's promo
Speaker 4:  code verge@codecademy.com to get 15% off code academy,
Speaker 4:  pro C O D E C a D E M
Speaker 4:  y.com promo code for church.
Speaker 10:  I am Scott Galloway. And along with Kara Swisher, the jungle cat, I host
Speaker 10:  the podcast pivot. Now, since this is an ad running on a
Speaker 10:  podcast, you might have no idea what I look like.
Speaker 10:  Imagine someone who was very handsome minus the handsome part. Anyways,
Speaker 10:  you're in luck. As we partnered with Salesforce to provide you
Speaker 10:  with bite-sized video snippets of the best content we have to offer
Speaker 10:  every week. Salesforce has new streaming service Salesforce
Speaker 10:  plus will now be the exclusive home for visual
Speaker 10:  highlights of pivot showing four video segments each and
Speaker 10:  every week. What a thrill, but it's not just pivot
Speaker 10:  Salesforce. Plus users can stream live experiences, original series,
Speaker 10:  virtual learning, and other programming to help your
Speaker 10:  business grow. The award-winning shows on the platform. Aluminate the future
Speaker 10:  of technology in the digital first work, anywhere world and Salesforce
Speaker 10:  plus will inspire business leaders like you to learn new skills, pursue
Speaker 10:  new career opportunities and drive change in the world. Sign up today to
Speaker 10:  watch pivot and more exclusive content free at
Speaker 10:  salesforce.com/plus that's
Speaker 10:  salesforce.com/p L U S.
Speaker 5:  All right. We're back this gadget news sound for a gadget lightning
Speaker 5:  round we're opening and closing the show. It's an Ilan sandwich with
Speaker 5:  gadgets.
Speaker 3:  Yes.
Speaker 5:  David has been thinking about like, you know, what are the, what are the
Speaker 5:  default structures of the Vergecast as we read, you know, refresh the show,
Speaker 5:  Ilan sandwich with gadgets, we should start naming them and putting on
Speaker 5:  the, on the wall, like a deli.
Speaker 4:  That's actually like if you were to perfectly describe every episode ever
Speaker 4:  done of the Vergecast and Ilan Sanders with gadgets is like, as bout, as
Speaker 4:  close as
Speaker 5:  All right. I will tell you I'm looking at the rundown and the in parentheses,
Speaker 5:  it just says, we're just going to let Kranz be excited for like 20 minutes
Speaker 5:  here. Let's go ahead, Alex.
Speaker 3:  I don't know if I can do 20 minutes. I could probably do 45. This
Speaker 3:  is going to be heavily edited for you listeners at home.
Speaker 3:  So apple is reportedly testing, a
Speaker 3:  foldable phone that has as a secondary display,
Speaker 3:  the outside display, an E ink display.
Speaker 5:  Oh boy.
Speaker 3:  I mean, it's, it's Minky quo who
Speaker 3:  we've talked about a lot on the show, usually really good at like picking
Speaker 3:  out what Apple's working on. What's probably coming
Speaker 3:  usually kind of considered to be spot on. I refuse to
Speaker 3:  believe they're spot on in this case, as much as I want them to be as
Speaker 3:  much as I want an E ink iPhone. I just don't
Speaker 3:  see how it happens.
Speaker 4:  Well, so, okay. We, we should say like, this is one of those things that
Speaker 4:  like, the longer you cover this stuff, the more you come to it as like the
Speaker 4:  word testing is very important here, right? Because like apple is testing
Speaker 4:  everything, right? Someone at apple has bought
Speaker 4:  everything that exists. That is an electronic on planet earth and
Speaker 4:  has tried to build something with it, like it just has happened. And so I
Speaker 4:  think the part of what's interesting about leaks like these is they tend
Speaker 4:  to come from the supply chain, which likely means someone has bought, you
Speaker 4:  know, more than three of them. But the idea that apple is testing a foldable
Speaker 4:  with needing to display makes me very excited. Also means
Speaker 4:  almost nothing about actual Apple's actual like future plans. This is
Speaker 4:  the device that I want in my life more than maybe anything else in the entire
Speaker 4:  world, but there is absolutely no indication that it's real.
Speaker 4:  Other than that, like somewhere in the giant spaceship in
Speaker 4:  Cupertino, someone is like standing at a desk, goofing around
Speaker 4:  with an ink screen on a foldable display
Speaker 3:  Enough eating screens that it got back to quote, to talk,
Speaker 3:  be like, this is happening. This is being tested. And
Speaker 3:  like, we don't know what kind of, as we've discussed in the past, there are
Speaker 3:  multiple types of E ink, electronic paper E
Speaker 3:  ink is the company. They get very testy. If you use E ink to
Speaker 3:  describe all electronic paper, electronic paper is the actual
Speaker 3:  display technology. There's a whole bunch out there. It was very excited
Speaker 3:  a couple of weeks ago because there's a new, like rollable color one. And
Speaker 3:  like, it just, didn't no way maybe, oh no, there's a
Speaker 3:  5% possibility. I can see a 5% possibility of this
Speaker 3:  phone existing in the world. Right. Because 95% of me says, apple will
Speaker 3:  never go with this display technology that feels really immature.
Speaker 3:  They typically go with very mature technologies or
Speaker 5:  They like apple watch it. And they're like, what if we just didn't have a
Speaker 5:  display for most of the time?
Speaker 3:  Right. And that's the 5% I'm like, okay. If they put like a, they get a
Speaker 3:  really good artists to do a really good eating wallpaper
Speaker 3:  and they're just using it for like notifications and the
Speaker 3:  clock. And it will look really, really pretty. There'll be like, look at
Speaker 3:  our artsy fartsy E ink display.
Speaker 3:  I could see that
Speaker 5:  I've been thinking about this in the context of the Google AR losses concept,
Speaker 5:  where they like got closer to a useful product by making it do far
Speaker 5:  less.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Even though it's just a concept, you know, whatever, we'll see if they ever
Speaker 5:  ship anything. But right now what the default three has a big eating,
Speaker 5:  a big old screen on the front. There's other foldables that have big
Speaker 5:  old screens on the front. And so basically you get, like, if you look at
Speaker 5:  that screen and you know, it's running Android, and then like, your
Speaker 5:  expectation is like, now I have a tiny phone. Like
Speaker 5:  what if instead of unfolding my phone to use it, I just use the
Speaker 5:  tiny shit version of my phone. Right. And it's like, I
Speaker 5:  kind of understand it, but you can see why you'd say, well, we'll just change
Speaker 5:  that expectation by new Ian, we'll save the power. We'll let it do
Speaker 5:  what a time. Maybe
Speaker 5:  notification of like calls or like number of I
Speaker 5:  messages, but to actually use the phone you got to unfolded.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. To me, I think the, the, the, what the apple watch looks like on your
Speaker 4:  nightstand is an interesting analog there. Cause it's become like a
Speaker 4:  really useful use case for the watch that it's like, it's also kind of
Speaker 4:  your bedside clock and it'll show you like just teeny tiny bits of
Speaker 4:  information. And I feel like that kind of thing where you can have this thing
Speaker 4:  that is always on and uses almost no power, but can tell you like sort of
Speaker 4:  the bare minimum that you need to know, especially if apple is invested in
Speaker 4:  the idea of not making you look at your phone a thousand times a day, giving
Speaker 4:  you more proactive information, all this stuff. Like that's where a
Speaker 4:  very basic thing that doesn't require you to open, or even
Speaker 4:  necessarily like touch your phone gets super interesting to me.
Speaker 5:  What was that thing that chumby I think ruled,
Speaker 5:  it was like a little, it was like a little soft guy with like a
Speaker 4:  Fluffy alarm clock. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And you could like do Linux apps.
Speaker 5:  It's a future. The iPhone is really, the front is a Trumpy. I,
Speaker 5:  as apple bought chumby is
Speaker 5:  let's swing. She will have to say about apple bank. Chompy mark
Speaker 5:  Gurman. Where are you at? Get on the chumby story. I just see, I can see
Speaker 5:  them cutting it down. I'm with David, like you reduce the
Speaker 5:  expectations of what that front display can do by using a different display
Speaker 5:  technology. Maybe you get some battery life back. Cause like the little dumb
Speaker 5:  Android phone on the front of a Z flip is just like fully ridiculous
Speaker 4:  Ad. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  You don't need that. Anyway. Apple is announced. They're gonna bring live
Speaker 5:  captions, see iPhone, iPad, and Mac daddy, some gesture control of the apple
Speaker 5:  watch. I saw a bunch of people read. This is, this is a live
Speaker 5:  captions in particular like a step towards AR. Right? Cause then you
Speaker 5:  can like, you can like listen to immediately understand text. It'll be like
Speaker 5:  the Google glass.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I mean, in an interesting way, a lot of Apple's accessibility features
Speaker 4:  have been kind of leading indicators for some of that stuff. Like it was
Speaker 4:  doing really high end screen reader and
Speaker 4:  voice stuff with as an accessibility feature before it brought it more broadly,
Speaker 4:  it's been doing the, the like gesture control that you can get on the watch
Speaker 4:  is an accessibility feature that also like you don't have to squint that
Speaker 4:  hard to see it as how you might control something on your phone by like pinching
Speaker 4:  twice to answer or hang up a call. That kind of stuff. Like I think
Speaker 4:  the live captions is probably just a genuinely useful accessibility feature,
Speaker 4:  which I think is obviously I think apple cares a lot about, but like, if
Speaker 4:  you're going to do AR that you gotta have something like that, that works,
Speaker 4:  right?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It seems like the first key thing. Right. You gotta be able to listen
Speaker 5:  and understand the text so that you can like translate it to other texts
Speaker 5:  or something. iOS 15.5 came out the new version of
Speaker 5:  maca west on we're basically just in the run up to WWDC here. Yup.
Speaker 5:  The thing that is important about these updates is the thing that I failed
Speaker 5:  to do, which is the studio display God, it's up to its final
Speaker 5:  update. And Dan's like, are you going to plug it in and change the review?
Speaker 5:  And I'm like, do I have to? So I
Speaker 5:  promise that today or tomorrow I'll plug it in. I'll give it the
Speaker 5:  final update. And it's still going to be a six or whatever we gave it. Cause
Speaker 5:  it's, it's still looks bad.
Speaker 4:  I look forward to you looking very slightly less sunburned.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It's going to
Speaker 4:  Be okay.
Speaker 5:  Unless they radically changed the crop. I don't, I think it's
Speaker 5:  still going to look bad. A bunch of headphones stuff. Chris Walsh
Speaker 5:  continues to curl around the events,
Speaker 5:  but he got hugely king actually. Congratulations, Chris, he's been leaking
Speaker 5:  all kinds of sinus stuff. We've got the sub mini, which is a product we've
Speaker 5:  all wanted for a million years because the existing
Speaker 5:  sub $750, which is too much money
Speaker 5:  to pay for a sub of her does not say how much it's going to
Speaker 5:  cost, but it's going to be cheaper. It looks cool.
Speaker 3:  I hope it sounds as good because the current sub is really nice. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  It's just not $800. Nice. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Did either of you also look at this render and think, oh,
Speaker 4:  Sonos bought all of the old Mac pro trash cans and
Speaker 3:  This
Speaker 5:  That's pretty good. It has a real earliest
Speaker 5:  2000 Sony vibe to it as well.
Speaker 4:  Oh yeah. I can see that. Yeah. It's like what if we get furniture, but also
Speaker 4:  sound
Speaker 5:  Yeah, that, that does sound like a Sony marketing campaign.
Speaker 4:  She liked to sit on your Ottoman and play music through your butt.
Speaker 3:  Very party speaker.
Speaker 5:  Hey, if you want to talk about party speakers and the virtuous, I'm here
Speaker 5:  for it. We can go for another hour. Here's what I want to know. If you work
Speaker 5:  at Sony or JBL or whatever, and you are in the
Speaker 5:  Bluetooth party, speaker division, just leak me, your P and
Speaker 5:  L's right. Cause we're on like 14 generations of these
Speaker 5:  things. And they're, from what I can tell a big
Speaker 5:  business, like, let me know, what is the budget for
Speaker 5:  LEDs? What is the bill of materials for extremely
Speaker 5:  garish LEDs parties, speakers in your division. When you
Speaker 5:  have your product meetings, does the PM come up and say, you know, we've,
Speaker 5:  you know, team, we've been looking at the research from the third generation
Speaker 5:  of party speakers, which we just launched. And you know, the data really
Speaker 5:  tells us that in frat houses around America, we need to add even more cup
Speaker 5:  holders to these speakers. Like let me know.
Speaker 5:  I'm, I've wanted the, the inside story of the party speaker explosion
Speaker 5:  for many years,
Speaker 4:  We're like four generations away from them just accidentally building a self-driving
Speaker 4:  car around the speaker.
Speaker 5:  Like there's more innovation happening in party speakers and almost any other
Speaker 5:  area in tech. They're great. We've had some amazing ones
Speaker 5:  like float through the verge office.
Speaker 4:  One more music thing. This is it's not party speaker related, but there's
Speaker 4:  one of the things Chris Welch also reviewed this week. The one
Speaker 4:  plus Nord buds review, which are these like $40
Speaker 4:  wireless earbuds. And I've also been using them for the last week, after
Speaker 4:  like a tour of every cheap pair of wireless earbuds. You can
Speaker 4:  buy because I've lost four pairs of AirPods and just can't justify
Speaker 4:  buying more AirPods. And so he landed basically in the same place that I
Speaker 4:  did, which is like, it's the, the case is a little big. The
Speaker 4:  microphone's not amazing, but they're 40 bucks and they pair really fast
Speaker 4:  and they're pretty comfortable and they're, they're pretty good. So my new,
Speaker 4:  like mega cheap pair of like, I just need some
Speaker 4:  headphones to wear while I'm walking. The dog is these. So if you're looking
Speaker 4:  for something stupid cheap, that won't hurt when you lose, these are the
Speaker 4:  ones, how are
Speaker 3:  You losing them?
Speaker 4:  Okay. So I'm convinced my mother-in-law stole one of my pairs. That's let's
Speaker 4:  start there. Okay. Absolutely. A hundred percent convinced she didn't have
Speaker 4:  AirPods. And then I lost mine and then she had AirPods
Speaker 4:  just saying there was one pair that I still have, but I got caught in the
Speaker 4:  rain. And so now the battery lasts like the time it takes to put them on.
Speaker 4:  And then the die, a third pair I traveled with and I think
Speaker 4:  left in San Francisco. So those I'm never getting back. And then a fourth
Speaker 4:  pair is just gone. I have no idea. I bought it and all like, like a
Speaker 4:  shockingly quickly, like a couple of weeks later they were just gone.
Speaker 4:  So I'm just, now I'm at a point it's like AirPods and fancy sunglasses. I'm
Speaker 4:  just not allowed to buy anymore because I will lose them.
Speaker 5:  The Sony link buds S the case looks suspiciously like an AirPods
Speaker 5:  case. So here's how you would know, cause she'd never buy those. So you got
Speaker 5:  to leave that line around and be like, you
Speaker 5:  really, what you come on the verge test for is ways to trick your mother-in-law.
Speaker 5:  You got to wear a wire David,
Speaker 5:  A bunch of these smart home stuff. I will say that one that's most interesting
Speaker 5:  to me, Samsung is going to start testing matter on the smart
Speaker 5:  things platform it's like in beta. We'll see if it works, but it's the first
Speaker 5:  big company to do it. And smart things is
Speaker 5:  real. You know, like a lot of people have it.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It's the first one to go past the, like, we are launching it soon thing
Speaker 4:  into like, this is now a thing you can do.
Speaker 3:  And they're actually like good.
Speaker 5:  And they went from launching a press release to launching a webpage where
Speaker 5:  you can sign up for a partner early access program that will come soon. So
Speaker 5:  they've gotten to the forums.
Speaker 4:  It's only coming soon. Okay. That's about where I thought, I thought at least
Speaker 4:  the partners could already early access.
Speaker 5:  All right. And then we got to end this thing. We, we have to talk about Eric
Speaker 5:  and pebble and the man go ahead, David man wants to smell small Android phone.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Okay. So Eric Makowski, who was the founder
Speaker 4:  of pebble and has since done a number of things. He's currently the CEO of
Speaker 4:  beeper, which is a cool multi messaging app messaging app that I
Speaker 4:  kind of dig like really, really badly, wants to make
Speaker 4:  Google, I guess, make Google make a small Android phone. He wants a small
Speaker 4:  Android phone to exist, and he seems to want Google to make it, and basically
Speaker 4:  what he seems to want. And by what he seems to want is like, he explicitly
Speaker 4:  said this many times over and over again, he wants an iPhone mini running
Speaker 4:  stock, Android. And the theory behind it is like
Speaker 4:  small phones are good. Not everyone wants to big monster
Speaker 4:  giant phones. And he doesn't necessarily want it to even
Speaker 4:  be like super, super fancy, just like
Speaker 4:  small, good, useful phone at a reasonable price.
Speaker 4:  And he's trying to get 50,000 signatures. I'm not sure what he's going to
Speaker 4:  do after that. Just like mail it to Sundar
Speaker 4:  Pichai and see what happens. But that is his quest. And I guess
Speaker 4:  it sounds like according to his website, over 10,000 people have already
Speaker 4:  signed the petition. So he seems to be well on his way.
Speaker 3:  Am I allowed to sign it? I'm going to,
Speaker 5:  He can sign it. I will say that Eric, to me, the petition was like, let's
Speaker 5:  see if we can get Dieter and his new bosses to build this world's
Speaker 5:  Diener. You got your first, Eric was at the screening of springboard that
Speaker 5:  we do at the computer history museum. So we saw him there and we were joking
Speaker 5:  about it, but I, I believe it. I just, here's what I know in my heart. People
Speaker 5:  say they want this thing. And then they go to the store and then they look
Speaker 5:  around furtively and then they gravitate towards the cheapest, biggest screen
Speaker 5:  they can buy. And they buy that one and they take it home and they open Twitter
Speaker 5:  and they say, why won't anyone make a small phone? And I swear to God, this
Speaker 5:  is like the cycle of life. Yes.
Speaker 3:  And it's because they never actually give us a truly good
Speaker 3:  small,
Speaker 5:  The iPhone mini is a truly good small phone. What are you talking about?
Speaker 3:  The battery life sucked for the first,
Speaker 4:  The phone is small. That's like, that's the thing. Like, do you know what
Speaker 4:  they do when they make the phone bigger? As they put more batteries inside
Speaker 4:  of it?
Speaker 4:  It's a miracle
Speaker 3:  Wouldn't have to, you wouldn't have to do that though. If it was an E ink
Speaker 3:  display, then you could have small phone and battery for years.
Speaker 5:  Okay.
Speaker 4:  And bring back the iPod classic people want as an EA
Speaker 3:  Want Eric called me
Speaker 5:  The pebble was the ink display C
Speaker 3:  C synergy.
Speaker 5:  We gotta end this year. You to sign the petition. Let's see if we can force
Speaker 5:  her to do something.
Speaker 5:  I don't know what kind of disclosure you need that to be because someone
Speaker 5:  can tell me what the Dieter disclosure needs to be disclosure. Dieter's
Speaker 5:  my boy. Like, I don't know what you want me to say. That works. Teachers
Speaker 5:  are co-founder, but not as it, I will say the Dieter and I are.
Speaker 5:  We're learning what we can talk about because we want to be very respectful
Speaker 5:  of the fact that we can't just share a brain anymore. And so
Speaker 5:  mostly it's me threatening to buy him increasingly
Speaker 5:  hard to use old digital cameras. I bought him an
Speaker 5:  apple quick, take 100. And I was mistaken because I thought that I
Speaker 5:  thought it was a Sony Maverick that shot to floppy disk, which has its own
Speaker 5:  set of challenges. I just want to clear, but no apple actually had licensed
Speaker 5:  it from Kodak and it only works with a special
Speaker 5:  cable.
Speaker 3:  Yes.
Speaker 5:  You have to plug into a power Macintosh
Speaker 5:  software has never updated and it only spits out eight
Speaker 5:  VGA quality photos and a proprietary image format or
Speaker 5:  32, 3 20 by
Speaker 5:  44. So dinner, just
Speaker 5:  send me a list. He sent me an invoice, all the cables stuck.
Speaker 5:  This is what, this is who we are. Now. I'm going to bind that Maverick and
Speaker 5:  next though, if you're listening, man, this is the second you solve the quick
Speaker 5:  take 100. He's solving a
Speaker 5:  camera with a significant number of motors inside of it to
Speaker 5:  operate a floppy disc. It's going to be great.
Speaker 5:  All right. That's the show a wild one. Thanks to
Speaker 5:  Liz. You can tweet at all of us. You know, this, you can tweet at David he's
Speaker 5:  at Pierce. Alex is Alex H Kranz. Liz is Ms. Lopatto. I am
Speaker 5:  at reckless. There's a bunch of stuff to call it on the site this week. A
Speaker 5:  great story about how fears of electromagnetic radiation
Speaker 5:  have spawned this entire industry of like snake oil, RF
Speaker 5:  protectors. It's a very good, and then Mia did a great story
Speaker 5:  on the content moderation challenges of the Buffalo shooting live
Speaker 5:  stream. If you listen to that part during our last conversation, you went
Speaker 5:  into more it's it's all in there and you did a great job playing apart. A
Speaker 5:  decoder this week was nebulous, EO, Dave whiskeys. That was
Speaker 5:  actually a great conversation
Speaker 1:  That he
Speaker 4:  Was great. I really enjoyed that one.
Speaker 5:  Usually creator company conversations where like how they're going to take
Speaker 5:  over Disney. And this one was like, no, here's just how we're going to get
Speaker 5:  people paid a healthy amount of money so they can live balanced lives. Like
Speaker 5:  I appreciate it. And then Alex, you got what's the series.
Speaker 3:  It was the last episode of the mini-series. And I spoke with Ben
Speaker 3:  heck, who was one of the first guys to really like start
Speaker 3:  modding X-Box 360 controllers to make them more accessible.
Speaker 3:  And I spoke with Bryce Johnson from Microsoft. Who's one of the
Speaker 3:  co-creators of the adaptive controller. And it was very, very cool.
Speaker 4:  It was a good episode and it was wild. And
Speaker 3:  So, yeah, we just talked a lot about like PCB boards and
Speaker 3:  contact points and kind of the challenges of making
Speaker 3:  controllers accessible.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Ben heck is a Madison Guy. I've I've had beers and burgers
Speaker 5:  Madison open heck in the past because he is a character. That's what I will
Speaker 5:  say. The purest character you will ever find. Great episode,
Speaker 5:  listen to that. Other than that, we've gone over as always. So that's it.
Speaker 5:  That's for chest rock'n'roll.
Speaker 1:  Thanks for listening to this week show and Hey, we'd love to hear from you.
Speaker 1:  Shoot us an email@vergecasttheverge.com. And if you'd liked the
Speaker 1:  show, share it with a friend Vergecast is a production of the verge. And
Speaker 1:  part of the Vox media podcast network today's episode was produced by
Speaker 1:  me, Liam, James, and our senior audio director, Andrew Marino,
Speaker 1:  our executive producer is Eleanor Donovan. That's it we'll
Speaker 1:  see you. Next week.
Speaker 10:  This episode was sponsored by Salesforce. Pivot is coming to
Speaker 10:  TV, sort of with the help of Salesforce. Plus
Speaker 10:  pivot listeners will now be able to watch for video segments of our podcast
Speaker 10:  every week, exclusively on their platform, but that's not all
Speaker 10:  Salesforce plus is a free streaming service that provides live
Speaker 10:  experiences, original podcast, and other programming help inspire
Speaker 10:  business leaders all around the globe. Sign up today to watch pivot
Speaker 10:  and more exclusive content free at
Speaker 10:  salesforce.com/plus that
Speaker 10:  salesforce.com/p L U S
Speaker 13:  Support for this episode comes from Fitbit. Here's the
Speaker 13:  question. What is sound have to do with our wellness?
Speaker 13:  Sorry about that. Here. Try this
Speaker 13:  Better. Huh? Fitbit is here to help you notice the ups and
Speaker 13:  downs of stress in your life. So you can start to bring a little more calm
Speaker 13:  into your every day. The Fitbit sense helps you put heart health first
Speaker 13:  with an EDA sensor and ECG app and advanced stress
Speaker 13:  monitoring. Listen to your body. Feel your power,
Speaker 13:  learn more@fitbit.com.