# Transcript
ID: 480b4ca0-68db-11ed-bc19-f11eee35a173
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: The AI-generated, oddly colored future of art
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-5334973589042054592/6244297833171967696/s93290-US-3775s-1668952576.mp3
Description: Today on the flagship podcast of the difference between CMYK and RGB colors:
02:19 - David talks about the future of Photoshop with Adobe's Chief Product Officer Scott Belsky.
13:37 - Verge senior reporter James Vincent joins the show to discuss generative AI art and all its possibilities and complications.
43:05 - The Verge's Kristen Radtke and Jess Weatherbed chat with David about Pantone's new subscription service and what it means for artists and designers.
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we'd love to hear from you.
We are conducting a short audience survey to help plan for our future and hear from you. To participate, head to vox.com/podsurvey, and thank you!
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (6 ads detected)
Speaker 2:  Welcome to the Verge Cast, the flagship podcast of the difference between
Speaker 2:  C M Y K and RGB Colors. I'm your friend David Pierce and I am at
Speaker 2:  Ace Hardware Shopping for Paint, which is both very fitting for the episode
Speaker 2:  we're about to do and also just a life necessity because apparently the fact
Speaker 2:  that I'm having a baby soon means I am required to repaint every single surface
Speaker 2:  in my house. So I'm here trying to figure out the difference between
Speaker 2:  Maui Mist and Moonlit Snow and Austrian
Speaker 2:  Ice, which are apparently all different colors despite looking absolutely
Speaker 2:  exactly the same to me. Anyway, we have a super fun show coming up for you
Speaker 2:  today, all about the future of art. We're gonna talk about Photoshop and
Speaker 2:  what it means to make a 30 year old piece of software work for the next 30
Speaker 2:  years. We're also gonna talk about AI art, things like Dolly and Mid Journey
Speaker 2:  and all the possibilities and complications that those bring up. And then
Speaker 2:  we're gonna talk about a strange beef in the world of colors and how it came
Speaker 2:  to be that Pantone is the authority on what colors actually
Speaker 2:  are. It's crazy world out there. All that is coming up right after the break.
Speaker 2:  But first, I need to actually like pick a paint color and buy something.
Speaker 2:  I'm leaning toward Arctic Dawn personally, but also I have literally
Speaker 2:  no idea what I'm talking about. Here goes nothing. This is a verge cast scene
Speaker 2:  in a sec.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. As I said a minute ago, we're gonna spend a lot of this
Speaker 2:  episode talking about digital art because in a world where everyone's a
Speaker 2:  creator, most of our life happens on screens and
Speaker 2:  we're all buying and selling JPEGs for millions of dollars. It turns
Speaker 2:  out art is pretty important and you really, really,
Speaker 2:  really cannot talk about digital art without talking about Adobe's
Speaker 2:  Photoshop. Photoshop is to art
Speaker 2:  what Google is to search or what Kleenex is to facial
Speaker 2:  tissues. What I don't know, Mario, is to games where you jump
Speaker 2:  on top of things that look like turtles. I'm getting away from the point
Speaker 2:  here. The point is Photoshop is a mission critical,
Speaker 2:  essential tool for artists around the world and it has been for
Speaker 2:  decades. You know what's wild by the way, I went back
Speaker 2:  and looked at some fun videos of Photoshop 1.0 which was
Speaker 2:  released in 19 90, 32 years ago and it's kind of incredible
Speaker 2:  how much has stayed the same. There was even this really fun video I found
Speaker 2:  from a couple of years ago where a graphic designer named Will Patterson
Speaker 2:  tried to use Photoshop 1.0,
Speaker 6:  This is weird playing with
Speaker 6:  Photoshop on here, right? Let's just get on
Speaker 6:  with the design anyway,
Speaker 2:  And he made it work.
Speaker 6:  There we go. We got our first design in Photoshop One. It doesn't look
Speaker 6:  great. I mean,
Speaker 2:  Looks like it's legitimately impressive and it's good evidence that Adobe
Speaker 2:  got a lot of things right even really early on. But in a way it's
Speaker 2:  also kind of a bad sign. Technology changes, users
Speaker 2:  change the things that we want and can do with technology
Speaker 2:  change and apps that don't change along with all of that tend to
Speaker 2:  turn out like Microsoft Word or Lotus Notes and they
Speaker 2:  eventually just kind of go by the wayside as a new generation of tools
Speaker 2:  emerges. It's this eternal struggle for a lot of successful
Speaker 2:  products. How do you make an app super successful and then change it to
Speaker 2:  appeal to new users without irritating the existing ones? If you were
Speaker 2:  to start Photoshop from scratch right now, it probably wouldn't
Speaker 2:  have a thousand menus and all those icons that haven't
Speaker 2:  changed in more than three decades. But if you made those changes now you'd
Speaker 2:  piss off millions of people. Scott Beski is the
Speaker 2:  person charged with threading this very careful needle.
Speaker 7:  Scott Beski, chief product officer of receiving creative products at
Speaker 7:  Adobe.
Speaker 2:  Scott told me he knows very acutely how important it
Speaker 2:  is to not screw up Photoshop, which is good. You don't wanna screw up Photoshop
Speaker 2:  and the way Adobe has avoided doing it so far is pretty
Speaker 2:  simple. It just does what customers want, which is mostly,
Speaker 2:  you know, don't touch anything. People want more features, but they
Speaker 2:  also really, really, really don't want to have to change the way that
Speaker 2:  they use a tool for no good reason.
Speaker 7:  Photoshop has one of the greatest product market fits ever.
Speaker 7:  It is a name brand that is also in some ways a verb. And
Speaker 7:  when you talk to a customer who loves Photoshop, what do they say
Speaker 7:  first? Don't change anything. Like don't screw with it. Like don't
Speaker 7:  redesign the interface or whatever. Now, of course, like as a modern
Speaker 7:  product builder, I look at the interface and the way that it's been
Speaker 7:  built. You know, there's 30 years of decisions that
Speaker 7:  have had to accumulate and you know, it's almost like the difference between
Speaker 7:  going to a European city that has been built over hundreds
Speaker 7:  and thousands of years of architecture and then you go to like a
Speaker 7:  modern American city that was dope from a desert or
Speaker 7:  something. It's just completely different.
Speaker 2:  The more I think about that city's analogy, the more I like it
Speaker 2:  because like those old cities are amazing, right? Nobody
Speaker 2:  thinks about it and goes, ah, Venice versus Phoenix, give me Phoenix all
Speaker 2:  day. But if your, your goal is just to get where you're going, I
Speaker 2:  suspect a more modern city helps. There are no obvious answers
Speaker 2:  here, especially as people keep wanting more and more of these new modern
Speaker 2:  things. But that's where it gets tricky, right? You give people everything
Speaker 2:  they want by just sort of shoving new features into Photoshop. You
Speaker 2:  eventually build an app that is big and powerful and
Speaker 2:  borderline unusable. It's like if you had a city that was both
Speaker 2:  Phoenix and Venice, I'm not sure you'd have a super good time there.
Speaker 2:  And I think a lot of designers would argue that Photoshop has been teetering
Speaker 2:  on that line for a long time. One way Adobe has tried to
Speaker 2:  combat this is by splitting off apps like Lightroom when it became obvious
Speaker 2:  that a huge number of people really needed a way to manage their photos.
Speaker 2:  But doing that in the confines of Photoshop, along with
Speaker 2:  everything else Photoshop can do, didn't really make sense. So Lightroom
Speaker 2:  became a thing. More recently, Scott told me the rise of social media
Speaker 2:  creators has gone kind of the same way.
Speaker 7:  An observation we've made over the last 10 years or so in Photoshop is
Speaker 7:  that there were so many customers coming in creating things for social
Speaker 7:  media and you know, and the subset of features that they were asking for
Speaker 7:  were easier interfaces, ways of making for mixed media.
Speaker 7:  Cuz most platforms, every social platform these days is mixed media.
Speaker 7:  You come in thinking you're making a graphic and then you realize you want
Speaker 7:  to add some animation and some text and maybe a little motion and then you
Speaker 7:  put a time on, you throw in some music and before you know it, it's like
Speaker 7:  a fully featured mixed media creation. So we realized that
Speaker 7:  Photoshop is not the right tool for that and that actually was one of the
Speaker 7:  reasons why we embarked on Express and the previous
Speaker 7:  incarnations of Express because we recognized that we needed to build something
Speaker 7:  specifically for the social media creator that probably had a lower
Speaker 7:  willingness to pay, had a lower tolerance for a learning curve, and wanted
Speaker 7:  mixed media creation. And so that's a story repeating itself all over
Speaker 7:  again.
Speaker 2:  Ultimately the business model here is pretty clear, right? What Adobe
Speaker 2:  really wants to do is introduce you to its suite through tools like Express
Speaker 2:  and Figma and then slowly upsell you all the way to
Speaker 2:  Photoshop and the whole creative suite. But one thing Scott said to me a
Speaker 2:  few times was that Adobe has to let Photoshop be Photoshop, but
Speaker 2:  even that means something different than it used to. Adobe is now bringing
Speaker 2:  Photoshop to the web, it's embedding some of Photoshop's functionality
Speaker 2:  inside of other apps and it's thinking about what collaboration
Speaker 2:  looks like. Again, technology changes, users change and Adobe has to
Speaker 2:  figure out how to keep up while letting Photoshop be Photoshop.
Speaker 2:  Thankfully it doesn't sound like Scott wants to do the whole
Speaker 2:  let's all edit a photo together thing, which honestly sounds like my
Speaker 2:  nightmare.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, I've seen very little evidence of customers saying, I want to have
Speaker 7:  three people editing my image at the same time. So I don't think that that's
Speaker 7:  where we're gonna take Photoshop. What we want to do with Photoshop is we
Speaker 7:  want it to be easy to work with every stakeholder, you know,
Speaker 7:  every single creative of our products. Unless you're an artist working
Speaker 7:  solely for yourself and you're never gonna share your creations. Everyone
Speaker 7:  has stakeholders, copy editors, clients, marketers, you know,
Speaker 7:  how do you name it? And currently the workflows to engage with those
Speaker 7:  stakeholders are extraordinarily antiquated.
Speaker 2:  That basically means making it easier to show stuff, easier to share stuff,
Speaker 2:  easier to leave comments on stuff, which fair enough, I can get
Speaker 2:  behind that. Anything that means fewer email attachments is a huge win
Speaker 2:  in my book. To me, the biggest question for the future of Photoshop
Speaker 2:  comes from AI advances in AI have made all kinds of
Speaker 2:  image editing, the stuff people used to do professionally in Photoshop,
Speaker 2:  suddenly easy, even automatic. Think of the Magic
Speaker 2:  eraser on the pixel phones.
Speaker 8:  All you do is outline what you don't want in the picture and it's
Speaker 2:  Gone. Or the iPhone's action mode, which automatically tries to steady
Speaker 2:  your video even as you run and jump and move around.
Speaker 9:  Normally these shots would only be possible with a ton of stabilizing equipment,
Speaker 9:  but with action mode, we didn't need any of that.
Speaker 2:  Photoshop has introduced a bunch of automatic filters recently.
Speaker 2:  It's trying to help people make their stuff better without requiring
Speaker 2:  a huge amount of repetitive work. And if you've ever spent what feels
Speaker 2:  like a thousand hours carefully masking around a part of your
Speaker 2:  image just so you can edit it, it's definitely good news that you can
Speaker 2:  now just like click on the tennis ball you're trying to remove and poof it's
Speaker 2:  gone. You
Speaker 7:  Can immaculately apply color to a black and white photograph or you can
Speaker 7:  just touch the button and it makes a color. I mean, why would you not do
Speaker 7:  that? And then make final edits and changes.
Speaker 2:  Adobe's also starting to really lean into generative ai, the tools that you
Speaker 2:  can use to not just edit your photos in art but actually create stuff
Speaker 2:  from scratch. What if the future of Photoshop is just like a
Speaker 2:  text box? You type what you want, the AI creates it and then
Speaker 2:  you apply the edits you want it. The whole text box thing is
Speaker 2:  probably a bit much, but that idea I think is actually where Scott and Adobe
Speaker 2:  are headed.
Speaker 7:  I think that's right and I think if you look at our fu our tools into the
Speaker 7:  future, they will all be AI assisted tools. But at the end of the day,
Speaker 7:  the creative control resides with the person and the AI is really
Speaker 7:  their co-pilot. It's working for them layer by layer by layer or
Speaker 7:  suggestion by suggestion and the creatives will either take it or leave it,
Speaker 7:  it'll make them feel more productive.
Speaker 2:  This sounds right to me in a lot of ways and also sounds messy and
Speaker 2:  complicated in a thousand ways we haven't even gotten into
Speaker 2:  yet. Generative AI art,
Speaker 2:  generative AI in general is gonna change things in bigger ways
Speaker 2:  than I think we even realize. So actually let's leave Scott and
Speaker 2:  Photoshop and Adobe for now and let's get into that. We're gonna take a quick
Speaker 2:  break and then we're gonna dive into the weeds of all things generative ai.
Speaker 2:  We'll be right
Speaker 2:  back.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. Like we were just talking about, generative AI is
Speaker 2:  kind of having a moment. Everyone's out there using Dolly
Speaker 2:  to make weird pictures of like the moon made of spaghetti
Speaker 2:  painted in the style of Andy Warhol or whatever. And
Speaker 2:  Stable diffusion and Mid Journey and a bunch of other companies and
Speaker 2:  organizations are building generative tools of their own. It's
Speaker 2:  weird and it's messy, but it's really interesting stuff happening out there.
Speaker 2:  So is the future of art just writing words in an
Speaker 2:  AI prompt? And if so, how does that change the way that we think about
Speaker 2:  art and artists? This is all fascinating and it
Speaker 2:  gets really complicated really fast. So I asked James Vincent
Speaker 2:  the verges resident AI expert to come wade through all of it with
Speaker 2:  me. Hey James. Hi
Speaker 10:  David. How you doing?
Speaker 2:  I'm good. I have been excited to talk to you about AI art for a long time
Speaker 2:  because this is to me like the most interesting and deeply
Speaker 2:  bizarre space in tech right now. I have no idea what to make of it. So you're,
Speaker 2:  you're gonna make all of this make sense for me. So thank you in advance
Speaker 2:  for doing so. I'll do my best. The first thing is like, let's just, let's
Speaker 2:  just like lay the land a little bit here. Everybody talks about open AI and
Speaker 2:  Dolly, but this, this is like the, the sort of generative AI space
Speaker 2:  turns out to be like much bigger than I realized.
Speaker 2:  Scope this industry a little bit for us right now. Yeah,
Speaker 11:  I mean generative AI is sort of this term that's become buzzy very recently
Speaker 11:  and we've sort of rec conned what we're a lot of older systems which
Speaker 11:  we're doing this sort of thing. But generative AI
Speaker 11:  technically includes stuff like G PT three, so generating
Speaker 11:  text stuff like GitHub co-pilot generating code,
Speaker 11:  a lot of experimental music models and art models. But the art models
Speaker 11:  are definitely the most visible and they're the ones that are, they've become
Speaker 11:  touchstones for a lot of the wider issues in the industry, which I'm sure
Speaker 11:  we will talk about stuff like copyrights, stuff like safety bias, et cetera,
Speaker 11:  et cetera. For the generative stuff it looks like these models have come
Speaker 11:  out of nowhere but there has been a lot of work going on in this area for
Speaker 11:  many years now. You know the, the latest sort of generation, if we're looking
Speaker 11:  in a multi-decade span of AI art models probably goes back
Speaker 11:  to 2014 or something where you have a type of
Speaker 11:  method known as gans or generative adversarial networks
Speaker 11:  which become the big new thing. And now in the years since then we've
Speaker 11:  had a lot of different methods pop up that have been sort of tried and tested
Speaker 11:  and you might remember some of them. Do you remember Google Deep Dream?
Speaker 11:  Oh
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 11:  And that was all the way back in 2015. But that was, you know, one of
Speaker 11:  these early forays where researchers went down
Speaker 11:  what turned out to be basically a sort of a bit of a cul-de-sac but
Speaker 11:  you have to explore those things. And then the latest wave, which was
Speaker 11:  very much kicked off by open eyes Dolly, has come about
Speaker 11:  cause of a method called diffusion, which is just,
Speaker 11:  it really fits with our current capabilities and it's proved to be
Speaker 11:  very, very rich in possibility. And it's from that which
Speaker 11:  sort of opening I first demo that we've got all these other models like
Speaker 11:  stable diffusion, like mid journey and all the rest.
Speaker 2:  Okay, so obviously I'm very smart and I know things and I definitely
Speaker 2:  for sure know what diffusion is, but let's just, let's
Speaker 2:  just for a second assume that I don't like what is it about diffusion
Speaker 2:  that is so new and different? Cause it really seems to me, and I've only
Speaker 2:  been following this from sort of a a like end user perspective over the last
Speaker 2:  several years, like something clicked in the last like 12 months
Speaker 2:  where this went from like nifty science project that people would demo on
Speaker 2:  stage to like real thing doing real stuff in real
Speaker 2:  people's lives and it sounds like diffusion, which again I understand
Speaker 2:  extremely well and know exactly what it is, is responsible
Speaker 2:  for that. So like is diffusion the thing? Like what is this thing and how
Speaker 2:  did it sort of change that?
Speaker 11:  I would say there are lots of factors here. Some of them are to do with
Speaker 11:  these new methods to do with diffusion. Some of it is sort of, as I say,
Speaker 11:  stuff that's been building for a while. You know, we've got a lot of things
Speaker 11:  that people have been working on in terms of computing capability in terms
Speaker 11:  of data sets that have accrued over the years. Diffusion though has
Speaker 11:  really improved things definitely to break diffusion down in
Speaker 11:  its sort of of simplest term is it? Is it basically you get models, you
Speaker 11:  feed them an image on one end, imagine an image on one end complete, you
Speaker 11:  know whatever, it's vango sunflowers. And then on the other end you have
Speaker 11:  static, you have TV static, you have nothing discernible just random
Speaker 11:  patterns. How do you get from vango sunflowers to complete static
Speaker 11:  imagery? You get it through a series of steps and what a
Speaker 11:  diffusion model does is it takes that image step by step by step by
Speaker 11:  step by step, you know hundreds and hundreds of hundreds of steps and it
Speaker 11:  det tunes it to nothing. And then this is the clever bit
Speaker 11:  is is it goes in the other direction. It tries to learn how
Speaker 11:  to get from sunflowers static to sunflowers.
Speaker 11:  It looks at every single step and it tries to learn about the image
Speaker 11:  by doing that. Now again that sounds like well why is that better than any
Speaker 11:  other method of making these things? And I think part of the reason is it
Speaker 11:  fits what has become the sort of default approach to of artificial
Speaker 11:  intelligence at the moment, which relies on a lot of paralleled
Speaker 11:  computation. So you know, people talk a lot
Speaker 11:  about, for example, the utility of GPUs and how they
Speaker 11:  have been really useful in pushing forward artificial intelligence. It's
Speaker 11:  because they are good at doing lots and lots and lots and lots of calculations
Speaker 11:  simultaneously now. Now if you ever imagine you are doing this diffusion
Speaker 11:  tango from sunflowers to static to sunflowers, that
Speaker 11:  is a process that involves lots and lots and lots and lots and lots of little
Speaker 11:  calculations simultaneously. So that's sort of the broad strokes
Speaker 11:  picture, the big picture to use a very appropriate metaphor of why
Speaker 11:  we've taken off now. But yeah, people saw open AI and Dolly do this
Speaker 11:  and they were like, right, we're gonna try that as well. And then everyone
Speaker 11:  else has sort of improved upon their methods and tweaked them in new ways.
Speaker 2:  Part of what's interesting to me about this now is it, it now seems like
Speaker 2:  we're in this phase of going from like you said, sort of proofs of concept
Speaker 2:  to like there are lots of slightly different takes on this same
Speaker 2:  kind of thing. Is there an underlying race here to be sort of the
Speaker 2:  technology provider for whatever's coming next? Is everybody still just kind
Speaker 2:  of experimenting to see what's gonna happen? Like what's building out of
Speaker 2:  all of these different projects here?
Speaker 11:  So the really interesting thing with the current, with what we've seen over
Speaker 11:  the last year is that we've had a new sort of approach
Speaker 11:  evolve and it starts with text to image models, but it's something that
Speaker 11:  was gonna, that it will certainly affect the wider AI industry.
Speaker 11:  People sometimes call them the first generation of AI labs and this
Speaker 11:  is deep mind and open ai. Those are the and Google
Speaker 11:  Brain, you know those are the big, the big ones that have made an impact.
Speaker 11:  Now they had a certain approach to this technology which is
Speaker 11:  a little bit more cautious shall we say. So you have open ai, they
Speaker 11:  create an API for Dolly for businesses and they put in
Speaker 11:  a lot of safety guardrails in there and they don't give people access to
Speaker 11:  it. Now the second wave of AI labs have sort of
Speaker 11:  come and looked at this model and gone, right, how do we beat these guys
Speaker 11:  because they've got so much money, they've got so much computing resources,
Speaker 11:  they've got such a a headstart, what can we do that's wildly different?
Speaker 11:  And they've gone, you know what, we're gonna build these and we're gonna
Speaker 11:  give them away for free. And this has upended a lot of what
Speaker 11:  people thought they knew about how the industry, how this particular part
Speaker 11:  of the industry should work. The standard bearer for that approach is a
Speaker 11:  company called Stability ai. They promote a
Speaker 11:  model called Stable Diffusion. Now a lot of people say they made that
Speaker 11:  model, I wanna be a little bit more specific about that. They funded that
Speaker 11:  model. The model was a lot of the research was done by
Speaker 11:  a university in Germany and there is a reason for that which will
Speaker 11:  become apparent later, but it's essentially to do with legal liabilities
Speaker 11:  and it means that st stability AI isn't legally liable
Speaker 11:  necessarily for what people do with this model and etc. But so that is
Speaker 11:  important but their approach has been why don't we make the model and
Speaker 11:  give it away? And that means our model will get
Speaker 11:  everywhere and we'll collect business as part of that. So
Speaker 11:  they do run a commercial version of stable diffusion called Dream
Speaker 11:  Studio but they are doing much more and they're having a much bigger impact
Speaker 11:  by GI giving this stuff away. And I can really vouch for that first
Speaker 11:  hand and that I've covered just in the last two months. So many companies
Speaker 11:  who have gone, we've got a new text image model and
Speaker 11:  we're doing new things with it and you ask them, oh you did you make this
Speaker 11:  yourself? And they go, it's stable diffusion. And I'm talking about
Speaker 11:  huge companies like Canva for example, you know the Australian design app,
Speaker 11:  they came out just this week, they had it in beta a month ago. Now it's
Speaker 11:  sort of available to all your users, a text to image model and it's
Speaker 11:  just stable diffusion, you know that they've built some
Speaker 11:  new UI stuff into it. But really stability AI have really sort of
Speaker 11:  upended the industry with this. Let's just make it free and let's see
Speaker 11:  what everyone else does as a result.
Speaker 2:  Interesting. Okay and to that point about all these things sort of starting
Speaker 2:  to show up in these products, it seems like there's been this run on it over
Speaker 2:  the last few months and my sense in talking to some of these product folks
Speaker 2:  is there is this like sense in the industry that this is something big, right?
Speaker 2:  Like this is gonna change things. The idea that you can make, especially
Speaker 2:  the text to image thing is like there, everybody seems to gro that there
Speaker 2:  is like something powerful here and so you're seeing it in Canva, you're
Speaker 2:  seeing it in TikTok, like shutter stock is doing stuff which I wanna come
Speaker 2:  back to, but as far as I can tell there are these like big
Speaker 2:  meaty questions about how this is supposed to work and how we understand
Speaker 2:  content veracity and how we understand ownership and how we under
Speaker 2:  and we've solved none of it as far as I can tell. So there's just a lot of
Speaker 2:  people who are like, who are like, oh these are interesting questions by
Speaker 2:  the way, it's available in our app right now. And it's like,
Speaker 11:  Yes
Speaker 2:  This feels slightly backwards to me. Is there, is there more progress being
Speaker 2:  made than I'm giving it credit for? Or is this just like total abject chaos?
Speaker 2:  That's
Speaker 11:  A tricky one. That's a tricky one to answer. I mean I think there
Speaker 11:  has been progress about this stuff and in a way some of the
Speaker 11:  debates that you alluded to about, for example,
Speaker 11:  copyright infringement about safety, our
Speaker 11:  debates we've had before in different guys. So for example, the copyright
Speaker 11:  debate is one we've sort of had with search engines, you know, when they
Speaker 11:  use a snippet of someone's text, is that fair? Is it a transformative use?
Speaker 11:  The debate we've had about content veracity is one we've been having for
Speaker 11:  years with deep fakes and there have been, you know, approaches put
Speaker 11:  forward by people like Adobe. You know, they have their content authenticity
Speaker 11:  initiative where they're discussing, you know, watermarks where they're
Speaker 11:  discussing ways to sort of embed veracity into metadata. So
Speaker 11:  there are big things happening, but we have been talking about some of these
Speaker 11:  problems for a while
Speaker 2:  Now. Well, yeah, I guess the difference to me is I think like the, the deep
Speaker 2:  fix thing is an interesting one, right? Where it's like, it's been possible
Speaker 2:  to do for a long time, but it's not like TikTok had a
Speaker 2:  deep fake filter, right? And now we're getting to the point where this
Speaker 2:  stuff is becoming like first class features of these things and
Speaker 2:  they're, you're actually being like they're easy to use and being made easier
Speaker 2:  to use all the time and being just made so available to you. It feels like
Speaker 2:  before we've answered some of these questions and part of me wonders if they're
Speaker 2:  gonna be big new answers about copyright and ownership and all of
Speaker 2:  a sudden all of these companies are gonna be like, oh dear God, you know,
Speaker 2:  stability AI owns all of the art that exists because some judge
Speaker 2:  decided so we're so screwed. I think you're right that the
Speaker 2:  problems are not actually necessarily as different as they've been made
Speaker 2:  out to be, it's just that like they are being put in front of people
Speaker 2:  at such greater scale so quickly.
Speaker 11:  Yeah, absolutely. I mean, and let, let's take copyright infringement as
Speaker 11:  a sort of example of that. So, so the big thing for these models and
Speaker 11:  copyright is that they are trained on usually vast amounts of
Speaker 11:  data scraped from the open web. Now we, we don't always have a clear
Speaker 11:  insight into what that data is. Open AI for example, has never,
Speaker 11:  has never disclosed what the complete contents of its training data.
Speaker 11:  And I have asked them multiple, multiple times and they always are like,
Speaker 11:  well why do we need to tell you? We don't get anything from telling
Speaker 11:  you, which is whatever, it's their prerogative. But I think it's, you know,
Speaker 11:  deeply suspicious and also completely counter to their name open
Speaker 11:  ai. That's been a misnomer for a long time but don't get me started. Don't
Speaker 11:  get me started on that David. So they scrape huge amounts of
Speaker 11:  internet, of internet content and they scrape it from, from personal
Speaker 11:  blogs, from stock image sites, from all these places. Their
Speaker 11:  defense, these companies is that using this material in this way is covered
Speaker 11:  particularly in the US by fair use doctrine. Now it's funny
Speaker 11:  you should ask about this cuz I've been working all week on a report trying
Speaker 11:  to answer that question. Is this covered by fair use? And I've spoken to
Speaker 11:  several lawyers over the past week and technologists and
Speaker 11:  risk analysis and the general consensus is we don't
Speaker 11:  know for sure which is a really interesting place
Speaker 11:  to be in. Okay? We're pretty sure that the training of these
Speaker 11:  systems that collecting this data and creating a model is covered by fair
Speaker 11:  use that most people are pretty confident on that. Where the questions
Speaker 11:  come in is how are you using these systems? So for example,
Speaker 11:  you know if I train an art model on a hundred million images and I use
Speaker 11:  it to create a new picture that looks kind of like nothing, that's fine.
Speaker 11:  Like nothing in the training data set, that's fine. If I train it on a
Speaker 11:  hundred images by artist X who happens to be living
Speaker 11:  and I tell the model to produce more images that look like artist
Speaker 11:  X made them, then we have a much stronger case for this
Speaker 11:  not being fair use and for it being copyright infringement. What lawyers
Speaker 11:  told me was that this is stuff that's gonna be
Speaker 11:  settled in the courts eventually. It probably will be anyway.
Speaker 11:  And the interesting thing is we've already seen the first legal case
Speaker 11:  launched in this area, the first sort of legal case aimed at a
Speaker 11:  generative AI model and it wasn't at an art model but at a
Speaker 11:  code model. It was a model built by open AI
Speaker 11:  and Microsoft and Microsoft subsidiary GitHub and it's
Speaker 11:  called GitHub co-pilot. And it basically think of it like an auto-complete
Speaker 11:  for code. You are typing your programming away and it will suggest what
Speaker 11:  the next line should be. The problem is it's trained on a lot of public
Speaker 11:  repositories of code, many of which have licenses that say if
Speaker 11:  you reproduce my code then you need to credit it to me in some way because
Speaker 11:  this is the sort of ethos that the open source community is built on. Now
Speaker 11:  copilot does not do that. It never credits where it gets the code from.
Speaker 11:  And so this lawsuit has been launched saying this is in violation of the
Speaker 11:  dmca, the lawsuit says a lot. It also says that there's a conspiracy that
Speaker 11:  there's unfair competition, but this could be something that really
Speaker 11:  changes the entire gen generative AI landscape if they get this
Speaker 11:  certified as a class action lawsuit, if it goes ahead, which it, it may
Speaker 11:  not, we don't know about that yet, then it could really rewrite the rules
Speaker 11:  about using copyrighted material.
Speaker 2:  Interesting. And it seems to me that part of the problem or just the mess
Speaker 2:  of all of this is that it's so hard to know, right? Like you really
Speaker 2:  can't draw a straight line from I fed these 10
Speaker 2:  images to this is why the output looks the way that it does. Like we have
Speaker 2:  some sense but all of this stuff is, is like black boxy to
Speaker 2:  some extent or or another.
Speaker 11:  Okay so have you heard of a tool called Clip Interrogator?
Speaker 2:  No, I've
Speaker 11:  Been meaning to write about it so you can blame me for not knowing about
Speaker 11:  it cuz I should have written about it by now. It was a fascinating thing.
Speaker 11:  So basically you feed Clip interrogator and clip is an
Speaker 11:  acronym that is another AI image generation tool, a module
Speaker 11:  component. You feed it an image and it tries to extrapolate what
Speaker 11:  words were fed into the system to create that image. So if you feed it
Speaker 11:  a picture of yourself, it'll be like how would I describe this if I wanted
Speaker 11:  to generate this image anew from the system? And so people are now
Speaker 11:  suggesting that with something like that you could feed someone's art into
Speaker 11:  that that they've generated with the help of mid journey or would it stable
Speaker 11:  diffusion or whatever it is. And you could get a clue about whether they'd
Speaker 11:  say I want this to look like a, a drawing by Greg Rotowski or
Speaker 11:  Rebecca Sugar or whoever it is now whether that will
Speaker 11:  ever be useful in court, whether that would ever be admissible evidence
Speaker 11:  in any way we don't know. And again, this comes back to the big thing here
Speaker 11:  that's like a lot of this is up in the
Speaker 2:  Air, right? That's really interesting when you say open AI doesn't wanna
Speaker 2:  share training data, my immediate response is like of course open AI doesn't
Speaker 2:  wanna share training data because a, that's like, it's like a trade secret
Speaker 2:  to some extent. And also yeah like there's a lot to be gained for these
Speaker 2:  companies by having it appear to be sort of
Speaker 2:  unknowable magic, right? And I think part of what we're trying to
Speaker 2:  figure out as a like society grappling with this stuff is like we just
Speaker 2:  need to understand this stuff better, right? Like yeah we need to be able
Speaker 2:  to understand how algorithms rank the stuff that we see on social networks.
Speaker 2:  We need to understand why this image looks the way that it does and where
Speaker 2:  it came from and whether it's original. Like all these things are just so
Speaker 2:  much more complicated and so much more intentionally
Speaker 2:  like opaque to us and we actually need to go in the other direction. But
Speaker 2:  like if I'm open ai, nothing is to be gained by helping you
Speaker 2:  understand how it works. All they wanna say is just like look at this nifty
Speaker 2:  thing that it does when you type in a frog writing a scooter
Speaker 2:  in the middle of the ocean like look isn't that great? Why do you need to
Speaker 2:  ask any more questions? And I think that tension to me is gonna be so, so
Speaker 2:  hard to resolve over time.
Speaker 11:  Mm, absolutely. And yeah I should say like the reason I press open AI on
Speaker 11:  this stuff is not necessarily because some people think journalists are
Speaker 11:  very like they want to break down this technology and criticize it in some
Speaker 11:  ways and it's like, no it's exactly the reason you've just said, I just
Speaker 11:  think it's beneficial to everyone if we knew a little bit more about how
Speaker 11:  this stuff works and for open AI a company that is
Speaker 11:  gonna make a lot, a lot, a lot of money and that has a lot of big tax money
Speaker 11:  in there. You know, Microsoft put a billion dollars in open AI and that's
Speaker 11:  why we, that's what we know about. There could be, you know, more big investments
Speaker 11:  like that. This is why it's important to be able to have some insight into
Speaker 11:  these systems. Now interestingly the one thing that Open Eye has told us
Speaker 11:  about is training data is that it bought hundreds of millions of images
Speaker 11:  licensed them along with the metadata from shutter stock. And this is
Speaker 11:  fascinating because a lot of people have been saying what's the first casualty
Speaker 11:  of text to image systems gonna be, it's gonna be stock photo
Speaker 11:  companies. Because if you can just generate, you know, pictures of
Speaker 11:  women laughing with salad or whatever it might be on the fly rather than
Speaker 11:  licensing it, you're you're gonna be in Clover. So it's interesting that
Speaker 11:  Shut stock has sort of preemptively done a deal and as part of this deal
Speaker 11:  they are now going to add text to image systems to shut a
Speaker 11:  stock's website. So you'll be able to generate new stock photos
Speaker 11:  and they've set up, or they're going to set up, we'll see how far they get
Speaker 11:  with it, something called a contributor's fund where they are gonna pay
Speaker 11:  royalties to the creators of copyrighted images used to train
Speaker 11:  Dolly. So they're gonna pay people for using their images in this
Speaker 11:  work.
Speaker 2:  Interesting. So the way they're thinking about it to some extent is like
Speaker 2:  your art is still helping make the art even when the art
Speaker 2:  is AI generated. So you should be compensated in some way.
Speaker 2:  Yes,
Speaker 11:  Exactly. But then the artists, the photographers, they've
Speaker 11:  said a one off payment, a royalty. How is that gonna replace the loss
Speaker 11:  of my job? You know, there's lots and lots of unanswered questions here.
Speaker 11:  I personally think the contributors fund from shut stock is not going to
Speaker 11:  satisfy people. I think there's no way it will be able to give out
Speaker 11:  enough money in order to make people think or feel and to have it be
Speaker 11:  worth their time that that their job has been cloned by this machine. And
Speaker 11:  it's very interesting cuz they stand in opposition shut stock to Getty
Speaker 11:  Images, which is of course the other big stock image site. Getty Images
Speaker 11:  has gone the other way. They have banned it
Speaker 11:  entirely, AI generated imagery. And I've spoken to their
Speaker 11:  CEO about this and he's been very critical of these
Speaker 11:  companies. He's saying that we would never sell AI generated
Speaker 11:  imagery on our sites because we think it would put our customers
Speaker 11:  in legal liability that we don't know about. So they've gone exactly the
Speaker 11:  other way and they're sort of wanting to differentiate themselves
Speaker 2:  Here. But it sounds like by that logic then Getty is not saying we think
Speaker 2:  this is a bad idea and bad for, you know, the business and the art community.
Speaker 2:  So we're out, they're saying who knows where this is gonna land.
Speaker 2:  We'd rather not be roped into whatever weird stuff is gonna happen
Speaker 2:  in the meantime.
Speaker 11:  Yeah, they're protecting their customers rather than their contributors
Speaker 11:  should we say.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, that's that's very fair. So yes. What are you seeing in terms of
Speaker 2:  like sensible guardrails on how this stuff is being done? Cuz right now we're
Speaker 2:  at this moment now that feels very much to me like the the sort of chatbot
Speaker 2:  era when everybody was like, here's a chatbot, do whatever you want
Speaker 2:  with it. And everybody was like, I'm gonna make it racist. And they
Speaker 2:  did and, and it was like, well this was obviously a bad idea
Speaker 2:  and so everybody has sort of tamped it down and made them smaller and these
Speaker 2:  things are much narrower now. And now they will like book you a flight but
Speaker 2:  it's very hard to make them be racist while they book you a flight. But now
Speaker 2:  it, it feels like we're in the kind of here's the text box, do whatever you
Speaker 2:  want with it phase with a lot of the image stuff. Are you seeing people sort
Speaker 2:  of putting rails on this in ways that make sense?
Speaker 11:  There have been a lot of guardrails put in and the guardrails
Speaker 11:  really differ based on the company doing it. So I mentioned
Speaker 11:  earlier that sort of, we had this first gen wave of AI labs which included
Speaker 11:  places like open AI and they have become, you know, because they're
Speaker 11:  now the incumbents, right? They've now got a reputation, they've got huge
Speaker 11:  amounts of investment in them, they've become much more cautious and they
Speaker 11:  do a lot of things in terms of safety. They filter a lot of keywords, you
Speaker 11:  know, so you can't explicitly ask for naked pictures of people or whatever
Speaker 11:  it might be. Sure. And they filter a lot of stuff that would result
Speaker 11:  in obvious bad images and they also have a look at the output as well
Speaker 11:  and they also study, it's not clear how, again, they're not very open about
Speaker 11:  it. They study to some degree what users are asking. So you
Speaker 11:  know, if you put in a lot of dodgy requests that keep on getting bounced
Speaker 11:  back, they might have a look at your request and go, well this guy's clearly
Speaker 11:  trying to mess up our systems and they will boot you out. And
Speaker 11:  not coincidentally I have been booted out of darli
Speaker 11:  because I was trying to, I was trying to stress test the
Speaker 2:  System. Damn it James,
Speaker 11:  I was trying to break it and, and they, they kicked, they banned my account.
Speaker 2:  That's good. That feels like the correct response I would say. Yeah,
Speaker 11:  No, I mean in in fairness fair play to them that was, that was the right
Speaker 11:  thing to do. But on the other hand you have places like civility, AI
Speaker 11:  making stable diffusion. They put stable diffusion out there with a sort
Speaker 11:  of a very basic tier of filtering. And I know it's basic because
Speaker 11:  they are used it myself and b I was speaking to Canva, this company that
Speaker 11:  integrated stable diffusion and they were like, it was trivial
Speaker 11:  to overcome their filters and we had to add another layer of our own cuz
Speaker 11:  we just thought it was so easy to bypass them. So that's not me saying it,
Speaker 11:  that's Canvas saying it, you know, they're putting their tool in front of
Speaker 11:  school kids. They were like this is not enough, we gotta protect these guys.
Speaker 11:  The thing with stable diffusion is that it's very easy to turn off these
Speaker 11:  filters all together and their CEO has said,
Speaker 11:  we just think that this is, you know, it's up to individuals,
Speaker 11:  it's up to people to make the right choices that, you know, they, they come
Speaker 11:  up with the same argument. You hear a lot in the tech industry, which is
Speaker 11:  technology is neutral and I'm very suspicious of that myself. I think technology
Speaker 11:  always has affordances that guides people in one direction or another, but
Speaker 11:  it's, you know, something of a mantra people say they've got, people are
Speaker 11:  gonna do good stuff with it, they'll do bad stuff with it. A moak the
Speaker 11:  stability AI ceo, he says, I think the good's gonna outweigh the bad. And
Speaker 11:  also if the model is out there completely accessible, we'll be able to create
Speaker 11:  better filters more quickly Now, you know, we yet to see what
Speaker 11:  this is gonna play out. Like I've personally think we're gonna see some
Speaker 11:  nasty stuff over the coming months. One thing that
Speaker 11:  is sort of just beginning to become an issue is a model called Dream
Speaker 11:  Booth. Now Dream Booth basically lets you fine tune very
Speaker 11:  easily that have stable diffusion on a specific set of images and you can
Speaker 11:  use that. A lot of companies have already implemented this or a few companies
Speaker 11:  anyway as selfie generators. So you feed the system,
Speaker 11:  you know, 10 of your pictures and it'll do a range of pictures of you
Speaker 11:  looking like a soldier, you looking like a monk, you looking like a whatever
Speaker 11:  it is a cyberpunk villain. However, this is gonna be very easy for people
Speaker 11:  to use for targeted harassment. And I think this is when a lot of the discussions
Speaker 11:  about deep fakes about non-consensual pornography, these are gonna start
Speaker 11:  coming back into prominence again because we're gonna see a lot of people
Speaker 11:  mocking up nudes of people essentially. It's, it's not gonna be pretty at
Speaker 11:  all.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And I think it's that kind of stuff. Like I, I
Speaker 2:  just, I'm permanently suspicious of the argument that people use that are
Speaker 2:  like, let's just figure out what happens and then we'll back our way into
Speaker 2:  successful answers. And we hear it from everybody in every industry all the
Speaker 2:  time, right? Like let's, let's let all the bad stuff happen so we can learn
Speaker 2:  all the bad stuff and that doesn't work. It turns out
Speaker 2:  it's like it just doesn't work. But I I I do think you're right and I think
Speaker 2:  we're, we're about to enter this really interesting phase where like we as
Speaker 2:  people are gonna start, have to have to figure out how we respond to this
Speaker 2:  stuff, right? Like we're still in the phase where like people just do a dolly
Speaker 2:  search and like take a screenshot of it and share it on Twitter and all of
Speaker 2:  our responses like ha ha that's sort of funny. But this stuff is gonna start
Speaker 2:  to end up in like, like it's, it's the new clip Art in Office is working
Speaker 2:  with this kind of AI art, AI art in business presentations is
Speaker 2:  like a whole weird thing that we're gonna have to figure out what we, we
Speaker 2:  think about. And art is really interesting cuz it seems to people like it's
Speaker 2:  very low stakes but it's actually everywhere and in a lot of ways it's really
Speaker 2:  high stakes and I think figuring out all the different things it means and
Speaker 2:  how we're supposed to approach each one feels like a big
Speaker 2:  challenge to go through kind of all at the same time. But it's gonna be super,
Speaker 2:  super interesting watch.
Speaker 11:  Yeah, absolutely. But I think you mentioned this stuff is clip
Speaker 11:  art and I think that's a really important thing to remember
Speaker 11:  and specifically, you know, Microsoft has created this app called
Speaker 11:  Designer that this part of the office suite it uses Dolly and they want
Speaker 11:  to, as you said, use it to generate clip art. Whenever I think about this
Speaker 11:  technology there's, you know, I flip between in this sort of quantum
Speaker 11:  superposition between thinking this stuff is the mad stuff there is possible,
Speaker 11:  you type in image and it exists, blah blah blah gonna change the world.
Speaker 11:  And then I look at what people are doing with it right now and I go, it's
Speaker 11:  clip art. They've just redone clip art, you know, and
Speaker 11:  it doesn't seem like that big a deal when you put it like that. And you
Speaker 11:  know, I think our, our job as journalists is to sort of say what we see,
Speaker 11:  right? It's to just not get too carried away by what could be
Speaker 11:  and just say what is and what is right now is a lot of clip
Speaker 11:  art, right? There's definitely stuff that's gonna bad stuff and amazing
Speaker 11:  stuff that's gonna happen with it. But actually the way we are gonna get
Speaker 11:  the impact of it really soon and right now is gonna be just people putting
Speaker 11:  new images and presentations and that's gonna be really good in many ways.
Speaker 11:  I think that's gonna be really fun. You know, if I was a six, seven year
Speaker 11:  old right now and I was making a mock up about, you know, why turtles are
Speaker 11:  the best animals in the sea and actually I do that anyway on a weekend,
Speaker 11:  but that's, you
Speaker 2:  Know, that one does. Yeah.
Speaker 11:  As one does then I would be so overjoyed that I could like ask for an image
Speaker 11:  of a turtle wearing a crown and I would be like, yeah, great. You know,
Speaker 11:  there's a lot of good stuff in there that I think is, is gonna be beneficial
Speaker 11:  and is low stakes. So we should remember that. Definitely.
Speaker 2:  Totally. I agree. Thank you for doing this James. I appreciate it.
Speaker 11:  My, my pleasure. My pleasure guys.
Speaker 2:  All right, we need to take a break. When we come back we're gonna dive into
Speaker 2:  the deeply confusing and surprisingly very important
Speaker 2:  world of digital colors and why designers are so mad
Speaker 2:  at Adobe and Panton right now. We'll be right
Speaker 2:  back.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. A couple of weeks ago a bit of small seeming
Speaker 2:  news kind of shook up the art world. Pantone and Adobe announced
Speaker 2:  that if you wanted to use Pantone colors in Adobe products, you now
Speaker 2:  need to subscribe to a service called Pantone Connect, which costs
Speaker 2:  $15 a month. Adobe kind of blamed
Speaker 2:  Pantone and sort of backhandedly accused it of money
Speaker 2:  gouging while Pantone said that Adobe wasn't supporting its latest stuff
Speaker 2:  and so it needed to go its own way. Whatever the reason, this was a big
Speaker 2:  deal for designers, many of whom have been relying on Pantone colors to do
Speaker 2:  their job for years. Personally all it did was
Speaker 2:  confuse me aggressively, aren't colors just like
Speaker 2:  codes on a computer? How did one company come to
Speaker 2:  own those colors? How do you even own a color? Like I said, I'm
Speaker 2:  very confused. So I grabbed Kristen Radke, a creative director at the Verge
Speaker 2:  and Verge reporter Jess Weathered to help me figure it out. Hi
Speaker 2:  Kristen. Hi. Hi Jess. Hi. This is gonna
Speaker 2:  be delightful because we are now entering a world I know absolutely nothing
Speaker 2:  about. So bear with me as we go through this, but I think the place
Speaker 2:  I wanna start is I think Kristen, we, we have to do like a weird amount of
Speaker 2:  defining like what colors are in order to understand what's going on here.
Speaker 2:  So can you just sort of walk me through like what
Speaker 2:  Pantone is and what sort of purpose it serves in the
Speaker 2:  design community?
Speaker 18:  So basically in the sixties Pantone created what they called
Speaker 18:  a universal color language, which is basically just a giant and
Speaker 18:  very expensive swatch book of colored ink. So
Speaker 18:  Pantone is only used for print design. Like if you're making a poster or
Speaker 18:  a product and you want to know for sure what the color is gonna look like
Speaker 18:  before you go into production, Panton is the best way to do that because
Speaker 18:  other ways of printing produce a lot more variation. Okay.
Speaker 2:  So the ideas basically like what I think of as blue and what you
Speaker 2:  think of as blue are different. But if we can agree on like
Speaker 2:  Pantone's version of blue, we can accomplish the same thing
Speaker 18:  Together. So I mean like in any version of color, whether it's on the
Speaker 18:  internet or in print, there are a million different ways to make that color.
Speaker 18:  If you look at something like black for example, the range of black is extreme.
Speaker 18:  There's like true black, there's rich black and then there's a million other
Speaker 18:  varieties because black can either be built just out of black or out of
Speaker 18:  all the colors kind of shoved together, different inks pushed
Speaker 18:  together. So Pantone is a way like there are a huge variety of black, there's
Speaker 18:  a huge variety of blue and Pantone just like there's a huge variety of any
Speaker 18:  color, but you can pick the exact one so you know exactly what it will look
Speaker 18:  like because it's an ink. It's not just, it's not just like a combination
Speaker 18:  of other inks, it's a specific ink.
Speaker 2:  Got it. Okay. And it's like figuring out how what Pantone
Speaker 2:  sort of owns and doesn't has been very confusing to me cuz I've like I've
Speaker 2:  read enough about this to know that like you can't own a color, which is
Speaker 2:  a thing. Yes. But Pantone is sort of the, we've just all agreed that it is
Speaker 2:  like as good a standard as any, so we kind of went with it, right,
Speaker 18:  A standard only for print. So I think that's one thing that some
Speaker 18:  people don't necessarily realize is that Pantone is really only used for
Speaker 18:  print. So like would it be helpful if I just like told you about different
Speaker 18:  color profiles and different color spaces
Speaker 2:  Please.
Speaker 18:  Okay. So there are like three main color spaces that designers use most
Speaker 18:  often. So like if you're using a color for the internet, if we're designing
Speaker 18:  something for the Verge, we're gonna use a six digit hex code that signifies
Speaker 18:  a mixture of red, blue, and green. So that's within the RGB
Speaker 18:  color space because it's built outta a formula of three primary colors.
Speaker 18:  But the way things look on a screen is a lot of times super different from
Speaker 18:  how they look when they're printed. Screens are back lit. Screens have the
Speaker 18:  ability to kind of communicate a certain range of color. So sometimes that
Speaker 18:  means there's a wider range and sometimes it's more limited depending on
Speaker 18:  the color that you're using. So that doesn't translate exactly to physical
Speaker 18:  printing. So there's also like added variables like what kind of printer
Speaker 18:  are you using and what kind of paper because different paper sucks up in
Speaker 18:  in different ways. So for print, a lot of times we use more advanced
Speaker 18:  color space, which is called CM Y K and that stands for the four colors
Speaker 18:  you're using, which are cyan, magenta, yellow and key.
Speaker 18:  And everyone's always confused what the case stands for. It's just black
Speaker 18:  and it got its name from, in traditional printing you would call the black
Speaker 18:  plate the key plate because you'd run it through last and that's how you
Speaker 18:  get all the detail in the art. But then we have Pantone and Pantone
Speaker 18:  isn't so much a color space like I said, but it's a specific kind of ink
Speaker 18:  so it ensures you know exactly the kind of color you're gonna get. And it
Speaker 18:  also lets you print a lot of stuff that C M Y K can't do. It can be a
Speaker 18:  lot brighter, a lot more vibrant. It can do neon, it can do
Speaker 18:  metallics and a lot of times it just looks better.
Speaker 2:  Okay, this all is very helpful. It also makes me realize like we are down
Speaker 2:  the deepest rabbit hole of things. I have never, I, if you had asked me what
Speaker 2:  CNY case stood for and we just like sat here in silence for an hour, I would've
Speaker 2:  never come up with it. But Jess, walk me through this like fight
Speaker 2:  between Adobe and Pantone because as I understand it, there's like
Speaker 2:  some slight backstory to this beef that predates this
Speaker 2:  news.
Speaker 19:  Yeah, we don't necessarily have the entire story. We only have kind of like
Speaker 19:  the sides that they're telling us from their perspective, well,
Speaker 19:  perspectives and that. So as far as Panton is concerned,
Speaker 19:  they have been in a partnership with Adobe now for, for years and years
Speaker 19:  and years. They do not feel that Adobe has either allowed them
Speaker 19:  to substantially update their product within the Adobe Creative Suite and
Speaker 19:  then subsequently the creative cloud or that Adobe has not
Speaker 19:  pulled its own weight and done those updates by ourselves. So they basically
Speaker 19:  turned around and said we no longer trust Adobe to maintain our product.
Speaker 19:  We are removing it from Adobe in order to preserve it and
Speaker 19:  keep it maintained to our own standards. Adobe
Speaker 19:  has for whatever reason, not fought against that and gone. Okay, sweet.
Speaker 19:  I can't see that anyone else is gonna have an issue with this buy and it's
Speaker 19:  all come to a head. There seems to be kind of rumors, speculating that either
Speaker 19:  Pantone has turned around and asked Adobe for more
Speaker 19:  money or vice versa. Either party has then turned around and gone,
Speaker 19:  no. And now they're just expecting the the consumer to absorb that cost
Speaker 19:  at face value.
Speaker 2:  Okay, so where this lands then is now if you want to use Pantone
Speaker 2:  colors, if I'm understanding this correctly, you have to pay an extra subscription
Speaker 2:  on top of your Creative Cloud subscription. And if you don't, was I reading
Speaker 2:  this right earlier that basically everything that use Pantone colors, if
Speaker 2:  you stop paying it just turns black. That is like the most bonkers, heavy
Speaker 2:  handed execution of this that like, oh, what do you want? Colors? You get
Speaker 2:  no colors.
Speaker 19:  It kind of goes against what Pantone were promising cuz they were saying
Speaker 19:  that any kind of legacy documents that already used Pantone colors would
Speaker 19:  preserve the access to those, those files or whatever books that they were
Speaker 19:  using at the time. That wasn't the case. Whoever got that initial update,
Speaker 19:  I have no idea whether those have been restored. I haven't seen any instances
Speaker 19:  of people saying that they've come back. But yeah, when that update went
Speaker 19:  live, existing Lexi documents that were opened that were using Pantone colors
Speaker 19:  initially are now just displaying complete black where they were.
Speaker 2:  Kristin, how big a deal is this like in your day to day life? Like
Speaker 2:  you, you work mostly digitally? We're we're not a print magazine. Yeah, so
Speaker 2:  I hopefully this doesn't like ruin your day to day but like in in your world,
Speaker 2:  how big a deal is losing this thing kind of overnight.
Speaker 18:  Okay. So anyone who's like a, who's working as a full-time designer
Speaker 18:  or who's working at a, you know a company where you're doing a lot of print
Speaker 18:  products, obviously they're gonna pay for the service, it's gonna be no
Speaker 18:  big deal. I think it is a much bigger deal when you're a freelance artist,
Speaker 18:  partially because working with Pantos is already a pain. When I work with
Speaker 18:  artists for print product, like for example we've been working at the Verge
Speaker 18:  on this big package almost all year about the 20 year anniversary of the
Speaker 18:  Department of Homeland Security that's mostly online where we're using this
Speaker 18:  really great electric blue but we are doing a print product that we really
Speaker 18:  couldn't replicate that blue in Cnyk. It just, we couldn't get it
Speaker 18:  as bright as it was online. So that's when you might turn
Speaker 18:  to something like Pantone. The problem is we're working with a lot of artists
Speaker 18:  who are used to working in digital spaces and converting art that was
Speaker 18:  built for the internet into Pantone is like the nightmare
Speaker 18:  that you can't believe. Like it takes more time than makes and is logical
Speaker 18:  sense and I feel like that's always been a broken part of the Adobe suite,
Speaker 18:  that translation because the way you're making something might change, the
Speaker 18:  application might change, you might want to shift and do something for print.
Speaker 18:  And so it's always been really broken. It's always been like there's been
Speaker 18:  this separate program with inside of Adobe Photoshop or Illustrator
Speaker 18:  or whatever you're using. So this just makes that a much more complicated
Speaker 18:  mess.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, this is the part of all of this that has been the hardest for me to
Speaker 2:  wrap my head around, which is like I think of it as like there is a whole
Speaker 2:  spectrum of colors and all of them are identifiable with hex codes, right?
Speaker 2:  And it's like I have the slider in RGB that I can use and I have hex codes
Speaker 2:  and between those I always thought I could access all the colors that like
Speaker 2:  goof around with that enough and you should be able to accomplish that. But
Speaker 2:  now we're in this place where it seems like what we actually have is a bunch
Speaker 2:  of standards that are overlapping but slightly different and none of them
Speaker 2:  actually understand each other. Yes. And now somebody is saying well this
Speaker 2:  one is ours and we are taking it away from you. And that I like, I can see
Speaker 2:  why that would be a big problem for people,
Speaker 18:  Which has always been kind of a problem with Pantone. Like Pantone updates
Speaker 18:  their color books like every year or two and they do that so they can charge
Speaker 18:  like another $175 for a swatch book and
Speaker 18:  that means that sometimes if your swatch book on your Adobe suite is out
Speaker 18:  of date, you have to pay to download that new color book.
Speaker 18:  Now what's really happening though is that Panton is just turning into a
Speaker 18:  subscription service rather than something you do every couple of years.
Speaker 2:  Jess, this seems like the kind of thing that it's like a funny match to when
Speaker 2:  Adobe went to Creative Cloud in the first place and everybody got really
Speaker 2:  up in arms about it and they're like, well I used to just pay for a thing
Speaker 2:  and then I would have the thing and now you're basically telling me to like
Speaker 2:  pay you a large amount of money every year or like the tools I need to do
Speaker 2:  my job disappear on me and I don't own them anymore. Like is
Speaker 2:  this just the inexorable path that all of this stuff is heading and to
Speaker 2:  be a designer or anyone is just gonna be a million subscriptions that you
Speaker 2:  basically have no choice but to pay for. Like is this where we're headed?
Speaker 19:  It kind of feels like that is the way it's going. There are a couple of
Speaker 19:  services recently that have also switched from a one time purchase model
Speaker 19:  over to subscription. I can think of kind of like a clip paint studio off
Speaker 19:  the top of my head a couple of months back. Their fan base felt quite significantly
Speaker 19:  betrayed by that. But by kind of standing their ground and saying,
Speaker 19:  well we as Adobe don't want to front this cost for our consumers, you can
Speaker 19:  now pay for it. They've kind of shot themselves in the foot by proving that
Speaker 19:  the software as a service model is as bad as people were worried it was
Speaker 19:  going to be. Because inevitably people that still have legacy Adobe
Speaker 19:  products, if you still have a copy of Creative Suite for example CS six
Speaker 19:  knocking around that will still have access to the Pantone color box within
Speaker 19:  there because it doesn't receive any legacy updates. So if you have Adobe
Speaker 19:  consists to be an updated product that's no longer up to industry standards,
Speaker 19:  you're actually better off if you're still using Pantone colors despite
Speaker 19:  the fact that they might be out of date by a significant margin.
Speaker 2:  So are we gonna get like a black market for old versions of
Speaker 2:  Adobe products? Like I, this, this is just, this all gets so crazy to me
Speaker 2:  where it's like suddenly several years old software becomes a really useful
Speaker 2:  thing to have.
Speaker 19:  It's already kind of happening. So there's a couple of things are like noteworthy
Speaker 19:  here. So one is that Adobe software in general is just one of the most
Speaker 19:  powered softwares in the world alongside Microsoft Office Suite. The two
Speaker 19:  of them are just like, they are the top ranking in terms of what people
Speaker 19:  will go and legally crack online for those reasons they don't want to pay
Speaker 19:  an ongoing subscription fee for the product. Yes it might be initial
Speaker 19:  hefty cash lump sum to begin with, but if you are paying that and you are
Speaker 19:  consistently working with the creative industry, I think it's within like
Speaker 19:  three or four years or something, you would've already paid for the most
Speaker 19:  premium monthly subscription tier of Adobe. And at that point
Speaker 19:  you are just handing Adobe money for a continual product that may not be
Speaker 19:  necessarily like getting updates that are worth your time. The other thing
Speaker 19:  from that is that people are finding that if they either had a preUpdate
Speaker 19:  version of Adobe products or an outdated version of
Speaker 19:  CS six, they can pull the the Pantone color box
Speaker 19:  from those, I'm not condoning this by the way, I'm just noting it's happening.
Speaker 19:  But they can pull the, the Pantone color box from those versions of the
Speaker 19:  software and then manually implant them into the updated version. It may
Speaker 19:  not work forever, it may not work well but it is what people are doing in
Speaker 19:  order to try and avoid paying Pantone a monthly subscription.
Speaker 2:  The other thing we would need here is a better version of this
Speaker 2:  kind of standard system. Cause I think part of the reason this story is interesting
Speaker 2:  to me is this is the kind of thing that has come up over and over across
Speaker 2:  a lot of tech is like everybody looks around and it's like, oh we've relied
Speaker 2:  essentially on a for-profit company to provide what we see
Speaker 2:  as sort of a necessary service across a lot of the things that we use. And
Speaker 2:  then that company turns around and says, oh we'd like to make more money.
Speaker 2:  And everybody goes, well that sucks but also fair enough. Like that's
Speaker 2:  what they do. And it seems to me like if I'm an enterprising
Speaker 2:  designer right now with some like, I don't know, coding skills and time in
Speaker 2:  my hands, like somebody should start building like open source color repositories
Speaker 2:  that start to replace some of this stuff in more functional accessible
Speaker 2:  ways. Like is that, is that a thing? Is that happening?
Speaker 19:  Yep, that that's happening. There are other kind of color books whereas
Speaker 19:  we, we consider Pantone to be the industry standard because of its longevity
Speaker 19:  and how many people already use the service, how many printers are already
Speaker 19:  calibrated to use Pantone inks. There are other color books available, they're
Speaker 19:  just not as popular. You've got like focal tone, true match and interesting
Speaker 19:  development recently there's an artist called Stuart Sample who has
Speaker 19:  kind of gained no notoriety for beefing with another artist, Anish Kapur
Speaker 19:  over gatekeeping art. He developed a paint called
Speaker 19:  like the Black Is Black and then sold that because Anish Kapur
Speaker 19:  notably painted the rights to Van to Black at the time and he didn't think
Speaker 19:  that was fair. He's now done a similar thing where he has created a open
Speaker 19:  source color book of his own and he is making it unavailable for
Speaker 19:  Adobe and Panton as some kind of like protesting that. But it, it's quite
Speaker 19:  easy to develop these, these color standards. It's getting everyone else
Speaker 19:  to use and that's the hard part.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Kristen, what are, are you seeing? What do you make of all the other
Speaker 2:  stuff that's out there right now?
Speaker 18:  I think the most important thing here is to remember that Pantone is only
Speaker 18:  for print products. So I think sometimes like the confusion over how
Speaker 18:  colors can be used. Like if you're not designing for print, this is kind
Speaker 18:  of like a totally irrelevant thing. Which is I think why because fewer and
Speaker 18:  fewer people are designing for print products over time. I thinks probably
Speaker 18:  that would be my guess is why Panton is now trying to gather more
Speaker 18:  money from the people who are using and printing that way. I mean Panton
Speaker 18:  also similar to Adobe has a lot of piloting. There's a lot of fake panton
Speaker 18:  ink out there that's being used at various printers across the world.
Speaker 2:  Do you see any of these kind of new color books and tools out there
Speaker 2:  that have a chance of being like just said the ones that everybody actually
Speaker 2:  latches onto? Cause that seems like, like you're saying, the biggest problem
Speaker 2:  here is that we need one that everybody looks at and goes, okay, this is
Speaker 2:  now the one. And as we've seen, that's a very hard thing to do.
Speaker 18:  I mean the, the hardest thing is to, as Jess mentioned, is to get all of
Speaker 18:  the printers to stock all of this ink. I mean printers across the world
Speaker 18:  are using this as the standard. So it's about kind of like that shift
Speaker 18:  happening in a, in an industry that is not often quick to make changes.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. As we've discussed before on this podcast, relying on the printing
Speaker 2:  industry to catch up to things really fast is a, a recipe for disaster. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Is there a version of this in the digital world? Like as we move toward
Speaker 2:  digital stuff? Like do do hex codes and RGB sliders solve this problem
Speaker 2:  for people who work digitally native? Or are we due for another one of
Speaker 2:  these at some point in the future?
Speaker 18:  I don't know. I mean the main most important thing to remember I think is
Speaker 18:  to understand the distinction between RGB and C M Y K if you're working
Speaker 18:  on the computer. Because you're basically only gonna be working in rgb,
Speaker 18:  which is using hex codes. So those colors will continue to exist. Those
Speaker 18:  are just codes, you know, there's nothing, there's no ink attached to those
Speaker 18:  things. To those colors.
Speaker 2:  And that seems like good news, right? That's a hard thing for someone to
Speaker 2:  decide that they own and take away from you. It's just a bunch of six digit.
Speaker 18:  Yeah, I suppose unless Adobe was like, if you use more than seven colors
Speaker 18:  you have to pay us additional 9 99 a month or something like that.
Speaker 2:  Don't give them ideas, Kristen, don't give them ideas.
Speaker 2:  Jess, what's your sense of where this goes next? This fight is, I think it's
Speaker 2:  a really interesting one because like Kristen's saying this applies to a
Speaker 2:  smaller and smaller group of people, but this is the kind of thing that a
Speaker 2:  lot of people care really deeply about and Adobe has already been under fire
Speaker 2:  for years for what I think people perceive as like nickling and diving people
Speaker 2:  out of a lot of money for the tools they need to do their jobs. Like
Speaker 2:  is this coming to a head in a meaningful way? Is this just the
Speaker 2:  cost of progress? Like where, where do you think we go from here?
Speaker 19:  I don't necessarily, as much as I'd love to say that I think that something
Speaker 19:  is gonna change in the next few years, I think that everything is so standardized
Speaker 19:  at this point and the captive market that this affects is so
Speaker 19:  small and to an extent kind of so able to
Speaker 19:  absorb those additional costs that it's not really gonna affect the industry
Speaker 19:  as a whole. So like illustrators and photographers aren't really gonna notice
Speaker 19:  that the Pantone colors are disappearing cuz they simply don't need to use
Speaker 19:  them. But if you own a huge manufacturing business and you work with several
Speaker 19:  big notable brands, you need to use Coca-Cola Red, you need to use
Speaker 19:  like whatever like brand specific colors that additional subscription charge
Speaker 19:  every month on top of what you inevitably are already paying for their,
Speaker 19:  their physical color books, watches and like any color matching systems
Speaker 19:  that they provide is negligible and it's frustrating that companies
Speaker 19:  will have to absorb those costs. But it, I think Adobe and Panton, as much
Speaker 19:  as they're beefing with each other, they are aware that the people that
Speaker 19:  this effects can afford to absorb that. So unless it starts to
Speaker 19:  affect the vast majority of creatives, we're not gonna see any kind of difference
Speaker 19:  here. There are kind of discussions of small manufacturing business that
Speaker 19:  are moving over to using different like color matching systems like CM
Speaker 19:  yk because with certain stuff you can get it
Speaker 19:  close, there are inconsistencies, you can't necessarily
Speaker 19:  guarantee that you're gonna have consistent results with whatever you're
Speaker 19:  printing. But if you are a one time printer and you just need to, I dunno,
Speaker 19:  make a couple of screen printed t-shirts, then you can get something as
Speaker 19:  close as you need to. But in terms of like big, yeah, big branded projects,
Speaker 19:  I don't think you're moving away from Panto and anytime soon
Speaker 18:  And a lot of times you're printing with C M Y K and Pantone
Speaker 18:  for the example for the Homeland project that we talked about, you know,
Speaker 18:  that's how we print it. That's how I printed it. And you know, when I worked
Speaker 18:  in books, when I worked at other magazines before coming to the Verge, you
Speaker 18:  would use the Pantone if you needed to accomplish something you couldn't
Speaker 18:  in C M Y K. So that's something like Jess said, that's a really recognizable
Speaker 18:  color, like a Coca-Cola red, that's something that's metallic, that's something
Speaker 18:  that's neon or that's something that's just like really bright and vibrant.
Speaker 18:  Those are things that you cannot get with C Y K, but you can maybe print,
Speaker 18:  if you were printing a poster, you might need some neon elements that you
Speaker 18:  print and Pantone and then the rest is C y K. So a lot of times, so that
Speaker 18:  means you're running something through the press five times rather than
Speaker 18:  four.
Speaker 19:  The inclusion, the brands is actually quite important here as well because
Speaker 19:  whereas the system like CMI K can replicate those colors
Speaker 19:  accurately. Pantone will actually let brands patent their branded colors
Speaker 19:  so in Pantone so that no one else can use it and provided that it's something
Speaker 19:  on a gamut that none of the other color matching systems can reach. No one
Speaker 19:  else can use that Coca-Cola red or like whatever other branded color you
Speaker 19:  have. So it's within a brand's best interest to keep Pantone as a color
Speaker 19:  standard. Like yes, you could use everything else, but there aren't
Speaker 19:  necessarily brands that would want you to do that.
Speaker 2:  Interesting. All right. Well you have both succeeded in successfully convincing
Speaker 2:  me that colors don't make sense and aren't real and no one actually knows
Speaker 2:  anything about what a color actually is.
Speaker 18:  That's true. Actually, no one knows anything about color. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  Apparently.
Speaker 18:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  All right, well thank you both. I, I appreciate this was really fun.
Speaker 19:  Thank
Speaker 18:  You. Cool. I'm gonna send you some color books, David.
Speaker 2:  All right, that's it for the Vergecast today. As always, thank you so much
Speaker 2:  for listening. There is tons more coverage on everything we talked
Speaker 2:  about@verge.com. It's website, it's cool, you should go check it out. You
Speaker 2:  can follow all of us on Twitter. Jess is zombie underscore retch.
Speaker 2:  Kristin is Kristin Radke. James is JJ Vincent,
Speaker 2:  and I'm Pierce. This show is produced by Andrew Marino and Liam James
Speaker 2:  Nore. Donovan is our executive producer and Brooke Miners is our editorial
Speaker 2:  director of Audio Vergecast is Verge Production and part of the Fox Media
Speaker 2:  podcast network. If you have thoughts, feedback, feelings, ideas about
Speaker 2:  colors or just six digit hex codes you wanna send me, you can always email
Speaker 2:  vergecast@theverge.com. And if you have tech questions, call the hotline
Speaker 2:  eight sixty six Verge 11, send us all your big thoughts and
Speaker 2:  questions about all things tech. We're gonna do a bunch more hotline between
Speaker 2:  now and the end of the year, so please keep calling with all your questions.
Speaker 2:  We'll be back on Friday to discuss Elon and Twitter because that just keeps
Speaker 2:  happening. Plus the ongoing crypto craziness, new GPUs, and
Speaker 2:  much more. We'll see you then. Rock and roll.