# Transcript
ID: 6a77dbd0-2c4c-11ed-8dea-aff10976f398
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Land of the Giants: It's a WhatsApp world
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/4324405339878354465/-6877074096174702626/s93290-US-2149s-1662294176.mp3
Description: We're sharing an episode of Land of the Giants: The Facebook / Meta disruption, a collaboration between Recode and The Verge.
Meta’s most expensive acquisition ever and one of the most used communication apps in the world: WhatsApp. With over 2 billion users, WhatsApp is embedded in the social, economic, and political infrastructure of countries across the globe. For better and worse. The story of WhatsApp’s incredible power, as told through its largest market: India.
NOTE: There are descriptions of graphic acts of violence in this episode. If you want to skip these descriptions, the section begins at 20:45 and ends at 22:05.
Hosted by Shirin Ghaffary (@shiringhaffary) and Alex Heath (@alexeheath)
Subscribe for free. Be the first to hear next week's episode by hitting the plus sign in your favorite podcast app
Follow @recode and @verge for more coverage of Meta and Big Tech
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Disabled
Speaker 1:  Welcome to the Vergecast the flagship podcast of unattractive messaging apps.
Speaker 1:  I'm your friend, David Pierce. And we are technically off today, but I wanted
Speaker 1:  to play you instead of just not having an episode, an episode of a
Speaker 1:  podcast called land of the giants, which hopefully you're listening to. But
Speaker 1:  if not this season, the land of the giants is all about Facebook
Speaker 1:  and meta. The show is a collaboration between Recode and the verge and Shereen
Speaker 1:  Ghafari and Alex, Keith have been exploring how Facebook
Speaker 1:  eventually Metta have changed the way that we live our lives, both on and
Speaker 1:  off the internet. The last episode of the season dropped today. The whole
Speaker 1:  series is great. You should listen to all of it, but I wanted to play you
Speaker 1:  an episode. That's actually the second to last episode in the season, all
Speaker 1:  about WhatsApp. WhatsApp is absolutely fascinating. It's
Speaker 1:  massive. And it changes the way that people live their lives
Speaker 1:  in ways. Many of us, especially in the U S where WhatsApp is not as popular,
Speaker 1:  don't even understand. So again, you should listen to the whole series, but
Speaker 1:  I think this episode stands pretty well on its own. This is land at the giants
Speaker 3:  You probably don't remember where you were on
Speaker 3:  October 4th, 2021,
Speaker 4:  Tonight, major outages affecting billions of users of Facebook,
Speaker 4:  Instagram, and WhatsApp. All of it starting this morning and continuing through
Speaker 4:  the day,
Speaker 5:  All three apps went offline at the same time around the world.
Speaker 3:  Inconvenience doom. Scroller is on Facebook and Instagram switched over to
Speaker 3:  other platforms so much so that the official Twitter account tweeted out.
Speaker 3:  Hello, literally everyone,
Speaker 5:  But for Rajiv, Kira WhatsApp going down was a much bigger
Speaker 5:  deal. We
Speaker 6:  Never, we don't for so long.
Speaker 3:  The official shutdown lasted for about six hours, but the effects
Speaker 3:  lingered in a few places, such as India, which meant
Speaker 3:  enormous consequences for people like Kira. WhatsApp is his
Speaker 3:  livelihood.
Speaker 5:  He founded a food tech business called Chucky piecing outside new Delhi,
Speaker 5:  India that delivers freshly milled flour and spices to people. And
Speaker 5:  he runs it primarily on WhatsApp. That's where he lists available items
Speaker 5:  chats with customers, processes orders.
Speaker 6:  Well, 70, 80% of our business was done.
Speaker 3:  Kierra was not alone. About 15 million businesses run on
Speaker 3:  WhatsApp in India.
Speaker 6:  And even today to be very honest, we don't have an alternative, which can
Speaker 6:  a hundred percent replace whatsoever. There is a downtime
Speaker 3:  In India. WhatsApp is more than a private messaging service.
Speaker 5:  Four it's 400 million users there. WhatsApp is the
Speaker 5:  internet, or you could put it like this.
Speaker 6:  Watch seven India is avail flight.
Speaker 3:  Keep in touch with your family, WhatsApp, buy and sell goods.
Speaker 3:  WhatsApp, send money, access, critical medical
Speaker 3:  information, like where to get a COVID vaccine WhatsApp
Speaker 5:  Though, it doesn't contribute much to Meta's bottom line. Yet WhatsApp is
Speaker 5:  the company's most essential product by far that's because
Speaker 5:  with over 2 billion users, WhatsApp is embedded in the social
Speaker 5:  economic and political infrastructure of countries across the globe,
Speaker 3:  But there's a dark side to connecting the world. Enormous
Speaker 3:  platforms can cause enormous problems.
Speaker 7:  India is WhatsApp's biggest market and viral hoaxes on the
Speaker 7:  platform are being blamed for a recent spate of mob violence.
Speaker 8:  Recently in India, internet Lynch mobs have killed a dozen
Speaker 8:  people, including innocent bystanders. Thank you.
Speaker 9:  Cryptid messaging platform has become a playground for conspiracy
Speaker 9:  theorists
Speaker 5:  Today. The story of WhatsApp's incredible power is told through its
Speaker 5:  largest market India. Mark Zuckerberg has had a
Speaker 5:  long history with India, even before WhatsApp solidified his company's
Speaker 5:  dominance there.
Speaker 3:  Now WhatsApp is particularly intertwined in Indian society
Speaker 3:  for better and for worse.
Speaker 3:  This is land of the giants
Speaker 5:  Long before WhatsApp was one of the biggest apps in the world. Niraj
Speaker 5:  Aurora noticed it's starting to climb the downloads chart of Google's Android
Speaker 5:  play store.
Speaker 3:  The year was 2010 and Aurora was working on corporate development at
Speaker 3:  Google. He was tasked with looking for startups to acquire at the Dawn
Speaker 3:  of the smartphone era.
Speaker 11:  WhatsApp had no information about them on the website.
Speaker 11:  So I emailed support@whatsapp.com. I didn't hear back
Speaker 11:  for several days. Finally. I think
Speaker 11:  Brian replied on support email
Speaker 11:  saying, why don't you come meet us at this mountain? We address
Speaker 5:  Brian is in Brian Acton, who co-founded WhatsApp with Yon
Speaker 5:  comb. The founders met while working at Yahoo. Now they were building
Speaker 5:  WhatsApp out of a small back office in Silicon valley, Aurora
Speaker 5:  members that had an informal meeting room.
Speaker 11:  So it was sort of like a, just a cubicle, not really a conference room.
Speaker 11:  And I was like, shit. Like, this is very weird because I'm going to talk
Speaker 11:  some sensitive stuff with you. And they're like, I don't care.
Speaker 3:  Neither did Aurora. He left the meeting excited about the potential for what
Speaker 3:  accent and Coon we're building.
Speaker 5:  He made an offer for this startup on behalf of Google, $10 million
Speaker 5:  and impressive price tag, considering that WhatsApp, boasted barely a million
Speaker 5:  downloads so far and hadn't raised any outside capital
Speaker 3:  And yet acting in Coon passed.
Speaker 5:  So Aurora came back within a few months with a better deal. One that he
Speaker 5:  says, Google co-founder Larry Page had to personally sign off on
Speaker 5:  $100 million.
Speaker 11:  They said, look, we left Yahoo to start WhatsApp for a reason.
Speaker 11:  We hate big companies and we cannot operate the baby B cam
Speaker 11:  hair. So thank you very much. Thanks for spending time with
Speaker 11:  us
Speaker 5:  Move that left a lasting impression.
Speaker 5:  When Aurora left Google looking for his next career move, he called
Speaker 5:  WhatsApp.
Speaker 11:  Obviously the only company I really wanted to like work at was
Speaker 11:  WhatsApp. Like I'd seen everything Dropbox, Airbnb
Speaker 11:  square, like all the heart darlings of the valley
Speaker 11:  were not that interesting. This was sort of like the hidden gem that nobody
Speaker 11:  knew about and was just growing really well. And the founders were incredible.
Speaker 3:  Aurora joined WhatsApp in November, 2011 as its chief business
Speaker 3:  officer. And by then what's apps growth was taking off
Speaker 3:  purely by word of mouth. Tens of millions of people were using the app.
Speaker 11:  The most important thing was that our daily to
Speaker 11:  monthly active users ratio was the best in the
Speaker 11:  industry. I think it was around 70 something percent
Speaker 11:  like 70% of your monthly active users would come back daily,
Speaker 11:  which was, I think better than Facebook's.
Speaker 5:  Here's why WhatsApp was taking off. It was a cheaper alternative to texting
Speaker 5:  traditional text messaging was expensive and a lot of the world at the time,
Speaker 5:  you often got charged per text messaging apps like WhatsApp
Speaker 5:  instead used internet data plans.
Speaker 3:  And WhatsApp was simple, both to sign up for and to use
Speaker 3:  Kumon. Acton made a priority of supporting every kind of smartphone possible.
Speaker 3:  So WhatsApp could work no matter the device and your account was just your
Speaker 3:  phone number. The app limited the information it collected on you,
Speaker 3:  not your location and not the names or addresses of your contacts.
Speaker 5:  This spoke to a key value for the founders of WhatsApp privacy
Speaker 5:  from the very beginning, privacy and security were built into the company's
Speaker 5:  DNA. This was more than a design feature. It was what the founders
Speaker 5:  felt. They owed their users.
Speaker 3:  Coon was born in Ukraine during the Soviet years, growing up, his parents
Speaker 3:  avoided using the telephone for fear. They were being monitored by the state.
Speaker 5:  If Kuhn's appreciation for privacy came from his personal history.
Speaker 5:  Actins came from his professional past at Yahoo in the
Speaker 5:  nineties, he'd run an advertising platform that collected click-through data.
Speaker 5:  It turned them off for good on targeted as
Speaker 11:  He had a very kind of like ugly experience, trying to
Speaker 11:  figure that thing out. I think he didn't really enjoy that experience of
Speaker 11:  collecting all the data and showing out and all that. So when they started
Speaker 11:  WhatsApp and when Brian joined, it was very clear. He said, I'm not never
Speaker 11:  going to do that. This is a very intimate and personal product that we are
Speaker 11:  building. I would hate to collect or know what people are
Speaker 11:  chatting about on my app, right? So from day one, it was
Speaker 11:  not an option.
Speaker 3:  Coon famously taped a note to his work desk from Acton that red, no
Speaker 3:  ads, no games, no gimmicks.
Speaker 5:  WhatsApp's the emphasis on simplicity and privacy was working by
Speaker 5:  early 2013. The company had 200 million active users.
Speaker 5:  And with advertising off the table, acting in Coombe, decided to charge a
Speaker 5:  whopping 99 cents a year for the app.
Speaker 3:  It wasn't much, but in the world of free social media apps like Facebook,
Speaker 3:  Twitter, and Snapchat, it was unusual. And according to Aurora,
Speaker 3:  it was actually part of an effort to slow down growth to a manageable pace.
Speaker 5:  But the strategy didn't work out exactly as planned.
Speaker 11:  The growth never stopped. People were still paying and they were shocked.
Speaker 11:  And I remember I still have those screenshots somewhere where I think
Speaker 11:  there was a point where we were the top paid app
Speaker 11:  on the app store in 50 different countries. At the same time,
Speaker 5:  What's up success was starting to make waves in April, 2013.
Speaker 5:  Coombe took the stage at the all things, Dean mobile conference, and revealed
Speaker 5:  that WhatsApp had more users than Twitter.
Speaker 11:  Everybody was taken a back like, who are these guys? They've never talked
Speaker 11:  about themselves. And now they're saying they're bigger than Twitter, right?
Speaker 3:  Aurora says after Coombs, Mike drop major acquisition offers rolled in
Speaker 3:  the Chinese company. Tencent was the first big one,
Speaker 3:  $10 billion. Google called again, this time
Speaker 3:  Larry Page wanted to meet and the meeting got scheduled, but
Speaker 5:  It would be too late because someone else had been keeping track of
Speaker 5:  WhatsApps success. Mark Zuckerberg,
Speaker 11:  You were getting into the zone of half a billion users, active
Speaker 11:  users. So really active everyday and
Speaker 11:  with an opportunity to definitely get to a billion users and do a lot
Speaker 11:  of other things than just messaging. So
Speaker 11:  it was absolutely an existential threat for Facebook. And he knew that
Speaker 5:  As he had shown with the purchase of Instagram, Zuckerberg was always on
Speaker 5:  the lookout for challengers to his social media empire, and
Speaker 5:  WhatsApp's growth on mobile phones directly challenged Facebook messenger,
Speaker 5:  especially because WhatsApp was taking off in parts of the world that messenger
Speaker 5:  just wasn't.
Speaker 3:  And at a more fundamental level, people were using WhatsApp for many of the
Speaker 3:  same reasons. They might otherwise use Facebook to keep in touch with family
Speaker 3:  and friends online. It was a network of users that might never enter
Speaker 3:  the Facebook universe, sucker Berg needed it, or he might
Speaker 3:  lose to it.
Speaker 5:  So he made his move before WhatsApp was set to meet with
Speaker 5:  Google Zuckerberg, invited Coombe over for dinner.
Speaker 11:  Facebook said, look, whatever it takes, the kind of deal you want to
Speaker 11:  structure, whatever you want, we'll give it to you
Speaker 3:  And buy whatever you want. They meant it
Speaker 11:  Autonomy nor ads, complete product independence
Speaker 11:  for Yon and Brian board seat for Yon, which we didn't ask for. They
Speaker 11:  offered, we said, okay, fine. And
Speaker 11:  encryption and doing encryption was, they cannot say no to it.
Speaker 11:  Like we were still in working on it. And they said, yeah, we'll support
Speaker 11:  that
Speaker 5:  End to end encryption was a deal point that spoke to actin and Coombs focus
Speaker 5:  on privacy. The technology would prevent anyone except the
Speaker 5:  sender and the recipient of a message from being able to read it. So
Speaker 5:  even WhatsApp itself, wouldn't be able to know the contents of the
Speaker 5:  conversation's flowing through its service.
Speaker 3:  The encryption deal point also spoke to an inherent tension between WhatsApp
Speaker 3:  and Facebook early on Facebook's business model depended
Speaker 3:  on collecting data about users, likes and interactions. So it could use that
Speaker 3:  data to personalize ads,
Speaker 11:  Obviously Yon and Brian might never put this on the record that we were
Speaker 11:  doing this partially so that Facebook never gets any information about our
Speaker 11:  users. But I know for sure that was one of the reasons that they wanted
Speaker 11:  to do it.
Speaker 3:  Even if WhatsApp's adherence to privacy was contradictory in some ways to
Speaker 3:  Facebook's business. Facebook just wanted to get the deal done.
Speaker 5:  Kumon Zuckerberg did just that on Valentine's day in 2014,
Speaker 5:  the agreed price, 19 billion in mostly Facebook
Speaker 5:  stock. It would be Zuckerberg largest acquisition ever by
Speaker 5:  far
Speaker 3:  The media reported at the time Zuckerberg and Coombs shared a plate of seasonally,
Speaker 3:  appropriate chocolate covered strawberries.
Speaker 5:  It was a whirlwind romance.
Speaker 13:  WhatsApp is a great company and it's a, and it's a great fit for us.
Speaker 3:  Just shy of two weeks after the deal was signed, sucker Berg was in
Speaker 3:  Barcelona at the mobile world, Congress, a gigantic trade show for the mobile
Speaker 3:  telecommunications industry.
Speaker 13:  I'll already almost half a billion people. I love using
Speaker 13:  WhatsApp for, for messaging. And it's the
Speaker 13:  most engaging app that, that we've ever seen exist on
Speaker 13:  mobile by far,
Speaker 5:  People were stunned by how much he paid for WhatsApp. It was the most expensive
Speaker 5:  purchase of any private tech startup to date. So in Zuckerberg was asked
Speaker 5:  to explain his rationale. He sounded a little defensive.
Speaker 13:  I actually just think that by itself it's worth more than $19 billion. I
Speaker 13:  mean, it's, it's hard to exactly make that case today because they
Speaker 13:  have so little revenue compared to that number. But I mean, the reality
Speaker 13:  is there are very few services that reach a billion people in the world.
Speaker 13:  They're all incredibly valuable, much more valuable than that
Speaker 3:  For Zuckerberg. WhatsApp was invaluable because it was a way to fulfill
Speaker 3:  his original mission of getting as many people in the world as possible using
Speaker 3:  one of Facebook's products
Speaker 13:  When Yon and I first met and started talking about this,
Speaker 13:  we really started talking about what it was going to be like to connect
Speaker 13:  everyone in the world, right? And a lot of this is the vision for
Speaker 13:  internet.org. And that's what I really want to take the time to focus on
Speaker 13:  today.
Speaker 5:  Internet.org, this project sucker Berg talked about in the same breath as
Speaker 5:  WhatsApp was an initiative to bring internet access to various countries
Speaker 5:  with untapped users, including India, which have become an
Speaker 5:  incredibly attractive market to Silicon valley.
Speaker 12:  So around 2015,
Speaker 12:  Silicon valley essentially looked eastwards
Speaker 12:  and said, here's this big market. It has more than a billion
Speaker 12:  people. A telecom war is just getting underway. Here's
Speaker 12:  our next billion users
Speaker 3:   as a technology reporter for Buzzfeed who was based in India
Speaker 3:  from 2014 to 2022, that telecom
Speaker 3:  war he mentions. It meant that suddenly India
Speaker 3:  experienced a huge drop in internet data costs
Speaker 3:  a whole bunch of people who couldn't afford to get online before now
Speaker 3:  could
Speaker 12:  Most people in India experience the internet almost entirely on
Speaker 12:  that smartphones, India leapfrogged, as they say,
Speaker 12:  the desktop PC era, most people never had them.
Speaker 3:  So back to Zuckerberg, internet.org project, a way to get onto all those
Speaker 3:  smartphones,
Speaker 5:  Practically it met Facebook, partnered with major telecom services in India
Speaker 5:  and other countries to provide a free stripped down version of the internet.
Speaker 5:  Facebook of course, would be one of a few sites available
Speaker 3:  Facebook branded internet.org as an idealistic project to deliver the
Speaker 3:  human right of connection. But many did not buy that branding,
Speaker 3:  especially in India, where there were protests against Facebook's
Speaker 3:  initiative, many people, and even the government saw it as an
Speaker 3:  attempt by Facebook to control the internet. The government ended up
Speaker 3:  outright banning the project, but lucky for Zuckerberg, he would
Speaker 3:  still have a way to those hundreds of millions of users
Speaker 6:  In India is a way of life.
Speaker 3:  In the years, following Facebook's acquisition of WhatsApp, the app flourished
Speaker 3:  in India, even with limited two G mobile internet connections,
Speaker 3:  people could load WhatsApp relatively quickly because it was simple with
Speaker 3:  far fewer features and social media apps like Facebook.
Speaker 5:  WhatsApp was a success except in one respect revenue
Speaker 5:  just a few years after the acquisition conversations inside Facebook
Speaker 5:  began to turn to how WhatsApp could make money that subscription WhatsApp
Speaker 5:  originally charged Facebook, removed it after the deal,
Speaker 11:  They want it to run ads on the
Speaker 11:  stories feature that WhatsApp built
Speaker 3:  Called status. This feature was a knockoff of Instagram stories. It
Speaker 3:  launched in 2017 to Facebook status was a natural place
Speaker 3:  to run ads.
Speaker 11:  They had all the infrastructure of running ads on Instagram and Facebook.
Speaker 11:  So they were like, we just plug it in. I think Brian had an allergic reaction
Speaker 11:  to that. He was like, I'm leaving. And he left a lot of money on the table
Speaker 5:  Act and walked away from roughly 850 million in Facebook shares.
Speaker 5:  He would go on to become the chairman of signal. Another encrypted messaging
Speaker 5:  app that's run as a nonprofit. And when the Cambridge Analytica scandal
Speaker 5:  broke in 2018, actin tweeted out, quote, it is
Speaker 5:  time hashtag delete Facebook
Speaker 3:  A few months after act and left Coombe quit too, though. It's
Speaker 3:  unclear how much ads had to do with it in his farewell post. He said he
Speaker 3:  wanted to spend more time on his hobbies, like collecting rare air
Speaker 3:  cooled Porsche's and playing ultimate Frisbee.
Speaker 5:  This whole situation is ironic because ads never came to
Speaker 5:  WhatsApp. Facebook decided that the risk of backlash wouldn't be worth it,
Speaker 5:  but not before actin Coombe and Aurora were out the door
Speaker 5:  and Facebook decided to lean into the values of
Speaker 5:  WhatsApp to embrace its focus on privacy as a selling
Speaker 5:  point.
Speaker 14:  I think you have to think about what it means to offer a service where people
Speaker 14:  communicate their most private thoughts
Speaker 14:  to the people they care about the most, all around the world.
Speaker 3:  The current head of WhatsApp will Cathcart Cathcart transferred over
Speaker 3:  from the Facebook app in 2019. Now he says Mehta has
Speaker 3:  embraced an ads free WhatsApp. Instead it's pushing to
Speaker 3:  make money by charging businesses, to message their customers.
Speaker 14:  There are a lot of really, really sensitive
Speaker 14:  conversations that happen on WhatsApp. Everything from people talking to
Speaker 14:  a doctor, people talking to a journalist and a lot of countries or WhatsApp's
Speaker 14:  popular government officials talking amongst themselves. So you've got to
Speaker 14:  offer the highest level of security.
Speaker 5:  This preaching of WhatsApp's original values. It's not just coming from Cathcart.
Speaker 13:  Privacy gives us the freedom to be ourselves.
Speaker 13:  It's easier to feel like you belong when you're part of smaller
Speaker 13:  communities and amongst your closest friends,
Speaker 5:  Mark Zuckerberg at Facebook's ethic conference in 2019
Speaker 5:  with Russian misinformation and Cambridge Analytica behind him. This was
Speaker 5:  the year Zuckerberg made a hard pivot to privacy specifically.
Speaker 5:  He said he believed the future of communication would increasingly shift
Speaker 5:  to encrypted messaging.
Speaker 13:  As the world gets bigger and more connected. We need that
Speaker 13:  sense of, of intimacy more than more than ever.
Speaker 13:  So that's why I believe that the future is private
Speaker 3:  Privacy and encryption. They become virtues to Facebook,
Speaker 3:  but these commitments are now putting Mehta and WhatsApp at odds with the
Speaker 3:  government of India. It's the largest market because connecting so many
Speaker 3:  people, even through private group chats can cause real world
Speaker 3:  problems.
Speaker 15:  Step into the all electric Cadillac, Lyrica and experience American
Speaker 15:  luxury elevated to an art form, meticulously crafted
Speaker 15:  fiercely original boldly electric. It's an Evie. As
Speaker 15:  uncompromising as you are be exuberant, be
Speaker 15:  electrifying, be iconic in the all electric lyric
Speaker 15:  order. Yours 2023 lyric orders default go
Speaker 15:  to cadillac.com and complete a pre-order for model year 24 to be among the
Speaker 15:  first order. A model year 24, when available
Speaker 16:  Facebook is taking action to keep its platform safe. Their safety and
Speaker 16:  security teams are over 40,000 strong. That's
Speaker 16:  more than the size of the FBI. All for more meaningful connections.
Speaker 16:  Learn more about the work ahead@facebook.com forward slash
Speaker 16:  action.
Speaker 3:  Please note, in the second half of the episode, there are descriptions of
Speaker 3:  graphic acts of violence. If you want to skip this content, exact
Speaker 3:  times are given in the show notes,
Speaker 12:  India lives and dies by what we call forwards,
Speaker 12:  which is just people forwarding pieces of content,
Speaker 12:  pictures, videos, text to
Speaker 12:  each other on WhatsApp.
Speaker 3:  Prinav diction technology reporter for Buzzfeed news, he's
Speaker 3:  describing a popular WhatsApp feature, forwarded messages, content
Speaker 3:  you could easily send off to your friends or whatever groups you were a part
Speaker 3:  of.
Speaker 12:  You will be in like 50 different WhatsApp groups,
Speaker 12:  full of people. You may know like your friends and family,
Speaker 5:  And maybe you're also in a few groups with people. You don't know that well
Speaker 5:  like once for your neighborhood or school, and those can get pretty big filled
Speaker 5:  with hundreds of people.
Speaker 3:  Most forwarded content tends to be mundane, good mornings, weather
Speaker 3:  reports, recipes,
Speaker 5:  But as with anything that can go potentially viral, some forwards
Speaker 5:  aren't so benign
Speaker 3:  In late 2017, a wave of so-called stranger danger
Speaker 3:  videos spread across WhatsApp in India,
Speaker 17:  Stranger danger videos that went out said the following things look out
Speaker 17:  for your children. There are strangers in your area. They're coming to kidnap
Speaker 17:  your children and take their kidneys. That was the basic message in multiple
Speaker 17:  different vernacular languages across India,
Speaker 3:  Chicago, Angela Banaji is a professor of media culture and social change
Speaker 3:  at the London school of economics and political science. She researches the
Speaker 3:  spread of misinformation.
Speaker 5:  What struck Banaji was that these videos were carefully edited and tailored
Speaker 5:  to different ethnic groups, often depicting local children being seemingly
Speaker 5:  kidnapped or hurt by malicious outsiders.
Speaker 17:  So for example, you'd have a video of a killing of children
Speaker 17:  from  overlapping that you would have a voiceover
Speaker 17:  in, in Tamel or Telegu or Hindi saying something like this
Speaker 17:  is what people traffickers are doing in your area. Even though it was so
Speaker 17:  clear from the visuals that the children were not locals, but nevertheless,
Speaker 17:  this spread absolute panic.
Speaker 12:  So there was a call to arms at the end of each of these messages,
Speaker 12:  asking people to forward them and essentially, almost cajoling
Speaker 12:  them to take things into their own hands and do something about these people
Speaker 12:  who were kidnapping the children,
Speaker 5:  Pranav Dick shit reported on what happened with one of these stranger danger
Speaker 5:  videos went viral.
Speaker 12:  I ended up traveling to this
Speaker 12:  tiny Hamlet called Ryan powder,
Speaker 12:  which is in the Indian state of Maharashtra in the Western
Speaker 12:  part of the country, where just days before I
Speaker 12:  visited five, people had been lynched to death
Speaker 12:  in an extremely gruesome and brutal
Speaker 12:  manner. Basically a mob of 40 people,
Speaker 12:  stoned them and beat them to death inside the village council
Speaker 12:  office,
Speaker 3:  The video that spurred that violence, it was complete misinformation.
Speaker 3:  It featured an image of dead children. That was actually from the aftermath
Speaker 3:  of a chemical weapons attack in Syria.
Speaker 5:  But the fact that the information was being shared by people in WhatsApp
Speaker 5:  groups made it feel more trustworthy.
Speaker 12:  WhatsApp is your window to the world, and you
Speaker 12:  believe everything that, that you see there
Speaker 12:  because you know, oh, somebody I know sent me this, a
Speaker 12:  friend sent me this, somebody from my village sent me this. So
Speaker 12:  it must be true.
Speaker 3:  Banaji says, in addition to the trust factor, there was something else at
Speaker 3:  work here, an atmosphere of heightened religious and political
Speaker 3:  tensions,
Speaker 17:  As we were doing our research, it became evident that very quickly,
Speaker 17:  the discourse morphed from it's just any stranger in your area
Speaker 17:  to it's Muslim invaders, it's Muslim infiltrators,
Speaker 17:  it's people from across the border. It's Bangladeshis
Speaker 17:  it's Rohingya. So really quickly. So it began to look
Speaker 17:  like there had been a kind of plan all along. So
Speaker 17:  distrust and enmity against new people coming into particular
Speaker 17:  areas,
Speaker 5:  Regional, ethnic, and religious conflicts in India predate the
Speaker 5:  internet, but just as access to the internet started to grow the
Speaker 5:  political climate changed.
Speaker 17:  So in 2014, Narendra Modi and his
Speaker 17:  government came to power in India after a very sort of concerted
Speaker 17:  new media campaign in which they linked modern
Speaker 17:  technologies to that outreach to different voter
Speaker 17:  groups,
Speaker 3:  Modi ran on a successful digitally savvy campaign of political
Speaker 3:  populism vowing to put an end to corruption and India's elite ruling
Speaker 3:  class, his political party, the BJP
Speaker 3:  historically has had a Hindu nationalist message. One which was
Speaker 3:  amplified during the campaign. And after Modi came to power.
Speaker 17:  This ideology basically states that India is an
Speaker 17:  always has been and always will be a Hindu mainly in the
Speaker 17:  nation. That Hindus should be proud of their Hinduism and
Speaker 17:  should be strong.
Speaker 5:  Modi's critics say that some of the viral stranger danger rumors on
Speaker 5:  WhatsApp will not directly started by Modi or the BJP draw
Speaker 5:  on religious divisions at the core of the party's politics
Speaker 3:  From around 2017 to 2018, Banaji says over
Speaker 3:  30 people were killed across India by mobs incited, by
Speaker 3:  misinformation, spread on WhatsApp,
Speaker 5:  The violence was gaining more and more attention and pressure was mounting
Speaker 5:  on WhatsApp to confront the issue.
Speaker 3:  So in July, 2018, WhatsApp rolled out some product changes in India
Speaker 3:  to try to curb the sharing of incendiary videos and misinformation.
Speaker 3:  It was a little over a year since the first major lynching connected to WhatsApp
Speaker 3:  happened. Here's WhatsApp's will Cathcart.
Speaker 14:  We said, okay, how do we approach the problem? What are the things we can
Speaker 14:  do to help society deal with misinformation?
Speaker 5:  One of the first things WhatsApp did was to add friction, to sharing, to
Speaker 5:  slow down the speed at which viral content could spread.
Speaker 14:  We latched on to, well, how easy is it to send
Speaker 14:  information around and how easy is it to find alternative sources of
Speaker 14:  information? So forward limits have been the biggest change by far
Speaker 14:  we've made
Speaker 3:  In India. That meant a user could only forward something to five individuals
Speaker 3:  or group chats simultaneously down from the previous limit of 100
Speaker 3:  WhatsApp adopted similar rules. Worldwide six months later,
Speaker 5:  It also removed a feature that allowed for quick forwarding and eventually
Speaker 5:  replaced it with a Google search button to remind people to confirm something
Speaker 5:  as true before forwarding it.
Speaker 14:  We're not trying to jump in and say, Hey, what you just said is false. But
Speaker 14:  by changing the design of the product, we can make it easier to find out
Speaker 14:  the truth than it is to quickly forward something without thinking about
Speaker 14:  it.
Speaker 3:  These were all important changes, but to Prinav diction, the company could
Speaker 3:  have considered the consequences of WhatsApp's original product design sooner.
Speaker 12:  That's a true line with all Silicon valley products and
Speaker 12:  platforms that have expanded into countries like India
Speaker 12:  without putting in the necessary checks and balances
Speaker 12:  first, without doing groundwork, without actually
Speaker 12:  studying the country that they were expanding into,
Speaker 12:  they saw a billion people and they were like, great, here's
Speaker 12:  a billion people. Let's just give them our
Speaker 12:  product, our app, our service, and then let's see how they
Speaker 12:  use it
Speaker 3:  For Indian regulators though. These measures weren't enough after WhatsApp
Speaker 3:  implemented some of the changes, the ministry of electronics in it issued
Speaker 3:  a statement, demanding a do more.
Speaker 5:  The government called for WhatsApp to filter out harmful content from the
Speaker 5:  source to trace a chain of forwards back. So it could
Speaker 5:  track down who is spreading violence, inducing rumors.
Speaker 3:  There was one big problem though, end to end encryption.
Speaker 3:  One of WhatsApps core values evaluate stuck to all along. Was it,
Speaker 3:  it couldn't see or trace people's messages. Me keel. Paula is
Speaker 3:  with the tech website, media Nama,
Speaker 18:  Then WhatsApp was doing something about
Speaker 18:  misinformation in terms of trying to prevent it. It would
Speaker 18:  mean that they're reading the texts and that wouldn't be in tuned encryption.
Speaker 18:  So WhatsApp is in a very tricky situation where at
Speaker 18:  one level it can't do much except at a product level could try and
Speaker 18:  address misinformation.
Speaker 3:  But another way
Speaker 18:  There's really nothing that they can do specifically to address
Speaker 18:  misinformation on the platform.
Speaker 3:  Here's what WhatsApp can do according to will Cathcart.
Speaker 14:  Sometimes on the team we talk about it is solving a problem as an architect
Speaker 14:  would rather than as a law enforcement officer would, I mean, architects,
Speaker 14:  think a lot about the design of a building, the design of a city. What can
Speaker 14:  you do that will help create a safe environment or a safer environment over
Speaker 14:  time, which is very different than when there's been a problem, a specific
Speaker 14:  problem. How do you go deal with it? I think for some of these problems,
Speaker 14:  like at misinformation, the private nature of the product has
Speaker 14:  pushed us more towards architect type solutions because you have to
Speaker 14:  given how private
Speaker 3:  Architect type solutions like limiting message forwarding, but other
Speaker 3:  Mehta platforms like Facebook and Instagram, they can take the kind of law
Speaker 3:  enforcement approach. Cathcart referenced. They're able to moderate content
Speaker 3:  directly because they can see it
Speaker 5:  In 2021 India's ministry of electronics. And it issued
Speaker 5:  new rules requiring social media companies to identify the quote
Speaker 5:  first originator of information when requested by the government,
Speaker 5:  essentially a legal mandate for WhatsApp to break encryption
Speaker 3:  In response, WhatsApp filed a lawsuit to block the regulations, which is
Speaker 3:  still ongoing.
Speaker 14:  We're trying to make the point that undermining end to end
Speaker 14:  encryption is actually bad for the things governments care
Speaker 14:  about in any free democratic society. I
Speaker 14:  believe security people's private communications is really, really, really
Speaker 14:  important. One of the points we've been making is that it is ironic.
Speaker 14:  Like governments are never asking us to increase the security. We offer
Speaker 14:  people. They're always asking us to lower it.
Speaker 3:  The Indian government says it needs to root out the viral misinformation
Speaker 3:  that incites violence, but the experts we talked to were skeptical of Modi's
Speaker 3:  intentions. They worried that this could be a way for the government to crack
Speaker 3:  down on open political debate in the country, Chicago Tula Banaji.
Speaker 3:  Again,
Speaker 17:  If I believed in good faith that governments
Speaker 17:  really intended to trace the people who were sending the
Speaker 17:  murderous messages and that they were not going to
Speaker 17:  only take action against the people who were
Speaker 17:  organizing through democracy rallies. So the people who were in
Speaker 17:  some way critical of the government, then I might consider
Speaker 17:  the DN cryption as an answer.
Speaker 5:  So what is the end game? The Indian government has proven it can be serious
Speaker 5:  about social media regulation. It went so far as to ban Tik TOK in
Speaker 5:  2020, claiming that the app was harmful to the quote sovereignty and
Speaker 5:  integrity of India, basically because of its companies, Chinese
Speaker 5:  ownership,
Speaker 3:  But many observers believe that despite this precedent and the ongoing legal
Speaker 3:  challenges, WhatsApp, isn't going away, Prinav
Speaker 3:  diction. Again,
Speaker 12:  I don't paying even the government wants to be in a situation
Speaker 12:  where they ban WhatsApp, because it's like, what are you going to replace
Speaker 12:  it with? There's there's nothing else.
Speaker 5:  Ultimately WhatsApp is at a high stakes face off with the Indian government,
Speaker 5:  but unlike Tik TOK, WhatsApp is so entrenched in India that it
Speaker 5:  can't be as easily accessed
Speaker 3:  At this point, both WhatsApp and the Indian government need each other, but
Speaker 3:  they're each distrustful of the other's intentions,
Speaker 5:  Metas, other social networks. We've talked about this season, Instagram,
Speaker 5:  Facebook they're fighting to stay relevant. WhatsApp's fight is
Speaker 5:  different. And that it's coming from a place of strength, which is
Speaker 5:  maybe why will Cathcart has a point when he says, he believes that
Speaker 5:  WhatsApp's model is the future.
Speaker 14:  We've had this incredible growth and innovation period,
Speaker 14:  social media, and he called a town square social media. We're now seeing
Speaker 14:  this incredible growth in more private communication services like
Speaker 14:  WhatsApp and features like stories that have
Speaker 14:  ephemerality groups.
Speaker 3:  What Cathcart means when he refers to the town square social media model
Speaker 3:  is essentially the core Facebook. We all know, well, everyone shouting
Speaker 3:  everything into the public arena, guided by algorithms. That guess what we
Speaker 3:  want to hear most it's a square that's incredibly crowded,
Speaker 3:  messy, chaotic
Speaker 5:  WhatsApp's way is instead more private, trusted and simple.
Speaker 5:  And even though it doesn't make meta that much money, the trust users have
Speaker 5:  in WhatsApp is invaluable, but what's up still runs into that
Speaker 5:  recurring Facebook problem of sometimes enabling the ugliest
Speaker 5:  aspects of human behavior.
Speaker 3:  Throughout the course of this season, the tension we've been tracking and
Speaker 3:  each of Metis platforms comes down in a way to scale.
Speaker 3:  Zuckerberg has always wanted to connect the world to have as many
Speaker 3:  people as possible using his technologies. And he's been able
Speaker 3:  to do that, made the right acquisitions, set the right growth metrics.
Speaker 3:  But when it comes to considering the complexity of every culture, the
Speaker 3:  trade off of every product design Metta, hasn't always been able to
Speaker 3:  think ahead
Speaker 5:  Next week, Zuckerberg, grandest, boldest, vision to date
Speaker 5:  the metaverse and our season finale. What would it look like for
Speaker 5:  Zuckerberg to invent the next era of how we connect with each other
Speaker 3:  News clips from ABC news, CNN business, PBS news
Speaker 3:  weekend and channel nine Australia.
Speaker 5:  Land of the giants to Facebook Mehta disruption is a production of Recode,
Speaker 5:  the verge and the Vox media podcast network. Megan Kunin is our senior
Speaker 5:  producer. Although a Kemi, a lady suey is our producer production
Speaker 5:  support from Cynthia beta Baeza. Jolie Myers is our editor.
Speaker 3:  Richard Sima is our fact checker. Brandon McFarland compose the show's
Speaker 3:  theme and engineered this episode. Samantha Altman is Recode's
Speaker 3:  editor in chief.
Speaker 5:  Jay Castro. Nachis is deputy editor of the verge. Art Chung is our show runner
Speaker 5:  and a shot Kirwa is our executive producer. I'm Alex Heath,
Speaker 3:  And I'm Shereen Ghafari. If you like this episode as always, please
Speaker 3:  share it and follow the show by clicking the plus sign in your podcast app
Speaker 19:  With no fees or minimums banking with capital one is the easiest decision
Speaker 19:  in the history of decisions, even easier than deciding to listen to another
Speaker 19:  episode of your favorite podcast with no overdraft fees. Is it
Speaker 19:  even a decision that's banking? Re-imagined what's in your wallet
Speaker 19:  terms, supply, see capital one.com/bank capital one and a
Speaker 19:  member FTSE.