# Transcript
ID: 3d06d2c0-2060-11ed-ac0c-c99e024403fd
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Ford F-150 Lightning review, stress-testing earbuds, and a Galaxy foldable Q&A
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/80935878543716423/2349813676916028016/s93290-US-4134s-1660983254.mp3
Description: 02:33 - The Verge's David Pierce brings in deputy editor Dan Seifert, reviewer Allison Johnson, and managing editor Alex Cranz to answer Vergecast Hotline questions about Samsung's new Galaxy Z Fold 4 and Z Flip 4.
24:18 - Chris Welch returns to the show for more earbuds voice call testing, this time on the NYC ferry with the new Samsung Galaxy Buds 2 Pro and the Google Pixel Buds Pro.
41:18 - Nilay Patel shares his experience reviewing the Ford F-150 Lightning, and the troubles with its touchscreen control panel.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Disabled
Speaker 3:  Welcome to the Vergecast. The flagship podcast of loud engine sounds.
Speaker 3:  I'm your friend, David Pierce. And I am currently sitting in my basement
Speaker 3:  playing Mario tennis on my Nintendo switch on my television,
Speaker 3:  which doesn't sound like a big deal, but is actually a very big deal to me.
Speaker 3:  You might have heard me complaining on the show a couple of weeks ago about
Speaker 3:  all of Nintendo's stupid proprietary docs and cables for the
Speaker 3:  switch. And a bunch of you reached out to recommend that I buy one product,
Speaker 3:  the Yankee janky, I don't know. It's GE N K I, and
Speaker 3:  the product is called the convert doc. I bought one. It works perfectly,
Speaker 3:  and I'm very grateful to everyone who recommended it. Anyway, we have a great
Speaker 3:  show for you today. We're gonna talk about Samsung. We're gonna answer a
Speaker 3:  bunch of your questions about Samsung's new phones, the future of flip phones
Speaker 3:  and what it's like to be at green bubble. We're also gonna continue our testing
Speaker 3:  of wireless earbuds to see if we have a new best choice for voice
Speaker 3:  calls and zoom meetings. And NELI patella is gonna come on and tell us about
Speaker 3:  all of his adventures with the Ford F-150 lightning, all that's coming in
Speaker 3:  just a sec. I just have to win this tournament real quick fun fact about
Speaker 3:  me. I'm not good at most video games, but I'm really good
Speaker 3:  at Mario tennis. If you ever wanna play, get at me, this is the verge cast.
Speaker 3:  See you in a second.
Speaker 4:  This episode was sponsored by Salesforce. Pivot is coming to TV,
Speaker 4:  sort of with the help of Salesforce. Plus pivot listeners
Speaker 4:  will now be able to watch four video segments of our podcast every week,
Speaker 4:  exclusively on their platform, but that's not all Salesforce
Speaker 4:  plus is a free streaming service that provides live experiences,
Speaker 4:  original series podcast on other programming to help inspire business leaders
Speaker 4:  all around the globe. Sign up today to watch pivot and more
Speaker 4:  exclusive content free at salesforce.com/plus that
Speaker 4:  salesforce.com/pl S.
Speaker 3:  This episode is brought to you by Clavio, a company that's reinventing email
Speaker 3:  and text marketing for e-commerce business owners. Clavio puts creators
Speaker 3:  makers and doers back in control of their marketing with an easy to use
Speaker 3:  data-driven platform. That does exactly what it says it can do. Clavio
Speaker 3:  puts creators makers and doers back in control of their marketing with an
Speaker 3:  easy to use data-driven platform. That does exactly what it says. It can
Speaker 3:  do. Deliver a simple, personalized email and text messages to your customers
Speaker 3:  at just the right moment, helping you make more money with Clavio.
Speaker 3:  You'll build better relationships with your customers by engaging and exciting
Speaker 3:  them get started for
Speaker 3:  free@klaviyo.com slash Fox
Speaker 3:  today.
Speaker 3:  Welcome back last week, as you probably already know if you've listened to
Speaker 3:  this show, Samsung held yet another unpacked event and launched
Speaker 3:  a bunch of new stuff.
Speaker 5:  We wanted you to be able to imagine something different, an entirely
Speaker 5:  new way to think about your smartphone.
Speaker 3:  There's the galaxy Z fold four, which folds together like a
Speaker 3:  hotdog bun. And then there's the Z flip for which flips closed like
Speaker 3:  a hamburger bun, plus some headphones and watches and all sorts of other
Speaker 3:  stuff. It's a lot to sort through. So we asked you to send in
Speaker 3:  whatever questions you had about the phones in particular to our Vergecast
Speaker 3:  hotline, which the number don't forget is eight, six, six verge. One one,
Speaker 3:  call us, ask us all your questions in this case. We got some great ones.
Speaker 3:  Thanks again to everyone who called in. It's super fun hearing from you.
Speaker 3:  Please keep calling to answer all of your questions about Samsung, which
Speaker 3:  were weird and all over the place. I brought in a panel of verge experts,
Speaker 3:  deputy editor, Dan Seifert.
Speaker 6:  Hello,
Speaker 3:  Reviewer Allison Johnson. Hello and managing editor, Alex. Crans
Speaker 3:  hello. I think we're gonna get through a bunch of questions, cuz a lot of
Speaker 3:  people have a lot of thoughts about Samsung. Let's start. I think our first
Speaker 3:  question is from Leo.
Speaker 7:  Hi David and merge crew. This is Leo calling from beautiful west Michigan.
Speaker 7:  I'm one of those mini iPhone mini or other
Speaker 7:  compact phone fans. There are dozens of us out there who like small phones
Speaker 7:  currently rocking a way too big pale six. And I'm wondering
Speaker 7:  is the Z flip four. Finally, what I'm looking for in a small Android phone,
Speaker 7:  I really miss my Sony experience Z three compact. And I don't know if I wanna
Speaker 7:  switch to the iPhone. So I'd love to hear your thoughts about size and if
Speaker 7:  not, Z four flip what are my options out there for small phones? And
Speaker 7:  do you hear any rumblings and anything coming down the bike? Thanks.
Speaker 3:  Okay. First of all, I really miss my Sony experience. Z three
Speaker 3:  compact is a sentence you will only hear on the verge cast. Yes. So congratulations,
Speaker 3:  correct to all of us, but also I really like this idea because it had never
Speaker 3:  really clicked for me that like maybe this new run of flip phones is like
Speaker 3:  the small smartphones we were promised. I think this is very interesting
Speaker 3:  theory, Dan, you're making a face. Why are you making a face?
Speaker 6:  I hate to pour cold water on that. But it's
Speaker 6:  what I do. As someone who's used a folding
Speaker 6:  flip phone, I'm here to tell you that they are small when they're closed
Speaker 6:  and fit in your pocket. Very nice. So if that's what you want from a small
Speaker 6:  phone is like to fit in more places easier, whether it's your pocket
Speaker 6:  or purse or a bag or whatever. Yes, they do that. But when I
Speaker 6:  think of a small phone, I think of, I can use this easily in one hand. And
Speaker 6:  that is where they do not work well because it takes two hands to open up
Speaker 6:  the flip every single time, unless you wanna like jam your thumb under there
Speaker 6:  and gouge the screen as you do it, don't recommend doing that with your thousand
Speaker 6:  dollars phone. And then when you open it, it's a 6.8 inch screen.
Speaker 6:  It's a big phone. So it's not like it's like easily reachable with one hand,
Speaker 6:  like to scroll down from the top or reach across with your thumb or anything
Speaker 6:  like that. It becomes a big phone. So in my mind,
Speaker 6:  no, these do not solve the small phone desire because they are not easily
Speaker 6:  used by one hand. But I think Allison probably
Speaker 6:  has a suggestion for you.
Speaker 8:  I sure do. Let's
Speaker 3:  Hear it.
Speaker 8:  No, this is the little kind of, I guess dark horse of
Speaker 8:  2022, the ASU Xeno nine.
Speaker 8:  I have used it. I haven't fully reviewed it yet because a couple of
Speaker 8:  things have come up, but it's a little one. It's a compact is like
Speaker 8:  a truly compact Android flagship.
Speaker 8:  It's got top of the line processor, really interesting camera
Speaker 8:  system where the stabilization like moves the whole camera
Speaker 8:  around. There's just a lot of cool stuff about it. It's like IP
Speaker 8:  68. There's a headphone Jack. I hold it in my hand and I'm just like,
Speaker 8:  this just feels right.
Speaker 3:  We establish on this show very recently, Allison, that 6.1 inches
Speaker 3:  is the correct size for a smaller smartphone.
Speaker 3:  Does the Zen phone pass the test?
Speaker 8:  So here's the asterisks on that 6.1 inches
Speaker 8:  is my, like I concede that not everybody wants a small phone.
Speaker 8:  Like I want a small phone. Everybody else seems to want a giant phone. So
Speaker 8:  I think like 6.1 inches is where we can all kind of like agree and
Speaker 8:  that's okay. I review a lot of Android phones. So
Speaker 8:  as my team has pointed out my perception on what a
Speaker 8:  small phone is, has been skewed. I took the
Speaker 8:  pixel six, a out of the box. I was like, look a tiny phone. And
Speaker 8:  everybody quickly corrected me that it was not tiny.
Speaker 8:  So yeah, I don't, I think I'm an unreliable narrator here. I like a small
Speaker 8:  phone. I'm desensitized to giant phones.
Speaker 3:  So it seems to me like the, the true answer for Leo here is like, if, if
Speaker 3:  what you want in a small phone is that it is like smaller and will fit in
Speaker 3:  your pockets more easily. Congratulations. The flip phone is great. If what
Speaker 3:  you want is like an actually small phone that you can hold in your hand either
Speaker 3:  by the Zen phone or just get over it and come live in the large phone world
Speaker 3:  in which we unfortunately all exist. Yeah. Which I feel like is the right
Speaker 3:  answer. Like if you want a small phone, just stop wanting a small phone,
Speaker 3:  feels like the correct way to live your life going forward.
Speaker 8:  I don't know if that's how I would put it. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  Look at the Zen phone nine. It's lovely.
Speaker 3:  I like it. Okay. So next up we have another call about
Speaker 3:  screen size actually from, I believe a caller from Aurora, Illinois.
Speaker 9:  Hey, I have a question about folding phones and video aspect ratios.
Speaker 9:  If you're watching YouTube and standard, like 16 by nine,
Speaker 9:  how much bigger is that video actually getting, when you go from the
Speaker 9:  outside screen on like a Samsung folding phone to the inside
Speaker 9:  screen, it seems like a lot of that would just be extra letter boxing
Speaker 9:  and then just like marginally bigger video itself. All right.
Speaker 9:  Thanks. Have a great day.
Speaker 3:  I believe I am the person on this podcast currently, who has used folding
Speaker 3:  phones, the least. So you all tell me, I think this is a
Speaker 3:  perfectly fair question though. Like what if you're just looking at a 16,
Speaker 3:  nine video on this, you know, giant ass internal display of the fold.
Speaker 3:  What are you really getting?
Speaker 6:  You do get a bigger video picture and yes,
Speaker 6:  you do get black bars above and be, and below it, especially if you turn
Speaker 6:  the phone into landscape mode and you're full screen that YouTube video,
Speaker 6:  the open fold phone is roughly four by three aspect
Speaker 6:  ratio. You know, there's, it's, it's not exact, but it's close enough. So,
Speaker 6:  so you will get black bars above and below it. However, within those black
Speaker 6:  bars, you still get a large video. Like I can put a
Speaker 6:  pixel six pro above the video and it's like the same size.
Speaker 6:  So you, when you full screen it, you are getting like a big, big phone
Speaker 6:  size video when you're playing it. What's interesting about it though,
Speaker 6:  is if you don't full screen it, then you get like all this extra UI
Speaker 6:  that you don't get on normal phones, cuz it behaves like a tablet UI. So
Speaker 6:  you get the right rail of suggested videos. You get your
Speaker 6:  descriptions, your comments and things like that. So like it, it depends
Speaker 6:  on like where you want to use this extra space that you have, but you can
Speaker 6:  make more use of it than if you just had a standard, a slab
Speaker 6:  smartphone with a giant screen on it.
Speaker 10:  Also 16 by nine is like a very popular aspect ratio.
Speaker 10:  It's hugely popular on YouTube, et cetera. But it's not the only one
Speaker 10:  all of TV up until what like the mid two thousands was in four by three.
Speaker 10:  Some movies were in four by three, like you've got even narrower
Speaker 10:  aspect ratios, like 1.8, five and
Speaker 10:  2.39 and, and all of these super cinematic ones. So like there's a lot
Speaker 10:  of different types of screens. And I think we saw like Microsoft even saying
Speaker 10:  four by three is actually a really good display size because it's gonna
Speaker 10:  give you all of those different ones feeling kind of nice.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I think the best way to think about it is like if you've ever watched
Speaker 6:  video on an iPad, it's gonna be a very similar experience to that. You're
Speaker 6:  going to have black bars above and be below it. Those will change in size
Speaker 6:  depending on what aspect ratio it is. But this is very much like having an
Speaker 6:  iPad mini that folds in half. And so all of the, you know,
Speaker 6:  compromises that you get with that, but all the benefits that you get to.
Speaker 3:  Okay. Allison, what have you found in, in testing the Z fold for so far?
Speaker 3:  Are you like a full screener or do you do the like big phone size video
Speaker 3:  plus all the interface around it?
Speaker 8:  It's kind of dependent on like how I wanna be sitting. Like
Speaker 8:  sometimes you wanna lay down and, and not hold your phone.
Speaker 8:  So I think that's the, like I've used this phone
Speaker 8:  more for us. Like it is a truly small screen experience
Speaker 8:  having it on like the cover screen, but you can prop that up
Speaker 8:  and play video. You can have it open in the L shape
Speaker 8:  and watch a teeny tiny video that way, which kind of
Speaker 8:  stinks. But you don't have to use your hands
Speaker 3:  Somewhere. Someone on Samsung's marketing team is so happy. The amount
Speaker 3:  of time they have spent being like, look, you can put this thing on a table,
Speaker 3:  folded into the L shape and watch videos. And I guess it's good. Like who
Speaker 3:  knew it was worth it?
Speaker 8:  I like propped it up like a book, I guess, where it's like
Speaker 8:  open. And I had a, I had TikTok playing on one side, which
Speaker 8:  that even kind of works so many different things you can do with it.
Speaker 3:  So you open it up, you go split screen TikTok on one side reels on the
Speaker 3:  other side and just infinite doom scrolling forever
Speaker 8:  Fight. The two of you fight it out.
Speaker 3:  That was helpful. Thank you all. Let's move on to the next one. A lot of
Speaker 3:  people have questions about screen size, which I guess is fair. This is what
Speaker 3:  folding phones are all about. Our next question comes from Kevin,
Speaker 11:  Big H cast. What is a computer? My name is Kevin. And my question is with
Speaker 11:  the Z three, there are already issues with things like the Google feed
Speaker 11:  and YouTube, the YouTube ops, basically having side column,
Speaker 11:  unless you were turned into what I guess essentially a landscape mode. So
Speaker 11:  now that they've made the screen shorter on the D 44, doesn't that mean
Speaker 11:  that that landscape real estate has been made smaller? Like, are those apps
Speaker 11:  gonna populate properly? They already had issues. Yeah. Let me know. Thanks
Speaker 3:  Allison. I really wanna know what you've seen so far, cuz I think this is
Speaker 3:  a thing Samsung has been tinkering with over the last few years
Speaker 3:  with like how apps should render at different screen sizes. And when you
Speaker 3:  open the phone versus when you turn the phone versus when it's closed, like
Speaker 3:  has Samsung figured out how apps are supposed to look on all these screens
Speaker 3:  yet?
Speaker 8:  I mean, I think they've gotten pretty close to me. Like the
Speaker 8:  difference is, you know, with the phone closed using the cover screen,
Speaker 8:  does it feel like a normal phone? Does it feel just super
Speaker 8:  thin and weird and claustrophobic? It's all right.
Speaker 8:  Like it's good enough. I don't think the screen size difference
Speaker 8:  is big enough to make any kind of big difference in, in how much
Speaker 8:  video, you know, and how things render or like how
Speaker 8:  much content you can get on the screen. It's just a matter of like, is it
Speaker 8:  a little more comfortable to use? And for me it's been the first
Speaker 8:  day of using it. I was like, I feel like I'm aiming at these really tiny,
Speaker 8:  you know, keys on the keyboard, but I got used to it after about a day. And
Speaker 8:  I think it's, it's like 90% there to where it's a big enough screen that
Speaker 8:  you feel comfortable being like, yes, this is my phone.
Speaker 3:  Does it feel less like a TV remote now? Cuz that was always my issue with
Speaker 3:  the early folds. Was that when you, when they were closed, it felt like you
Speaker 3:  were holding this like impossibly long TV remote.
Speaker 8:  It's still a little remote ish. Okay. Almost there. But you, you still
Speaker 8:  get that vibe
Speaker 3:  And Dan Android is supposed to solve this at some point, right? Like isn't
Speaker 3:  Android 12 L going to be the magic thing that fixes everything for us.
Speaker 6:  The fold for does run 12 L or it's based on Android, 12 L with
Speaker 6:  Samsung optimizations on top of it. So it does have that. What 12
Speaker 6:  L really does though is really kind of hard to say. We've only seen
Speaker 6:  12 L on a big tablet and then this fold four.
Speaker 6:  So we haven't seen it on a lot of places yet. Mostly what you see it on in
Speaker 6:  the fold. Four is the little task bar at the bottom. Where on the fold
Speaker 6:  three or the earlier models you had like a task bar. You could like
Speaker 6:  swipe in from the side of the phone to launch apps from now, it's gonna be
Speaker 6:  at the bottom, similar to how Mac S and windows work and things like that.
Speaker 6:  And I think that like, there are a couple of things that Samsung does to
Speaker 6:  how you decide how you want the screen to render apps.
Speaker 6:  Like you can go into settings and adjust the screen zoom. So you can say,
Speaker 6:  give me less zoom. So I fit more stuff on the screen or gimme
Speaker 6:  bigger zoom. So I got bigger icons and it's easier to read and stuff like
Speaker 6:  that. And that will impact how certain apps render, because that will adjust
Speaker 6:  whether an app says, oh, I'm displayed on a tablet and I'm gonna show my
Speaker 6:  tablet interface or, oh, I'm displayed on a phone and I'm just gonna be a
Speaker 6:  big phone interface. So that can like tweak things a little bit. I think
Speaker 6:  that the difference between the fold three and the fold four is really not
Speaker 6:  that significant. Even though like on a spec sheet, the aspect ratio is
Speaker 6:  slightly different and the screen size measures slightly different. The difference
Speaker 6:  in practice is not that huge. So like an app is likely going to
Speaker 6:  display exactly the same on the fold four, as it did on the fold
Speaker 6:  three. And we kind of like did a little bit of comparisons. We know that
Speaker 6:  YouTube definitely does. Like it's exact same way on the fold three in the
Speaker 6:  fold four. So there's like, you know, some tweaks you can make to it and
Speaker 6:  things like that. And it's really gonna very depend on what apps that you
Speaker 6:  are really into famously. The one app that really does
Speaker 6:  not like foldable phones is shocker, Instagram. And the way
Speaker 6:  that it opens on the inside screens is it opens in a,
Speaker 6:  essentially a letter box format. So Samsung has like built
Speaker 6:  software to, to handle Instagram. So you can see Instagram without
Speaker 6:  it like zooming in and cropping out everything really horribly. But
Speaker 6:  like that was Samsung fixing it because Android does not really fix it.
Speaker 3:  So before we move on, the thing I have to know is how zoomed in is your phone,
Speaker 3:  Dan, for anyone who is not familiar with Dan seafer uses bigger
Speaker 3:  font on his computer than almost anyone else. I know. So I just feel like,
Speaker 3:  I just need to know like, are we, are we a right in the middle guy? Are we
Speaker 3:  a zoom all the way in guy? Like where are we at?
Speaker 6:  I was tinkering with it today, actually. Cuz of course I also
Speaker 6:  tinker, I've got the zoom set all the way to the plus and then
Speaker 6:  I make the font smaller. I tried it the other way so that I could have like
Speaker 6:  more space, but just make the font bigger. And that made like the interface
Speaker 6:  elements all weird.
Speaker 3:  So like big UI, small text.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I think it's actually the default UI size cuz there's two, at least
Speaker 6:  on the fold three, there are two settings there's default and then more space.
Speaker 6:  And so I've got it set on default and then I just take the font back one
Speaker 6:  notch so that I can fit more stuff in the screen. All right. And then just
Speaker 6:  hold it closer to my face, I guess
Speaker 3:  Just ramp up the prescription on your glasses just real quick.
Speaker 3:  Alright, let's move on. So next up we have a question from Justin.
Speaker 12:  Hey David, it's Justin, Jay Mitch, and your Twitter DMS. I
Speaker 12:  wanted to know if the new Z flip four has USBC
Speaker 12:  display port out or USB HD I over USBC
Speaker 12:  so that I could do decks or just mirror my Android phone to my
Speaker 12:  AR headset so that I can watch movies in bed without bothering my wife.
Speaker 12:  That is my dream set up a small foldable device that I can put
Speaker 12:  in my pocket and then plug into a huge display and none of the other
Speaker 12:  flips had it. And I was waiting to see if they would announce it. And I
Speaker 12:  didn't say anything at the event and I can't find any information on this
Speaker 12:  anywhere. So I would appreciate an answer to this question. Thanks man.
Speaker 6:  To address Justin's question. We can confirm that the flip forward
Speaker 6:  does not support Samsung decks and we are very certain
Speaker 6:  that it does not support video out over U SBC, but we'll be testing
Speaker 6:  that in the future. So stay tuned, but
Speaker 6:  TLDR, I would not expect it to do what you're hoping it to do. Unfortunately.
Speaker 3:  Any idea why not Samsung has made this big deal about Dex for so long. This
Speaker 3:  is an odd line to pick, to not put it on.
Speaker 6:  So this is pure speculation here, but I think that when you are running
Speaker 6:  like video out over USBC on a phone and if you're running
Speaker 6:  a desktop environment like Dex or things like that, it's very taxing on the
Speaker 6:  phone's processor and it's taxing on the thermal system. And the one thing
Speaker 6:  with the flip phones is that they do not have as good thermal management
Speaker 6:  as the larger devices or the other devices. And so they will throttle their
Speaker 6:  processor faster than say a fold will or an S 22 ultra will.
Speaker 6:  And I know, I think PC mag did some side by side benchmark comparisons
Speaker 6:  with temperatures and everything like that. And they noticed that the flip
Speaker 6:  four was throttling faster than the fold four did. So that would be my guess
Speaker 6:  is it's a performance management system thing, limitation or
Speaker 6:  whatever, but it'd be it. Like I think his idea is really cool and
Speaker 6:  like, it'd be like a really cool idea if it did work
Speaker 3:  Just to confirm really quickly, the fold does support
Speaker 3:  decks. Right. And all the other H D I out stuff.
Speaker 6:  That's correct. Yep. Yeah. So the fold is like the full computer in your
Speaker 6:  pocket Delio, but unfortunately the flip does not.
Speaker 3:  Justin, when you figure this out report back, we, we wanna know. All right,
Speaker 3:  we have one more question before we go here. It is slightly different, but
Speaker 3:  we're gonna answer it anyway. This is from Gordon.
Speaker 13:  This is Gordon. Thanks guys. I have not received
Speaker 13:  a text back from the last two women to give me their phone number. Obviously
Speaker 13:  a man Android user. Is it time for me to just give up on the fight
Speaker 13:  for independent text messaging platforms and buy into an
Speaker 13:  iPhone? I wish I could say I'm not this desperate, but I am
Speaker 13:  definitely desperate enough to pay $3,000 to migrate
Speaker 13:  my entire digital life. Thanks.
Speaker 10:  I got this. Okay,
Speaker 3:  Alex, go,
Speaker 10:  Hey Gordon. I hate to tell you this, but it is the green bubbles.
Speaker 10:  I, I could confirmed this.
Speaker 3:  Wow.
Speaker 10:  Not with Gordon specifically. I had a friend and he was, he was having
Speaker 10:  trouble. He had at least two women say to him, it's your green
Speaker 10:  bubbles. I don't want them in my life. It could be the green
Speaker 10:  bubbles. It could be a wide variety of things going on.
Speaker 10:  Are you looking at the green bubbles on your phone more than you are talking
Speaker 10:  to the woman across from you? That could be part of the problem, but no,
Speaker 10:  I think it's okay to migrate because iOS is superior in the
Speaker 10:  United States and will help you a lot more than, than
Speaker 10:  Android will. But I think also if you love your Android
Speaker 10:  phone and a lot of people do at least like one person on the
Speaker 10:  Vergecast loves their Android phone. If you love your Android phone,
Speaker 10:  keep it because out there somewhere as a woman who loves her
Speaker 10:  Android phone and when you text her and you pop up that green bubble and
Speaker 10:  you're like, oh, here it goes. Here's another one she's gonna reject me
Speaker 10:  cuz of this green bubble, she's gonna go, oh my God, there's another one
Speaker 10:  like me. And that that's like a love connection right there for you.
Speaker 10:  So like honestly I think you should keep it. Don't don't change your
Speaker 10:  devices to, to try to get with a girl. Just focus on being really
Speaker 10:  awesome and cool. Which it sounds like you are and keep holding out for
Speaker 10:  that green bubble girl. Cuz I swear she's out there somewhere.
Speaker 3:  I just can't believe that we let you get through a whole thing after you
Speaker 3:  said, as everybody knows, iOS is just better than Android in the us.
Speaker 3:  That's just like a thing you said. And we're just, we're just cool with that.
Speaker 3:  Apparently
Speaker 10:  I'm out here speaking the truth, David, I'm just speaking truth to power
Speaker 10:  and the power is Android. I don't know what's going on.
Speaker 3:  Listen, I'm a blue bubble and my wife is a green bubble and we
Speaker 3:  mostly get along. Okay. Aww.
Speaker 10:  That's inspiring.
Speaker 3:  But here's what I wonder is, is the correct answer to just give them some
Speaker 3:  other, like, should you give them your Instagram handle? Should you just
Speaker 3:  be like, oh no, I use signal and then they'll be like, oh wow, such great
Speaker 3:  personal data policies and then fall in love with you even harder. Like like
Speaker 3:  is there a better answer than your cell phone number out there that we can
Speaker 3:  give?
Speaker 10:  Like I only use signal because I, I care about your privacy and
Speaker 10:  mine.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, exactly. Our love is end to end encrypted. It's like done lock it down
Speaker 10:  End to end encryption. Woo.
Speaker 3:  All right, Gordon, let us know how it goes. We're all rooting for you Dan,
Speaker 3:  Alex, Allison. Thank you. I appreciate it. Thank you. Thank you.
Speaker 3:  We are gonna take a break and then we will be back to continue our testing
Speaker 3:  of earbud microphones because I just need to know if I bought the right
Speaker 3:  headphones. We'll be right back.
Speaker 3:  If you run an e-commerce business, this ad might change everything for you.
Speaker 3:  If you've ever scrolled wistfully through incredible marketing emails and
Speaker 3:  texts from major brands and wondered quietly allowed, what sort of magic
Speaker 3:  dusts are these guys sprinkling over their communications? Here's a secret.
Speaker 3:  They probably use Clavio. Clavio takes the mystery out of email and SMS
Speaker 3:  marketing offering all you marketers, entrepreneurs and creators out there.
Speaker 3:  The data driven automated platform. You need to create authentic relationships
Speaker 3:  with your customers. Like a top tier brand, say goodbye to blasting vague
Speaker 3:  newsletters, to an entire massive faceless people. Combine your customer
Speaker 3:  data with a smart marketing platform like Clavio and you'll engage every
Speaker 3:  customer one on one, like they're your only customer engagement like this
Speaker 3:  builds valuable relationships that make you money. If you're the creator
Speaker 3:  of an e-commerce brand, you need a platform that hustles as hard as you do.
Speaker 3:  Clavio unlocks the power of your e-commerce data. So you can personalize
Speaker 3:  and automate messages that keep customers coming back to get started with
Speaker 3:  a free trial of Clavio visit clavio.com/v
Speaker 3:  that's K L a V I Y
Speaker 3:  o.com/fox.
Speaker 14:  Big wireless companies have used confusing contracts to hide fees and
Speaker 14:  fine print and charge you more money for way too long. We've all seen it
Speaker 14:  happen. You sign up for a plan at the advertised price and then when you
Speaker 14:  get the bill, it's completely different. This is one of the reasons I signed
Speaker 14:  up for mint mobile. It offers premium wireless starting at just 15 bucks
Speaker 14:  a month. And I figured there would be some hidden fees, but I, I read the
Speaker 14:  contract twice and there aren't any and here's why mint mobile cut out
Speaker 14:  the one middle man, big wireless still relies on in person retail.
Speaker 14:  Every plan gets you high speed data delivered on the nation's largest 5g
Speaker 14:  network. Plus unlimited talk and text. Keep your phone, keep your
Speaker 14:  number, just change your provider to mint OAL to get your new wireless
Speaker 14:  plan for just 15 bucks a month and get the plan shipped to your door for
Speaker 14:  free. Go to mint, mobile.com/verge that's mint,
Speaker 14:  mobile.com/verge. Cut your wireless bill to 15 bucks
Speaker 14:  a month@mintmobile.com slash verge.
Speaker 3:  Welcome back a couple of months ago on this show, I found myself with
Speaker 3:  a question which wireless earbuds should I buy to use for phone calls,
Speaker 3:  zoom meetings and all the voice dictation and chattering
Speaker 3:  with Siri. I do all day. We talk a lot about sound quality with
Speaker 3:  headphones, but I really just wanted to know about microphones. So I
Speaker 3:  sent verge of you or Chris Welch, who is a good sport to a coffee shop to
Speaker 3:  test out a bunch of different wireless earbuds to see how they sound
Speaker 3:  specifically for voice calls,
Speaker 15:  The outdoor seating. There are several people out here. There's music playing
Speaker 15:  overhead. Someone's like call directly next to me. So
Speaker 3:  The pretty clear winners of that test were the apple AirPods pro and the
Speaker 3:  Sony link buds, which both had the clearest detail in the voice
Speaker 3:  and took out a lot of background noise. I actually ended up buying a pair
Speaker 3:  of link buds after that test. And I have to say, I love them so far,
Speaker 3:  but I'm always looking for something better. And since that test two new
Speaker 3:  earbuds have come out. There's the Samsung galaxy buds to pro, which came
Speaker 3:  out at that unpacked event last week and the Google pixel buds pro. So
Speaker 3:  now obviously we have to put those new earbuds to the test, along with the
Speaker 3:  winners of the last round to see who is the current champion,
Speaker 3:  but we wanted to up the anti with the test this time. So we actually put
Speaker 3:  Chris on a boat. Like I said, he's a good sport. The New York city fairy
Speaker 3:  to be exact, which is a very noisy and chaotic part of the city. It has
Speaker 3:  engines, waves, people talking helicopters, wind.
Speaker 3:  It should be terrible for headphones. So let's see how this goes. Chris Welch.
Speaker 3:  Hello?
Speaker 16:  Hello. It's good to be back.
Speaker 3:  Tell me where you are right now. Your, your location and setup is deeply
Speaker 3:  hilarious to me at this moment, which we force you to do. And I'm sorry.
Speaker 3:  So tell, tell us where you are.
Speaker 16:  We are down at the wall street ferry waiting to get on a boat. Wanna
Speaker 16:  come up with a new way of testing earbuds. That's not the everyday, just
Speaker 16:  out on the street stress test. So we thought we'd go on the water
Speaker 16:  on a nice day. It's finally pleasant out in New York. Again, there's a helicopter
Speaker 16:  overhead. So we've got all sorts of
Speaker 3:  Things happening here. Yeah. We came outta the coffee shop test being like,
Speaker 3:  okay, this was good. But they all did like relatively, well, my big takeaway
Speaker 3:  was like great job earbuds. So it was like, okay, we need to like, let let's
Speaker 3:  break these things and see how we do. Okay. So which earbuds are we using
Speaker 3:  right now? How are we doing
Speaker 15:  Right now? These are the AirPods pro the standard bear for the
Speaker 15:  iPhone at least. And usually pretty competent, pretty good.
Speaker 3:  There's more sort of low level rumble than we had the last time where it
Speaker 3:  like it, it sounds like somebody is sort of breathing into the headphone.
Speaker 3:  Okay. So this is not great noise cancellation of the announcements
Speaker 3:  there. I was much more impressed at the coffee shop. This is rough times.
Speaker 15:  Okay. We're getting on the boat.
Speaker 3:  All right. It's bow time.
Speaker 18:  East river.
Speaker 18:  Yeah, the verge,
Speaker 15:  The guy at the ferry just said, hello. He wants to work at the
Speaker 15:  verge. We got a fan here. So that's good.
Speaker 3:  We didn't even plant that. That was amazing. While we're still here,
Speaker 3:  let's switch to, let's do the link buds real fast.
Speaker 17:  Bluetooth can. Now we're on the link buds. Hopefully they sound
Speaker 17:  as, as much. They sound love Luke.
Speaker 3:  This sounds like I can hear the noise cancellation happening all the time.
Speaker 17:  I can hear you pretty clearly. The knees are open earbuds. So I also hear
Speaker 17:  everything else.
Speaker 3:  I went back and forth on the open ear thing a lot. And I would assume that
Speaker 3:  as you get like onto the ferry, I'm, you're not gonna be able to hear me
Speaker 3:  at all when we try to do this.
Speaker 17:  Yeah. So we'll see how the engine roar treats these.
Speaker 3:  Your voice sounds better than you did on the AirPods, but it's slightly less
Speaker 3:  pleasant just because it's, it's like there's clearly way more processing
Speaker 3:  going on.
Speaker 17:  It's more gated.
Speaker 3:  Whereas I think the AirPods do a, they do an okay job of kind of splitting
Speaker 3:  the difference. That's why I'm curious to hear on the ferry, how hard these
Speaker 3:  things go and what it ends up sounding like, but just in terms of like raw
Speaker 3:  background noise, I'm getting much less from you now than I was with the
Speaker 3:  AirPods, which is interesting.
Speaker 17:  Good job Sony and the one.
Speaker 3:  All right. Do you think you can switch one more time before you get on the
Speaker 3:  ferry? How much time do we have? Sure.
Speaker 17:  We can give it a go. Should we do the galaxy buds next or the pixel
Speaker 3:  Buds? Let's do the galaxy. They're the newest ones.
Speaker 17:  These are the brand new galaxy buds to pro
Speaker 17:  just announced at the event alongside the whole four flip four,
Speaker 17:  $230, I believe. And so far I'm a fan of a sound
Speaker 17:  quality. This is my first rail call test. So we're
Speaker 17:  putting them through the ringer.
Speaker 3:  You sound bad. Yeah. Like I can hear you. I can understand everything you're
Speaker 3:  saying, but it sounds like you're sort of yelling at me like through a
Speaker 3:  pillow, if that makes sense. Okay. But I can hear everything you're saying.
Speaker 3:  And the noise cancellation is really good. I'm hardly hearing any background
Speaker 3:  noise at all. You just don't sound very good.
Speaker 17:  Yeah. There are people shouting. There's a guy in the bike riding around.
Speaker 17:  There's a lot of background noise. So if you're not hearing any of that,
Speaker 17:  that's good. But the pillow thing is less than ideal.
Speaker 3:  I will say this is the worst. One of the three we've tested so far. Okay.
Speaker 3:  But it's still it's again. It's kinda like where we were the last time. It's
Speaker 3:  like, it works. I wouldn't recommend like calling the president of the
Speaker 3:  United States from these headphones in this situation. But like it's, it's
Speaker 3:  fine. We're we'll it'll do the job.
Speaker 17:  Okay. Well, we're getting aboard the boat right now. So it's time to change
Speaker 17:  the scenery and the sound and see how we make out.
Speaker 19:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  All right. We are, are now aboard the ferry and like, I can tell it got noisier,
Speaker 3:  but it's like, it's not particularly painful for me to listen to still.
Speaker 17:  Yeah. That's impressive. Cause in real life here, like we're right next
Speaker 17:  to the engine and it's just quite intense so I can hear you
Speaker 17:  still, but it's definitely just a constant roar.
Speaker 17:  So if you're not hearing that too badly, then all Samsung, I'm not
Speaker 17:  sure how often people work from the ferry boat, but we're not here for that
Speaker 17:  reason. We here to just show what these things they're capable of.
Speaker 3:  And I feel like it's like, even if you don't wanna work from the ferry, like
Speaker 3:  I had this literally yesterday, I was on Amtrak on the way home. And I had
Speaker 3:  like a three and a half hour thing. And it's like, it's another one of those
Speaker 3:  where it's like, sometimes it's very loud because there's announcements and
Speaker 3:  people are talking and sometimes it's like relatively quiet and just sort
Speaker 3:  of going. And so I feel like knowing that it'll at least be
Speaker 3:  okay, even when the noise is really bad actually is very useful for me.
Speaker 3:  Right. Okay. So before the ferry leaves and stuff gets crazy, even crazier,
Speaker 3:  let's switch to the pixel bloods pro and get, get our last quick test. Here
Speaker 3:  you are on the Google pixel bloods pro. Yes. How do you like these in general?
Speaker 3:  We haven't talked about this on this show yet.
Speaker 17:  Yeah. I'm a fan. We've got a multipoint to compare them to two devices at
Speaker 17:  once, which the AirPods and Samsungs and even the Sony of the world
Speaker 17:  cannot do. So that's a nice little thing. I've had a few calls,
Speaker 17:  indoors, you know, very basic stuff. And haven't had many complaints,
Speaker 17:  but how do they sound on a boat?
Speaker 3:  I would put these kind of right in line with the AirPods. Actually.
Speaker 3:  I'm definitely getting that sort of baseline sort
Speaker 3:  of white noisy hum. But not in any particularly
Speaker 3:  unpleasant way. And your voice sounds pretty normal. So I think it's, it's
Speaker 3:  trying to sort of split that middle ground too, of like not overprocessing,
Speaker 3:  but also not getting all of the noise out as a result.
Speaker 17:  Right. Okay. That's pretty good then considering, you know, that's Google
Speaker 17:  their last few year, but it's the pixel buds too in particular were pretty
Speaker 17:  terrible. So you have like none of the issues and the dropouts that was
Speaker 17:  had. So I've been very, very happy about that. Sound quality is great. We're
Speaker 17:  gonna have spatial audio later this year with the head tracking, all that
Speaker 17:  stuff. So yeah. They're definitely Google's best Friday yet.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I'm kind of impressed. The only thing that is annoying me is there
Speaker 3:  is this one band of high pitched audio that's coming through. And when
Speaker 3:  you're not talking, it kicks in even harder. So it's like, it's, it seems
Speaker 3:  to be trying to figure out how to find your voice and not getting it quite
Speaker 3:  right. But then when you're not talking it's noise, cancellation is really
Speaker 3:  good. Apple was kind of pulling everything out, but like a sort of
Speaker 3:  subtle white noise. This is definitely, there's like a little bit of a screeching
Speaker 3:  happening. It's like the train car on the railroad tracks noise a
Speaker 3:  little bit
Speaker 17:  Interesting how like each company tunes their algorithms, you know, so pick
Speaker 17:  out certain frequencies. So I guess it comes down to preference or what
Speaker 17:  have you, but at least you can hear me pretty well.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Can you hear me? Okay. How are you, how am I doing
Speaker 17:  You? Like fine. We're gonna stay on the boat and keep going to our next
Speaker 17:  destination on the ferry.
Speaker 3:  Wait, is the ferry moving?
Speaker 17:  Oh yeah. The Ferry's been moving.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Wow. I didn't even hear the ferry start to move. I expected a big horn
Speaker 3:  or something.
Speaker 17:  We've got a big Enogen behind us, you know, but none of that's coming through
Speaker 17:  on the earbuds. So
Speaker 15:  Pretty good
Speaker 3:  While we're here. Why don't we go back and do the other two? Let's get the
Speaker 3:  AirPods in the Sony. So we have all four sitting at this table.
Speaker 15:  We're back on the AirPods pro we're still dark. So we don't have both movement
Speaker 15:  sounds, but still pretty loud. We were at the same table we were at before
Speaker 15:  when the buttons were super quiet when I was not talking, as you said,
Speaker 15:  so apple might left through a bit more noise.
Speaker 3:  I kind of can't believe I'm saying this, this, the pixel buds sounded better.
Speaker 3:  You can very much tell that apple is like obsessed with making your voice
Speaker 3:  still sound like your voice. Like you sound the most like you on these, but
Speaker 3:  as a result, I'm definitely hearing more background noise. Like I can hear
Speaker 3:  the people talking as they walk behind you in a way that the pixel
Speaker 3:  buds would not, I'm still getting that same kind of like high pitched wine.
Speaker 3:  So I think it's, it's kind of even with Google on that front, but like Google
Speaker 3:  is definitely more aggressive than apple on this front, but it seems
Speaker 3:  like almost as natural, I'm kind of impressed with the pixel buds here.
Speaker 15:  Interesting. Not what I expected. These AirPods are known quantity. They
Speaker 15:  will see what happens with the rumored AirPods bro too. I think that might
Speaker 15:  come around this fall. Cause we've been out for a while. It's time for something
Speaker 15:  new apple, I think. And I think we're getting close to it. Should we do
Speaker 15:  link buds now?
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Let's switch the link buds.
Speaker 15:  We're back to Sony's link buds so I can hear everything around me. I can
Speaker 15:  still hear you, but I can imagine like if we go off the top on the boat,
Speaker 15:  it's going to be very, very dire very quick. So for now
Speaker 15:  I can still make you up.
Speaker 3:  Chris. I have really disappointing news. What? These are not as good. The
Speaker 3:  pixel bloods might be the best one so far, which I would not have bet at
Speaker 3:  all would be the case, but this is like, it's still sort of that same thing.
Speaker 3:  It's like, it's trying really, really hard to process and I can hear it
Speaker 3:  happening. And so it's, everything is kind of coming up and then coming down
Speaker 3:  and then coming up and then coming down and everything is a little topsy
Speaker 3:  turvy. You sound more pleasant to me on both
Speaker 3:  the AirPods and the pixel buds.
Speaker 15:  Wow. Fascinating. Cause these were far and away the champion, like the coffee
Speaker 15:  shop setting, but here they seem to be struggling with all the factors
Speaker 15:  around, so. Hmm.
Speaker 3:  All right. Well, while you're still moving, let's let's go back to the galaxy
Speaker 3:  buds and see if they can come out of last place in this test.
Speaker 17:  Yes. The brand new galaxy buds, two pro buds pro two,
Speaker 17:  whichever you prefer. Yeah. Like I was saying before, the Samsung's best
Speaker 17:  sounding here buds yet, but from the noise cancellation is great. Almost
Speaker 17:  at Sony's level. Maybe it's just, just shy.
Speaker 3:  The noise cancellation on here is pretty good. Like I'm, I'm, I'm not
Speaker 3:  getting a ton of background noise, but you sound
Speaker 3:  by a mile. The worst of the four we've been testing here, it's
Speaker 3:  very muffled. And like you're talking to me through the wall of
Speaker 3:  mud.
Speaker 17:  Not sure if that's like placement or what differently, but yeah, it's
Speaker 17:  not great to hear two $30 on earbuds. You don't wanna hear that. You
Speaker 17:  sound like you're talking to bud.
Speaker 3:  Let's do one last test. We're gonna throw out the link buds and we're gonna
Speaker 3:  throw out the galaxy buds and we're gonna take the AirPods. And the pixel
Speaker 3:  buds pro up to the top of the ferry where things are gonna get even crazier.
Speaker 3:  And that's where we're gonna do our, our final test here.
Speaker 17:  It's gonna be windy. It's gonna be noisy. It's gonna be a very big test
Speaker 17:  for this. See who wins?
Speaker 3:  All right. We're on a moving ferry. Just went under the bridge
Speaker 15:  Beautiful day here in
Speaker 15:  hellacious.
Speaker 15:  It's a nice day. We're on, we're on top of the ferry.
Speaker 15:  Lot of folks,
Speaker 15:  it's a cool up here. So worst case scenario for any
Speaker 15:  set of your sort of being on the,
Speaker 3:  This is pretty bad. I caught about 80% of that. I would say
Speaker 3:  Apple's doing a good job here of making it. Like I suspect if it was just
Speaker 3:  unprocessed audio, this would be like unlistenable and I would've to take
Speaker 3:  my headphones off. So it's canceling out most of it. But unfortunately, that
Speaker 3:  also includes your voice. So I think we have officially reached the, do not
Speaker 3:  make phone calls on top of the ferry portion of the proceedings here.
Speaker 15:  So make phone calls. If we do gotta project, it's really loud and
Speaker 15:  we yell, just freak out the other ferry passengers and
Speaker 3:  Listen, the last time we did this, we scared everybody out of a coffee shop.
Speaker 3:  So I think the least we can do is scare everybody off the ferry today.
Speaker 15:  Shall we switch to the possible new winners?
Speaker 3:  Let's do it. I have high hopes. Let's see what happens.
Speaker 3:  All right. Pixel blood stress test.
Speaker 17:  These are the pixel buds pro top of fairies in New York city.
Speaker 17:  We are about to dock though. So it's not quite a fair comparison versus
Speaker 17:  I mean the engine's on no, but we're not full speed right now.
Speaker 3:  You sound substantially better than you did on the AirPods. I think
Speaker 3:  we, I think we might need to do this test when, when we're fully moving again.
Speaker 3:  Cause it's, this is usable. Right? Whereas the AirPods were like, I
Speaker 3:  would just hang up on you and tell you to call me later. But yeah, this is,
Speaker 3:  this is too good to be true. I think we're, we're gonna have to wait until
Speaker 3:  you're back out on the, on the open sea for this one.
Speaker 17:  Okay.
Speaker 3:  Looks like we're moving again.
Speaker 17:  We are at speed. Once again,
Speaker 3:  This is better than the AirPods. I cannot believe
Speaker 17:  This better than the AirPods. Okay. I'm coming through like no words are
Speaker 17:  getting cut off nothing. You're not losing me at all.
Speaker 3:  The AirPods were definitely clipping you occasionally. It was like, I
Speaker 3:  could get all of your sentences, but it was, it was cut. You were kind of
Speaker 3:  coming and going, but this seems like it's, it's pretty clean.
Speaker 17:  That's impressive.
Speaker 3:  Turn and face your head directly into the wind. Let's make this as hard as
Speaker 17:  Possible. Okay. Facing into the wind, speaking
Speaker 17:  to you at a fairly normal volume for a ferry, I can hear the winds in
Speaker 17:  the earbuds. So is that coming through?
Speaker 3:  I can hear you fine. This is insane.
Speaker 3:  I kind of can't believe it. That's worked. Like we could have a call like
Speaker 3:  this and I don't think I would ever be like, Chris, are you on the top of
Speaker 3:  a ferry calling me?
Speaker 17:  Well, that's what they do Google.
Speaker 3:  Like I would guess right now that you're like walking down the street
Speaker 3:  and there's like a breeze, right? Like, but that's, that's what it sounds
Speaker 3:  like. It definitely doesn't sound like you're on top of a very loud ferry.
Speaker 17:  There is a breeze. Alright. Yeah. This is impressive. I mean, I can hear
Speaker 17:  you. It's fine. Obviously the active noise cancellation is pretty good.
Speaker 17:  You get someone noise with all your buds that have that. I think. But by
Speaker 17:  and large, we might have found our favorite new pick for very
Speaker 17:  earbuds. So, you know, any kind of like extreme circumstances, didn't expect
Speaker 17:  a pull up pro to come out on top today.
Speaker 3:  All right. Well this is we've. We've learned something here. I'm now looking
Speaker 3:  sadly at my link bloods S and I'm like, do I, did I make the right decision
Speaker 3:  in buying you? I'm gonna, I'm gonna go look at Amazon for a while and just,
Speaker 3:  just see how I feel.
Speaker 17:  Okay. Well, we gotta find your way home. Now that can be office, but
Speaker 17:  this has been fun.
Speaker 3:  Well, thank you. Go back to quieter places and we'll we'll. We'll hang again
Speaker 3:  soon.
Speaker 17:  All right, sir. See you soon.
Speaker 3:  We're gonna take a break and then we're gonna talk about pickup trucks. Neil
Speaker 3:  Patel just finished reviewing the Ford F-150 lightning. And
Speaker 3:  I don't know anything about pickup trucks, but he tells me it's a big deal.
Speaker 3:  We'll be right back.
Speaker 21:  Today's episode is sponsored by draft Kings draft. Kings marketplace is
Speaker 21:  the place to grab digital collectables, but this football season check out
Speaker 21:  draft Kings first ever NFT fantasy game rainmakers football,
Speaker 21:  buy, sell, and win player card NFTs are the biggest names in the game like
Speaker 21:  Lamar Jackson and George Kittle. Then craft lineups of athletes from your
Speaker 21:  NFT card collection and earn points for touchdowns, receptions, and more
Speaker 21:  just like daily fantasy football. And right now everyone can get their first
Speaker 21:  full roster starter pack for free build your entity franchise and enter
Speaker 21:  free rainmakers football contest all season long. Download the draft King's
Speaker 21:  daily fantasy app now, and sign up with promo code. Vergecast click the
Speaker 21:  rainmakers tile and opt in to get your first full roster starter pack for
Speaker 21:  free plus play for millions and prizes all football season and build the
Speaker 21:  ultimate NFT fantasy franchise with rainmakers football that's promo code
Speaker 21:  Vergecast build play wing
Speaker 21:  only@draftkingsentriesdependentontypeandnumberofnftsheldvoidwearprohibitedorrestrictedseadraftkings.com
Speaker 21:  for eligibility restrictions and details.
Speaker 22:  This episode is brought to you by Moen. If you're looking to upgrade your
Speaker 22:  kitchen, you should look to the Moen smart faucet with motion control,
Speaker 22:  it's sleek, modern, and a totally touchless experience. Turn it
Speaker 22:  on and control the temperature of the water with a wave of your hand. Plus
Speaker 22:  it comes with voice activation and custom voice enable presets that allow
Speaker 22:  you to create common commands. So you can make your time in the kitchen,
Speaker 22:  feel more magical, learn
Speaker 22:  more@moen.com.
Speaker 3:  Welcome back. So I should confess this right up front. I am
Speaker 3:  not a truck guy, not even a little bit, but I'm
Speaker 3:  fascinated by the Ford F-150 lightning. Anyway, because this is Ford trying
Speaker 3:  to take its most iconic vehicle, maybe the most iconic
Speaker 3:  vehicle that anybody makes into the electric truck of the future.
Speaker 3:  And I think weather Ford can pull that off. Might say a lot about
Speaker 3:  the whole car industry's attempt to go. Electric Mitel spent
Speaker 3:  a bunch of time over the last several weeks, racing around upstate New York
Speaker 3:  in a lightning, hanging out at home Depot parking lots, because apparently
Speaker 3:  that's what you do when you're a pickup truck guy. And he wrote a review
Speaker 3:  for the verge about all of it. It's up now I'll put the link in the show
Speaker 3:  notes. And what surprised me most about it was that the Ford
Speaker 3:  F-150 lightning is a truck. Yes, but it's also basically just a
Speaker 3:  really big tablet on wheels. And I love talking about
Speaker 3:  tablets. So I told NEI that he had to come tell us about this Ford tablet,
Speaker 3:  whether touchscreens are the future of cars and whether Ford software design
Speaker 3:  can match its pickup prowess. Hi Eli.
Speaker 23:  Hey buddy.
Speaker 3:  So you're a truck guy.
Speaker 23:  One of the more surprising developments of my entire life.
Speaker 3:  Have you always been a truck guy? Like when, when did Eli Patel truck guy
Speaker 3:  become a thing?
Speaker 23:  Well, I've always enjoyed a truck. Okay. Like I grew up in Wisconsin, there
Speaker 23:  were trucks around. I've always thought trucks were neat. The idea that
Speaker 23:  I would own a pickup truck and then consider purchasing a second pickup
Speaker 23:  truck. That's pandemic. That's just pure pandemic outcome.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I mean, pre pandemic NELI was much more interested in like an
Speaker 3:  unnecessarily fast BMW than a second pickup
Speaker 23:  Truck, city cars. And now I'm like country cars. Yeah, that's good.
Speaker 3:  Okay. So the reason I bring this up is we're gonna mostly talk about the
Speaker 3:  F-150 lightning as like a gadget, because I think that's how you mostly think
Speaker 3:  about it. That's how you mostly reviewed it. So we're gonna talk mostly about
Speaker 3:  that, but like real quick before we do put this thing in like
Speaker 3:  future of cars, context for me, cuz I don't, all I know is that
Speaker 3:  Ford sells a lot of F one 50 S and it would be good if they were electric.
Speaker 3:  I guess like this thing seems to matter a lot. Tell me why.
Speaker 23:  Yeah. I think that's the basics. So pickup trucks are the most popular vehicles
Speaker 23:  in America. The F-150 in particular is the most
Speaker 23:  popular vehicle in America for like 45 years running. Wow. And that's
Speaker 23:  not a consumer number. That's a vehicles in
Speaker 23:  America number that is contractors that is delivery people that
Speaker 23:  is fleets like people by F one 50 S for their
Speaker 23:  businesses, huge companies buy hundreds of F one 50 S at a time.
Speaker 23:  So the most popular vehicle in America, they obviously are huge.
Speaker 23:  They've gotten incredibly big over time. If you look at F-150 from
Speaker 23:  the nineties, they look teeny they're little baby cars. Yeah. They're heavy.
Speaker 23:  They have big engines. They have a lot of emissions from the big engines.
Speaker 23:  So if you can electrify that and in particular electrify it, not
Speaker 23:  for consumers, but for that huge number of commercial customers that
Speaker 23:  don't often drive more than 300 miles in a day. Right. So they can come
Speaker 23:  home and they can charge back at their depots. That's what Ford calls it.
Speaker 23:  You've like made a huge impact on emissions. There's just an opportunity
Speaker 23:  here to electrify a lot of cars at once, cuz you're aiming kind of at
Speaker 23:  the biggest part of the market.
Speaker 3:  Okay. So if I'm forward, then I would basically try to make the
Speaker 3:  F-150 lightning as much. Exactly the same as the
Speaker 3:  F-150 that has been the best selling car in America for 45 years as possible.
Speaker 3:  Like change as little as you possibly can. And like hope nobody notices
Speaker 3:  seems like a very good business strategy in that sense. And to some extent
Speaker 3:  that that almost seems like what Ford did here. Like almost, but not quite.
Speaker 23:  It's an F-150. My joke is like Ford literally did not redesign the wheel.
Speaker 23:  It's the F-150 steering wheel. F-150 seats,
Speaker 23:  F-150 body panels. F-150 windshield wipers. F-150
Speaker 23:  everywhere. Then some minor tweaks, the taillights and headlight have the
Speaker 23:  little led surrounds the interiors. Like depending on your view
Speaker 23:  of the touchscreen, a little bit nicer than the platinum F-150
Speaker 23:  cuz it's just been redesigned a little bit. And obviously it has that drivetrain
Speaker 23:  and it can, it can just go real fast in a way that very few F-150 S can
Speaker 23:  go real fast.
Speaker 3:  That's fair. The headlights thing. There are very few things in the world
Speaker 3:  that drive Anna, my wife, as crazy as like non-standard headlights
Speaker 3:  and taillights. And every time we drive at night, she's like, this should
Speaker 3:  be regulated. All headlights and taillights should have to be the same. And
Speaker 3:  the thing the Mustang does where it like the lights sort of tick outward
Speaker 3:  drives her. Absolutely insane. So I'm sure the F-150 lightning is gonna do
Speaker 3:  the same thing.
Speaker 23:  So one thing that's true across car design is everybody wants the cool L
Speaker 23:  E D headlights that are like really thin and look really neat. They don't
Speaker 23:  make enough light. So if you actually look at where the real headlights
Speaker 23:  are in cars, they're all over the place in place. They're like hidden. So
Speaker 23:  it looks like the cool lights are the lights, but then the real lights are
Speaker 23:  like hidden somewhere else.
Speaker 3:  There's just somebody shining a flashlight behind it.
Speaker 3:  Okay. All right. So the software is the thing, right? And it's like, everybody
Speaker 3:  seems to have decided that Tesla's idea of like, what if we just put a giant
Speaker 3:  ass portrait mode screen in the middle of the car is the
Speaker 3:  correct idea. And before we even get into the specifics of it, are we sure
Speaker 3:  that's the right idea? Like I'm just like buttons, buttons are so good.
Speaker 3:  Give me like dials and the, the F-150 you have, if, if I'm remembering right
Speaker 3:  from seeing your video is like big landscape screen and then a bunch of buttons
Speaker 3:  at the bottom and I'm like, that is the future I can get behind.
Speaker 23:  So my F-150 is a generation behind. Okay. So it's not the new
Speaker 23:  F-150 S the new F one 50 S have a 12 inch landscape screen, climate control
Speaker 23:  buttons underneath it. I have the older model, which smaller
Speaker 23:  tinier screen that really is just like for the radio. And then
Speaker 23:  buttons ever like fast tuned with buttons. And I'm in love with the buttons.
Speaker 23:  Give more buttons, I'll take the buttons. The thing you're talking about
Speaker 23:  cars as computers, it's not the infotainment screen is like the smallest
Speaker 23:  piece of that puzzle. So like a normal car from
Speaker 23:  early two thousands was actually like 19 computers. And those
Speaker 23:  computers are all built by various suppliers. And the job of the car maker
Speaker 23:  was to like, buy those computers and integrate them. And they would
Speaker 23:  integrate them using like a pretty slow networking standard called like
Speaker 23:  can bus or like, whatever. It's the big Tesla. Innovation is like,
Speaker 23:  what if the car was one computer? Sure. Or what if we designed all
Speaker 23:  those computers and we networked it all with like ethernet and like you
Speaker 23:  talk to car people, and they're like single twisted pair. Ethernet is the
Speaker 23:  biggest revolution in automotive. And you're like, what ethernet? You're
Speaker 23:  talking about ethernet. Right. But it's real that like, yeah, being able
Speaker 23:  to send more data faster, more reliably, ground
Speaker 23:  a car and control all the software, the pieces like you need an
Speaker 23:  interconnect for that. So Ford isn't all the way there. Like Rivian is like
Speaker 23:  a, is an all ethernet networked vehicle. They've written every
Speaker 23:  line of code in that car. It's the future in that way? It's the same way.
Speaker 23:  The Tesla's the future. The lightning is again right in the middle.
Speaker 23:  Like they have a drive train that's new. They want to do over the year
Speaker 23:  updates and be able to update the software all across the car. Still lots
Speaker 23:  of supplier components again, cuz you've got a bunch of F150 stuff, lots
Speaker 23:  of supplier components flowing through it. And the thing that is expressed
Speaker 23:  to you is like, oh, it has a big vertical touchscreen fair. So it's like
Speaker 23:  the touchscreen is like the last piece of the puzzle. When you talk about
Speaker 23:  the car as a computer, what they're really talking about is previously we,
Speaker 23:  we basically like lightly connected a bunch of individual computer,
Speaker 23:  like modules. And now we're the whole car is one big computer,
Speaker 3:  Which I guess is like, I keep having to remind myself like that counts as
Speaker 3:  a large innovation. It's like, well and everything else. We did this a really
Speaker 3:  long time ago.
Speaker 23:  Yeah. And like, if you really, the car companies, traditional car, they're
Speaker 23:  all on this. Like their executives will all use the business. Like we're
Speaker 23:  on this journey of transformation. And what they mean is we had no idea
Speaker 23:  how to write a line of code before. Right. And now we that's all we do
Speaker 23:  like to the exclusion of, we know how to make wheels,
Speaker 23:  like, like they can buy wheels. They're like, actually, what will differentiate
Speaker 23:  the cars is the software engineering in the cars, but they never had to.
Speaker 23:  There's a story about like VW. They launched this massive program to
Speaker 23:  write all software in the cars. And it was like this like 10 year failure,
Speaker 23:  cuz they're just not good at it in a way that a clean sheet company, like
Speaker 23:  a Tesla or a Rivian or lucid or whatever, they start by hiring the software
Speaker 23:  engineers.
Speaker 3:  I feel like given that this touch screen is like the thing we're gonna treat
Speaker 3:  this thing, like a classic like verge smartphone review. So I went back to
Speaker 3:  like 2012 and I found all the categories of our smartphone review and they
Speaker 3:  fit, they fit hilariously well into the construct of, of
Speaker 3:  this car. Yeah. So the first one is the hardware, which is just like
Speaker 3:  the, the thing itself. Like, is this a good screen? Do we like,
Speaker 3:  do we like the touch? Does, how what's the hand feel like you like?
Speaker 23:  Yeah, it's slow. It's a really fast truck with a really
Speaker 23:  slow screen. And I have this line that I've been sneaking into reviews for
Speaker 23:  years and got cut out of the video cuz I said it like
Speaker 23:  in a very frustrated way, which is that life is too short for slow computers.
Speaker 23:  And the F-150 lightning is like the ultimate example of life being too short
Speaker 23:  for slow computers. Like it's slow. The truck
Speaker 23:  is fast. Like at any moment you can crack a huge grin
Speaker 23:  by just going fast in this truck. Yeah. One of the fastest production trucks
Speaker 23:  ever made, I got into a race with a Corvette, held my own again, like a
Speaker 23:  brand new Corvette, stingray held my own in a pickup truck. That's cool.
Speaker 23:  Like that's really fun. Then you're like, I need to do anything.
Speaker 23:  I need to turn on the seat heaters. And you're like, I hate it. So like
Speaker 23:  there's just this big discrepancy in like when you're like the hardware,
Speaker 23:  like the truck is a beautiful truck. The front is cool. But the actual like
Speaker 23:  hardware of the screen, the screen is nice. It's, you know, retina display,
Speaker 23:  it's thick in a way that all automotive screens appear to be needlessly
Speaker 23:  thick. If you look at how it's designed is actually a little, it appears
Speaker 23:  to be off center because the sensor for blue crews is like next to the screen.
Speaker 23:  So like they've just like rejiggered the F-150 interior, everything about
Speaker 23:  it seems to nice. It's just slow. Yep.
Speaker 3:  Describe slow to me cuz there's like I pull down on a menu
Speaker 3:  and it, this sort of old Android thing where it would like lag ever so slightly
Speaker 3:  behind your finger, that's like one version of slow. Then there's the version
Speaker 3:  of slow where it's like, I press a button and seven seconds later or
Speaker 3:  something happens where on that spectrum does the F-150 like, because I would
Speaker 3:  also think this is literally like slow touchscreens are like literal life
Speaker 3:  and death in a car like this. Like it's, it's pretty high stakes time
Speaker 3:  to like make things happen when you press buttons. Like how, how slow is
Speaker 3:  slow here.
Speaker 23:  It's both of those things, but sporadically,
Speaker 3:  Oh, even better. It's unreliably slow.
Speaker 23:  I think the touch latency part is connected to this overall slowness. So
Speaker 23:  there are many times when you like swipe on the screen to like swipe through
Speaker 23:  the cards at the bottom and you're like, this isn't keeping up with me,
Speaker 23:  but it's not that the touch screen is like not registering your touch events.
Speaker 23:  It's that the thing is slow and it's not nothing's happening. So like in
Speaker 23:  a smartphone would be like, does it have 120 hearts touch, sensitivity response
Speaker 23:  or whatever. And it's like, maybe it does. But the computer is so slow.
Speaker 23:  Doesn't know what to do. So like as a touch screen,
Speaker 23:  it is slow sometimes. But I think that is mostly related to sometimes
Speaker 23:  you touch it and it just needs a beat. Right? Like I wanna switch on the
Speaker 23:  radio to the maps and it's like, what we're gonna do.
Speaker 23:  Okay. We're gonna take the radio away and it'll be blank for a minute.
Speaker 23:  And then let's go ahead and fill in the map window. And then
Speaker 23:  where are we? All right. Let's get, let's pull down the data for you're
Speaker 23:  located and then like draw on them. And it's like, all this is just happening.
Speaker 23:  Whereas you know, on a smartphone, you swipe between absence instant
Speaker 23:  and there are cars that are instant now. And this one is just slow.
Speaker 3:  And this is I'm skipping ahead to the software section of the review now.
Speaker 3:  But the, you described this well and I still can't figure it out. This is
Speaker 3:  like Ford software, but it's kind of Android, but it's gonna be even more
Speaker 3:  Android over time.
Speaker 23:  So it's not Android at all right
Speaker 3:  Now. Oh,
Speaker 23:  Okay. So right now Ford's main software is called sync and
Speaker 23:  sync has this like long tortured history. They've first built it with
Speaker 23:  Microsoft on windows CE, this is like ancient sync. Then they kicked
Speaker 23:  Microsoft to the curb. They've rebuilt it on some proprietary stuff.
Speaker 23:  I think there's some QIX in there. Like now four owns it. Then they've
Speaker 23:  updated it now to sync four that's sync fours in most of their cars,
Speaker 23:  the Mustang lock E and the lightning have sync four a, which is just portrait
Speaker 23:  sync. It has like some portrait features, I guess you could call it like
Speaker 23:  it's got those little widgets. And then what is the big move
Speaker 23:  is they're gonna toss all of that out. They've signed this huge deal with
Speaker 23:  Google. They're gonna rebuild all of sync on Android using Android
Speaker 23:  automotive and with Google services.
Speaker 3:  Oh, this is gas that we've been talking about. Google automotive services,
Speaker 3:  gas
Speaker 23:  It's coming. So this was a big deal. It took years in the making Farley,
Speaker 23:  just CEO, Jim Farley just signed this deal with Google. They're very excited
Speaker 23:  about it. They hired Doug field from Tesla and apple
Speaker 23:  to run all of Ford's EV stuff. And he is gonna be in charge of all this
Speaker 23:  software too. The problem is none of that's coming out forever. Like in
Speaker 23:  terms of lightning, the new cars at the end of 2023, we'll have this new
Speaker 23:  version of Android sync, but the lightning
Speaker 23:  probably won't get it. Why until there's a new generation of the
Speaker 23:  lightning. That's just my understanding. And I think even inside of Ford,
Speaker 23:  this is somewhat confusing. So I talked to Jim Farley when the lightning
Speaker 23:  first started shipping and I said, what's going on with Android? And he
Speaker 23:  said, yeah, you know, second half of this generation, then I got a call
Speaker 23:  from someone who would know. And they said, you need to change like the
Speaker 23:  electrical systems of the car to support the new software. So
Speaker 23:  like maybe there'll be like a mid-cycle refresh, but I don't think the lightning
Speaker 23:  or, or Maki in this form are gonna get it all that is to say like you're
Speaker 23:  using this software and you're like, man, this would be great if they would
Speaker 23:  update the software. But all of their software engineering energy
Speaker 23:  is pointed at the new platform. And so there's supposed to be some big update
Speaker 23:  for this version of sync coming. Don't buy anything based on the promise
Speaker 23:  of software updates, I think is always our advice. And this is like a pretty
Speaker 23:  good example of that advice because you know that there's a dead end here.
Speaker 3:  Okay. Slowness aside, it seems like car UI is very
Speaker 3:  much like an unsolved problem. And we've talked a lot about like CarPlay
Speaker 3:  plans to take over the universe on this podcast, which I continue to think
Speaker 3:  are fascinating and potentially insane. But just watching your video, it's
Speaker 3:  like Ford has a lot of ideas about like side
Speaker 3:  scrolling menus. That don't strike me as
Speaker 3:  like the way that I would like to interact with my car.
Speaker 23:  Okay. There are hours of me ranting about this software to make it into
Speaker 23:  the video. Let me, I'll give you one example. First of all, nothing is labeled
Speaker 23:  there's oceans of pixels in this car and like,
Speaker 23:  oh, like oceans, it has more pixels than almost any car I've ever been in.
Speaker 23:  It's
Speaker 3:  Like a 15 and a half inch screen or something. Right. It's huge.
Speaker 23:  It's a 15 and a half inch screen. And it has like 10 inch instrument cluster.
Speaker 23:  And like a lot of it to your point from before is like, they're just
Speaker 23:  simulating a Ford F-150 from 1985. Like
Speaker 23:  there's like lots of those like old school icons in the instrument cluster.
Speaker 23:  And it's just like, I don't, that's a picture of an engine, like, like sure.
Speaker 23:  Like I don't, I don't know what that means. Like here's the letter C next
Speaker 23:  to a thermometer. Like, you know, if you're a car person, like, you know
Speaker 23:  what these means, but like they made those icons cuz they, all they had
Speaker 23:  was like LEDs and they had to ship them to a hundred countries or whatever.
Speaker 23:  It's like dudes, you've got pixels just like right out engine
Speaker 23:  temperature, like whatever it's. So like there's just like an infinity amount
Speaker 23:  of that going on, which is even more frustrating when you see the size of
Speaker 23:  the screen. Like the instant Custer is basically empty. It's rarely full
Speaker 23:  of information, but it's a huge screen. Then you've got the center
Speaker 23:  screen the big one and like the top row of it has
Speaker 23:  icons in it that are just as inscrutable as like the Android status
Speaker 23:  bar. Oh God. Like there is one in it that, you know, that little like
Speaker 23:  asterisk sign that you see on the side of an ambulance. So the entire
Speaker 23:  time I had this car, there was that symbol with a line through it. And
Speaker 23:  I was like, is it just telling me I'm not an ambulance,
Speaker 23:  but like you can't tap on it. It doesn't tell you what it is. And I like
Speaker 23:  finally was like, what is this? And it, all it means is that 9 1, 1 assist
Speaker 23:  is off. So if you get an accident in the car will not call 9 1 1 behalf.
Speaker 23:  Totally useful piece of information to know, I suppose, putting
Speaker 23:  it permanently on the screen without any way to tell you what is going on
Speaker 23:  when you have a 15 and a half inch touch screen is ridiculous.
Speaker 3:  You could write out 9 1, 1 assist is off without trying very hard. Like that's
Speaker 3:  a, that's a thing screens do.
Speaker 23:  Yeah. It's it's right there. Then there's like two different connectivity
Speaker 23:  icons, one for your phone, one for the internal LTE radio. When you've got
Speaker 23:  your phone on the wireless charging pad, there's just a picture, another
Speaker 23:  little icon of a phone up there. And so like it just for all the world feels
Speaker 23:  like your phone is disconnecting from the head unit. When really it's just
Speaker 23:  rattling around the wireless charging pad. Why? And then you like click,
Speaker 23:  you would never know this to change any of the settings of the truck. You
Speaker 23:  have to click a picture of the truck. Like there's a picture of the truck
Speaker 23:  in the upper left hand corner. And you're like, yeah, it's the truck. And
Speaker 23:  you would never know that almost all of the settings are buried in the picture
Speaker 23:  of the truck. So you click on the picture of the truck. This is why they
Speaker 23:  cut it outta the video. I just wanna be clear. I just did this fucking hour
Speaker 23:  to a camera. It drops down a menu and the menu is
Speaker 23:  divided into two sections. One is labeled
Speaker 23:  settings and one is labeled controls and who, God knows the difference
Speaker 23:  between these things. And then you like go into the controls and there's
Speaker 23:  like little buttons and you clip between them. And then all of the buttons
Speaker 23:  in those are labeled settings. And it's just like, what is happening?
Speaker 23:  Like, did anybody look at this and like pay attention
Speaker 23:  to what words we're using? Cuz we seem to be using all the words interchangeably
Speaker 23:  as though they're a taxonomy of. And like, this is how we would review a
Speaker 23:  phone. Like if we were reviewing a new operating system, we would go into
Speaker 23:  this in extraordinary detail and be like the settings,
Speaker 23:  the new version of windows have been moved from here to here. Like, you
Speaker 23:  know, apple changed window management on the iPad. And we'd like, as we
Speaker 23:  have, we would like hammer away at scrolling your mouse to the bottom, right.
Speaker 23:  This open stage manager. And we don't do that with cars. Right. And I
Speaker 23:  I'm just looking at this car. I'm like, if anyone did this to this car,
Speaker 23:  seriously, you would just throw it out and start over
Speaker 3:  The way you're describing. It makes it sound like they hired a bunch of people
Speaker 3:  who had like deliberately, never looked at a screen before. And they were
Speaker 3:  like, let's just start this from scratch. Like we know we have just decided
Speaker 3:  as a society, like what a settings menu looks like and like, should it be
Speaker 3:  the gear icon? Maybe not, but it doesn't matter. And we all know that's what
Speaker 3:  it means. And it's like, we just don't need new ideas about how to get to
Speaker 3:  setting venues. Like I'm, we're good on that front. Let's fix other things.
Speaker 23:  Yeah. At almost no point does this thing trade on your knowledge of how
Speaker 23:  computers
Speaker 3:  Work, which is crazy because that's, again, it's like, this is the moment
Speaker 3:  to, if you're ever gonna do the like skew more fake nonsense, that's just
Speaker 3:  like, let's help everybody understand it as quickly as possible. This feels
Speaker 3:  like the time.
Speaker 23:  Yeah. But, and then on the flip side they've got all these like old school
Speaker 23:  weird unlabeled icons, like in the instrument cluster. Right? Right. So
Speaker 23:  like the part where you're like simulating the old F-150 and then on the
Speaker 23:  other hand, you're like, what if we try to invent
Speaker 23:  settings taxonomy from scratch? It's like, you're not, you gotta do
Speaker 23:  one or the other all the way. And like in this case, I just think Ford
Speaker 23:  is a little trapped between two worlds and they've got this like gigantic
Speaker 23:  Android refresh coming where presumably, because they're working with Google.
Speaker 23:  Well, I mean, it's not like Android status bar. So like a vast gen of clarity,
Speaker 23:  but presumably they've got some people who are versed in user interface
Speaker 23:  design, like helping them along the way. So it just, that part of it to
Speaker 23:  me is like, I think I say in the video it's caught between two worlds. It's
Speaker 23:  it's held back and it's held back cuz it's not going far enough in I think
Speaker 23:  in either direction.
Speaker 3:  That's fair. Do you figure it out eventually? Like it's, it's like
Speaker 3:  part of this makes me think that like the best case scenario here is it's
Speaker 3:  kind of like getting into somebody else's car where you like reach where
Speaker 3:  the volume no is. And actually that's the temperature knob. But like after
Speaker 3:  a little while you sort of get the muscle memory back and you figure it out,
Speaker 3:  like, did that happen with the lightning?
Speaker 23:  Yeah. It, you know, I end the video by saying, if I could find one to buy
Speaker 23:  for a reasonable price, cuz dealers are working like crazy and they're hard
Speaker 23:  to buy. I would trade in my gas truck. Right? Like the, the part
Speaker 23:  where I don't have to pay for gas for a truck that gets 16 to the gallon
Speaker 23:  on a good day. And it's faster than my truck. And it's like fun
Speaker 23:  to have and the front is useful. Yeah. I would just try if I could get one,
Speaker 23:  I would buy one,
Speaker 3:  But that's a, like, that's a, in spite of the software
Speaker 23:  In spite of the software. Okay. Right. It's not like a deal breaker. It's
Speaker 23:  if you are the sort of person who pays attention and values, good
Speaker 23:  software, this is gonna drive you bonkers every day. But it's
Speaker 23:  survivable, which I think is like where the car industry has been for a
Speaker 23:  long time. The thing you're describing is is it eventually
Speaker 23:  just ignorable? Yeah. And the answer is yes. To some extent, like you're
Speaker 23:  not gonna dive into the settings of any car every day and like mess with
Speaker 23:  it. The thing that is not ignorable is the touch stream, climate controls,
Speaker 23:  which are just the worst and they're the worst in every car and
Speaker 23:  they should be illegal. And here you're like, I want to turn on the seat
Speaker 23:  heaters and you're just stabbing at an unresponsive touchscreen
Speaker 23:  and that's the worst. Or you're like, I wanna turn on the, the, I wanna
Speaker 23:  change the vents and you have to like open a full screen menu with
Speaker 23:  a render of the car that is split into three zones
Speaker 23:  and like light up the zones. And you're like, my mom's car in the eighties
Speaker 23:  had this solved. Like why are we redoing this? And then you look at the
Speaker 23:  gas F one 50 S and they've got hardware buttons. And you're like, I coulda,
Speaker 23:  this was fine.
Speaker 3:  Yep. It should either be a dial that goes up and down or an up button and
Speaker 3:  a down button. Those are the two answers. And those are the only two answers.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 23:  So like there's a part of it. That's totally normal. Like, yes, you'll be
Speaker 23:  occasionally annoyed because you have to use the built in maps to plot a
Speaker 23:  charging route slow, but survivable and I used it. Yes. You'll be
Speaker 23:  occasionally annoyed because wanting to change the radio station while you're
Speaker 23:  in the map requires an awful lot of clicks. Fine. It's annoying.
Speaker 23:  The climate controls are like, I hate this. Like almost a deal breaker.
Speaker 23:  Not quite cuz like really, they just want you to set a temperature, an auto,
Speaker 23:  which I think a lot of people quietly do. So maybe not the worst depending
Speaker 23:  on who you are. But for me, I was like, I hate, I hate all of this.
Speaker 3:  Okay. Fair enough. Alright. Last thing on the version of you checklist
Speaker 3:  before I let you go is cameras. And this is another one that fits oddly
Speaker 3:  well in your experience of the F-150 lane. Tell me about the cameras on
Speaker 3:  this car.
Speaker 23:  My favorite thing about new cars is the cameras are getting really good
Speaker 23:  and they're like super high resolution. So this is no exception,
Speaker 23:  super high resolution cameras. Really nice touch screen. Like the cameras
Speaker 23:  on my old F-150 are like garbage, like VGA,
Speaker 23:  tiny, low res touchscreen. It's like, I think I'm gonna hit another car.
Speaker 23:  I don't know. Maybe who knows this thing has like all the cameras all
Speaker 23:  over the place. You get the top down 360 view. You can look out the front,
Speaker 23:  big screen, all high res there's a little just, they're doing all kinds
Speaker 23:  of weird camera, warping tricks to give you all these views. So there's
Speaker 23:  a little distortion of the edges, but like it's me who notices these things?
Speaker 23:  Not like our video people are like, what are you talking about? And I was
Speaker 23:  like, look at the, the thing that kills me at the cameras. So again, on
Speaker 23:  my truck, there's a hardware button above the screen. You push the button,
Speaker 23:  pops into the cameras. You just do whatever you want. You push the button
Speaker 23:  again. You change the views. Amazingly simple, amazingly efficient,
Speaker 23:  super useful. This thing is like three taps into the cameras. When
Speaker 23:  you put in reverse, it obviously automatically opens the cameras. But any,
Speaker 23:  any other place you gotta like tap your way into the cameras.
Speaker 3:  Do you have to like hit the truck and then like front truck front left truck
Speaker 3:  camera.
Speaker 23:  Yeah. No. So I think, yes. I think you hit the truck and you gotta like
Speaker 23:  open the cameras and you got the cameras on the screen. Then you've got,
Speaker 23:  you've got a landscape view at the top and then a 360 view of the truck
Speaker 23:  below it and like a T shape. Okay, great. Then there's a little menu button
Speaker 23:  in that bottom part and you click on the menu and that gives you all the
Speaker 23:  views. So, so far like annoying, but not the end of the world.
Speaker 23:  Like maybe too many clicks. Lots of touch screens, but big screen high-res
Speaker 23:  cameras. Sure. So you're like maybe this trade off is worth it. Then you're
Speaker 23:  like, you've got it. Open the menu to switch cameras. You pick a camera
Speaker 23:  then for some reason that menu will just close itself all
Speaker 23:  by itself all the time. So you're like, wait, there's so much room on
Speaker 23:  this display. Why was this a menu to begin with? And then why does that
Speaker 23:  menu hide to what end is this menu hiding itself? Cause it's not
Speaker 23:  covering anything up. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  It could show you so many cameras.
Speaker 23:  It could, yeah. It could show you all the cameras all the time. You could
Speaker 23:  open a camera and still have controls to see the other cameras. And it's
Speaker 23:  just shit like that. That just drives me bonkers. It's like this truck is
Speaker 23:  so smart with blue crews. It can happily drive itself down a bunch of major
Speaker 23:  highways, incredible technology, like best driver assist I've used
Speaker 23:  and it's on a mainstream truck. Very cool. And you're like, I just wanna
Speaker 23:  look at the rear camera and it's like, no, we're gonna close that on you.
Speaker 23:  Not at this time, sir. All of that just needs to like just an interface
Speaker 23:  designer needs to go through this thing and do the things that interface
Speaker 23:  designers use here are the things that people use most often. We're gonna
Speaker 23:  promote those to the top of the interface so you can get to them quickly.
Speaker 23:  Here's the things, here's the user pathways through all the rest of the
Speaker 23:  stuff. We're just gonna organize that into a coherent system and we're gonna
Speaker 23:  take all the garbage and we're just gonna like hide it in the back of settings.app.
Speaker 23:  And everyone will be fine with that. And instead it's just like, what if
Speaker 23:  it was a maze? There's no destination. It's like,
Speaker 23:  I need you to stop it.
Speaker 3:  What if you explore your truck through a VR render of your truck,
Speaker 23:  You know that thing you do when you get in new gadget and you like play
Speaker 23:  with the settings, like usually I find that to be just a, a delight.
Speaker 23:  Like I'm gonna mess with this setting and I'll come back to it with this.
Speaker 23:  Yes. Still a delight. You extremely fun, new gadget, many, many
Speaker 23:  settings. But I, in the back of my mind, there's always the fear. I will
Speaker 23:  never see this screen again. I have no idea how I got here
Speaker 23:  and I have no idea how to get back.
Speaker 3:  And in the worst case scenario, you literally cannot get home at the end
Speaker 3:  of it. And that's just, that's where you are.
Speaker 23:  Yeah. I mean, there's that? Well, that's like the charging thing, right?
Speaker 23:  Like you've gotta fine. Chargers can charge a thing fast. And all of
Speaker 23:  that happens in Ford's maps cuz Apple's maps and Google's maps have
Speaker 23:  no idea of where chargers are interesting. And like where the fast chargers
Speaker 23:  are and Ford has that information it's map. So, you know, one note I was
Speaker 23:  anticipating about CarPlay and Android auto is like everyone in every car
Speaker 23:  view is like, you can just use CarPlay and Android auto. Yep. And it's like,
Speaker 23:  no, actually if you drive an EV you can't right. Cuz you spend an
Speaker 23:  awful lot of your time on trips, plotting out your charging stops and Ford
Speaker 23:  system for that is better. Cuz it's tied to the actual range of the car.
Speaker 23:  So the car knows how much battery it has left. Sure. And it's just sort
Speaker 23:  of plotting you a route and it Ford also knows where the fast chargers are.
Speaker 23:  Cuz it runs the charging network in a way that apple and Google do not.
Speaker 23:  So every part of this is like, oh you gotta use their software again. Huh?
Speaker 23:  You thought you could escape it. You thought you were gonna use CarPlay.
Speaker 23:  Cool guy. No, thank
Speaker 3:  You. So all this and you're still the coolest guy in the home Depot parking
Speaker 3:  lot. And you still wanna buy one
Speaker 23:  Old guys were wa wandering up to me just saying, congratulations.
Speaker 23:  I've never had that happen with the review product before I was like, it's
Speaker 23:  not mine. They're like take good care of it. I was like, again, we have
Speaker 23:  to give it back. And he is like, congratulations, one more time. It's like
Speaker 23:  a reverence around this trip. Cause one thing that is true of EVs is people
Speaker 23:  know they're fast. Yeah. So you've got the fastest car in the parking lot.
Speaker 23:  Like all the trepidation, like they'd ask me the range they be. Is
Speaker 23:  it fast though? And be it's so fast. Like Ford's gotta hit. I think some
Speaker 23:  of it will be fine. The software piece, if they really wanna make that turn
Speaker 23:  into being the tech company, that it seems very clear. They want to do that
Speaker 23:  is a long road.
Speaker 3:  All right. Well good luck buying one. I know it's been a journey. So God
Speaker 3:  speed.
Speaker 23:  Yeah. We haven't even talked about that, but these things are being marked
Speaker 23:  up by like $50,000. So we'll see if anyone has one, they wanna flip to me.
Speaker 23:  You just let me know. We'll negotiate it.
Speaker 3:  All right. NE's off to keep calling dealers about buying a lightning and
Speaker 3:  we've gotta go to that's it for the Vergecast this week. Thank you so much
Speaker 3:  for listening. As always. There is tons more coverage about everything we
Speaker 3:  talked about@theverge.com and you can also follow all of us on Twitter.
Speaker 3:  Eli is reckless. Chris is Chris Welch. Alex is Alex H
Speaker 3:  crayons. Allison is Allison Joe one. Dan is
Speaker 3:  DC sea and I'm Pierce. The show is produced by Andrew Marino and Liam
Speaker 3:  James Nori. Donovan is our executive producer and Brooke mins is our editorial
Speaker 3:  director of audio. The Vergecast is a verge production and part of the Fox
Speaker 3:  media podcast network. If you've thoughts, feedback, feelings, paella,
Speaker 3:  recipes, or ideas about headphones, you can always email Vergecast
Speaker 3:  verge.com Alex and I will be back on Friday to talk about crazy
Speaker 3:  looking monitors, John Deere hackers, Android 13, and a whole
Speaker 3:  bunch of other stuff. We'll see you then rock and roll.