# Transcript
ID: 113b45d0-720a-11ed-863d-3705d666b03c
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Elon Musk meets with Tim Cook, Neuralink's show and tell, and FTX's collapse
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-1407168016826313377/6158705326674101002/s93290-US-5255s-1669962206.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, Alex Cranz, and Alex Heath discuss this week in Elon Musk, everything that went wrong with FTX, and the latest gadget news.
Speaker 1:  Today in the Verge cast, the fake war between Twitter and Apple. Then Sam
Speaker 1:  Bankman, free of ftx, just can't stop admitting to fraud. And of course,
Speaker 1:  all the catching news from this week that's coming up right after
Speaker 1:  this.
Speaker 4:  Hello. Welcome to the Ro Cast, the flagship podcast, talking to
Speaker 4:  the New York Times. Even though your lawyer says, don't do
Speaker 4:  that, I'm your friend Eli, Alex Franz is here.
Speaker 5:  I'm your friend who thinks you should always do that. Do whatever the lawyer
Speaker 5:  says. Do the opposite. I,
Speaker 4:  I have to encourage the audience to stop listening to this podcast immediately.
Speaker 4:  I don't know what else to tell you. Just
Speaker 5:  It just, just if it's like, if it's of journalistic value to me
Speaker 5:  personally, do the opposite.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Alex Heath is here.
Speaker 6:  Hey, I'm, you know, I'm actually coming around to hating free speech in
Speaker 6:  America.
Speaker 4:  It's really quite, quite tiresome.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it's becoming annoying, honestly.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, you know, I think we should just shut it down. Let's, let's go back
Speaker 4:  to what the founders intended, which was quite honestly not the free speech
Speaker 4:  that you expect today. That's a different podcast. We can get into it later.
Speaker 4:  I will note for the listener, it's to Alex's today know
Speaker 4:  David Pierce. David and his family produced a
Speaker 4:  child. Congratulations. David, tell me what said child
Speaker 4:  is named. I can only assume that he's named the
Speaker 4:  baby Bluetooth 2.1 plus EDR Pierce.
Speaker 4:  That's just my guess.
Speaker 6:  He's holding up different cables going, this is
Speaker 6:  sbt, this is three
Speaker 4:  S b A Pierce, but David not be here for the next few weeks.
Speaker 4:  Congrats to David. We're gonna have a bunch of people filling in. It's gonna
Speaker 4:  be a good time for everyone except David who's not gonna get any sleep. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  But but he got a baby out of it.
Speaker 4:  You got a baby out. Don't
Speaker 6:  Say that. Childbirth I've heard is amazing.
Speaker 4:  Well, David do, he just had to, to like, anyhow, congrats David
Speaker 4:  Tweet at him. I'm sure he'll like to hear from you. Okay,
Speaker 4:  so let's, why are we talking about the Tiresomeness free speech for America?
Speaker 4:  It's because Elon and Twitter and Apple went at it again this week.
Speaker 4:  We gotta talk about that. Sam Bankman Freed won't stop
Speaker 4:  talking to reporters. What Ftx like just won't, that
Speaker 2:  Will not be free speech
Speaker 4:  For him. Yes. This is the speech that will put him in jail. It will lead
Speaker 4:  him directly to not being free. And I, you know, I was at the deal book conference
Speaker 4:  for that big interview with Andrea Sorkin. Well, where by the way, speaking
Speaker 4:  of Free Speech America, Mike Pence said, first I revere the Constitution
Speaker 4:  and then was asked about content moderation was like, well you can't shout
Speaker 4:  fire in a crowd theater. Can I just say for the record, for the VER has audience,
Speaker 4:  the fire in a crowded theater line. I'm sure you've heard me or Addie say
Speaker 4:  this before in the show. That line is just a throwaway line
Speaker 4:  in a Supreme Court case called Shank in which the Supreme Court
Speaker 4:  held the government could arrest you for telling people not to go into
Speaker 4:  the military.
Speaker 6:  We are what, less than five minutes in. I'm just so you knew I was already
Speaker 6:  talking about fire in a crowded theater.
Speaker 4:  It's gone. It's, it's just like driving me crazy. This
Speaker 6:  Episode's
Speaker 4:  Over that case was overturned in another case called Brandenburg. So it's
Speaker 4:  like this like throwaway line. A case got overturned and everyone keeps saying
Speaker 4:  it tries bonkers. Yesterday, Mike Pence, the former vice president of the
Speaker 4:  United States was, you know, he was doing Mike Pence. He's like, well, you
Speaker 4:  know, you can't say fire. And I out loud was like,
Speaker 4:  Ugh. In like a row of reporters who all looked at me. So
Speaker 4:  Mike, if you're listening I can walk you through
Speaker 6:  It. The best part of this was SPF and Mike Pence were on stage together,
Speaker 6:  right?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. At the same time. Yeah, no, they were not on stage together. Same time
Speaker 4:  they were nearly back to back. Impressive conference. Incredible lineup of
Speaker 4:  speakers. Again, I believe that Mike Pence is a listener of this show.
Speaker 6:  Absolutely. Very
Speaker 4:  Sharp feelings about htm I, CEC
Speaker 6:  Pence and spf. Really two excellent figures.
Speaker 6:  Two excellent public figures that we should all aspire to be one day.
Speaker 4:  Yeah
Speaker 2:  Baby.
Speaker 4:  You know, I keep telling this, I told this show maybe a hundred trips yesterday.
Speaker 4:  It's like, I know my limit as a reporter is like a tech reporter.
Speaker 4:  Like I can't cross over into politics or general news
Speaker 4:  cuz I just can't figure out how to pretend that I care about what Mike
Speaker 4:  Pence has to say. Like I just can't, I can't turn it on.
Speaker 4:  I'm like, yep, there, there's,
Speaker 6:  Well he has a really great book about his time in office. Eli.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, don't read it. Andrew Ross can actually did it.
Speaker 6:  It's free speech. He should read it.
Speaker 4:  So the book is called, so Help Me God. And yesterday Sorkin was, he was saying
Speaker 4:  goodbye to Pence. He looked at him and said, so help me God Thank you. Which
Speaker 4:  was deeply funny. Wow. Okay. Wow. We'll get to SPF
Speaker 4:  on that stage and all the interviews and what's going on at FTX in a
Speaker 4:  bit. Let's start with Twitter, apple Tim Cook
Speaker 4:  giving Elon a tour of the Apple campus, which
Speaker 4:  was a weird outcome of this whole thing. It was just a weird
Speaker 4:  week of like the culture war and
Speaker 4:  Elon wanting to launch Twitter Blue and the Apple tax all
Speaker 4:  just colliding.
Speaker 6:  Ron DeSantis. Ron
Speaker 4:  Desant just like the most crazy that you could get. Heath,
Speaker 4:  what's going on?
Speaker 6:  Oh, what is going on? It looks like Musk and Cook squashed the
Speaker 6:  beef Musk started the week saying Apple, you know, do they
Speaker 6:  hate free speech in America? No. Spoiler alert, they hate it in China, not
Speaker 6:  America. Yeah. But saying this and then you know, complaining about the
Speaker 6:  30%. This was a few days after Phil Shiller had
Speaker 6:  mysteriously, you know, the head of the app store deleted his Twitter account
Speaker 6:  after Trump had been reinstated. The vibes were starting to shift between
Speaker 6:  Apple and Twitter. Why is this important? Our listeners are smart
Speaker 6:  but I should just say Twitter, wolves probably ceased to exist if Apple ever
Speaker 6:  decided to kick it off of its app store. So Apple is its most critical
Speaker 6:  source of distribution. Also taxing Blue. The
Speaker 6:  subscription product that Elon is essentially betting the future of the company
Speaker 6:  on. And so there was some speculation as to is he critiquing Apple
Speaker 6:  because he's mad about the 30% or has Apple done this thing that it does
Speaker 6:  sometimes quietly behind the scenes with apps
Speaker 6:  and say, Hey, we don't like what we're seeing on here.
Speaker 6:  There's too much, you know, x I think you all Roth
Speaker 6:  Twitter's former head of trust and safety had said it in New York Times op-ed,
Speaker 6:  that, you know, there were people at Apple who had raised concerns about
Speaker 6:  there being too much nudity on the platform before for
Speaker 6:  example. So you know, Musk comes in, he fires a lot of the, you
Speaker 6:  know, moderators talks about letting pretty much anything
Speaker 6:  go amnesty for all the band accounts. I could imagine Apple got concerned,
Speaker 6:  Twitter is wanting to push an update for the new to Relaunch Blue, which
Speaker 6:  got delayed again this week. But Apple's tied up in all that. And they have
Speaker 6:  the power to actually keep the Twitter app from being updated
Speaker 6:  until Twitter meets whatever their specific slash
Speaker 6:  vague demands are that they don't publicly articulate because they're
Speaker 6:  Apple somehow this all led to Elon Musk and Tim
Speaker 6:  Cook walking Apple Park together around, have you been
Speaker 6:  there to that, to that specific body of water? Eli? Yes. Or a Kranz?
Speaker 6:  Yes. It's beautiful. So I imagine like if you're an Apple engineer and you're
Speaker 6:  out there taking lunch, taking a call and maybe that's like a normal thing
Speaker 6:  to see. I, I doubt it, but I would've loved to have seen the entourage or
Speaker 6:  laugh.
Speaker 5:  So it was definitely Tim Cook cuz we, I saw the photo and I saw
Speaker 5:  the shadow. Would we confirm
Speaker 6:  This? Yeah, there was some shadow analysis done and it looked like him. What
Speaker 5:  If we had like a cardboard stand-in? It
Speaker 6:  Could not even be just given the state of Twitter. You know, that could have
Speaker 6:  been a fake account that tweeted that. We don't actually know that that was
Speaker 6:  Musk. I
Speaker 4:  Will say that we were told Apple employees had seen the two
Speaker 4:  of them walk around together, like very specifically like
Speaker 4:  that. Like they did it that way so that it would get out.
Speaker 4:  Like they made a show of the two of them walking around such that other
Speaker 4:  people would see them walking around to so that they wouldn't have to confirm
Speaker 4:  it officially. Which is,
Speaker 5:  And we assume it was because he wanted to talk about the 30%, which
Speaker 5:  Twitter wouldn't actually have to pay because it's less for these kind of
Speaker 5:  subscriptions.
Speaker 4:  Well it's 30% the first year. So there, there this is like,
Speaker 5:  But then it like drops,
Speaker 4:  Right? It drops to 15 in the second year. This is when I say
Speaker 4:  like this whole story is out of
Speaker 4:  control. We've done this before. I've been here, I
Speaker 4:  live here, I built a, I have a vacation home in the app
Speaker 4:  store like Tim Sweeney, you know, he
Speaker 4:  sails the ship here once a year to yell about it. Like
Speaker 4:  we spend a lot of time talking about these policies. They're not
Speaker 4:  great. I don't think that the vast majority of the tech
Speaker 4:  industry loves the duopoly power of Apple and Google when
Speaker 4:  it comes to their stores and especially these fees for in-app purchases.
Speaker 4:  Right? And I know that that's true because there
Speaker 4:  were trials about it because
Speaker 4:  Epic sued these companies over those policies.
Speaker 4:  The trial took a month, apple won the Google one is like
Speaker 4:  ongoing. The Apple one is all the way up at the court of appeals. They've
Speaker 4:  already had arguments like that's where we're all the way
Speaker 4:  there and now it's because of Elon. We're like starting at the beginning
Speaker 4:  and he's literally tweeting, did you know Apple charges a fee?
Speaker 4:  And it's, to me it's, there's an element of
Speaker 4:  bad faith embedded in that you don't say, well
Speaker 4:  that's like the most gentle way of saying
Speaker 5:  I have a question though. Was the 30%, the 30% is the first year you're on,
Speaker 5:  you're on the app store, right? Like the first year you have the
Speaker 4:  For a subscription product. Yes.
Speaker 5:  Didn't Twitter already launch this launch this subscription
Speaker 5:  product?
Speaker 4:  So the Twitter blue, which was I blew is $4 a month. I paid for that version
Speaker 4:  of Blue cuz that was the one that on our site and many others
Speaker 4:  got like blocked the ads. So if you clicked on a link to our site
Speaker 4:  from Twitter and you were paying for Twitter Blue, we wouldn't show you the
Speaker 4:  ads and we would get like, you know, sense we would get, we would click pennies
Speaker 4:  from you. This is part of your Twitter blue subscription. Thank you. The
Speaker 4:  Spotify, the business model that Spotify has used to make so many artists
Speaker 4:  Rich had finally come to publishing by your $4 a month Twitter
Speaker 4:  blue subscription. But I was paying for that one cuz I thought it was nice
Speaker 4:  to pay the publishers that I visit most often
Speaker 4:  directly. Was I mostly paying the company that I work for? Yes,
Speaker 4:  but I was paying for that one and that one was indeed an in-app
Speaker 4:  purchase. And I had talked to Cavan BPO who
Speaker 4:  was two heads of product ago. Alex.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, actually, yeah,
Speaker 4:  yeah. I dunno how to describe it. Kaban was the head of product of Twitter.
Speaker 4:  He was, he was reasonably successful for a Twitter, had a product under
Speaker 4:  Dorsey and he was on decoder and I spent a lot of time asking
Speaker 4:  him about the 30%, 15% fee. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Because everything Twitter wanted to do at that time
Speaker 4:  ran into the fee, this is Twitter Blue
Speaker 4:  expanding it. This is, they were gonna do a competitor, a sub stack,
Speaker 4:  you know, the swirl of NFT nonsense
Speaker 4:  was raging. It was like NFT summer. And I was like, what are you gonna do
Speaker 4:  about these fees? And he was very clear in that interview.
Speaker 4:  We are not, not in the business of skirting the platform real. So we're gonna
Speaker 4:  pay the money and try to build our businesses the right way. And maybe if
Speaker 4:  we get enough leverage we can go talk to Apple. So that's where Twitter
Speaker 4:  was this new version of Blue $8. He
Speaker 4:  needs every one of those pennies to make up for the lost advertising revenue.
Speaker 4:  Right.
Speaker 5:  But my question is, did Apple restart the clock was Apple
Speaker 5:  like, oh, new owner. All right, we're back to 30%. You gotta wait a whole
Speaker 5:  year.
Speaker 4:  No, no, no, no. Cuz it's a new product. It doesn't matter.
Speaker 5:  Oh, it doesn't matter. Okay.
Speaker 4:  Right. It's the consumer, it's not the company. So I sign
Speaker 4:  up the first year that I subscribe to you Alex
Speaker 4:  Kranz, and that purchase Apple will take 30%. The second year
Speaker 4:  of my subscription to you is 15%. Okay. But that's per product,
Speaker 4:  per customer.
Speaker 5:  Okay.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I, I actually think we're maybe overplaying the importance of the
Speaker 6:  30%. Elon has even talked internally since he took over about
Speaker 6:  how they're intentionally only doing blue through iOS because they want to
Speaker 6:  use Apple's payments layer and security
Speaker 6:  because they don't have it in house. They don't have the ability to do
Speaker 6:  it. So I don't actually think Musk has a problem with the 30%.
Speaker 6:  If anything, he was probably sending out grenades because a conversation
Speaker 6:  had started to happen where Apple was going. And this is exposing the reality
Speaker 6:  of Silicon Valley, which is that Apple is Silicon Valley's strongest
Speaker 6:  speech regulator. They just don't call themselves that. And that's because
Speaker 6:  they routinely will go to a social network if they don't like what they're
Speaker 6:  seeing or they don't like the direction something is going. I mean they booted
Speaker 6:  Parlor, this is the most famous example of them actually.
Speaker 5:  Whoa, whoa, whoa. That's not the most famous example.
Speaker 6:  What is the most famous example?
Speaker 5:  Movie gate at Tumblr?
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Okay. I I know it all comes back to Tum. It
Speaker 5:  Always comes back to Tumblr. Always.
Speaker 6:  I would say Parlor in the moment it was in was a bigger deal. Yeah. But,
Speaker 6:  but Apple is, Silicon Valley's defacto speech are
Speaker 6:  this because of the way they leveraged the store. What probably happened
Speaker 6:  around the time Schiller deleted his account was Twitter got a message
Speaker 6:  saying, Hey, we're noticing the direction that the site's
Speaker 6:  going. All the reports we saw early on about the spike in
Speaker 6:  racist tweets, hateful tweets, you fired all your
Speaker 6:  moderators. We have concerns here. And guess what Twitter's trying to queue
Speaker 6:  in the revamp of Blue, which they need to push an update for which
Speaker 6:  Apple can hold. And they do this all the time where they don't say we're
Speaker 6:  gonna remove you. They say, ah, this update, you know, it would be a shame
Speaker 6:  if it never, you know, came out. And that's probably
Speaker 6:  what was going on. And you know, Elon actually
Speaker 6:  responded to our own Jake Kas earlier in the week when Jake
Speaker 6:  asked directly, is Apple threatening you all or making
Speaker 6:  moderation demands? And he said yes. And so that
Speaker 6:  conversation with Cook was probably Elon saying, no, look like
Speaker 6:  I care about this stuff. You know, I don't want the bad stuff and
Speaker 6:  Cook going, okay, okay now gimme my 30% and, and Musk
Speaker 6:  left.
Speaker 5:  So definitely just real quick, it definitely definitely wasn't
Speaker 5:  him going and begging Tim Cook to do what Tim Cook has repeatedly
Speaker 5:  refused to do and buy Twitter.
Speaker 6:  I don't Well it's kind of amazing that this is what got Elon a meeting
Speaker 6:  with Tim Cook because if we all remember there was some reporting, I don't
Speaker 6:  remember if this was two years ago, three years ago, about how there were
Speaker 6:  conversations where Elon maybe wanted Apple to look at buying Tesla many
Speaker 6:  years ago when it was struggling and Tim Cook like didn't answer his
Speaker 6:  call. Yeah. And, and Cook was like, we've never spoken and
Speaker 6:  it only took buying, you know, Twitter for 44 billion to get a meeting with
Speaker 6:  Cook.
Speaker 4:  So. Well no, we can, we can unpack that further. So I think Alex, the, the
Speaker 4:  general sweep of what you've laid out is correct. Right. What
Speaker 4:  we also know is that what for Facebook
Speaker 4:  or Instagram or any of the big companies, it's,
Speaker 4:  it's not just an irregular series of conversations with Apple,
Speaker 4:  right? Yes. These, if you run an app like Twitter or Instagram or whatever
Speaker 4:  it is, your relationship with App
Speaker 4:  Review, like you're in each other's pockets. Yes. Cause those
Speaker 4:  companies are pushing updates constantly. That's why their release notes
Speaker 4:  are so bad in their apps. Like it's just like bug figs is and other improvements,
Speaker 4:  it's because they're, they're just like hundreds of updates, right. That
Speaker 4:  go into these apps constantly and they wanna push them out really fast to
Speaker 4:  support whatever they're doing at the other companies.
Speaker 4:  There's basically an entire staff of people that just
Speaker 4:  manages Apple. Right? Like you're in charge of these
Speaker 4:  app reviewers, you're going to Phil Short, Eddie Q are your best friends,
Speaker 4:  take 'em out to dinner, take 'em out to like get it done. Yeah. Elon
Speaker 4:  fired all those people. So there's a, there's
Speaker 4:  I would say like yes, maybe Apple's a little worried Yes.
Speaker 4:  Whatever. At the same time the way they express those
Speaker 4:  concerns and the very true implicit threat
Speaker 4:  of if you don't meet our demands we can kick you off the
Speaker 4:  store. Elon just doesn't have the people C can translate
Speaker 4:  the Apple weirdness for him Yeah.
Speaker 4:  To manage that relationship. Yeah. And I think this just quickly
Speaker 4:  spiraled out of control where Apple is probably saying
Speaker 4:  stuff that almost always says that's, that's my like vague
Speaker 4:  understanding of it. That from Apple's perspective, this was just the normal
Speaker 4:  course of business. And like if you're not used to them,
Speaker 4:  mafia sort of threat is like very threatening.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  You gotta go make your pilgrimage if you're,
Speaker 4:  Yeah. So Elon was like, they threatened me and Apple's like no, no, this
Speaker 4:  is just the basic, this is just like the foundational threat.
Speaker 5:  So we didn't even take this mad out of the car, we left it, we're just
Speaker 5:  knocking. We're just saying hi, what's,
Speaker 6:  He's like, can I tell you about a thing called app tracking
Speaker 6:  transparency?
Speaker 4:  So like, so here's what we did. We destroyed ME'S business
Speaker 4:  overnight and made it seem like we're the good guys. That's what we're able
Speaker 4:  to do to
Speaker 6:  You. It's just, this is such a strange dynamic because as we also found out
Speaker 6:  this week and it, it makes perfect sense to where, I wish I would've just
Speaker 6:  thought of this earlier. Apple is Twitter's largest advertiser. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  So not only is Twitter totally reliant on Apple to
Speaker 6:  survive from a distribution perspective, they also need their
Speaker 6:  money to just like pay the bills.
Speaker 4:  This is the question mark I have. I don't know why Apple is Twitter's biggest
Speaker 4:  advertiser. I don't know what they get out of it because
Speaker 6:  They hate Facebook. Where else are they going to advertise on social? So
Speaker 6:  I mean like Apple famously will not even put Facebook in like
Speaker 6:  an app store list of like apps you need for the holidays. Like Apple
Speaker 6:  will not touch Facebook or any of their properties. They also don't really
Speaker 6:  care about targeting as we
Speaker 4:  See.
Speaker 6:  So if you're, if you're them like Twitter's actually the perfect platform.
Speaker 6:  It's like just a brandy advertising like thing
Speaker 6:  for events and live stuff which they do all the time that promoted
Speaker 6:  hashtags. It makes perfect sense that Apple would actually be Twitter's
Speaker 6:  largest advertiser. I'm just kicking myself that I didn't think of it sooner
Speaker 4:  And now and that spend is going down, although there is some reporting that
Speaker 4:  it has gone up.
Speaker 6:  Well you can't just, Twitter is not plug and play like Facebook is where
Speaker 6:  it's a lot of direct response advertisers that are running like
Speaker 6:  hyper, you know, measurable campaigns that can be turned or on or off
Speaker 6:  at a dime. Twitter's much more brand centric. We've talked about this on
Speaker 6:  past shows and you can't, you can't just claw back everything immediately.
Speaker 6:  Although it seems very real that Apple has significantly clawed back at spend
Speaker 6:  though not all of it.
Speaker 4:  So that's one piece, right. Which is the
Speaker 4:  overreacting to the threat of app store
Speaker 4:  control. Which is very funny.
Speaker 4:  Like I, I think app store control is bad. I think if you have listened to
Speaker 4:  the show for more than five minutes, you know that I think Apple's control
Speaker 4:  of innovation on its phone is maybe a little bit more than
Speaker 4:  it should be. Yeah. And that's like me being
Speaker 4:  nice, but it's still there and it's also
Speaker 4:  just everyone knows it. Like we've, we've done 15
Speaker 4:  rounds of this story.
Speaker 5:  It was kind of like when like your parent calls you after an Apple
Speaker 5:  event and says, well did you hear they had a new iPhone? And you're like,
Speaker 5:  yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah definitely. Like
Speaker 4:  Is this, but then actually my mom lately is like, what does the new one do?
Speaker 4:  And I have to be like
Speaker 6:  Dynamic island
Speaker 5:  Parents are not impressed by the dynamic island.
Speaker 4:  It's not a point for that
Speaker 6:  Black black box on the top. Now you can't move.
Speaker 4:  I will say that my mom, first of all, my mom cried
Speaker 4:  when Steve Jobs died. It's a real fact. She was very sad about it. And now
Speaker 4:  lately she, whenever she's unhappy with her phone, she's like, Steve Chop
Speaker 4:  would've never signed a film like this. It's like perfect.
Speaker 6:  Can you imagine Steve Jobs negotiating with Elon this week?
Speaker 4:  He wouldn't. All I can imagine I would spend the rest of the show just writing
Speaker 4:  out that negotiation. He
Speaker 5:  Would've
Speaker 4:  Destroyed it. Cause he wouldn't put up with any of it. This is actually,
Speaker 4:  I think the important thing, this is why Elon ended up on
Speaker 4:  the Apple campus because Tim Cook is
Speaker 4:  an underrated, savvy political operator. Right.
Speaker 4:  If you think about Tim Cook and what he accomplished over the past five
Speaker 4:  years, yet we can name a lot of things actually at the top of the
Speaker 4:  list is managing Donald Trump, Foxcon and China
Speaker 4:  through a trade war and coming out having manufactured and
Speaker 4:  shipped war iPhones than ever before. Cause that was not
Speaker 4:  a guaranteed situation at all. Well it's
Speaker 5:  Not going great for him with Foxcon right now,
Speaker 4:  But it's not, it's, it's going very badly with him for Foxcon right now.
Speaker 4:  But in terms of his understanding Yeah. Of how to
Speaker 4:  manage that kind of personality,
Speaker 4:  he has more practice than maybe any business owner in America.
Speaker 4:  Right. And Alex, he, well
Speaker 4:  and two Alex's and he keeps reminding me a lot
Speaker 4:  of what we're seeing from Elon right now tracks with Trump. Like it's very
Speaker 4:  reminiscent of Trump. Yeah. Yeah. So I don't know this for
Speaker 4:  sure, but I have spent over a decade paying a lot of attention
Speaker 4:  to Apple and knowing a lot of people in and around there
Speaker 4:  like, you know, sometimes I'll just be in my house like pouring
Speaker 4:  coffee and my wife will walk into the room and be like, why are you tense?
Speaker 4:  And I haven't said a word to her and we haven't been in the same room for
Speaker 4:  more than 10 seconds and she knows, and the vibe's coming off
Speaker 4:  of Apple were, were that right? Like you just pay a lot of attention
Speaker 4:  to this company, you see. They
Speaker 6:  Were like, I'm charging my mouse right now and it's upside down and I'm just
Speaker 6:  pissed.
Speaker 4:  And my sense is he started doing these tweets about Apple on free speech
Speaker 4:  and the store and the 30% and they wanted to come out
Speaker 4:  storming and basically being like, yeah, it's our
Speaker 4:  store 30% like our way or the highway, we just beat
Speaker 4:  Epic screw you. And then the weird
Speaker 4:  g p tweets started and Ted Cruz lit up and Ron DeSantis lit up and
Speaker 4:  Mike Lee who co-sponsored the antitrust bills lit up.
Speaker 4:  Tucker Carlson did a segment and the culture war started a
Speaker 4:  McKenna wrote a great piece about this Apple, like Elon drove
Speaker 4:  Apple into the most
Speaker 4:  unpredictable ideologically incoherent part of America, which is the Go
Speaker 4:  P culture war. And they realized, oh this somehow this is going
Speaker 4:  to end with a bill that allows side loading on the app.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And they decided that instead of going on offense,
Speaker 4:  Tim Cook would be a politician and he would charm Elon with a walker
Speaker 4:  in a circle around the campus. And they get, and I'm pretty sure that that
Speaker 4:  is just the, the flow of that decision that occurred because
Speaker 4:  unlike Epic and Fortnite, when they went fully on
Speaker 4:  offense, they see this other thing, this other thing that Elon
Speaker 4:  has a handle into, which is just the wildness of the culture
Speaker 4:  war. Like Fortnite did not get a Tucker Carlson segment about free speech.
Speaker 6:  No, no. I mean what did Ron DeSantis say? It was basically like if Twitter
Speaker 6:  is banned by Apple, you know, we need to regulate Apple.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I mean that was the direct
Speaker 4:  Yeah. He was like, Congress should respond to this like raw demonstration
Speaker 4:  of monopoly power and it's like, first of all, it's
Speaker 4:  not that I'm not sympathetic to it. Yeah, right. We've had
Speaker 4:  like David Ci and Amy Klobuchar like have been on this show
Speaker 4:  talking about their antitrust builds. Yeah, I get it. But
Speaker 4:  the, the solution is like market competition. It's not,
Speaker 4:  we should punish Apple because they pissed off Elon. And when you're, I I
Speaker 4:  just think that level of unhinged actually made Apple
Speaker 4:  change its tactic away from what they did with Epic.
Speaker 4:  Which is we'll see you in court.
Speaker 5:  Like what's gonna happen though because we also have
Speaker 5:  Ireland who is saying you suck
Speaker 5:  to Twitter and is it seems ready to like fine it into
Speaker 5:  oblivion. So we have like we have
Speaker 4:  So wait, wait actually let's organize this conversation. Okay. So I think
Speaker 4:  Keith was saying let's put a bone out. Yeah. We should talk about the rest
Speaker 4:  of Twitter.
Speaker 6:  Okay. And, and to put a bow on this, you know, with how smooth Tim is
Speaker 6:  Elon tweets after the meeting goes, look we resolved this
Speaker 6:  misunderstanding was the word he used where like two days before, maybe even
Speaker 6:  a day before he was tweeting at Jake and other people being like, apple hates
Speaker 6:  free speech in America. He meets with Tim Cook for 30 minutes and
Speaker 6:  is like, it was a misunderstanding. Tim was clear that Apple never
Speaker 6:  considered banning us. Everything's chill and then he follows Tim Cook on
Speaker 6:  Twitter and then it's
Speaker 4:  Like he deletes his, I'm gonna go to war with you tweets. Right, right.
Speaker 6:  So like if you, if you're gonna comment the king, you best not miss. I mean
Speaker 6:  that was the lesson I think for Elon and Apple this week.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Wait, who's the king in this scenario? Tim
Speaker 4:  Cook. It's Tim Cook. Is
Speaker 5:  It because
Speaker 6:  Tim Cook? Absolutely.
Speaker 5:  No. Cuz Elon threw a giant tantrum and got what he couldn't get for
Speaker 5:  years, which was a meeting with Tim Cook.
Speaker 4:  That's not, he's the richest fan in the world. If he really wants a meeting
Speaker 4:  with Tim Cook, he can get a meeting with
Speaker 6:  Tim also. Like Tim Cook didn't come to Twitter, apple, you know, like, like
Speaker 6:  Elon came to Apple. Like there's this, Tim Cook's not
Speaker 6:  gonna go meet. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Tim Cook is not wandering the, the desolate empty halls with
Speaker 4:  Twitter. He's like, we're not even getting
Speaker 4:  in the building, we're gonna walk around outside
Speaker 5:  Kitchen sink sitting over there.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I mean that's the, I mean we have no idea what was said in this
Speaker 4:  conversation, but Microsoft has tried for years to get out of the 30%
Speaker 4:  cut. Microsoft has tried for years to evade after rules around game
Speaker 4:  streaming and give Apple and they can't get there. And so I I think
Speaker 4:  you'd, there's no way that Elon got anything outta the deal and I have
Speaker 4:  no idea what Tim traded ahead to
Speaker 4:  make him tweet what he tweeted right there. There has to be, they're both
Speaker 4:  savvy business people. Yeah. They're not bad at this. They had to
Speaker 4:  have come, he didn't just tell him, he like smelled good and he was like,
Speaker 4:  oh I forgive you. Like he was, they exchanged something and we have no idea
Speaker 4:  what that
Speaker 6:  Exchange was. The most logical explanation was Apple was threatening to keep
Speaker 6:  Twitter's app update in purgatory because of concerns about content moderation.
Speaker 6:  Elon assured Tim that he had a handle on it, which
Speaker 6:  debatable, but he obviously assured Tim and they left the meeting
Speaker 6:  Tim going, okay we won't, we won't keep you in purgatory. That's the most
Speaker 6:  likely explanation of what happened. I actually think 30% was
Speaker 6:  maybe not raised at all. I would be shocked if it actually was cuz like that's
Speaker 6:  not, that's a non-negotiable thing. Right. That's
Speaker 5:  Well it is negotiable depending on who you are.
Speaker 5:  Just,
Speaker 4:  It's, yeah. It's negotiable. If you get a bunch of right wing members
Speaker 4:  of Congress to sign in Charville,
Speaker 4:  it's right there and it's, it was on an unlikely
Speaker 4:  outcome. Yeah. Right, right. Like that's, and I, I think
Speaker 4:  Apple recognized that and that's why they played it this way instead of the
Speaker 4:  way that they have been playing. By the way Apple's position this whole time
Speaker 4:  has been clear since the EPIC trial. Yeah. You can do
Speaker 4:  side loading on our store. Yeah, you can whatever the stuff we're forced
Speaker 4:  to in South Korea and other countries, developers still have to pay us
Speaker 4:  the money. Right. Right. It's not just you can get around us, it's
Speaker 4:  what we actually care about is the money and the decision, at least in
Speaker 4:  this country. The judge basically said, yeah,
Speaker 4:  apple is entitled to being paid for its intellectual property and its
Speaker 4:  effort developing iOS. So even if the bill has passed Apple is,
Speaker 4:  they've been pretty clear and consistent this whole time and they have rolled
Speaker 4:  out this system in other countries that require, you know, other kinds of
Speaker 4:  in-app purchasing systems to be present in iOS. The Apple still wants a cut,
Speaker 4:  they don't really care. Yeah. You might not use your credit card process
Speaker 4:  processor. What Apple's getting it's, it's money and I think that's actually
Speaker 4:  the non-negotiable part, whether it's in-app purchases or whatever else.
Speaker 4:  And I think Elon is, is smart. I think we can agree on that.
Speaker 4:  But coming late to the game and pointing right at Tim Cook's
Speaker 4:  services revenue line and being like, what if Les is like, you
Speaker 4:  gotta try harder than that,
Speaker 6:  That's a reality of life. The sun will rise and Apple will get its money.
Speaker 6:  Yeah,
Speaker 4:  Exactly. All right, let's talk about Twitter itself. If you've been reporting
Speaker 4:  on it. Yes. What's the vibe in there right
Speaker 6:  Now? Oh, well I think Monday was like the perfect like
Speaker 6:  just microcosm of life inside Twitter. So Elon sends this
Speaker 6:  email at like 3:00 AM as he's prone to do, saying
Speaker 6:  we're gonna do code reviews again, bring your lines of code,
Speaker 6:  which any engineer will tell you is an absurd
Speaker 6:  exercise. And reminded again that he expects managers to be coding as well.
Speaker 6:  Engineering managers. I think his direct quote was being unable to do so
Speaker 6:  as like a calvary captain who can't ride a horse. Does he like, and
Speaker 6:  does
Speaker 5:  He know how like anything
Speaker 5:  works outside of like the Elon Musk crafted
Speaker 5:  world? Does he just understand
Speaker 6:  He's the richest man in the world, Kranz. He knows all, he knows all, he
Speaker 6:  knows
Speaker 5:  Everything. He
Speaker 6:  Knows everything. We respect Capitalism in America and free speech
Speaker 6:  and in that order. So anyway, he sends this email, everyone's like
Speaker 6:  frantically trying to figure out what this means. Does this mean more people
Speaker 6:  are about to get fired? The code review doesn't happen. So everyone shows
Speaker 6:  up to Twitter. San Francisco offices amazing for the Elon code review
Speaker 6:  Monday evening. It does. He's not the, the no one can find Elon. There's
Speaker 6:  no code reviews that happen. The fire alarm does get pulled and a bunch of
Speaker 6:  engineers end up spending about an hour standing outside of Twitter's office
Speaker 6:  as they figure out what goes on with the fire alarm. So that was like just
Speaker 6:  Monday and then
Speaker 4:  Progressively fire alarm got pulled.
Speaker 6:  Yes.
Speaker 4:  That's really
Speaker 6:  Good. So that's, that's just like, and and then you have this
Speaker 6:  remarkable thing where you have, and I think Kranz you were wanting to mention
Speaker 6:  this earlier. Yeah. Twitter's VP of public policy who's based in
Speaker 6:  Ireland, sued the company to keep them from
Speaker 6:  firing her over the hardcore that she didn't say check the
Speaker 6:  yes to from a couple weeks ago. And she won. Like this is the first
Speaker 6:  example of a VP that I I've ever seen suing
Speaker 6:  to stay employed. Have, have we heard of this? Has this is this, I mean it's
Speaker 5:  Very common in like Europe because they have much stronger labor
Speaker 5:  laws there. So I think we've seen this repeatedly with
Speaker 5:  Twitter in Europe is that he has no grasp of labor laws there and he doesn't
Speaker 5:  understand that. Like no, absolutely he
Speaker 6:  Can't just fire. But I'm saying, but I'm saying a high ranking executive
Speaker 6:  suing a company to stay employed. Right.
Speaker 4:  Again, I think this is like a very European in America we solve our problems
Speaker 4:  with cash.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, that's true.
Speaker 4:  Right. So you're like, you're mad at your company in America, you see them,
Speaker 4:  you're like, pay me however much money I would've made the next year of employment
Speaker 4:  and then I'm done with you. Other countries, other legal systems, you,
Speaker 4:  other remedies are available. Like,
Speaker 5:  No, you have to hire me back.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, you're gonna hire me back. I still work here.
Speaker 6:  So it's just, it's just, I think it's an, and like she
Speaker 6:  was, she was technically like employed still under European law,
Speaker 6:  but like had been locked out of her systems and she, she's just like toiling
Speaker 6:  her thumbs. This is a VP of public policy being like, and now she's apparently
Speaker 6:  back in the slack.
Speaker 4:  It's like amazing. Well I can
Speaker 5:  Tell someone Germany, there's is either Germany or France, there's a
Speaker 5:  number of Twitter engineers who are also suing because they also got
Speaker 5:  fired and you can't fire them. You
Speaker 6:  Can't just do
Speaker 5:  That. Yeah. You have to give like a ton of notice and pay them out and all
Speaker 5:  of this. And they're like, no you, you broke the law. We're we're not America.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So he's, but he's also struggling. Like he's struggling with the labor
Speaker 5:  law there, but didn't the EU commissioner this week,
Speaker 5:  one of the EU commissioners say we're gonna like, what
Speaker 4:  Was it? Yeah, they've gotta have the data controllers that they, I mean the
Speaker 4:  EU is a very regulated environment, especially as it pertains to privacy
Speaker 4:  issues. And they're like, who all the people are gone. So get on
Speaker 5:  Your game. He told Mr. Briton, so this is from the Irish times. Mr.
Speaker 5:  Retton told Mr. Musk he must adhere to a checklist of rules
Speaker 5:  including ditching an arbitrary approach to reinstating band
Speaker 5:  users pursuing disinformation just aggressively and agreeing to an
Speaker 5:  extensive independent audit of the platform by next year.
Speaker 6:  None of that's gonna happen.
Speaker 5:  So I mean you say that, but the EU has a pretty good record of
Speaker 5:  like bodying tech companies
Speaker 6:  Finds, which I mean that's he
Speaker 5:  Fines for a company that needs to make how
Speaker 6:  Much money. Yeah, that has no money. Yeah, I know that's,
Speaker 5:  I think Ireland's the risk dark horse in this, this race for,
Speaker 5:  for Elon, he keeps ignoring the world
Speaker 6:  Exist. Whether the FTC decides fines, any evidence that they
Speaker 6:  have actually violated their compliance for, you know,
Speaker 6:  requirements in the eu. If either one of those, those
Speaker 6:  regulators decides to act on Twitter, that could legitimately put it outta
Speaker 6:  business. Right.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And so instead he's like, I'm gonna pick a fight with
Speaker 5:  Tim.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, well he did wear a suit for the meeting with the eu so
Speaker 6:  maybe he is taking that seriously.
Speaker 4:  Elon is not bad at getting government money. Yeah, yeah. In fact
Speaker 4:  it might be his greatest
Speaker 6:  Skill. It is. Tesla's the way Tesla makes money Yeah. Is
Speaker 4:  Carbon credits and grants and SpaceX is a government contractor.
Speaker 4:  So it's, I don't think that, I think we might, I might be saying that Tim
Speaker 4:  Cook is an underrated political operator. That's the main thing he does.
Speaker 4:  It's true. Elon is a pretty good political operator too. The difference
Speaker 4:  is Elon's businesses are monopolies, right? Like
Speaker 4:  where are you gonna go nasa, right? Like the sls like not doing it for
Speaker 4:  you. Like you got one choice, where are you gonna get Like, like
Speaker 4:  who are you gonna buy your carbon credits from Tesla. So there's just like
Speaker 4:  an element and if you're like a state governor and you want prove that you're
Speaker 4:  green, like you, you have a supercharge put in, right? Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Like I think there's like a, there's just a difference in
Speaker 4:  complexity that both of them face. And I think fundamentally
Speaker 4:  the EU stuff, he's, he's about to learn what it
Speaker 4:  takes to run a business there. And there's a reason that that a lot of these,
Speaker 4:  like when we talk about regulation in this country, like the VCs jump
Speaker 4:  out the world to be like there's a reason there's no innovative companies
Speaker 4:  in Europe. Which is not true. But that's the argument is the re
Speaker 4:  the regulatory environment is so insane that you can't do it. I think Elon
Speaker 4:  is trying to run this thing like a scrappy startup, but it is actually like
Speaker 4:  a world historically important communications platform
Speaker 4:  and the Europeans are, they care about it a lot. Yeah. What else is going
Speaker 4:  on inside of Twitter Alex? Is it, is it settled down?
Speaker 6:  I would say it's become very siloed. So like in inside Twitter
Speaker 6:  you used to be able to browse any Slack channels. See basically what any
Speaker 6:  team is working on that is stopped. So channels have all been set private.
Speaker 6:  He's doing these like inserting different language and different
Speaker 6:  emails to try to find leakers. Edicts are still being
Speaker 6:  mysteriously passed down from Tesla. People inside the company
Speaker 6:  about what Elon wants. The internal directory is not online. So
Speaker 6:  there's no, nobody really has any understanding of like who reports to who,
Speaker 6:  how orgs are set up. It's been communicated like in a team siloed
Speaker 6:  environment but not broadly. And you know, he said that like
Speaker 6:  this transitional period, he may get a lot of things wrong, but
Speaker 6:  you know, the idea is that in the near future
Speaker 6:  all this will become more visible, it'll make more sense and then he'll step
Speaker 6:  back and appoint a CEO I guess. Which, you know, I can't wait
Speaker 6:  to see who that is. But yeah, I would say right now it's still people just
Speaker 6:  going if, if you're not working on an Elon project, right? Which is like
Speaker 6:  encrypting dms, competing with YouTube by
Speaker 6:  adding video to Twitter and doing monetization blue, the revamp
Speaker 6:  of blue and verification. If you're not working on something like that or
Speaker 6:  cost cutting, you're kind of twiddling your thumbs and trying
Speaker 6:  to understand who your manager may or may not be tomorrow.
Speaker 4:  There is a lot of noise in, you know, wave
Speaker 4:  five of layoffs that Twitter wouldn't survive the World
Speaker 4:  Cup. Things were gonna start breaking. Has that started happening?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I'm glad you brought this up cuz like literally as we were talking
Speaker 6:  I got got another notification from a, from a musk boy
Speaker 6:  like referencing one of my tweets where I said, you know, Twitter employees
Speaker 6:  were telling me they expect the site to stop breaking and everyone's dunking,
Speaker 6:  you know, still waiting on this like yada yada. I just also like if you're
Speaker 6:  a musk boy and you're listening to this, like your experience with Twitter
Speaker 6:  is not indicative of everyone else's experience with Twitter.
Speaker 6:  So like just because you're not experiencing something breaking doesn't mean
Speaker 6:  stuff isn't breaking. We've seen like my timeline's gone bonkers a couple
Speaker 6:  times. I don't know about you guys where like all
Speaker 5:  My notifications don't work.
Speaker 6:  Notifications have been breaking. There was a a moment where SMS verification
Speaker 6:  wasn't working. There's been little glitches all over and I do
Speaker 6:  think we as the media, the the, the week of the first
Speaker 6:  purge where half of the employees were fired, we did maybe
Speaker 6:  buy a little bit into the hysteria of like, cuz we all have this weird relationship
Speaker 6:  with Twitter too, where we're all just like, oh what happens? I was part
Speaker 6:  of a Twitter space that went on for hours where it was like, what is Twitter
Speaker 6:  meant to you? What's gonna mean when it's gone yada yada. And I can
Speaker 6:  understand people trying to latch onto that and say the media like wants
Speaker 6:  this thing to fail and wants Elon to fail. And
Speaker 6:  I would just like, I can only speak for how I report, but I think for all
Speaker 6:  the people who are reporting on like what's happening inside Twitter, Casey,
Speaker 6:  Zoe, et cetera, we're just relaying what employees are telling
Speaker 6:  us. And there were a lot of current
Speaker 6:  and former Twitter employees with direct knowledge who were very,
Speaker 6:  very concerned based on the cuts Musk made, that it would lead to a catastrophic
Speaker 6:  outage very quickly. That's not like a reporter
Speaker 6:  saying, oh I'm like pontificating or just like assuming this is gonna happen.
Speaker 6:  This is, I'm just like, I'm saying what employees are telling me so you can
Speaker 6:  trust that or you cannot, that's fine. Like you don't have to whatever media's
Speaker 6:  fake. But that's, that was the real
Speaker 6:  concern and it's actually amazing that hasn't happened. I think it's a testament
Speaker 6:  to the people who already were maintaining Twitter, the fail safes that
Speaker 6:  were in place when you have a service this large and you have
Speaker 6:  any level of competency in how it's run, which, you know, Twitter didn't
Speaker 6:  have as much competency as it should have, but it did have a lot, there
Speaker 6:  are a lot of fail safes and just ways that, you know, the service can,
Speaker 6:  can stay operational even on, you know, a skeleton crew.
Speaker 6:  But that said, there are, you know, glitches and this isn't gonna
Speaker 6:  mean that like Twitter won't break at some point. It very, very well could.
Speaker 6:  Musk has like been pretty open about that. So I just wanted to address that
Speaker 6:  cuz like I'm still getting at messages about that. Well
Speaker 5:  Also the World Cup just started, right? Like we're not even to the ones where
Speaker 5:  people like line up and pack in the bars. I mean
Speaker 5:  I guess some of them are, we've seen some of that but like we're, we're just
Speaker 5:  in the beginnings of the real crunch period for the World Cup
Speaker 5:  traffic for them. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And it may, it may go off great and that will be great if Twitter doesn't
Speaker 6:  break. I don't want it to break, but there's, you know, there's
Speaker 6:  a lot of institutional knowledge that's gone. Yeah, like we were just talking
Speaker 6:  about with the app store stuff, you know, there's a lot of people that like
Speaker 6:  there was a moment where the wifi went out,
Speaker 5:  FTC regulations,
Speaker 6:  Compliance. Like there was a moment where Elon was in the New York
Speaker 6:  office and the wifi went out because like the server room where the wifi
Speaker 6:  was overheated and no one knew how to get in there and fix it cause like
Speaker 6:  he'd fire the person who knew how. So there's gonna be stuff like that that
Speaker 6:  just happens and that's, that's what Elon bought and that's what he did.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I think the, will it break right away that that
Speaker 4:  particular day was bonkers. Like it's software. Like I
Speaker 4:  think we've all experienced software that just sort of putters along.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, there was definitely a hysteria.
Speaker 6:  There was a hysteria
Speaker 4:  And
Speaker 5:  I think people were acknowledging it at the time. I think everybody was even
Speaker 5:  being like, I'm hysterical and I don't know what's happening. But like, so
Speaker 5:  I think people were pretty candid about it and it is just part
Speaker 5:  of that conversation where, where there's a both sides of them to this
Speaker 5:  whole thing. Everybody has to have like a team, they have to be Team Elon
Speaker 5:  or team Twitter or something. It's like
Speaker 4:  No team Twitter,
Speaker 5:  You don't,
Speaker 4:  Well so Elon keeps tweeting the numbers are up. Right, right. Engage,
Speaker 4:  time is up that users have gone up using the metric that he said was
Speaker 4:  totally fake, very confusing. I've
Speaker 4:  experienced the flip and I know a lot of people who are kind of on the flip
Speaker 4:  side of things where I took it off my phone. Yeah. Because my experience
Speaker 4:  of Twitter, in addition to just stuff breaking, like when my notifications
Speaker 4:  break, they break in the most deeply hilarious way. They just
Speaker 4:  recommend tweets from Elon
Speaker 4:  Like that that's, and I don't follow Elon, it's just like, here's another
Speaker 4:  tweet you might like. And it's like, no, you got this wrong. I don't need
Speaker 4:  more of this. This is why I took it off my phone. But I know a lot of people
Speaker 4:  in the past week or so who are like my experience
Speaker 4:  of Twitter is becoming more negative because he hasn't even let everybody
Speaker 4:  back on yet. But the people who remain are
Speaker 4:  like more inclined to yell at one another and they're more inclined to
Speaker 4:  test the limits of what is and isn't allowed anymore. And it's just
Speaker 4:  noisier. And more people are on Twitter talking about Twitter, which is just
Speaker 4:  the worst. And that to me is the real danger. Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 4:  Right. Is that the people you need to make it vibrant,
Speaker 4:  we'll get driven off or they'll quit or they'll find something new
Speaker 4:  or I think maybe what might be the healthiest outcome
Speaker 4:  will all just stop being addicted to social media feeds in
Speaker 4:  this specific way and like something else will emerge. Which is
Speaker 4:  really unusual if you just think about the number of times that that
Speaker 4:  kind of shift has even been possible over the last decade or
Speaker 4:  so. It's maybe three, like at best three I'm
Speaker 4:  thinking it's like Friendster to
Speaker 4:  MySpace. MySpace to to Facebook
Speaker 4:  and then the emergence of Twitter and then maybe
Speaker 4:  most recently the emergence of TikTok. Right. And like I I
Speaker 4:  said three and I, the friend started in MySpace. MySpace to Facebook. That
Speaker 4:  just is one that all happened in like 24
Speaker 6:  Months. Yeah I think snaps in there. There's there's some other shifts in
Speaker 6:  there. But
Speaker 5:  A lot of shifts though, right? Like I think one of the earliest ones wasn't
Speaker 5:  even Friendster. It was, it was Live Journal. Live Journal was a social media
Speaker 5:  platform. It was was really big, just was a different kind of social media
Speaker 5:  platform. And then everybody was like, oh, Russia's bought it. We gotta kill
Speaker 5:  it, we gotta leave this place. We can't have the Russians on us. This was
Speaker 5:  what, 2009 or something? And it didn't die
Speaker 5:  rapidly. I think that like, I would honestly say live journalists, the most
Speaker 5:  similar analogy to this where suddenly got a new owner, everybody
Speaker 5:  started to really question what they were doing on the service, why they
Speaker 5:  were doing it, and whether they were like being good people by using
Speaker 5:  this service owned by people who were potentially not good and might not
Speaker 5:  use their data correctly. And then what happened was it's a long slow
Speaker 5:  death. There were a ton of clones. Everybody said dream with this is the
Speaker 5:  new future
Speaker 4:  And dream with
Speaker 5:  No it means I'm sure people use it. And then a bunch of people migrated to
Speaker 5:  Tumblr but it took what, three or four or five years for that to happen.
Speaker 5:  It just happens like this long slow thing. We saw the same thing with Tumblr.
Speaker 5:  Like we've seen this happen with these smaller social media platforms, not
Speaker 5:  just the big ones. And in those smaller platforms where you do see these
Speaker 5:  big changes that upset the, the majority of the
Speaker 5:  users, it's not a big sudden shift because people
Speaker 5:  don't operate that way. Like Tumblr died and everybody said pillow
Speaker 5:  fort's the new thing and the same thing that's happening now with hi social
Speaker 5:  is happened with Pillow Fork where it couldn't handle
Speaker 6:  Fort what are you, what are you even talking? Yeah,
Speaker 4:  Alex is just making up service names. You're just
Speaker 6:  Saying words was it
Speaker 5:  Was, and I'm it's still
Speaker 4:  Exists. She's like cluck a duck that huge, huge few minute. But it but
Speaker 5:  But it was the same thing that happened though where they just said where
Speaker 5:  everybody's like, yeah we're gonna go to this. It broke it and it's
Speaker 5:  slowly coming back. But like we've seen a time, time again with these
Speaker 5:  smaller platforms that it isn't a sudden migration. It is always a very
Speaker 5:  slow thing.
Speaker 6:  No, yeah, people will experiment. You know, I noticed that Tap Bots
Speaker 6:  the maker of one of the best original Twitter clients tweet bot, they're
Speaker 6:  building a Macon client now. I actually just got on the beta. Thank you Paul.
Speaker 6:  And like there is interesting activity happening on
Speaker 6:  Macon. I don't think Macon's gonna necessarily like take the world by
Speaker 6:  storm. I think people don't wanna organize it or understand servers. Like
Speaker 6:  that's just an inherent Yeah. Human nature thing to like not give
Speaker 6:  a shit about servers, but,
Speaker 4:  But
Speaker 6:  At Macon's trying, there will be other stuff, but
Speaker 6:  I think like Twitter is really elon's to,
Speaker 6:  to mess up. Like either it will get fined out of existence or
Speaker 6:  he will not have anyone left who can actually
Speaker 6:  make it better and he's not able to hire for some reason. Which I think he
Speaker 6:  actually will. I think he actually, I've actually gotten random people emailing
Speaker 6:  me being like, do you know how I can apply to work at Twitter? Wow. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Like people, engineers,
Speaker 4:  You print out the last 50 pages, print out your code, just go over,
Speaker 4:  just hold em up above your head. Like say, or you
Speaker 5:  Just show up to one of his show ints. Like we had a Neurolink event this
Speaker 5:  week where almost nothing happened. He showed a bunch of old
Speaker 5:  videos and then he was like, maybe I'll stick a chip in my head one year
Speaker 5:  and you could watch him. I was watching, wait,
Speaker 4:  Hold on, let's take a break. We come back, we'll talk about
Speaker 4:  event seamlessly transition from monkeys wirelessly charging
Speaker 4:  their brains to Sandbank. We're gonna take a break.
Speaker 4:  I'm gonna figure out that transition. We'll be right
Speaker 4:  back.
Speaker 4:  Okay, we're back. Let's talk about near link briefly. We're
Speaker 4:  all Musk all the time. So you have the event. He did announce some things,
Speaker 4:  but the most improbable is that he will start
Speaker 4:  implanting brain implants in people within six months.
Speaker 5:  He originally promised in 2020 to do the brain implants.
Speaker 5:  So they were like, they were like, I think it was 20 18, 20
Speaker 5:  19. He said 2020 we're gonna be implanting these in humans. And
Speaker 5:  then 2020 came and then they're like, actually it's gonna be 2022.
Speaker 5:  And then Decem what? November 30th, 2022. They were
Speaker 5:  like, no, no, no, it's, it's six fronts, six months from now. But the majority
Speaker 5:  of the time for the Neurolink conversation was spent on like saying
Speaker 5:  we really don't do the monkeys enjoy being tested on.
Speaker 5:  We're totally fine because Neurolink has been getting a lot of flack for
Speaker 5:  the fact that it does a lot of animal testing. And it's like sometimes the
Speaker 5:  monkeys die. Don't worry about it. We're gonna put chips in people's brains.
Speaker 4:  Thousands of monkeys have died is what writers reported today. USA Today.
Speaker 5:  So many. Also you can control the mouse with
Speaker 5:  your brain slower than you could with your hand.
Speaker 4:  All I'm gonna tell you is the single most important part of this entire demo,
Speaker 4:  which was all for recruiting. And they were very open about it. Come work,
Speaker 4:  go work it. And you're like, if you're wanna be the cutting edge of monkeys
Speaker 4:  typing with their brains, they like got deep into chargers. So like, here's
Speaker 4:  the problem, we need to, it needs to be convenient, it needs to deliver a
Speaker 4:  lot of power and go fast. We also can't heat your brain up more than two
Speaker 4:  degrees or we'll kill you. That's fair. That's
Speaker 4:  like this is raw. Like I wish more tech companies were this
Speaker 4:  raw stating the problem.
Speaker 6:  You know, thermals are a huge issue and a lot of technology
Speaker 6:  and when you put that in the brain and you heat the brain, you gotta be
Speaker 4:  Careful. They were like, so here's our solution. And they showed this like
Speaker 4:  you gotta watch this video. Like this was, this was the president
Speaker 4:  is was not Elon, it was like a Neurolink engineering manager. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And this was his life. He was dead serious about this.
Speaker 4:  Like it, I gotta charge you up in more than 15 minutes. The battery has
Speaker 4:  to last all day and I can't, I can't boil your
Speaker 4:  brain and your skull. It's a very challenging problem. And he is like, so
Speaker 4:  here's what we've done. There's a lever that delivers
Speaker 4:  banana smoothie and the monkeys have learned to charge their own
Speaker 4:  brains by standing under this wireless charger. And they're like, here's
Speaker 4:  this monkey. And he goes and he is just like drinking a smoothie and there's
Speaker 4:  a graph and the graph goes up. He's like, see, it's
Speaker 4:  charging, watching this. I'm like, one this
Speaker 4:  rules, like, I honestly wish more Apple events featured
Speaker 4:  this exact situation.
Speaker 5:  Monkeys drinking smoothies, wirelessly charging.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Like Samsung used to be close to this. They really toned it
Speaker 4:  down. There was a time when any Samsung event would veer right
Speaker 4:  into also in addition to washers, dryers, nuclear
Speaker 4:  submarines, a fleet of charging monkeys.
Speaker 4:  Like it was always right there. Little smoothies. They've really toned it
Speaker 4:  down since I'm just saying this was like that part of this event the whole
Speaker 4:  time I was like, all events should be like this. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Just do we think the, do we think the monkeys could learn how to code and
Speaker 6:  then they could be at No,
Speaker 5:  He, he addressed this. He addressed it. He was like the
Speaker 5:  monkeys because he's doing the demo where the monkeys drink in the smoothie
Speaker 5:  and it's moving the mouse and typing and he is like, I just want you to understand
Speaker 5:  they're typing gibberish. We do plan to one day maybe make
Speaker 5:  them type.
Speaker 6:  That'll be huge.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Like he definitely, but it was very clearly a joke,
Speaker 5:  sadly. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  The monkeys get pissed when the code review gets canceled. I just lose their
Speaker 4:  pronouns.
Speaker 5:  I worked, I filed it, saving my job.
Speaker 4:  Speaking of illegal things with monkeys, oh there
Speaker 6:  It is. There's this segue. Yes, that's a good one. That's really good. So
Speaker 6:  you, you were in are
Speaker 4:  Monkeys in the The Bahamas. That's what I was like. I was like there's gotta
Speaker 4:  be monkeys in The Bahamas. Speaking
Speaker 6:  Of tropical animals. Bahamas. Yeah. Yeah. So Eli,
Speaker 6:  you were in beautiful New York City this week to
Speaker 6:  watch Andrew Ross Sorkin of the New York Times do his
Speaker 6:  annual deal book conference and he had none other than
Speaker 6:  the illustrious Sam Bakeman freed there virtually. He was the closer,
Speaker 6:  a pretty remarkable interview. We watched it. You were in the room. Can you
Speaker 6:  just describe what it was like being in the room for this truly bizarre moment?
Speaker 6:  And we should note that like people were mad that Sorkin was even doing
Speaker 6:  this interview, right? Because SPF is, I think we can all say here,
Speaker 6:  like probably a criminal. Yeah, allegedly. And yeah, so there was
Speaker 6:  like a debate about whether this interview should even happen and then it
Speaker 6:  does happen. And then, and what was that like?
Speaker 4:  It was strange. I, I will candidly admit that I feel
Speaker 4:  a sense of smugness about all of crypto because we
Speaker 4:  have been so skeptical of it this whole time. And so
Speaker 4:  the way we have covered it, I think is a little more detached than people
Speaker 4:  want us to be. Like we're just not as mad about it. And I, I
Speaker 4:  recognize that people have had their lives destroyed and I am mad for those
Speaker 4:  people on, on their behalf. And that's actually how Andrew opened the interview
Speaker 4:  with Sam. He's like, here's some letters I got from people whose lives have
Speaker 4:  been destroyed. His life savings are taken away. But just from the verges
Speaker 4:  of consumer site, it's not a financial services site, it's on a business
Speaker 4:  site where a consumer technology site. And so we, we just covered it,
Speaker 4:  sort of a remove, like it's a caper to us I think. So it was interesting
Speaker 4:  to go into that audience and the DealBook audience, it's, it's
Speaker 4:  the code conference. Like it's the closest parallel to
Speaker 6:  It. Bill Ackman's in the room asking,
Speaker 4:  Yeah, all these big investors are in there, major businessmen are in there,
Speaker 4:  major politicians in there. Pretty cool to be in that room. Like that was
Speaker 4:  neat. And for most of the day, like you're in a
Speaker 4:  large theater with a lot of important people. There's just like a
Speaker 4:  layer of background noise in the room. No matter who's being interviewed,
Speaker 4:  Reid Hastings is on stage talking about the future of Netflix. There's sort
Speaker 4:  of like a layer of background noise. People are getting up. But like I got
Speaker 4:  up in the middle and took a phone call. People are typing, there's some like
Speaker 4:  murmurs, there's reactions to the interview. You know, it's very polite and
Speaker 4:  respectful and people are focused. But there's sort of like this layer of
Speaker 4:  background activity happening in the room, right? Yeah. It's a big
Speaker 4:  theater. You get to Sam and it's just pin drop silent, like
Speaker 4:  no one's even moving. Like no, no one
Speaker 4:  knows what to do and it's remote and Sam
Speaker 4:  can't perceive the room. Like this is the,
Speaker 4:  here's the hard limit of a Zoom conversation, right?
Speaker 4:  Like he's looking into his webcam and he can see Andrew os
Speaker 4:  Sorkin and he can probably hear the room and Sorkin is on stage
Speaker 4:  and I was sitting off to the side so I could see what Sorkin was looking
Speaker 4:  at. He didn't have a monitor that he could not see Sam, Sam was behind him.
Speaker 4:  So he was just looking into the camera to create the illusion
Speaker 4:  of eye contact. This is exactly what I am doing right now. I am staring down
Speaker 4:  the barrel of a camera lens to make it look like I'm looking at the, the
Speaker 4:  two Alex's. But I'm looking at my camera lens and I was like, oh,
Speaker 4:  Andrew Serkin is a CNBC anchor. Like he's just falling
Speaker 4:  back on his cable news training to
Speaker 4:  create intimacy even though he is dead aware of what's happening
Speaker 4:  in this room. And yes, there's what happened on, we talked about the interview
Speaker 4:  and Sam and the scam and all that stuff. I just, from a creation
Speaker 4:  of a cultural moment using technology standpoint,
Speaker 4:  I was just like blown away. Like I, I've never experienced anything
Speaker 4:  like that and I've been to a million of these conferences. We've done a million
Speaker 4:  interviews. I host an interview show remotely.
Speaker 4:  But that mismatch between, here's this room
Speaker 4:  full of bankers and executives and
Speaker 4:  politicians just tensed at the, on the edge
Speaker 4:  of their seat all kind of like, you should shut up.
Speaker 4:  Like
Speaker 5:  Shut up.
Speaker 6:  That's the amazing thing. And
Speaker 4:  He's just like video chatting.
Speaker 5:  You just having a time. Didn't
Speaker 6:  Sorkin's, didn't Sorkin ask at one point like what are your lawyers advising
Speaker 6:  you? I mean he did like that was the big question we all had was
Speaker 4:  Like this was like the most incredible mumble side of all time. He was like,
Speaker 4:  are your lawyers telling you to talk to? He's like, they are not. And he
Speaker 4:  just kept talking.
Speaker 6:  Cause there were times where Sam would look off to the side of the camera
Speaker 6:  and you know, Liz and I and others were in Slack and we're all talking and
Speaker 6:  we're like, man, is he looking at his talking points? Is he looking at a
Speaker 6:  lawyer who's going no. Like what is, what is going through this guy?
Speaker 5:  I think he was just doing, there's a thing I do it a lot, a lot of people
Speaker 5:  do where you sometimes will like look away when you're talking and and trying
Speaker 5:  to get over whatever conversation you're supposed to have. And I think that's
Speaker 5:  just a tick of his that he has.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it
Speaker 4:  Was just very strange. Strange. I mean he, from what I can tell, he, he continues
Speaker 4:  to just admit to frauds. Like he won't stop
Speaker 4:  admitting to frauds, which seems like a huge problem.
Speaker 6:  Well he said he didn't intend to do fraud. Oh yeah, I
Speaker 6:  believe.
Speaker 5:  And he apologized to everybody's losing their money. He's like, I just wanna
Speaker 5:  do right by my customers. And I was like, well you know where you could done
Speaker 5:  that. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  Yeah. But it was like this weird exercise of like, I don't know how
Speaker 6:  the thing I made works. It was like the common refrain he would
Speaker 6:  go to. It was like, it was like he was pointing to some boogeyman that wasn't
Speaker 6:  him that he couldn't name because he's obviously the
Speaker 6:  culprits. Right? And so what are you gonna do if you're also like enough
Speaker 6:  of a psychopath to put yourself in a public interview in this moment you're
Speaker 6:  gonna just like invent something to blame that you
Speaker 6:  can't describe. I mean is that a fair read? I don't, I don't know how else
Speaker 6:  to describe you
Speaker 4:  Handled
Speaker 5:  It. I was talking with Liz Bunch about this yesterday. We were trying to
Speaker 5:  figure out why is this man coming and talking to everybody repeatedly. Wait,
Speaker 4:  Before we go any farther with this, let's just back up a little bit. Keith,
Speaker 4:  can you tell us just the elevator version of what's going on with
Speaker 4:  ftx?
Speaker 6:  Sure. This is probably important. So FTX basically
Speaker 6:  started as this hedge fund called Alameda Research. They
Speaker 6:  did a very basic thing and made a lot of money doing it where they basically
Speaker 6:  traded the difference between the price of crypto in one country versus
Speaker 6:  the next, I believe it was maybe Japan and the US for a while. Sam
Speaker 6:  Bakeman freed young dude with seems like other really
Speaker 6:  young people, some of which he had extra, you know, kind of relationships
Speaker 6:  with are all running this thing. It's like a classic like
Speaker 6:  finance bro, like pounding Red Bulls
Speaker 6:  like at your desk all day thing. And
Speaker 6:  FTX gets created as Alameda is taking off
Speaker 6:  and you know, I'll skip all the, all the intricacies. What essentially how
Speaker 6:  it all came down is there was a obvious, you know, massive collapse in the
Speaker 6:  price of cryptocurrency and essentially a run on the bank happened on
Speaker 6:  ftx. And the problem was is that FTX didn't actually have the money
Speaker 6:  that its depositors, that its customers put with
Speaker 6:  them because Alameda research took that money to
Speaker 6:  back the bets that had lost all of its money on, as a hedge fund
Speaker 6:  betting on certain crypto assets that plummeted. And
Speaker 6:  so Sam did the, you know, one of the worst things you could possibly
Speaker 6:  do in finance and what is actually legal if you're like a fully
Speaker 6:  regulated financial institution, which FTX was not, it was based in The
Speaker 6:  Bahamas. All this is very relevant now because it was very clear he was trying
Speaker 6:  to skirt regulation and he doesn't actually care about regulation even though
Speaker 6:  he was saying he was the one who cared about the most. And yeah, FTX ended
Speaker 6:  up not having the money to be able to give people their, their deposits.
Speaker 6:  And so the whole thing came crashing down 10 plus billion. You know, this
Speaker 6:  was a guy who was the largest or one of the largest donors in the
Speaker 6:  midterms to
Speaker 4:  Both sides. It turned out to
Speaker 6:  Both sides. He says like, you know, he was the youngest billionaire of
Speaker 6:  his stature. I think he was the richest, you know, billionaire under 30 for
Speaker 6:  a minute on paper. And now he says he's got, he's broken, you know, but we
Speaker 6:  don't actually know that there's been a lot of reporting that money was taken
Speaker 6:  out and it's unclear a lot of home bought that sort of thing. So
Speaker 6:  that's like the, that's the elevator
Speaker 4:  Story of the Yeah. And Liz has been doing great work covering FTX on the
Speaker 4:  site just for our purposes again, our,
Speaker 4:  it's a financial story at the end of the day. It's a, yeah, you started an
Speaker 4:  unregulated bank and then did the shadiest things that an unregulated
Speaker 4:  bank could do and the amount of technology involved. Yes,
Speaker 4:  crypto has some interesting tech baked into it, but like at the end of the
Speaker 4:  day it's, it's like a bank story. So yes, we've cover it, but I'm watching
Speaker 4:  this interview and what actually really struck me is
Speaker 4:  crypto, crypto in general. I don't if
Speaker 4:  you remember what I think of as crypto summer was hailed as like
Speaker 4:  the next gigantic turn for the tech industry and we all
Speaker 4:  had to hear about web three in Terminable and just
Speaker 4:  for an endless amount of crypto stuff occurred.
Speaker 4:  And Washington scenario was like, oh this, this is the moment where it's
Speaker 4:  dead. Right Where he, he, yeah. He talks to the Times yesterday he talked
Speaker 4:  to New York Mag, our sister publication, he was on Good Morning America this
Speaker 4:  morning and he's like, I need, I owe it to my customers to explain
Speaker 4:  what happened. To explain every prosecutor in every state
Speaker 4:  and the country is like, and you should keep talking.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Because everything you say is admissible in any discrepancy in
Speaker 4:  what you say, we're gonna hold up in front of a jury and used to put you
Speaker 4:  in jail. And it just feels like maybe the entire industry is
Speaker 4:  tainted in irrevocable way because of all of this
Speaker 4:  now. Right? I mean if you remember the Super Bowl with to like all the crypto
Speaker 4:  ads, like Tom Brady was a FTX spokesman. He made an ad with
Speaker 4:  Giselle and the entire ad was basically like you should be in our Ponzi scheme,
Speaker 4:  there was no mention of utility. It was just him being like, are you in
Speaker 4:  over and over again to his famous friends?
Speaker 6:  Well and we saw what that did to Tom and Giselle and you know, that's
Speaker 6:  a
Speaker 4:  Metaphor
Speaker 6:  For what it's
Speaker 4:  Doing. He's not having a good year,
Speaker 6:  Not
Speaker 5:  A great year
Speaker 4:  For Tom. It's not the best year Tommy's life.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  But fundamentally like do you, do you, do you think that that's the case
Speaker 4:  that this moment for crypto has just come to an end
Speaker 4:  in the next moment? I mean there might be an next moment. There has been
Speaker 4:  some interesting technology developed, but I have heard
Speaker 4:  more from vindicated skeptics than I have heard from people
Speaker 4:  who are like, we'll come back from this.
Speaker 5:  I talked to a friend who was like an executive at one of these big crypto
Speaker 5:  companies and he got laid off because they, it was running out of money
Speaker 5:  because so many of these companies were like, we're gonna throw a bunch of
Speaker 5:  investment at it and see what happens. And it's like, wait, just giant Ponzi
Speaker 5:  schemes, eventually your money goes somewhere and it never comes back.
Speaker 5:  And I was like, is crypto kind of done with the collapse of ftx? And he's
Speaker 5:  like, I don't see how it can recover. It just really, yeah, he's like,
Speaker 5:  I just do not see how it happens after this. And I think
Speaker 5:  even people in the crypto community always
Speaker 5:  kind of knew that a big chunk of this is a Ponzi scheme because this money
Speaker 5:  is fake money and it doesn't, there's no like, there's no gold standard,
Speaker 5:  there's no, there's nothing at the other end saying this
Speaker 4:  Is real. All money is fake money. Did you just advocate for the gold standard
Speaker 4:  on the Verge cast?
Speaker 5:  Yes, I did.
Speaker 4:  By that standard. All, all money is fake money. But
Speaker 5:  I mean, you know, there's no difference between this money
Speaker 5:  and the goal that Ash and I are currently mining on World of Warcraft
Speaker 5:  as we pretend to be Little Dragons. Like what's the difference? Both of
Speaker 5:  them can theoretically be used to buy goods and as more
Speaker 6:  People, well one you can actually use for something and World of Warcraft,
Speaker 6:  that's it.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. One I can go and I buy mats to make my dragons
Speaker 5:  stronger. The other one I can hopefully get some cash for
Speaker 5:  if I traded in crypto. And like, I think they all
Speaker 5:  kind of were aware that the bottom could drop out of this at any time.
Speaker 5:  If anybody wants to run on the bank, a totally unregulated bank
Speaker 5:  will be destroyed. And so like, yeah, I think it's done.
Speaker 6:  I, I think, I don't think it's done. I think what we saw in this last
Speaker 6:  wave was a lot of key infrastructure tech was built
Speaker 6:  like layers of blockchains were built with no use cases on top
Speaker 6:  of them. So it was a Ponzi scheme because once you buy a bunch
Speaker 6:  of whatever, what are you gonna do with it? Right? Yeah. Except, you know,
Speaker 6:  know certain illicit things that I, you know, obviously have no idea what
Speaker 6:  those are. So, so if if you, if if that's the only
Speaker 6:  use case, it is a Ponzi scheme. And so I am actually
Speaker 6:  seeing interesting startups, there's a lot of VC money deployed into
Speaker 6:  crypto into these startups that are actually trying to build use
Speaker 6:  cases. And I, I think, you know, we saw some of that in gaming. It
Speaker 6:  didn't really go anywhere. There was, it was kind of a brief moment but
Speaker 5:  Where, where are the use cases you're seeing that like could go
Speaker 5:  somewhere all was gaming and it went Payments, payments.
Speaker 6:  I think we'll see some of the large social apps. Elon has talked, I
Speaker 6:  know it's like, you know,
Speaker 4:  All way back around.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, all the way back around. But like Twitter will add, crypto Telegram
Speaker 6:  is adding crypto, I think Metas apps, they're already doing
Speaker 6:  NFTs on Polygon. I think they will probably have some kind of crypto payment
Speaker 6:  feature within three years. But there there is a payments layer
Speaker 6:  where it does make sense to eliminate a middleman
Speaker 6:  if you can. And like if you use one of these tokens that
Speaker 6:  actually can move quickly and a chain that actually is performative,
Speaker 6:  like it does make sense as a payment mechanism. You just have to have
Speaker 6:  the network effects for that. And no one's done that yet.
Speaker 5:  How does it make sense to go and invest, go
Speaker 5:  find a crypto that I feel good about, find an app
Speaker 5:  that I wanna use to invest in it. Invest
Speaker 5:  my my my cash, my my my legal Tinder
Speaker 5:  that is regulated. Then go like how is that
Speaker 5:  faster and easier than Apple Pay or my
Speaker 5:  Amex?
Speaker 6:  It's not. But like that you're describing is the retail
Speaker 6:  covid fed STEMI bubble mania that we had
Speaker 6:  that was like the perfect cocktail of people wanting to speculate in crypto.
Speaker 6:  Right. And a bunch of companies being opportunistic about you know, prime.
Speaker 5:  But I'm saying like now that crypto's been pretty poisoned in public
Speaker 5:  Yeah. View, right? Like most
Speaker 6:  People definitely on a retail level. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  How does it go, how does it come back from that? Like on the retail level,
Speaker 5:  how am I gonna get my best friend who has no idea what a crypto
Speaker 5:  wallet is to go and use
Speaker 6:  That? I mean it has to move outta speculation. It has to move out of like
Speaker 6:  you're buying this thing because it may go up one day. It has to be like,
Speaker 6:  oh I actually need this to like send someone money on Twitter or on
Speaker 6:  Telegram or
Speaker 4:  This is the thing that, that truly struck me about watching Sam
Speaker 4:  in person book and watching the other interviews. There are like two stories
Speaker 4:  in tech right now, right? There's Elon and Twitter and there's ftx. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And we are cover, we might be over covering Elon and Twitter and we are
Speaker 4:  covering to a certain degree FTX and crypto because there's a tech
Speaker 4:  element to it. But when you peel back the layers, you have
Speaker 4:  be a finance expert to really understand what happened at ftx.
Speaker 4:  To really catch him in the, in the fraud that everyone alleges that he's
Speaker 4:  committing. Which you probably did there. I cannot find the part
Speaker 4:  where it's like, and here's the thing they did technically
Speaker 4:  that created the fraud. It's all just the shell game
Speaker 4:  of an unregulated bank. And then people saying I want my money
Speaker 4:  and the bank saying, sorry we spent it on my girlfriend's hedge fund. Which
Speaker 4:  is an incredible outcome by the
Speaker 5:  Way. It was just, it's a wonderful life. Yeah. Just the whole
Speaker 5:  scene. But this is the tech You ready for the tech element
Speaker 5:  of it? Yeah, it happened
Speaker 5:  online.
Speaker 4:  We used to a long time ago at the beginning of the Verge when we had
Speaker 4:  like vet stories, so to decide whether we were gonna write about them, we
Speaker 4:  had to draw a line that's like, we can't do this just because someone tweeted
Speaker 4:  about it. Yeah. Like that, that's not, that doesn't make it a text story.
Speaker 4:  That's just something
Speaker 6:  How that has changed.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Now it's like all day, every day as people are tweeting, we have to
Speaker 4:  react to it. We should actually talk about this part cuz I did get a bunch
Speaker 4:  of questions and I said we would talk about the Verge asked a little bit
Speaker 4:  the notion that just by interviewing Sam Bankman free,
Speaker 4:  you're perpetuating this fraud. I I like
Speaker 4:  fundamentally our job is to talk to people. So it seems, and I understand
Speaker 4:  that you don't wanna platform like there's people you don't wanna platform.
Speaker 4:  But at this moment it's like, well he's the bad guy,
Speaker 4:  right? He's the villain. Like you, you want to know if you can get the villain
Speaker 4:  to admit the villa and like, but he did him speaking is actually like
Speaker 4:  a public service in its way. Like if, if you are a good interviewer, I dunno,
Speaker 4:  what do you guys think?
Speaker 6:  I find it bizarre. I mean I guess I can understand if you don't work in the
Speaker 6:  media thinking that the media is like aiding and embedding him if they're
Speaker 6:  giving him a platform. But I mean why, why would you
Speaker 6:  not? Because you think that he doesn't deserve
Speaker 4:  The attention. Like,
Speaker 6:  Or that the attention,
Speaker 5:  I think it's really down to like how that platform, how you use that platform,
Speaker 5:  how
Speaker 4:  You use it,
Speaker 5:  Right? Like if if he'd gone up there with somebody who was a really soft
Speaker 5:  interviewer who was just like, tell me, okay, now what's your day like now
Speaker 5:  that you've bankrupted your company
Speaker 4:  That's going on bomb is escaping the
Speaker 5:  Feds. Like what kinda plastic fern is that that you have looming over
Speaker 5:  your head for this entire interview?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I don't, I haven't seen that. I have seen a lot of cred like
Speaker 4:  credulous interview.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And that's the thing is that's why I think it's okay. Like I think
Speaker 5:  we, we've gotten, we've seen a lot of interviews with bad actors like this
Speaker 5:  in the past where they go and they give their sob story and there's no pushback.
Speaker 5:  But Sorkin was like, to his credit, pushing back. Yeah. Really
Speaker 5:  consistently. Oh
Speaker 4:  Yeah, the last, the last you should all watch. Actually there was a very
Speaker 4:  funny like very verge moment in this
Speaker 4:  interview. He's coming to the end and he
Speaker 4:  asks a question and he is like, so you had no CFO and
Speaker 4:  no board of directors. Did you, did you think that was a problem? And
Speaker 4:  again, this is a room full of bankers and people who have invested in FTX
Speaker 4:  who all should have seen the lack of a CFO and the lack of a board of directors,
Speaker 4:  a giant waving red flag, spend the money anyway. And Sam goes,
Speaker 4:  I think we had too many boards and the call drops. And
Speaker 4:  so everyone thinks that he did this on purpose,
Speaker 4:  right? That he's like yanked the plug or like his lawyers have finally stormed
Speaker 4:  into the room and like thrown the laptop out the window. And I'm looking
Speaker 4:  at it, I'm like, oh that's the elga cam link.
Speaker 6:  Did you stand up and yell at
Speaker 4:  His camera? Just died. That's all.
Speaker 6:  I'm the tech
Speaker 4:  Expert. Yeah. I was like, I can check the Delgado. It's just like, and
Speaker 4:  everyone's like, oh my God, is he coming back? And I was like, no dude, that's
Speaker 4:  just the
Speaker 5:  Computer just timed down.
Speaker 4:  He'll be back like this dude can't shut up he'll. And lo and behold he came
Speaker 4:  back and I encourage everyone to just watch the last five
Speaker 4:  minutes of this interview on the Times this site. And it's also, it's, it's
Speaker 4:  all over TikTok. Like this is, this thing has been free rebooted everywhere
Speaker 4:  sort just like mash. And he ends by saying, are you lying? Which is, I
Speaker 4:  think I'm gonna end every decoder interview by being like, so are you lying?
Speaker 6:  We'll note that S SPF did not give a quick
Speaker 6:  no, which is never a good sign that you're
Speaker 6:  actually not lying. I did think that the awkward clapping at the
Speaker 6:  end was like a little, I understand that that's like a conference thing that
Speaker 6:  you always clap. But like it was really funny to see people like
Speaker 6:  clapping as SPF was like leaving but I
Speaker 5:  Clapping for him. Clapped. They were like, good
Speaker 4:  Interview. No I know they're for Andrew also. You can't see this. You
Speaker 4:  couldn't see this on the stream show. But then this all ends and he is like,
Speaker 4:  all right, so last thing you know, here are some Broadway
Speaker 4:  performers to close this out. And it was like rapping. It was like Broadway
Speaker 4:  rap. It was just, it was just a very odd
Speaker 4:  moment. Very surreal. All
Speaker 5:  Right cause that was the last interview of
Speaker 4:  The day. That was, yeah and there was, I, I would just, from what I
Speaker 4:  gathered from various people there, there was a lot of
Speaker 4:  skepticism that SPF would show up.
Speaker 5:  Yeah cuz he booked this before
Speaker 4:  He booked all this before he said he was gonna do it but he's in The
Speaker 4:  Bahamas, he doesn't have to do it. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  That poor events planner who is working on this thing and
Speaker 5:  they're like, we're gonna have this great triumphant final interview with
Speaker 5:  the guy who did ftx. He's into all this altruism, it's gonna
Speaker 5:  be so lovely. And then we're gonna have these dancers come out and it's gonna
Speaker 5:  be this great moment Then just going, do I get rid of the
Speaker 5:  dancers? Like what do I do? How do we follow this now?
Speaker 4:  Yeah
Speaker 5:  It was shout out to that dude.
Speaker 4:  You should go watch just at least the last 10 minutes of it just cuz Andrew
Speaker 4:  did such a good job and like it was so weird. It was so
Speaker 4:  weird. Truly one of the weirdest moments. All right, we
Speaker 4:  gotta take a break and come back. We'll do a tiny little gadget lightning
Speaker 4:  around and we'll get out here. We'll be right
Speaker 4:  back.
Speaker 4:  All right, we're back. We need like a pallet cleanser here. We gotta talk
Speaker 4:  about some gadgets and some buttons and knobs and bleeps and bloops. Alex,
Speaker 4:  we got for us?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. All right. I'm not gonna talk about it too much because
Speaker 5:  David and I talked about it a whole bunch recently in a recorded
Speaker 5:  episode before the baby came. But the Amazon
Speaker 5:  Kindle scribe came out this week. I reviewed it. If
Speaker 5:  you really, really, really, really, really want a Kindle that you can write
Speaker 5:  on, go for it. Otherwise don't just skip
Speaker 5:  it.
Speaker 4:  I'm not Alex and I like art edit meeting was like I reviewed the Kindle scribe
Speaker 4:  and like I, you know I'm on the show with you. I know how you feel about
Speaker 4:  ein. Yeah, I would describe the look on your face as
Speaker 4:  pure devastation.
Speaker 5:  It's pretty, it's pretty bummer. Pretty big bummer. Why
Speaker 5:  it's bad. I think it's bad because the software is bad.
Speaker 5:  Amazon has gotten really complacent with its software design and is
Speaker 5:  like, yeah you'll enjoy this slop cuz you need it. Cuz
Speaker 5:  we sell the eBooks. That's kind of the funny monopoly guys for using it.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, that's how they are. No but but it just like
Speaker 5:  shoved a bunch of stuff in your face. It kept showing me like comics to buy
Speaker 5:  on my black and white e-reader. It was just bad at recommending
Speaker 5:  stuff and the, the note taking elements of it were like
Speaker 5:  pretty unfulfilling. And the fact that the largest
Speaker 5:  cloud computing company in the world still has you
Speaker 5:  emailing yourself in order to sync
Speaker 5:  documents that just
Speaker 5:  seems,
Speaker 4:  Hey, it's still not as bad as horizon work. Yeah, I'll
Speaker 5:  Tell you that. That's true. It's like, it's like three below it
Speaker 5:  but it was just, it was just a, a big bummer and
Speaker 5:  you'll have to stay tuned for an upcoming episode of the Wednesday show where
Speaker 5:  I talk all about it. It's really great. But also there was a new track ball
Speaker 5:  mouse. David's not here to like stop all of my better. Like stop
Speaker 5:  me.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I can really, I'm looking at this rundown and I'm like, oh this Alex
Speaker 4:  made this rundown of gadgets. This is a real, you can tell that
Speaker 4:  David wasn't here this week. It's,
Speaker 5:  It's, this is very exciting because for years the track ball space
Speaker 5:  was totally undeveloped. We didn't have a lot of track balls. They
Speaker 5:  were all wired. It was horrible.
Speaker 4:  Finally, track ball space was
Speaker 4:  undeveloped.
Speaker 5:  Kensington said
Speaker 4:  No it's actually not crypto you guys, it's track balls.
Speaker 5:  Balls. That's
Speaker 4:  The future. Like the hot VC money is going into the track ball space. Kensington
Speaker 5:  And Logitech are just like, send us all your cash. Invest in us,
Speaker 5:  but New
Speaker 4:  Wireless. Who is the SPF of track balls? Clarence, Steve Kensington?
Speaker 4:  No, it's
Speaker 5:  The guy who makes poopy. Oh okay. No, the poopy guys are actually lovely.
Speaker 5:  They're, they're,
Speaker 4:  They're the track ball looks sick and I kind of want one, I gotta be honest
Speaker 4:  with you. It looks sick. Yeah. Do they still do the thing where they make
Speaker 4:  custom track ball balls with like eight balls and things? Yes. Track ball
Speaker 4:  balls. Yeah. No this is like a hot, like when I was like eighth grade, like
Speaker 4:  the custom track now now
Speaker 5:  You, you build your own track ball and then you, I know a guy who takes
Speaker 5:  like steel ball bearings and he polishes them and then he like colors
Speaker 5:  them with metal. I don't know, I'm not a metaler just,
Speaker 5:  but he does stuff and so he's got his own little fancy custom a track
Speaker 5:  balls. But if you don't wanna do that you can get
Speaker 5:  this new wireless version of the Slim Blade, which is a great name.
Speaker 4:  I'm reading the actual press release for this product. Can I just read you
Speaker 4:  the headline of this press release?
Speaker 5:  Yes.
Speaker 4:  Kensington's Slim Blade Pro takes track balls to the next
Speaker 4:  level.
Speaker 5:  Yes, I believe
Speaker 4:  It. They had a meeting like this got sent around. They're like, what's the
Speaker 4:  headline of a press release? And they're like, do it the next level, next
Speaker 4:  level.
Speaker 5:  No
Speaker 4:  One's stopped. I love it. No one's stopped. I'm buying one of these.
Speaker 4:  Why is the track ball encrypted? Right. You know, so
Speaker 4:  I guess the Bluetooth I guess.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, you wanna have the Bluetooth encrypted then what else?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, Allison Johnson reviewed the, or checked out the new
Speaker 5:  GenY Covert doc mini, which lets you like
Speaker 5:  dock a lot of your different game systems very easily. And
Speaker 5:  historically those docs for like the Switch are these giant
Speaker 5:  devices. Like it's a
Speaker 4:  Big plus these things like the size of an iPhone charger.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And so it's just cool. It's just
Speaker 5:  nice. I was, when the switch first came out, everybody was complaining about
Speaker 5:  how they couldn't just plug a USBC cord in and you still can't, you still
Speaker 5:  can't just like plug a USBC to H D M I cord into your TV and
Speaker 5:  have a doc.
Speaker 4:  But that does seem like amis. But this thing looks cool. This is a great
Speaker 4:  gadget.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Just very, very close. This is like the rare Indiegogo that like really went
Speaker 4:  off. Yeah
Speaker 5:  Cuz Genie's been, they've, they've had a couple of these. This is, this is
Speaker 5:  the newest one. It's only $50 and like
Speaker 5:  you can just check it in your purse, which is what she did. You guys
Speaker 5:  I guess would put it in your cargo pants. Your, your
Speaker 5:  fanny pack. I don't what what
Speaker 4:  How did, how did you know that's what I wear every day. Is it
Speaker 4:  because I live in Southern California
Speaker 5:  Just with flip flops,
Speaker 4:  Your board shorts.
Speaker 5:  That's actually what Alex is wearing right now. You guys can't see it but
Speaker 5:  looking
Speaker 6:  Great. That was a probing, that was a very revealing,
Speaker 4:  You were just like, throw out cargo pants and see how they react.
Speaker 4:  That's right. Look, I appreciate an extra pocket. Yeah, I feel like we, we
Speaker 4:  need to talk about the UFI thing. Maybe we should have Sean come on a Wednesday
Speaker 4:  show and like really get into it. But Sean Holster I would say
Speaker 4:  very annoyed with ufe. There's a story that UFE
Speaker 4:  security cameras can just be accessed by a vlc, the app vlc. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  You could basically just type a URL in the VLC and start streaming your camera
Speaker 4:  sick.
Speaker 6:  Which
Speaker 4:  Is not great. It's a little bit harder than that. There needs to be, have
Speaker 4:  been an event that triggered the camera, all this stuff. But UFE is out there
Speaker 4:  being like our cameras are fully encrypted and safe end to end encrypted
Speaker 4:  And so he asked him for a statement and he is like, this is impossible. And
Speaker 4:  then he did it and it worked
Speaker 6:  Well. Okay. So I have s they're through home kit
Speaker 6:  though. Like they're through my home app and I don't use the UFI app, therefore
Speaker 6:  I'm safe. Right. Cause if it goes through home
Speaker 5:  Kips camera
Speaker 6:  App, if it goes through Apple Home Kit, isn't it?
Speaker 5:  It's real bad. Like yeah, gin's talked about this a few times,
Speaker 5:  but the, the Home Kip camera situation is,
Speaker 5:  is not one she would recommend. I
Speaker 6:  Gotta go guys, I problem
Speaker 5:  Everybody just start like randomizing
Speaker 5:  UFI camera links and you'll, you'll be like, hello?
Speaker 5:  And you'll see Alex's cargo pants. It's gonna be great.
Speaker 6:  So even if, even if you had your UFI routed through home kit,
Speaker 6:  you're still susceptible to this.
Speaker 4:  I think it is unclear at this time. Home kit secure video is supposed to
Speaker 4:  be encrypted. Right. But the VLC thing is just
Speaker 4:  going to the camera. Right? So
Speaker 4:  it's like maybe the connection from the camera to home kit to the cloud service
Speaker 4:  to your phone, all that is encrypted. But if you can just talk
Speaker 4:  to the camera directly, it'll just give you a video file.
Speaker 6:  Would thread have kept this from
Speaker 6:  happening?
Speaker 4:  I mean I don't, we we got a bunch of cameras outside and I think cameras
Speaker 4:  inside are really weird and I have always picked the ring
Speaker 4:  cameras not because I like love the entire
Speaker 4:  ring ethos of like, what if we terrify old people into having cameras outside
Speaker 4:  their house?
Speaker 6:  No. Yeah. You like bad software. I
Speaker 4:  Love it. It's the best. Yeah. But it's also that I, I know that Amazon
Speaker 4:  will probably like last a long time and they are fair
Speaker 4:  and they are gonna run, they're gonna make their own software and run AWS
Speaker 4:  directly and like,
Speaker 5:  I mean not if the Kindle's any indication
Speaker 4:  All these other companies that are
Speaker 5:  Sorry.
Speaker 4:  That's true. But I can you VLC into a Kindle. Like
Speaker 4:  there's just a part of these other companies where it's like they're just
Speaker 4:  buying commodity bits and bobs off the shelf Yeah. And assembling them
Speaker 4:  into products and it's like that's where the security consequences come from.
Speaker 4:  Whereas at least for the Ring, it's like I know they're a company that will
Speaker 4:  like last a long time because
Speaker 5:  You feel, I think you feel the appeal was, it wasn't one of these other
Speaker 5:  companies it could use Home Kit. You could just have it attached to your,
Speaker 5:  your local storage and not have to have any kind of cloud at all. Which is,
Speaker 5:  as someone who loves a server, I'm a huge fan,
Speaker 5:  but it just like, you still have to, there's still security. You still have
Speaker 5:  to think about these things. There's still ways to hack this stuff and Yeah,
Speaker 4:  By typing the address of the camera into VLC and accessing
Speaker 4:  an unencrypted stream. Perfect. Beautiful. I saw a TikTok
Speaker 4:  of somebody just like talking to their Plex server the other day. I forgot
Speaker 4:  to send it to you, but now this is because of our relationship here. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  TikTok is like, we need to start showing him Plex content.
Speaker 5:  I I'm so happy for you.
Speaker 6:  Kranz, do you have a Mastodon server?
Speaker 4:  No,
Speaker 5:  I was looking into putting one on my s sonology or like my S Sonology server.
Speaker 5:  That's what I use. And then I like read about three
Speaker 5:  lines into how to create a Macon server
Speaker 5:  and that was the end.
Speaker 6:  So as a lover of servers, you can't even get behind Mastodon. So I think
Speaker 6:  Macon's, domed we can on
Speaker 5:  That. It's dimmed guys go to Disor.
Speaker 4:  No, Macon is gonna be, what's going to happen to Macon is gonna be
Speaker 4:  incredible. Someone is gonna centralize a Macon instance and
Speaker 4:  that's gonna become the service and everyone else, they're gonna have like
Speaker 4:  fake interoperability with other MA on servers. But everyone's
Speaker 4:  gonna join Twitter clone.com, you know who it is, which is
Speaker 4:  Macedon and then it's gonna have all the same problems as
Speaker 5:  You know who it is. Who's that? It's all full circle. So this
Speaker 5:  little company has so small social media company we've never talked
Speaker 5:  about on this show before. I definitely have never talked about, has announced
Speaker 5:  that they're gonna support Mastodon instances. So you'll be able to log in
Speaker 5:  with your Tumblr account a Mastodon.
Speaker 4:  That's pretty good. It's
Speaker 5:  Gonna be Tumblr. Just, just embrace it guys. I'm sorry.
Speaker 4:  I feel like Matt Mullen like who's the CEO of Automatic, which owns WordPress
Speaker 4:  and Tumblr. Yeah, I think he sends this blood in the water.
Speaker 6:  Yeah,
Speaker 4:  You have the feeling. He's like, oh, I went through this app store review
Speaker 4:  shit with with Tumblr. Like you can't hurt
Speaker 5:  Me. He bought that for, how much money did Yahoo lose when they sold it to
Speaker 5:  him?
Speaker 4:  It was like 80 billion. It was crazy. It was like the full amount. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  So
Speaker 6:  Well this is, this is Yahoo loves to do this. I don't think they've ever
Speaker 6:  made money on anything. So
Speaker 5:  Automatic is gonna make some money.
Speaker 6:  Yeah,
Speaker 4:  98.1% loss. Yeah, they bought it sounds right.
Speaker 4:  They bought it for 1.1 million and they sold it
Speaker 4:  for 20 million. A well below 20 million.
Speaker 6:  That was a Marissa Mayor special I think. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  It
Speaker 4:  Was. It was, yeah. Yeah. One hair strategy was buying every app to get
Speaker 4:  talent in the
Speaker 5:  Door in between Zamboni drives.
Speaker 4:  Actually neither of you know this story. When we first started The Verge,
Speaker 4:  we had this like horrible office in New York City and fifth Avenue. It
Speaker 4:  was small. I, I feel very fondly for it, but objectively it was like crap.
Speaker 5:  Didn't you guys do the Verge cast in like a closet?
Speaker 5:  Last one, I'm just gonna tease the fact that we're working on this review.
Speaker 5:  The Oceanic Plus app for the Apple Watch Ultra is now out for
Speaker 5:  our scuba divers in the audience.
Speaker 4:  I'm only bringing this up because I, what I've heard about our Apple Watch
Speaker 4:  Ultra Review video, it's
Speaker 5:  Gonna win an Oscar.
Speaker 4:  It's, I mean this is the highest budget thing. This a Marvel movie at this
Speaker 4:  point. Full billion dollar avatar Stand back
Speaker 4:  verges Apple Watch Ultra Review is coming. We're gonna, we're gonna throw
Speaker 4:  it out of an airplane.
Speaker 6:  I was gonna say, did we do any skydiving for this one?
Speaker 4:  I, there's, there's, I know that there's an attempt to crash a car. I don't
Speaker 4:  know if actually happened.
Speaker 6:  Oh,
Speaker 4:  And now we're trying to dive with it, so it's gonna be stunning. We were
Speaker 4:  waiting for this, but that review is coming and we'll see. We'll
Speaker 4:  see if, we'll see if the dive button does everything that we ever hoped it
Speaker 4:  would do.
Speaker 5:  V and Becca have been working really hard on it sounds like it's gonna be
Speaker 5:  a lot of fun.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, it does. I mean, again, we've just been, every time I hear about it
Speaker 4:  I'm like, huh, that's a new problem that we have
Speaker 6:  To like, we need a 2003 Ford Fiat that we can
Speaker 6:  just destroy.
Speaker 5:  Does anyone have an oxygen tank? Who Scuba
Speaker 4:  Certified the company can sign this insurance waiver. And I'm like, I don't
Speaker 4:  think any of them are gonna do that actually. Like we might have to hire
Speaker 4:  a new lawyer and lie to them
Speaker 6:  To pull. Yeah, just pull, just pull an E on and have them self
Speaker 4:  Certified. That's great.
Speaker 4:  Last thing, just, this is a very funny headline. Kanu has
Speaker 4:  repurposed its electric pickup truck for the army. I encourage you to go
Speaker 4:  look at the canoe pickup truck. It's adorable. And then try to imagine this
Speaker 4:  thing as a weapon of war.
Speaker 11:  That's
Speaker 4:  A very, it's very good. It's a very good idea. Fully.
Speaker 4:  That's it. That's V cast. We back, we, we've got grand plans
Speaker 4:  in David's absence. He was the one who really kept this thing on the rails
Speaker 4:  and as you can tell, even with two hours notice,
Speaker 4:  it's already going sideways. But tweeted him. Tom, congratulations.
Speaker 4:  You can tweet at us. I met Reckless. Alex is Alex h Kranz.
Speaker 4:  Heath is Alex E. Heath. Very confusing. You two. You both. We
Speaker 5:  Like to use our, our middle names. Good job.
Speaker 4:  We're back on Wednesday. Actually, this is like the last episode David did
Speaker 4:  before he took off. David and Alex are gonna talk about 15 years of the
Speaker 4:  Kindle. Yeah, Russell Brandon is gonna join us. He did a big project with
Speaker 4:  Consumer Reports, mapping out broadband. That's really cool. Last thing
Speaker 4:  we're working on our end of year wrap ups. Call into our hotline.
Speaker 4:  Eight six six Verge
Speaker 4:  11. 8 6 6 8. 3 7, 4 3,
Speaker 4:  1, 1. Tell us who you think your winners and losers of
Speaker 4:  2022 are. Here's a challenge show. You can't pick meta for either one. Oh,
Speaker 4:  that's rough. Yeah, it's, it's tough.
Speaker 5:  Can you put Elon,
Speaker 4:  I the people are gonna call, alright, Vox pop vox day
Speaker 4:  or
Speaker 11:  Whatever
Speaker 4:  To let the people speak. Call the number. Eight,
Speaker 4:  six, six Verge
Speaker 4:  1-866-837-FOUR 3 1 1. Winners and losers of 2022. But you
Speaker 4:  can't pick meta. All right. That's tough. I would've to think about that
Speaker 4:  for a while, but call the number and we'll, we'll, we'll let you know What
Speaker 4:  people say.
Speaker 1:  Sbs both
Speaker 4:  Sides. That's truly the highs and
Speaker 4:  lows. All right. That's it. That's V
Speaker 4:  Cast
Speaker 1:  And that's a wrap for Vergecast this week. Thanks for listening. If you enjoy
Speaker 1:  the show, subscribe in the podcast app of your choice or tell a friend, you
Speaker 1:  can send us feedback at vergecast@theverge.com. This show is produced
Speaker 1:  by me, Liam James, and our senior audio director, Andrew Marino.
Speaker 1:  This episode was edited and mixed by Amanda Rose
Speaker 1:  Smith. Our editorial director is Brooke Miners and our executive producer
Speaker 1:  is Eleanor Donovan. The Verge Cast is a production of the Verge and Box
Speaker 1:  Media podcast network. And that's it. We'll see you next
Speaker 1:  week.