# Transcript
ID: 58e71880-58ad-11ed-bd19-d1e4a3a9b905
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Twitter is now an Elon Musk company
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/2441121861087490009/-6365024637408409357/s93290-US-2867s-1667173647.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, Liz Lopatto, David Pierce, and Alex Cranz discuss Elon Musk officially becoming the owner of Twitter, and what that means for the future of the company.
Speaker 5:  Hello and welcome to The Road Chest, the flagship podcast of
Speaker 5:  impulse buying things you shouldn't have bought. I just bought a car. That's
Speaker 5:  a real thing that happened on the show. We'll talk about it later. I'm just
Speaker 5:  gonna be, I'm your friend of my hi. I'm just gonna be honest with you. We
Speaker 5:  thought we had today to prepare for this emergency. Elon
Speaker 5:  buys Twitter podcast. We thought it was gonna happen at like
Speaker 5:  4:20 PM today.
Speaker 5:  Nice. Right? See lot like if, if he could have
Speaker 5:  bought Twitter at 69 o'clock, he would've bought Twitter at 69
Speaker 5:  o'clock. So we thought we had like a day to prep and, but we didn't
Speaker 5:  because in classic Elon fashion, he appears to have bought it at
Speaker 5:  like 10:00 PM last night and then he fired
Speaker 5:  all the executives and then he just like wandered the halls. Like, I don't
Speaker 5:  know. I don't know man. Elon, So we're doing this, It's early, we're just
Speaker 5:  gonna get through it. I just got an email saying my recent article
Speaker 5:  sucks. That article is entitled Welcome to Hell Elon.
Speaker 5:  I forgot to turn off my notifications. This is how unprepared we are. My
Speaker 5:  notifications are Shalon. Anyway, I'm here. I'm Eli. David's here. Hi,
Speaker 5:  Alex is here.
Speaker 6:  Hey, I'm your friend who also impulse bought something this week, but it
Speaker 6:  was a fruit bowl so
Speaker 5:  It's fine. And Liz La Plato's here who has been writing this week in Elon
Speaker 5:  and she just very happily said, My part of this story is over
Speaker 5:  Welcome, Liz.
Speaker 7:  Hey, thanks for having me. I got about three hours of sleep last night, so
Speaker 7:  let's see how coherent I am.
Speaker 5:  It's, it's a lot. I mean we really did think that he was
Speaker 5:  gonna do it at like 4:20 PM today. Like the amount of confidence I
Speaker 5:  had in that outcome was very high.
Speaker 3:  The thing that this process has made me realize, like I've realized this
Speaker 3:  a hundred different times, but even this like last bit has made me realize
Speaker 3:  is that there's just no rules to anything. Yeah. Like you would think there's
Speaker 3:  like a thing that's supposed to happen where like a, like a person with authority
Speaker 3:  says like you now own Twitter. It's like the the like Michael
Speaker 3:  Scott, I declare bankruptcy, right? And it's just like, but
Speaker 3:  instead, instead it just like happened. There was just a minute where like
Speaker 3:  Elon Musk had a sink and then it was it.
Speaker 5:  That part is ridiculous. So I am pretty sure, I don't know if you've,
Speaker 5:  if you ever bought anything large, right? You actually show up to
Speaker 5:  a ceremony. Like even if you buy, like you buy a house, you're to like
Speaker 5:  go to a lawyer's office and then there's like lots of
Speaker 5:  randos there and then you have to sign 9,000 documents, get keys.
Speaker 5:  For some reason their entire lawyers like have an entire business just having
Speaker 5:  these meetings where you close the house and you leave and you're holding
Speaker 5:  the keys to the house and you're like, Crap, I hope I bought the right house,
Speaker 5:  right? Like yep, that's a thing when you buy a car, there's like lots of
Speaker 5:  stuff. There's a bank involved. I'm pretty sure Elon had that moment
Speaker 5:  yesterday he just did it with a sink that he had brought
Speaker 5:  to the meeting, like a physical bathroom sink that he had walked into
Speaker 5:  Twitter with to post a meme where he got to say let that sink in, which is
Speaker 5:  v very funny. Like,
Speaker 3:  Oh I loved it. He,
Speaker 6:  So he did that. He brought the sink in on, he did that Wednesday.
Speaker 5:  He went, okay,
Speaker 6:  But I do have a question. Did he bring that sink in,
Speaker 6:  go straight into Prague's office, drop it on the table and say
Speaker 6:  tomorrow you're fired.
Speaker 5:  So the sink was on Wednesday. I think he left the sink at Twitter. I don't
Speaker 5:  think he took the sink back out. So I think the sink just ominously sat in
Speaker 5:  the executive board in the Twitter and then he had his
Speaker 5:  closing meeting where he and his lawyers showed up yesterday. Twitter's
Speaker 5:  executives and board were there because they have to sign the documents,
Speaker 5:  turning all the stuff over to Elon. And then when that was done,
Speaker 5:  he just looked at them all and said, Most of you are fired.
Speaker 5:  Because the first report, if you recall the first report, I think it was
Speaker 5:  David favorite CNBC said Twitter CEO and CFO
Speaker 5:  have left the building and they are not expected to return. Which is an
Speaker 5:  incredible, like if you just think about what that he fired them right after
Speaker 5:  they signed the deal. He's like, you're gone. And then he fired
Speaker 5:  Vigo who's their head of policy, which is a big decision that we should talk
Speaker 5:  about. And I think he fired the general council, general council by the way,
Speaker 5:  who led the legal team that defeated Elon Musk. That
Speaker 5:  made Eon by Twitter, which he definitely tried to get out of Liz. That's
Speaker 5:  the part I want to start with.
Speaker 7:  The general counsel was escorted out by security. Like there were a couple
Speaker 7:  of people where it was, they weren't just like fired, They were fired in
Speaker 7:  humiliating fashion. So Sean t is the general counsel
Speaker 7:  and Bloomberg says security escorted him out. Paraag Aggarwal, the
Speaker 7:  former CEO and Neg Siegel who was the chief financial
Speaker 7:  officer, were also escorted out by security according to Reuters. Like can
Speaker 7:  you imagine like you've just done a deal with Elon Musk, you've signed the
Speaker 7:  thing and then two burley security guards like strong
Speaker 7:  arm you out of the building.
Speaker 5:  Oh they, I mean I can absolutely imagine that in this context.
Speaker 3:  I'm guessing if I'm parag aural, that's like the least
Speaker 3:  bad thing I thought might happen to me when all of this went down. Like that
Speaker 3:  dude has gotta have spent the last six months wondering what
Speaker 3:  horrible thing Elon was gonna do to him when this deal closed.
Speaker 7:  Well he is getting a nice payout.
Speaker 5:  Well he's gonna pay him $30 million.
Speaker 3:  Well there's that,
Speaker 5:  Right? So these, some of these executives got huge payouts. So like, if you
Speaker 5:  wanna give me 30 million and escort me out of a building, you pick
Speaker 5:  the to not run Twitter, I'm here
Speaker 5:  tomorrow. You just tell the building to show up at. I'll be escorted in the
Speaker 5:  building out of the building. As long as there's a check you, you just let
Speaker 5:  me know.
Speaker 7:  You hear that Elon?
Speaker 5:  So Liz, I wanted to start there, right there. This has been a long and winding
Speaker 5:  m and a journey. And I think that he escorted the general counsel of
Speaker 5:  Twitter outta the building by security as revenge because he got owned
Speaker 5:  in this process. Like he bought it for the number, he said he was gonna
Speaker 5:  buy it to the to the dime. He didn't even get a
Speaker 5:  discount after
Speaker 7:  All this. No, I actually would've kept that lawyer because he is a nightmare.
Speaker 7:  I I like full respect to all of the legal teams.
Speaker 7:  But Twitter's legal team in particular was quite good. And you may remember
Speaker 7:  that they were, the outside team was brought on and they were like the inventors
Speaker 7:  of the poison pill, which is a deal provision that that prevents,
Speaker 7:  prevents hostile takeovers that Twitter implemented before
Speaker 7:  the agreement to buy Twitter happened. And then Elon
Speaker 7:  canceled the deal and they canceled the deal some more And and, and then
Speaker 7:  we all were like, Oh I guess we're going to court. And then we didn't go
Speaker 7:  to court. So this was a really, really good agreement that was
Speaker 7:  negotiated. Like this was a really strong agreement. And like, I
Speaker 7:  think we've talked about this before, but I was of the opinion that Elon
Speaker 7:  Musk was gonna lose a trial and it looks like Elon Musk was also of the opinion
Speaker 7:  that Elon Musk was going to lose a trial. And so here we all are on Elon
Speaker 7:  musk's twitter.com or quitting elon musk's twitter.com
Speaker 7:  specifically because of all of these shenanigans.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I mean that's the,
Speaker 7:  No one's gonna quit.
Speaker 5:  So here's what I've, okay, first of all, I quit smoking while cold
Speaker 5:  Turkey while studying for the lsat. My faith that I can quit anything is
Speaker 5:  very high. It wasn't easy and I blew bubbles. I like took like kids
Speaker 5:  bubbles and I blew them outside of the law school in between class breaks.
Speaker 5:  Cause I needed to do something on my hands. But I'm willing to do it. You
Speaker 5:  can, if you find the bubbles equivalent of Twitter, I'll quit Twitter. It's
Speaker 5:  still there. I think we should see what happens to it. I just think a
Speaker 5:  lot of people are gonna stop using it. I think a lot of people are gonna
Speaker 5:  stop using it the way they had been using it. There is that
Speaker 5:  report in Reuters last week
Speaker 5:  that Twitter is already seeing a massive decline in quote
Speaker 5:  heavy tweeters and they kind of don't know why, but
Speaker 5:  the answers are obvious. It's that Twitter is an
Speaker 5:  inhospitable place.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, I mean like the thing about that report is that the decline started
Speaker 7:  well before Elon Musk, right? Like it starts during the pandemic. And I think
Speaker 7:  Ryan Broderick had the best explanation. He writes a newsletter called Garbage
Speaker 7:  Day. And I've just been thinking about this over and over where like Twitter
Speaker 7:  is a place where the users all hate each other and also the product itself.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. And like that's Twitter. It's just like we're all here at hell
Speaker 7:  and like if you turn up the heat a little more on hell, more people leave.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And I, this is I think the fundamental problem
Speaker 5:  for Elon. This is what I, I promised I would write this piece, Welcome
Speaker 5:  to hell Elon. It was supposed to be had something else and then it was just,
Speaker 5:  I just wrote it. But the problem for him is that to
Speaker 5:  make any money at all, he actually can't do
Speaker 5:  the things that he's promised his ardent fans that he would do. So
Speaker 5:  if you wanna make money and you don't just want to have ads
Speaker 5:  for supplements in like racist pillows, you have to promise
Speaker 5:  advertisers brand safety, right? You have to say your ads are gonna go in
Speaker 5:  a place that is, that won't make your brand look bad. Taco Bell
Speaker 5:  like it, it's just the, it's the basic. If you just read
Speaker 5:  about internet advertising, they are always constantly talking
Speaker 5:  about brand safety. It is the thing. And so Twitter
Speaker 5:  is a real problem with that, as in general it has
Speaker 5:  somewhat managed to find ways to overcome it. But it is the
Speaker 5:  smallest to the social networks because it is inhospitable, it does not
Speaker 5:  make you feel good to use it. Like if you're a new Twitter user,
Speaker 5:  your desire to tweet is pretty low because
Speaker 5:  the things that will happen to you after you tweet are mostly
Speaker 5:  negative, right? Like bots will try to sell you crypto or some Randa
Speaker 5:  will pop up and talk shit to you. Like those are the, or no one
Speaker 5:  or nothing will happen. Which is actually the worst outcome for a social
Speaker 5:  network. Like if you're trying to incentivize content creation
Speaker 5:  because a social network without lots of people working for free is
Speaker 5:  a bad idea. So you're, you're trying to get people to work for free
Speaker 5:  and if the thing that happens most often is nothing, like no one pays attention
Speaker 5:  to you. That's bad. If it's bots try to sell you crypto, that's bad. Maybe
Speaker 5:  Elon can solve that problem and he's focused on it or it's you get
Speaker 5:  harassed all this is bad. Like none of these are, this is why the
Speaker 5:  only people who tweet are like hopelessly addicted online people.
Speaker 3:  Well, and this is why you see Elon like talking out of both sides of his
Speaker 3:  mouth throughout this whole process. On the one hand he's, he's talking to
Speaker 3:  people about, you know, scaling down content moderation and bringing back
Speaker 3:  Donald Trump and, and open sourcing the algorithm whatever the hell that
Speaker 3:  means. And this idea that like it should be a freer place that follows the
Speaker 3:  laws. And then he's sitting with advertisers saying, No, no, no, it's still
Speaker 3:  gonna be fine. I won't like free for all. Hellscape is the phrase that he
Speaker 3:  used that I think is going to haunt him for a long time because it is now
Speaker 3:  very stuck in my brain. And like, and and so
Speaker 3:  he's, he's trying to do a thing that everyone has proved over and over
Speaker 3:  is impossible. Which is to let chaos reign in
Speaker 3:  an advertising friendly way and like you just can't do
Speaker 5:  That. Right? And so the pro like Elon does not like being told what to
Speaker 5:  do. Liz, I feel like that's a Liz is shaking your head. Okay. I feel like
Speaker 5:  that's a safe statement. Elon Musk does not like being told what to do. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  When you own a social network, all kinds of people get to
Speaker 5:  tell you what to do. So the advertisers say we need brand safety. You need
Speaker 5:  to moderate away the racism, the sexism, the transphobia, all the bad stuff
Speaker 5:  so that we can sell more shoes. That's just the basics of the thing. They
Speaker 5:  want their ads near stuff. That's nice. Then you gotta incentivize people
Speaker 5:  to make nice things, which is hard, just like flatly hard. Like
Speaker 5:  YouTube can't do it. YouTube is maybe the most successful of
Speaker 5:  these companies, right? We don't think of it as a social network in that
Speaker 5:  way, but YouTube gets like most kids in America want to be
Speaker 5:  YouTubers when they grow up. Like YouTube has created the incentive
Speaker 5:  structure where people wanna show up and make nice things for other people
Speaker 5:  on YouTube and advertisers want pour money into that and that's fine
Speaker 5:  great. YouTube has moderation problems every single day at this scale that
Speaker 5:  you could not possibly imagine. That's just the basics. Like you
Speaker 5:  need people to show up, you need to get money from advertisers, advertisers
Speaker 5:  that want nice things. Now you have to listen to the advertisers, which is
Speaker 5:  why Elon Musk wrote an open letter on Twitter promising advertisers it was
Speaker 5:  gonna be fine cuz he can't kill his revenue right away.
Speaker 5:  Then there are governments around the world which love
Speaker 5:  passing speech regulations, love it. Can't get enough of it. It seems like
Speaker 5:  if you become a politician, the first thing you wanna do is tell people what
Speaker 5:  they can say. This is true in our country.
Speaker 5:  So in Texas and Florida there are these social media laws that are effectively
Speaker 5:  impossible to comply with because they ban
Speaker 5:  any moderation that is based on viewpoint without really defining it.
Speaker 5:  That's going to the Supreme Court. Elon is out here saying I'm gonna support
Speaker 5:  DeSantis for president and he is massively
Speaker 5:  invested in Texas and he's gotta fight those governments,
Speaker 5:  those governors, those are their laws. He's gotta go tell the Supreme
Speaker 5:  Court these laws are unconstitutional. That's just like I that that's a
Speaker 5:  tight rope he has to
Speaker 6:  Launch. Does he have to tell them that? Like I think we
Speaker 6:  are assuming that he is going to run this company like
Speaker 6:  every other social media network and that he is going to
Speaker 6:  incentivize advertisers like every other social media network and I just
Speaker 6:  don't think that's
Speaker 5:  True. We can use the advertiser assumption because he just told
Speaker 6:  And then he fired the person who does advertising at Twitter. Like I
Speaker 6:  genuinely do not. I think we are in a whole new
Speaker 6:  space with him because he is the richest man in the world and he
Speaker 6:  has shown again and again and again he can do what he wants.
Speaker 7:  And I, so yes, I agree with you Alex.
Speaker 7:  100% I think we were in for like a big reign of chaos and you all know how
Speaker 7:  I feel about chaos. I love it very much. But I'm just thinking about like
Speaker 7:  all of the moderation problems that every larger company has had, right?
Speaker 7:  And like I'm not even like for like leave aside like the most
Speaker 7:  nasty part of it. Like politics, like livestream,
Speaker 7:  shootings, all of those things like leave aside the nastiest parts
Speaker 7:  of moderation. Like if you think about Google
Speaker 7:  for instance, their text snippets have at times told users
Speaker 7:  that Snoopy assassinated Abraham Lincoln and
Speaker 7:  at Facebook they actually lost a piece of their moderation policy for three
Speaker 7:  years. So in addition to like the big stuff, there are all these little things
Speaker 7:  that can also go wrong. But on top of that, this is the
Speaker 7:  cherry on top for me working with people is not like
Speaker 7:  engineering. Yeah. Because building a community is really different from
Speaker 7:  building a rocket cuz rockets don't talk back.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I mean this to, Well they tend to explode
Speaker 5:  that in that way. They're a lot
Speaker 6:  Like Twitter.
Speaker 5:  No, I mean I agree with you. I mean this is to me that I, we see this
Speaker 5:  repeated over and over again, right? People approach these community problems
Speaker 5:  like engineering problems and they say things I'll give you,
Speaker 5:  I'll give you a totally unrelated example, but it it's the same example because
Speaker 5:  it's the same approach. You talk to self-driving car CEOs,
Speaker 5:  you're like, how are you gonna build the cars? Who's gonna write the rules?
Speaker 5:  And they're like, the rules are already written down, it's just the rules
Speaker 5:  of the road. And it's like, so you, you think you can just like ingest the
Speaker 5:  state DMV into your robot car and then it's gonna be fine. And
Speaker 5:  it turns out like cars are totally unpredictable. Like this is not how it
Speaker 5:  works. Like other people in cars tend to make decisions that have nothing
Speaker 5:  to do with the what the DMV thinks you should do. And they're stuck because
Speaker 5:  they thought there was a list of rules they could just follow. And you can
Speaker 5:  apply that exact same thinking to Elon has tweeted this,
Speaker 5:  If people want the speech to be legal or if people want a ban speech,
Speaker 5:  they can write a law. He said this, so we're just gonna take the first amendment
Speaker 5:  and glue it into some AI and then that will run
Speaker 5:  moderation for us against the principles of the First Amendment. Well the
Speaker 5:  problem is, the thing the First amendment actually does is it prevents
Speaker 5:  the people of America from making a law that bans some
Speaker 5:  speech, right? It prevents government speech regulation. It
Speaker 5:  allows for private speech regulation, it
Speaker 5:  allows for the it for private companies, for private citizens to speak
Speaker 5:  however they want to publish however they want and it keeps the government
Speaker 5:  out of it. At least that's how it should work. So you you
Speaker 5:  like just from like an end, like a systems engineering perspective,
Speaker 5:  you're saying okay, we're gonna grab the first amendment,
Speaker 5:  which prevents our system from doing much of anything. And if
Speaker 5:  people wanna change it, they wanna change how Twitter works,
Speaker 5:  they can somehow overrule the first amendment, which is the, the
Speaker 5:  main thing and it's like you are trapped in a doom loop. No,
Speaker 5:  He is the first thing that's gonna happen. No, cuz the first thing that's
Speaker 5:  gonna happen to him is he's like every other social network that promises
Speaker 5:  the same thing, he's gonna start banning people that do horrible
Speaker 5:  things. Par this happened to Parlor happened to Getter happened to Truth
Speaker 5:  Social. Yeah, truth social has like the most restrictive mother age.
Speaker 6:  But I wonder like, is he actually going to do that? That's
Speaker 6:  that's the thing is like we, we keep assuming that he's going to be like,
Speaker 6:  Oh this person said something horrible online. They they go,
Speaker 6:  but he has repeatedly said he wants every viewpoint on
Speaker 6:  Twitter. He wants to make this a big open ecosystem.
Speaker 6:  He wants to minimize moderation. So I like
Speaker 5:  Don't think he knows what that means.
Speaker 6:  No, I agree. But that's why I
Speaker 5:  We have reasonable here's some like reasonable debates you could have, right?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. That every viewpoint on Twitter, you can have
Speaker 5:  a reasonable debate about the Fed setting interest rates
Speaker 5:  and people will scream at each other and wanna murder each other
Speaker 5:  over half a percentage point of the Fed setting interest rate. You can
Speaker 5:  have a reasonable debate about whether the government should provide healthcare,
Speaker 5:  right? I think it should. A lot of people don't. That has a reasonable
Speaker 5:  debate, right? There are numbers on both sides of that argument. Yeah. You
Speaker 5:  can have a reasonable debate on education policy. You
Speaker 5:  can, you really can. Lots of ways to educate your kids, but you can't have
Speaker 5:  a reasonable debate on like whether brown people are inferior to
Speaker 5:  British people. Like yeah, that's not a choice. And that is the actually
Speaker 5:  the aperture that everybody wants to open. Yep. Right?
Speaker 5:  The app, the thing that everybody wants to open is Kanye West saying Jewish
Speaker 5:  people control the media and the reason that Twitter doesn't allow
Speaker 5:  it is well one that's like dangerous. Yeah, it
Speaker 5:  causes actual political violence in the world, but Twitter does not wanna
Speaker 5:  be associated with, and two, it makes people fucking
Speaker 5:  leave the platform. Like the most cynical motivation that anyone could have
Speaker 5:  is, oh, this retards user growth like this makes people go away.
Speaker 5:  It makes the number go down. And like all of that is
Speaker 5:  the people who want to open the aperture of free speech on the
Speaker 5:  margin are not people with more conservative economic policy.
Speaker 5:  It's basically people who want to like reintroduce racism.
Speaker 5:  Right. Reintroduce sexism. Right. And what they are complaining about
Speaker 5:  is not even that they can't do it. Cause have you been on Twitter? No,
Speaker 6:  No, no. I'm, I'm very aware they
Speaker 5:  Can do it. What they're complaining about is they don't get the reach
Speaker 6:  Right.
Speaker 5:  They're like their shadow banned. Right. And like, is Elon gonna increase
Speaker 5:  their reach? Is he gonna solve that problem? Like I just don't, I don't think
Speaker 5:  that that problem is tractable.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I I just don't think that Elon
Speaker 6:  cares like, like I think he is going to go after
Speaker 6:  whatever gets him the biggest numbers and I think if he sees, Oh I brought
Speaker 6:  Trunk back, I'm gonna get bigger numbers. Oh if I bring Kanye back, I'm gonna
Speaker 6:  get bigger numbers. He's going to focus on the numbers, not necessarily on
Speaker 6:  the shit show. Those numbers bring because he cares about the
Speaker 6:  numbers. He's like a reality TV producer
Speaker 7:  And he likes shit shows. Let's be real. I mean like think about Tesla,
Speaker 7:  remember like the the robots that were gonna build the cars and he was like,
Speaker 7:  I'm re-engineering from first principles how to build cars. And everybody
Speaker 7:  was like, Toyota knows how to build cars, like just do that. And he was like,
Speaker 7:  No, no, it's going to be an alien dread knot. And then that didn't work out
Speaker 7:  and he put a an extra card building tent in the parking lot
Speaker 7:  of the Fremont factory. I mean like I don't know that he necessarily
Speaker 7:  is thinking about any of this stuff because as we've discovered from his
Speaker 7:  text messages where he quits the Twitter board two minutes after Agro
Speaker 7:  Wall asks him not to say mean things about Twitter,
Speaker 7:  like this man has no impulse control. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Well and I think part of this is also like a lot of the stuff that we're
Speaker 3:  talking about assumes on some base level that Elon Musk
Speaker 3:  tends to keep Twitter at like a very fundamental level the
Speaker 3:  same. And I'm not sure there's actually like a lot of evidence that that's
Speaker 3:  the case. I think like you look at what Elon Musk has wanted to do and
Speaker 3:  he talks about, he talks about TikTok and he talks about payments and he
Speaker 3:  talks about WeChat and it's like this idea of like, I wanna make
Speaker 3:  this sort of beautiful network where people can talk to each other
Speaker 3:  that like Jack Dorsey used to talk about, I don't know the dealer Musk has
Speaker 3:  any particular interest in that. So like this idea that like he's just gonna
Speaker 3:  sort of shunt that off to the side and like let it burn down while he tries
Speaker 3:  to build a payment network on top of it and also tries to like retain his
Speaker 3:  own audience where he can use it to sell Tesla's. That seems perfectly plausible
Speaker 3:  to me that he's like, Oh no, is twitter.com or moderation nightmare and everybody's
Speaker 3:  gonna stop using it. That's really not a problem. I'm gonna go like
Speaker 3:  try to do something else on top of this network and make money at when people
Speaker 3:  like buy subscriptions.
Speaker 7:  Well I also think about airlines here because we're talking about a hellscape,
Speaker 7:  right? And one of the things that Elon Musk has promised
Speaker 7:  to do is he's, he wants to increase subscription revenue. Most of Twitter's
Speaker 7:  revenue is advertising, but if you can make a subscriptions, you know, service
Speaker 7:  really work for you, then it doesn't matter if you're brand safe because
Speaker 7:  that's not where the bulk of your money is coming from, it's coming from
Speaker 7:  your users. And so like one possible thing that you can do if you're evil
Speaker 7:  is like you can be like, yeah you can have the hellscape or you can pay,
Speaker 7:  I don't know, $10 a month and not have a hellscape.
Speaker 5:  So this is the most interesting idea to me for
Speaker 3:  The Spirit Airlines version of Twitter.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I just watched an incredible to talk with
Speaker 5:  the Sea of Ryanair where he admitted that for a while he
Speaker 5:  wanted to create a standing room only part of
Speaker 5:  the plane.
Speaker 6:  They tested it with like seats that where you just like stood up
Speaker 6:  and kinda leaned.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, yeah. And he was like, here's the thing, here's what I know. We would've
Speaker 5:  filled that part of the plane first, but like it's morally outrageous so
Speaker 5:  we didn't do it. I'm fine with this, but the reason I'm, I'm,
Speaker 5:  I mean I don't, I refuse to fly Spirit Airlines. I'm the sucker is like,
Speaker 5:  no I need, I need comfort plus at least come on. But
Speaker 5:  the thing that is super interesting about this is there isn't a market
Speaker 5:  for moderation. Like the thing the airlines have proven is that there's actually
Speaker 5:  a market for fair classes, right? You can, you can set, you
Speaker 5:  can segment the plane all the way to at the back, you are
Speaker 5:  standing up and at the front you are lying down and people will pay various
Speaker 5:  amounts of money to be in all those tiers of the plane. That's weird. You
Speaker 5:  know, like maybe that's a little too capitalistic, but they've proven that
Speaker 5:  there's a effective functional market for all those different kinds of service
Speaker 5:  to get from point A to point B. We have never seen any
Speaker 5:  social network really try to experiment with is there a market for levels
Speaker 5:  of moderation even between the social networks because of all of the
Speaker 5:  external pressures they all face from advertisers, from governments, from
Speaker 5:  their own users and service of growth. They all kind of land
Speaker 5:  at the same places with moderation, which I think is deeply
Speaker 5:  frustrating to a lot of people. We've never seen any social networks say
Speaker 5:  with a single user base. Okay, you can, you can pick
Speaker 5:  all like all the way moderation, happy place, Disney World
Speaker 5:  or Hellscape. And this is like one of those
Speaker 5:  academic ideas that we like hear about all the time, like Addie and Casey
Speaker 5:  and I have just like heard this idea a million times that maybe moderation
Speaker 5:  should be outsourced and you should be able to bring your own moderation
Speaker 5:  provider and your own algorithm to your social graph and you should buy the
Speaker 5:  one you want. That sounds great. Except when you play it out, it's like,
Speaker 5:  no, people don't want to think that hard about any software in their lives.
Speaker 5:  Like they just want the one that comes in the box like, and
Speaker 5:  so we'll just see if the default Twitter algorithm is the one that's
Speaker 5:  safest for advertisers and the one that will create more growth, that's the
Speaker 5:  one people are gonna use. And if your choice is I can turn it down and see
Speaker 5:  more racism, no one's gonna turn it down or we are all gonna be
Speaker 5:  very surprised at the market dynamics of what turning it down looks like.
Speaker 7:  I also, while we're talking money, one thing that I am really curious about
Speaker 7:  is not Twitter directly, but Twitter's effects on Elon's other companies.
Speaker 7:  So like Twitter for instance, you know, if you have a strong free speech
Speaker 7:  stance on Twitter and you're trying to sell cars in China, you have a very
Speaker 7:  large attack surface whenever anything happens on Twitter that the Chinese
Speaker 7:  government doesn't like. And one of the things that's true about Tesla is
Speaker 7:  that it's not in India yet, but India is a really big market and
Speaker 7:  Twitter is extremely controversial in India. And like you can imagine
Speaker 7:  if you're taking a strong free speech stance where you don't remove Nazis,
Speaker 7:  well you have a Tesla factory in Germany where a Nazi speech is banned.
Speaker 7:  So there are, there's like, one of the things that I think is really interesting
Speaker 7:  here is that Eli Musk has a much larger attack surface than anybody like
Speaker 7:  Mark Zuckerberg or you know, anybody running any of these other
Speaker 7:  companies. Like you can actually punish him through the other things that
Speaker 7:  he does. And so I think that's going to be really fascinating to see how
Speaker 7:  that plays out both for Twitter and for everything else. Like
Speaker 7:  what happens to SpaceX? Like if, you know
Speaker 7:  he does something that the government doesn't like, does, does SpaceX
Speaker 7:  suffer?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I mean that one is like deeply
Speaker 5:  contentious, right? Because SpaceX is in Texas, if he fights
Speaker 5:  Abbott, that's just a big problem. But the government
Speaker 5:  needs SpaceX, like it doesn't have the capability to launch anything by itself.
Speaker 5:  So that's a good spot. I think Tesla is the
Speaker 5:  scariest one, right? If you're Elon, you've now,
Speaker 5:  you've got a big business in, in Germany, like you said, which has very
Speaker 5:  stringent speech laws. You have a huge business in China where you can't
Speaker 5:  even operate Twitter. Like your, the game you are now
Speaker 5:  playing with Tesla in China is, if there's a lot of anti-China
Speaker 5:  stuff on Twitter, they can, they, they're the Chinese
Speaker 5:  government has no compunction about just destroying companies left and
Speaker 5:  right. It destroys companies. Yeah. Especially the companies seem too powerful
Speaker 5:  or the executives of those companies seem too powerful. Elon is now in a
Speaker 5:  place where the pressure he will feel to make Twitter
Speaker 5:  more China friendly is actually real because
Speaker 5:  Tesla needs to expand in China because that is the market for
Speaker 3:  Those cars. Yeah, and I, well, and I think e even more sort of abstractly
Speaker 3:  like Liz, you've been, you've written about this a bunch in the last six
Speaker 3:  months. There's like this force of personality that Elon Musk has that
Speaker 3:  has gotten him a lot of what he has gotten over time. And it
Speaker 3:  has like been his bet that just by virtue of the fact that I am Elon Musk,
Speaker 3:  I can do whatever I want at any time and it'll probably work out because
Speaker 3:  I'm Elon Musk and the rules don't apply to me. And historically speaking
Speaker 3:  that is true. But it also seems like that like with
Speaker 3:  this trial that didn't end up happening in Delaware, there
Speaker 3:  was this real tide turning against him and you could feel that
Speaker 3:  like the, the sort of cult of Elon Musk in which like the richest man in
Speaker 3:  the world can do no wrong by virtue of who he is seems to be going away.
Speaker 3:  And now he's like tied this incredible anvil around his neck
Speaker 3:  called Twitter that feels like, like, like if
Speaker 3:  anything is going to make everyone sour on the whole idea of Elon Musk,
Speaker 3:  it's it, boy it seems like it would be Twitter. And it does feel
Speaker 3:  like it's gonna have all kinds of ramifications
Speaker 3:  across these other companies. Like the, the Tesla investors have been worried
Speaker 3:  about this crazy distraction that is Twitter that is not going to get less
Speaker 3:  distracting now that he owns the place and it just, yeah, it seems like if
Speaker 3:  I'm interested in any of his other companies, Twitter feels like
Speaker 3:  it's gonna just drag everything around him down into the
Speaker 3:  muck forever and ever.
Speaker 7:  David, I wouldn't say Anvil. I would say Albatross.
Speaker 3:  Sure.
Speaker 5:  Good at it from Liz. All right, let's take a break. I think we've made it
Speaker 5:  abundantly clear what we think is going to happen to Twitter. Let's take
Speaker 5:  a break though. Come back and let's do a little bit on what the upside might
Speaker 5:  be. It's gonna be a short segment, but we ran back.
Speaker 1:  This episode is brought to you by Blazing Trails and original podcasts. When
Speaker 1:  the mind's over at Salesforce, their new six part series Meet the Customer
Speaker 1:  hones in on the relationships between businesses and the people who buy their
Speaker 1:  products. I had a chance to get an advanced listen to their first episode.
Speaker 1:  It's all about how King Arthur Flower listens to their customers to know
Speaker 1:  where they're going. And if you like pizza, I mean of course you like pizza,
Speaker 1:  you'll like this episode to hear, meet the customer, search for Blazing
Speaker 1:  Trails from Salesforce in your podcast player and thanks to Salesforce for
Speaker 1:  their support.
Speaker 3:  Today's episode is sponsored by npr, the podcast Planet Money
Speaker 3:  imagines a world where the complex economy actually makes sense,
Speaker 3:  where human stories supersede complex theories and where listeners
Speaker 3:  can learn, laugh and be entertained. It's econ down to earth
Speaker 3:  from How the Perfect Apple was created to new ways to pay for college, to
Speaker 3:  breaking down the price of gasoline. The Planet Money Team lives to break
Speaker 3:  down an interesting topic and tell a good story all in a 30 minute episode.
Speaker 3:  I have to tell you, I've been listening to Planet Money for years. It's one
Speaker 3:  of the best podcasts about just like the weird side of how the
Speaker 3:  economy works. They find deeply strange things like that. Apple episode
Speaker 3:  was about how we went from really crappy apples to really great apples
Speaker 3:  and how the business world made that happen. It's super interesting.
Speaker 3:  You should listen to it. The episodes are pretty short. The hosts are really
Speaker 3:  fun to listen to. It's a very good podcast. I cannot recommend it enough.
Speaker 3:  Planet Money comes out every week and you can tune in to hear entertaining
Speaker 3:  stories and insights about how money shapes our world stories that can't
Speaker 3:  be found anywhere else. Check out Planet Money from NPR wherever you get
Speaker 3:  your podcasts.
Speaker 5:  Okay, we're back. Let's, I think it's clear
Speaker 5:  we don't think this is gonna go well, but let's, let's do the thought exercise
Speaker 5:  and let's stipulate, but let's do the thought exercise of what might go
Speaker 5:  well here, what might work. And we should stipulate like I will happily concede,
Speaker 5:  Twitter is not a well run company. It has not had good
Speaker 5:  executives running it or even like executives who are paying
Speaker 5:  attention or use the service. Like it's just not,
Speaker 5:  it's it, it probably has too many people. I, you know, it has
Speaker 5:  thousands of people doing nothing in Prag Auger roll the the
Speaker 5:  outgoing ceo, like his greatest accomplishment was forcing Elon to buy the
Speaker 5:  company. The only person who has ever stood up to Elon Musk is Prag aural.
Speaker 5:  Congratulations, you shipped no software but yet you
Speaker 5:  executed this. You had the stones to, to stand up to Elon. Great
Speaker 7:  Incredible man, Not incredible deal
Speaker 7:  by the way. Like incredible moves. Like this is like CEO hall of fame
Speaker 7:  shit and he wasn't even CEO for a year. So like hats off
Speaker 7:  man. Good
Speaker 5:  For you. I think that, Who's the Salesforce guy? Benioff? No, the other
Speaker 5:  guy who's on the board. Brett Taylor. I think Brett Taylor who's the, the
Speaker 5:  chairman of Twitter's board and the co CEO Salesforce might have helped.
Speaker 5:  I just wanna put that out. But congrats to Prague.
Speaker 5:  It's not like Twitter is well run, right? So Elon's showing up, maybe he's
Speaker 5:  gonna run it. Well what are the good things that could happen?
Speaker 3:  The first thing that jumps out to me is that by virtue of being private and
Speaker 3:  also by being owned by someone like Elon Musk, Twitter can
Speaker 3:  in theory start to do some of these things that don't
Speaker 3:  obviously scale, which we've never really seen in social before. Like this
Speaker 3:  idea that you know, you could start charging money for Facebook and some
Speaker 3:  percentage of people would sign up for Facebook, like Facebook was never
Speaker 3:  gonna invest in that because you have quarterly results and you can't
Speaker 3:  make a dent in your business in order for like, there just is no such thing
Speaker 3:  as like a long term vision for something like that, for these like big public
Speaker 3:  companies because everything has to look like growth and everything has to
Speaker 3:  look like scale. And Elon has even talked about this that like the
Speaker 3:  only way to reset Twitter is to basically go through some really, really,
Speaker 3:  really like messy times on the platform. And if he actually has
Speaker 3:  the patience to do that, we can like get this incubator of
Speaker 3:  interesting social ideas that I think could in theory be very cool.
Speaker 3:  And some of the stuff he's talked about like trying to experiment with subscriptions
Speaker 3:  and trying to like build new ways of thinking about algorithms and like
Speaker 3:  will any of that work? I don't know, but at least there's like an interesting
Speaker 3:  test bed with a lot of people inside of it that could actually lead to some
Speaker 3:  interesting stuff.
Speaker 7:  I am going to say one thing that's close to reality and one
Speaker 7:  thing that I think is pretty far fetched but I think is also interesting,
Speaker 7:  the thing that's close to reality is I personally would love to see encrypted
Speaker 7:  dms and I understand that there are probably downsides to doing that
Speaker 7:  kind of encryption specifically around like reporting spam in your
Speaker 7:  dms and so on. But the upside is that you have secure dms now, which has
Speaker 7:  been a long time problem for Twitter and for anybody using Twitter. And that
Speaker 7:  seems like it could be a really good thing and it's something that we've
Speaker 7:  heard Musk talking about. So like I certainly hope that he executes on that
Speaker 7:  at least. But the other thing that I think about that's really like more
Speaker 7:  far-fetched is we know he has an interest in AI and we know he has an interest
Speaker 7:  in neurolink, which is a brain machine interface that's like
Speaker 7:  he Musk's ambitions for it are well beyond what brain
Speaker 7:  machine interfaces probably can do. But he wants to like have
Speaker 7:  it be like, you know, your way to communicate with a computer, you can be
Speaker 7:  a cyborg if you want. So like there's like this wild idea that has been
Speaker 7:  circulating that like I now have as an intrusive thought where it's like
Speaker 7:  oh he's going to use all of our language inputs to train like
Speaker 7:  an AI of some kind and it's gonna be like the meanest,
Speaker 7:  nastiest AI you've ever seen. But
Speaker 7:  you know it's gonna be trained with all of this real world input from
Speaker 7:  all of these real people who are really all on Twitter and like as a database
Speaker 7:  set, if you're a person who likes ai, that's potentially interesting.
Speaker 5:  I'm just, sorry, I'm just imagining these AI that are just doing Twitter
Speaker 5:  memes all day like this,
Speaker 9:  Just
Speaker 6:  Dolly pictures, boom,
Speaker 6:  it's gonna be great.
Speaker 3:  You say like, hello. It just responds with the thread icons.
Speaker 5:  The most sophisticated AI in the world is all like I did a thing.
Speaker 8:  Oops.
Speaker 7:  All I'm saying is he brought in a sink. You never know.
Speaker 5:  Just, all right, so David's on interesting
Speaker 5:  tested, let's experiment on the population of celebrities
Speaker 5:  and world leaders to see what happens. Internalists Liz is, I
Speaker 5:  want brains and vats basically brains and vats.
Speaker 5:  Alex, what do you got?
Speaker 6:  I think like this guy is going to try to use AI
Speaker 6:  to solve the moderation problem, right? And he's going to put a
Speaker 6:  ton, he's already putting resources towards it. He was like, all right, I'll
Speaker 6:  use Tesla self-driving car engineers get on over to Twitter
Speaker 6:  and figure this out. And so I think we are pretty rapidly going
Speaker 6:  to have a very conclusive answer to can AI solve
Speaker 6:  moderation? I think the answer's gonna be no. But I think we're going to
Speaker 6:  see so many resources put towards it in a way that we just at a level we
Speaker 6:  just have never seen before that like we're gonna be able to say he did
Speaker 6:  everything and still couldn't do it. And we'll finally be able to
Speaker 6:  put that like put that baby in bed.
Speaker 6:  That's it. We have the,
Speaker 5:  Here you go, dumb baby, you're asleep now We've
Speaker 6:  Seen it. We've seen it, We know we can't do it. Move on.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So the one thing I'll say about that I agree, I again, I
Speaker 5:  think a lot of what we're gonna see here is ideas that are abstract and
Speaker 5:  academic getting run to ground. Yep. Right? Marketplace of
Speaker 5:  moderation systems that ideas gonna get run to ground. Can we scale
Speaker 5:  AI to do it? That idea is gonna get run to ground because if he wants to
Speaker 5:  fire as many people as he has said he wants to fire, Twitter itself said
Speaker 5:  it wanted to fire 25% of its employees this year before Elon showed up
Speaker 5:  with a sink. So if he wants to get rid of all the people he wants to get
Speaker 5:  rid of you, you have to automate some of it. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Right? Like or you realize like you just have a bunch of engineers who are
Speaker 5:  drinking coffee all day, not doing anything, tune us. But to me the
Speaker 5:  the thing that he's, because he's the king of Twitter, every moderation
Speaker 5:  decision is gonna be, it's his reputation. Yeah. And the thing that
Speaker 5:  is true of every automated system anywhere in the
Speaker 5:  world doing anything is that they false a lot, right? They
Speaker 5:  just like, they have an error rate. It's inherent to everything. So you
Speaker 5:  have an, I'll give you another benign example. Content ID on YouTube
Speaker 5:  is theoretically a benign system. I don't think it's Ayn system,
Speaker 5:  but theoretically it's a benign system, right? Where
Speaker 5:  the music industry doesn't wants to get paid for its music, which
Speaker 5:  is also theoretically a benign motivation. And so they can take stuff down
Speaker 5:  if it matches the copyrights of songs. This thing falses
Speaker 5:  so much all the time. I think
Speaker 5:  most people have a better sense of the copyright
Speaker 5:  policy of YouTube than like the speed limit
Speaker 5:  two miles away from their house,
Speaker 5:  Right? Cuz you are just confronted with this automated system
Speaker 5:  fucking with people all the time and all the YouTubers are constantly
Speaker 5:  talking about it. And that's like a inherently benign system,
Speaker 5:  right? That's a system that's designed that has the motivations like
Speaker 5:  basically everybody can agree on, which is artists should get paid for their
Speaker 5:  music. And yet it's like a in practice, a maligned
Speaker 5:  force, right? It like makes the experience worse for lots of people. You
Speaker 5:  expand that to like semantic analysis of whether is this joke
Speaker 5:  racist or is it in context? Justine Sacco, Like who
Speaker 5:  knows, right? That when that system starts fing whatever,
Speaker 5:  error raid, all of it gets blamed on Elon. And that is like a
Speaker 5:  disaster zone.
Speaker 3:  I think you might be vastly underestimating Elon Musk's ability
Speaker 3:  to not give one single shit about whether
Speaker 3:  people are mad at him about moderation decisions like this has all made me
Speaker 3:  think about Mark Zuckerberg a lot because there was this like, this like
Speaker 3:  joker origin story from Mark Zuckerberg where he like, I think
Speaker 3:  genuinely felt bad about some of the mistakes that Facebook was making and
Speaker 3:  and sort of, you know, apologized over and over and over in public. And then
Speaker 3:  you could just see over the course of the last few years went to a point
Speaker 3:  where he's just like, I'm not gonna talk about this anymore. Like, I'm just
Speaker 3:  not interested in this. I'm gonna talk about the metaverse and if you wanna
Speaker 3:  be mad about moderation problems, go be mad at somebody else. This is no
Speaker 3:  longer my problem. I pay nickle a lot of money to be the one who apologizes
Speaker 3:  for all the dumb stuff that happens on Facebook. I'm
Speaker 5:  So excited for the first Elon Congressional hearing.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Elon is like a 40 out of 10 on that scale of just like,
Speaker 3:  he's like, Oh, you're mad. Congratulations. Enjoy being mad
Speaker 3:  on Elon Musk. Goodbye. A
Speaker 5:  69 out
Speaker 3:  Of 10, he's a 60, he's a four 20.69.
Speaker 5:  Alright, so what do I, the one good thing that I think will happen out of
Speaker 5:  all of this is that this is such a backwards
Speaker 5:  compliment. All right, here's my backwards compliment. I
Speaker 5:  think people are tired of Twitter, I think they're tired of social
Speaker 5:  networks like this. I feel tired of them and I, I
Speaker 5:  think that all this noise is just like a shock
Speaker 5:  to the system that will make people reconsider how they spend their time.
Speaker 5:  And I, I, we talked about it on the vercast earlier today, like
Speaker 5:  we are surrounded by tech giants that are pretty complacent.
Speaker 5:  Like, and their products are getting weird and bad. Like Google search is
Speaker 5:  bad. Like whatever is going on with the
Speaker 5:  iPad is not the force of focused competition,
Speaker 5:  it's just the stuff is happening and they're trying to extract more money
Speaker 5:  from everything. Twitter is in this unique position where everyone's just
Speaker 5:  sort of, it's the default for a bunch of journalists and politicians. It's
Speaker 5:  where we're all mean to each other. It's like we issue dunks and if this
Speaker 5:  just creates a moment for some people to reconsider their relationship with
Speaker 5:  that product cause they don't wanna work for Elon for free, right? And if
Speaker 5:  you are creating content for Twitter, you are now working for Elon
Speaker 5:  Musk for free. I don't think you should work for the richest man in the world
Speaker 5:  for free. That's just my my take on it. That might actually shake a
Speaker 5:  bunch of competition loose. And I think that is just a huge benefit for everybody
Speaker 5:  right now cuz they're so in the sort of core internet services,
Speaker 5:  there's such vanishingly little competition
Speaker 5:  in like, everyone's afraid of TikTok. That's it. That's what you got.
Speaker 5:  That's the evidence of competition on the internet. Today's TikTok and they're
Speaker 5:  all competing with it by just slavishly copying it.
Speaker 5:  I'm just, I'm just hopeful that this is, you can't just tell people to be
Speaker 5:  different. You have to like provide some shock to the system and this is
Speaker 5:  like the biggest possible shock to the system.
Speaker 6:  Tumblr's gonna come back. That's, that's my prediction
Speaker 3:  That that might be real. But I've been thinking, I've been thinking a lot
Speaker 3:  about this cuz I think like one of the big questions coming out of this is
Speaker 3:  like, okay, if you wanna leave Twitter, like where do you go? Tell me if
Speaker 3:  there just isn't something else like Twitter. But then I think the question
Speaker 3:  is morphing into something much more interesting, which is like, and this
Speaker 3:  is what's happening to a lot of people with social in general. It's like,
Speaker 3:  is this a thing that I want, Like, like is is, is is
Speaker 3:  the premise of Twitter a good idea? Is a thing
Speaker 3:  that like, I I have not, I've spent a lot of time wondering why Twitter is
Speaker 3:  such a bad platform, but like, is Twitter a bad idea? Is like not a question
Speaker 3:  I think a lot of people have thought about and I think a lot of people are
Speaker 3:  going through this now with like what Facebook has become and what Instagram
Speaker 3:  has become and now what, what Twitter has become is gonna spark that in a
Speaker 3:  lot of people. So I think you're right. And it's like, for me at least, it
Speaker 3:  has become this like weirdly philosophical thing where it's like, I'm not
Speaker 3:  trying to like replace Twitter with Mastodon. I'm like, maybe I should just
Speaker 3:  be done with this thing that I do and consume all day in
Speaker 3:  general. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  I mean, I quit Instagram this year. Like I still have an Instagram account,
Speaker 7:  I just don't open the app anymore. And I've been thinking
Speaker 7:  seriously about like, my relationship with Twitter and much like
Speaker 7:  the people in that Reuters report, unless I'm live tweeting a
Speaker 7:  trial or something, I, I have seriously decreased my Twitter
Speaker 7:  use partially because it's like, I open it up and it's like
Speaker 7:  a lot of bad feelings and people being mean to each other and like, I don't
Speaker 7:  know about you guys, but like, I felt bad enough during the pandemic.
Speaker 7:  Like I didn't, I didn't need the bad feelings app that said, I do
Speaker 7:  think there is a very funny outcome where like some also ran social network,
Speaker 7:  like Tumblr or LinkedIn gets an influx
Speaker 7:  of like weird garbage users who
Speaker 7:  like go full Twitter on the platform. Oh my
Speaker 5:  God, that would be amazing.
Speaker 6:  Tumblr's already seen it. Tumblr's seen like between TikTok and Twitter,
Speaker 6:  Tumblr's has seen like this influx of users and they're young users. That's
Speaker 6:  the thing is like everybody in this room is like, I've grown tired of social
Speaker 6:  media and that's because everybody in this room remembers a time before social
Speaker 6:  media and we have a whole generation of people who don't remember that, who
Speaker 6:  social media is just a part of their lives. They assume that it's,
Speaker 6:  that it's like universal. Everybody has it. And that's the group that I
Speaker 6:  don't necessarily think is going to have these big moments of is social
Speaker 6:  media for me, I think that's just a question that never enters
Speaker 6:  their head. And they are going, if they choose to migrate, they're going
Speaker 6:  to migrate. They're not just gonna like delete the app and
Speaker 6:  touch grass.
Speaker 5:  Well, I mean Tumblr is, there's a PhD thesis
Speaker 5:  why Tumblr persists. Like
Speaker 5:  despite the best efforts of everyone around Tumblr, including
Speaker 6:  The users of Tumblr, right?
Speaker 5:  Like
Speaker 6:  Everyone has tried to destroy,
Speaker 5:  Here are some things that have tried to kill Tumblr. Apple, straight up trying
Speaker 5:  to murder Tumblr, Verizon, the user base
Speaker 5:  of Tumblr.
Speaker 5:  Okay, Yahoo. Yahoo.
Speaker 5:  Like through the years, like a new challenger emerges and Tumblr's like,
Speaker 5:  I stand best stride you. So
Speaker 5:  Steve Tumblr, if you're in the Tumblr meeting this morning
Speaker 5:  where they're like, fucking, it's on, it's on. Sneak
Speaker 5:  that shit to us. We will write about it without even checking the sources
Speaker 5:  out. All
Speaker 7:  12 people that work there, they're like, Oh man, it's our time.
Speaker 5:  Right? That's the best outcome. Tumblr resurgence.
Speaker 3:  Thank
Speaker 5:  You Elon. It's back. We, we, we have carried on for too long about this.
Speaker 5:  We, who knows what happens next. The deal is closed, He's taking it over.
Speaker 5:  We'll see what happens next is like the only logical
Speaker 5:  thing to end on, because honestly, none of us know.
Speaker 5:  There's, there's no prediction here. How many people are gonna quit Twitter
Speaker 5:  today? Right? It's just a, who knows. So yeah,
Speaker 3:  The, the leadership question seems like the most immediate one, right? Like
Speaker 3:  who is going
Speaker 5:  To, He said he's gonna be the ceo that was a report in Bloomberg yesterday.
Speaker 3:  Right? But like forever, like at some point there are going to have to be
Speaker 3:  people who like run this company professionally.
Speaker 7:  So he's previously said he's an interim CEO and he will be bringing somebody
Speaker 7:  in. And if you remember from the text messages, Jason Callons, Jason,
Speaker 7:  the, the VC and entrepreneur has said that Twitter
Speaker 7:  CEO is his dream job. So like maybe we have that to look forward to.
Speaker 5:  Yes, everything is hustling. The
Speaker 3:  Only good outcome is if it's Jack Dorsey. Just that's just, it's
Speaker 3:  just full chaos mode. Bring Jack
Speaker 3:  back. Let's just do this all again.
Speaker 5:  All right, well that's our last prediction, Jack Dorsey. It's,
Speaker 5:  it's, he's not gonna look like he came outta the woods. He's looked like
Speaker 5:  he came outta the woods for like five years
Speaker 7:  Now. Just one more tw in his
Speaker 3:  Beer. I mean, what's F Williams doing now? Bring him back. He's outta medium.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, Bi stone, Just all the founders. Just,
Speaker 3:  Just start Twitter at the beginning again. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Oh man. All right. That's it. That's the verest. We've done enough thanks
Speaker 5:  to Liz for joining us. It's super, it's the west coast. She's on the west
Speaker 5:  coast. It's very early for hers. Thank you so much, Liz. We are gonna have
Speaker 5:  a weekend. Everybody have it. Don't tweet, just have a weekend, take your
Speaker 5:  foot off the gas. It's gonna be great. We'll see you next week.
Speaker 1:  And that's a wrap for Verge Cast this week. Thanks for listening. If you
Speaker 1:  enjoy the show, subscribe in the podcast app of your choice or tell a friend,
Speaker 1:  you can send us feedback at vergecast@theverge.com. This show is
Speaker 1:  produced by me, Liam James, and our senior audio director, Andrew Marino.
Speaker 1:  This episode was edited and mixed by Amanda Rose
Speaker 1:  Smith. Our editorial director is Brooke Mins and our executive producer
Speaker 1:  is Eleanor Donovan. The Vergecast is a production of the Verge and
Speaker 1:  Box Media Podcast network. And that's it. We'll see you next week