# Transcript
ID: b07b7a70-d27d-11ec-80fd-bfe000ee6c8b
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Google CEO Sundar Pichai on Google I/O 2022 📲 Stablecoins struggling to survive the crypto crash, and Apple discontinues the iPod
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/3779259075510587960/2429131316279132428/s93290-None-5928s-1652419687.mp3
Description: Nilay Patel and David Pierce interview Google and Alphabet CEO Sundar Pichai after Google announcing a bunch of products at their I/O conference.
34:25 - Dan Seifert joins the show to discuss the hardware previewed at Google I/O 2022.
55:38 - Liz Lopatto explains "the crypto crash" in this week's Crypto Corner.
1:07:19 - Alex Cranz hops in to run through this week's gadget rumors, reviews, and announcements.
Speaker 1:  This week on the verge cast, Google CEO, Sundar Pichai joins us to take us
Speaker 1:  through Google IO afterwards. We'll talk about all their hardware
Speaker 1:  announcements and the gadget news from this week. That's coming up right
Speaker 1:  after this,
Speaker 6:  Well, welcome to the Vergecast flagship podcast, the tablets that come
Speaker 6:  out a year from now, your friend Nila, we've got a huge share
Speaker 6:  today. Google CEO, Sundar Pichai is on the verge cast today.
Speaker 6:  David and I talked to him about everything announced at Google IO and kind
Speaker 6:  of the future of Google. It's really good conversation. Then Dan Sievert,
Speaker 6:  drones, the show we talk about all the rest of IO and Alex Cranz comes on
Speaker 6:  at the end little gadget lightning round. It's a really fun one. Let's
Speaker 6:  start here's David and I talking to Google and alphabet CEO,
Speaker 6:  Sundar Pichai, Sundar Pichai. You are
Speaker 6:  the CEO of Google. You are the CEO and chairman of alphabet. Welcome to the
Speaker 6:  Vergecast.
Speaker 8:  Hello. It's a pleasure to be here. Good to see any line, David.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it's great to see you again. It's been a while since we've talked also,
Speaker 6:  I appreciate that you're on the verge cast. Real ones are on the verge cast
Speaker 6:  to talk product. That's like that's, this is where it gets serious about
Speaker 6:  products. True that, so it's Google IO. We obviously came off the keynote.
Speaker 6:  The keynote was two hours long, lots of products, lots of really
Speaker 6:  hardcore AI tech Lambda, big language
Speaker 6:  models. Here's my question for you. Just kind of a big picture. And then
Speaker 6:  I want to dive into some of the products themselves. Google does a lot of
Speaker 6:  things. It has a lot of research projects, a lot of far
Speaker 6:  out ideas, a lot of things on the ground like
Speaker 6:  maps and recommendations, and obviously search you run
Speaker 6:  YouTube. Then you've got Android. Like it's a lot of things, kind of the
Speaker 6:  theme of IO this year was you're bringing it all together and it's going
Speaker 6:  to become a very focused set of products and experiences for people, the
Speaker 6:  whole ecosystem. So just from the baseline, how real is that? How much
Speaker 6:  are you actually bringing Google into focus versus you're just
Speaker 6:  lining up the pieces and making sure they make sense together?
Speaker 8:  Well, you know, I do think a few things which
Speaker 8:  have tried to do at the company one is at an underlying more
Speaker 8:  foundational layer that focus on AI. So when you say
Speaker 8:  research, you know, there's a real deep focus on
Speaker 8:  AI in some ways, the big bet is AI is transformational
Speaker 8:  across, you know, all the products and services we do. So for sure,
Speaker 8:  that's been a big focus back and other with a focus on knowledge and
Speaker 8:  computing, right? And both BCS core aspects of our mission.
Speaker 8:  And so to me, you know, it is the same AI, which, which makes
Speaker 8:  that change in search, you know, B because we are able to do
Speaker 8:  things in a more multimodal way and is that same multimodal model, which
Speaker 8:  in YouTube can create auto chapters and so on. So it's an underlying
Speaker 8:  theme. So with which we are doing it across our
Speaker 8:  key products and services, but there is a set of products which our
Speaker 8:  users use multiple times per day. These are big
Speaker 8:  active user bases. And so, you know, there's a lot of focus on beads
Speaker 8:  search or Gmail or maps or YouTube, making sure those
Speaker 8:  products are evolving in a way that makes sense. And so I think both are
Speaker 8:  important.
Speaker 7:  So on the AI front though, there's a piece of that. That's really interesting
Speaker 7:  to me because one of the things I noticed in the keynote was that things
Speaker 7:  like Lambda and translate and Palm kept
Speaker 7:  coming up kind of in different contexts. And I think one of the things that's
Speaker 7:  been tricky for us to figure out is like, when you say we're focused on AI,
Speaker 7:  that can mean lots of things, right? AI is this huge sprawling thing that
Speaker 7:  can mean a lot of things within that space. It feels like maybe Google is
Speaker 7:  picking its spots a little more instead of kind of trying to
Speaker 7:  do lots of things. You have sort of a few big bets, even just within AI.
Speaker 7:  Is that fair?
Speaker 8:  Yeah. I mean, it's, it's a great question. You know, you can think about
Speaker 8:  it this way, right? There's, we're all making progress in
Speaker 8:  state-of-the-art MLN AI, then there's things symptoms of what we are
Speaker 8:  deploying in production, which is the latest version of Peter's speech models,
Speaker 8:  vision models, et cetera, or multimodal models, right. And then there is
Speaker 8:  the future of AI, which, which is not in production yet.
Speaker 8:  And that is large language models. I think we are talking about that
Speaker 8:  and that's where Lambda and Palm and everything comes in and some of that
Speaker 8:  will keep flowing back into cutting-edge production and, you know, and
Speaker 8:  that's what keeps the innovation going. And we are talking about
Speaker 8:  both of them.
Speaker 7:  And I think part of that, it seems like my sense would be then that your
Speaker 7:  job as CEO is in part to sort of make sure all of those things are
Speaker 7:  moving at the correct speed because I just the idea of sort
Speaker 7:  of living deep in the future and two years from now, and also
Speaker 7:  right now is just, it seems impossible. Right?
Speaker 8:  I think something which is probably, you know, there are two sides to the
Speaker 8:  coin, right? So for example, when we build something like Chrome, you know,
Speaker 8:  we unveiled the end to end product one day, the comic book bleak two
Speaker 8:  days ago, but at least, you know, it's a product in which you come out
Speaker 8:  and, you know, unveil it when it comes to things like AI, both a
Speaker 8:  lot of it, we publish research. So, you know, you're not quite can do
Speaker 8:  that. And B because in a technology like that,
Speaker 8:  transparency is important too, I think. And so we are
Speaker 8:  talking about it ahead of time, which is what gives a sense of,
Speaker 8:  well, is this too futuristic? What of this will apply to the products? And
Speaker 8:  I think it's a fair question, but I'm trying to explain why we are doing
Speaker 8:  it the way we are doing it. And so that's what I think makes it a
Speaker 8:  bit different.
Speaker 6:  I think that kind of the classic story of IO has been a
Speaker 6:  demo of a really impressive AI tool. I
Speaker 6:  can't help, but think of the one that took the fence out of the picture in
Speaker 6:  the image editor, and then it turns out like that's actually a really hard
Speaker 6:  problem. It's gonna take a long time to actually ship that to consumers.
Speaker 6:  But at the same time, you're demoing things in actual products
Speaker 6:  like translation that are real for people, or it could be real today. And
Speaker 6:  it's just really hard to calibrate. What are we looking at? That's real right
Speaker 6:  now, or that is a vision of what I could
Speaker 6:  accomplish versus Google is one of the few companies that
Speaker 6:  still demos really impressive software. Every time you have an event,
Speaker 6:  most other companies are like, I don't know we were going to stream some
Speaker 6:  baseball games to you. You know, like there's a really like very hardcore
Speaker 6:  engineering component to what you showed at IO, but it's just hard to know
Speaker 6:  which of it is going to come into focus and turn into a product. And which
Speaker 6:  of it is Google has an intense set of capabilities. And part
Speaker 6:  of Google's culture is chasing them down where wherever they might leave,
Speaker 8:  If you go back, let me give a couple of examples. Like, you know, we showed
Speaker 8:  Google lens many years ago, right? And you know, the promise of what Google
Speaker 8:  lenses, it's a real product, right. Then like, you know, people query it,
Speaker 8:  you can access it. And we are taking as lens matures.
Speaker 8:  We are bringing those capabilities into search. And that's what helps you
Speaker 8:  from a multi-service standpoint, even the fence, you can, you can see magic
Speaker 8:  eraser in pixel. And I would argue, gets at some of
Speaker 8:  that promise in the context of a product. You know, so the goal of everything
Speaker 8:  we are showing is to actually build it into a product. That's how, that's
Speaker 8:  what we are trying to do. So I have no interest in being an R and
Speaker 8:  D lab. You know, we actually genuinely believe in doing cutting
Speaker 8:  edge R and D, right. We are one of the world's largest R and D
Speaker 8:  investors, you know, probably over a hundred million dollars in the past
Speaker 8:  five years. And so we had definitely doing typ of three R and
Speaker 8:  D, but the goal is all with a clear lens of our
Speaker 8:  mission, how we will apply it and working it backwards.
Speaker 8:  And then I think both are true. So, you know, there may be times, you
Speaker 8:  know, there's a probabilistic outcome. And so that there may be one or two
Speaker 8:  elements in it, which we fail. And so that there, there is that
Speaker 8:  risk of talking ahead. And, and I think the failures are
Speaker 8:  also obvious to the external world, but I do think if you have looked at
Speaker 8:  the capabilities we are bringing in pixel, et cetera, that is we are translating
Speaker 8:  it into products and features everything to do with translation though, I
Speaker 8:  would argue we've been steadily making progress, you know, be it
Speaker 8:  monolingual translation or what we showed in the context of
Speaker 8:  translation and transcription in the context of the prototypes AR glass
Speaker 8:  prototypes. Those are real products we are working on. Right?
Speaker 6:  Well, it's the where to skip ad. He brought up the glasses are real. It's
Speaker 6:  a real pair of glasses.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, that'd be the prototypes are real. I mean, they are real use cases
Speaker 8:  and you know, people testing it out are real. Absolutely. We are
Speaker 8:  still obviously working through what the right product in terms of
Speaker 8:  AR is, but they are, we were trying to communicate two things. One is a
Speaker 8:  lot of the innovation for what we are building in AR. We are building it
Speaker 8:  in the context of a smartphone today. And so lands multi-serve scene
Speaker 8:  exploration, live in view and maps. These are all AR
Speaker 8:  experiences if we are doing it in a smartphone today, but the magic is in
Speaker 8:  fully obvious till you can live in that future. And so we are
Speaker 8:  exploring that future also in terms of hardware form factors, but that's
Speaker 8:  going to take time to do, and we, we have a few more decisions ahead of us
Speaker 8:  there.
Speaker 6:  So I looked at the glasses. So if people haven't seen the video, she wash
Speaker 6:  it. It's cool. It's a pair of glasses that listens, and it shows you real-time
Speaker 6:  translations someone speaking in different language. You get real-time translation
Speaker 6:  on the screen of the glasses. I look at that and I say, oh, that's really
Speaker 6:  smart right now, all the AR experiences you're describing, they happen on
Speaker 6:  a phone because a phone has a fancy camera built into it. It
Speaker 6:  has a 5g network connection for whatever that's worth. It has a fast
Speaker 6:  processor. It has a big battery putting that stuff in glasses is very
Speaker 6:  difficult. And I look at the translation glasses, you demo it. And I say,
Speaker 6:  oh, this is actually, you're cutting the problem way down. Now, all
Speaker 6:  we're doing is listening to someone, translating it and then showing some
Speaker 6:  text on a screen, which in the grand scheme of computer problems is still
Speaker 6:  hard. But in the scheme of AR is like a very narrow
Speaker 6:  solution. Is that how you're thinking about it? That you're going to cut
Speaker 6:  it all the way down to that, and you're not going to do real-time graphic
Speaker 6:  overlays and stuff that seems really far out right now.
Speaker 8:  I think it's part of how we are thinking about it because, you know, I, I
Speaker 8:  don't think we want to overshoot it. The more you overshoot, the longer it
Speaker 8:  is away. Right? And so we are trying to find that sweet spot of Lord is
Speaker 8:  it that you can do something which people can wear, maybe doesn't
Speaker 8:  have, you know, it's comfortable, you can wear. And also doesn't
Speaker 8:  have the other broader issues around, well, if you have a camera, you have
Speaker 8:  to solve a set of different issues. It's a harder system integration
Speaker 8:  problem as you're pointing out and so on. So we're thinking through, I
Speaker 8:  think anytime in a constraint I've always felt constraints help, right. You
Speaker 8:  know, having constraints helps you actually deliver a product. And so
Speaker 8:  I'm a fan of that. And so I think that's part of, what's informing our thinking
Speaker 8:  that
Speaker 6:  One of the other challenges they are, and you're kind of hinting at it. Yep.
Speaker 6:  There's the big you have to develop the hardware. That seems very
Speaker 6:  challenging. There's also the idea that you're going to augment reality,
Speaker 6:  which just on its face seems like the world's biggest content moderation
Speaker 6:  challenge. You run YouTube. YouTube is a content moderation
Speaker 6:  challenge. Have you put time into thinking about, okay, we're into an
Speaker 6:  AR future. Someone's looking at the Capitol building, Google's going
Speaker 6:  to put some information over the Capitol building to say what happened
Speaker 6:  there. And people are going to be upset regardless of what we put on that
Speaker 6:  screen. Have you gotten all the way that down that road in your thinking
Speaker 6:  yet? Or are you still focused on, we have to make a computer you put on your
Speaker 6:  face?
Speaker 8:  No, I think, look, I think we are in earliest stages, you know, you can
Speaker 8:  imagine use cases where there are products like maps
Speaker 8:  or, you know, you want to listen to music when you run or, you know, the
Speaker 8:  translation use cases. I think any time you show information
Speaker 8:  with that, you have to think through all that. And I agree with you, but
Speaker 8:  I don't think we are quite there yet. If I were to be Frank thinking, thinking
Speaker 8:  all that through
Speaker 6:  Just on a timeline, do you think this is a five-year problem? Is it a
Speaker 6:  25 year problem? Is it 18 months?
Speaker 8:  Well, we have that problem today, right? I think, I think information is
Speaker 8:  working at scale on the internet and, you know, I think we've already
Speaker 8:  crossed the inflection points. So I would argue, you know, solving
Speaker 8:  content moderation, you know, it's a hard enough problem
Speaker 8:  today. And if I think to the future, I don't know, maybe, maybe areas where
Speaker 8:  I worry about more are, you know, synthetic content and how
Speaker 8:  do we deal with that? And, you know, so maybe 80 is like, that would just
Speaker 8:  not Nestle AR as a dimension, but I think there are other
Speaker 8:  dimensions, you know, which, which, which I think are probably thinking about
Speaker 8:  a bit more
Speaker 7:  Fair enough. And I think this comes back to the, kind of, how you think about
Speaker 7:  the company as a whole question too, because I think we've seen a few companies
Speaker 7:  most aggressively, I think Metta make a lot of noise
Speaker 7:  about AR being like a bet, the company thing, right? That, that this thing
Speaker 7:  that is coming next is going to require everything that we have. And we have
Speaker 7:  to put everything we have behind it, and it's gonna require changing how
Speaker 7:  we work. My sense is you're not shifting Google quite that
Speaker 7:  aggressively, but
Speaker 6:  Sooner as like the real world is pretty good. Yeah. Which is about a part
Speaker 6:  of a shot is I've ever heard you take
Speaker 7:  That is true.
Speaker 8:  Look, I mean, I mean, we are definitely focused
Speaker 8:  more and more on the AR side in the context of the
Speaker 8:  real world is important. It's not a, it's how we see
Speaker 8:  it. And we were building it. I think, look, we are as has an
Speaker 8:  important use case too, and there'll be mixed reality, but those things all
Speaker 8:  have different timelines and access and so on.
Speaker 7:  Well, I, I was curious as you think about, and I mean it with AR cause eventually
Speaker 7:  if they are, is going to be as big as a lot of people think it is, it's going
Speaker 7:  to require basically every team at Google to build new things
Speaker 7:  for it. Where are you in sort of how you're thinking about how much energy
Speaker 7:  you want to put within the company onto that kind of stuff.
Speaker 8:  I mean, we worked through, remember, you know, Google was came from the
Speaker 8:  desktop era, right. And you know, we are doing the shift to
Speaker 8:  mobile. AI is a big shift. We are driving. And so to
Speaker 8:  me, I think it cuts across. And so we think about it. So I don't view it
Speaker 8:  as bedding. The company, meat is a natural evolution of the
Speaker 8:  company. And I think if you're thinking deeply and billing for the future,
Speaker 8:  it is a big part of getting it. Right. So for me, it's important. Search
Speaker 8:  works in AR context, you know, and maps is thinking it
Speaker 8:  true and YouTube is thinking it through right then. And
Speaker 8:  Google photos is thinking it through. And so I think if we get it right that
Speaker 8:  way, you know, you're, you're, you're bringing the company along through
Speaker 8:  these big transitions. And so maybe, you know, maybe it's a, it's a, but
Speaker 8:  how we think about it,
Speaker 6:  All right. Let's come back out of the clouds from it. That's a, I mean, it's
Speaker 6:  interesting. I think the glasses are fascinating in the sense that
Speaker 6:  by reducing the problem you're trying to solve, you
Speaker 6:  actually can make a more useful product. That's supposed to try to boil the
Speaker 6:  ocean there, but they're still pretty far out. You've got another problem
Speaker 6:  right in front of you, which is trying to sell pixel phones and create a
Speaker 6:  pixel ecosystem. Even at that, for a while, we saw a pixel seven
Speaker 6:  pixel six, eight pixel buds pro you
Speaker 6:  hinted at a tablet. There's a lot of energy in that
Speaker 6:  space. And one of the things that Rick told
Speaker 6:  David on another piece of the broadcast is that the Android team
Speaker 6:  and the pixel team are much closer together. Now they're operating in
Speaker 6:  harmony. Historically that arrangement has made your
Speaker 6:  OEMs very mad, but I believe at one point Google was forced to sell Motorola
Speaker 6:  because things were too close, but now you're doing it again. Tell me about
Speaker 6:  that is that pixel is Samsung and Lenovo and whoever else don't see
Speaker 6:  pixel as a threat, so you can bring them close together. Is it you're going
Speaker 6:  to spin some innovations from pixel out, into Android, proper.
Speaker 6:  How are you thinking about managing that dynamic?
Speaker 8:  Let me step out and firsthand and struggle to focus there, you know, to me,
Speaker 8:  no different or the past five years, if you taken an idea like YouTube
Speaker 8:  or, you know, we've put a lot of focus into it. Cloud is the same thing,
Speaker 8:  both as big areas and as important businesses to be built to
Speaker 8:  me, hardware and computing is equally important. I do
Speaker 8:  think the ecosystem, all of us see value in, you know,
Speaker 8:  working together to make sure we make progress particularly beyond
Speaker 8:  folks. Right? So where all this has been a great example. I think we have
Speaker 8:  done both, you know, because when you're, when you're, when you're building
Speaker 8:  these new categories, it's hardware and software it's app developers,
Speaker 8:  you all understand as well. So there is value in what we did with
Speaker 8:  Samsung on where ours aligning and as
Speaker 8:  developers, the fact that pixel watch is coming and they're all
Speaker 8:  assessed a lot more traction of that matters for those developers address
Speaker 8:  that too. So a rising tide lifts, all boats, kind of a
Speaker 8:  scenario. I think I, I think is genuinely what plays out.
Speaker 8:  So, you know, we will work super hard with Samsung on foldables and
Speaker 8:  phones and, you know, and also I think there's some added
Speaker 8:  value in our approach in the sense that sometimes we have a strong
Speaker 8:  view on what to do on top of Android, right? Our OEMs may have a different
Speaker 8:  viewpoint. They, one of the benefits of Android is it allows both viewpoints
Speaker 8:  to be expressed and we can do it in the context of pixel and the ecosystem
Speaker 8:  BC and Samsung can, you know, have a vision on top
Speaker 8:  of galaxy. And they're, they're a hardware ecosystem too. So I think there's
Speaker 8:  some value in that too. So, you know, I don't see
Speaker 8:  necessarily this being that complicated. I think the
Speaker 8:  industry has evolved to this level. You can, you can look at
Speaker 8:  somebody like Microsoft, it's surface and windows, and you
Speaker 8:  can ask the, you know, the same question, but I think, you know,
Speaker 8:  I, I think it's natural. We work with Samsung, by the way, you
Speaker 8:  know, our pixel division is a major customer of
Speaker 8:  Samson's competence. So we don't sit down and ask, Hey, Samsung
Speaker 8:  is supplying its own phones and us. And like, how do you do this?
Speaker 8:  And the industry has worked that way for awhile. So I, I, you know,
Speaker 8:  I, I see it as a natural evolution
Speaker 7:  On the ecosystem side of things. What changed your thinking about that? I
Speaker 7:  think one of the things that Neil and I both noticed from IO is it was, there
Speaker 7:  was a lot of kind of resurrecting of old products and old ideas. Like
Speaker 7:  tablets was a thing that it doesn't seem like Google has cared about in a
Speaker 7:  while and same with watches. And while it is back after not being back.
Speaker 7:  And it's definitely the, the ecosystem thinking seems
Speaker 7:  to have gotten much bigger. What sort of sparked that internally?
Speaker 8:  I think there are two aspects to it. One is what you said, you know, the
Speaker 8:  ecosystem is important and, you know, thinking it through and, you
Speaker 8:  know, an Android is open source, which means there are many different OEMs
Speaker 8:  making things. So the Android team is thinking hard about, better together
Speaker 8:  and how do these things work together better? And the additional categories
Speaker 8:  becoming more important. That's, that's one part of it. The second
Speaker 8:  part of it is why not sooner as you know, hardware is such an economies of
Speaker 8:  scale listens, right? There's so many things to do to get it right. You know,
Speaker 8:  we have been building the capabilities, right? So for example, we
Speaker 8:  knew tensor has been five years in the making, right? The years you're
Speaker 8:  seeing it now, but we knew we needed that to work
Speaker 8:  well, to be able to do a tablet so that it shares the same Silicon
Speaker 8:  platform with phones. And so you had to
Speaker 8:  crawl, walk and start to run on phone for, you can actually
Speaker 8:  do do the other things. So there's a difference between intellectually understanding
Speaker 8:  it a few years earlier, whereas this, the actual practical ability to
Speaker 8:  get scale and to be able to do it all in the additional
Speaker 8:  things. And so I think, I think that's the practical side of it,
Speaker 6:  But let me ask you about phones in particular, and then maybe extended the
Speaker 6:  tablets you made the comparison to Microsoft. Microsoft had surface
Speaker 6:  because the windows ecosystem was not producing thousand
Speaker 6:  dollar laptops. Panos has been on the show. He said that to us very directly,
Speaker 6:  very loudly. And so they were like, we need to, we need to reinvigorate this
Speaker 6:  segment of the market. We need to compete with apple because apple is winning
Speaker 6:  at the segment of the market in phones right now. Right. If pixel is a
Speaker 6:  huge success, you're not necessarily getting apple switchers,
Speaker 6:  right. You're getting Samsung switchers, or you're just moving people around
Speaker 6:  the Android ecosystem. If you watch a tablet, I don't know if you're thinking
Speaker 6:  you're going to get iPad switchers. You might just get like chroma Les
Speaker 6:  switchers or other Android tablets switchers. Like how do
Speaker 6:  you think about managing that competition? And then I guess the real question
Speaker 6:  is how do you think about opening the gate to get people to
Speaker 6:  switch from the apple products where however many conversations I want to
Speaker 6:  have about lock-in and I promise you, we will soon ask what RCS, but they
Speaker 6:  seem to be pretty happy over there and not enticed to switch to your
Speaker 6:  platforms.
Speaker 8:  I definitely think us doing tablets and us
Speaker 8:  working better with Samsung tablets, we'll end up in
Speaker 8:  together. Each of us, both individually, better off and overall, you know,
Speaker 8:  Android as an ecosystem will do better than tablets. That's how the map works
Speaker 8:  out. At least empirically for awhile on the phone
Speaker 8:  side too. You know, I do think on a high end, you know, we need to be
Speaker 8:  competetive similarly, you know, you're talking about switching, but we could
Speaker 8:  also lose users from the Android ecosystem because we don't have a
Speaker 8:  good tablet offering as well when you've made this point before on, on
Speaker 8:  Vergecast. But you know, about nexus seven and the impact it
Speaker 8:  had, we are doing it because we think we will give a
Speaker 8:  clear view on how you can do these things and how they
Speaker 8:  can work together. And, and I think it will impact the whole ecosystem to
Speaker 8:  do better. So I see all of that playing out. I see it's so
Speaker 8:  far from being a zero sum game. And to my earlier point, we ended up being
Speaker 8:  a very successful other cell competent to us. We buy displays, we
Speaker 8:  buy memory buys. I mean, it's Excel. I think it's a bit more complex
Speaker 8:  than that. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  All right. So now I definitely have to ask the RCS question, shout out to
Speaker 6:  our friend Dieter, Bohn and ruthlessly took from us sinner, but
Speaker 6:  right. The, the noise that Google has started to make about RCS has
Speaker 6:  gotten louder over the past five years. I w I would just say it started
Speaker 6:  with here's the new standard. We hope the carriers adopted we're running
Speaker 6:  our own RCS servers to two days ago,
Speaker 6:  onstage everyone should adopt RCS pointed, look in the
Speaker 6:  direction of Cupertino, right? Like you're starting to advocate now for it
Speaker 6:  as a company, very loudly, there are good reasons for it. There's security,
Speaker 6:  there's encryption, there's all that stuff. There's also just
Speaker 6:  inter-operability and ease of switching in the sense that IMS had just
Speaker 6:  pure lock-in for apple. How are you bouncing all of that stuff? Is it
Speaker 6:  you're more focused on this is the next generation of standards and we gotta
Speaker 6:  get there, or is there an element of competitiveness to it?
Speaker 8:  Well, first of all, a few things, you know, I mean, for, for all the ,
Speaker 8:  you've had alarm focus on our messaging efforts. And I would
Speaker 8:  say RC is a tribute to, I still
Speaker 8:  recall being in mobile world Congress. Maybe now I may get the
Speaker 8:  timing wrong six to seven years ago, and seeing the
Speaker 8:  moment where the carrier severely looked at us and said, we
Speaker 8:  need you to do this. And historically it had been difficult. The
Speaker 8:  carriers viewed as we don't want anyone else to come into messaging. And
Speaker 8:  so there was a big shift. And so I actually view it as a great
Speaker 8:  example of against extraordinary odds
Speaker 8:  being so focused on an area or six to seven years
Speaker 8:  and being where we are there. I think at least on the Android ecosystem
Speaker 8:  side, RCS is on a clear path to
Speaker 8:  both being a standard supporting end to end encryption and so on.
Speaker 8:  So, you know, super excited about the progress there. I think, look,
Speaker 8:  interoperability is great here. You know, we all take it for
Speaker 8:  granted in areas like email today. You know, I, it would be
Speaker 8:  great for it to work. I think we couldn't even make the case till we
Speaker 8:  had a viable alternative. So we've crossed that pot. And
Speaker 8:  so, you know, I think idealized teams being
Speaker 8:  excited and making calls and stuff, but to me, what's in our control
Speaker 8:  is to build a compelling standard and all the time make the
Speaker 8:  compelling case. It's the benefit of everyone involved, including iOS
Speaker 8:  users to have that end, to end encryption
Speaker 8:  working and have that interoperability. And the rest
Speaker 8:  is, you know, I would say the for hands. And as he said, you know, time will
Speaker 8:  tell, but, you know, I'm at least glad we reached the stage where we
Speaker 8:  are and, and making progress and taking data.
Speaker 8:  That's of all, you guys focus a lot on products, which is great.
Speaker 8:  And I think unique, but the more you focus on product, you almost like
Speaker 8:  product manager type of people at Google is always hiring product managers.
Speaker 8:  So, sorry, I think it comes.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. You need someone who thinks about the people. I
Speaker 6:  guess that's like another, I think just big thing question, and I want to,
Speaker 6:  I want to ask about a more distributed future, but just on a big
Speaker 6:  perspective right now, when you think about the big companies, they
Speaker 6:  have signature products, Google has a lot of signature
Speaker 6:  products, as you're thinking about the future of the company and how all
Speaker 6:  those products might work together and how you might layer that the technologies
Speaker 6:  underneath them together. Are you thinking about changing how Google operates
Speaker 6:  or how it's organized? Like historically Google has just been a,
Speaker 6:  has been doing a lot of things all at once. I think messaging is actually
Speaker 6:  the ultimate example of this, where lots of teams at Google have built
Speaker 6:  messaging products, but the strategy for messaging has only
Speaker 6:  recently begun to perhaps coalesce. Are you thinking about that more
Speaker 6:  broadly across the company?
Speaker 8:  Yes. I mean, you know, things such as really, you know, one of
Speaker 8:  the things which they coming see, you was one. I wanted the
Speaker 8:  company to go back and think a lot about its core mission,
Speaker 8:  because I felt that it was important to ground ground ourselves there
Speaker 8:  and really focused on knowledge and core
Speaker 8:  of knowledge for us is on search and YouTube. It's our core consumer
Speaker 8:  services and then computing, right? It's it's
Speaker 8:  Android. And as part of that, there was a big bet on hardware too. And then
Speaker 8:  making sure we are a world-class enterprise platform as
Speaker 8:  well with cloud and workspace. So we have done a lot of work to
Speaker 8:  focus the company along those dimensions, right. And so, you know, you
Speaker 8:  see those are our five big product areas, how we have structured and how
Speaker 8:  we run them. And with a common view of all the cross
Speaker 8:  cutting R and D and technology, particularly AI, which,
Speaker 8:  which really, you know, drives innovation forward there. So that's
Speaker 8:  definitely, you know, that's the big picture, how, how I think about it and,
Speaker 8:  you know, we'll continue to be very focused and that's why I gave the
Speaker 8:  examples. And I think it takes a lot in tech. You know, tech is very
Speaker 8:  competitive. He looked at something like tick-tock emerge, you know, things
Speaker 8:  happen in a very fast cycles. And so
Speaker 8:  to stay on top of, on any significant tech product, you know, needs a
Speaker 8:  lot of focus and continued innovation. And so I've always viewed as a
Speaker 8:  company. We need to be very, very focused on it. And
Speaker 8:  definitely we have brought focus some of us, or looks
Speaker 8:  outside as well. You're focused on these products and you're improving
Speaker 8:  them. Yes. I mean, because these are in a billion
Speaker 8:  user products, doing important things. And I think people
Speaker 8:  rely on them. And to me, there's nothing more important than
Speaker 8:  making it better constantly and continually evolving
Speaker 8:  it as a web service. Sometimes it's hard because, you know, if you're doing
Speaker 8:  hardware or something, you get these once in a year moments to go talk about
Speaker 8:  it. Something like search where you're shipping stuff every two weeks and
Speaker 8:  you're continuously releasing them. You know, it is even more important,
Speaker 8:  I think, to be very focused on making sure you're actually moving the
Speaker 8:  needle. So I think it's definitely a big part of what I think about
Speaker 6:  One of the things that I've been thinking about a lot lately is the blockchain
Speaker 6:  decentralized computing. I talked to blockchain companies and
Speaker 6:  CEOs, and whenever they're like web to the examples they give
Speaker 6:  me are always Google. It's always Google search. It's always G it's
Speaker 6:  always YouTube, right? These are the web platforms that the blockchain companies
Speaker 6:  are going to disrupt. Are you making big bets? I mean, you and I
Speaker 6:  were talking right now in the middle of like a literal cryptocurrency crash.
Speaker 6:  So I'm assuming you're not making huge bets today, but are you
Speaker 6:  thinking about that next future for Google
Speaker 8:  They'll come in? I too was a big part of why I joined
Speaker 8:  Google and, you know, seeing the transition from
Speaker 8:  the web, moving from content to apps and the excitement around
Speaker 8:  XML has shapey and Ajax and
Speaker 8:  realizing that, you know, maps and Gmail all represent a
Speaker 8:  fundamental shift in how the web works. So I think it's exciting to
Speaker 8:  be anytime the web evolves, but of ever is a big
Speaker 8:  thing. And like, there are no one person can evolve it, like it it's like
Speaker 8:  that's, that's the beauty of the Bab. And so, so I always
Speaker 8:  look at any innovation in a excited try to understand what are the good
Speaker 8:  things coming out of it. And, and so it is still early days though.
Speaker 8:  So that's how I would probably be, probably say, but, you know, I'm
Speaker 8:  always trying to think ahead about what are the key trends bead on
Speaker 8:  computing, bead on how the web servers evolving and trying to
Speaker 8:  see, you know, where Google can contribute, where Google
Speaker 8:  can also lead. And it's, it's a big part of how we should think
Speaker 8:  about not to mention AI being the most important of it
Speaker 8:  all.
Speaker 6:  Do you think of let's call it web three, the blockchain web three
Speaker 6:  stuff, right? The innovation, there is not, there's a lot of cryptographic
Speaker 6:  innovation shore, but the innovation there is not
Speaker 6:  necessarily technological capability. It's I don't
Speaker 6:  have to trust your database. Google is effectively like the world's
Speaker 6:  most powerful database company. There's a very important database at the
Speaker 6:  heart of Google that you can query and get results from. Do you ever think,
Speaker 6:  oh, this will displace the search index or this will displace the YouTube
Speaker 6:  database
Speaker 8:  Look a decent release model. I mean, don't forget dating Skype or at some
Speaker 8:  point on a B2B based smart. I think distributed
Speaker 8:  databases are a hard, interesting computer science challenge too.
Speaker 8:  So I think we get equally excited about that and, you know, and so
Speaker 8:  on. I think it's important to think through user problems, what you're
Speaker 8:  trying to solve and the underlying technology. And so
Speaker 8:  all of that is important, you know, into an asshole
Speaker 8:  he's been anything. It was, you know, the big part I, to make sure you're
Speaker 8:  leading in all these services, will you get disrupted yet
Speaker 8:  by definition, if you're not trying hard enough? Yes. The answer is
Speaker 8:  absolutely 100% yet. I'm like, let me show
Speaker 8:  up to work on Mondays. And yes, I worry about all of this all the
Speaker 8:  time and you know, so maybe I leave it at that.
Speaker 7:  So my, my last question is, tell me what your killer app is for
Speaker 7:  smartwatches. We spend a lot of time debating what smart watches are for,
Speaker 7:  and having now spent a lot of time building one. I'm curious, kind of what
Speaker 7:  you see as like the sort of reason for smart watches at the moment for
Speaker 7:  Google.
Speaker 8:  I'd probably leave it with, I want to make sure the team has something to
Speaker 8:  say in September when they pick some watches.
Speaker 8:  And I think they've pieced it enough
Speaker 8:  that look, I'm excited because I think for
Speaker 8:  me, it's the thing I'm excited about is it's an end to hen
Speaker 8:  hardware portfolio and you will see a lot of the pixel brand
Speaker 8:  identity. And, you know, if you're a big silver user, a lot of
Speaker 8:  the design language and, and some of the customizable, how
Speaker 8:  easy it is to change bands and the expressiveness is, is
Speaker 8:  great in terms of killer apps, love community, look at something like
Speaker 8:  GPS being on phones and, and what happens later,
Speaker 8:  or the fact that XML history be created the whole set of apps. As I talked
Speaker 8:  about earlier, I'm always humbled by when you
Speaker 8:  create underlined capabilities, the creativity of developers outside,
Speaker 8:  you know, it's not the Google they'll have the killer app. You know, I think
Speaker 8:  down the line, someone will do something really cool with it, but I would
Speaker 8:  argue one of the exciting aspects of the big silver watches, of course, Fitbit
Speaker 8:  coming on it, right. You know, Fitbit coming as a service on it is a
Speaker 8:  killer app. We are putting on that watch. And you know, so that is
Speaker 8:  something I'm super excited by.
Speaker 6:  Well, Sundar, thank you so much for coming out of your chest. It's been us
Speaker 6:  always great to talk to you, and I always appreciate that you want to come
Speaker 6:  on the hardcore nerd show. So that's very good. It's good to talk to you
Speaker 8:  Greatly enjoyed it. And thanks for all the focus on, I appreciate it.
Speaker 6:  All right. We got to take a break. We'll be right back with Dan Siefert to
Speaker 6:  wrap up the rest of Google
Speaker 6:  IO.
Speaker 6:  We're back. Dan Seaford. Welcome. Hello. So obviously David and I just talked
Speaker 6:  to Sundar. He's great. By the way, I keep saying this, it takes, it takes
Speaker 6:  real guts for a product CEO to come on. The verge chest Dakota is like, you
Speaker 6:  know, that's where you do your thankful and say on the verge faster, like
Speaker 6:  let's skip down to brass
Speaker 7:  Tacks.
Speaker 6:  So that was great. We had big picture conversation, but there's some stuff
Speaker 6:  at IO that we should talk about with Dan actual
Speaker 6:  products. What's Dan, you have some real feelings about this tablet.
Speaker 7:  I was going to say, we got to start with the tablet,
Speaker 6:  This tablet. I don't know why they announced it.
Speaker 10:  I haven't been able to figure out why they announced it. So
Speaker 6:  They pre-announced the tablet that's coming out in 2023. What we know about
Speaker 6:  it is that it will have a tensor chip. And that's what we know about
Speaker 6:  it.
Speaker 10:  Well, we know it will have a bigger screen than
Speaker 10:  a phone. It will
Speaker 10:  be rectangular. It apparently has big white bezels.
Speaker 6:  Yep. They announced Basil's that camera's on the middle of the screen landscape.
Speaker 6:  They did that, right. That's a big improvement over your iPads
Speaker 10:  Credit where credit's due.
Speaker 6:  The back looks like plastic. There's a camera on the back as well. It does.
Speaker 6:  They showed us some, they did show us some Android tablet, software stuff,
Speaker 10:  And it yet, and it runs injured,
Speaker 6:  But they showed us, you know, here's some apps running by side. I will say,
Speaker 6:  if you just go watch the event again, watch the tablet,
Speaker 6:  UI presentation, just like rewatch it closely.
Speaker 6:  And it is almost as though they're inventing computers.
Speaker 7:  Oh yeah. The, the number of things that they have not even
Speaker 7:  heard of before that, it's like, what if you had an app and then you went
Speaker 7:  to another app, but at the same,
Speaker 6:  At one point they're like, I love using two apps at once. And it's like,
Speaker 6:  yeah, it's pretty good. It's a
Speaker 6:  great actually I've been doing for years, welcome to the party, which is
Speaker 6:  funny. Cause you can already do that on many Android tablets.
Speaker 10:  Yeah. An Android phone. So you can just split screen them very easily.
Speaker 6:  Okay. So then we've been sarcastic, like what do you think they're trying
Speaker 6:  to do with this tablet?
Speaker 10:  It's really hard to say, you know, David talked to Rick Costello. I had
Speaker 10:  a chance to talk to Rick Costello briefly. And every time he mentioned
Speaker 10:  this tablet, he positioned it as a quote,
Speaker 10:  perfect companion to the pixel phone. He called it the pixel tablet onstage.
Speaker 10:  He said, it's a premium, large screen device. They are like filling this
Speaker 10:  gap in their lineup so that they have a full ecosystem ranging all the way
Speaker 10:  from the watch. That will, I'm sure we'll talk about through the phones
Speaker 10:  to tablets, out to laptops with Chromebooks, they've got like the full
Speaker 10:  of the device portfolio in this thing by the time this thing launches. And
Speaker 10:  so like that all makes sense. Like they could just say, we're going to launch
Speaker 10:  a tablet next year and like tell that same story. But for some reason
Speaker 10:  they decided we're going to also show this hyperreal of
Speaker 10:  this tablet, which looks like it was designed in 2014
Speaker 10:  and is like the combination of 2014
Speaker 10:  era Samsung tablet and like an Amazon fire
Speaker 10:  HD. Like if you just mash those together, that's what you got the concept
Speaker 10:  of this tablet. And it's really weird to like use that
Speaker 10:  kind of product, look to build hype for product. That's not coming
Speaker 10:  for seven months a year, whatever, not this calendar year. So
Speaker 10:  like, I really don't understand this announcement at all.
Speaker 7:  I think there's sort of two separate things there, right? There's like if
Speaker 7:  the tablet had been beautiful and cool and exciting and even just like what
Speaker 7:  it was, but with no bezels, that would have been something. And at least
Speaker 7:  I think strategically, Strategically, it makes sense.
Speaker 7:  Right? Cause like the thing Google desperately needs is for people to build
Speaker 7:  tablet apps. Cause the reason Android tablets suck is because Android tablet,
Speaker 7:  apps
Speaker 6:  Suck. No, I disagree really? Oh, I have a, I
Speaker 6:  have a much Wilder conspiracy theory about this whole thing.
Speaker 7:  Okay. Let's do it.
Speaker 6:  They're doing this. This is all just a front run. Cause they said
Speaker 6:  this thing, which makes no sense. They're like there's so much developer
Speaker 6:  interest in Android tablets.
Speaker 7:  Oh yeah. I don't believe that for a second.
Speaker 6:  Say they said this on stage and that's when I started doing my
Speaker 6:  own research, developing
Speaker 6:  this
Speaker 6:  conspiracy.
Speaker 11:  So sorry.
Speaker 6:  No. Okay. The future, the only way they're going to get people to switch
Speaker 6:  off the iPhone is that they beat apple, the foldables and they
Speaker 6:  create the moment, the hardware form factor, a moment
Speaker 6:  that rules. Right. So, yep. You've got your galaxy folds and
Speaker 6:  whatnot, but like those are still early. You gotta make
Speaker 6:  the mainstream folding phone. And if you unfold
Speaker 6:  the phone and then it's a garbage tablet, you're
Speaker 6:  you're hooped. So the developer interest is not in tablet apps.
Speaker 6:  It's not in this thing. It's in what can I do in the
Speaker 6:  phone unfolds? And so they're building a
Speaker 6:  tablet ecosystem because they know that their, their
Speaker 6:  big upcoming shot to recapture market share from apple is beating
Speaker 6:  apple the folder.
Speaker 7:  So, okay. I hate to burst your bubble on this. That's not a conspiracy theory.
Speaker 7:  That's just true. Like Google, Google told me this and cause we
Speaker 7:  were talking about it. I'm like, you look at the multitasking and it's, and
Speaker 7:  it's like, that's a, that's a foldable phone. And so it's like, if you
Speaker 7:  just take the tablet with the two apps and folded in half, like, oh my God,
Speaker 7:  what does that? And that is like Google considers, foldable phones and
Speaker 7:  tablets to be functionally identical software
Speaker 7:  systems and whether or not that turns out to be a good idea, I think really
Speaker 7:  remains to be seen because I'm not sure that what works well on one
Speaker 7:  unfolded screen is the same as two folding screens, but we will see. But
Speaker 7:  I think you're absolutely right that like the bigger possible wind here
Speaker 7:  for Google solving larger screen Android is on foldable phones than it is
Speaker 7:  on tablets. And I think like this idea that Google has suddenly discovered
Speaker 7:  the iPad is popular, I think is like kind of bonkers.
Speaker 7:  And
Speaker 6:  Yeah, so I got a little bit of a head fake.
Speaker 10:  Why not tease a pixel foldable, which has been like rumored
Speaker 10:  forever. And like, this is not this, the products that they showed off is
Speaker 10:  not coming out till next year. It's got a while to go because they
Speaker 6:  Got to sell the pixel seven.
Speaker 10:  I mean, this is the company that is like, we're launching a phone in two
Speaker 10:  months, but also we're launching a phone in October. Like,
Speaker 10:  I mean, this is the company that has no concerns about
Speaker 10:  cannibalizing hardware
Speaker 6:  Because they don't sell any funds. They're like, they were like the pixel
Speaker 6:  six sold as much as the pixel four and then pixel five combined, which
Speaker 6:  is one of the harshest cellphones that you can
Speaker 6:  issue. Right. But it's also still not a lot. So then you can announce a
Speaker 6:  pixel seven or a pixel six, eight. You're not like I'm worried about tanking.
Speaker 6:  Why successful pixel six line, if you announce a pixel seven and then announce
Speaker 6:  a pixel foldable like going to, even now, you have
Speaker 6:  no hope of selling as many pixels sevens as pixels four or five and six
Speaker 6:  is combined. It's never going to happen for
Speaker 10:  You.
Speaker 6:  Maybe you got to slow roll it in this way. I think the
Speaker 6:  pixel tablet, whatever this thing is, is all just a gigantic
Speaker 6:  head fake to get people to think that they care about tablets.
Speaker 10:  There's another theory going around because there's been this rumor product
Speaker 10:  for a while. Now that I
Speaker 7:  Was going to ask you about this, this is
Speaker 10:  That Google is working on this like nest hub device that has a
Speaker 10:  detachable screen and becomes a tablet. And the theory going around is what
Speaker 10:  the tablet that they showed during the event is the tablet that connects
Speaker 10:  to the nest hub and becomes a smart display when
Speaker 10:  it's at home. And there's some like some
Speaker 10:  credibility to that in that the tablet looks like the front of a NetSuite
Speaker 10:  hub. Like if I look at my nest hub max over here, yeah.
Speaker 10:  That's exactly what the tablet looks like, that they showed off. So like
Speaker 10:  sure. Lots of design similarities there. The hesitation I have with that
Speaker 10:  theory is that pixel teams and nest teams are like wholly separate and they
Speaker 10:  have separate branding everything. And they did not call this a nest device.
Speaker 10:  They call it a pixel tablet. And then of course they also didn't show any
Speaker 10:  of that, like functionality or tease any kinds of that, where it would
Speaker 10:  dock into a, a smart display screen or whatever. So I mean far, be
Speaker 10:  it from Google to do something like that. Like, like they are the, like
Speaker 10:  they've done much weirder things and they could possibly turn that into
Speaker 10:  a smart home device or whatever. And, and then it becomes, it's like, well,
Speaker 10:  it's primary purpose is a smart display, but then you can use it as a tablet
Speaker 10:  when you want sometimes, which is like, again, a weird way to frame
Speaker 10:  something as the perfect companion to your pixel phone.
Speaker 6:  Awesome. Lenovo built this front of like six times in a row. Amazon bought
Speaker 6:  the product just like this, right? Like, yeah. It's not a category
Speaker 6:  one, whatever. We'll see, we've got until 20, 23 to argue about
Speaker 6:  these vessels.
Speaker 10:  I don't know why they're white. Like the whole problem was they made them
Speaker 10:  white. Like it's like, you can have big vessels. Okay. There's a place for
Speaker 10:  bezels. You got to put your thumbs, you're holding the tablet or whatever.
Speaker 10:  You can make that argument. Don't make them white. Like it's a, it's a
Speaker 10:  like content consumption device.
Speaker 6:  We'll see. But that's what, that's my conspiracy theory, which David tells
Speaker 6:  me is true.
Speaker 7:  Oh, I, I definitely think you're right. What if, what if it's a smart display
Speaker 7:  that you take off and then when you leave to go outside, you fold it closed.
Speaker 7:  What if it's, what if it's a foldable and we didn't even know there's your
Speaker 7:  conspiracy theory.
Speaker 6:  There you
Speaker 10:  Go.
Speaker 6:  We should actually quickly talk about the nest hub. Just for one second.
Speaker 6:  Before we titled the pixel watch, they announced a bunch of features to invoke
Speaker 6:  the assistant only for the nest hub max, that require you
Speaker 6:  to look at it because it has a camera. And that was the one part of
Speaker 6:  this whole presentation where I was like, oh, that's too far. I really don't
Speaker 6:  want it. I don't want an always on camera in my, I have the little mess.
Speaker 6:  Cause it doesn't have a camera. Yeah.
Speaker 10:  So, I mean, then you, I guess just wouldn't use this feature, but if you
Speaker 10:  have a nest hub max, and you don't have the camera disabled,
Speaker 10:  then it recognizes you already, like that was a launch feature. Like it
Speaker 10:  says, hi Dan, when I walk up to it or whatever, and it shows my little avatar.
Speaker 10:  And then in theory, if it, if Google ever got its
Speaker 10:  calendar system straight, where it can see my work calendar, it would show
Speaker 10:  my work calendar of events, as opposed to like, if my kids look at it, they
Speaker 10:  would not see my calendar events. So it's already doing that. This is just
Speaker 10:  kind of like the next step of like, oh, you're looking at it. We know you're
Speaker 10:  looking at it. We know you're in range of it. If you just say like start
Speaker 10:  a timer, we don't need you to say, Hey G
Speaker 10:  to wake up.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I don't know the urge. The idea of the camera always looking to see
Speaker 6:  if you're making eye contact with it. Just like don't no,
Speaker 6:  thank you. I don't need to make eye contact at
Speaker 6:  the community.
Speaker 7:  Well, and I think part of this, what's interesting about that to me is like,
Speaker 7:  it's a constant reminder that it is doing that, right? Like the, the thing
Speaker 7:  where you walk up to it and it knows you as, at least you can sort of feel
Speaker 7:  in your brain, like you're doing something to enable it. Even though you're
Speaker 7:  not, it's just watching all the time. But this is like, they're just directly
Speaker 7:  telling you via the feature. Like it's watching you a hundred percent of
Speaker 7:  the time. Anytime you look at it, it knows like, don't, don't forget, like
Speaker 7:  that's a, that's a bold thing.
Speaker 6:  And they said all of the right things when it all happening locally and no
Speaker 6:  device, no data leaving the device and data minimization. It just, you know,
Speaker 6:  you can't take a picture of me if there's not a camera on the thing, it's,
Speaker 6:  I'm going to stick with the little ones until, until they forced me out the
Speaker 6:  way, then I'm gonna put tape one, one of my white tape. All right. There's
Speaker 6:  cameras all over my house. I don't even want, I'm talking about there's five
Speaker 6:  cameras on my cell phone that I carry in my pocket. We started
Speaker 6:  pixel watch Dan. It seems like they're trying
Speaker 6:  again in a serious way. They've got this platform they did with Samsung.
Speaker 6:  What do you think?
Speaker 10:  Yeah. The pixel watch is interesting. I mean, we've, this thing has been
Speaker 10:  rumored and leak for over a year now and it's still not coming out to the
Speaker 10:  fall. This is one of the announcements along with the pixel seven that it's
Speaker 10:  going to be released in the fall, but here's a teaser look. There's a couple
Speaker 10:  of interesting things with it. I think the big move for it is that this
Speaker 10:  is finally the first product of the
Speaker 10:  Fitbit integration with Google that we're really seeing in a real, tangible
Speaker 10:  way. Google closed. David, was it 2021? Excuse me.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, it closed. Yeah. January, 2021. And they announced the acquisition
Speaker 7:  in like mid 20, 19.
Speaker 10:  Yeah. Like a light literal lifetime ago. They announced that acquisition.
Speaker 10:  And now we're finally getting a product that is using that. So they are
Speaker 10:  going to have like a big fitness integration play, which as we know is
Speaker 10:  what makes the apple watch popular. So that's like a smart move. The
Speaker 10:  watch itself looks pretty nice. I guess
Speaker 10:  it's interesting that they only seem to show one size of it as opposed to
Speaker 10:  multiple sizes. It's got a proprietary bands,
Speaker 10:  which is Hm. Maybe, and it's round and
Speaker 10:  it's got a little, little control dial on the side, whatever you call it.
Speaker 10:  One of those,
Speaker 6:  The digital crown that you don't know, this Johnny I've told us this
Speaker 6:  revolutionary
Speaker 7:  Input
Speaker 6:  On par with multitouch.
Speaker 10:  Yeah. And like, you know, it's going to be running where ROS three, which
Speaker 10:  is currently only available on Samsung watches. They also announced on stage
Speaker 10:  a bunch of watches from the usual Android watchmakers from
Speaker 10:  fossil and all the brands associated with that are going to be releasing
Speaker 10:  where it was three watches. But so far we've only had an, not a Samsung
Speaker 10:  watch and it's been very much a Samsung driven experience. So when the pixel
Speaker 10:  watch comes out, ideally we would be getting, what is a Google
Speaker 10:  driven experience for an Android smartwatch? Is,
Speaker 6:  Is there any news on the processor, battery life,
Speaker 6:  front new? I mean, this is like the thing that has held this
Speaker 6:  entire category.
Speaker 10:  Yeah. So like for many years, Android wear watches have been relying on
Speaker 10:  many of the Android wear watches have been relying on Qualcomm processors,
Speaker 10:  which Qualcomm has not really put a lot of development into its processors
Speaker 10:  for wearables. And they've been slower and way behind what apple is doing.
Speaker 10:  The only reason that the Samsung watch runs where it was three is because
Speaker 10:  it's using a Samsung processor inside of it.
Speaker 10:  The Qualcomm processors that are available thus far, apparently can't run
Speaker 10:  all the features of where it was three. So it'll be interesting to see what
Speaker 10:  processor they do put in this pixel. They did not speak to that at all.
Speaker 10:  They didn't speak to anything in terms of like battery life or features
Speaker 10:  like always on display, you would assume that it would have like the Google
Speaker 10:  assistant and you could talk to it. Like you can talk to Siri on the apple
Speaker 10:  watch. They did say that you can control Google home stuff through it. So
Speaker 10:  you can control smart home stuff. It's like all the typical smartwatch stuff
Speaker 10:  we've seen for like years now. Like they're just like putting it all together
Speaker 10:  in one product that'll hopefully work well and not die at like 5:00 PM,
Speaker 10:  which is like a thing that
Speaker 6:  They haven't
Speaker 10:  Been able to in the past. So there's a lot of unknowns here. We don't know
Speaker 10:  exactly what it's gonna cost. I think it's going to be more on the premium
Speaker 10:  side. I would be surprised at this thing's under $300. They're using stainless
Speaker 10:  steel with it, which is generally going to pump, push the price up. And
Speaker 10:  if they put a tensor chip in there, we have no idea.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I think the main thing for me is, you know, they went with a circular
Speaker 6:  display, which they've been doing across where for awhile, it does not
Speaker 6:  seem like they have really rethought the UI if there's still a lot
Speaker 6:  of scrolling of rectangular objects in their demos. And it's
Speaker 6:  like, you guys, all right, like we've just been at smartwatches for
Speaker 6:  awhile. Yeah. This isn't a first-generation product kind
Speaker 6:  of problem. But like, here we are and it's still like, well, I guess the
Speaker 6:  edges of that list item will be cut off as a
Speaker 6:  scroll.
Speaker 10:  That reminds me of like what pebble did with their circular smartwatch many
Speaker 10:  years ago, they would just scroll the whole page. So it perfectly fit each
Speaker 10:  circle. So you couldn't scroll line by line. They would just do an entire
Speaker 10:  page. And each page was rendered to fit the circle.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I mean, I don't think there's any great solutions except for
Speaker 6:  square watches. And then you're stuck with a direct apple comparison. So
Speaker 6:  I kind of get it, but we'll see. I think the Fitbit stuff is really interesting
Speaker 6:  that we've been waiting, but I think the main things for me are like battery
Speaker 6:  life. And then obviously they can only, I mean, this is like the pixel buds
Speaker 6:  pro too, right? Like they're starting to make hardware devices that
Speaker 6:  only really work well with their hardware and that's,
Speaker 10:  Or at least at least Android hardware, right? Like, you know,
Speaker 10:  I'm sure that the pixel watch will work with other Android phones not made
Speaker 10:  by Google and the pixel buds pro, which they also announced we'll
Speaker 10:  probably work with non Google phones. Maybe there might be a feature or
Speaker 10:  two that you get with a pixel that you don't get on a Samsung phone, but
Speaker 10:  like, they really are not designed to work with iPhones at all.
Speaker 10:  So like you probably won't be able to pair the watch with an iPhone. You
Speaker 10:  might be able to pair the pixel buds with an iPhone, but then have no access
Speaker 10:  to any feature control or anything like that. They will just be like very
Speaker 10:  basic Bluetooth headphones,
Speaker 6:  Just wait until the Europeans hear about this.
Speaker 7:  Well, and on that same level, what do we know about how Fitbit gets integrated
Speaker 7:  into things? Because one thing that is true is there are a lot of people
Speaker 7:  out there in the world who love Fitbits and have used them for a
Speaker 7:  long time, who might theoretically want a device like this. But what I can't
Speaker 7:  get a sense of is like, is Fitbit going to be a
Speaker 7:  separate service, like Google fit that others can use? Is it going to be
Speaker 7:  part of Android? Is it just going to be for the pixel watch? Like, did they
Speaker 7:  spend all this money on this company just for the pixel watch? Do we have
Speaker 7:  any idea how this is going to shake out?
Speaker 10:  Yeah. It's hard to say, I know that James Park who
Speaker 10:  is CEO, or he was a CEO before the acquisition. I don't know what his current
Speaker 10:  title is now, but he's basically the leader of Fitbit. He did say that when
Speaker 10:  the pixel watch launches, Google fit is still gonna exist for
Speaker 10:  whatever reason. So they're going to, they're going to run concurrently.
Speaker 10:  Fitbit is going to be making other hardware. They've got trackers, they've
Speaker 10:  got their other smartwatch lines, but apparently it was his team
Speaker 10:  that drove the development of the pixel watch. So there's a lot
Speaker 10:  of Fitbit expertise built into this, maybe in the way that the watch
Speaker 10:  wears the way it fits you, the way it kind of works as a
Speaker 10:  functional watch, it seemed like they leverage a lot of that Fitbit experience.
Speaker 10:  But as far as like what the platforms do, it's still like up in the
Speaker 10:  air, you know how that's going to shake out. And, and are you going to have
Speaker 10:  to fitness apps on your watch? Like if you have a Samsung watch, you do,
Speaker 10:  you've got Google fit and you've got Samsung health and you could install
Speaker 10:  any others, but yeah.
Speaker 7:  And I'm sure there's a team at Google working on like Android
Speaker 7:  fitness pro and that'll come too. And it'll it all just be really delightful.
Speaker 6:  As Sandra told us, they're focusing man, ecosystems,
Speaker 10:  What are we doing?
Speaker 6:  All right. Last thing real quick. I feel like we can actually get through
Speaker 6:  it real quick. They tease the pixel seven and seven pro. They
Speaker 6:  also announced the pixel six, eight, but fine. Yeah. It's
Speaker 6:  450 bucks. It has a millimeter wave which had 450 bucks, I think might be
Speaker 6:  one of the only phones. Well, oh no. They tell us something
Speaker 6:  wrong a little bit. Yeah.
Speaker 10:  Shocker that Google had their specs wrong on their
Speaker 10:  wireless radios. The unlocked $450 version
Speaker 10:  does not have millimeter wave. The version that Verizon is selling
Speaker 10:  is $500 and it does have millimeter wave. So you get to pay
Speaker 10:  a 10%, 10%. Yeah. 10% tax
Speaker 10:  to get millimeter wave of horizon.
Speaker 6:  Very good. Just what everybody wants, who was, who hasn't wanted
Speaker 6:  to stand at her one street corner in download in pirate movies
Speaker 6:  at blazing fast speeds on their $450 a month.
Speaker 10:  The other interesting thing about the pixel six, eight real quick is that
Speaker 10:  it is aggressively priced and, but it runs the same
Speaker 10:  tensor processor as the pixel six and six pro, but it does not have the
Speaker 10:  same camera system as the six and six pro. Instead, it appears to have the
Speaker 10:  same camera system as the five and five  from
Speaker 10:  before it. And this is the first time that the, a line Alison
Speaker 10:  Johnson on our team pointed this out, that like, this is the first time
Speaker 10:  that the a line has a different camera system than
Speaker 10:  the flagship pixels. So Google treated a
Speaker 10:  better processor for inferior camera. And it made that trade this year,
Speaker 10:  which is, which is interesting. That's obviously what apple does with the
Speaker 10:  se line on its budget phones. It's got the latest eight, 15 processor, but
Speaker 10:  it's got an inferior camera compared to the rest of the iPhone. So it's
Speaker 10:  interesting that Google made that transition this year.
Speaker 6:  Well, I think they're all focused on tensor, right? Like they, they said
Speaker 6:  nothing about these cameras at all,
Speaker 10:  Other than they're 12 million pixels.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Correct. And then they teased the seven and seven
Speaker 6:  pro, which are still ugly. I don't know
Speaker 6:  what else they, they
Speaker 10:  Carry on that, that design language and either you like it or you
Speaker 10:  don't. And, and the one thing that they're changing with the seven pro is
Speaker 10:  interesting is on the six and six pro the, the
Speaker 10:  camera bar, or as Dieter used to call it, the shelf
Speaker 10:  was glass. If you didn't use a case and you put your phone down, you're
Speaker 10:  putting the glass like camera lens right down on
Speaker 7:  The brake. The third time you did it
Speaker 10:  Very frequently broke. So they are shifting that to like an aluminum band
Speaker 10:  that has cutouts for the camera in it. So that's gonna be a little bit different
Speaker 10:  of a look. Maybe there'll be more durable or what have you. The other thing
Speaker 10:  we know about the pixel seven and seven pro is that they will have a second
Speaker 10:  generation tensor chip in them. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  I just, they're not beautiful. Maybe it won't go all the way to the
Speaker 6:  U word
Speaker 10:  I need. I've seen, I've seen worse design.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. You've seen that pixel tab.
Speaker 7:  What if you could dock your phone to your nests smart
Speaker 7:  hub. Yeah,
Speaker 10:  Yeah, yeah. Didn't the Seuss do that like 10 years ago, you dock the phone
Speaker 10:  to the tablet
Speaker 6:  Period now where like early 2010s
Speaker 6:  product innovation, like enough people have forgotten
Speaker 6:  it. Yeah. We're like, we're just going to do like
Speaker 10:  A tricks time to shine, baby
Speaker 6:  Docks here. You can turn this phone into a shit windows, computer. Let's
Speaker 6:  do it. You guys heard of Linux on the desktop.
Speaker 6:  This is the year. All right. There's other stuff they brought that wallet.
Speaker 6:  I mean, it's all on the side. Just bring it back.
Speaker 10:  The
Speaker 6:  Hits. It is very much. Google is in a and
Speaker 6:  again, you just heard us talking sooner. If they're more focused, they're
Speaker 6:  actually trying to deliver on this stuff. It's interesting.
Speaker 6:  I would not say there's they announced anything that was wildly new at this
Speaker 6:  year site.
Speaker 10:  No, I mean, I think we'll see. I think that the fall hardware launch will
Speaker 10:  be interesting because one will obviously learn more about the pixel
Speaker 10:  sevens and the pixel watch. But I have a feeling, just a hunch that if
Speaker 10:  they're willing to tease the tablet IO, maybe they will tease a foldable
Speaker 10:  in the fall if they're not ready to launch yet, because that thing's been
Speaker 10:  rumored forever.
Speaker 7:  That's a good theory. All
Speaker 6:  Right. I've been doing my own research.
Speaker 10:  Yes. You've been Googling
Speaker 7:  Dan. Thank you. We will see you again here soon. We're going to take a break,
Speaker 7:  but before we do that, the crypto world is insane right
Speaker 7:  now. And we could spend like nine hours talking about it, but instead we
Speaker 7:  just grabbed Lizel Pato and decided to spend like 10 minutes trying to figure
Speaker 7:  out what's going on in crypto. So here's
Speaker 7:  that Liz Lopatto. Hi, welcome to what we're calling crypto
Speaker 7:  corner. The new possibly only ever happening once the segment on the
Speaker 7:  first Katz.
Speaker 13:  Well welcome ladies and gentlemen, my fellow dirt bags and everybody else
Speaker 13:  here we are. It's time to talk about money.
Speaker 7:  Okay. So there's a million things we could talk about, but I think the like
Speaker 7:  general story here is crypto is falling apart. And as far as I can tell,
Speaker 7:  and please correct me if I'm wrong. A lot of this comes back to Luna
Speaker 7:  and Tara as like the, the sort of middle of all of the chaos. If
Speaker 7:  you had to pick one, it seems like it's, that is that fair
Speaker 13:  Kind of, okay. So I'm going to like zoom way back and then we're going
Speaker 13:  to zoom forward to Luna and Tara. So one of the things about an asset, like
Speaker 13:  a cryptocurrency is that it's super risky. And for the last
Speaker 13:  several years we've been living with very, very low
Speaker 13:  interest rates like near zero. The reason why we've had
Speaker 13:  near zero interest rate policy is to stimulate the
Speaker 13:  economy during the pandemic. And so in this environment, it doesn't necessarily
Speaker 13:  make sense to put your money in safe investments because you're not going
Speaker 13:  to earn enough interest to keep up with inflation. So a bunch of weird shit
Speaker 13:  happened. We've got SPACs, we've got meme stocks, we got MNF tees.
Speaker 13:  And like a lot of the like sort of weirdness is because there was so
Speaker 13:  much money, like sloshing around and looking for places to
Speaker 13:  have returns that inevitably it spilled into some of these
Speaker 13:  other areas. But also, like, I think some people got bored during the pandemic
Speaker 13:  and risk can be really fun. Like that's the point of the gambling
Speaker 13:  industry? So a lot of people got involved with like
Speaker 13:  trading anyway, around November, the fed indicated that it was going to
Speaker 13:  raise interest rates. And that by the way, was the peak of the crypto market
Speaker 13:  was November. And then last week the
Speaker 13:  fed increased the interest rates by half a percentage point, which is like
Speaker 13:  the biggest increase in 20 years. And so we all saw like the stocks
Speaker 13:  fall, right? Crypto has been falling farther because it's much
Speaker 13:  more volatile. And anybody who's looking to de-risk is probably going
Speaker 13:  to start with crypto. And so to get to
Speaker 13:  your question about Luna and Tara, I think maybe it's helpful
Speaker 13:  to understand in the crypto ecosystem, what a stable coin
Speaker 13:  is
Speaker 7:  Because stable Queens are supposed to be like immune to all of this. Isn't
Speaker 7:  that like they're literally called stable coins, right? Like all this
Speaker 7:  chaos should not be affecting stable coins.
Speaker 13:  Oh, that's fun. Because some
Speaker 13:  economic research from Bruce Ms. Rack, he's an
Speaker 13:  economist and he looked at stable coins and they're not that
Speaker 13:  stable actually like 80% of them go to zero. But the idea behind a
Speaker 13:  stable coin is essentially that it's pegged to
Speaker 13:  something like, let's say a dollar just for simplicity's sake. So you have
Speaker 13:  something like tether, which is supposed to represent a dollar in the
Speaker 13:  crypto ecosystem and is theoretically backed by reserves. I
Speaker 13:  say theoretically, because there are a lot of questions about tethers reserves
Speaker 13:  and we'll get there in a second. But the idea is that if you want
Speaker 13:  to exit, let's say your Bitcoin position and you want to move into, let's
Speaker 13:  say a theorem. One way to do that is to cash out
Speaker 13:  through tether or another stable coin. That's about equivalent to a dollar
Speaker 13:  and then move into the Ethereum ecosystem as for why you might want
Speaker 13:  to do that. Well, it's really difficult to go
Speaker 13:  between crypto and fiasco or what you and I understand to
Speaker 13:  be money like dollar
Speaker 7:  Real human people, money. Yeah.
Speaker 13:  I mean, as real as money ever is. And so that's partly because of
Speaker 13:  like things like, you know, anti money laundering regulations,
Speaker 13:  stuff like that, it sometimes takes a couple of days for your crypto investment
Speaker 13:  to show up in your like dollar bank account. So if you want to do trading
Speaker 13:  more quickly than that, you move into a dollar equivalent, which is a stable
Speaker 13:  coin. Those are used to do things like
Speaker 13:  create loans in the device space, bunch of other stuff in
Speaker 13:  the ecosystem with something like tether it's backed
Speaker 13:  by reserves. Now, like there are questions about tethers reserves, which
Speaker 13:  I got into at length last year. But the thing about Tara
Speaker 13:  and Luna about that ecosystem is that it is an
Speaker 13:  algorithmic stable coin, which is if possible, worse than a regular one.
Speaker 13:  The thing about algorithmic stable coins is that
Speaker 13:  I'm trying to think of a real gentle way to put this and
Speaker 13:  I'm not coming up with one.
Speaker 7:  I think it's increasingly not in need of a gentle explanation based on
Speaker 7:  what's happened.
Speaker 13:  And basically the way that this works is you
Speaker 13:  have two, two coins, right? One of them is
Speaker 13:  called Tara and Tara is supposed to be worth $1. And
Speaker 13:  the other is called Luna. And that value floats. So it's worth whatever
Speaker 13:  somebody wants to pay for it. The same as like, I don't know, Bitcoin, Ethereum,
Speaker 13:  whatever. Now the two can be converted into each other. So let's say Luna's
Speaker 13:  were 30, which it was recently and certainly is not right now, but like,
Speaker 13:  let's say it's worth 30. You can destroy Luna and get
Speaker 13:  30 Tara because Tara is worth a dollar each. Right.
Speaker 13:  And so if Tara's worth less than a dollar and you can think
Speaker 13:  to yourself, oh, great idea. I'm going to destroy,
Speaker 13:  I don't know, like 45 Tara to create
Speaker 13:  one Luna at a discount, which, you
Speaker 13:  know, decreases the supply of Tara, making it more valuable, pulling it
Speaker 13:  back up to a dollar. And if you're thinking, wait a minute. But like what
Speaker 13:  makes this valuable? The answer is belief
Speaker 13:  in community. And so, you know, if you believe in this stuff,
Speaker 13:  if you're in Luna, this can be useful because you're
Speaker 13:  like, oh, a number go up. This is great. And you feel like, sort of
Speaker 13:  backed by arbitrage, but the moment that confidence
Speaker 13:  is lost, then you find yourself in a really
Speaker 13:  interesting position because you can essentially buy dollars at
Speaker 13:  a discounted price. So if you know,
Speaker 13:  you dump everything, then they both fail and we've hit
Speaker 13:  this point of failure. And to be clear, the people behind this project
Speaker 13:  are trying to like fix things.
Speaker 7:  Well, and that's the last piece of this we're going to get into before I
Speaker 7:  let you go. Cause it's, it gets even crazier. But yeah, like I keep
Speaker 7:  looking and I feel like every time I refresh the page, the value of Linda
Speaker 7:  goes down further and further.
Speaker 13:  So right now it's worth 2 cents,
Speaker 13:  which just to be clear, like as of like April
Speaker 13:  4th, it was worth $116. So some people
Speaker 13:  just really got like wrecked in a really, really
Speaker 13:  painful way that I am genuinely sorry for, because like the
Speaker 13:  thing about money and the thing about investments is that they play
Speaker 13:  on human emotions. And like the biggest thing in the crypto space
Speaker 13:  is like hope and greed versus fear, uncertainty and doubt, or what people
Speaker 13:  like to call FID. And so like, if you look at
Speaker 13:  Tara's price right now, you know, for the, the UST the
Speaker 13:  thing that's supposed to be worth a dollar it's worth 38 cents at the time
Speaker 13:  of this recording,
Speaker 7:  Which is definitively not a dollar.
Speaker 13:  Correct. And so like, I love the arbitrage idea of buying a dollar
Speaker 13:  for 38 cents. Cause that's a lot of profit for me, assuming I
Speaker 13:  can exit the trade, which I may not be able to do at this point. So that's
Speaker 13:  kind of what's going on. You're in a death spiral. Now what
Speaker 13:  has happened is that the people behind this
Speaker 13:  ecosystem have halted the blockchain, they say
Speaker 13:  to prevent governance attacks. But I think like that's like the only
Speaker 13:  way that you can make the death cycle stop and like reset it if
Speaker 13:  that's even possible, which I, I don't think it is
Speaker 7:  Just by literally not letting people continue to sell.
Speaker 13:  Yeah. And like, to be clear, like this is not that unusual in the
Speaker 13:  regular financial system, right? Like the markets and the
Speaker 13:  regular financial system close it, like for when there's some aftermarket
Speaker 13:  trading, whatever. But like, you can, like, you're not going to get wrecked
Speaker 13:  while you're asleep. The problem with cryptocurrency
Speaker 13:  ecosystem is that the markets are always open. And so there's no time to
Speaker 13:  like pause and like reevaluate your position and
Speaker 13:  like restrategize and like get out of your feelings. Because like one of
Speaker 13:  the biggest things that like happens during periods, like this is panic
Speaker 13:  selling where people sell stuff that actually might be good, but they're
Speaker 13:  so freaked out about all their losses that they don't like, think it all
Speaker 13:  the way through and sell. And so like, you know, if
Speaker 13:  you're opportunistic, like when you see a bear market like this, you start
Speaker 13:  thinking, okay, when do I want to buy in? Because like, there are plenty
Speaker 13:  of people who are in this space who think that, you know, cryptocurrency
Speaker 13:  is going to come back because so far it has. And like I've seen a lot of
Speaker 13:  people sort of reassuring each other and themselves. Like I remember when
Speaker 13:  Bitcoin like plunged in, you know, 2018. And like, I remember all of these
Speaker 13:  crypto winters, whatever. I guess one of the things that I find myself
Speaker 13:  really interested in is like, are we going to see this
Speaker 13:  chaos going into the regular markets? Because you know, there
Speaker 13:  are cryptocurrencies that are on the stock exchange right now, like Coinbase,
Speaker 13:  like that's, that's a publicly traded company, like things
Speaker 13:  going wrong for crypto. It means things going wrong for Coinbase in the
Speaker 13:  Coinbase shareholders. And of course, Coinbase has been plunging also as
Speaker 13:  all of this is happening. And so, like, I can't tell you for sure that this
Speaker 13:  is going to stay contained to crypto. I hope it is. But there's
Speaker 13:  the possibility that there are linkages between these two systems. So between
Speaker 13:  like trad five and crypto, but also because like a lot of the people who
Speaker 13:  are in crypto are retail investors. And so it may just be that we're going
Speaker 13:  to see a lot of retail capitulation. And so if they
Speaker 13:  decide that like all risk assets are a problem, then
Speaker 13:  there's spillover. So it's,
Speaker 13:  I don't know what happens. I am absolutely riveted. And
Speaker 13:  you know, I know that some of our listeners are into crypto into the
Speaker 13:  crypto ecosystem. If you're in crypto and you want to talk about this
Speaker 13:  and like, let me know what's going on from your position, like email me,
Speaker 13:  I'm liz@theverge.com. I am genuinely
Speaker 13:  curious about what's happening to retail investors right now. And like,
Speaker 13:  if this is you, like, what are you thinking? How's it going
Speaker 13:  like, please drop me a line. I'm I think there's carnage in the markets.
Speaker 13:  And I think there's more carnage coming.
Speaker 7:  Fair enough. All right. Well, we're going to come back to all of that on
Speaker 7:  the next episode of crypto corner, which is probably a segment they'll never
Speaker 7:  let us do again, but I hope we do. Thank you, Liz. Appreciate it. And
Speaker 7:  we are for real, going to take a break this time. We'll be
Speaker 7:  right
Speaker 7:  back.
Speaker 6:  We are back apologies to the crypto verse. If things work out
Speaker 6:  for you, Alex Kranz is here. Hey Alex,
Speaker 5:  Hey, I'm very excited to not talk about crypto.
Speaker 6:  Well, that makes just one now. So this is great. Liz is a refocus. She's
Speaker 6:  on the crypto beat now. So now when, whenever we need anything, Liz
Speaker 6:  is there. That's great. She's there. And what a time to be on the crutch
Speaker 6:  of heat. That's where I talked about that with Alex, Alex, we're talking
Speaker 6:  about the lightening for classic Vergecast.
Speaker 5:  Yes. I love that. There's like currently a threat to the
Speaker 5:  lightning port,
Speaker 6:  A looming threat,
Speaker 5:  A looming threat. It's it's been looming for like a decade now,
Speaker 5:  but no, it's really, really looming. There's we're getting more and more
Speaker 5:  reports that they're going to finally get rid of the lightning port on
Speaker 5:  the iPhone and the air pods and replace it with USB-C.
Speaker 6:  If you drop it off the iPhone, you got your hoop, you gotta take it
Speaker 6:  off. Everything,
Speaker 5:  Everything. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  That's the end of it. It's it's actually, there's like some really inside
Speaker 6:  tech journalism based while here. So there's a very famous
Speaker 6:  analyst, Ming. She quo who issues reports, great
Speaker 6:  track record on apple rumors, surveys, the supply
Speaker 6:  chains, component suppliers. He is a
Speaker 6:  controversial figure. Apple
Speaker 6:  hates and
Speaker 6:  Accusations that he's bribing, like all the stuff, but he is an analyst.
Speaker 6:  He is deeply sourced in the supply chains and component
Speaker 6:  world gets a lot of apple stuff, right? Sometimes he get some stuff wrong.
Speaker 6:  I'm only saying this to set up the fact that now they have a Twitter, which
Speaker 6:  is just not where you would like your stuff used to come out. That max sites
Speaker 6:  would get it for sure. Right? The
Speaker 5:  Reason is
Speaker 7:  Yeah, but all like percolate out from his analysts, from the analyst reports
Speaker 7:  that it was like, you never quite knew where it was coming from.
Speaker 7:  Somebody got an email that they sent to somebody else and then it eventually
Speaker 7:  ended up on the internet. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. But now he's like, whatever, I got a Twitter, Twitter has
Speaker 6:  got six months left and I'm going hard for the last six months.
Speaker 6:  So he's tweeting directly now. And he says, my latest survey indicates in
Speaker 6:  second half of 23, new I-phones will abandon lightening and switched
Speaker 6:  to USB-C. And then the suppliers, the USB-C
Speaker 6:  ecosystem will become they're going to do great. So what he's basically saying
Speaker 6:  is I've talked to all the suppliers and they're expecting USBC sales to go
Speaker 6:  through the roof because apple sending it, this is this true or not. We don't
Speaker 6:  know good track record, but you put this next to when they announced lightening,
Speaker 6:  they said it was Phil Schiller said, it's a connector for the next decade.
Speaker 6:  And they've hit the mark.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Is this year? The decade?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. They're like, they're done September, 2012, Phil Schiller
Speaker 6:  called lightening a modern connector for the next decade.
Speaker 5:  So technically they kept their promise to
Speaker 6:  Made it a decade. That's true. All the rumors were that they were going to
Speaker 6:  go portlets and just do wireless charging. And then I think they released
Speaker 6:  a mag safe in wireless charging. And then every apple
Speaker 6:  executive experienced what wireless charging is like. And they're
Speaker 6:  like, cables are still pretty good at this.
Speaker 7:  And they can sell cables for so much money. You can buy a
Speaker 7:  10 foot apple cable for $40,000 and the margins
Speaker 7:  pretty good.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. It's every day Tim cook gets an email. That's like, this is how
Speaker 6:  many, $150 Thunderbolt cables we sold. And he's like, well, that's
Speaker 6:  the future of the business. We'll see. They've they have been very committed
Speaker 6:  to lightening. They have not wanted to let it go, but it's it's time. Doesn't
Speaker 6:  it feel like it's time.
Speaker 5:  I have they been committed. Cause they've already pretty much taken out most
Speaker 5:  of the iPads at this point.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. It's still only in the cheapest couple and that's about it.
Speaker 5:  And it just feels like a legacy thing. Much. Like most of those really cheap
Speaker 5:  iPads, like most of the components of them are legacy components. So
Speaker 5:  I could see it. We're doing a brand new iPhone. We're doing a brand
Speaker 5:  new air pots, USBC, and then we all cry.
Speaker 5:  And there's like, at least one analyst, how you think said they were going
Speaker 5:  to shave their eyebrows. If it actually happens, that guy will have no
Speaker 5:  eyebrows.
Speaker 6:  Twitter's getting weird. And these last six months of Twitter, it's just
Speaker 6:  getting weird,
Speaker 5:  Super weird.
Speaker 6:  A SOC that's the big rumor. It's funny. Cause that came right on top of the
Speaker 6:  news. Apple was going to discontinue the iPod. But while the
Speaker 6:  iPod touch, which was like ancient at
Speaker 6:  this point,
Speaker 5:  It's an iPhone seven. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  It had the iPhone seven ship in it. But you know, we just had Tony Fidel
Speaker 6:  on decoder. He was on his big Tories and tweeting all these pictures
Speaker 6:  of iPods. He got in a little, I would say like a respectful
Speaker 6:  bro argument with Phil Schiller on Twitter who had the idea for
Speaker 6:  the wheel and where the idea for the wheel came and it ended up sounding
Speaker 6:  like loved working with you, man. Do like in the middle of your, like, this
Speaker 6:  could go another way, but it's just like a moment. The iPod had a moment
Speaker 6:  in the past couple weeks. Is it the Fidel book? I'm just going to say, I
Speaker 6:  was thinking about how much stuff I used to have in my pockets all the time.
Speaker 6:  So it was an iPod, but I always had a classic. I always had the big
Speaker 6:  dog. I had Canon Powershot elf. That was very important to
Speaker 6:  me and God, thank God. Those pictures in
Speaker 6:  survive, Sony, Sony candybar phone, always those three
Speaker 6:  things. And I had to charge them all every night.
Speaker 5:  And you had to wear cargo pants?
Speaker 6:  No, I didn't have cargo pants. I'm like a jacket oriented person. And
Speaker 6:  I was like, What were you? Did you have, were you permanent
Speaker 6:  iPod person?
Speaker 7:  Oh yeah. I had a gold iPod mini that went absolutely everywhere with me for
Speaker 7:  a very long time. It was
Speaker 5:  Incredible.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Oh, I loved it. It got, it was one of the things like that. It got
Speaker 7:  stolen out of my car. And I still remember like where I was,
Speaker 7:  what the weather was like, where my car was parked. Like I remember it, it
Speaker 7:  was a, it was one of those moments in my life that like is so
Speaker 7:  scarred into me because that's when someone stole my iPod and I couldn't
Speaker 7:  afford to buy anyone, but I still had the white headphones. So I plugged
Speaker 7:  those into my crappy other MP3 player. I kept using it and it was kind of
Speaker 7:  like I had an iPad.
Speaker 5:  My original iPod was also a disappeared. I have no idea who
Speaker 5:  took it. I suspect my brother. I've never found it. It
Speaker 5:  never reappeared.
Speaker 6:  Well, if he's listening now,
Speaker 5:  I, since I've moved many times, so who was in any of those places? I would
Speaker 5:  have found it when I moved. Right. But it wasn't there. So
Speaker 5:  who knows. And then I got an iPod shuffle. It was not the same.
Speaker 6:  Did he have the one without any buttons?
Speaker 5:  Yes. I had that one and I had like the USB stick looking
Speaker 5:  one.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  That was my favorite because I felt, I would feel like a spy. I'd go to like
Speaker 5:  the college computer lab and it'd be like, I'm in
Speaker 5:  guys feel very, very
Speaker 5:  cool.
Speaker 7:  Cause
Speaker 6:  The iPod is one of the last products
Speaker 6:  that constantly changed its design every year. Like every year it looked
Speaker 6:  different and it was a very exciting. And now it's like, well, we're under
Speaker 6:  the 35th year of this iPhone. We figured
Speaker 6:  out laptops. And that's what you're going to get forever. Just go. I would
Speaker 6:  encourage everyone to go back in time and look at like what digital cameras
Speaker 6:  looked like. They were all over the
Speaker 7:  Place.
Speaker 6:  And then like, everything is conversion to a candy bar, which is fine. They're
Speaker 6:  very powerful. And they're great. And we love them obviously, but be nice.
Speaker 6:  It'd be nice if we'd
Speaker 5:  Click wheel
Speaker 6:  Diverged, the things that you just say, click we old people
Speaker 7:  There really was something magical about it, by the way, like the coolest
Speaker 7:  thing about the, the iPad thing this week was like, everybody has
Speaker 7:  an iPod story and everybody like has feelings
Speaker 7:  about iPods. They had just, they were this like cultural
Speaker 7:  phenomenon for so many people for so long that I don't feel like there's
Speaker 7:  that many things like that. Like, you're not going to hear people telling
Speaker 7:  you like their stories about their quest to in 10
Speaker 7:  years. Like it's just the same
Speaker 7:  thing.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. One of the, actually the things I thought about the I've heard a lot
Speaker 6:  this week was so much
Speaker 6:  iPod usage was communal. Like you think about it, it's like a headphones
Speaker 6:  device. Like you're alone. You're like having your moment, but you were
Speaker 6:  not worried about people seeing your photos, pads
Speaker 6:  weren't locked. Right? Like they had the switch on the top to prevent like,
Speaker 6:  but plays. But like, you can just like, you would just like hand your iPad.
Speaker 6:  Other people are like plug it into their doc or like whatever.
Speaker 6:  And like that was the ad campaign. It's like what? It was just such a shared
Speaker 6:  device. And very few of our devices are designed to be shared in that way
Speaker 6:  anymore because they contain the past present and future of our personalities.
Speaker 6:  And now you're like, no, you don't even look at my phone. How dare
Speaker 6:  you.
Speaker 7:  But also that feeling when you hand somebody, your iPod and they
Speaker 7:  start scrolling through your artists and judging your music taste was like,
Speaker 7:  that was it. That was a real moment. It was, it was like, maybe not as high
Speaker 7:  stakes as you can now scroll through all my photos. But it felt as someone
Speaker 7:  with like deeply, deeply terrible music taste, it was, it was, it was
Speaker 7:  a tough moment. It's a lot of people who are like, wow, you have a lot of
Speaker 7:  Britney Spears on your iPad.
Speaker 6:  There's a lot of jangly jam bands on your iPad.
Speaker 7:  So many, so many,
Speaker 6:  Just like the entire jam
Speaker 6:  bands, discography.
Speaker 5:  That was the best part of it though. I loved having like terrible music
Speaker 5:  on it and like wording it. So that was the first thing you would see on
Speaker 5:  my iPod. So you'd be like, what? This is what we're going to have to listen.
Speaker 5:  Like anime music from the 1980s. This is what you're going
Speaker 5:  to make us listen to Alex. I'm like, yeah, it's exactly what you're going
Speaker 5:  to have to listen to. It was incredible.
Speaker 6:  Were you a, were you a perfectly organized person?
Speaker 5:  A hundred percent like that was a dopamine hit. Same
Speaker 5:  to like, I'd get in there. I'd I'd mess with the genre. I'd be like, is that
Speaker 5:  really, is it really country Western? Is it
Speaker 5:  Texas country? I don't know, but it had to have it just right
Speaker 6:  When you got the weird MP3s and they had the deeply weird genre and you're
Speaker 6:  like, do I have to be really into this
Speaker 6:  now?
Speaker 7:  Because
Speaker 6:  Look, we're missing a lot with having streaming services categorize all culture.
Speaker 6:  I'm just saying there was a moment with iPods and it was real
Speaker 6:  speaking of music, a Welsh reviewed, I'm never going to get this right. The
Speaker 6:  Sony w H 1000 X M fives.
Speaker 5:  You did
Speaker 6:  It. I did it because I read it. I'm going to buy these
Speaker 6:  so fast.
Speaker 7:  Yes,
Speaker 6:  Yes. Even though I think that they're not going to be my favorite,
Speaker 7:  I'm a little bummed. I kind of expected them to be Sony has
Speaker 7:  just done such a good job of just making it substantially better every
Speaker 7:  time that this was kind of the one that was like, okay, certain things are
Speaker 7:  better. It seems like it sounds better. The noise cancellation is better,
Speaker 7:  but it's more expensive for what I think is like a nicer looking,
Speaker 7:  but less sort of impressive design.
Speaker 7:  And I
Speaker 6:  Pulled up.
Speaker 7:  That's the thing. That's the thing that kills me. The fact that it just lays
Speaker 7:  flat in the case and doesn't curl in on itself to fit into it
Speaker 7:  drives me absolutely insane.
Speaker 6:  I just went to San Francisco and back and I carried my M twos, which
Speaker 6:  are dying In like decrepit. But like
Speaker 6:  they fold up small into the case. And now these,
Speaker 5:  This is, this is inflation. This
Speaker 6:  Is unfortunate.
Speaker 5:  This isn't there. They're increasing the price and giving
Speaker 5:  us less like space in our bags.
Speaker 6:  So Wild's points out that they're going to keep sign. The M is, I hope the
Speaker 6:  price will go down. I think I'm going to end up buying  because
Speaker 6:  they fold up. This is my,
Speaker 7:  There was an interesting argument on our YouTube channel too, about comfort
Speaker 7:  over versus design. Like that was just sort of the question that we posed
Speaker 7:  as we uploaded the video. And at least when I checked, it was
Speaker 7:  like overwhelmingly comfort. People are just like, just give me a thing that
Speaker 7:  is easy to wear. And for me, I would add to your point, like easy to carry.
Speaker 7:  And it's like, will I deal with slightly worse sound in order to
Speaker 7:  get that? Yes. Like the only thing for me that I like won't trade is battery
Speaker 7:  life. But beyond that, like give me comfort over just about
Speaker 7:  everything.
Speaker 6:  No, it's just like, no matter what if you're like, will you pick this or
Speaker 6:  sound quality? People are like, whatever the other one is,
Speaker 5:  Convenience,
Speaker 6:  Comfort. Just like, whatever it is, speed, like sound quality.
Speaker 6:  Now that's always the lowest thing on the list.
Speaker 5:  Great. Oh, would be like a fortune 500 company right now. If
Speaker 5:  people actually
Speaker 7:  Cared seriously,
Speaker 6:  I tweeted by the way, wandering announced podcasts and Atmos, which we are
Speaker 6:  going to have to do. And I think our engineer Andrew is very hard for us
Speaker 6:  to tell you, so where are we sneaking all around you soon? But I was
Speaker 6:  like, I think spatial audio is like for not movies is like, I'm wondering
Speaker 6:  laundering scheme. And now that the spatial audio people work out
Speaker 6:  in force. Oh
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Are there, are there like Atmos bros out there?
Speaker 6:  I don't know what, I don't know how to describe it. They're not passionate
Speaker 6:  about it. And they backed down immediately. So they're not like
Speaker 6:  Elan fans, right? They're like, I think it sounds good. You're like, I don't,
Speaker 6:  you know, like to each his own and it's legal. That was the most pleasant
Speaker 6:  online interaction that
Speaker 5:  It's because they like, they wandered over from the AVS
Speaker 5:  forum and they were like, oh, you're talking and you're talking trash about
Speaker 5:  the system. I spent thousands of dollars on how dare you.
Speaker 6:  I do it for movies. I think it's great for movies. But
Speaker 6:  I was just thinking when we released this podcast Atmos, which we
Speaker 6:  will inevitably do, I think we will quickly
Speaker 6:  discover that the value of very low, the reason I bring this up in the context
Speaker 6:  of these headphones, Sony says they're going to issue an update to make their
Speaker 6:  own spatial audio on Android
Speaker 7:  Classic disclaimer, about trusting software update promises.
Speaker 6:  Well, right? Who knows, but it won't run an iOS. And then on Android,
Speaker 6:  you can have lossless audio or you can have pairing with multiple devices.
Speaker 6:  And those are your two choices because Bluetooth is stuck. And then
Speaker 6:  on apple, you can only get AC
Speaker 5:  I'm just going to start the clock
Speaker 6:  While I'm still the next version of AirPods with these USBC connectors are
Speaker 6:  going to get the win of the USB-C connector. And then I really like it only
Speaker 6:  works on iOS devices By way of completely made a proprietary
Speaker 6:  Bluetooth protocol telling you it's coming by the way, the six, eight, the
Speaker 6:  pixel six, eight, no headphone Jack. The nightmares here, people
Speaker 7:  Were
Speaker 6:  In it every day. I definitely sat next to somebody on the plane, back from
Speaker 6:  San Francisco who looked at the movies on the Delta seat-back and
Speaker 6:  held up their air pods and then looks at the
Speaker 6:  AirPods. And
Speaker 7:  That's devastating.
Speaker 6:  It's like, there's a number of adapters and dongles that you can.
Speaker 7:  But then on the flip side, did you notice when we got on with
Speaker 7:  Sundar at the beginning of the show, he asked us if it was okay that he
Speaker 7:  couldn't find a pair of 3.5 millimeter headphones to plug into
Speaker 7:  his computer. And it's like, this is the world we live in. Like the CEO of
Speaker 7:  Google can not track down a pair of headphones that plug into a headphone
Speaker 7:  Jack.
Speaker 6:  We had somebody on the corner. I don't remember what it was, was another
Speaker 6:  CEO of an accessory company. And they were like, I need a microphone. I was
Speaker 6:  like, but you would make them
Speaker 6:  Go outside. Well, he did shout
Speaker 6:  mark Zuckerberg, trying to cause a little hype
Speaker 6:  situation today that did an Instagram real that's where he's got
Speaker 6:  it. He doesn't have a choice. He can't tweet anything. But he tweeted a link
Speaker 6:  to an Instagram video of him in the
Speaker 6:  project, Cambria headset, which was the new high end headset
Speaker 6:  that's coming out, seated the, the entire roadmap. It's a high
Speaker 6:  end and mixed reality headset. So it's like cameras in the outside
Speaker 6:  streams video to you in low latency to your eyes. And then it
Speaker 6:  does AR stuff over that video because no one can figure out actually AR so
Speaker 6:  now we're just doing video V like mixed reality
Speaker 6:  like that. This is all great. It's he says it's going to come to quest soon.
Speaker 6:  Like some sort of preview mode. The funniest thing about this is they
Speaker 6:  blurred out selectively the headset on his face, like frame
Speaker 6:  by frame. So it's just him with like a blurry line over
Speaker 6:  his eyes.
Speaker 5:  The funniest thing for me was a lot of hype in this entire video.
Speaker 5:  And they're like, we're finally doing it. We're giving you pass through
Speaker 5:  in color. And I'm like, I want you to
Speaker 5:  know color, color. Video's been a
Speaker 5:  thing. This is not new.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I I'm assuming maybe in the lab, like
Speaker 6:  they started liking, but they did announce color, very proudly, full
Speaker 6:  color pass through. I was just wondering like, what if you just showed us
Speaker 6:  the device, like leaking a headset at this point, it's going to look like
Speaker 6:  a VR headset.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. It's also like, not that well, blurred, it's pretty clearly just
Speaker 7:  a VR headset, but it's also, I'm looking at this right now. And
Speaker 7:  the, the cover image on the Instagram that he shared is
Speaker 7:  him standing up sort of holding one hand out in front of you,
Speaker 7:  smiling with him, with the headset on him blurred. And it's like, my dude,
Speaker 7:  like this is going to go right there with the sunscreen photo
Speaker 7:  flag. Like this is just a movable moment. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And the render, if you watch the video at one point, it zooms out of
Speaker 6:  the headset just shows you that it's a very
Speaker 6:  good, all. This was very hypey. Very cool. This is Apple's building a version
Speaker 6:  like this. That's what Alex tells us Meadows building this. It's gonna come
Speaker 6:  out later this year. But their demo is like, he's
Speaker 6:  like petting and alien. And then it's like, what if you could work in
Speaker 6:  your office? And he's just sitting in his desk, but the video is being passed
Speaker 6:  through, but then he's got virtual screens too.
Speaker 5:  Wait, wait, what, if you could work in your office and just pet an
Speaker 5:  alien?
Speaker 7:  Nope.
Speaker 6:  Now I'm going to read you the thing it says, imagine me will pull up your
Speaker 6:  perfect workstation, which is with as many screens as you want, anywhere
Speaker 6:  you go. Which is, I mean, I do imagine that from time
Speaker 6:  to time, But this is, this is
Speaker 6:  the next step of, of VR AR because no one can build
Speaker 6:  the glasses, right? Like even Google is like, we're not going to build the
Speaker 6:  glasses where we could build this a little display that shows you texts to
Speaker 6:  people talking to you. So apple and Facebook are chasing this like high end
Speaker 6:  mixed reality. We'll see. It was, I don't know they
Speaker 6:  did it.
Speaker 5:  'cause I figure both Google and Metta are
Speaker 5:  showing this stuff off because they know WWDC is coming in.
Speaker 5:  Presumably we're going to see a lot more of the apple headset. So
Speaker 5:  my question is, do you think Metta hyped
Speaker 5:  the color because the apple headset will be in black
Speaker 5:  and white,
Speaker 6:  Maybe that's out. That'd be great. If apple released a fully black and white,
Speaker 6:  like a perfect AR experience in black and white, like the glasses,
Speaker 6:  the whole thing, but it's just in black and white. Like that's up there with
Speaker 6:  like the watch has a display that isn't on all the time.
Speaker 6:  Like it doesn't have a floppy drive. Like that's like a perfect apple news.
Speaker 6:  Yes.
Speaker 5:  Very European aesthetic. Anytime you put it on, you're in a
Speaker 5:  very fancy movie. It's great.
Speaker 6:  That'd be amazing. Samsung leak of
Speaker 6:  the galaxy Z fold four, which actually looks beautiful. It does
Speaker 6:  really refine this design,
Speaker 5:  The bump, the camera bumps.
Speaker 6:  I love the camera bumps. There are three individual
Speaker 6:  camera bumps. Yeah. Perfect circles,
Speaker 5:  Perfect circles that I just, I can already feel my thumb running over
Speaker 5:  them and like having feelings. And I don't know if there'll be good or
Speaker 5:  bad feelings,
Speaker 6:  Feelings. He might
Speaker 5:  Get me having feelings as I like the texture. There's just something
Speaker 5:  about it that like, I was like, Ooh, I don't know. Just they're
Speaker 5:  too thick.
Speaker 6:  It's amazing that they're on the fourth generation of this device. And like,
Speaker 6:  there are, there are finding the design. It really
Speaker 7:  Will. And it's, it's like to your point, it's getting kind of good.
Speaker 7:  I mean, obviously like a lot to see
Speaker 7:  between here's a video from Samsung and an actual thing that does or does
Speaker 7:  not break when you try to touch it. But I mean, these things
Speaker 7:  are getting better fast. Like it, I still think of foldable phones in
Speaker 7:  my head is kind of a like silly prototype that are a long way away
Speaker 7:  from being really competitive things. And I can still count on one hand,
Speaker 7:  the number of foldable phones I've seen, like in the wild, but yeah, but
Speaker 7:  there's like, this is the, the Z fold four was one of those things where
Speaker 7:  it's like, okay, there's, there's something here. Like this is the kind of
Speaker 7:  looking like a phone.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And then if Google figures out its tablet situation, then you
Speaker 6:  unfold it and becomes a useful tablet as opposed to just a giant
Speaker 6:  foam. Right. Which is what we're going on now. And then lastly, speaking
Speaker 6:  of foldable displays, it was the display week conference this week,
Speaker 6:  obviously the talk of the town,
Speaker 5:  Honestly, one of my favorite conferences.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Display week in SIGGRAPH for my two conference, went to fair conferences.
Speaker 6:  Cause we were stuff comes out LG and Samsung, either feeling like their display
Speaker 6:  teams, like they're geared up for display big.
Speaker 6:  It y'all. So just lots of stuff. LG had an
Speaker 6:  eight inch foldable touchscreen, which fold in both directions, which
Speaker 6:  is wild. You can fold that all the way back on over
Speaker 6:  itself. Lots of rolling displays and like extended hulls, which
Speaker 6:  is really cool. So you just like pull this way out and it gets longer.
Speaker 7:  And we should just say, if you're wondering, why are these things useful
Speaker 7:  in my life? And do I need them? You're asking the wrong question. That doesn't
Speaker 7:  matter.
Speaker 6:  You're listening to the wrong show.
Speaker 7:  It's if you're saying, why do I want to pull up my phone two inches to see
Speaker 7:  notifications on it? I don't have an answer for you. I also don't care. It
Speaker 7:  looks very cool. And it makes me happy.
Speaker 6:  I'm just saying the Samsung put out a video and at one point it just put
Speaker 6:  the words wide slidable unsprayed and showed it and then
Speaker 6:  showed up being like pulled out. And I was like, this is a
Speaker 6:  rules. Like I've been, I've been walking around being like, where am I
Speaker 6:  wide slidable? Is it like, no one's been answering until
Speaker 6:  today.
Speaker 5:  Why are they though going after it in the mobile space and not in
Speaker 5:  the TV space where like the only
Speaker 5:  rollable TV we have is $10,000. And I personally would like
Speaker 5:  a rollable TV. So I don't have a giant black square
Speaker 5:  behind me in every zoom call.
Speaker 6:  And it's the Samsung is selling more frame TVs than you can shake
Speaker 6:  a stick. That thing is so popular. They're like, yeah,
Speaker 6:  people, what people want is a subscription to fine art. Not to make your
Speaker 6:  TV go away. Even though it's not their best
Speaker 6:  TV. I'm just saying wide sides, right up rise up.
Speaker 6:  Like that's the future is,
Speaker 7:  Sounds like a catchphrase from like a Disney cartoon, a really
Speaker 6:  Wide slot,
Speaker 5:  Starring goofy.
Speaker 6:  It's such a cool, you got to see it. It's like, so let me try
Speaker 6:  to describe their demo to you. So David's right. The
Speaker 6:  vertical slidable, as someone's watching like a surfing video and they
Speaker 6:  pull the up and they sh like notifications and menu
Speaker 6:  stuff there, the wide slidable demo, this is real. I swear
Speaker 6:  to God, this is real. It's like it's kids trick or
Speaker 6:  treating. It's a video of a kid. So they're all dressed in like, like costumes
Speaker 6:  and they pull it out and they reveal
Speaker 6:  a
Speaker 6:  ghost. That's not how movies work. It's like a scream costume guide out.
Speaker 6:  It goes, but it's like, it's like a guy being
Speaker 6:  like,
Speaker 14:  Ooh,
Speaker 6:  It's just such a good demo.
Speaker 5:  It looks so good that you're like, this isn't real. This
Speaker 5:  looks fake.
Speaker 6:  I can't stop watching. It's like they had to film it and
Speaker 6:  make it, and then put the words wide slidable on it. And there was meetings
Speaker 6:  for days about this. And they're like, whose kids are going to be in the
Speaker 6:  ghost video.
Speaker 5:  They paid some kids to be in that video.
Speaker 6:  I just love the idea that if you didn't have the ability to stretch your
Speaker 6:  screen out, like if they didn't do all of that engineering, you would never
Speaker 6:  know there was a ghost.
Speaker 7:  You can let all this stuff that's happening on your phone. That you've just
Speaker 7:  never even seen
Speaker 6:  In every movie
Speaker 7:  You've ever watched. There's something off to the side that you just did.
Speaker 6:  You could just wide slide your
Speaker 6:  site. It's very good. I hope these are all real. And we should all have
Speaker 6:  them other stuff we should talk about really quick. The F-150 lightning
Speaker 6:  is shipping. Andy Hawkins got to drive. One. Lots of people got to drive
Speaker 6:  one by all accounts, this product is going to be hit. That people seem, they
Speaker 6:  just can't make any of them. Like that's the
Speaker 6:  problem.
Speaker 5:  Also the tow capacity on them. Like, I love that he was
Speaker 5:  talking about how it, it actually shows you how about your battery life
Speaker 5:  is going to go down when you start towing something. But also your battery
Speaker 5:  life goes way down when you start towing something.
Speaker 5:  No long distance trips, faculty.
Speaker 6:  This is the real Texas coming out. And Alex, I'm very worried
Speaker 6:  about towing.
Speaker 5:  Let's see. Yeah. I had to tell one time and ended up calling a friend
Speaker 5:  crying because I was so upset. I was just towing like a U haul
Speaker 5:  trailer. And she's like, you just learn how to do it. You get
Speaker 5:  used to it.
Speaker 6:  Very good. You do overtime. I've only towed twice. I think
Speaker 5:  It's
Speaker 6:  Scary. It wasn't, it wasn't a big deal. And I wasn't, it was, I was talking
Speaker 6:  a very small thing. All right. Here's what we got to. Everyone's got to get
Speaker 6:  a truck, but I got to practice towing together. But no, seriously like it,
Speaker 6:  the product seems great. They just kind of make a lot of them. So that's
Speaker 6:  great. Check out that coverage on the site dish, the project,
Speaker 6:  Jenna five SIS
Speaker 6:  keeps stumbling into some
Speaker 6:  sort of disaster like reality. I would say that dish
Speaker 6:  network keeps talking about crypto in relation to its wireless
Speaker 6:  network in ways that are not necessarily connected to reality. So
Speaker 6:  they had an investor and analyst event in Vegas. And I'm just going
Speaker 6:  to read this to you. This is on the slide. Imagine if there was a wireless
Speaker 6:  carrier that embraced digital acceleration, the web
Speaker 6:  3.0 trends to reshape the list
Speaker 6:  wireless
Speaker 6:  experience, or, Or imagine
Speaker 6:  if you could turn your unused data into a real digital
Speaker 6:  currency.
Speaker 7:  What,
Speaker 6:  What,
Speaker 7:  What do any of those words
Speaker 6:  Mean? But let me continue. Imagine if you could leverage
Speaker 6:  decentralized financing to get the latest iconic devices. Imagine if there's
Speaker 6:  a wireless carrier that actually paid you back.
Speaker 6:  So I'm just going to tell you, if you have a Bitcoin do not buy an
Speaker 6:  iPhone with,
Speaker 7:  I don't know, at this point, the price of those two things is getting ever
Speaker 7:  closer together.
Speaker 6:  It's true. It just seems like a, not the right use for it. They've got to
Speaker 6:  launch this thing by June. They've got all these targets to hit. It seems
Speaker 6:  like we're going to be in the market for a lot of actual marketing. I would
Speaker 6:  remind you that right now, this network exists only in Las Vegas. The only
Speaker 6:  film that it can work with is the Motorola edge. Plus it is not
Speaker 6:  on track. I hear the Iran fanboys, their fear. They're furious. When
Speaker 6:  I talk about this open radio access networks are great. I'm excited for the
Speaker 6:  next generation of technology to enable competition
Speaker 6:  for infrastructure. I'm with
Speaker 6:  you, man. But I think we're in for a lot of
Speaker 6:  weird crypto bro market. Like they're supposed to cover 20% of the
Speaker 6:  population. I'd say it's interesting a few weeks. And what they've got is
Speaker 6:  a slide about pigs that funds with digital currency.
Speaker 7:  All I see here is dish like desperately begging to be a
Speaker 7:  medium stock. They're like, please, we love and FTEs
Speaker 7:  so much. Give us your money. Just MIMA
Speaker 7:  so hard.
Speaker 6:  Oh yeah. By the way, if you tester on the network, you get
Speaker 6:  NFTs.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, of course you do.
Speaker 6:  It's it's all, it's all very confusing.
Speaker 7:  If you don't get cell service, but you do get
Speaker 7:  an empathy.
Speaker 5:  We've just inflicted violence on Alison Johnson, our
Speaker 5:  phone and in network reporter this week,
Speaker 5:  every day, just being like, Hey, dish said something else about their new
Speaker 5:  network that's coming. You can just hear her groaning across
Speaker 5:  the country.
Speaker 6:  Well, they just need to put up a network. It's not that they bet on
Speaker 6:  the wrong. What's not, not that they better not in technology.
Speaker 6:  They promise they would build this network faster and cheaper
Speaker 6:  by using overran and having all these other vendors involved
Speaker 6:  that aren't the traditional vendors. And like in a normal context,
Speaker 6:  that'd be like the great disruptive thing to do, you know? And it would like
Speaker 6:  fail and whatever, but they're only do they're doing it like the point of
Speaker 6:  a gun because they only took over
Speaker 6:  these assets because T-Mobile was allowed to buy sprint.
Speaker 6:  And like, it's just like, this is not actually how innovation or good businesses
Speaker 6:  work. Like the government was like, what if you married you and then we'll
Speaker 6:  take your house and we'll give it to that guy. And then
Speaker 6:  that guy will build another house. It's like, what are
Speaker 6:  you doing? It's not great, but who has not
Speaker 6:  wanted to turn their, anytime it's a
Speaker 6:  rollover data. Cryptocurrency.
Speaker 5:  Do people still have rollover data?
Speaker 6:  I don't know. I don't know what that means. I keep reading it. And I'm just
Speaker 6:  like, imagine if there was a wireless carrier that embraced digital acceleration
Speaker 6:  comma, the web 3.0 trends to reshape the entire wireless
Speaker 6:  experience. What does that mean? Do you know if the wireless experiences
Speaker 6:  you take your phone out of your pocket and it connects to the internet? What
Speaker 6:  web 3.0 trends are going in the middle of that? Okay. Fine. Or imagine if
Speaker 6:  you turn your unused data into real digital currency, not that fake shit.
Speaker 6:  What does that mean?
Speaker 7:  You know, you've been trying to buy stuff with your data. You can't do that
Speaker 7:  anymore. Hey, you got real.
Speaker 6:  Oh, it just implies that you will have unused data. First of all right.
Speaker 6:  Your unused data. So I don't know if dishes away with this,
Speaker 6:  the hottest trend in wireless it's unlimited data plan.
Speaker 7:  So this is dish saying we made a network it's so bad. Please don't use it.
Speaker 7:  We will give you money.
Speaker 6:  Okay. You and dojo coins. I don't know, man.
Speaker 5:  I'm a little worried though, because this is coming from like the subsidiary,
Speaker 5:  right? It's going to be boost mobiles network. It's going to run
Speaker 6:  Super unclear.
Speaker 5:  They keep like dancing around it, but they had boost mobile CEO out
Speaker 5:  there talking about this thing. So it's a little, feels, a little
Speaker 6:  Boost coins.
Speaker 5:  Is it predatory? It feels a little predatory.
Speaker 6:  I don't know. All I know is you're going to, there's the concept
Speaker 6:  of unused data in 2022 for wireless
Speaker 6:  plans is a new look. The theme of the show is
Speaker 6:  everything old is new. Again, you know, true. Google's like wallets back
Speaker 6:  boost smell was like limited data plans.
Speaker 5:  Roll over data
Speaker 6:  For minutes or back. Yo, what a time were you alive? I can't
Speaker 6:  wait to cover this more. If you, by the way, if you're a dish network executive
Speaker 6:  and you want to come on one of our shows or the doors open to you, just get
Speaker 6:  out your, your Motorola
Speaker 6:  edge
Speaker 6:  pumps.
Speaker 5:  You have to be in Las Vegas.
Speaker 6:  I'll come to Vegas for you. All right, we've gone over. We got to wrap this
Speaker 6:  thing up. Thank you as super shy for joining the Vergecast real ones. Come
Speaker 6:  on. The verge cast. Dakota is the safe space for executives. You
Speaker 6:  want to come into this chaos. You got it. Congratulations to Sundar for coming
Speaker 6:  on the show. That's the one he wanted to be on this ship. So you have
Speaker 6:  decoder the CEO of UI path, which is a software automation company. Mike,
Speaker 6:  one of my favorite nerdy things talk about COI path. Daniel Dines was
Speaker 6:  on Dakota. We talked a lot about whether big companies hire UI path
Speaker 6:  to automate their software. And so there's a feedback loop
Speaker 6:  happening where the people who make software and making it for lots, not
Speaker 6:  people, it was just wild. Think about it's a very good Alex's
Speaker 6:  creators mini series. And the virtue has continues. We just had poopy touched
Speaker 6:  our hearts next week. It's what successful game controllers.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It's it's controllers. We talked to Ben. Heck who
Speaker 5:  like has been doing this for over 20 years.
Speaker 6:  I've done one for over 10 years. He's a fascinating
Speaker 6:  character. Absolutely. And then the site looks great this week. There's all
Speaker 6:  kinds of stuff. We have coverage of Josh, Holly trying to punish Disney.
Speaker 6:  And he's got some stuff on the Texas social media bill. We've got the aura
Speaker 6:  strap to review there's DJ mini three pro,
Speaker 6:  which I'm buying for. No reason. That's on the site. Scurry the version.
Speaker 6:  That's why it exists. It's a great, it's true site
Speaker 6:  looks great this week. That's it. Thanks Dan. Alex. Thank you. Thank you
Speaker 6:  as Sundar. One more time. That's it. Rock and
Speaker 6:  roll.
Speaker 1:  Thanks for listening to this week show and Hey, we'd love to hear from you.
Speaker 1:  Shoot us an email@vergecasttheverge.com. And if you liked the
Speaker 1:  show, share it with a friend Vergecast is a production of the verge. And
Speaker 1:  part of the Vox media podcast network today's episode was produced by
Speaker 1:  me, Liam, James, and our senior audio director. Andrew Marino, our
Speaker 1:  executive producer is Eleanor Donovan. That's it. We'll see you
Speaker 1:  next week.