# Transcript
ID: f810b5b0-4b8d-11ed-a848-7fc45b198762
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Microsoft's Surface event, Pixel 7 and Pixel Watch reviews, and Meta Connect 2022
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/5820336392754873830/-8824671305033048728/s93290-US-4795s-1665730766.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, Alex Cranz, and David Pierce discuss the announcements at Meta Connect, the new products from Microsoft's Surface event, and reviews for Google's Pixel 7 and Pixel Watch.
Meta Connect 2022: all the news on the Quest Pro
The Meta Quest Pro is a cutting-edge headset looking for an audience
Meta figured out legs for its Horizon avatars
What does Mark Zuckerberg think ‘open’ means?
Mark Zuckerberg takes a shot at Apple’s closed ecosystem
FTC files to block Meta from buying VR fitness studio Within
Google Pixel Watch review: it’s a smarter Fitbit
Google Pixel 7 and Pixel 7 Pro review: better and better
Smartwatches, not phones, are where the action is at this year
The biggest announcements from Microsoft’s Surface event
Microsoft Office will become Microsoft 365 in major brand overhaul
Microsoft’s Surface Studio 2 Plus ships with an RTX 3060 for $4,299
Microsoft’s Surface Pro 9 is the latest major gadget to ditch the headphone jack
The Surface Laptop 5 arrives with Thunderbolt 4 but no AMD options
Surface Pro 9 lets you pick between Intel or Arm 5G and new color options
Microsoft partners with Meta to bring Teams, Office, Windows, and Xbox to VR
Apple shows Windows some love with new Music, TV, and iCloud photos integration
AI-generated imagery is the new clip art as Microsoft adds DALL-E to its Office suite
New York’s weed laws mean marijuana is legal but the stores selling it aren’t yet
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we'd love to hear from you.
We are conducting a short audience survey to help plan for our future and hear from you. To participate, head to vox.com/podsurvey, and thank you!
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Disabled
Speaker 1:  Today on the Vergecast through Crew reacts to all the news from Meta. This
Speaker 1:  week we'll break down our reviews of the Pixel hardware and somehow
Speaker 1:  Microsoft makes its way into literally everything this week that's coming
Speaker 1:  up right after this
Speaker 1:  with one of the best savings rates in America. Banking with Capital One is
Speaker 1:  the easiest decision in the history of decisions. Even easier than deciding
Speaker 1:  to listen to another episode of your favorite podcast. And with no fees
Speaker 1:  or minimums on checking and savings accounts, is it even a decision get
Speaker 1:  started today? It only takes about five minutes to open an account with Capital
Speaker 1:  One and there's no minimum to open and keep your account. That's banking
Speaker 1:  Reimagined. What's in your wallet terms? Apply c capital
Speaker 1:  one.com/bank Capital one, NA Member fdic.
Speaker 3:  This episode is supported by NetApp. NetApp wants our listeners to know
Speaker 3:  that they are in love with the cloud. So in love they'd climb a mountain
Speaker 3:  or cross an ocean just to prove it, but that's not actually necessary. So
Speaker 3:  instead they just made this podcast. Ad. NetApp makes the cloud work smarter
Speaker 3:  and harder by letting you automate processes, optimize infrastructure
Speaker 3:  access, and securely manage your data no matter where it is. NetApp, For
Speaker 3:  the love of Cloud Vergecast, listeners can visit
Speaker 3:  netapp.com/verge to see how amazing the cloud can be.
Speaker 3:  Hello, I'm welcome to Vergecast. The flagship podcast of the
Speaker 3:  studio kind of smelled like weed.
Speaker 3:  You
Speaker 6:  What? You guys do it in there?
Speaker 3:  We weren't doing anything. What I said to David as we walked in
Speaker 3:  was bet that Kara Swisher was in here with her new V Media
Speaker 3:  Podcast network show on with Kara Swisher presented by New York
Speaker 3:  Magazine. Listen, when you leave the New York Times, you get to just go crazy.
Speaker 3:  That's, that's what happens. Y'all want me to plug the show? I'm gonna mention
Speaker 3:  that it smells like weed. Yeah, go subscribe to on with Kara
Speaker 3:  Swisher wherever podcast are served. Get her, get that five star review.
Speaker 3:  Don't mention the weed thing to anyone that I report to.
Speaker 1:  Yes, Dear listener, There's no evidence to back up Eli's claim.
Speaker 3:  Thanks Liam.
Speaker 3:  Opinions expressed on the Vergecast are not the Opinions Box Media
Speaker 3:  or Liam, We
Speaker 6:  Haven't even finished the intro. We've already done the disclaimer.
Speaker 3:  That's great. That's great. Hi everybody. I'm your friend Eli. David Pierce
Speaker 3:  is here. Hi. I'm sitting right next to you. Yeah, we're, This is very exciting.
Speaker 3:  We're together in New York City, which hasn't happened in quite some time.
Speaker 3:  No, and it smells like weed. I dunno if we've talked about that yet. I think
Speaker 3:  that might just be New York City. It's very possible. There's a
Speaker 3:  real chance. It's just the city wafting into the office. Alex Kranz
Speaker 3:  also New York City, but, But at her home,
Speaker 6:  I am at my home smoking weed just furiously in the middle of
Speaker 6:  this podcast so I can feel like I'm there in the office with you. Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 3:  That's great. That's good. She's got her Plex server. She's, Do you use the
Speaker 3:  Plex server to heat the weed? Are you like a, Is that a multi, multi-functional
Speaker 3:  vape situation?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, you know, it gets hot enough.
Speaker 3:  It's it possible that like firing up the Plex server is like a euphemism
Speaker 3:  for Alex smoking food and every time she talks about the Plex server, that's
Speaker 3:  actually the time thing. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  It's actually a bong. It's
Speaker 3:  Great. It's good. No, you gotta, you gotta heat it so you heat the crystals.
Speaker 3:  It's, it vaporizes the weed. It doesn't burn. It clicks
Speaker 3:  streamer in the future. All right. There's been a quite a lot
Speaker 3:  going on this week in Tech news in addition to whatever happened in
Speaker 3:  the studio earlier today, which was very chill. It's been a big week for
Speaker 3:  everybody. It's been a big week for everybody. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Everybody's having a great time
Speaker 3:  On with Kara Swisher. Now part of the V podcast network MediConnect was this
Speaker 3:  week we, you all did a whole episode about Medic Connect. We should talk
Speaker 3:  about it just a little bit. There's the VR people have Legs now. The new
Speaker 3:  Quest Pro is out. We Google reviews hit, so the Pixel Watch
Speaker 3:  review Pixel seven, Pixel seven Pro and then Microsoft
Speaker 3:  just announced everything that it had. It just was like, Is anybody
Speaker 3:  at Microsoft have something to announce? Today's the day. And they did it
Speaker 3:  like all at once. So you got new Surface Studio two
Speaker 3:  plus Surface Pro Nine. It's 10 years of Surface by
Speaker 6:  The way, crucial Microsoft Teams news. Crucial
Speaker 3:  Teams news. They rebranded Office to Microsoft 365,
Speaker 3:  which something. But Tom sat down with Panas Pane, talked about
Speaker 3:  10 years of Surface, Surface laptop, five, I mean just everything you can
Speaker 3:  think of. Sasha just walked around Redman saying, Does anybody have anything
Speaker 3:  to announce? And then Microsoft Teams came out and they said, We have
Speaker 3:  Microsoft Teams to announce
Speaker 6:  Somebody walked behind him and took notes.
Speaker 3:  That second step is very important. Sasha walks around and says, What do
Speaker 3:  you have to announce? And then they tell him and he says, How does teams
Speaker 3:  figure into this? And then they tell him and then they get to announce it.
Speaker 3:  Microsoft announced so much stuff. They announced stuff at Facebook's event.
Speaker 6:  Yeah,
Speaker 3:  It just spilled over. They're like, This is our event too.
Speaker 3:  So let's, let's quickly start with Meta Connect. We, y'all did a whole
Speaker 3:  episode on it already so we don't have to overdo it. But Quest Pro two kind
Speaker 3:  of looks incredible, also kind of looks like an expensive boondoggle.
Speaker 3:  Like I can't tell. Yeah, both of those things are true at the same time,
Speaker 3:  Right? Like it is by all accounts, very impressive. The facial expression
Speaker 3:  tracking seems to be pretty good. The pass through video seems to be pretty
Speaker 3:  good. The overwhelming question is like, what is this for? And who's going
Speaker 3:  to buy it? And there are a bunch of people on Twitter who are like, How dare
Speaker 3:  you not love the future? I can't wait to spend $1,500 on the Quest Pro.
Speaker 3:  And then it's like, what are you gonna do with it? And they're like, Well,
Speaker 3:  I'm gonna have it. Yeah. Yeah, that's, that's how I, I almost pre-ordered
Speaker 3:  one. I came so close to pre-ordering one yesterday
Speaker 3:  just
Speaker 6:  To have, So you could just play like Supernatural and, and beat Saber, but
Speaker 6:  in slightly higher resolution. But
Speaker 3:  So there's that. So we, we use our Quest two like almost
Speaker 3:  every day to do Supernatural. It's great. Love it. Yeah. Almost nothing
Speaker 3:  else happens in the VR headset so that whatever. But then you know,
Speaker 3:  you look at the white boardy thing that they did. So that controllers are
Speaker 3:  really cool. They have, the controllers now have their own sensors. So the
Speaker 3:  controllers have their own sense of where they are in a room. They do their
Speaker 3:  own inside out tracking and they have all these haptics. So Add and
Speaker 3:  Alex Heath who both got to use the thing were like, it actually feels like
Speaker 3:  you're pushing the controller against something when you write. Yeah. And
Speaker 3:  the bottoms you can screw in Little Stylist tips. You gotta love this
Speaker 3:  virtual e ink drawing tablets.
Speaker 6:  Come on. Yeah, I mean it brings me a lot of joy. Like I, I think, I think
Speaker 6:  the Quest Pro is very, very cool. But I was
Speaker 6:  thinking about this earlier this week. You know, we're coming up on the,
Speaker 6:  what was it, the 30th anniversary of the Lisa
Speaker 6:  No, 40th. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  It's
Speaker 6:  Old. The Apple Lisa, which like the Quest Pro
Speaker 6:  was super, super cool and did a lot of really cool stuff that hadn't really
Speaker 6:  been done before. And like the Quest Pro was super, super
Speaker 6:  expensive and unlike the Quest Pro ended up being buried in
Speaker 6:  like a landfill somewhere in Utah. Yeah. But I think like,
Speaker 6:  I just keep thinking about that and like how, how expensive this thing
Speaker 6:  is and how cutting edge it is and how it's probably a little too cutting
Speaker 6:  edge. It's probably not quite ready. Like the audience doesn't quite exist,
Speaker 6:  but,
Speaker 3:  But, but the, Lisa was supposed to be like a real product for Apple,
Speaker 3:  right? This was like Steve Jobs thing before the Mac and then back and forth.
Speaker 3:  And then he cruelly abandoned the Lisa took
Speaker 6:  So long on to do the Mac that he had to like get kicked off to do the Mac.
Speaker 6:  They were like, Stop, stop messing with Lisa. You suck at it. Yeah. Go do
Speaker 6:  the Mac. And you just took all the best ideas and was like, here's the Mac.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. They made it and we all smaller, cheaper one. Notably the Mac also
Speaker 3:  came from Apple. So like the lease is a disaster, but it's a disaster. It's
Speaker 3:  sort of like almost thank Apple cuz they were betting too much on it, but
Speaker 3:  then they refactored everything into the cheaper Mac and they did it right?
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Z is not positioning the Quest Pro is the
Speaker 3:  future of meta. He's like, I've taken yet another
Speaker 3:  small step to my dream of permanently surveilling you in virtual
Speaker 3:  reality. And here's the most advanced headset.
Speaker 3:  And he has given a version of the speech now several times. He gave it to
Speaker 3:  Joe Rogan, he gave it to Alex Heath. He's, I've heard him say this thing.
Speaker 3:  He's coming at it from two directions. Yeah. So one,
Speaker 3:  they are coming at sort of ar or mixed reality
Speaker 3:  from we're gonna pack all the technology into the biggest headset we can
Speaker 3:  design and build, but it'll have all the tech in it. Yeah. And that's the
Speaker 3:  Quest Pro. And then we're gonna make glasses that can actually fit your head
Speaker 3:  and shove as much into that form factor. And over time those things will
Speaker 3:  converge. So he is basically got like Ray bands or the camera over here and
Speaker 3:  he is got the Quest Pro over here that can actually do mixed reality.
Speaker 3:  And his plan is they'll meet in the middle. I don't know why he
Speaker 3:  thinks that's the right approach. Like you should just say, you know, like,
Speaker 3:  so I kind of think it is. I mean the, the reality is if you're,
Speaker 3:  if you're doing it from one side, you're also doing the other side. You
Speaker 3:  just don't ship it. Right? You just, that's the stuff that like lives in
Speaker 3:  the labs that you make for a long time and it's a, it's a big prototype and
Speaker 3:  then you make it a smaller prototype and then eventually you can ship it
Speaker 3:  inside of the thing. But the other thing Meta is trying to do is make all
Speaker 3:  of the rest of this stuff happen. So like they need stuff to be out there,
Speaker 3:  there for developers to play with. They need people to be like dreaming up
Speaker 3:  cool new apps. They need all of this stuff to happen all at once. So if they're
Speaker 3:  to sit there inside until they can fit all of this tech into RayBan
Speaker 3:  glasses, they're gonna be way too early because they won't have given anybody
Speaker 3:  anything to do or anything to work with. So I kind of feel like, but why
Speaker 3:  ship the RayBan glasses? That I think is a more fair question,
Speaker 3:  but I That's what I mean. It's like
Speaker 6:  I think the RayBan glasses make sense though because that was part of their
Speaker 6:  attempt to normalize
Speaker 3:  Cameras on your face.
Speaker 6:  The surveillance. Yeah. Like, right. Like that's the entire point of it
Speaker 6:  is like, let's normalize cameras on your face because if we want ar to work
Speaker 6:  in the future, people have to be comfortable being constantly surveilled
Speaker 6:  by everyone around them at all times.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And like I, I mean I do kind of think that that that idea of
Speaker 6:  everything meet in the middle makes sense. But also why do
Speaker 6:  I wanna spend $1,500 to be a beta tester if I'm a developer
Speaker 6:  who's, who's really excited about the future of vr that Quest Pro makes sense.
Speaker 6:  Are there enough of those developers to make the Quest Pro a
Speaker 6:  success?
Speaker 3:  No. And that's why you sign up Microsoft Yep. To throw the
Speaker 3:  HoloLens out the window and put Microsoft Teams
Speaker 3:  on the Quest Pro and then you sign up Accenture. Yeah. And you have the CEO
Speaker 3:  of Accenture in hologram at your event being like,
Speaker 3:  we're gonna do corporate training in the metaverse using Quest. Like
Speaker 3:  they are making a full on enterprise play Yeah. With
Speaker 3:  this product. But not which fine. Because this is the thing that has driven
Speaker 3:  me the most crazy about all these announcements is everybody has come out
Speaker 3:  and said, you know, Microsoft and meta believe VR is the future of work.
Speaker 3:  Like no, they don't, They absolutely do not think that Sahi Nadella
Speaker 3:  even said to Ben Thompson that like, this might be a thing that you own,
Speaker 3:  but this is not going to be like your primary device. You'll also have a
Speaker 3:  laptop, you'll also have a phone. What this is is like a pretty naked attempt
Speaker 3:  to make a thing that someone will pay for, Right? Like yeah, Google made
Speaker 3:  glass and it failed. And so Google went Google Glass Enterprise
Speaker 3:  and then they sold some people. And that's just like, that's a, that's a
Speaker 3:  thing you do when you can't get consumers to buy your device. You come up
Speaker 3:  with this really narrow work thing and try to sell it that way. And it turns
Speaker 3:  out that companies love to burn money on fancy cool new technology
Speaker 3:  that gets them in press releases from companies like Netta and Microsoft.
Speaker 3:  And so this is, this is like a, a stepping stone to get from
Speaker 3:  here to there. And I think anyone who is like, everybody thinks the
Speaker 3:  first killer app for VR is work. No.
Speaker 3:  It just isn't. And none of the companies building this think that they just
Speaker 3:  think this is a way for them to make some money while they continue to build
Speaker 3:  deeply imperfect products into ones that actually work for people. So I will
Speaker 3:  say that expensive technology happens in corporate America first is a
Speaker 3:  real pattern. Yeah. PCs happen in corporate America. Max actually
Speaker 3:  the first, they were so expensive, they were four or $5,000 a piece. Graphic
Speaker 3:  design shops are the thing that like blew the Mac up with desktop publishing.
Speaker 3:  This is like ancient history now, but it was enterprise product. There's
Speaker 3:  wrong with that. It works. My mom had, I mean
Speaker 6:  Even the Blackberry. Yeah
Speaker 3:  The Blackberry. I was saying my mom had a one of those giant Motorola bag
Speaker 3:  phones that our hospital gave her. Yes.
Speaker 6:  Those are the best.
Speaker 3:  So like there's, yeah, somewhere on the adoption curve, there's the business
Speaker 3:  has a business need and I can solve it using this tool. It's just really
Speaker 3:  unclear what beaming a Windows desktop into the
Speaker 3:  Metaverse does for you at work, which is more or less what
Speaker 3:  they have promised. And then there's this, you know, they, they, they did
Speaker 3:  the more realistic avatars which aren't yet coming to teams. Like
Speaker 3:  there's like all these bits and bobs that aren't yet connected, but
Speaker 3:  you can see Microsoft was like, screw it, we don't wanna pay for the HoloLens.
Speaker 3:  Also we fired that guy, right? Alex
Speaker 6:  Kitman.
Speaker 3:  Alex Kitman is gone for Microsoft I first series of pretty devastating reports
Speaker 3:  about his behavior and they have this like, it just didn't work, it just
Speaker 3:  didn't happen for them. And they can just divest themselves with that hardware
Speaker 3:  investment, let meta take all of the pain and get to work building
Speaker 3:  software experiences that potentially, you know, they'll put on Apple's headset
Speaker 3:  or whoever's headset once somebody wins, which is more modern Microsoft
Speaker 3:  anyway. Yeah. Like that basically tracks with who Microsoft wants to be as
Speaker 3:  a company and like they might make a surface headset someday, but like there's
Speaker 3:  no reason for Microsoft to really try super hard to be way ahead of the game
Speaker 3:  here. They're much better off being on everybody else's stuff right now than
Speaker 3:  trying to build it their own. Yeah. Yeah. Which is funny cuz the flip side
Speaker 3:  the next day they're like surface the computers that we make. Right.
Speaker 3:  Fair. What were you saying Alex?
Speaker 6:  No, I was gonna say I am putting my, my inbox at risk for
Speaker 6:  saying this, but I do think Microsoft Teams
Speaker 6:  is actually like sneakily a killer app for vr.
Speaker 3:  Oh boy. All right.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I mean, again, my inbox just pr just
Speaker 6:  flooded it as soon as I said that. Just a hundred.
Speaker 3:  Alex Crans willing to accept future of work pitches.
Speaker 3:  alex@theverge.net.
Speaker 6:  I'm so sorry.
Speaker 3:  How will you collaborate in the metaverse ai predicts
Speaker 3:  workplace collaboration? Alex dot crans@theverge.com. Yeah, she's ready.
Speaker 3:  But
Speaker 6:  I think that, I think there is a very small potential for VR to
Speaker 6:  solve, like a lot of the problems we're seeing in remote work, right? Like
Speaker 6:  remote work is, is I think about this a lot because working at the Verge,
Speaker 6:  we're a fully remote company. We have a lot of people and work has just changed
Speaker 6:  and how we communicate with each other and how we can like just turn and
Speaker 6:  talk to somebody has changed. And there is some desire to have that connectivity
Speaker 6:  again. And teams could, could
Speaker 6:  do that if they nail it. But currently it's all super creepy and weird.
Speaker 6:  And also like nobody wants to have a meeting with their boss and get fired
Speaker 6:  by like a cartoon avatar that's just like a hell scape that we're
Speaker 6:  all trying to avoid.
Speaker 3:  Yes, that's
Speaker 6:  Fine. But if Tes like figures out a way to be like a good
Speaker 6:  VR app, then maybe that could be a thing that,
Speaker 3:  Okay. I just, the the, the logical leap that you just did in
Speaker 3:  this sentence, if teams can figure out how to be a good VR app is just
Speaker 3:  enormous. Here's, I just want to just, here's a little, here's a little slice.
Speaker 6:  They're not putting any resources towards HoloLens. They got, they can put
Speaker 6:  it towards that
Speaker 3:  Now and they love teams. No, no. Let me just offer everybody a little slice
Speaker 3:  of corporate life. So sometimes we're all talking and I sense,
Speaker 3:  boy Slack makes everybody a jerk. It's happening again. It happens
Speaker 3:  every day. Slack makes you a jerk. So you should stop doing that. Yeah, you
Speaker 3:  should talk to each other like adults with your voice. And so I say something
Speaker 3:  like, let's get on a Slack call or let's hop on a Zoom or just
Speaker 3:  call me and I can hear the devastating size
Speaker 3:  from 200 miles away of people just being like, Ugh.
Speaker 3:  And all I'm asking them to do is push one button
Speaker 3:  in the app in which they are already pushing buttons and
Speaker 3:  talk with their voice instead of their fingers. And people are like,
Speaker 3:  Ugh. Every day. This happens every day. And it doesn't matter what
Speaker 3:  company you work in, it doesn't like The Verge is a great culture. People
Speaker 3:  love each other. Ugh. Right? Like I assume if you
Speaker 3:  work at a place where people like each other left, it's even a more devastating
Speaker 3:  si. Now imagine being like, all right coworker and Microsoft teams,
Speaker 3:  what I'd like to do is for you to put on your headset
Speaker 3:  so you can look at me as a cartoon so we can more
Speaker 3:  intimately connect on an emotional level. I just
Speaker 3:  don't think that's gonna go well.
Speaker 6:  I feel like there's a lot of things they have to do.
Speaker 6:  Like there's at least three steps they have to clear. But no,
Speaker 6:  at least three,
Speaker 3:  At least three seems, I cannot wait for you to get one of these headsets.
Speaker 3:  I'm getting one of these headsets. We are only meeting in VR from no one.
Speaker 3:  I love it. I will say we got a note, I can't remember if it was ADD or Alex
Speaker 3:  who got a note from a reader. It was like, the thing I miss most in my
Speaker 3:  life is a designer is whiteboards. Whiteboards are now
Speaker 3:  have always been and always will be the future of collaboration. I
Speaker 3:  am so excited about the virtual whiteboards. And I was like, yeah, I am too.
Speaker 3:  We we trash talk boards a lot and we were put soundly in
Speaker 3:  our place by that dm that that I think it was add who got that? Yeah, it
Speaker 3:  was rough times. Right. Here's the last thing I wanna talk about with Meta.
Speaker 3:  It's what you know, and we, again, whole episode with Addie, with Chris Grant
Speaker 3:  I believe Go listen to that. But here's the thing I wanna talk about on this.
Speaker 3:  Is it legs not
Speaker 6:  Like none of us on a call have legs,
Speaker 3:  Although the way that Meta has co-opted the legs from being a joke to like
Speaker 3:  being like a joke they're in on is like it's, you're not in on it yet.
Speaker 3:  I hate to tell this to you, I just, it's still a joke. This sentence that
Speaker 3:  Mark Zuckerberg said out loud that legs are probably the most requested feature
Speaker 3:  on our roadmap is just, it's not true. Beautiful. It's not true.
Speaker 3:  Like it's just the most requested feature on the roadmap is like, don't make
Speaker 3:  me nauseous better vr, it's like
Speaker 3:  cool things. Okay, well wait, keep going. What did you wanna talk about?
Speaker 3:  Okay, so what I wanna talk about is a Zuck took this shot in the keynote
Speaker 3:  at Apple and again you can tell he is got these, like these, these
Speaker 3:  speeches, these fragments of speeches that he's been rehearsing. So he did
Speaker 3:  it in the keynote, he did it with Alex. I've heard him say this stuff like
Speaker 3:  this before or he is like in the history of computing that I'm aware of,
Speaker 3:  sometimes the open system wins and sometimes the closed system wins. And
Speaker 3:  the only history of computing that he's talking about is mobile and PCs,
Speaker 3:  which to be fair are the only errors of computing that we have all lived
Speaker 3:  through sometimes I remember the Uck is about my agent terrifies me
Speaker 3:  and what he means is in PCs quote, Open one
Speaker 3:  Microsoft one and there are lots of PC vendors. And then in mobile,
Speaker 3:  and this is wildly up for debate, he means a closed one because Apple's a
Speaker 3:  closed ecosystem. We don't apparently mention Android in this
Speaker 3:  conversation. The world's most dominant operating system
Speaker 3:  does not count. And Z's interpretation of open V closed, right? Because
Speaker 6:  We use iPhones in America. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  Sure. But it's like the Android is more popular. I don't, I don't know
Speaker 3:  what he means by winning and losing whatever I, I just like
Speaker 3:  the Quest is an iPhone, right? Like at best it
Speaker 3:  allows some sideline,
Speaker 6:  Well technically it's an Android phone. Well
Speaker 3:  Right, It runs Android and it allows side loading. You put other stores on
Speaker 3:  it. Yeah. But like the operating system is made by Meta. The hardware
Speaker 3:  is made by meta. Most of the applications are made by companies that
Speaker 3:  have been bought by Meta. What do you, what are you talking about? Yeah,
Speaker 3:  so Add wrote a great piece that was like, what do you mean by open? And what
Speaker 3:  he basically means by Open is like many app developers participate in our
Speaker 3:  platform and I just, I'm I'm curious what you two think about it cuz a,
Speaker 3:  I don't even know that Open has lost in this generation of mobile
Speaker 3:  cuz Android exists and there are lots of, there are lots of
Speaker 3:  forks of Android out in the world running on phones in China, for example,
Speaker 3:  forked Android with no Google involved running all over the place. There
Speaker 3:  are lots of hardware vendors. Samsung obviously dominates and it's the most
Speaker 3:  popular operating system in the world. And in the previous era it's like
Speaker 3:  sure there are lots of PC makers but I mean they called it Wintel
Speaker 3:  and the government sued them for being a monopoly. Yeah. It's a bull strategy
Speaker 3:  to hold up the nineties arrow Microsoft as like your bastion of openness.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, it's, it's, I just kind of don't get what the argument is. I
Speaker 3:  forgot. And like I said, he's been saying it in different forms around the
Speaker 3:  same shape for a while now. He,
Speaker 6:  I think he's trying to like hope nobody notices that they,
Speaker 6:  that Facebook, excuse me, Meta still makes the hardware
Speaker 6:  meta is still in control regardless of the software,
Speaker 6:  regardless of the developers. They're still in control. It's not like
Speaker 6:  when when Microsoft did its VR attempt what in 20 17, 20 18
Speaker 6:  and they're like, everybody can do headsets and everybody made that. There
Speaker 6:  was the Ace or headset and the HP headset and then we never talked about
Speaker 6:  it again. Yeah. Like that's not happening at meta. Meta is making the
Speaker 6:  headsets. That's it. And if they control, if you control the hardware
Speaker 6:  and you control the primary app store, how can you call yourself an
Speaker 6:  open ecosystem?
Speaker 3:  I don't think it's, it's the primary app stores been like Microsoft would
Speaker 3:  love to control the primary app store on Windows. Yeah. Like it's there.
Speaker 3:  They can, no one uses it. You know, like Apple would love to control the
Speaker 3:  Mac app store. No one uses it. Like I, it's to
Speaker 3:  me it's is the operating system and the hardware are the independent of each
Speaker 3:  other. Then you can, you start to begin to claim that things are open,
Speaker 3:  right? Anyone can come build some hardware that runs this software. You can
Speaker 3:  compete as a great hardware vendor or you can on the flip side, anybody can
Speaker 3:  build an operating system that runs on any piece of hardware, which is less
Speaker 3:  likely. But you know, I think in the Windows ecosystem you can just run Linux.
Speaker 3:  I think in so many ways, listening to Mark Zuckerberg talk about
Speaker 3:  a lot of this stuff is like you have to assume his entire brain is in like
Speaker 3:  2035 and is in a world where like the metaverse is
Speaker 3:  everything he imagined. And I think he does genuinely imagine a
Speaker 3:  like broad sort of standards based thing that works more like
Speaker 3:  the open web than like the app store, right? Cause I think when he talks
Speaker 3:  about open versus clothes, like very specifically where that has bit him
Speaker 3:  is like Apple on. I think the, the way adding phrase it, which I really liked
Speaker 3:  was basically like the, the extent to which they dictate the rules of the
Speaker 3:  platform. And to the extent that there are lots of developers all over
Speaker 3:  the world building stuff for Apple platforms. It's wildly open in that way.
Speaker 3:  But Apple is like extremely in control of absolutely everything
Speaker 3:  about the platform and can do whatever it wants to you for basically any
Speaker 3:  reason at any time. And even if you don't run afoul of those rules, you know
Speaker 3:  they exist and you know that they can come crashing down upon you at any
Speaker 3:  time. So here's what he said specifically. I strongly believe that an open
Speaker 3:  interoperable metaverse built by many different developers and companies
Speaker 3:  is going to be better for everyone. Sure. I believe him when he says that.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  But I don't believe that he's doing
Speaker 3:  That. I would say there's nothing in his company's history that would lead
Speaker 3:  me to believe he'll do that. But I think I believe him when he says that.
Speaker 3:  Sure.
Speaker 6:  Like isn't he going around and buying up every single super successful
Speaker 6:  VR company right now?
Speaker 3:  And also Facebook exists. Like if you believe this stuff, Facebook
Speaker 3:  would be different. Like
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And open ecosystem will do it, but he's not doing that. He's
Speaker 6:  aggressively against it.
Speaker 3:  I'm just deeply confused. I think like what he means is
Speaker 3:  the only competition he sees on the horizon is Apple, which is also making
Speaker 3:  a headset very much like the Quest press. Yes. Right. We're
Speaker 3:  anticipating that. We'll see it next year.
Speaker 6:  Same pricing
Speaker 3:  VR headset with cameras on the outside. It'll do mixed reality with video
Speaker 3:  passer. Alex Heath has reported on that at the information and at the Verge
Speaker 3:  many times. Great. So then he's gonna have a competitor and what Apple is
Speaker 3:  gonna sell to you is Apple. Apple, Right. A tightly
Speaker 3:  defined experience that other people can participate in in Apple's terms.
Speaker 3:  Right. So Z is obviously just trying to differentiate that. I'm just saying
Speaker 3:  I don't, nothing about what he has today is actually differentiated from
Speaker 3:  that. Agreed. Agreed. And that's what I mean by you. Like, you have to assume
Speaker 3:  Mark lives in 2035. Cause like I really think when he looks at the metaverse,
Speaker 3:  he sees a totally different thing than actually exists in the world. And
Speaker 3:  it's like, it's why he talks about everything in these like crazy 10 year
Speaker 3:  things. It's why when you say like, who are you gonna sell this to? He's
Speaker 3:  basically like, ah, I don't give a shit. Yeah. Like we're gonna, he really
Speaker 3:  is at this point. Like we just gotta keep doing it. You know, like Yeah.
Speaker 3:  He's just like, I'm gonna burn so much money and that it's gonna be amazing.
Speaker 3:  And I, I like, I think he is, he is already at the end of that road
Speaker 3:  when he talks about some of this stuff and like, but I agree. I mean the,
Speaker 3:  the quest as it exists is price is precisely
Speaker 3:  the Apple model of how this stuff should work. Is Apple bought all of the
Speaker 3:  best developers. It's an iPhone with like a medium amount of side boating.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Right? Like, not even like a lot of like a medium amount of side boating.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. The thing that kills me, and I've was thinking about this because you
Speaker 3:  know, this was like another prerecorded keynote and we, we've done, we just
Speaker 3:  had the Google event which was in person and the Apple event is like this
Speaker 3:  hybrid where you like, David watched the video and like whatever,
Speaker 3:  You know, it's like, it's kind of like fine with phones. I don't even think
Speaker 3:  it's fine with phones to like see the stuff on video. I think you have to
Speaker 3:  hold and perceive these objects. But like we've been reviewing a lot of phones
Speaker 3:  lately and we're like trying to tell people about 120 hertz variable refresh
Speaker 3:  rate displays. And no one can tell you what that looks like. Right. You can't
Speaker 3:  even watch a video about it. It's even harder with this VR stuff.
Speaker 3:  Like to have the experience of whatever the Quest Pro is
Speaker 3:  compressed and I sent over the internet and displayed on somebody's like
Speaker 3:  crappy uncalibrated 30 hertz display. Like
Speaker 3:  there's something about these, this generation of products that's coming
Speaker 3:  up where people, this, this cynicism is amplified
Speaker 3:  by how we perceive them, right? It's like the internet, like looking at
Speaker 3:  pictures, JPEGs on the web do not actually communicate anything about these
Speaker 3:  products. Right. And like I, that's like, I think gonna be the hardest turn
Speaker 3:  for everyone. It's gonna be the hardest turn when we review it. It's gonna
Speaker 3:  be the hardest turn we write about it. It's gonna be the hardest turn is
Speaker 3:  more and more companies launch the stuff because there's just nothing.
Speaker 6:  Unless we're already wearing our VR
Speaker 6:  and watching the keynotes.
Speaker 3:  Most we're watching brilliant Pixelated four ADP display
Speaker 3:  of our Quest two, I think it's seven 20 with legs.
Speaker 3:  With legs could there's a a go find it in the video.
Speaker 3:  We didn't like whatever. There's a moment where they're saying they're in
Speaker 3:  the metaverse, right? And it's like Zuck and it's like PM and he is like,
Speaker 3:  we've done legs. And they have hosted this in like a
Speaker 3:  virtual, it looks like a basketball court. It was like really hard to understand
Speaker 3:  what kind of thing they were in cuz it had bleachers.
Speaker 3:  Did you see the bleachers? I missed the bleachers. So they were like talking
Speaker 3:  to each other like in Horizon and they were like, here's all the stuff we're
Speaker 3:  doing.
Speaker 6:  And there's like people sitting around in bleachers watching them
Speaker 3:  And they, they clearly, it's like who knows if they were live or if they
Speaker 3:  were programmed, whatever. But the little avatars had the ability to like
Speaker 3:  throw confetti and they were all jumping and throwing the conf. And so like,
Speaker 3:  Mark is there, but they didn't have legs. They didn't have legs. So Mark,
Speaker 3:  the ceo, the billionaire god king CEO of MEA
Speaker 3:  is like, look at my legs. And then everyone in the crowd is like throwing
Speaker 3:  confetti and jumping and their avatars are cut off and then there's just
Speaker 3:  like a black space in a bar underneath it. And the whole thing is just like
Speaker 3:  vertically jumping like an old Atari game. What if this is the Metaverse
Speaker 3:  business model, you get to pay for legs. And they keep throwing this
Speaker 3:  confetti and I was like, everyone's just go watch this moment. It is
Speaker 3:  truly one of the most bizarre tech keynote moments
Speaker 3:  you have ever seen Mark Virtual, Mark Zuckerberg
Speaker 3:  trying out his new legs while an audience of cartoons
Speaker 3:  just vertically moves up and down throwing confetti on him.
Speaker 3:  It's great. It's, I was like, I like all my meetings to have that
Speaker 3:  and like, you know, we're all remote. So like, I literally was at home watching
Speaker 3:  this Zoom by myself or watching this on the TV by myself and I was like,
Speaker 3:  is anybody else seeing this? Like no one,
Speaker 3:  like you're just like, this is the loneliest I've ever felt
Speaker 6:  Again, you could have been in VR and slowly turned your
Speaker 6:  cartoon
Speaker 3:  We're doing the next Verge Cast. In in the, in the
Speaker 3:  Metaverse we're the whole time. This was supposed to be a quick
Speaker 3:  conversation about the Metaverse and look at what happened to us. This is
Speaker 3:  what the weed smell it does to you. We're gonna take a quick break. We come
Speaker 3:  back, we had talk about the Pixel stuff. We went back.
Speaker 7:  Any job at Amazon can turn into a high paying career for
Speaker 7:  employees looking for security. Today Amazon offers good pay and healthcare
Speaker 7:  on day one. New parents also get up to 20 weeks of fully paid
Speaker 7:  leave. So they have the flexibility to spend time with family while making
Speaker 7:  a living for opportunity. Tomorrow Amazon is investing
Speaker 7:  1.2 billion into free technical training that's available to over
Speaker 7:  750,000 associates across the country. With
Speaker 7:  these programs, hourly employees have the opportunity to move into higher
Speaker 7:  paying highly skilled jobs in fields like software engineering and
Speaker 7:  robotics. Learn more@aboutamazon.com
Speaker 8:  One day. The Metaverse will help students learn about the rings of Saturn,
Speaker 8:  allowing them to get up close to the planets and gain a deeper understanding
Speaker 8:  of how our solar system works. The Metaverse may be virtual but the impact
Speaker 8:  will be real. Learn more at meta.com/metaverse impact.
Speaker 3:  Okay, we're back. It's review season. This is great. So we reviewed the
Speaker 3:  Pixel watch, we reviewed the Pixel seven and the Pixel seven Pro. What do
Speaker 3:  you think? I, Well let's start with the watch because I think as our reviews
Speaker 3:  confirmed, the watches substantially more interesting than the phones this
Speaker 3:  year. Just in terms of like new stuff happening. My takeaway, these
Speaker 3:  reviews really great and everyone should read it, but indeed I was kind of
Speaker 3:  unimpressed in a way that was a little bit of a bummer. Like Google
Speaker 3:  first ever smart watch, they like, they made a nice thing, which I think
Speaker 3:  was a big win. Yeah. And by all accounts it is a nice thing. It's
Speaker 3:  a little small. The, the bezels are a little big but my experience has been
Speaker 3:  the same as vs. Where like in actual use you don't really notice the Bezzle.
Speaker 3:  They did a good job with the ui, the band thing is nifty, but it's like I
Speaker 3:  wanted Google to like really get one piece of this.
Speaker 3:  Right. Right. And it was like there was a, this is their first one. It was
Speaker 3:  clearly not gonna you mean
Speaker 6:  Right? Or like just nail it like,
Speaker 3:  Like crush it. Yeah. Like I, I think what what Google really needed to do
Speaker 3:  was like have one thing that it was like a plus job Google
Speaker 3:  and I assumed that would be the health stuff because they have Fitbit. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  They like talked to be game about all the sensors they were putting into
Speaker 3:  this and it was like, okay, if this thing was a kick ass fitness tracker
Speaker 3:  and a pretty good everything else, that's like an awesome start from Google.
Speaker 3:  They're gonna be in this for real. Yeah. And instead it seems like Google
Speaker 3:  did pretty well on everything without nailing
Speaker 3:  anything. Yeah. And that kind of left me cold. Yeah. They didn't push the
Speaker 3:  on it felt
Speaker 6:  Very Pixel. It
Speaker 3:  Was very Pixel. That's fair. Well no, but the Pixel, you know,
Speaker 3:  pushes the envelope at least on photography every other year or so. Right.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. That's that's true. That's true.
Speaker 3:  And Pixel drama aside, like the, the thing of the
Speaker 3:  Pixel is not designed to win. You know, it's like it's a hedge against Samsung
Speaker 3:  and it's like a showcase for Google to be googley. Yeah. You know, every
Speaker 3:  30 days the pixel just kills one feature automatically.
Speaker 3:  It just takes one thing away. That's horrible.
Speaker 6:  If you want 'em to live, you have to start buying pixels.
Speaker 3:  Exactly. But but I see what you're saying about the watch. Like they made
Speaker 3:  an Apple watch for Android users but like an Apple watch
Speaker 3:  for for Android users. Yeah. Yes. And like the Google
Speaker 3:  assistant thing is a big win. My overwhelming experience is the Google assistant
Speaker 3:  is better than Siri at absolutely everything. Yeah. I, I dunno if this has
Speaker 3:  been your experience recently, but Siri is worse than ever for me. All of
Speaker 3:  a sudden like it's so bad,
Speaker 6:  So stupid.
Speaker 3:  It's crazy. And I get the thing where I'm just like,
Speaker 6:  Just
Speaker 3:  Thunderously done. I do like a basic reminder and it does the thing where
Speaker 3:  it's like one moment still thinking, Yeah, I'm sorry please try again. And
Speaker 3:  I'm like, I'm on wifi dude. Like what's the problem here? But anyway,
Speaker 3:  Google assistant is way better than Siri at all of the things you would wanted
Speaker 3:  to do on a smart watch. And that seemed to be v's experience too. Like the
Speaker 3:  mic is pretty good, the speakers are pretty good. Outside of that it just
Speaker 3:  doesn't feel like Google nailed anything here. Like the Fitbit stuff is good,
Speaker 3:  but missing some of the best Fitbit things like it doesn't have automatic
Speaker 3:  workout detection and at the very least this thing should have been like
Speaker 3:  the mega Fitbit. Yeah. Right. Yeah. Like it's more expensive, it's more impressive.
Speaker 3:  It's clearly where Fitbit is headed is this device which
Speaker 3:  V wrote, I think she reviewed the sense too and was basically like Google
Speaker 3:  is going to eat this thing to death with devices called Pixel. Yeah. And
Speaker 3:  I think that's right. But in order to do that, this needed to be, if nothing
Speaker 3:  else, like a truly, truly kick ass Fitbit and it gets, it gets
Speaker 3:  almost there and it does all the things it does pretty well. But there were
Speaker 3:  just a bunch of like little places it fell down. It like ended a couple of
Speaker 3:  her workouts early and it didn't do the workout detection and just little
Speaker 3:  things that it's like they knew they had to get this right. Like Rick Olo
Speaker 3:  told me, he was like, we know the thing we have to do if we want to get to
Speaker 3:  this like magical wrist computer smartwatch future, we have to get fitness.
Speaker 3:  Right. And that's why people will buy it today. And they'd like almost but
Speaker 3:  not quite. Got there. The thing that got me in, in vis review and about the
Speaker 3:  Pixel watch in general is it doesn't know when you're washing your hands,
Speaker 3:  which is not a useful feature of the Apple watch at this point. Like they
Speaker 3:  rolled out hand washing detection when it was useful in
Speaker 3:  early 2020. Yeah. When everyone was still like afraid to
Speaker 6:  Remind them already not to be
Speaker 3:  Disgusting. Yeah. People are like windexing their cardboard boxes. Do you
Speaker 3:  guys still wash your hands specifically by the way? Cause that is one I do
Speaker 3:  wash my hands. I'm not doing it for 20 seconds. Are you kidding me? That's
Speaker 3:  who has, you're still singing Happy Birthday twice. Like what are you doing?
Speaker 3:  You you sing the chorus of Mr. Brightside. That's what it's chorus of Mr.
Speaker 3:  Brightside. David's still like, and David's like, I'm a
Speaker 3:  sophomore in college and I'm gonna sing with, it's perpetually
Speaker 3:  3m. David has come home from the bar every time he washes his hand.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Man. Like, you know, I'm like wearing, I'm trying to be careful all
Speaker 3:  this stuff, but like, I'm like, you know what, like a little bit of soap
Speaker 3:  we're good, right? Like Yeah. But like at least the Apple
Speaker 3:  Watch is like, you know, 75%. It's like I I think
Speaker 3:  you're washing your hands. Yeah. Like yeah the Pixel watch, you have to
Speaker 3:  tell it that you're washing your hands and I'm like, this guarantees that
Speaker 3:  no one will ever use this feature. Correct. And Google is like the
Speaker 3:  most powerful AI company on planet Earth and it hasn't figured out are
Speaker 3:  is this watch on a wrist connected to hands that are being watched.
Speaker 3:  And that to me is just like a, it's just a miss. They didn't finish the feature
Speaker 3:  all the way. Yeah. And I that well
Speaker 6:  How would they have known? Like I don't wanna give picks,
Speaker 6:  I don't wanna give Google any credit here because they're one of the largest
Speaker 6:  richest companies in the world. They should be able to do this and figure
Speaker 6:  it out and nail it on the first try. But this is also like the first try.
Speaker 6:  And they're not, they're used to a lot of ways that humans interact with
Speaker 6:  computers, but computer risk computers is, is a totally new
Speaker 6:  thing for them. As evidenced by where os one and two,
Speaker 6:  like they've sucked at it for a long time and they've made no effort. Now
Speaker 6:  they're like, okay, we've gotta make our effort.
Speaker 3:  Well no, they've been chasing after this for like five or six years. They
Speaker 3:  would so peace about it. This is why you buy Fitbit. Like the, the, the answer
Speaker 3:  to your question is they screwed it up. So they had to spend billions of
Speaker 3:  dollars on Fitbit. Right. And to be fair, it does seem like, like the, the
Speaker 3:  leap from what you get with Google fit to what you get with Fitbit, thus
Speaker 3:  the Pixel watch is massive. So like in that sense, Yeah, kudos
Speaker 3:  that did the thing. But I mean I, and I take your point Alex,
Speaker 3:  that like a year of people wearing these things will give Google a lot of
Speaker 3:  data about when they're doing things like washing their hands that might
Speaker 3:  turn out to be useful for V2 of this. But again, the hand washing thing to
Speaker 3:  me is not important because no robot is gonna tell me to wash my hands
Speaker 3:  for 20 seconds. Like again, I'm in and outta there like I believe the soap
Speaker 3:  works. You know what I'm saying? You
Speaker 6:  Just like run your hand under it real fast.
Speaker 3:  I'm like a little kid, I go in there, I turn on the water and make sure my
Speaker 3:  wife heard it. I turn off the water, I'm out. You know, like
Speaker 3:  you should wash your hands correctly.
Speaker 6:  No one shaked you.
Speaker 3:  It's how little kids do it. You know, I don't care what they ask. Siri
Speaker 3:  can't force me to do anything, but they know this is the
Speaker 3:  bar. That's what I mean. If you're gonna have this feature and you know your
Speaker 3:  competition is Apple and it's not even just Apple. This is the thing where
Speaker 3:  if it's good enough, people might leave the iPhone. Right? You make you
Speaker 3:  make a risk computer that's for the,
Speaker 6:  It's not for the hand wash.
Speaker 3:  Right. And so then you gotta, you gotta look at every feature of this thing
Speaker 3:  and say, is it that much better than the only
Speaker 3:  competition? That's real. Cuz they're not trying to take market share away
Speaker 3:  from Samsung. They're trying to build a compelling wearable that lots
Speaker 3:  of people will wear because they think this is the future of ambient computing
Speaker 3:  is to have a compute on your body. And then you take share away from Apple
Speaker 3:  all, all these things and they're like, okay, ship the hand washing
Speaker 3:  feature that you have to tell it count to 20. So it's not even a hand
Speaker 3:  washing feature, it's just a 22nd timer that you can enable with a tap. Right?
Speaker 3:  And it's like, that's obviously not good enough. Like it obviously
Speaker 3:  isn't a complete idea. Like just don't like take it out. Actually
Speaker 3:  don't ship halfway ideas, ship only the things that are so much
Speaker 3:  better that people are like, Maybe I should give up my iPhone because
Speaker 3:  this thing looks so cool and I don't think anybody's looking at this thing
Speaker 3:  and thinking that looks so cool. I wanna give up my iPhone. Especially not
Speaker 3:  in a world where the Apple Watch ultra exists.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Like where where's the disconnect coming at at Google though? Because
Speaker 6:  Rick O was like, Yes, this is the future, we're doing this and then like
Speaker 6:  apparently the the PM or whoever was in charge was like, we're doing what,
Speaker 6:  like we're do, we're doing a nice Apple Watch
Speaker 6:  knockoff, we're doing the Android version of an Apple Watch series for So
Speaker 6:  like why did it, like why
Speaker 3:  It took a long time, right? I mean this thing was basically delayed. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  It took a long
Speaker 3:  Months year at least. Yeah. I mean yeah it, it is an interesting counterfactual
Speaker 3:  to know like what would've happened if the Fitbit acquisition had gone through
Speaker 3:  much quicker. Because at least the story Google has told me is basically
Speaker 3:  like we wanted do this thing. We knew we couldn't do it properly until we
Speaker 3:  got Fitbit and then the Fitbit thing took forever. And I think Google correctly
Speaker 3:  surmised that every day they didn't launch a smart watch was a problem. So
Speaker 3:  I think I definitely got the sense that this was like not a rush job, but
Speaker 3:  like there was a, there was a day circled on the calendar a long time ago
Speaker 3:  that it was like, if we miss this, it's a problem. And that day was probably
Speaker 3:  in like 2020 and now here we are. But I think, I mean
Speaker 3:  to me it's like the, the question of what is Google trying to do with this,
Speaker 3:  I think is part of what's super interesting. Cuz on the one hand it's, I
Speaker 3:  think they are trying to take away from Samsung. I I I think Rick Oslo's
Speaker 3:  remit is to get market share in the phone space. And the easiest
Speaker 3:  way for them to do that is to steal share from Samsung. Like, I don't know
Speaker 3:  that Sundar Percha is that worried about it, but like Rick Olo definitely
Speaker 3:  is. Yeah. They also wanna take away from the iPhone. They
Speaker 3:  also wanna do the like big broad ambient computing vision, which means
Speaker 3:  plugging into everything else that Google does. And they want to make sure
Speaker 3:  that they have a thing that will keep people who currently use Android phones
Speaker 3:  from switching to an iPhone in order to get an Apple watch. And so they're,
Speaker 3:  they're playing with all these things in the bar for each one of them is
Speaker 3:  very different. And it just feels like trying to do that, trying to satisfy
Speaker 3:  all of those things on your first try was just always gonna be very
Speaker 3:  hard. Yeah. So for that reason I'm sympathetic, the stuff I'm less sympathetic
Speaker 3:  to is like not getting the Fitbit stuff right. Because they knew they needed
Speaker 3:  to and they got it fine but not good enough. The battery life is the one
Speaker 3:  that really kills me. Yeah. Like if you wanna come out and instantly have
Speaker 3:  a move in the smart watch market, it's the battery. Yeah. Like that's just
Speaker 3:  it. And Fitbit has done good battery stuff over time and if I'm Google I
Speaker 3:  would've stripped the thing way down and basically been like, it's a Fitbit
Speaker 3:  and it's Google assistant, it does nothing else and it lasts for three days.
Speaker 3:  Like what's up? And I think I genuinely think that would've done something
Speaker 3:  and said instead it like barely lasts a day.
Speaker 3:  If you like Visa takeaway was basically if you really, really baby it, it'll
Speaker 3:  last a day. But that's if you don't use it very much and you don't have
Speaker 3:  the always on display on, and I mean that matches the first
Speaker 3:  gen I, the first gen Apple watch. Yeah. That was seven years ago. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  You don't get to do like, you don't get to play by 2015 rules and 2022. Even
Speaker 3:  if this is your first smartwatch what like it is and it
Speaker 6:  Yeah. She lost like what, 25% of her battery in an hour
Speaker 6:  long run. Yeah. With just GPS on it. That's, that's it. I mean GPS does suck
Speaker 6:  a lot of battery, but that should not be a thing in 2022 for
Speaker 6:  a big Apple competitor. You shouldn't have to worry about losing a quarter
Speaker 6:  of your battery just because you are making the awful choice to run.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Kudos to all people who run
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Runnings. Exactly. I love you. You. But I like the, I think it was
Speaker 3:  v who told me that like one of her theories is like the marathon test. Like
Speaker 3:  could I run a marathon with this and it wouldn't die and this would die.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. And it fails the marathon test. Yeah. I don't know how fast v runs
Speaker 3:  marathons, but I I would not make it with with this thing through a marathon.
Speaker 3:  One of my favorite to trends is the people who are trying to run a marathon
Speaker 3:  at the pace of the world record that was just set, which is you have to basically
Speaker 3:  run it 13 or 14 miles an hour. Dead dead sprint. Yeah. And like they're like,
Speaker 3:  you did it for two hours and people are like 30 seconds of falling down.
Speaker 3:  Like they treadmill ramps all the way up and they fall down. It's great.
Speaker 3:  That's my, that's my marathon test. Talk about the Pixel seven. Pixel seven
Speaker 3:  pro. They are very iterative. I mean they
Speaker 3:  fix some things. It seems like they don't get as hot. The cameras are ever
Speaker 3:  so slightly improved. The fingerprint seems to work better, which is a win.
Speaker 3:  She, Alison said it was a beat faster in the review. I'll take it so
Speaker 3:  it's not slow, but it's a beat faster. And they added face on lock
Speaker 3:  on to you. Right? I mean I, I'm looking into photo, I mean obviously what
Speaker 3:  do I look at? I look at the photos and I'm just blown away by how
Speaker 3:  much Google is doing with these cameras now. Especially the, the Zoom stuff
Speaker 3:  they're doing, which is not as good as Samsung and some of our sample shots.
Speaker 3:  But Samsung is a dedicated lens. This is like Google's adding
Speaker 3:  the ultra wide, the main camera, the Zoom, and they're getting a really
Speaker 3:  passable super zoom, but it, I still just scares me. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  She has Allison put a shot in here comparing the pixel seven pros
Speaker 3:  10 x crop mode to the 10 x dedicated zoom on the
Speaker 3:  S 22 Ultra. And the S 22 ultra, like you said is, is definitely better. It's
Speaker 3:  a, it's dedicated glass. And Allison even says in the review like there's
Speaker 3:  only so much you can do by cropping pixels. Like that just is true. It looks
Speaker 3:  so much better than I expected it to. Oh yeah. On like it's really,
Speaker 3:  really, this wasn't an image slider and you weren't directly comparing the
Speaker 3:  two. You'd be like, Oh that's great. Yeah. It's a smidge dark. Which actually
Speaker 3:  makes sense given Yeah. What it is. But it looks really good and 10
Speaker 3:  x I mean I'm used to like the five x pictures coming outta phones looking
Speaker 3:  borderline unusable and this is like a perfectly functional photo.
Speaker 3:  It's really impressed. It does bring up fascinating philosophical. It's
Speaker 6:  Like a photo you could send to your friends and family Yeah. And not get
Speaker 6:  jumped. Totally.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. But again, it's like they're merging three cameras into one
Speaker 3:  multiple frames at some point you're just holding your phone up to reality
Speaker 3:  like in AI prompt and being like, tell me what you think the sign
Speaker 3:  looks like. I'm just like fascinated by this. Like it Google
Speaker 3:  has pushed so far beyond the what is a photo debate
Speaker 3:  with, with particularly the Zoom stuff and some of the video stuff they're
Speaker 3:  doing that. Yeah. I don't know. Like I, we probably just need to call Google
Speaker 3:  and be like, give us the pixel team again. Let's, let's smoke some weed in
Speaker 3:  the studio and really get into it. Yeah, we should do that cuz it's not you're,
Speaker 3:  you're right. They're way beyond like what kinds of nifty stuff can we do
Speaker 3:  with your pixels? And they've gone into, we're gonna take all these pixels,
Speaker 3:  we're gonna feed them into our neural network and it's gonna spit out
Speaker 3:  what it thinks it's seeing. And it's like, there there is a, there is a black
Speaker 3:  box step in there. Yeah. That even like, even pixel binning is like
Speaker 3:  a little bit of black magic, but it's at least it is math with pixels.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. This is like math with pixels, underpants. No, Step two,
Speaker 3:  step three photo. Yeah. It's nuts, right? You're taking multiple exposures
Speaker 3:  off on camera, you're taking multiple exposures off another camera and a
Speaker 3:  different focal length and then you're producing a assume image at yet
Speaker 3:  in third and it's like, I don't know what's going on. Yeah. I don't know
Speaker 3:  what's going on. That's good though. It looks amazing. But
Speaker 3:  I'm dying to have some more detail on how this works. Just cuz you
Speaker 3:  know, they say when companies claim they're gonna do this kind of stuff.
Speaker 3:  There's a part of me when Mark Zuckerberg shows off is ultra
Speaker 3:  realistic and extremely well moisturized,
Speaker 3:  high resolution avatar. That shit's Dewey.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. You're like, that's great. This is a demo. Like whatever. Like, and
Speaker 3:  he tells you how complicated Google announces this stuff and they say they're
Speaker 3:  gonna do all this stuff when you see the photo, then that's when all the,
Speaker 3:  what is a photo? Like they, we actually, they shipped the phone.
Speaker 3:  Allison has it, we've taken a lot of pictures with it. Oh, it works.
Speaker 3:  And there's a step in there where they are recreating whatever
Speaker 3:  the image is that is just utterly fascinating to me. Well, and the,
Speaker 3:  the photo and blur feature is, is an even more like direct version
Speaker 3:  of tape. Right? You're like, it, I took a photo and it's like, oh, here's
Speaker 3:  a different photo here. I mean, it's literally enhanced button.
Speaker 3:  Right.
Speaker 6:  It's like, so it's my favorite part of the review on a
Speaker 3:  Slide that photo ular slider. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  I just, I spent, I'm, I'm like, I just scroll down to look at it again and
Speaker 6:  I'm just like, we look at this guy, he's so unfocused. His hair is
Speaker 6:  so detailed blur. It's great.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. But like the computer just made up the detail.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Like, and I think we, we've seen that sometimes with Adobe
Speaker 6:  too.
Speaker 3:  Oh, David zoomed way in on this thing. I'm watching, I'm watching him do
Speaker 3:  the slider pixel by pixel. There's just something about his
Speaker 3:  eye that doesn't look human. Yeah. Because a computer
Speaker 3:  made it up, right? Yeah. That's the thing, right? It looks drawn like a,
Speaker 3:  it looks better. Like it clearly improves the photo in terms of like, it
Speaker 3:  looks more like what a photo should look like. But as I look at this, he
Speaker 3:  looks less like a person in the processed photo. This is a
Speaker 3:  shot of basically, I think it's Novakovic from a bunch of years ago right
Speaker 3:  after he hit a tennis shot and it's like a profile shot and it's, it's blurry
Speaker 3:  in the like person who is slightly, slightly moving blurry. Yeah. Right.
Speaker 3:  And then you, you go over and it's like, it looks a little like if you just
Speaker 3:  open like the photos app and just crank sharpness up to a thousand in
Speaker 3:  that it, it kind of looks like it just drew edges around it. But then there's
Speaker 3:  like something in his eyes that it just, it he looks less human
Speaker 3:  afterwards. Yeah. And it's a little creepy. Well
Speaker 6:  Like it gives him these highlights that just feel that again, feel like that
Speaker 6:  that the sharpening thing in Photoshop where you're just like, Oh that's
Speaker 6:  a little unpleasant. He's got like highlights on his face. There's like a
Speaker 6:  guy in the background wearing a, a striped shirt and his shirt just gets
Speaker 6:  gross looking when when it goes to
Speaker 3:  The computer is like, your shirt's a little uglier than before. Now this
Speaker 3:  is how I perceive reality. That guy, his shirt sucks.
Speaker 3:  He sucks. I That's fine. Look, go read the reviews. Allison
Speaker 3:  Sway is, they're slightly better versions of last year's phone. They're competitive
Speaker 3:  with Apple and Samsung. What more can you ask for? And I think that ties
Speaker 3:  well into a piece of Dan wrote today that's like all the action this year's
Speaker 3:  in the watches. Yep. Like Apple Watch, Ultra Pixel watch, Samsung's
Speaker 3:  latest watches, even Garmin's latest watches far more interesting products
Speaker 3:  than the iPhone 14 or the S 22 or
Speaker 3:  whatever like Right. The pixel set. Like they're all just like extremely
Speaker 3:  iterative phone updates and the watches are where all the heat is. So there's
Speaker 3:  just more to do in watches at this point. Yeah. Like more like work to be
Speaker 3:  done. Phones are just phones. There's little rectangles of
Speaker 3:  despair. Yeah. And it's like you can go in and slightly fix the things that
Speaker 3:  are broken and if you try to do new things, people freak out. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  I will say, and I'm just pointing this at to all the YouTube commenters like
Speaker 3:  out there who are like, you had never, did I do this last week? Yeah. You
Speaker 3:  did this last week. You can do it again if we'll make you feel better. No,
Speaker 3:  I don't remember what I did last week. I also did a version that's supposed
Speaker 3:  on YouTube shorts and Ven didn't post it, so I don't remember.
Speaker 3:  I was like, I'm too short about it. And Ven was like, Don't do this. Oh wait.
Speaker 3:  Speaking of things that have not changed about phones, I got an iPhone 14
Speaker 3:  pro. It has a dynamic island. Ooh. Do you know how many times I
Speaker 3:  have remembered to do something with a dynamic island? Zero times
Speaker 3:  as spoiler alert, the dynamic island instantly ceases to exist in
Speaker 3:  my brain. As soon as I got the phone, I turned off the always on display
Speaker 3:  because I hate it. Does not, It's awful, awful implementation of
Speaker 3:  that feature. And the dynamic island is like, fine. I don't notice it. I
Speaker 3:  do like the thing where there's like a little bit of a wave form and it shows
Speaker 3:  the podcast that I'm listening to, but like as a, as a place for interaction,
Speaker 3:  I have gotten nothing out of it so far. So if you make a cool app that uses
Speaker 3:  that dynamic island, please send it to me. Otherwise I'm just sad about it.
Speaker 3:  You're waiting on live activities man. I guess so. Like there it
Speaker 3:  doesn't, it's
Speaker 6:  Gonna be a game changer.
Speaker 3:  It's not gonna be tell you it's huge,
Speaker 3:  huge move around. It's
Speaker 6:  A huge moment in
Speaker 3:  Your life. Have you noticed it? Like now that you've got it and you're using
Speaker 3:  it, it's like, oh, it's like, oh it's, it's still computer stuff. Like sometimes
Speaker 3:  it does, doesn't do what it's supposed to do. I like it. My thing that I've
Speaker 3:  really noticed is there's something about the phone stand on my desk that
Speaker 3:  the sun hits it at the exact angle where you can see all the parts underneath.
Speaker 3:  Oh wow. So it just doesn't look like I have a, a dynamic island. It's just,
Speaker 3:  it's just like here's some sensors. Enjoy. I'm like, it's fine.
Speaker 3:  Richard Baller by the way, Vir has superstar Richard Baller that
Speaker 3:  the loved the audience clamoring to get this man back on the show, which
Speaker 3:  maybe you will do. We can't do it again. It was, was too much. Aren't ready
Speaker 3:  too good. The people aren't ready. He showed up. He dunked on crypto for
Speaker 3:  45 minutes. You left. That's it. That's the full Richard experience. There's
Speaker 3:  a Android version of Dynamic Island and Richard is,
Speaker 3:  he keeps posting it on the site cuz we had quick posts. He keeps pointing
Speaker 3:  out. It's better than the dynamic. It's very good. It's very good. Okay,
Speaker 3:  we gotta take a break. We still have like 9,000 Microsoft announcements to
Speaker 3:  get through, so we'll take a break while, be right back.
Speaker 9:  Kara Switcher here. You may know me as the person who made Mark Zuckerberg's
Speaker 9:  sweat pushed Kim Kardashian to talk dollars or got Secretary
Speaker 9:  Mayor Pete Buttigieg to eat a juicy strawberry live on stage.
Speaker 9:  Okay. That one was awkward, but that's what I like to do. Make
Speaker 9:  powerful people comfortable with being uncomfortable. Now I'll be doing that
Speaker 9:  on my new show from New York Magazine on with Kara Swisher.
Speaker 9:  We'll bring you news and the newsmakers I'm paying attention to and
Speaker 9:  we'll do it twice a week on Mondays and Thursdays. Go check it out
Speaker 9:  on with Kara Swisher wherever you get your podcasts.
Speaker 3:  All right, we're back. I don't even know how to get through
Speaker 3:  the amount of Microsoft News. There is. Alex, do you wanna try?
Speaker 6:  We start with teams. Start with
Speaker 3:  Work. Our here here's, there's only one piece of important Microsoft News.
Speaker 3:  Microsoft Office is being rebranded to Microsoft 365
Speaker 2:  Woo.
Speaker 6:  Which
Speaker 3:  Is just, I don't like it. It's weird. I like it. I hate it.
Speaker 6:  I'm saying that, I know David hates
Speaker 3:  It. Yeah, you go first. I'd like to hear your case so I can pick it apart
Speaker 3:  piece by piece.
Speaker 6:  I, I like it. Not necessarily like for me as a person,
Speaker 6:  but I like it for Microsoft attempting to get away from the fact that they're
Speaker 6:  known as the boring office company by being like, what if we just get rid
Speaker 6:  of that word because work is now 365 days a year
Speaker 6:  and so will we. Yeah. Like and in that way I'm like, yes,
Speaker 6:  this makes a lot of sense. This is what a great branding exercise. But that,
Speaker 6:  that's as far as I get. I'm just like neat.
Speaker 3:  It sounds like the store brand at the grocery store. That's what I have to
Speaker 3:  offer you. Yeah, it absolutely does.
Speaker 6:  Okay. It's Whole Foods.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I have two thoughts on this. One. 365
Speaker 3:  is a bad brand that no one is allowed to have because the Earth
Speaker 3:  has it. Like the, Our Planet has a
Speaker 3:  trademark on 365 as a brand. So you, no one else
Speaker 3:  gets to have that. Also, do you know what everyone on Earth
Speaker 3:  knows about Microsoft Office? It is like
Speaker 3:  honestly on in the scheme of like brand recognition, there are probably
Speaker 3:  not that many things that have more of it than Microsoft Office. So now this
Speaker 3:  is not like Google trying to rebrand G Suite into Google Workspace
Speaker 3:  and look how messy that's been. This is Microsoft taking like one of
Speaker 3:  its oldest most successful and best known products and giving it
Speaker 3:  a stupid name for no reason. This like, this just, I can imagine
Speaker 3:  the meeting here, which is my favorite part of this. It's a bunch of executives
Speaker 3:  sitting in a meeting saying, Okay, we have a lot of office users but they're
Speaker 3:  older and like the Gen Z doesn't vibe with Office in the
Speaker 3:  same way. And we want, we want people to think of this as something new and
Speaker 3:  cool and no one raised their hand and said, well as long as they're called
Speaker 3:  Word and Excel, we're not accomplishing anything. Yeah. But they,
Speaker 3:  So then they decide like, we need an edgy, cool, new brand. It's called Microsoft
Speaker 3:  365. Yeah, no it's good. But
Speaker 6:  Somebody skateboarded in with their backwards baseball cab. It
Speaker 6:  was like 365 and skateboarded out.
Speaker 3:  We had Office 365. Yeah. Cause everyone's, everyone knows that
Speaker 3:  that went great. Well that's how you pay for it 365 days a
Speaker 3:  year. Yeah. The SA Smile in Office is
Speaker 3:  365. It does seem like a huge miss.
Speaker 3:  And I buy that. They were like, the kids hate work. Right. You get a bunch
Speaker 3:  of cranky holds and you're like, these kids today don't wanna work. You
Speaker 3:  can't tell 'em to go back to the office. Yeah. So we're gonna call it like
Speaker 3:  Microsoft Kick ass fun time. Yeah. Microsoft work from home.
Speaker 3:  Microsoft Vacation Days. That's
Speaker 6:  What they did. They absolutely were like, Oh no, we, we, The kids don't like
Speaker 6:  the office. The Gen Z, they're 12 and they hate the office because
Speaker 6:  they're 12.
Speaker 3:  But we are Microsoft and we are unavoidable. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  It is one of the most baffling brand decisions all the time. One of the
Speaker 3:  strongest brands in all of tech is Microsoft Office. Next they're gonna call
Speaker 3:  Windows Computer Time and it's not gonna work. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Windows 24 7. Windows 24 7. So
Speaker 3:  what they're allowed to do, because they got rid of this year's, the art
Speaker 3:  version 10, they got rid of the office brand name. They can roll more products
Speaker 3:  into it. Right. So Office was tightly defined. The bundles getting too big.
Speaker 3:  Microsoft 365 is like anything, I can't even think
Speaker 3:  like at some point they'd be like, Xbox, that part of the Microsoft
Speaker 3:  365 family,
Speaker 6:  It's coming. That's
Speaker 3:  Absolutely Just get Ready. They did it. Yeah. They were like, well Microsoft
Speaker 3:  Designer isn't an office product. And somebody goes, Well we gotta change
Speaker 3:  that then. Yeah, at some point they're gonna bring back the office branding
Speaker 3:  just for the word Excel and PowerPoint and one, One Drive,
Speaker 3:  one note, whatever it's called. It's just, if you have a good brand that
Speaker 3:  everybody knows that has been very successful you for, for you for decades,
Speaker 3:  don't change it. Yeah. There's my free business advice for you for the day.
Speaker 3:  Just change the logo. I be mad about the logo. Trust me. You gotta
Speaker 3:  believe me. Coca-Cola we're now Soda America. Like it's nothing. It's nothing.
Speaker 3:  F 365 again sounds like the store brand. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  All right. So that's the big Microsoft News. That's it. That's the first
Speaker 3:  cast. No, they announced like 500 other things. I would drink fizzy 365.
Speaker 3:  I just want, I just, it's that's, it'll be cheaper. That's,
Speaker 3:  that's carbonated soil. No,
Speaker 6:  You'll get, you'll get Mr. Or Doctor Fizzy
Speaker 3:  5 365 Pit Bulls luster known
Speaker 3:  Alter Ego, Mr. Fizzy 365.
Speaker 3:  Dr. Fizzy is my father. That's horrible.
Speaker 3:  Oh my god. Pit Bulls got a son 360
Speaker 3:  can't for him to hit.
Speaker 6:  But they did announce a lot of
Speaker 3:  Stuff. They did.
Speaker 3:  Or
Speaker 6:  This week
Speaker 3:  I They did and they didn't, They, they announced a lot of products but did
Speaker 3:  they announce much? Okay, so let's start. Let's start with the thing that
Speaker 3:  I'm always the most fascinated by, which is the Surface studio too, because
Speaker 3:  I desperately wanna Surface Studio. I love this product. Love the Hinge.
Speaker 6:  I believe you mean the Surface Studio to
Speaker 3:  Plus Plus in the streaming service. It's very clear
Speaker 3:  why they named it the Surface Studio two plus because they changed virtually
Speaker 3:  nothing including the CPUs stuck with
Speaker 3:  11th gen until CPUs in there. But they added a laptop
Speaker 3:  grade 30 60 as a gpu, which is the knock on the service
Speaker 3:  studio as it always had a week gpu. So they're like, Do you want this gpu?
Speaker 3:  It's from last year and we are running it. Laptop speeds fine.
Speaker 3:  It seems great. It's also $4,300.
Speaker 3:  Which is been who Biased? Yeah. I want
Speaker 3:  one very badly. I've always wanted one and one day they're gonna make one.
Speaker 6:  The hinges cool.
Speaker 3:  The hinges cool. I I just make
Speaker 6:  A monitor. Why don't they just make a monitor? The Office 365 monitor,
Speaker 3:  Monitor 365 every day.
Speaker 3:  I've got this dream. Again, most of my life is Zoom meetings. So
Speaker 3:  I'll be in a Zoom meeting and it particularly tense and I'll stand and I'll
Speaker 3:  like roll the monitor down and then point down at people and be like,
Speaker 3:  we're making this decision. I don't, I have
Speaker 3:  weird ideas about work
Speaker 3:  ever been like suddenly is towering above me. I've not moved.
Speaker 6:  But you could do that in VR too.
Speaker 3:  Teams vr, every, every part of this.
Speaker 3:  It's just me being it more tyrannical boss at work, you
Speaker 6:  Move everybody else's legs, you loo over.
Speaker 3:  So the Studio two plus they added the 30 60, which is a
Speaker 3:  reasonable good GPU for that device. Yeah. To me
Speaker 3:  honestly it's so expensive. That's the main problem. Like I still think it's
Speaker 3:  a cool thing and the one they shipped two years ago is like relatively powerful.
Speaker 3:  Like it's weird that they didn't update it, but it's still probably a very
Speaker 3:  good machine. It's just twice the price. It should be. Yeah. It's crazy.
Speaker 3:  Then they did the Service Pro Nine kind of a lot going on with
Speaker 3:  the service Pro nine. Yes. The
Speaker 6:  The CPU stuff there interests me a lot cuz they did, They did
Speaker 6:  Intel. They got rid of AMD or no, they never had AMD on the surface. Pro
Speaker 6:  Nine. Yeah, that was just
Speaker 3:  The laptop. Okay.
Speaker 6:  So it's, it's kind of interesting to me because they did Intel and then they've
Speaker 6:  also just gotten rid of the Surface Pro X and put the arm chip
Speaker 6:  into this and that's very clearly like Apple's running circles around
Speaker 6:  both Qualcomm and Microsoft for years. I mean two
Speaker 6:  years but still that's years and now they're gonna try to compete.
Speaker 6:  They've been trying for years. But this could
Speaker 3:  Be good. This chip is a, it's a Microsoft Qualcomm co jam, right? Like I
Speaker 3:  don't actually know anything about this chip. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  What you know. Yeah, so, so this is like the next, in that generation they
Speaker 6:  did the Surface Pro nine that had the last generation of this chip. This
Speaker 6:  is the new S Q three, it's gonna have 5G support. This is the
Speaker 6:  only way to get 5G on the surface Pro Nine. And it's like,
Speaker 6:  it's, it's interesting but we haven't seen it yet. We haven't gotten to play
Speaker 6:  with it. Tom played with it and he was like, well it seems fast enough, it
Speaker 6:  seems to do the stuff. And that's always been the complaint about the Surface
Speaker 6:  Pro Nine is it's this really cool super tiny, super thin device and it's
Speaker 6:  awesome. But then you go and and try to do anything besides
Speaker 6:  some little Office 360 fiveing and then you're, you're done.
Speaker 3:  It's actually called Microsoft 360, excuse
Speaker 6:  Me, Microsoft 360 fiveing. Sorry
Speaker 3:  It's Dr. Fizzy to you Alex. Well I mean so it's interesting
Speaker 3:  that you can pick between Intel and Arm. You know the surface line
Speaker 3:  is kind of like an odd one cuz it caught totally blown up by the pandemic
Speaker 3:  in a way that I don't think Microsoft is still reckoning with. Like the last
Speaker 3:  time we talked to Panos in depth, he was here in the office pre
Speaker 3:  pandemic. He had the surface was the Neo, the dual screen, the Surface
Speaker 3:  duo. Yeah. They were pushing and the surface, what
Speaker 3:  was it, the Surface prox that was their ARM device at the time
Speaker 3:  and they were pushing towards this dual screen future. They're pushing towards
Speaker 3:  ARM and then the pandemic hit and all of those plants evaporated.
Speaker 3:  Like they just went away. So this is kind of like just a re just a
Speaker 3:  refocusing of what they're doing with Surface in a real way. But like Windows
Speaker 3:  on arm, like we're still trade off city and now it's like what you get for
Speaker 3:  that trade off is 5G probably better battery life, unclear what the performance
Speaker 3:  will be and then your other choice is Intel where you get all your apps but
Speaker 3:  it's still an Intel chip in this form factor, which means it's gonna run
Speaker 3:  hot in the battery. That'll be low. Yeah. The thing for me with
Speaker 3:  the ARM stuff has always been that you're fighting a bunch of battles simultaneously.
Speaker 3:  It's like there are performance questions, there are battery life questions
Speaker 3:  and I would argue continually, most of all it's it's an app compatibility
Speaker 3:  thing, right? Like you, you buy these devices and they just don't run
Speaker 3:  most things because Microsoft has not either done enough or been able to
Speaker 3:  get its developers to do enough to be part of this. And Alex, you and I were
Speaker 3:  talking about this earlier this week. Like Microsoft is clearly committed
Speaker 3:  to this. Like it, it has these developer kit out there, it's made it easier,
Speaker 3:  it's issuing all kinds of new stuff. It seems to be mercifully done with
Speaker 3:  the idea of trying to make a whole new windows just for Arm and it's like
Speaker 3:  we just need to make actual Windows work. Yep. Yep. But I, I
Speaker 3:  am suspicious of the idea that this is gonna be the one
Speaker 3:  like I think Microsoft is right to keep trying on this because it has to
Speaker 3:  and it has to keep convincing developers to play along and
Speaker 3:  convince them that it's the future and it's worth, you know, rearchitecting
Speaker 3:  their apps to make it work. I just, I have a hard time imagining that this
Speaker 3:  is gonna be the one that like magically makes Windows work well on Arm. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  I hope that's true.
Speaker 6:  What I have to figure out like the secret sauce of, of the Mac of
Speaker 6:  Mac o s is that they, they now just emulate
Speaker 6:  everything on Arm, right? They were like, okay, we know a lot of people are
Speaker 6:  gonna switch over, but also we're just gonna do really, really, really good
Speaker 6:  emulation so it doesn't even matter so you can play your games or whatever
Speaker 6:  and go And Microsoft just hasn't done that. And
Speaker 6:  I'm not really clear why they haven't, I
Speaker 3:  Mean part of it is the chips, right? Like the, the max just has so much
Speaker 3:  performance to spare that it can, it can do a lot of that
Speaker 3:  emulation pretty successfully in a way that, you know, these, these deeply
Speaker 3:  subpar Qualcomm chips just have not been able to hack so far.
Speaker 3:  I would also say right catalyst on the Mac is like all over the place In
Speaker 3:  my experience, I've had some apps that work really well. Really I've had
Speaker 3:  some apps that suck and I don't know if that's just my own experience but
Speaker 3:  that's, that's certainly what I've seen sometimes. But I think Microsoft,
Speaker 3:  again, it's, it's like back to that same thing, right? You kinda have to
Speaker 3:  get all these things right simultaneously before it's gonna really work.
Speaker 3:  And it's a weird sort of chicken and egg problem where it's like without
Speaker 3:  the right chip you're not gonna get the apps to work and without the apps
Speaker 3:  the chip isn't gonna get you there because the apps don't matter. So it's
Speaker 3:  like they, they have to, they have to pull a lot of things all together at
Speaker 3:  the same time and have not successfully done that so far.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I mean I'll be real, I'm not super, super confident in the
Speaker 6:  s q three. Like Apple has a ton of resources behind it to make really, really
Speaker 6:  good chips and Microsoft just does not prove that
Speaker 6:  out as evidenced by the studio two plus
Speaker 6:  existing out in the world with super old chips in it like that,
Speaker 6:  that kind of hardware stuff. There's some of that that they just are failing
Speaker 6:  on repeatedly. So I'm not like, I wanna be excited about this. I,
Speaker 6:  I wanna be really enthusiastic. I can't wait to try it out and see how
Speaker 6:  fast it is but ooh I'm not confident that they're gonna
Speaker 6:  nail it this time.
Speaker 3:  I will say if they have gotten closer
Speaker 3:  than the thin and light long battery life reasonable
Speaker 3:  performance, but it's Windows, it's a whole ass operating
Speaker 3:  system that's actually represents the, the
Speaker 3:  competitive break with Apple that Microsoft's been chasing for. Oh absolutely.
Speaker 3:  Right. Hundred percent. Instead of like, here's here's everything you've
Speaker 3:  ever wanted but we are gonna treat you like a baby versus Yeah it's not
Speaker 3:  quite everything you ever wanted but we treat you like an adult to get a
Speaker 3:  virus on their computer. Yeah. Like those your choices and like Microsoft
Speaker 3:  might have a product that actually make that case in a way that no until
Speaker 3:  tablet has ever really made that case. Two things I want to ask though. One,
Speaker 3:  well two things related ideas. One, there's no headphone jack
Speaker 3:  on this thing, which is just brutal for a tablet of this size. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Especially cuz the design is the same as last year basically. And last iPhone
Speaker 3:  Jack what are you doing? You can't just don't,
Speaker 6:  Well they have to make room for the neural processing unit on the new
Speaker 6:  Qualcomm chip. You know, you gotta, you gotta, sometimes you have to sacrifice
Speaker 6:  for stuff that may or may not actually make the product
Speaker 3:  Better. Okay, so that's one. Yeah. Two. How well do you think this will take
Speaker 3:  Tom Brady just absolutely ripping this thing down the field?
Speaker 3:  Cause it's gonna just break it in in half. It's the first thing it's gonna
Speaker 3:  happen. You know the NFL had to be like a directive to the teams
Speaker 3:  being like stop destroying the tablets. Please. I hope that's Tom Brady's
Speaker 3:  true legacy.
Speaker 6:  Do they all use the Surface Pro Eight or do they give them like really old
Speaker 6:  surface Cuz they know they're just kind flee.
Speaker 3:  I like to imagine they're like surface rts. Yeah and they just barely work.
Speaker 3:  That's why they're, yeah that's pretty good. Last piece of
Speaker 3:  Microsoft hardware really is the Surface laptop five. This is basically
Speaker 3:  another chip story. So last year Microsoft hedged some
Speaker 3:  bets added some AMD into the mix AMD price,
Speaker 3:  performance, heat kind of better than Intel for the past couple
Speaker 3:  generations. You could see why they went with it in the laptop this year
Speaker 3:  where back to Intel 12th generation. Can I run a conspiracy theory by you?
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I'm curious if there's any chance that I'm right. So you just talked
Speaker 3:  to Pat er on the other podcast that we don't talk about. Yeah, it was actually
Speaker 3:  very good. It was a good episode of Decco. Unlike all the rest of it. That
Speaker 3:  dude's a huge name. Oh my god. The acronyms. Good lord. Okay.
Speaker 3:  But anyway, one thing all of these announcements made me wonder is
Speaker 3:  like is Microsoft aware of the Intel roadmap and slowing
Speaker 3:  its role to meet Intel at a point at which everyone is doing good things
Speaker 3:  again. And so at this point it's like why are we gonna reinvent the wheel
Speaker 3:  for continually crappy intel chips when something real and good is coming
Speaker 3:  in 1, 2, 3 years And all we need to do is actually just match that and then
Speaker 3:  we can run together. Why
Speaker 6:  Would anyone wait? Yeah.
Speaker 3:  What's her
Speaker 6:  Intel screwed it up so badly. Why would anybody trust Intel
Speaker 6:  again? Because what
Speaker 3:  Other choice do they have?
Speaker 6:  AMD
Speaker 3:  But then they chose not to do it. This is what I'm saying. So is that
Speaker 3:  why they chose, like is that why you keep throwing your light in? Cause otherwise
Speaker 3:  I'm with you. I agree like you're nuts to not continue to
Speaker 3:  pit intel and AMD against each other unless there is a like moment
Speaker 3:  in the future that you're betting on in a big way. I just can't see any other
Speaker 3:  reason.
Speaker 6:  I wouldn't be surprised if external pressures like
Speaker 6:  Monica and I were talking about this in the office earlier this week after
Speaker 6:  the event and we were both like, she was super, super bummed that that AMD
Speaker 6:  wasn't on this thing. We're like, well why isn't it there? And
Speaker 6:  sometimes in the laptop world somebody says, Hey
Speaker 6:  how about you just use our chips in your devices?
Speaker 6:  And I wouldn't be surprised if that was part of what happened here
Speaker 3:  But in like a, I feel like you need to say that again in like a much scarier
Speaker 3:  way.
Speaker 6:  Yeah like, like
Speaker 3:  Can't nice computers you have there Tim, look what it's computers. Microsoft
Speaker 3:  can just issue that threat right? Back to Intel being like, yes this is,
Speaker 3:  Yeah it would be a shame if Windows didn't run on your chips Pat.
Speaker 3:  Well
Speaker 6:  I mean I don't necessarily think like also there's just money. Money
Speaker 6:  gets, people just give people money and are like hey I wanna be exclusive
Speaker 6:  here. Yeah. I don't know if that's legal or illegal. I'm hoping I'm
Speaker 6:  not accusing two companies of breaking the law.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, I mean they're allowed to. You're allowed to. You're allowed to spend
Speaker 3:  some money.
Speaker 6:  Yeah,
Speaker 3:  It's a little cash walk around money. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  It's just fascinating. Like Microsoft's chip choices here are fascinating
Speaker 3:  across the board. I agree everyone's waiting for Intel to take this turn
Speaker 3:  but it's also Microsoft. The stack of things Microsoft has to accomplish
Speaker 3:  with Surface is just as complicated as Google's pixel watch stack, right?
Speaker 3:  They have to set the bar for all their OEMs. They have to keep
Speaker 3:  both chip makers happy and participating. They have to not over compete with
Speaker 3:  the Lenovos and Dells of the world. They have to compete with Apple a thousand
Speaker 3:  dollars and above, which is where the Lenovos and the Dells don't really
Speaker 3:  compete anymore. On and on and on. And he kind of just like the thing is
Speaker 3:  inherently political like the laptop more than anything the laptop
Speaker 3:  is inherently political because the OEMs have basically stopped making
Speaker 3:  surface shaped things. Or they do but they're like very enterprise
Speaker 3:  focused. So like, and no like Lenovo's not out there with a Surface
Speaker 3:  Studio two plus like that's just like the Hinge engineers at Microsoft
Speaker 3:  got They they got one. You know like PS was like yeah that's fine.
Speaker 3:  This is the most complicated hinge in America and you should ship it. So
Speaker 3:  like I think the laptop is in, it's where the politics really come to play
Speaker 3:  most directly with this. But we'll see. I mean there's just like,
Speaker 3:  there's so much Microsoft stuff going on and it service is 10 years. Like
Speaker 3:  we should say this service is a huge success.
Speaker 3:  It is accomplished. Every single thing Microsoft ever wanted it to accomplish,
Speaker 3:  it really did. Reinvigorate Windows laptops. Panos has done an amazing job
Speaker 3:  like running this program in the face of all these politics, there are
Speaker 3:  effectively no companies that have ever managed to be the the
Speaker 3:  OS vendor and the premium hardware vendor and make everything
Speaker 3:  work. Like Google has not done it Pixel. No. Cuz Apple doesn't have
Speaker 3:  OEMs. They're not a vendor of software. That's true. Way true, right? That's
Speaker 3:  true. The Google hasn't accomplished it with a Pixel. Right? They're a successful
Speaker 3:  OS vendor in Samsung is their primary. It's interesting. Blackberry and Qix.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, Blackberry failed. Palm famously failed.
Speaker 3:  We've gone through that. We have a whole documentary about that that you
Speaker 3:  can watch. It's called Springboards. Very good. Basically no companies ever
Speaker 3:  managed to pull this off, but Microsoft did it with the surface. Yeah it's,
Speaker 3:  it's kind of remarkable. They pulled it off for the past decade, like people
Speaker 3:  doubted them very much and they thought the OEMs would run and it kind of
Speaker 3:  turns out there's nowhere to run too. Like it has never been the year of
Speaker 3:  Linux on the desktop Sadly. So they, they were in a little bit of a stronger
Speaker 3:  position. But I've talked to p I've walked around CS with P pane and like
Speaker 3:  she's been like, look, we invent hardware and we
Speaker 3:  license it back out to the OEMs and like that's our hinge and that's our
Speaker 3:  thing and that's our design. And like you can see them pushing the Windows
Speaker 3:  hardware innovation ecosystem ahead because they knew that Apple would just
Speaker 3:  kill them and Dell and everybody else would focus on the high
Speaker 3:  margin sheep computers for business and never sell the thousand dollar consumer
Speaker 3:  laptop. And so like we're just gonna do it. Huge success. Very
Speaker 3:  complicated politics that express themselves and things like the Qualcomm
Speaker 3:  s Q3 and this like weird lack of arm but, or weird lack of amd
Speaker 3:  but pretty rad. But you should watch the video with Tom and Panos cause it's
Speaker 3:  great. Okay, let's do a lightning. Well the other Windows
Speaker 3:  thing we should talk about before we switch is this Apple
Speaker 3:  partnership to some extent I guess with Windows where
Speaker 3:  I think, what is it you're gonna get music and TV apps both on
Speaker 3:  Windows and on the Xbox, which is like, it's one of those things that
Speaker 3:  both seems insane to me that that's a thing that's happening. And also like
Speaker 3:  oh, an iCloud photos windows. Oh right. An iCloud photos. Everybody's favorite
Speaker 3:  photos app. That is a thing that I care about that definitely What's the
Speaker 3:  default? It's the default iPhone photo app. It's just there so that when
Speaker 3:  I search phones it, it still works. I don't care about it on any other platform
Speaker 3:  anyway. You get all your photos in your laptop, that's a big win. That is
Speaker 3:  true. No, I'll give you that. Yeah. iCloud photos is legit. Yeah I think
Speaker 3:  it was just, it's one of those things that it's, it's representative of the
Speaker 3:  thing that Apple is desperately trying to do, which is like BA services business
Speaker 3:  and like speaking of, you know, the politics between companies, Apple and
Speaker 3:  Microsoft are not like famous for being best friends. And so it says a lot
Speaker 3:  about what Apple is trying to do that it's willing to put music and TV
Speaker 3:  and photos into all of these different Windows products like that
Speaker 3:  is Steve Jobs would never in a million years have done that. And even five
Speaker 3:  years ago, I don't think Tim Cook would've known that well put iTunes on
Speaker 3:  Windows to iPods. But that's like that, that's actually probably a good example,
Speaker 3:  right? Cause you get to a point where it's like, okay, this is, this is our
Speaker 3:  move, this is how we reach a lot of people. And that's clearly where music
Speaker 3:  and TV are next. Like a lot of people who have Windows wanna watch Ted Lasso.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. And that's a way to get a lot of people to do so. And so it makes sense.
Speaker 3:  It was just slightly surprising to me to see Apple and Windows be like, we
Speaker 3:  make apps together. So my, my theory here is very cynical. So the
Speaker 3:  game consoles are underappreciated as streaming devices.
Speaker 3:  Tons and tons of people Yep. Run streaming apps on their game consoles all
Speaker 3:  the time. And so if you're Apple, you gotta get the Apple TV app on the game
Speaker 3:  console just to compete. Yep. Yeah. That's life. So
Speaker 3:  they're like, we wanna go on this game console and Microsoft is like, haha,
Speaker 3:  we tightly control the economics of the Xbox and there are no, it's not
Speaker 3:  an open app store to get on this game console. You gotta come through
Speaker 3:  us. Interesting. And they were just like, Sasha just walked around campus
Speaker 3:  and was like, what do you want? We got one chip with Apple. They want, they
Speaker 3:  want Apple TV app on the Xbox, like who's got something that we
Speaker 3:  want. And the, the team that runs the photos tab in
Speaker 3:  like explorer Was like, can we just
Speaker 3:  get the high iCloud photos integration like every other photo
Speaker 3:  service supports this tab. Please can you just get them to give us the
Speaker 3:  API hooks? And Saha was like, Yeah, we could probably get that out them so
Speaker 3:  that that was the trade. They were like, we want fast pairing AirPods. And
Speaker 3:  Tim Hook was like, No. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  you this was a straight up just tit for ta. You want be in the Xbox,
Speaker 3:  what are you gonna do for me? Yeah. Sounds right. And they landed at iCloud
Speaker 3:  photos on Windows. And that's just everybody listen,
Speaker 3:  I'm for fast pairing. I want an iMessage client for Windows
Speaker 3:  like death first. Yeah. That's when Craig Frederiki hangs up.
Speaker 3:  He's like, here's, here's a got iCloud photos.
Speaker 1:  Wait, I can't help myself. I I have to ask, do you
Speaker 1:  think that they tried to get the Xbox, I forget what it's,
Speaker 1:  it's called, but the service that has to run Safari on iOS.
Speaker 3:  Oh do you try to like a game streaming app on iOS? That's where I thought
Speaker 3:  you were going. Yeah. Yeah. And they ended up at iCloud photos. They're like,
Speaker 3:  can we get the Apple TV app in the Xbox? And Microsoft was like,
Speaker 3:  Yeah, if you let us do cloud gaming on the iPhone and Apple is like death
Speaker 3:  first. No, absolutely. Here's our counter offer iCloud photos,
Speaker 3:  which you can already access in a web browser and any computer on Planet
Speaker 3:  Earth Fair. But now it's in the start menu.
Speaker 6:  That's all that matters.
Speaker 3:  It's a high stakes negotiation. Had teams in two separate conference rooms.
Speaker 3:  There's one person had to walk back and forth. It's PTOs for sure.
Speaker 3:  It's just like someone is gonna write the inside the deal that
Speaker 3:  iCloud photos to Windows. It's like, you know, it's like a 600 page
Speaker 3:  novel with barbarians at the gate. Yeah. I like imagining it.
Speaker 3:  Right? It's, it's more like a, like a wheel you spin and it just landed on
Speaker 3:  iCloud photos. It's like, cause like right past
Speaker 3:  Mac integration for Xbox goes right past
Speaker 3:  all of the iMessage stuff and it just lands on iCloud, FedEx and the one
Speaker 3:  right next to it is bankrupt. Yeah, yeah, yeah. iCloud photos
Speaker 3:  is like the 5 cents on the prices Right Wheel. And it's like well least we
Speaker 3:  get zero. It's actually bad news. I the wheel
Speaker 3:  spinning goes are great. All One last
Speaker 3:  thing we should mention before we get outta here. Netflix disclosure.
Speaker 3:  We made a Netflix show Box Media makes, Netflix shows Comcast investor in
Speaker 3:  box media. Everyone has, everyone here owns a television. Everyone hears
Speaker 3:  a Netflix subscriber theory disclosures for day. All right, what are we but
Speaker 3:  Paws and the Great Game of Capitalism and Netflix is adding ads,
Speaker 3:  it's gonna cost 6 99 a month ads by the way, run by Microsoft.
Speaker 3:  Microsoft shown up and everyone's announcements this week. Seriously? Do
Speaker 3:  you have something you're not syntax. Microsoft will be there and they will
Speaker 3:  rebrand off. This is probably involved. It's called Netflix 365.
Speaker 3:  Now all the Netflix ads are just for teams. Well
Speaker 6:  No that's how you do group watch. Now it's through teams.
Speaker 3:  Like all the Amazon ads on football are just for Amazon.
Speaker 3:  Last week the ads were for Hero and I was like, you guys like just let's
Speaker 3:  someone else buy adss. Like if you're watching football
Speaker 3:  Thursday night football streaming on Amazon Prime, it seems likely you've
Speaker 3:  got your wifi situation sorted out. So that's definitely the best case scenario
Speaker 3:  for this Netflix thing, right? Is that it's, it's, what is it, four, four
Speaker 3:  to five minutes of ads per hour. If that four to five minutes is just trailers
Speaker 3:  for other Netflix shows like I'm down me. So let's do this.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. $7 a month Nielsen is gonna start offering data about
Speaker 3:  Netflix audience for the ad business only. Which is
Speaker 3:  fascinating. But ad buyers want a standard source of data
Speaker 3:  to know who their ads are hitting. So letting Nielsen into the ad side but
Speaker 3:  not the paid side. So Reed can still do fake numbers whenever he wants.
Speaker 3:  It was the most watch show on Netflix.
Speaker 6:  Sure, sure.
Speaker 3:  We that means something to somebody. Believe you. And then they're gonna
Speaker 3:  do less ads than competitors. Here you go.
Speaker 6:  When do you think they start standardizing their, the lengths of shows
Speaker 6:  like Network TV does Because right now they're all over the place.
Speaker 3:  I don't think they're ever gonna do that. Cause it just like
Speaker 6:  Too much. You end up seeing a lot of ads for like an hour and five minute
Speaker 6:  show and you're like, okay, I guess I'm into my next set of ads.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, well that's, I think that's why they're doing four to five. They're
Speaker 3:  giving themselves a little buffer. You know, that's why this whole thing
Speaker 3:  is like you're gonna watch the next one. Right. So like they're, I don't
Speaker 3:  think they're worried about whether shows are 20 minutes or 22 minutes or
Speaker 3:  35 minutes or whatever. They're just like, what we'd like from you is four
Speaker 3:  uninterrupted hours. Well and I'm assuming, and correct me if I'm wrong,
Speaker 3:  I don't think Netflix has said anything about like compensating content
Speaker 3:  makers differently because of ads. Right. Because
Speaker 6:  That that heavens that is a big, that would change argument right now in
Speaker 6:  the unions. Oh interesting. The unions are all getting upset about this because
Speaker 6:  right now when they sell the rights to these shows, they end up basically
Speaker 6:  being like you own it forever. And then it's like, wait, I only get
Speaker 6:  $5 for the hours of blood, sweat and tears I put into this.
Speaker 6:  Right. I used to be able to live on my residuals with other shows. So that's
Speaker 6:  actually like I think we're gonna be seeing a lot of that in the next rounds
Speaker 6:  of union negotiations across the industry cuz they get mad
Speaker 6:  about
Speaker 3:  It. Yeah. And, and if, if that comes it's gonna be fun back the
Speaker 3:  gamesmanship on how long should my content be then becomes really
Speaker 3:  interesting Cuz even if Netflix doesn't standardize it, like you see YouTubers
Speaker 3:  who have like vastly changed the stuff that they make in order to maximize
Speaker 3:  the ad load in the videos that you see And like, But the YouTubers did that
Speaker 3:  because YouTube told them to, YouTube was like 10 minutes. Yeah. And
Speaker 3:  YouTubers like fine 10 minutes. But if Netflix says, you know, we're gonna
Speaker 3:  show you two ads over a 20 minute show or four ads over a 30
Speaker 3:  minute show, like tell you confidently what's gonna happen. But that only
Speaker 3:  matters if the compensation changes. So I guess for now it doesn't necessarily
Speaker 3:  matter, I'm not an expert on TV deals, but those residuals are paid by licensing
Speaker 3:  to other people who broadcast the shows. Netflix isn't doing that. Right?
Speaker 3:  Right. They're just adding ads. Yep. Yeah. And they're lowering the price.
Speaker 3:  So yeah, I think they're how those deals get done.
Speaker 3:  I
Speaker 6:  Think those deals are gonna start changing. Yeah. And and we're already seeing
Speaker 6:  that that that those discussions in those union channels and at networks
Speaker 6:  of like, okay we need to start changing how we're doing this because we're
Speaker 6:  getting screwed Because there's infinite content and not infinite dollars
Speaker 6:  and dollars there are going straight to the streamers and bypassing all the
Speaker 6:  creatives.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Well it's funny cuz none of the streamers make enough money. It's like
Speaker 3:  it, at no point did we actually make this better. But the streaming awards
Speaker 3:  are here
Speaker 6:  Just a pyramid scheme. Disney's at the top and everybody else is just like,
Speaker 6:  I guess we're also here making stuff. We're not Disney
Speaker 3:  Subscribe. That's coming. It's launching in November. The other plan there
Speaker 3:  was big Bloomberg piece, Lucas shot big Bloomberg piece in the future of
Speaker 3:  Netflix today. So the ads are one part of the plan. The other one cracking
Speaker 3:  down on password sharing. And they were like, not enough people are paying
Speaker 3:  for Netflix. And these are the two things they're doing. Like the CFO of
Speaker 3:  Netflix said to Lucas, here's the two things. It's
Speaker 3:  ads and it's password sharing. Yeah. Haven't they said there's like a hundred
Speaker 3:  million users they think are getting Netflix through shared passwords.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. And so they're trying to reframe it. They know it's hard. They've like
Speaker 3:  launched a bunch of trials in South America and they're trying to reframe
Speaker 3:  it as not cracking down on it. But wouldn't you like
Speaker 3:  to pay for your ex-girlfriend? What if you paid a little bit more
Speaker 3:  money? Huh? That'd be nice. We're, We'll just see how this goes.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Sorry. All my old roommates. I'm definitely gonna start VPNing to wherever
Speaker 3:  your house is
Speaker 3:  just so it looks like I'm around. That's the, the password
Speaker 3:  changes gonna get more complicated. People are just gonna VPN into one apartment
Speaker 3:  at the start. You could do it. Yeah. I'm
Speaker 6:  Excited for everybody to know what a VPN is. That's gonna be great.
Speaker 3:  I feel like any, like the kids all know what VPNs are cuz VPN companies advertised
Speaker 3:  so heavily on like YouTube and TikTok. That's true. And podcast. All right.
Speaker 3:  We've gone over, it's been amazing to be in the studio with my friend David Pierce.
Speaker 3:  It's an amazing to just send digital weed to you, Alex
Speaker 3:  over
Speaker 6:  This. I'm so high right now. It's
Speaker 3:  Great. Alex is firing up the plex server as we speak. Go
Speaker 3:  tons and tons of news, all the coverage of Microsoft, Google
Speaker 3:  Meta, it's all on the site. Check it out. Also, tons of other stuff, Tons
Speaker 3:  of little updates. The site experience and however you wanna see about those.
Speaker 3:  We got another big set coming maybe in two weeks from now. We're gonna redo
Speaker 3:  the top of the site, the hero area. We got some big plans there. Also, we
Speaker 3:  should just say if you do read all the Microsoft stuff, send Tom Warren nice
Speaker 3:  tweets about how much you love him. Cuz he did all of this while having Covid.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. And did a great job. Yeah. So tell Tom you love him. You can't tell
Speaker 3:  in the video unless you know. Yeah, exactly. That's
Speaker 3:  that's good. It's really good. But yeah, Tom came to America, had to go back
Speaker 3:  to the uk all dealing with is and put out just absolutely tremendous coverage.
Speaker 3:  Yep. So yeah, tweeted Tom told me did a good job. Don't mention that Covid
Speaker 3:  thing. Just tell he a good truck. Don't let him know we had to stop. Be cool.
Speaker 3:  Be cool. Be cool man. Be cool. All right. That's it. That's a, you can tweeted
Speaker 3:  us. I'm Matt Reckless. Davids at Pierce. Alex is Alex h Crayons
Speaker 3:  be back on Wednesday. We get the hotline coming this week. Yeah. 8 66 Verge
Speaker 3:  one one. I will tell you this, I already answered a hotline question this
Speaker 3:  week. Huge. It's pretty good. Game changer. It's, it's so deeply
Speaker 3:  exactly the thing that you would expect someone ask an hotline. I don't know.
Speaker 3:  I'm not giving away it just perfectly in the week I answer the question and
Speaker 3:  Andrew goes, I knew you'd know the answer to that question.
Speaker 3:  Very good. Okay, that's it. That's where,
Speaker 1:  And that's a wrap for Vergecast this week. Thanks for listening. If you enjoy
Speaker 1:  the show, subscribing the podcast app of your choice or tell a friend, you
Speaker 1:  can send us feedback at vergecast@theverge.com. This show is produced
Speaker 1:  by me, Liam James, and our senior audio director, Andrew Marina.
Speaker 1:  This episode was edited and mixed by Amanda Rose Smith. Our
Speaker 1:  editorial director is Brooke Min and our executive producer is Eleanor
Speaker 1:  Donovan. The Verge Cast is a production of the Verge and Box Media
Speaker 1:  podcast network. And that's it. We'll see you next week.