# Transcript
ID: 52008a50-597b-11ed-82bf-5321e0c0f2e5
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Cybersecurity Hotline Special
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-35526882113895854/3248333836622212411/s93290-US-3124s-1667262104.mp3
Description: We asked listeners to send in all their questions related to cybersecurity for this special Vergecast Hotline episode. David Pierce talks to Nilay Patel and Russell Brandom to get you the best advice for staying safe online.
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we'd love to hear from you.
We are conducting a short audience survey to help plan for our future and hear from you. To participate, head to vox.com/podsurvey, and thank you!
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Disabled
Speaker 1:  Support for this episode comes from Zelle. You'd never
Speaker 1:  fall for an online scam, right? You use
Speaker 1:  two factor authentication, ignore calls from everyone named
Speaker 1:  spam risk and never use the password.
Speaker 1:  Password.
Speaker 1:  But scammers are getting more sophisticated and more active,
Speaker 1:  which means they're finding millions of new victims every
Speaker 1:  single year. The good news is that there's a lot you can do to
Speaker 1:  protect yourself on the wild, wild web. For starters,
Speaker 1:  Zelle wants to remind you only send money to people you know
Speaker 1:  and trust. Zelle is available to United States bank account
Speaker 1:  holders only terms and conditions apply.
Speaker 2:  Welcome
Speaker 3:  To the Verge Cast, the flagship podcast of turning off wifi
Speaker 3:  on all of your devices and putting on tinfoil hats. I'm your friend David Pierce.
Speaker 3:  Russell Brando is here. Hi Russell.
Speaker 4:  Hi.
Speaker 3:  And this is a, this is very special Vergecast episode. This is,
Speaker 3:  is this the second week of cybersecurity week Russell? Is this like infrastructure
Speaker 3:  week? It's kind of every week. I,
Speaker 4:  Well, I, it's hard because for me every week is cybersecurity week. That's
Speaker 3:  Fair.
Speaker 4:  And it should be for you too,
Speaker 3:  But here, here on the Verge cast today is cybersecurity week, I
Speaker 3:  guess.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, yeah, exactly.
Speaker 3:  And we were thinking about a bunch of things to do and we decided that the
Speaker 3:  best thing we could do is just see what everyone wanted
Speaker 3:  to know about. So we opened up the Verge Cast hotline. We got a bunch of
Speaker 3:  really great questions. You and I have been doing a bunch of research in
Speaker 3:  prep and talking to folks, and we are gonna just roll through some of the
Speaker 3:  most interesting and popular questions we got. It's gonna be fun. I'm, I'm
Speaker 3:  very excited. I have been out some weird rabbit holes in getting ready for
Speaker 3:  this that I did not expect. I don't know how it's been for you, but it's,
Speaker 3:  I'm in a weird corner of the internet
Speaker 4:  Now. Oh yeah. I've, I've learned about myself and cybersecurity.
Speaker 3:  It's beautiful. Isn't that, It's really the same thing if you think about
Speaker 3:  it.
Speaker 4:  It's really wonder. No, no, they're, they're different.
Speaker 3:  Alright, let's get to our first question, which I think let's just start
Speaker 3:  with, I think the one that is actually in a strange way, the easiest to answer,
Speaker 3:  which is from Alex.
Speaker 5:  Hey there, this is Alex from Madison, Wisconsin.
Speaker 5:  I'm walking, walking my dog in the Bri Wisconsin
Speaker 5:  evening. And I had a question about a
Speaker 5:  browser malware extension. So I
Speaker 5:  recently cleaned my computer of something called Bundle
Speaker 5:  and it was really weird. It, it sort of, it,
Speaker 5:  it hid itself by making it so that whenever I tried to
Speaker 5:  access the page to manage my extensions, it just wouldn't go there. It was
Speaker 5:  like redirect the traffic. What I have is
Speaker 5:  whenever I tried to search for something in the like
Speaker 5:  Chrome search bar, it would redirect my search to Bing.
Speaker 5:  Why would I do that? What, what benefit does some malware program have
Speaker 5:  of redirecting my search through Bing instead of Google also who
Speaker 5:  uses Bing? Thank you.
Speaker 4:  Malware victims. There's
Speaker 3:  Apparently good questions in here. Yeah. Who uses Bing is no one on purpose,
Speaker 3:  but sometimes it happens. We, we've all been there. You just end up on Bing.
Speaker 3:  You don't know how you got there. You don't, you don't know where you are,
Speaker 3:  but it's dark outside and you're, you're bleeding from
Speaker 3:  somewhere and you don't know.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. So I, there's a lot to dig into here. I will say the thing that's,
Speaker 4:  that that I was kind of coming around to listening to this is
Speaker 4:  a lot of people being savvy about security
Speaker 4:  is sort of knowing implicitly what to trust. So it's like,
Speaker 4:  is it sketchy if I, you know, I'm reading
Speaker 4:  my credit card number out over the phone. Yep. And it's like, well if
Speaker 4:  you called the restaurant and their thing is down, like that's not actually
Speaker 4:  that weird. Like you're probably okay, it's okay to put your credit card
Speaker 4:  number into amazon.com. Like it's fine. And, and then like
Speaker 4:  there's other things where I got a weird email and lots of stuff is misspelled.
Speaker 4:  It's like that's obviously sketchy. You should, you should be careful I think
Speaker 4:  browser extensions and particularly bundled browser
Speaker 4:  extensions cuz he mentioned that he got this bundle. People who work
Speaker 4:  in this stuff have known for a while that this is a real
Speaker 4:  sort of place where scams happen and just, Yep. It's a
Speaker 4:  mess in there and you shouldn't trust anything. But I don't know if
Speaker 4:  the average user has really gotten around to like
Speaker 4:  the vast majority of browser extensions are
Speaker 4:  actively exploited and harmful and bad.
Speaker 3:  Well I'm not, I vast majority might be slightly overstated, but it
Speaker 3:  is. There's
Speaker 4:  A lot of, there's a lot of crap. There's a lot of crap I guess.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Well and it's, and it's tricky because like over the years
Speaker 3:  Google Chrome in particular has sort of devoted more and more
Speaker 3:  resources to fighting that. But even still, it's basically like an
Speaker 3:  automated system. And the thing that's crazy about Chrome extensions and
Speaker 3:  browser extensions in general is when you install them, most of
Speaker 3:  them require you to give them access to everything you do inside of your
Speaker 3:  browser. Like in order to do the very basic thing that they want to do,
Speaker 3:  you have to, because there's no like middle setting in many cases
Speaker 3:  you have to turn on like Sure. Read later app. You can see
Speaker 3:  every single thing I do in my browser and that's just bonkers and it's
Speaker 3:  like systemically, this
Speaker 4:  Is not like you can replace what I'm seeing
Speaker 4:  on the screen with other stuff. Yes. So you know that there, like the
Speaker 4:  classic joke extension is like, we made it so it replaces the word
Speaker 4:  millennial with snake people. Like, haha isn't that funny? It's like, no,
Speaker 4:  this is, you're looking at the website and what you're seeing is
Speaker 4:  something different from what the website is trying to show you. Like do
Speaker 4:  you not see how this is potentially a problem?
Speaker 3:  We had one of those when I was at Wired, this was during the 2016 election
Speaker 3:  and somebody had downloaded a bunch of like jokey
Speaker 3:  political extensions onto their computer and one of them replaced every
Speaker 3:  mention of Donald Trump with the phrase Tiny Hands. And,
Speaker 3:  and it's like a very funny joke cuz you're reading the internet. But then
Speaker 3:  they filed a story about Donald Trump and
Speaker 3:  missed one of the times where the browser had changed like in
Speaker 3:  our CMS to Tiny Hands. So we published a story in which
Speaker 3:  this person had typed Donald Trump and it spit out tiny
Speaker 3:  hands. It was really, it was really something special
Speaker 4:  Man. Yeah. Okay, so so
Speaker 4:  what he said bundle this is I, I did wanna, I want to see on this too
Speaker 4:  because a lot of what happens is you were talking about Chrome.
Speaker 4:  So like Chrome's a very popular browser as you know,
Speaker 4:  it's free and a calm and scammy thing is people will bundle
Speaker 4:  free software with this predatory unwanted
Speaker 4:  software if we're allowed to call it malware, spyware, adware.
Speaker 4:  It like gets into weird legal territory. Sure. But basically there's the
Speaker 4:  software you want and you should just get that. But instead you're getting
Speaker 4:  this bundle that has a bunch of other bad things in it. And
Speaker 4:  that happens very often with browsers. I suspect that what
Speaker 4:  is happening here, the reason it's sending him to Bing is there is
Speaker 4:  some, I don't think Microsoft is purposefully
Speaker 4:  paying this like adware company. Like I don't think that
Speaker 4:  that's what's happening. But it is broadly true
Speaker 4:  that like Google pays Mozilla
Speaker 4:  to have the default Firefox search go to google.com
Speaker 4:  because Google makes money through advertising when people search things
Speaker 4:  on google.com. And so for a while they were paying
Speaker 4:  Apple, I mean they're still paying Apple, right? For, for the iPhone searches
Speaker 4:  that direct to google.com billions of dollars. So
Speaker 4:  I suspect that one way or another that
Speaker 4:  money is going from being to
Speaker 4:  these scammy people with lots of intermediaries that make it
Speaker 4:  hard for Bing to know who exactly they're paying. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  I think that's right. And that like, to be clear, all of that can be done
Speaker 3:  without Microsoft doing anything nefarious or even anything at all.
Speaker 3:  Like I think it's very unlikely that Microsoft is like loading adware into
Speaker 3:  Chrome extensions. It'd be amazing if that were true, but I mean it'd be
Speaker 3:  amazing.
Speaker 4:  I think it's, I think it's probably a Microsoft executive who had had too
Speaker 4:  much and sort of went joker mode and then they're like, we don't know
Speaker 4:  what happened to
Speaker 3:  Him. Just call it bundle, leave it alone. He
Speaker 4:  Just makes, he just makes it ad where now.
Speaker 3:  No, but it is one of the main things that these extensions
Speaker 3:  do is they will insert ads onto
Speaker 3:  websites in such a way that if you then click those ads,
Speaker 3:  they make money. Right. So like the main two things, a browser extension
Speaker 3:  that you don't want will do is collect all of your data and sell it to somebody
Speaker 3:  or put ads into your experience or replace the ads you're
Speaker 3:  seeing with other ads and make money that way. So it's
Speaker 3:  like 98% of the time it's like if some hack is happening on the internet,
Speaker 3:  it's somebody trying to find like a cheap way to make money, right? Like,
Speaker 3:  like that's usually what this is. Yeah. And in in this case, that is kind
Speaker 3:  of the overwhelming thing And one of the things that I've seen a lot of,
Speaker 3:  and there was this big story, I forget when relatively recently where
Speaker 3:  McAfee found a bunch of really well known Chrome extensions
Speaker 3:  including the one Netflix party where you can like CoWatch Netflix with your
Speaker 3:  friends. What Netflix party was doing was all the things Netflix
Speaker 3:  party was supposed to do. But then also doing things
Speaker 3:  like adding affiliate links when you go to e-commerce websites
Speaker 3:  so that it makes money and all this is just like sneakily happening in the
Speaker 3:  background and you never see it because it's able to get in between you and
Speaker 3:  the browser because that's what Chrome extensions do. And so it's just that
Speaker 3:  kind of thing that it's like often you might not even notice but they are,
Speaker 3:  they are aware of what you're doing and they're either changing it in some
Speaker 3:  way or taking something from you. So my read of it is not that
Speaker 3:  like all chrome extensions are dangerous, I do think the fact that they automatically
Speaker 3:  update in the background without telling you is dangerous, but also like
Speaker 3:  it is the kind of thing that you should be super, super, super aware of what
Speaker 3:  you're downloading and make sure, the advice I always give people is never
Speaker 3:  search in the store. Always go from like if you're looking for an app's Chrome
Speaker 3:  extension, go to the app and find the link to the Chrome extension from there.
Speaker 3:  Cuz if you go into the Chrome web store and search for an app, you're gonna
Speaker 3:  get a hundred things that all look the same. 99 of them are scammy and one
Speaker 3:  of them is real and it's often very hard to know. So if you need to have
Speaker 3:  a Chrome extension and you should use only the bare minimum for all the reasons
Speaker 3:  we've been describing, like find it from somewhere else. Don't just go hunting
Speaker 3:  through the Chrome store for things that seem cool because like there be
Speaker 3:  dragons.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And, and if you're listening to this and and being like, what can I
Speaker 4:  do? Like go to your Chrome, you know,
Speaker 4:  check out what the extensions are. It's chrome colon
Speaker 4:  slash slash extensions. Right. But you can see
Speaker 4:  it'll just show you everything and you can
Speaker 4:  like a absolutely delete anything you do not recognize or that you are like,
Speaker 4:  oh I sort of remember installing that, but I don't really use it. Like you
Speaker 4:  should really have as few as possible. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  A hundred percent. If you, if you don't use it like every day, you probably
Speaker 3:  shouldn't have it. It's, it's worth the like extra two clicks
Speaker 3:  in the browser to not have this stuff sitting between you and everything
Speaker 3:  you do on the internet is my general read.
Speaker 4:  Totally. All right, should we do another one?
Speaker 3:  Yeah, let's, let's move on. So let's see, we have, we have a couple
Speaker 3:  in a row about passwords. So let's, let's knock those out first.
Speaker 3:  First we have one from Eduardo to that
Speaker 6:  Hello the Verge team. Second question about
Speaker 6:  passwords. I use different passwords for every single app
Speaker 6:  or website that I log into, but
Speaker 6:  I'm deeply into the Apple ecosystem. So my question
Speaker 6:  is should I go into the suggested
Speaker 6:  passwords or should I just keep using my own
Speaker 6:  different passwords for everything? Is there any
Speaker 6:  drawback on going into the Apple passwords
Speaker 6:  or we'll all be able to do everything
Speaker 6:  I've been doing so far. Thanks.
Speaker 3:  Okay, so first of all Eduardo, kudos for using different passwords for
Speaker 3:  everything that immediately puts you ahead of almost everybody. So congratulations.
Speaker 3:  This is the question that sent me down the deepest, weirdest rabbit hole
Speaker 3:  of any of the questions we got. But before I get real weird about random
Speaker 3:  number generators, which is gonna happen, what are your thoughts Russell?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I mean I think, so partially this is like a question about password
Speaker 4:  strength, right? Because if he's coming up with these different passwords,
Speaker 4:  they're presumably sort of human comprehensible passwords. Yes.
Speaker 4:  Not just random strengths of, And so it's like is it better to
Speaker 4:  use the random strings that Apple is using? And I don't
Speaker 4:  think it's a huge deal. I think the main,
Speaker 4:  so the the, the place where your password strength is
Speaker 4:  most likely to be tested is you can't just guess
Speaker 4:  millions of passwords at once on like the Gmail login screen.
Speaker 4:  Like they will, they will catch on, they're like, this seems like a robot
Speaker 4:  is just doing 1, 2, 3 and then the next one.
Speaker 4:  But occasionally hash is hashed versions. So
Speaker 4:  hash is what the website is checking your password against. It sort of has
Speaker 4:  a hashing function that does a special dance to the password
Speaker 4:  that you inputted and then it checks it against, well this is
Speaker 4:  what all this is what the correct password should look like after the special
Speaker 4:  dance so that it doesn't just immediately know what your password is and
Speaker 4:  have that information for everything. And so you're not supposed to be able
Speaker 4:  to work back from the hash to the actual password, but if you
Speaker 4:  already know what the password is or you have, if
Speaker 4:  you like check a bunch of really common passwords and then that can help
Speaker 4:  you crack the hashing algorithm and undo the other ones,
Speaker 4:  then it's a problem. But like the difference between
Speaker 4:  a fairly uncommon word that's in a dictionary and a couple like
Speaker 4:  random characters and the complete gobbly book that
Speaker 4:  Apple spits out is just really not that significant. And I
Speaker 4:  wouldn't worry about it. I think the main question is like are you more
Speaker 4:  likely to lose it because it's not automatically being
Speaker 4:  logged by Apple's password manager, but that
Speaker 4:  also doesn't seem like a huge difference since it sounds like this system
Speaker 4:  is working for him.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, I think I agree with all of that actually. And I think the, the
Speaker 3:  two parts of this just jumped out to me are one the like
Speaker 3:  convenience thing you just talked about and I think to me the biggest
Speaker 3:  downside of using apple's the, the whole like key chain
Speaker 3:  system within Apple is it's very convenient but it's also tied to all of
Speaker 3:  your other Apple stuff, right? And like one very common sense cybersecurity
Speaker 3:  piece of advice is don't have all your eggs in one basket. And so
Speaker 3:  the idea of if somebody gets into my iCloud they can also get into my password
Speaker 3:  should make you nervous and there's a, there are good ways to get around
Speaker 3:  that by like protecting your iCloud and multifactor authentication and all
Speaker 3:  that stuff stuff. But like I would, I would say the only reason not to do
Speaker 3:  it is that a, it's not very cross platform. So if you use other devices pass
Speaker 3:  key chain doesn't work all that well and it is attached to all of your other
Speaker 3:  Apple stuff. So do it that way. You will, To your point about the randomness,
Speaker 3:  I think you're exactly right. I think my worry would be that for somebody
Speaker 3:  like our friend Eduardo here, that when they say I have different passwords
Speaker 3:  for everything, what they actually mean is like variations on a theme where
Speaker 3:  it's like I have one password that is like cool kids and then I have
Speaker 3:  another one that's cool kids with two S's and then I have one that's cool
Speaker 3:  kids six and that is not great password hygiene,
Speaker 3:  it's better than having the same password for everything, but it's not great
Speaker 3:  password hygiene because Well
Speaker 4:  Go ahead. Yeah. And, and it's worth going into what the attack is there.
Speaker 4:  So there are these like LinkedIn
Speaker 4:  was breached in like 2009 or something 2011, it's, it was
Speaker 4:  a while ago. This is all public, this is not, I'm not blowing up on your
Speaker 4:  spot, but then this means that like anyone on the internet who wants it
Speaker 4:  basically by now has the LinkedIn password I was using
Speaker 4:  in 2011. Yes. Right. And so if I was using
Speaker 4:  that for anything else, when they were able to get to it, they
Speaker 4:  probably went through, you know, well what's Russell's Gmail account? What's
Speaker 4:  Russell's other account? Let's see if the same password
Speaker 4:  works. Right? Right. And a lot of times they have this password
Speaker 4:  and the breach isn't public, no one knows about it. And so
Speaker 4:  they're likely to have sort of find out about it before you do. Now
Speaker 4:  are they going to try, well, okay, what about Russell's password?
Speaker 4:  But the number's slightly different. Exactly. What about Russell's password?
Speaker 4:  And there's some extra S's on one hand, like they're doing this
Speaker 4:  with 10 million passwords and just running through the list because
Speaker 4:  it's fairly, it's rare that you get a hit, it's just like it's worth
Speaker 4:  it if we get a hit. On the other hand, they have a lot of
Speaker 4:  time and not a lot of these breach things, so they're probably gonna try
Speaker 4:  as much as they can get away with and that's, that's why
Speaker 4:  the password hygiene of like here's this slight alteration
Speaker 4:  is not great if a password very, very similar to
Speaker 4:  that gets breached.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, I think that's right. And I think the, the deep rabbit hole I went
Speaker 3:  down was about pseudo random number generators and this idea
Speaker 3:  that even things that purport to give you random sets
Speaker 3:  of characters are not random, right? Like computers on their own can't do
Speaker 3:  random. There is the logic. So what they do is they start basically from
Speaker 3:  what's called a seed and then run an algorithm to do what is this, what looks
Speaker 3:  a lot like randomness? But if you can figure out what that seed is,
Speaker 3:  you then know where the randomness started from and you can start to figure
Speaker 3:  it out. So Bruce Schneider, who is a, a security researcher who has done
Speaker 3:  a lot of work on this over the years, a thing he talks about that I like
Speaker 3:  and I think is a useful framework to think about all of this is basically
Speaker 3:  like degrees of entropy, right? Like if I, if all of my passwords
Speaker 3:  are one last character off, that's one degree of entropy, right? If
Speaker 3:  you know all of my password except that one character, all you have to do
Speaker 3:  is figure out one thing. But if you, if you don't know any of my password
Speaker 3:  because it's all different, you're starting from nothing and suddenly the
Speaker 3:  like work you have to do to get there is much, much stronger. So I think
Speaker 3:  in a case like this, what I went the rabbit hole I really went down is like,
Speaker 3:  is Apple's pseudo random number generator better than the competition?
Speaker 3:  Pseudo random number generators? And the answer is like, not really.
Speaker 3:  There are a lot of very good ones out there. And the real question is
Speaker 3:  just about a lot of other things that actually, like the random number
Speaker 3:  generators are not likely what's gonna screw up your passwords over time.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. That's like, that's like your, you're like, is this plane
Speaker 4:  I'm getting on safe? And they're like, well let's look at the fuel.
Speaker 4:  Exactly. Who's using the best tool? It's like, it's, it's, it's probably,
Speaker 4:  it's not gonna come down to that. Is it information?
Speaker 3:  Yes. But is is it, is it gonna be the difference? Almost certainly not.
Speaker 3:  But generally, like what I would say is, is think about entropy, right? And
Speaker 3:  if you want to keep your password as secure as possible, have as much entropy
Speaker 3:  between your different passwords as you possibly can. And if that means letting
Speaker 3:  Apple fill it out for you and save it in ways that everyone agrees are
Speaker 3:  solid and secure, that works. I use one password, which I love
Speaker 3:  very much. I I will stand for one password to anyone who listens. It's
Speaker 3:  a really good password manager. There are a lot of good ones out there and
Speaker 3:  I think having them be randomly selected for me, I don't know
Speaker 3:  most of my passwords. And I like it that way and I feel like that's, that's
Speaker 3:  where everyone should be. Let let a system know my passwords and then I don't
Speaker 3:  have to.
Speaker 4:  Absolutely.
Speaker 3:  Alright, let's move on.
Speaker 4:  So what's the, what's the other, yeah, what's the other password? I mean
Speaker 3:  Our next one is even weirder and I'm very excited. It's from Leon.
Speaker 3:  Let's hear it.
Speaker 7:  Hey Vergecast team, it's Leon from Virginia.
Speaker 7:  What's up with websites having a maximum character limit
Speaker 7:  for their passwords? Like why do I have to create a password
Speaker 7:  with a maximum of eight or 12 characters?
Speaker 7:  Why is that safe? Thanks.
Speaker 3:  This is the other question that sent me down a crazy rabbit hole. Yeah. And
Speaker 3:  it was deeply unsatisfied. It's,
Speaker 4:  I mean, it's not safe, right? Like broadly these limits are
Speaker 4:  bad security people don't like them. I think that the reason
Speaker 4:  that you see them is kind of has to do with
Speaker 4:  making life easier for the architects of these systems more than
Speaker 4:  like security fundamentals. But it sounds like David, you have
Speaker 4:  a lot of research to, to spill out.
Speaker 3:  No, so you're, you're right, but you're missing one piece of the
Speaker 3:  equation, which is users. The simple truth of the matter, based on all the
Speaker 3:  research I've done and all the people I've talked to, is that fundamentally
Speaker 3:  if you allow people to have 500 character passwords, they
Speaker 3:  will forget them. They will type them incorrectly. They will call customer
Speaker 3:  service to reset their passwords more often. And that will suck for everyone
Speaker 3:  involved. And so I went down looking for like
Speaker 3:  really useful technical answers and what it seems like is, on the one
Speaker 3:  hand, you're right that like, and especially in the early days of the
Speaker 3:  internet, there was a lot of like technological systems that just couldn't
Speaker 3:  handle that much data coming in at the same time. Like if you're sending
Speaker 3:  somebody a one megabyte password, that's a lot. And it was especially a lot
Speaker 3:  many years ago. So,
Speaker 4:  Well, and and also that like remember there's the hashing algorithms, like
Speaker 4:  if you can know the amount of
Speaker 4:  information very precisely, it lets you, it just sort of
Speaker 4:  smooths things out. Totally.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. And then there that just sort of became the norm. So people kept doing
Speaker 3:  it. But then I was looking and like the, the National Institute of Standards
Speaker 3:  in Technology has a bunch of rules about passwords and what they actually
Speaker 3:  recommend is that you allow at least 64 characters
Speaker 3:  because yeah, the, the kind of new password theory
Speaker 3:  is like, what you don't need is just a bunch of like random he decimal stuff,
Speaker 3:  which you need is like a long, relatively random string of words
Speaker 3:  that you can remember that that's actually the most useful thing. Like if
Speaker 3:  it's five words
Speaker 4:  In a
Speaker 3:  Row, I, so I will, you can do it.
Speaker 4:  I will say at the risk of compromising my own security, so this is the
Speaker 4:  past phrase, right? Think of some phrase that you remember and I'm a
Speaker 4:  word guy, so I remember phrases like, there are a lot of phrases where
Speaker 4:  I'm like, oh yeah, that one line really meant something to me. And so
Speaker 4:  when we, I was setting up my like work account for
Speaker 4:  Vox Media, I did the phrase and I was like, I'm not gonna, you know,
Speaker 4:  this is gonna be in my password manager, I'm not gonna type this in that
Speaker 4:  much. And then as it went on, it sort of
Speaker 4:  propagated until now it's the thing I need to
Speaker 4:  type in every time I wake up my laptop
Speaker 4:  and it's like, it's like a bunch of words long, like it's over
Speaker 4:  50 characters. It's it, and and also if I can't see
Speaker 4:  it, I'll like have a typo sometimes. So it'll take me like two or three tries
Speaker 4:  and I'm just trying to like mute whatever song is playing. It's
Speaker 4:  really, so that's a, that's a cautionary tale. I guess
Speaker 3:  It's just like the first chapter of Moby Dick every time you wanna wake up
Speaker 3:  your computer.
Speaker 4:  Oh my god, how did you guys, No, but I mean it's really like,
Speaker 4:  yeah, I'm trying not to do it. I'm, I'm trying not to put any information
Speaker 4:  out there that would, that would make it easy for that actors. But yeah,
Speaker 4:  it's, so think about the fact that you'll have to
Speaker 4:  maybe type this in a lot,
Speaker 3:  But I think yeah, in general it is. I I think I would agree bad
Speaker 3:  form if they only allow you to have something like eight characters, what
Speaker 3:  does seem to be true is there are pretty severe diminishing returns after
Speaker 3:  about 20, Hmm I dunno if that's a magic number, but it that,
Speaker 3:  that one kind of came up a bunch that like the difference between a 20 character
Speaker 3:  password and a 200 character password is not massive in
Speaker 3:  terms of like, can a regular person brute force their way into getting your
Speaker 3:  password? Whereas the difference between eight and 20 is when it goes from
Speaker 3:  like hard but feasible to hard and sort of infeasible.
Speaker 3:  So I think, yeah, if, if you're only allowed to have short passwords, you
Speaker 3:  should, you should yell at them to let you have longer ones is what I would
Speaker 3:  say.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Cool. Do you have short passwords? I feel like I just shamed you by accident.
Speaker 3:  You're changing all your passwords
Speaker 4:  For, I will say I, I changed from on the,
Speaker 4:  in the iPhone unlock they give you the option of four
Speaker 4:  numbers, which the security people really don't like. Or six
Speaker 4:  numbers, which is, you know, it's powers of 10 or it's a
Speaker 4:  hundred times more secure or this alpha numeric thing, which
Speaker 4:  you're gonna type in I keyboard, which is probably the best thing to do.
Speaker 4:  But I mean, who has the time? I'm not gonna
Speaker 3:  Honestly like it's, I'm a four, I'm a four digit
Speaker 3:  iPhone password person. Wow. And I'm ashamed of it like I am. It's
Speaker 3:  not great and and the best part is it defaults to six and it makes you
Speaker 3:  change to four when you set up your phone it's like, do you wanna make a
Speaker 3:  stupid decision right now? And every time I'm like, yes I do. Thank you for
Speaker 3:  asking.
Speaker 3:  I'm very happy to do so. Yeah. Right. We need to take a break and then we're
Speaker 3:  gonna come back and answer a couple more questions, including with our very
Speaker 3:  good friends Eli Patel. We'll be right back.
Speaker 9:  Fox Creative,
Speaker 11:  This is advertiser content from Zelle.
Speaker 11:  So you find the perfect puppy online, you email, they
Speaker 11:  send cute photos and say act fast. Lots of people want this puppy.
Speaker 11:  Send me the $500 adoption fee tonight and she's all yours.
Speaker 11:  You send it, you wait and they just
Speaker 11:  disappear. No puppy, no money.
Speaker 10:  You know, everyone thinks these are new since the internet. They're not
Speaker 11:  Robert Burda, CEO of the Cyber Crime Support Network says
Speaker 11:  puppy scams are just one example of countless online marketplace
Speaker 11:  scams. Scams aren't new but the Internet's speed and anonymity are,
Speaker 10:  They've always exploited human nature. They're always trying to build that
Speaker 10:  sense of urgency. There's nothing that can't wait. Slow
Speaker 10:  down spot check and don't send the money because they know
Speaker 10:  that once they convince you to let it go, very little chance is coming back.
Speaker 11:  Elle wants you to pay it safe, treat every transaction like cash
Speaker 11:  and only send money to people you know and trust. Learn more safety
Speaker 11:  tips@ellepay.com.
Speaker 3:  Okay, next up we have a question I think a
Speaker 3:  bunch of us got very excited about this is from our friend Chuck who has
Speaker 3:  a question about babies.
Speaker 12:  Hey guys, this might be very niche so maybe it doesn't go on the show,
Speaker 12:  but maybe it could go on an article sometime I have a
Speaker 12:  newborn and I don't know how to keep her safe from
Speaker 12:  online stuff. Like do I need to do anything? Do I do nothing?
Speaker 12:  So yeah, I just, I don't want to leave doors
Speaker 12:  open, but yeah, I don't, there's nothing good out there
Speaker 12:  that says like, do this and you'll be safe. Thanks. Love the show.
Speaker 12:  Bye.
Speaker 3:  Okay. I, this question gives me so many feelings and you can just,
Speaker 3:  you can just feel the like vibes and energy from
Speaker 3:  this person. Neil Patella is here to help us answer this question. Hello
Speaker 3:  Nelia, you are our resident baby expert. Congratulations.
Speaker 4:  That's bad
Speaker 13:  For America.
Speaker 4:  You are all that stands between the horrors of the
Speaker 4:  internet and the Children of America and
Speaker 4:  some of Canada.
Speaker 13:  The whole show to parent blogging, that's what I do here. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  I will say has been threatening to do this ever since he had children. So
Speaker 3:  it's, it's gonna happen eventually. What I feel like we, we could start almost
Speaker 3:  anywhere here, but there's like, is there stock parenting
Speaker 3:  advice for what you should do? Like, cuz there, there, there comes a time
Speaker 3:  when like your kid is gonna start wanting to be online and you have to do
Speaker 3:  things about that. But we're talking even way before then. This is the like
Speaker 3:  they don't even know what the internet is yet. Do you have responsibilities
Speaker 3:  to them? Which I think is a super interesting question.
Speaker 13:  Yeah, well David, you're about to have a kid so you're gonna become the
Speaker 13:  new, Am I allowed to say that on the show? Do the people know,
Speaker 3:  The people don't know, They know Now I this is, this is as good a time as
Speaker 3:  any, my wife is due December and I'm gonna be the version is the next baby
Speaker 3:  correspondent.
Speaker 4:  Congratulations.
Speaker 3:  It's great. Thank you. You
Speaker 13:  Gotta, you gotta rotate in a new one because the kids keep getting relentlessly
Speaker 13:  older. It's a real problem. So here's what I would say
Speaker 13:  to everybody, almost everything about being a first
Speaker 13:  time parent is just how afraid you choose to be and how
Speaker 13:  much you allow corporate America to pray on that fear.
Speaker 13:  The best advice I ever got was from my friend Spencer Hall who some of you
Speaker 13:  may know from other endeavors in the internet and he just looked at me very
Speaker 13:  seriously. I think he has like four kids and he was like, babies are more
Speaker 13:  resilient than you think and if you just hold that in your head, you're
Speaker 13:  gonna be like, just remember people did this before any technology
Speaker 13:  existed. That's how you got here. So he's like, hold onto that. The second
Speaker 13:  thing I'll say much more specifically about computers is
Speaker 13:  once you realize that all that's designed to pray in your fear, you realize
Speaker 13:  that a lot of like computer products exist to just reassure you
Speaker 13:  that actually provide you like no additional safety.
Speaker 13:  So there's like infinity baby monitors and socks
Speaker 13:  and snooze that you can buy and you just have to decide how much you
Speaker 13:  wanna like participate in that universe of things. Our decision
Speaker 13:  was that we didn't want anything that required a user
Speaker 13:  account. Ooh. Like we just didn't wanna start sharing data about our kid
Speaker 13:  at any moment. So we did not buy a connected
Speaker 13:  baby camera. We bought the UFE one that's on Amazon I'm sure by now.
Speaker 13:  There are many iterations of it, but there was one that everyone bought
Speaker 13:  and then ufe, which is the division of anchor, came out with like this slightly
Speaker 13:  upgraded riff on that one And we, we just have that one and it works
Speaker 13:  great and it is, you know, like a proprietary RF protocol. It's a
Speaker 13:  rock solid in our house, no wifi involved and it has a little
Speaker 13:  piece of hardware. That's great. So I, we carry around a little
Speaker 13:  screen in our house to watch our kid that is
Speaker 3:  So your your thinking was not only like no user
Speaker 3:  accounts for your kid but no user accounts related to your
Speaker 3:  kid like, cuz it wouldn't have been, it wouldn't have been your kid's name
Speaker 3:  on the UVA or on the baby monitor thing, it would've been yours but even
Speaker 3:  still like that crossed the line.
Speaker 13:  Yeah, I wanted, I'll use a security term here. I wanted to air gap the baby
Speaker 13:  from the internet for as long as possible.
Speaker 3:  Oh I love that. Okay, that's good. Yeah,
Speaker 13:  Right. So I didn't want anything connected to the internet near
Speaker 13:  the baby for as long as I could hold off air
Speaker 3:  Gap. Your baby is a verge t-shirt that needs to, this is a thing we're gonna
Speaker 3:  make onesies, it's gonna say air gap, it's gonna be incredible.
Speaker 13:  One thing you're gonna want to do is track a bunch of baby
Speaker 13:  stuff related to a newborn when they eat, when they poop, when they sleep
Speaker 13:  and there's infinity apps that are, you know, you can log into and you can
Speaker 13:  use them and we don't wanna use them. So we use one called Sprout which
Speaker 13:  syncs the database over iCloud to another phone using a key.
Speaker 13:  There's no user accounts and they actually advertise it as having no user
Speaker 13:  accounts. Now this is like four years ago, we have not tracked our four
Speaker 13:  year olds sleeping and pooping. We're good. She lets us know when it's
Speaker 13:  gonna happen.
Speaker 4:  I mean are you weighing it? What, what's the fine grain of the
Speaker 4:  data? How much data on the poop are we collecting here?
Speaker 13:  Well so when you have a newborn you don't sleep very often.
Speaker 13:  So your memory of what happened when
Speaker 13:  becomes very limited and you're like, did I feed the baby?
Speaker 13:  And you just don't remember and you certainly don't remember how much or
Speaker 13:  what you fed them cause it's like two in the morning. So like how many
Speaker 13:  ounces of milk did I feed? The baby is like, you are just not gonna remember
Speaker 13:  this five hours from now. So you just track that stuff. Just have a log
Speaker 13:  between you and your partner. Cuz ideally one of you is asleep while the
Speaker 13:  other thing is happening. Ideally, I said sometimes it's just a pure panic
Speaker 13:  situation. So we just constantly made choices
Speaker 13:  to keep the kid away from the internet and at some
Speaker 13:  point your parenting choice is going to be in order
Speaker 13:  to make this child eat or survive a restaurant or be in an airplane,
Speaker 13:  we're gonna give them a tablet and then all of it kind of goes up the window.
Speaker 13:  But for us anyhow, our choice was very much no user
Speaker 13:  accounts, no wifi connected toys, none of this stuff where I have to become
Speaker 13:  the IT manager of like a very helpless human
Speaker 13:  beings internet presence. Because once you open the door
Speaker 13:  you're just fully down the road.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  How about that? The, the only other big picture question I can think of that
Speaker 3:  it would be useful to ask or to like have answers to pretty early on would
Speaker 3:  be like how do we take and share pictures of our
Speaker 3:  child in a way that makes us comfortable?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I I will say, so my, I have two
Speaker 4:  nieces and my brother, I think I was impressed by this although I
Speaker 4:  think maybe some people would be worried about it, but basically they didn't
Speaker 4:  want to be on Facebook or putting like have
Speaker 4:  for Facebook to have accessible record of various pictures of
Speaker 4:  of the girls. And so, but you wanna
Speaker 4:  share it with family. And so they set up this Tumblr
Speaker 4:  that is public to the internet but that like only
Speaker 4:  cer like only the family members really have the address to, and it doesn't
Speaker 4:  have their names on it or any like words whatsoever. It's
Speaker 4:  just a public facing webpage on the internet, which I
Speaker 4:  think worked out for them. I mean the main thing is like grandma doesn't
Speaker 4:  have to get a Facebook account or like maintain access to a Facebook account,
Speaker 4:  which I think is probably good And like, you know, grandma
Speaker 4:  doesn't really wanna see, Grandma doesn't wanna go on Facebook,
Speaker 4:  she just wants to see pictures of her grandchildren. So yes, it's fine. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I so I, I don't know if that's like, if that solves every problem
Speaker 4:  but that is a baby picture hack I have heard.
Speaker 13:  So that one I buy it right cuz you, you're not inside a big tech like
Speaker 13:  Tumblr is not big tech. It's like small struggling tech.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, small to medium tech I think. Yeah.
Speaker 13:  But public to the internet terrifies me. Right. Like that's a, that's just
Speaker 13:  a URL on the internet that could get picked up. That clear view. AI is looking
Speaker 13:  at pictures like who knows, you can't see what's happening.
Speaker 4:  Well it's not tied to their names. Right. So it's just these
Speaker 4:  pictures of people on the internet. It's true. It could get scraped them.
Speaker 4:  I mean they didn't,
Speaker 13:  So one day this family is gonna be in a Walmart looking at like empty photo
Speaker 13:  frames and being like, well that is us.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 13:  Very unfortunate. So we, we kind of went the other way
Speaker 13:  which requires more trust but feels more closed. So
Speaker 13:  we, we started with Apple Photos which seemed very closed share photo
Speaker 13:  streams and then more people wanna be involved. And then in particular
Speaker 13:  this thing about grandma wanting to see the photos, we wanted to set up
Speaker 13:  digital photo frames that just had the newest photos on them for various
Speaker 13:  people in our family. So then we switched to Google photos,
Speaker 13:  which Google will insist as a closed private ecosystem.
Speaker 13:  But we were able to just set up Google homes and then
Speaker 13:  lots of digital photo frames, like just the ones you can buy have Google
Speaker 13:  photos, connections. So they just, we just have one album that we add photos
Speaker 13:  to and it shows up on picture frames in our various family member's house.
Speaker 13:  So they don't have to do anything. And the more that I, and that feels like
Speaker 13:  I am just in control of that database of pictures and I am
Speaker 13:  control of who has access to it. And that feels
Speaker 13:  important to me as she's gotten older, as Max has gotten older, I've stopped
Speaker 13:  posting her Instagram as much. I feel like babies are fine and now
Speaker 13:  she's like a person with a personality and I feel very like exploitive
Speaker 13:  of her personality. Like that's just a choice that she's gonna have to make
Speaker 13:  over time and I'm gonna tell her not to do it. But,
Speaker 4:  Well I mean if you're, if you're going through the GR sponsorship
Speaker 13:  When she was first
Speaker 4:  Get brand deals and
Speaker 13:  She was first
Speaker 4:  Born, she's gotta be on the gram,
Speaker 13:  We gotta get this kid in the catalog and then it turns out Benton doesn't
Speaker 13:  exist anymore. So my one target was gone.
Speaker 3:  I dunno, she's got good hair. You could work with that. Yeah. Lot of places
Speaker 3:  to go. Any, are there any other like, I'm just even trying to think about
Speaker 3:  like what are the questions you should be asking early on and like conversations
Speaker 3:  you should be having? Are there other big ones we haven't hit on yet?
Speaker 13:  The main ones are really just how public do you want your
Speaker 13:  child's life to be? Yeah. Right. Like you start to have all these
Speaker 13:  experiences and it turns out being a parent, parent is like among the most
Speaker 13:  universal experience you can have. You can relate to all kinds of people
Speaker 13:  just by talking about your child. That's why people talk about their kids
Speaker 13:  so much. It's very annoying before you have a kid and then you have a kid
Speaker 13:  and you realize why it keeps happening. There's a reason people wanna show
Speaker 13:  you photos.
Speaker 3:  There's kids in the weather. Like those are the only two things. Yeah.
Speaker 13:  Sort of lots and lots of people have all Yeah. Which is great
Speaker 13:  but there's an instinct to do it very publicly on the internet. There's
Speaker 13:  an instinct to profit running for some people. Like you could be a, a
Speaker 13:  parent YouTuber like all this stuff. I think you gotta make that decision
Speaker 13:  early and like hold onto it because otherwise you're, I
Speaker 13:  I think a lot of people are gonna grow up and unless your parents been talking
Speaker 13:  about them in public for a very long time and they are not like they lose,
Speaker 13:  they might lose a sense of agency over who they get to be cuz there's this
Speaker 13:  rich backstory about their life. And I think you just have to make that
Speaker 13:  decision that I have thought about that a lot with our kid. I've talked
Speaker 13:  to other parents who think about that a lot. I think there's a rich and
Speaker 13:  very debate about that in the world of the internet,
Speaker 13:  like in the world of internet parenting. And so that's the one that I would
Speaker 13:  just encourage people to think about. It's like really hard to see when
Speaker 13:  you have a newborn. It's just a picture of a newborn like that is kind of
Speaker 13:  a story about you and how much you're not sleeping but soon it becomes a
Speaker 13:  story about them and you gotta flip that switch.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I will say the, the point that the internet is just there to make you
Speaker 3:  afraid and sell you stuff is a useful one to remember and has been very useful
Speaker 3:  for me to remember even in this like we're in the phase now of like trying
Speaker 3:  to figure out like what happens when you give birth and all the things you
Speaker 3:  have to do. And it's like I've started reading about sleep training and the
Speaker 3:  only thing I've learned about sleep training is no matter what you do, you're
Speaker 3:  wrong and you're a bad person and you hate your kids and it costs millions
Speaker 3:  of dollars to buy all the right products to solve all of their problems.
Speaker 3:  And so I just, like, every time I go on the internet now I have to just be
Speaker 3:  like the internet is here to lie to me and sell me things and that is what
Speaker 3:  this is for. And I, I am now like I am everyone's target demo,
Speaker 3:  like new parents are everyone's target demo.
Speaker 13:  Cause you're terrified. Yeah. Yeah. And you and you
Speaker 13:  whatever, whatever you might say about modern society, you don't have all
Speaker 13:  the people around you to keep you from being terrified, which is like a
Speaker 13:  real thing.
Speaker 3:  Right. We need to let you go. We have some more questions to get to you,
Speaker 3:  but thank you and, and you know, good luck to all of us. Good luck Dave.
Speaker 13:  I'll buy you some
Speaker 3:  Booze. Alright Russell, we have a couple more. We're just gonna, we're gonna
Speaker 3:  blow through these really fast one that we didn't
Speaker 3:  technically choose to do here. But I just wanna talk about quickly cuz this,
Speaker 3:  this is a thing that comes up a lot in conversations that we have with like
Speaker 3:  regular people thinking about cybersecurity is VPNs. Liam, do we have Ben's
Speaker 3:  question we can play about VPNs?
Speaker 14:  Hey Verge, this is Ben. I've been thinking about
Speaker 14:  subscribing to a VPN service, but it's very
Speaker 14:  unclear which one is the best. Some of the most
Speaker 14:  promoted ones like Express and Nord VPN
Speaker 14:  have questionable audits. And yeah,
Speaker 14:  just very curious about what VPN service people should
Speaker 14:  subscribe to. Thanks.
Speaker 3:  I love this question because I find find it completely impossible and I
Speaker 3:  feel like we've talked a lot about just deciding who to trust and who not
Speaker 3:  to trust in the course of this episode. Yeah, and I feel like this is sort
Speaker 3:  of the same thing. Like fundamentally if you get
Speaker 3:  a vpn you are, it it it's like, it's like letting someone into
Speaker 3:  your house, right? Like you're, you are giving them a massive amount of
Speaker 3:  theoretical access to your stuff and a lot of them say they don't want it.
Speaker 3:  A lot of 'em say they don't store it, but like you just don't
Speaker 3:  know for absolute certain and it is fundamentally a question of trust. But
Speaker 3:  then if you don't do it, you're trusting, I don't know all of your browser
Speaker 3:  extensions and you're trusting Google and you're trusting Facebook, which
Speaker 3:  has all this kind of information. Like you just can't browse the internet
Speaker 3:  without somebody knowing. And at some point you just have to decide who you
Speaker 3:  trust the most. And I feel like it gets very nihilistic for me from there,
Speaker 3:  but that's kind of where I land.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I, it's funny, I was, I was writing about,
Speaker 4:  actually in the wifi coconut piece, there's this question of like, how much
Speaker 4:  control does like a router, like if the bad guy is controlling the
Speaker 4:  router that you're logging in through how like that's not good. How much
Speaker 4:  of a threat is that? And one of the, I I was thinking about it and I
Speaker 4:  realized one of the fundamental things you see in internet technology
Speaker 4:  at all sorts of different levels is you're basically using
Speaker 4:  encryption to secure info infrastructure. So it
Speaker 4:  doesn't matter who's controlling the router, it doesn't matter who's at the
Speaker 4:  is p you know, the router you, you'll have like WPA keys that are keeping
Speaker 4:  it from, from sort of being a point of attack. The ISP
Speaker 4:  ideal U have ssl and that's that level of encryption. The
Speaker 4:  VPN is kind of like adding another one. And so
Speaker 4:  there's a sense in which the attacks
Speaker 4:  that it helps against are if you are
Speaker 4:  working for a company like it's corporate security
Speaker 4:  and they're like, these are the plans to our next hot new airplane
Speaker 4:  and the bad guys wanna steal the plant. And so
Speaker 4:  we know exactly where the perimeter is of like who we trust and who we
Speaker 4:  don't. And if the VPN is running through the company, then ideally you're
Speaker 4:  not expanding the trust at, you know, at all because it's, it's running
Speaker 4:  through that same infrastructure. It's the same group of people who are gonna
Speaker 4:  have access to it, but you can have sort of an extra
Speaker 4:  layer of protection to log in through the conference wifi
Speaker 4:  and not get injected because the only thing you connect to is
Speaker 4:  this wi you know, this VPN service which then hardens the tunnel
Speaker 4:  through the rest of it. Right. Having said that, that is not
Speaker 4:  generally how I see people talking about why they're using
Speaker 4:  VPNs. Oh honestly, the most, maybe this is cuz I'm hanging
Speaker 4:  with a sketchy crowd, but like the most common thing is people like, well
Speaker 4:  this will keep me from getting sued for pirating movies or
Speaker 4:  something. Oh,
Speaker 3:  Absolutely. Or this is how I can watch stuff on Netflix that's only available
Speaker 3:  in another country. Those are the two things I hear the most.
Speaker 4:  Right. Well I, I mean, so the Netflix
Speaker 4:  geolocation thing that might be robust, I don't think that
Speaker 4:  Netflix is really cracking down on it yet because it would just be so,
Speaker 4:  it would be so much of a pain for them without, they don't really care if
Speaker 4:  this is happening anyway. So, but anything illegal you're doing,
Speaker 4:  if you're paying for a commercial VPN service, it's just
Speaker 4:  another subpoena that the police have to send. So they subpoena the VPN
Speaker 4:  service to then subpoena the ISP to then get to you
Speaker 4:  and like maybe it's in Switzerland so it's harder,
Speaker 4:  but like if you are the dread pirate Roberts or something, this is not going
Speaker 4:  to help you. And I see people talking as if it is,
Speaker 4:  and that, that to me is like my main experience
Speaker 4:  of engaging with VPNs. Very rarely do I see it lining up with
Speaker 4:  the actual threat model it could protect against
Speaker 3:  Yeah. That, that totally tracks. And I think in general, we talked a little
Speaker 3:  bit about VPNs with McKenna a while ago on this show, and one of the
Speaker 3:  things I heard over and over even from VPN people is
Speaker 3:  that if you're just a regular person doing regular internet things, you
Speaker 3:  probably don't need one. And even to your point about like what if the bad
Speaker 3:  guys are on the router, Like thanks to things like https, like they
Speaker 3:  can start to know what website I went to,
Speaker 3:  but not what I did there. And that stuff is
Speaker 3:  increasingly encrypted and the internet is, is much harder as a result. And
Speaker 3:  so the, the advice I've gotten from folks is basically like if you know
Speaker 3:  you have a specific thing that either you need to avoid being
Speaker 3:  seen for or you have a specific thing you
Speaker 3:  need access to that you can't get access to, those are good reasons to get
Speaker 3:  a vpn. But if you're just like a person in a coffee shop worried about security,
Speaker 3:  a VPN to your point is not actually going to solve that
Speaker 3:  sort of same mainstream problem.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Also, I trust my coffee shop more than I trust my
Speaker 4:  family. That's, to me, that's the pinnacle of, they're so nice.
Speaker 3:  Shout out to Russell's coffee shop somewhere in deep upstate New York,
Speaker 3:  I think, I don't know who's
Speaker 4:  To say.
Speaker 3:  Russell doesn't tell us where he is. That's his real cybersecurity trick.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I I keep operational security. No one knows where I am at any
Speaker 3:  Time. Yeah. He's in a, he's in a dark room with a black background and no
Speaker 3:  one's allowed to know what he's doing. All right, let's move on. We have
Speaker 3:  one more question to do before we get outta here. It is from Emmanuel.
Speaker 3:  Let's hear it. Hey
Speaker 15:  Verge, this is Emmanuel. I had a question related to your
Speaker 15:  security podcast that's coming up. I've always wondered what
Speaker 15:  could a bad website do to me? So for example, I,
Speaker 15:  I clicked on a, on a, a bad ad on, on Google search results
Speaker 15:  and I stayed on the website, didn't do anything. Then close my browser,
Speaker 15:  closed the window. What is the worst thing that could have happened to my
Speaker 15:  machine? Could, could and what could be installed? Like what do I have to
Speaker 15:  worry about? Thanks.
Speaker 3:  This is such a good question and made me realize I also have this question.
Speaker 4:  It made me very worried for Emmanuel Safety. Like, we're gonna find
Speaker 4:  out, this is the last communication anyone got
Speaker 3:  Emmanuel's just clicking every link everywhere just to see
Speaker 3:  like what could happen, what's the worst? So what's the answer? What is the
Speaker 3:  worst that could happen?
Speaker 4:  I, to me it's like, it's like what if the brakes stopped
Speaker 4:  working on your car? It's like there are so many bad things that could happen.
Speaker 4:  I almost don't even want to think about it. It's like, no, you should be
Speaker 4:  able to use the Right, Well
Speaker 3:  Let's let's frame this slightly differently then like
Speaker 4:  Yeah, yeah. It's,
Speaker 3:  I think one, one obvious bad thing that can happen to you on a computer
Speaker 3:  is that like you go to a website and it installs a keylogger and takes
Speaker 3:  your credit card information, right. Like that we grant, But I think the,
Speaker 3:  what seems to me to be implicit in this question is if I go to a bad
Speaker 3:  website and I leave that bad website before I do anything, can it do
Speaker 3:  anything to my computer after I leave the website?
Speaker 3:  And the answer to that I think is like unequivocally Yes, absolutely. Right?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, because you loaded loading the website. When, when we say
Speaker 4:  I'm on the website, what that means is the server
Speaker 4:  has sent this information to
Speaker 4:  your browser and your browser has used that information and sort of
Speaker 4:  executed the files to build the thing that you're looking
Speaker 4:  at. Right? But that could have also included, they're like,
Speaker 4:  run this code, it'll make this fancy cool ad that with the
Speaker 4:  little guy who dances around, he's gonna love it. And like it made
Speaker 4:  a fancy cool ad with a guy who danced around and you did love it, but it
Speaker 4:  also installed this malware, which is now like
Speaker 4:  encrypting your entire computer and gonna ransomware you or just
Speaker 4:  like hang out there for six months and gradually sort of expand its
Speaker 4:  access in the network. I mean I think the, the tricky thing is once
Speaker 4:  the perimeter has been breached, it's kind of like, well,
Speaker 4:  what mischief do they want to do? One, they're on the inside. It's like,
Speaker 4:  I, I don't know. I hope nothing too bad, but like it's out of my
Speaker 4:  control now.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I I spent a lot of time in prepping for this, talking to people and
Speaker 3:  reading about exploit kits. Oh yeah. It's just my god. Terrifying.
Speaker 3:  And basically it's, it's exactly what you're talking about. The idea is like
Speaker 3:  you, you load this website and what it does is it installs software on your
Speaker 3:  computer that essentially just looks for vulnerabilities, right? And it says
Speaker 3:  like, you know, do you have this technology to play
Speaker 3:  videos in your browser? No. Do you have this one to read PDFs in your browser?
Speaker 3:  Ah, you do. I'm gonna use that and just sort of open up a little hole in
Speaker 3:  it and then download whatever I feel like it's like,
Speaker 3:  and it's, it's, it's just once it's in it, it does sort of all this different
Speaker 3:  hunting, it finds its place and then it can just sit there and it can wait
Speaker 3:  as long as it needs to and then it just has access to your computer. And
Speaker 3:  this stuff is like, it, it's dormant forever. It's tiny, it's hard to find
Speaker 3:  and it just sits there sort of waiting to be activated. And it's gotten really
Speaker 3:  sophisticated to the point where like, like flash, if I'm remembering this
Speaker 3:  right, used to be like the main problem here, right? And it was like flash
Speaker 3:  was a garbage piece of software.
Speaker 4:  It was a very big
Speaker 3:  Problem that had full of loopholes and exploits and every
Speaker 3:  time you would load a flash thing it was loading a, an app from your computer
Speaker 3:  and running it. And by doing so they could put code in it and then
Speaker 3:  load other stuff. But there are still a bunch of ways like that into your
Speaker 3:  computer now.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I would say, I mean the other thing that classically people were worried
Speaker 4:  about, and this is something that, you know, in the time I've been working
Speaker 4:  at the Verge https adoption, including by the verge.com,
Speaker 4:  has just gone from sort of zero to 60. Yeah. Like it was, it was maybe
Speaker 4:  a third of websites in 20 I it was, it was definitely below
Speaker 4:  half and now we're well over 95%. It's sort of rare that you go somewhere
Speaker 4:  on the internet that doesn't have it. The result of that is these
Speaker 4:  injection attacks where someone is at the I S P or at the router or
Speaker 4:  at sort of tapping into some cable because they're the NSA
Speaker 4:  and they want to, you're sort of opening a legitimate
Speaker 4:  website, but they are injecting malware into it as sort of turning
Speaker 4:  it into a malicious website. You know, those are still
Speaker 4:  possible, but they're much harder to do. And so
Speaker 4:  seems to me in many ways things have gotten better. But it still is the
Speaker 4:  case that you should not like clicking the problem
Speaker 4:  is clicking the link to the website. Right. Not like once I'm on the
Speaker 4:  website, what do I do? Yeah.
Speaker 3:  But we should say, and I think I, I think not to like downplay any of this
Speaker 3:  stuff, but I feel like it, it continues to be a useful thing to remind people
Speaker 3:  that like most people get into trouble because they enter
Speaker 3:  information in places that they shouldn't. And this is like what you were
Speaker 3:  talking about earlier about like, don't give your credit card over the phone
Speaker 3:  and this like basic stuff. But like anytime you're gonna type in your username
Speaker 3:  and password, anytime you're gonna click on a link in your email, anytime
Speaker 3:  you're gonna type in your social security number or your home address or
Speaker 3:  whatever, like most people get into trouble because they give up information
Speaker 3:  willingly to people. They shouldn't. Like the malware stuff is real, the
Speaker 3:  exploit kit stuff is real. The stuff they can download is real. But like
Speaker 3:  you are much more likely to get in trouble by reading your credit card number
Speaker 3:  to someone you shouldn't than by like having your routers tapped by the nsa.
Speaker 4:  Well and also I think I, I mean even more immediately, the thing
Speaker 4:  right now that people are most likely to get taken by is
Speaker 4:  someone calling you on the phone and telling you they're from Texas.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And it's like Microsoft will not call you on the phone
Speaker 4:  to, because there's a problem with your office installation that will not
Speaker 4:  happen. They, they, they have email, they're good
Speaker 4:  at it. They know a lot about email. They'll send you an email and
Speaker 3:  Mostly they're avoiding you. They don't want to call you, they don't want
Speaker 3:  you to call them. Like if, if you ever get a customer support person who's
Speaker 3:  like desperate to talk to you, that should set off all your alarm bells because
Speaker 3:  that is not a thing that happens in real life. I'm just
Speaker 4:  Saying. Absolutely.
Speaker 3:  I like it. Alright. Any, any other like common sense security stuff we should
Speaker 3:  tell people? I feel like the advice we always give is like two factor authentication
Speaker 3:  is good. Do that.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, absolutely. I would say, yeah. I mean, work on
Speaker 4:  knife skills. Knife skills are always useful. That's more of a physical
Speaker 4:  security thing, but I tell everyone, you know, practice with a knife,
Speaker 3:  Online knife skills, couple a week.
Speaker 4:  Yep.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, I like it. All right, we should go. Russell. Thank you.
Speaker 3:  This has been very fun and enlightening and if anybody ever wants to talk
Speaker 3:  for many, many hours about pseudo random number generators, I now have all
Speaker 3:  of this information in my head and nothing to do with it. I know which ones
Speaker 3:  are good. I know which ones are bad. I have a lot of thoughts, but anyway,
Speaker 3:  follow all of us on Twitter. There's a ton more good cybersecurity stuff
Speaker 3:  we've done at the Verge the last couple of weeks and always because it is
Speaker 3:  always cybersecurity week on the verge.com. Russell is Russell
Speaker 3:  Brando on Twitter. Ne Eli is reckless on Twitter. I'm pierce on Twitter.
Speaker 3:  Thank you for listening. This is the Verge Cast. We will be back on Wednesday
Speaker 3:  and Friday with our regularly scheduled programming. We will see you then.
Speaker 3:  Rock and roll
Speaker 1:  Support for this episode comes from Zelle. You'd never
Speaker 1:  fall for an online scam, right? You use
Speaker 1:  two factor authentication. Ignore calls from everyone named
Speaker 1:  spam risk and never use the password.
Speaker 1:  Password.
Speaker 1:  But scammers are getting more sophisticated and more active,
Speaker 1:  which means they're finding millions of new victims every single
Speaker 1:  year. The good news is that there's a lot you can do to protect
Speaker 1:  yourself on the Wild, wild Web. For starters,
Speaker 1:  Zelle wants to remind you only send money to people you know
Speaker 1:  and trust. Zelle is available to United States Bank account holders.
Speaker 1:  Only terms and conditions apply.