# Transcript
ID: d7d68760-3bdf-11ed-b3d3-e3805ac0a0bf
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Will the future of music sound a lot like the past?
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-2851313018537268010/-3893520258136931455/s93290-US-2186s-1664006761.mp3
Description: In part 1 of our Vergecast: Future of Music series, Alex Cranz talks with Switched on Pop's Charlie Harding about the trends in music today that make new songs out of old material, and whether it's foreshadowing the future of pop.
Speaker 2:  Welcome
Speaker 3:  To the Vergecast the flagship podcast of the cassettes that you lost underneath
Speaker 3:  the seat of your first car. I'm your friend, David Pierce, and this is the
Speaker 3:  beginning of a new series. So for the next three Mondays, we're
Speaker 3:  gonna be bringing you different stories about the future of music. It's kind
Speaker 3:  of exactly what it sounds like. We're gonna try to figure out what the future
Speaker 3:  of music is, but we have a bunch of different ideas about what that might
Speaker 3:  look like. Our first episode this week comes from the verges managing editor,
Speaker 3:  Alex Krantz. Hi Alex.
Speaker 4:  Hello, David.
Speaker 3:  What is this episode about? I realize, I know almost nothing about what this
Speaker 3:  episode is about. You just like disappeared and made podcast.
Speaker 4:  It's it's about the future of music.
Speaker 3:  Oh, okay. Good. That's perfect.
Speaker 4:  We were looking into like, what about old music what's happening with old
Speaker 4:  music? Cuz it felt like we were seeing a lot of like remixes and samples
Speaker 4:  and interpolations and stuff. And as we thought about it more, we were like,
Speaker 4:  wait a minute, this seems like the future of music might be more related
Speaker 4:  to like the back catalog of music, all the old stuff.
Speaker 3:  I mean, it is kind of true. You listen to music now and it's like every part
Speaker 3:  of songs now is actually like the drum line from a song from the
Speaker 3:  1950s.
Speaker 4:  Yes. So we wanted to figure out, is this like just a thing?
Speaker 4:  Is this just randomly happening? What's going on here? Is this on purpose?
Speaker 4:  Our music executive saying, yes, I need more of this song from the
Speaker 4:  1950s as a baseline in this little NAS song.
Speaker 4:  So that's what we did. We went and we spoke with Charlie Harding, who
Speaker 4:  is a music journalist. He's a songwriter. And he also
Speaker 4:  co-host the podcast switched on pop.
Speaker 3:  One of my favorite podcasts.
Speaker 4:  It's so good. So he felt like the perfect person to talk to about this. And
Speaker 4:  it was a lot of
Speaker 3:  Fun. Awesome. All right, take it away. Let's go.
Speaker 4:  Okay. So I have Charlie here. Charlie, you are like a music expert,
Speaker 4:  especially compared to me, but I think probably compared to most people,
Speaker 4:  is that accurate? Can I say that about you?
Speaker 5:  I report on music. So yeah.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I feel like that's fine. Music
Speaker 5:  Is an infinitely large vocabulary with many
Speaker 5:  languages that one must learn. And so I know a few of them,
Speaker 4:  You know, pop music though.
Speaker 5:  I know pop music pretty well.
Speaker 4:  Okay. So we're gonna talk about a couple of different trends that are happening
Speaker 4:  here in music. And I'm curious about whether this is an indication of the
Speaker 4:  future of music. Great. So the first one I wanna talk about was this article
Speaker 4:  I read on vulture Sina. Nia will sound older on her
Speaker 4:  new Postmus album. Hmm. So Selena died in 1995
Speaker 4:  and they're using recordings from when she was like 13 to 16
Speaker 4:  years old. And they're, detuning her voice to
Speaker 4:  make her quote sound like she stepped out of the booth at 23
Speaker 4:  years old.
Speaker 5:  This is a obviously very particular and tragic case of
Speaker 5:  the need to revive a voice. But people have been
Speaker 5:  manipulating vocals since the beginning of recorded
Speaker 5:  music. And I think it's important to contextualize vocal
Speaker 5:  manipulation and changes as a very age old
Speaker 5:  thing. If you even think about the era of the crooners Sinatra, if you
Speaker 5:  will. I did it
Speaker 5:  a big part of their technological advancement was
Speaker 5:  microphone technique. It was getting up real close on the microphone and
Speaker 5:  getting that deep base. When behind you, you have the
Speaker 5:  support of an orchestra. Now that's an auditory illusion. It's
Speaker 5:  impossible to sing to an entire arena of people with an
Speaker 5:  orchestra and you're singing. If you didn't have a microphone, you'd have
Speaker 5:  to be belting to be heard. And so that's just an early example of how people
Speaker 5:  sang even Billy holiday, that sort of whiny vocal that you know,
Speaker 9:  And
Speaker 5:  A lot of the reason why she had this very constrained vocal sound
Speaker 5:  that is now iconic, was that she needed to make sure to
Speaker 5:  not make the needle jump as it was recording. If
Speaker 5:  there were too many fluctuations in the voice, the needle could skip and
Speaker 5:  ruin the recording. And so part of the vocal technique is actually determined
Speaker 5:  by the technological requirements of Billy holidays era
Speaker 5:  in contemporary pop music, vocal manipulation is
Speaker 5:  very common place. Now every major pop star
Speaker 5:  minus one or two uses some amount of vocal tuning
Speaker 5:  to clean up sometimes just, you know, a small error. Sometimes there's auto
Speaker 5:  tune through an entire vocal performance. That's extremely common.
Speaker 5:  And for creative effect, I think about Miley Cyrus, we can't stop
Speaker 5:  where you hear this really low manipulated vocal that was
Speaker 5:  taken from the world of chopped screwed music
Speaker 5:  or Billy Isle's bad guy has this low vocal where
Speaker 5:  it's like, I'm the bad guy. I'm
Speaker 12:  The bad guy.
Speaker 5:  Even Kanye West's entire early catalog of chipmunks. Soul music
Speaker 5:  is predicated on taking samples and pitching them way up. So they sound like
Speaker 5:  they're in a different world.
Speaker 5:  You know what I'm saying? When a doctor told me now what you're talking about
Speaker 5:  here is potentially a little bit different, right? Because it's about trying
Speaker 5:  to perfect the voice change the age,
Speaker 5:  certainly I've done this. It's not that hard. I've taken my
Speaker 5:  three year old's voice and recorded it and then put it through vocal
Speaker 5:  processing to get a sense of like, what might he sound like when he's 12
Speaker 5:  years old, all you have to do is just change the pitch and a setting called
Speaker 5:  format, which is kind of like how, where you place the vowels in your
Speaker 5:  voice that can make an old voice sound young or a young voice sound
Speaker 5:  old. It can change the perceptions of gender and the ways that gender is
Speaker 5:  stereotypically perceived in the voice. These things are all actually fairly
Speaker 5:  easy to manipulate. And so I'm not surprised that this is a, a way that
Speaker 5:  flees a state may want to update her music. It's a very
Speaker 5:  achievable thing to do. People look to change,
Speaker 5:  clean up, update voices all the time.
Speaker 4:  Is it kind of like, I think we've seen maybe with Nirvana and some of these
Speaker 4:  older bands, they go and they find like, oh yeah, they did these garage session
Speaker 4:  recordings. And now we're gonna clean 'em up and make 'em sound a little
Speaker 4:  more studio. Is it kind of that same thing, just finding these old,
Speaker 4:  almost lost tracks and just updating them.
Speaker 5:  They're connected. They're slightly different processes. Like when you're
Speaker 5:  trying to clean up bad recordings, a lot of what needs to be done is
Speaker 5:  removing hiss and crackle and trying to
Speaker 5:  separate the instruments in a way where you can actually really mix them
Speaker 5:  with modern mixing techniques. But part of that will certainly
Speaker 5:  be, Hey, this vocal wasn't recorded very well. How can we get the most out
Speaker 5:  of it and using techniques of cleaning tools and plugins that
Speaker 5:  will nicely EQ and compress and do all kinds of things to the voice, to make
Speaker 5:  it the best sounding performance possible. It's very common. The reality
Speaker 5:  though, is that technology has come a long way at recovering bad
Speaker 5:  audio, but every mix engineer is gonna tell you don't fix it in the mix.
Speaker 5:  Get it good the first time, you know, this as someone who makes a podcast,
Speaker 5:  if someone delivers you bad audio, it takes 10 times as long to deal with
Speaker 5:  their audio. So a lot can be done. Yeah. But it's, it's very hard work.
Speaker 4:  Have we heard of other artists doing the detuning method? Like in
Speaker 4:  Salina's case?
Speaker 5:  I think this is a somewhat unique case. I'm sure there could be other examples
Speaker 5:  out there. But part of what we're talking about
Speaker 5:  is the uncanny valley of relating to the human
Speaker 5:  voice. You know, humans are immensely tuned into
Speaker 5:  the voice. In fact, our ears are EQD to hear the human voice over. Other
Speaker 5:  sounds makes sense because we wanna be aware of when our parents call for
Speaker 5:  us when there's danger. Yeah. And so we are very good at hearing
Speaker 5:  when voices don't sound right. It's why some people don't like the sound
Speaker 5:  of auto tune. Cause it doesn't sound natural. I think that when you're
Speaker 5:  updating a vocal, getting an old recording that is recorded
Speaker 5:  poorly at a different age to sound contemporary and totally
Speaker 5:  natural is very challenging. Even if it's done
Speaker 5:  properly, could create fan
Speaker 5:  confusion. I think especially for a living artist, if
Speaker 5:  they were to release a recording of their younger self, I think it would
Speaker 5:  be more likely that they would actually just make it sound like they're younger
Speaker 5:  self and mix it so that maybe it's a little more in tune. It fits
Speaker 5:  in the mix. Well, but you're talking about not just technology, but
Speaker 5:  also aesthetics and people's expectations and culture. There's
Speaker 5:  a lot of reasons why people might not want to hear that recording. You
Speaker 4:  Talked about that confusion. And I was thinking a lot about like Michael Jackson,
Speaker 4:  after he passed away, Sony music released this whole new like album.
Speaker 4:  And there were a couple of songs on it that people were like, this isn't
Speaker 4:  Michael, this doesn't sound like him. I think this is an impersonator,
Speaker 13:  Everybody piece of Michael Jackson,
Speaker 13:  every in the, of Michael Jackson,
Speaker 4:  One fan actually in 2014 sued Sony music
Speaker 4:  because she was like, it's not him. So Sony actually had to pull the songs
Speaker 4:  from streaming services this year to avoid further controversy.
Speaker 5:  Pop music is deeply predicated on a performance of
Speaker 5:  authenticity. People want to believe that the
Speaker 5:  performer is performing their identity in their life. And that a
Speaker 5:  listener can have this parasocial relationship with that person and potentially
Speaker 5:  see their own life in that music. And for that
Speaker 5:  performance of authenticity to work, you have to believe in the
Speaker 5:  thing. And so in any place where someone is
Speaker 5:  using impersonators and ghost writers, fans frequently become
Speaker 5:  very suspect of those kind of techniques. Fans have long
Speaker 5:  critiqued, the idea of boardrooms participating in the
Speaker 5:  songwriting process, things being overly commercial. There's a lot
Speaker 5:  of reasons why I think we should challenge some of those assumptions. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Because it's their age old. There is reason to believe that fans should be
Speaker 5:  suspect of how is technology potentially
Speaker 5:  manipulating my relationship to that artist that I love
Speaker 5:  technology or potential fake recreations. Like
Speaker 5:  if you're gonna recreate a song that I love or release a new
Speaker 5:  song from someone who has died, like either be like, Hey,
Speaker 5:  we're getting someone else. Who's awesome. Who you really love to perform
Speaker 5:  in the style of that person and be very clear about it or give me an
Speaker 5:  old recording that is mixed in a strange way. One of the
Speaker 5:  earliest examples of what you're talking about in fact that I can recall
Speaker 5:  was the Beatles. When they put out their anthologies
Speaker 5:  found songs that John Lennon had
Speaker 5:  recorded and the three remaining surviving members of
Speaker 5:  the band at that time put out the song real love
Speaker 5:  and free as a bird.
Speaker 5:  And those were kind of like the Beatles final two recordings
Speaker 5:  of the four of them by taking tape of John Lennon that had been left on the
Speaker 5:  floor, writing new verses for Paul to
Speaker 5:  sing in between and sound like they're a band again. And
Speaker 5:  that works because that I think passes the authenticity test
Speaker 4:  Is the intent part of that, that like the intent of the artist is
Speaker 4:  part of that, that desire from fans,
Speaker 5:  The artist's intent is always something that people are questioning
Speaker 5:  about is an estate managing the artist in a
Speaker 5:  way that they intended a great example would be the prince
Speaker 5:  estate. You know, prince was suspect of streaming and limited
Speaker 5:  the amount that his songs were available on streaming services, but
Speaker 5:  his estate has made his music available on Spotify. And so
Speaker 5:  there is reasons why fans might want to question whether or not that is a
Speaker 5:  thing that he would have done and may want to participate
Speaker 5:  in his music in a way that would be closer to his intent. It
Speaker 5:  is always a part of the conversation
Speaker 4:  Also adjacent to this is AI voices. Like we
Speaker 4:  see that happen a lot in films and stuff like that, where they'll
Speaker 4:  recreate the voices is that happening in music where people are like,
Speaker 4:  I'm gonna recreate Judy Garland. Like, are they doing that
Speaker 4:  recreating these? And is that like a viable future
Speaker 4:  for music?
Speaker 5:  This is happening. It is a fairly
Speaker 5:  nascent area of AI research. I'm sure people have been working at for a
Speaker 5:  couple of years, but I don't know of at this point
Speaker 5:  publicly available tools where you can like
Speaker 5:  manipulate someone else's old vocal. But I know that there are firms
Speaker 5:  that are doing this, that are successfully recreating voices
Speaker 5:  off of training sets of that singer. That sound
Speaker 5:  reasonable at this point and could be used for future recordings. And
Speaker 5:  there are reasons why people may want to use those AI recordings.
Speaker 5:  A great example might be, Hey, you finished a track and you're a really busy
Speaker 5:  pop star and all of a sudden you're not available, but you missed one backing
Speaker 5:  note. And we want to recreate that backing note. There's a bunch of different
Speaker 5:  ways you could do that today, but why don't you just like, eh, we'll just
Speaker 5:  have the AI sing it for you. I could see lots of applications, why people
Speaker 5:  might use these tools in the future, but
Speaker 4:  Using more as tools, not necessarily as like the centerpiece of an album.
Speaker 5:  No, of course not. And yes, someone's going to do it because
Speaker 5:  first of all, someone's gonna do it as an art project because it's interesting
Speaker 5:  art people love making AI. Art is like the conversation that is happening
Speaker 5:  right now. So someone's gonna make the full AI vocal album at some point
Speaker 5:  in which nobody's saying it, and nobody wrote the lyrics like that's gonna
Speaker 5:  happen for sure. There's a lot of precedent for bands continuing
Speaker 5:  on past the, we'll just say availability of their
Speaker 5:  lead singer, whether they've left the group, whether they're deceased, I
Speaker 5:  can think of like queen van Halen Genesis, the grateful dead
Speaker 5:  Nirvana Zappa. They have all continued to
Speaker 5:  perform with other lead singers. Maybe
Speaker 5:  Frank Zappa is one of the really interesting cases. His son dwindles has
Speaker 5:  a project where he performs his father's music Zappa without Zappa. There
Speaker 5:  are cases where fandoms want to continue to engage in the
Speaker 5:  artwork and the music of their favorite bands. And as long as that fandom
Speaker 5:  is around, there's probably a marketplace for this kind of
Speaker 5:  recreation of a voice, but it's gonna have to pass
Speaker 5:  through the lens of culture through these authenticity tests. Do people want
Speaker 5:  to hear this? And so will it be used? Absolutely.
Speaker 5:  How it's gonna be used, I think is gonna be determined by where is the culture
Speaker 5:  at and are we willing and wanting to hear new, especially new
Speaker 5:  material with old voices? We'll see. I think we might definitely hear maybe
Speaker 5:  like remixes and updated lyrics and things that are like
Speaker 5:  mashups and kind of more in the EDM
Speaker 5:  hip hop remix culture. That feels like a very ripe place
Speaker 5:  for AI voices from deceased artists.
Speaker 4:  Well, it's funny you bring up remixes because we are actually gonna talk
Speaker 4:  about that, but first we're gonna take it to a break
Speaker 2:  Fox creative.
Speaker 1:  This is advertiser content brought to you by amp
Speaker 14:  Building your own style tick forever. It is a never ending process, but
Speaker 14:  once you kind of understand what that sounds like, the confidence
Speaker 14:  brushes in I'm Alda August, I
Speaker 14:  go by CHNG the nomad on stage. And I am a DJ producer from Seattle,
Speaker 14:  Washington,
Speaker 1:  Alda captures inspiration wherever. And whenever it strikes
Speaker 1:  using a familiar tool, voice memos on her phone,
Speaker 14:  I'll be in the car and I'll embarrass myself in front of my partner and
Speaker 14:  be like, I, I got a really quick
Speaker 1:  On her song, go away. All that took frustration and rage and turn it into
Speaker 1:  something empowering and cathartic.
Speaker 14:  I was at my line cook job, and
Speaker 14:  another big artist was outed as an abuser.
Speaker 14:  And I was just so sick of hearing all these men
Speaker 14:  in power abusing and manipulating women. I
Speaker 14:  came up with the hook right then and there and sing it to myself
Speaker 14:  in the freezer,
Speaker 2:  Get the outta here. You got five
Speaker 14:  Seconds for drag,
Speaker 14:  whenever I'm at work or playing golf or just spacing out.
Speaker 14:  I find inspiration everywhere. And I never really know when it's going to
Speaker 14:  strike. So I just try to stay open to whatever the next sound or
Speaker 14:  next song is going to be
Speaker 1:  Ready to find your next favorite song, discover new artists and
Speaker 1:  explore the sounds shaping the music of tomorrow on amp, download
Speaker 1:  amp on the app store today.
Speaker 4:  Okay. And we're back during the break. Charlie was telling me he has a very
Speaker 4:  cool AI remix story. You wanna share.
Speaker 5:  One of the biggest challenges in remixing music is do you
Speaker 5:  actually have the original music available? There was a famous fire that
Speaker 5:  burned down a ton of masters in the world of popular music.
Speaker 5:  One band included was the band green day
Speaker 15:  In my bedroom, staring at the,
Speaker 5:  They lost their masters. And so they, they
Speaker 5:  wanted to do remixes, mash up their music in new and original ways, but they
Speaker 5:  only have the finished final products. You can't change the voice. You can't
Speaker 5:  take the guitars out until they partnered up with an AI company
Speaker 5:  called audio shake, who can do AI
Speaker 5:  stemming, where they can actually use AI to remove
Speaker 5:  and separate the guitars, the base of the drums, the vocals background instruments,
Speaker 5:  and create them as separate tracks so that you can do new things with them.
Speaker 5:  And green day did that and release one of their songs
Speaker 5:  on TikTok, where they actually just completely removed the guitar so
Speaker 5:  that other people could play guitar. Along with it,
Speaker 15:  Stand alone in my bedroom, staring at the
Speaker 15:  walls,
Speaker 5:  Any sort of guitar hero, mash up competition
Speaker 5:  of your dreams if you're a fan. And so I think that you're gonna see
Speaker 5:  AI tools using you use for all kinds of creative purposes for fan
Speaker 5:  engagement and for putting music
Speaker 5:  in new contexts that you couldn't do in any other way.
Speaker 4:  And I think that like those remixes seem to be one of those things that's
Speaker 4:  really taking off. I know TikTok, we talk a lot about on the Vergecast TikTok
Speaker 4:  is kind of this big engine for, for music right now. It's it's driving
Speaker 4:  music in a way maybe more so than Spotify even. Is that
Speaker 4:  just like a fad, is that, you know, because everybody's
Speaker 4:  got TikTok and the fancy new tools, or is this just like kind of
Speaker 4:  a new future, we're just gonna be getting more and more remixes
Speaker 5:  Remix of culture. And especially the use of interpolations is at an all
Speaker 5:  time high. We're seeing more new music mashed up with older
Speaker 5:  music than we have in the last decade. I've done some reporting that shows
Speaker 5:  that inter interpolations have in fact doubled in the last five years on
Speaker 5:  Billboard's year end hot, 100. You asked me, is this here to stay?
Speaker 5:  I think all of culture is a fad, right? Like at
Speaker 5:  some point we're all gonna be wearing moon boots again, I'm
Speaker 4:  So excited.
Speaker 5:  And so at some point, remixes are not gonna be cool, but
Speaker 5:  is this here for a minute, for sure, because TikTok is the biggest,
Speaker 5:  most important social network at the moment. And it's gonna have staying
Speaker 5:  power for how long. I don't know the cycles of power and
Speaker 5:  staying power within social media seem to be
Speaker 5:  increasing in time. And so I think it's gonna be around for
Speaker 5:  a minute. I just, if you ask me what's happening in 50 years, I don't know.
Speaker 5:  I, like I said, I'm gonna be wearing moon boots on the moon and you
Speaker 4:  Be looking
Speaker 5:  Great making music in ways. I can't even imagine. Thank you. Well,
Speaker 4:  You talk about in inter interpolations, how is that different than
Speaker 4:  remixes? Like how, how do we define those two?
Speaker 5:  Sure. If you want to use someone else's song,
Speaker 5:  there are roughly three things that you can do. One is you can make
Speaker 5:  a cover of a song, which is basically, you know, redoing all
Speaker 5:  of the melody and the lyrics with maybe slight variation, but staying
Speaker 5:  really close to the original. You could sample a song where you actually
Speaker 5:  take the original recording and you put it into a new song and you
Speaker 5:  change the context. So you're not singing the same lyrics throughout the
Speaker 5:  entire thing, but you're using the actual recording itself. The last thing
Speaker 5:  you can do is you can interpolate a song, which is that you're going to borrow
Speaker 5:  a musical element from another song. It could be a melody, it could be a
Speaker 5:  lyric. It could be a big part of the vibe in production,
Speaker 5:  and you're going to update it into a new song. And so
Speaker 5:  this has become extremely popular. Recently,
Speaker 5:  young gravy has a song called Betty, get money, never
Speaker 16:  Took a, never take a damn.
Speaker 16:  All I know is chase this
Speaker 5:  Though, which interpolate Rick Asley is never gonna give it up.
Speaker 11:  Gonna give you, gonna let you,
Speaker 5:  Which is great. Cuz if you play that, then I've just Rick rolled all of your
Speaker 5:  listeners. Yes Lato is a great example. Her song,
Speaker 5:  big energy. One of the most fun song last couple years uses both
Speaker 5:  a sample of the Tom Tom club
Speaker 5:  and interpolate Mariah Carrie's fantasy,
Speaker 5:  which had used the same sample, but because Lato uses
Speaker 5:  some of Mariah Carey's lyric she's I interpolating Mariah
Speaker 5:  Carey's version of the Tom Tom club.
Speaker 17:  Hey beach. I could be a fantasy. I could tell you got the
Speaker 17:  energy.
Speaker 5:  That's a very popular interpolation. There's a new interpolation of the song.
Speaker 5:  Blue ABA Diba that David GTA has out
Speaker 5:  there is even a song by Rita aura, which interpolate
Speaker 5:  the Beverly Hills cop theme.
Speaker 11:  It's
Speaker 5:  A very common thing right now that people are taking old
Speaker 5:  hits that are still in the cultural memory. Still interesting, but maybe
Speaker 5:  have faded just a little bit and then updating them and bringing them back
Speaker 5:  because frankly there's no better hook than a song that's
Speaker 5:  already hooked you before. So people like to update them. It's kinda like
Speaker 5:  the Hollywood strategy of rebooting everything. And it all has to do with
Speaker 5:  the cost of marketing marketing. A new film is extremely expensive. People
Speaker 5:  wanna go see things that are familiar and it's easier to market
Speaker 5:  something that is already in the popular consciousness. And so I
Speaker 5:  think the same thing is true of music. There is more competition in music
Speaker 5:  today than there ever has been before. The number of songs released daily
Speaker 5:  a few years ago was 60,000 songs on Spotify. And so I don't even know what
Speaker 5:  the number is updated to today, but you have so much competition when you're
Speaker 5:  putting a song out. So maybe if it connects to another major, hit it, you
Speaker 5:  have a better chance of being remembered.
Speaker 4:  Are the studios doing this intentionally? Is this just the
Speaker 4:  artist being like, I want people to listen to my song, which I totally get.
Speaker 4:  Where is the, the, the kind of drive coming from to do this?
Speaker 5:  I think it's bidirectional clearly listeners like
Speaker 5:  this music because it's performing very well on billboard. People are choosing
Speaker 5:  to go and listen to it. Radio DJs are continuing to play this music cuz
Speaker 5:  it's working at the same time. Music, publishers, music publishers are the
Speaker 5:  people that own the songwriting credit, which is the part that gets interpolated.
Speaker 5:  Music publishers are actively pitching the idea of
Speaker 5:  I interpolations to major artists to continue the
Speaker 5:  lifetime value of their catalog of music.
Speaker 5:  So I spoke recently with hypnosis sounds and primary wave,
Speaker 5:  two of the biggest financially backed music publishers. These are the people
Speaker 5:  who are buying up old catalogs, like paying
Speaker 5:  sometimes hundreds of millions of dollars for old catalogs. They believe
Speaker 5:  that it's a stable financial asset because they can predict streaming revenue
Speaker 5:  off of these songs for a number of years. And they think that they're gonna
Speaker 5:  make money back off of it. And they're also trying to find new
Speaker 5:  markets and new life for that music. They're doing it through
Speaker 5:  biopics, they're doing it through docs. They're getting people to cover those
Speaker 5:  songs, all which increase the value of that catalog, but they're also
Speaker 5:  actively pitching interpolations. They, they literally go through their list
Speaker 5:  of songs, make lists sometimes even produce ideas for songs
Speaker 5:  that then turn into hits that get played on the radio because
Speaker 5:  through the label system, they're able to pitch those ideas. They get them
Speaker 5:  to a major artist and they get remade. One of my favorite examples of this
Speaker 5:  kind of a thing happening was the song higher love, not
Speaker 5:  talking about Steve Winwood. I'm talking about Kigo taking
Speaker 5:  a bonus track from Whitney Houston, covering that
Speaker 5:  song and then updating it with contemporary production.
Speaker 11:  Where's that pile.
Speaker 5:  This is one of those cases where a music catalog company
Speaker 5:  helped facilitate the revival of this
Speaker 5:  body of work. And I think it's an amazing song. I love the new
Speaker 5:  version.
Speaker 4:  So these, these studios who are buying all of these catalogs
Speaker 4:  because they want this predictable revenue, because like, I guess
Speaker 4:  music, like all forms of entertainment is not predictable in its revenue.
Speaker 4:  Is this kind of a newer thing in music? Have they been doing this a while
Speaker 4:  that this predictability play?
Speaker 5:  Well, certainly streaming has changed how publishers
Speaker 5:  perceive the lifetime value of their work. Music catalogs
Speaker 5:  have always been valuable and people have made a
Speaker 5:  lot of money off of legacy artists and owning that
Speaker 5:  publishing. That's not new there's AAL
Speaker 5:  story about Paul McCartney telling Michael Jackson, Hey, it's
Speaker 5:  a really good idea to own publishing. Like there's a lot of value in it.
Speaker 5:  And Michael Jackson went behind his back and bought the Beatles cattle off
Speaker 5:  the end. Paul was not so happy about that. So there's always been value
Speaker 5:  in it. What has changed is that streaming provides more predictable
Speaker 5:  revenues. You can see how your revenues are changing literally, you know,
Speaker 5:  day by day and previously you would've had to relied on physical
Speaker 5:  retailers. And of course, if you have a legacy catalog, maintaining shelf
Speaker 5:  space in a physical location is more challenging. When so
Speaker 5:  much new music is being released on streaming, fandoms are able to
Speaker 5:  continue listening. If you're a boomer and you love boomer music,
Speaker 5:  you're gonna keep listening to that on Spotify. You know, if you're from
Speaker 5:  the greatest generation and you really love listening
Speaker 5:  to the old classics of pop music, you probably couldn't find
Speaker 5:  them at best buy today. But if that's your thing, you can find playlists.
Speaker 5:  You can find them music, you can be engaged with it on streaming in a way
Speaker 5:  that provides some predictability now. And so it's not hard to build
Speaker 5:  out financial forecasts of this is how much money this artist is making over
Speaker 5:  streaming year over year. Is it growing? Is it declining? And you can predict
Speaker 5:  what those the revenues might be, which is all predicated on. Listener behavior
Speaker 5:  is going to be the same in the future as it is today. And we don't know about
Speaker 5:  that, but
Speaker 4:  You've got these companies who are going, they're buying this music and they're
Speaker 4:  saying, okay, I know I can predict this. And then I also know I can
Speaker 4:  get somebody to go do an interpolation. I can go have a whole
Speaker 4:  bunch of let's slow it down. So it'll look, sound great
Speaker 4:  on a movie trailer to know just how dramatic it is.
Speaker 5:  If you wanna be CRAs and think about music as a marketplace, listeners have
Speaker 5:  to want this kind of music in the sixties. The worst thing you could
Speaker 5:  possibly do was to sell out and work with a brand. And now it's like, if
Speaker 5:  you're not working with a brand, you're not a real artist. So ideas around
Speaker 5:  this in culture are gonna change, but listeners are
Speaker 5:  definitely tuning into this music and it's working. And, and so I think
Speaker 5:  you see the suppliers of this music are recognizing, okay, we need to figure
Speaker 5:  out how to supply more of this and do it. Well, all of the publishers
Speaker 5:  I've spoken with work very hard to
Speaker 5:  maintain high quality. Now that obviously is
Speaker 5:  extremely subjective, but they're not just letting their catalog out there.
Speaker 5:  Willy-nilly saying, Hey, go cover this song. Do whatever you want with it.
Speaker 5:  They're trying to connect old songs with new artists where there is a,
Speaker 5:  a really strong, resonant connection that fans are gonna love.
Speaker 5:  They're getting approvals on the songs, the usages,
Speaker 5:  et cetera, et cetera. And hypnosis sounds. For example, told me over email
Speaker 5:  that they usually tell the artists who did the
Speaker 5:  recording originally, that this is gonna happen even when they
Speaker 5:  don't need to, because a lot of these deals are like these publishers just
Speaker 5:  own all of it. So they don't need to get the artist's permission in some
Speaker 5:  cases they do, but they do so anyway, because you don't wanna mess with
Speaker 5:  these legacies, right? If you're going to use old
Speaker 5:  IP, don't mess it up because it's actually gonna potentially hurt the
Speaker 5:  entire value of the overall catalog. So I think people are trying to do this
Speaker 5:  intelligently and do it in a way that builds value
Speaker 5:  rather than dilutes it. So the publisher pitching part
Speaker 5:  of it is definitely important, but I think it's just one part of
Speaker 5:  the marketplace of how we are listening to old hits and new ways.
Speaker 5:  Is
Speaker 4:  There an end date for this kind of business model where they, they buy the
Speaker 4:  catalogs, they put 'em on streaming and then they work with a lot of artists
Speaker 4:  and stuff to do remixes to do interpolations. Is there an end date to that?
Speaker 4:  A point where like there just aren't any more artists who can do these songs
Speaker 4:  or there aren't any more artists who you can buy the catalogs from
Speaker 5:  Pop is always turning over. So there will always be new acts coming along,
Speaker 5:  but there are a couple of end dates. One, you have to have a fandom,
Speaker 5:  you know, not a lot of people are currently buying, say
Speaker 5:  John Phillips's music who was one of the biggest pop stars
Speaker 5:  of the 19th century. It's
Speaker 4:  Just me.
Speaker 5:  Oh yeah. Okay. That's awesome. I mean, if people still play the SAF phone,
Speaker 5:  that's awesome. But like horn music from that era is not very popular
Speaker 5:  today. We might hear it in marching bands, et cetera, but generally
Speaker 5:  that's not driving pop music. You also have copyright explorations.
Speaker 5:  So at some point all work will enter the public domain, but that is a
Speaker 5:  long period of time, many generations. And I think you're gonna see a lot
Speaker 5:  of music publishers pursuing Disney's strategy, which is
Speaker 5:  maintaining the lifetime of your intellectual property and trying to constantly
Speaker 5:  reignite it so that the fandom for that thing grows
Speaker 5:  and at least sustains an ongoing business
Speaker 5:  for each of these mini artist brands.
Speaker 4:  And when all else fails, they will go petition the government to make sure
Speaker 4:  they can hold Mickey mouse forever. Do you think
Speaker 4:  we'll see the music labels doing that as well
Speaker 5:  In the music community. There's probably a mixture of what people want. Some
Speaker 5:  people want, like, let me sample anything. I wanna pay. Certainly the people
Speaker 5:  who own the intellectual property are working to maintain the lifetime value
Speaker 5:  of that in the longest possible way that they can. Yeah. And so
Speaker 5:  certainly I know for a fact there are labels that don't want
Speaker 5:  to believe in, for example, fair use, because they would prefer
Speaker 5:  that in every case, people pay for any instance
Speaker 5:  of recognizing that music, which is why we see an increase in
Speaker 5:  music docs that are actually like owned and operated by the artists.
Speaker 5:  Those are not docs. Those that is artist
Speaker 5:  propaganda. They can be fun. You should watch them enjoy them. That's totally
Speaker 5:  fun, but that's not a documentary, but so many music docs today are sold
Speaker 5:  as a doc. When actually it is a, like someone with complete
Speaker 5:  creative control about how they are being represented.
Speaker 4:  Is there any kind of music trend that you're seeing right now that you think
Speaker 4:  that's the one that's the future of music? Cuz a lot of these we've talked
Speaker 4:  about, you're like, you know what, this is gonna be part of the future. This
Speaker 4:  isn't the fabric of the future of music. Is there any, that's like just stand
Speaker 4:  out to you.
Speaker 5:  I'm not gonna put my Oracle hat on for a very specific reason,
Speaker 5:  which is that I think music is one of the fastest moving media
Speaker 5:  format that the culture around music evolves so
Speaker 5:  quickly. Every time people wanna say all pop music sounds the same. It's
Speaker 5:  like just listen to what pop music sounded like five years ago does not sound
Speaker 5:  the same. It updates and changes. It's very, chameleonic I
Speaker 5:  can't tell you the combination of how pop music is gonna sound, how it's
Speaker 5:  gonna be created and how technology is going to inform it. Because I think
Speaker 5:  it's gonna shift every single year, even when we get to the point
Speaker 5:  where AI is going to perfectly recreate a song, if, and when
Speaker 5:  that happens and create new, interesting music, humans are still gonna participate
Speaker 5:  in music in wild and creative ways that I can't even possibly imagine
Speaker 5:  it's all gonna happen so fast that I just would
Speaker 5:  feel irresponsible to pinpoint like this is the thing that's gonna be around
Speaker 5:  for the next hundred years. I mean, again, I love the za phone, but
Speaker 5:  it's got a very particular place. At one point it was very, very popular.
Speaker 5:  You know, it's like, it's just all gonna change
Speaker 4:  All of these. Interpolations all of these remixes. Are we just kind of,
Speaker 4:  I don't know if it's doomed as the right word they're they're absolute pops,
Speaker 4:  but are we, are we gonna just be in this loop, this endless loop
Speaker 4:  of recall,
Speaker 5:  We definitely seem to be living in the greatest era of nostalgia
Speaker 5:  and that is reflected. I think in all of our media and it particularly
Speaker 5:  is true in popular music. Interpolations are on the rise.
Speaker 5:  It seems like every year there's a new throwback to a previous
Speaker 5:  generation. We are very much into the eighties in disco right now. One of
Speaker 5:  the biggest albums in the last couple years was DPA's future nostalgia. And
Speaker 5:  it is an update to the disco sound
Speaker 7:  Thinking about
Speaker 7:  big change me.
Speaker 5:  We are, I think in a nostalgia loop, I maintain that. I think
Speaker 5:  the ideas around pop culture and what's going to be interesting will change
Speaker 5:  and that at some point nostalgia will be frowned upon, but
Speaker 5:  we are in it for a minute. There's no doubt about that. I think every
Speaker 5:  musician's secretly hopes for the moment where actually what's gonna happen
Speaker 5:  is we're going to go to the most avant-garde weird thing that's ever been
Speaker 5:  created. And you know, we, we lean on artists like Bjork and other folks
Speaker 5:  to, to help push those sort of boundaries and help change our understanding
Speaker 5:  of what music can sound like. It's always gonna be a push and a pull.
Speaker 4:  Ah, I love it. All right. Well thank you Charlie so much for, for taking
Speaker 4:  the time to talk to us and educate me about music and all the
Speaker 4:  artists that I've never heard of until today.
Speaker 5:  Thank you for chatting.
Speaker 4:  All right. That's it for the Vergecast today. Thanks for listening. You can
Speaker 4:  find Charlie's podcast switched on pop anywhere you get podcasts.
Speaker 4:  This is the first episode of our future music series, which will be
Speaker 4:  every Monday for the next three weeks. In the meantime, you should check
Speaker 4:  out the verge.com. We've got a new look, tons of cool
Speaker 4:  articles. And we're here to talk about the future of everything else, including
Speaker 4:  music. This show is produced by Andrew Marino and Liam James
Speaker 4:  Nori. Donovan is our executive producer and Brooke mentors is our editorial
Speaker 4:  director of audio. The Vergecast is a verge production and part of the V
Speaker 4:  media podcast network. If you have thoughts, feedback, feelings, mix
Speaker 4:  tapes, you can always email Vergecast the
Speaker 4:  verge.com or you can call us on our Vergecast hotline at
Speaker 4:  8 66 verge. One one, David will be back on Wednesday to talk
Speaker 4:  about TikTok, search your iPhone, 14 questions and a whole lot more.
Speaker 4:  See it then rock and roll.