# Transcript
ID: 7eb53540-467b-11ed-b5d1-e7ad4c8c0777
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Google's Pixel 7 and Pixel Watch event / Elon Musk vs. Twitter trial update
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/1670767159885598105/4864093586318955927/s93290-US-4727s-1665173081.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, David Pierce, and Alex Cranz discuss all the announcements from Google's Pixel 7 event.
Senior correspondant Liz Lopatto joins the show to explain the latest in the Elon Musk/Twitter trial saga.
The Super Mario Bros. Movie trailer is here (and so is Chris Pratt)
Hands-on with the Pixel 7 and 7 Pro: something familiar
The Pixel 7 and 7 Pro double down on Tensor-fueled features
Google’s Pixel 7 and 7 Pro will fix your old blurry photos
Google once again calls out Apple for not adopting RCS
Google’s including its VPN service with the Pixel 7 and 7 Pro
Pixel Watch hands-on: Google's taking a page from Apple
Google thinks smartwatches are the future again — are you buying it?
Google’s Pixel Watch marks a new chapter for Wear OS
Google shows off wireless charging dock that turns the Pixel Tablet into a smart display
Google overhauls Home app as it prepares for Matter
Everything we think we know about Elon Musk’s plan for Twitter
The Elon Musk vs. Twitter trial is on hold until October 28th
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we'd love to hear from you.
We are conducting a short audience survey to help plan for our future and hear from you. To participate, head to vox.com/podsurvey, and thank you!
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (4 ads detected)
Speaker 1:  Today in the Vergecast, we'll break down the whole Google event. Pixel seven,
Speaker 1:  Pixel seven Pro, and of course the Pixel Watch. And Elon Musk somehow
Speaker 1:  interrupts the show with some more news about Chancery court and
Speaker 1:  buying Twitter that's coming up right after this.
Speaker 2:  Hello and welcome to Road Cast, the flagship podcast of Chris
Speaker 2:  Pratt's. Mario Voice, which was a lie.
Speaker 5:  Just a, it's just a normal podcast. Just a regular podcast.
Speaker 2:  It's a regular old podcast.
Speaker 2:  So you don't know this cuz you're listening later you're, you know, time.
Speaker 2:  The magic of time shifting this, covering this up. You're in your
Speaker 2:  car, you're going about your day. We are starting late. Me
Speaker 2:  your friend Eli David Pierce. Hi Alex Kranz.
Speaker 6:  Hi.
Speaker 2:  We are starting late because we were waiting for the
Speaker 2:  Nintendo direct reveal of Chris Pratt's voice in the New Mario
Speaker 2:  movie. And it's just his voice.
Speaker 5:  It's just Chris Pratt.
Speaker 6:  No. Bob Hoskins impression. No potentially
Speaker 6:  offensive impression. Just, just Chris Pratt.
Speaker 2:  I mean he said it will be unlike anything you've ever heard. Right.
Speaker 5:  Parentheses, if you've never heard Chris Pratt before, I mean
Speaker 6:  A lot of people haven't watched Parks and Rec, they haven't seen
Speaker 6:  ever would I get it
Speaker 2:  Right. But your choices are like the entertainingly but
Speaker 2:  somewhat racist. It's a me mark. You
Speaker 5:  Know, he was gonna say every other option was worse.
Speaker 5:  So like, in a way, this is the least
Speaker 2:  One.
Speaker 6:  Bob Hoskins. Bob Hoskins does. Bob Hoskins just went
Speaker 6:  out there and he was like, I'm in this movie, I'm playing Mario.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. He was just mad by the way you would keep talking Bob Hoskins.
Speaker 2:  I'm pretty sure most of our listeners have not seen the Super Mario
Speaker 2:  Brothers movie starting
Speaker 6:  Bob Hoskin classic starring him
Speaker 6:  and John Lake Zamo shot in
Speaker 2:  Brooklyn. It was not good. Like that movie came out when I was a child
Speaker 2:  who was playing Super Mario Brothers. And I was like, now I'm gonna give
Speaker 2:  this one a mess.
Speaker 6:  Oh, I loved it. It was like a transformative moment for me. I tried
Speaker 6:  to do my hair like Coupa
Speaker 2:  Bob Hoskins, I think he, he played it as I'm an actual plumber.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, right. He was like, what's wrong with these guys? Your turtles? Like,
Speaker 2:  he was like a very strange voice. And then obviously
Speaker 2:  there's like the famous sort of like modern day Mario
Speaker 2:  voice. Well,
Speaker 5:  Who?
Speaker 2:  Which again, it seems fine. Like we've, we've all
Speaker 2:  come up with it. I, my assumption is that if Chris Pratt had done
Speaker 2:  that voice, he wouldn't be immediately canceled
Speaker 2:  by like regular Italians and Italian Americans. They
Speaker 2:  would've just been like, You're done
Speaker 6:  Not doing
Speaker 2:  This. And so he was like, I'm gonna do this other voice. You've never heard
Speaker 2:  it before. It's like unlike. And so we all waited with baited breath. He
Speaker 2:  only said one line that was like, what is this place? But it was just Chris
Speaker 2:  Pratt.
Speaker 2:  Anyway, so we're starting late today and I gotta tell you, I think we're
Speaker 2:  all starting from a place of profound anger at CRISPR for lying to us.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I had high
Speaker 2:  Hopes, but that's not, Wait we look Well maybe there's more movie. Maybe
Speaker 2:  he's gonna grow into the voice over the course of the movie. Yeah, that's
Speaker 2:  a thing you can do. Maybe
Speaker 5:  It's a trilogy and by the end it'll be full Mario.
Speaker 6:  So like at the end of the movie Bowser's gonna be like, who are you?
Speaker 6:  And he's just gonna be like, it's a me
Speaker 5:  Slam to credits
Speaker 2:  The hardest. It's a me Mario ever delivered
Speaker 6:  So hard. Deadly serious.
Speaker 2:  The movie looks very silly. What we, when we started watching the trailer,
Speaker 2:  Alex just went, Oh this movie's for children.
Speaker 5:  Yep.
Speaker 6:  We're too old.
Speaker 2:  There was a little bit of like the sort of thing they do in all trailers
Speaker 2:  now where there's like the minor key theme comes up. Yeah. To make like
Speaker 2:  Dark Mariot. But then it was just a Mario movie. Anyway, go watch the trailer.
Speaker 2:  You could watch it right now. Pull your car over, see if you are as disappointed
Speaker 2:  as we were.
Speaker 5:  I'm already for the the gritty reboot starting Tom Holland. I'm ready for
Speaker 5:  it. It's gonna be amazing. That
Speaker 6:  Was the Bob Hoskins movie.
Speaker 2:  It
Speaker 6:  Was the gritty
Speaker 2:  Movie. It really was. They were like, what if Mario and Louise
Speaker 2:  were actually plumbers in this situation and they played it
Speaker 6:  Future where everyone's a human dinosaur.
Speaker 2:  Perfect. Oh yeah, that was the, I mean that's movie. Can I wanna say it?
Speaker 2:  I can't believe you remember this movie, so, Oh my God. All right. That's
Speaker 2:  not the news. We thought it was gonna be the news. What? What were we thinking?
Speaker 2:  The news? I mean it's a big news week. Yeah, there was a
Speaker 2:  Google event today. David was there along with V and Welch
Speaker 2:  and Allison. We got New Pixel seven new Pixel seven Pro. We
Speaker 2:  saw the Pixel watch, we saw a tease with a Pixel tablet.
Speaker 2:  Elon is just eling like a maniac in the Delaware
Speaker 2:  court system. The European governments are like, Yeah, usbc
Speaker 2:  remember that you're gonna use it now. Apple Allison reviewed the iPhone
Speaker 2:  14 plus, which still has a Lightning connect. Just a lot going on. So I think
Speaker 2:  the way we're gonna break this down, we should start with Google and Pixel
Speaker 2:  and then we're gonna have Liz join us and talk about Elon. Right? Yeah. Sounds
Speaker 2:  like a plan. We should do it. That feels like the right plan. Let's start
Speaker 2:  with a Google event. David, you were there with a full crew live logged it,
Speaker 2:  the whole thing, what's going on?
Speaker 5:  So this event was weird because Google back
Speaker 5:  in June at IO just was like, here's all the stuff we're gonna
Speaker 5:  launch in September. And then just told us about all the things like we have
Speaker 5:  a Pixel seven and we have a Pixel seven Pro and we have a Pixel watch. And
Speaker 5:  we were like, Tell us more. And they were like later no problems. But, so
Speaker 5:  we get there today and it's at this place in Brooklyn called
Speaker 5:  National Saw Dust, which is I guess like a music venue, I don't know, used
Speaker 5:  to live near there. Did you ever go to National Saw Dust? Yeah, it's
Speaker 2:  A place, It's cute. It's in Williamsburg. It's nice.
Speaker 5:  But it was like we're used to these things being sort of big spectacles.
Speaker 5:  This one was very intimate. I like, it was basically four rows
Speaker 5:  of these chairs, probably 60 people. It was like all journalists. And
Speaker 5:  I was like eight feet from Rick Olo as he's like introducing all these new
Speaker 5:  gadgets. It was nice to be in person again. Yeah, like we Eli,
Speaker 5:  you and I have done a couple of these now where like a lot of people get
Speaker 5:  together and we all watch a video. This was not that, which was nice. But
Speaker 5:  yeah, they launched the Pixel seven. The Pixel seven Pro Pixel watch. They
Speaker 5:  told us a little bit about the Pixel tablet, which is coming next year and
Speaker 5:  I think is actually like sneaky. Very interesting. And then basically made
Speaker 5:  the like grand case for Google Gadgets, right? This like, they've talked
Speaker 5:  a lot about ambient computing, they've talked a lot about like putting all
Speaker 5:  the pieces together. They started the whole thing with basically a long,
Speaker 5:  I think ne you were the one who called it the, the corporate webinar about
Speaker 5:  product design. Yes.
Speaker 2:  It was a product design and And and privacy and safety. Right. And
Speaker 2:  it just, if you've ever had to take a corporate training before in your life
Speaker 2:  where like at the end there's gonna be a short quiz. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Very much that vibe.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, no, I think that that
Speaker 2:  Track but just, I was like, I don't, I I don't wanna remember what kind of
Speaker 2:  aluminum you use. I refuse. In fact sir. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  But yeah, they gave us the whole rundown and then we went down the street
Speaker 5:  to I think, what is the newest Google store that they said just opened
Speaker 5:  this summer and got to actually see the things and I don't know how y'all
Speaker 5:  felt sort of watching it, but being there, it was like the watch was by
Speaker 5:  a mile the most interesting thing that happened today. And the phones were
Speaker 5:  phones and we should talk about them, but like their phones and if you just
Speaker 5:  like imagine a Pixel seven in your head, you're correct. That's what it is.
Speaker 5:  And then everybody went around looking for this, but the tablet wasn't there.
Speaker 5:  But the best part about it was there were a bunch of Nest hub maxes there
Speaker 5:  and I was one of probably 50 people who walked up to one and tried to pull
Speaker 5:  the two pieces apart to see if it was a tablet. And
Speaker 5:  it wasn't. It's a a
Speaker 5:  but it was interesting. And I will say I think the watch to me is, is
Speaker 5:  both better seeming from the experience we've had of it so far and just like
Speaker 5:  way more interesting than anything else that came out to Gabe. Was that y'all's
Speaker 5:  experience too? Yes. Or do you think Yes,
Speaker 2:  Yes and no. Oh, I mean I, I, I mean, yes in the
Speaker 2:  sense that like it's the new product category. David E did a
Speaker 2:  big feature with Rick and some other Google folks about it. People should
Speaker 2:  go read it. It's interesting. My no is like,
Speaker 2:  all I can think for better or worse is when will Google
Speaker 2:  stop caring about it? Yes. Right. Which is kind of the thrust of your feature.
Speaker 2:  And like Google it's, it's Google. Like they have
Speaker 2:  created this problem for themselves where I just
Speaker 2:  need to believe them. Right. And I'm actually more, and so like if I just
Speaker 2:  had to rank them, I would say like the Pixel tablet to me, which isn't even
Speaker 2:  out yet and is like kind of paperwork. Cause the ship date is just 2023.
Speaker 2:  Like I know they're committed to Nest hubs. I know how I use
Speaker 2:  the one in my house. I've watched it get software updates. Yep. I know that
Speaker 2:  the CEO of Google Cares a lot about Google Assistant and Chrome.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And like I want that product to run Google Assistant and Chrome on
Speaker 2:  it. So like I know it's gonna ship and it's gonna do those things
Speaker 2:  really well. And the watch is like it'll ship and you'll get it
Speaker 2:  and then maybe two years from now they're just gonna shut it down. And like,
Speaker 2:  I, I don't know, I I just dunno how to quantify that. So it's true. Like
Speaker 2:  it is the most interesting thing cuz it's a new category for them. A new
Speaker 2:  kind of hardware, a bunch of new capabilities, a new thesis.
Speaker 2:  But you know, there's just a dark cloud around new Google things now.
Speaker 2:  So
Speaker 6:  You're worry about commitment isn't for the phones, it's for the other products.
Speaker 6:  Like the tablet and the watch.
Speaker 2:  I know why they have to make the phones. Yeah. Every year it's obvious. Yep.
Speaker 2:  Because they need something to scare Samsung with. Right, right. There's,
Speaker 2:  if they let go of that, they might as well just like give Android to Samsung
Speaker 2:  and be done with it. Yeah. So they like, there's like a reason for that thing
Speaker 2:  to exist. There's a reason for their smart home efforts to exist.
Speaker 2:  Right. And you can make some case for the watch to exist. Right. If you
Speaker 2:  don't have this category, Apple's just gonna eat you at the watch. And then
Speaker 2:  the, you know, like there's a whole sort of like meandering road.
Speaker 5:  Yes. Yeah. But it's a weird one because on the one hand I think you could
Speaker 5:  make the case, and this was the fun thing about writing this story and talking
Speaker 5:  to Rick and a bunch of folks on the team. Like you could make the case that
Speaker 5:  the watch is actually like crucially important to all of the things that
Speaker 5:  Google wants to do because it's on your body, because it has biometrics,
Speaker 5:  because it like understands you. It's like all the stuff that they wanna
Speaker 5:  do actually might require a thing that lives on your body. Right? Yeah.
Speaker 5:  So like I can see that. But it's also, to your point by far, the easiest
Speaker 5:  one to walk away from right now. And Google has a really long history
Speaker 5:  of walking away from these things. Like literally, I, I had, I had two
Speaker 5:  calls with Google two days apart. It was like a whatever, like a Tuesday
Speaker 5:  and a Thursday and on the in between day Google killed Stadia.
Speaker 5:  And so it's just like, okay, this is, and I
Speaker 5:  literally, I I opened both of those calls with like, why on Earth should
Speaker 5:  I believe you that you're serious about doing this? And basically their answer
Speaker 5:  is like, all we can do is prove it to you. Right? Like people ask us this
Speaker 5:  question about the pixel phones and we kept making the pixel phones and now
Speaker 5:  people don't ask us this question anymore. And like I look forward to five
Speaker 5:  years from now when I can say the same thing about a watch. And I was like,
Speaker 5:  that's all well and good, but like you're asking me for $350
Speaker 5:  today. Yeah. And that is, that's a very different thing. The watch looks
Speaker 5:  really nice. I will say like Alex, we, we have a couple of them around like
Speaker 5:  Alex and I have both been playing with them and it's got the round face.
Speaker 5:  It's not huge. The interface has made huge strides. Yeah. It's much better
Speaker 5:  to use than any Android smart watch I've ever used. It's
Speaker 6:  Definitely feels like it's probably gonna be one of, if not the best Andrew
Speaker 6:  smartwatch.
Speaker 5:  I think so too. And it also, v and I were talking about this earlier, like
Speaker 5:  it basically just decimate Fitbit forever. Like Fitbit
Speaker 5:  as a, as a thing that exists outside of Pixel products is dead. Like
Speaker 5:  there's just no reason to buy a Pixel or a Fitbit that isn't baked into the
Speaker 5:  Pixel watch. Well,
Speaker 2:  Unless you have an iPhone.
Speaker 5:  Right. That's I'm fair there is that, which is, it turns out
Speaker 5:  quite a large number of people, but No, but I think you're right and, and
Speaker 5:  there's just, Google has to like prove this weird thing that all evidence
Speaker 5:  is against Google, which even with smartwatches, like Google has been making
Speaker 5:  smartwatch software for a long time and intermittently seems to care about
Speaker 5:  it and then forget about it and then care about it and then forget about
Speaker 5:  it. I can see they're four years in now to caring
Speaker 5:  about it and that's a reasonably long time. But like what I bet on Google
Speaker 5:  continuing to make smart watches on without stopping for the next 10 years.
Speaker 5:  Like absolutely not.
Speaker 6:  I wonder how frustrating it is though for people who aren't like us. Like
Speaker 6:  I think every single one of us has sat in at least three calls where Google
Speaker 6:  says this is the time we care about smart watches. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  We're so serious.
Speaker 6:  We are so serious. And most people haven't had to sit through that. Most
Speaker 6:  people don't know that the LG style came out and was terrible.
Speaker 6:  Most people don't know about all those other times or they haven't cared.
Speaker 6:  So like I wonder if that fatigue is unique to us or if that's
Speaker 6:  a bigger thing. I
Speaker 5:  Think that's a fair point. But the, the part that kept jumping out to me
Speaker 5:  was there was this whole section in talking about the pixel phones,
Speaker 5:  I think it was Brian Markowski, one of the Google execs who's in charge of
Speaker 5:  all the Pixel stuff who was talking about how part of the Pixel promise
Speaker 5:  is that it gets better over time, right? Like they do the, they do the drops
Speaker 5:  and their whole thing is like, we have this very powerful processor with
Speaker 5:  a lot of machine learning and we can do all this stuff. And so we're actually
Speaker 5:  in position for your phone to get better over time as the AI work that we
Speaker 5:  do continues to improve. And it's like that's all well and good and there's
Speaker 5:  actually some truth to that. Like the Pixel software has gotten substantially
Speaker 5:  better over the years. It only works if you keep doing
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And
Speaker 5:  Like the Pixel Watch bio accounts has a bunch of stuff going for it, but
Speaker 5:  it's like in no way a finished product and Google has these big ambitions
Speaker 5:  and it's like, you know, it's like a thing we always say never buy a thing
Speaker 5:  based on what it might be someday. Yeah. And Google is making these big promises
Speaker 5:  about where they'll go someday. And I, I just think you, you'd sort of be
Speaker 5:  crazy to believe them even if they're telling the truth or they think they
Speaker 5:  are.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I mean the evaluating something on potential of future software
Speaker 2:  updates is like, I'm old now and I'm just gonna tell you it's a suckers game.
Speaker 2:  Yes. You shouldn't do it. But the, you know, this was true of like
Speaker 2:  Amazon last week too, right? Amazon has just sort of like
Speaker 2:  relentlessly iterated on Alexa, but it has reached its final form. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  And like there's not much more they can say Alexa can do. Right. And so now
Speaker 2:  they just like put it into like Alexa can fly now
Speaker 2:  it's like literally a product is like a flying ring camera with l like
Speaker 2:  fine. And I just think phones are that thing and watches are not that
Speaker 2:  thing yet. Yeah. We don't know where watches are going to go and Google's
Speaker 2:  just starting well behind Apple. Right. So we should talk about the watch
Speaker 2:  as it is and what the promises are today, what it can do. But then it's the
Speaker 2:  question of, as you were saying David, the the question is like, it might
Speaker 2:  be central to their whole strategy and it's like worth understanding what
Speaker 2:  that whole strategy even could be for this thing. Even though it's like obvious
Speaker 2:  it's not this one and that, Right? Like they're gonna make a Pixel Watch
Speaker 2:  two and a Pixel Watch three and a Pixel Watch four. And maybe by then we
Speaker 2:  will believe them that they're committed to the product and we'll like live
Speaker 2:  up to more of their ideals. Right. Right now, just from watching it,
Speaker 2:  it seems like it's round, it's cool, it's a little bit smaller than
Speaker 2:  Apple watches. It's got a bunch of cool Fitbit stuff in it and it's where
Speaker 2:  os and that is, it is, am I missing something? No,
Speaker 5:  That's pretty much, that's pretty much the extent of it. I mean e even the
Speaker 5:  fact that they had James Park who was formerly the CEO
Speaker 5:  of Fitbit before they were bought by Google do the presentation for the Pixel
Speaker 5:  watch I thought was deeply fascinating. Yeah. Like, like Google and I wrote
Speaker 5:  about this bunch in the story, but like Google has these big ideas about
Speaker 5:  like risk computers, right? And it's like this thing should be contextual
Speaker 5:  and it should understand you and it should interact with your other devices.
Speaker 5:  Like they made a Fitbit, like make no mistake. Like the Pixel Watch is a
Speaker 5:  Fitbit that also runs Google Maps. Like that is functionally what this thing
Speaker 5:  is. But we
Speaker 6:  Should, we should note a very good looking Fitbit.
Speaker 5:  It is, it's, it's nice looking and by all extent or by all accounts very
Speaker 5:  powerful.
Speaker 6:  Like, and Fitbit was terrible at making good looking smart watches. Yes.
Speaker 6:  Like the worst at
Speaker 5:  It. Yes. There was a
Speaker 2:  How's the bezel? This is what I mean, honestly, we we're 16 minutes into
Speaker 2:  this and now I'm asking about the bezel. I've not done my job. How's the
Speaker 2:  bezzle? It's,
Speaker 5:  This question is so hard to answer. Alex can vouch for this. So it's a weird
Speaker 5:  thing where like the Bele is large. Yeah. It, it just is large,
Speaker 5:  but the way they've designed the UI is such that you don't actually notice
Speaker 5:  the bele most of the time. It's
Speaker 6:  Like the bele on on earlier Apple watches where like there's a
Speaker 6:  bezel and, and you sometimes bump up against it and I think you are gonna
Speaker 6:  bump up against it a lot more in this watch than on an Apple watch. But you
Speaker 6:  don't really notice it that often. You're not like ah, a lot. Whereas previous
Speaker 6:  round watches you'd put it on and be like, Yep, it's a big old bezel
Speaker 6:  on.
Speaker 5:  Totally. Or it had that flat tire at the bottom. Yeah. Like the, the Moto
Speaker 5:  watches did. Like, it doesn't feel like any of that. It feels like it's all
Speaker 5:  screen. Except if for anybody who hasn't watched the keynote, I encourage
Speaker 5:  you to go back to the keynote and look for the moment where they're testing,
Speaker 5:  they're showing off that you can take a photo using the watches
Speaker 5:  of View Finder and there's a moment where you can see the little square view
Speaker 5:  finder on it and that is the moment where you're like, Holy God, is that
Speaker 5:  be enormous? Yeah. And Google does a really good job of hiding it with the
Speaker 5:  other ui. Like it's all really dark and it all sort of like fades off to
Speaker 5:  the sides. So it doesn't, it's not just like color into a black bezel, but
Speaker 5:  it's big. It's real, real, real big. Yeah. If you actually find
Speaker 5:  the thing where it hits against the bezel with color, you'll notice how big
Speaker 5:  it is.
Speaker 6:  I mean I was thinking like, we published this piece yesterday that was kind
Speaker 6:  of like a timeline of the Pixel phone over the years and
Speaker 6:  it reminds me of that very first pixel phone where it was like, there's like
Speaker 6:  some cool ideas in here, but oh, there's some really
Speaker 6:  ugly design choices. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It was not an attractive phone.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And, and it feels like that same thing
Speaker 6:  where it's like y'all have some really good ideas but boy, and when it comes
Speaker 6:  to design, Apple just schools you, Samsung just schools you
Speaker 6:  and they haven't done much to improve that.
Speaker 2:  You know, it's funny, I feel that way about the phones. I don't feel that
Speaker 2:  way about the watch really. I mean you guys have seen I have not. You got
Speaker 2:  Yeah, Alex and David are in the office. We have a bunch of units. They've
Speaker 2:  actually seen them. David was at the thing. I'm just watching the videos
Speaker 2:  and reacting to the photos like everybody else, the watch seems like a composed
Speaker 2:  thing. Like they have a point of view about it.
Speaker 2:  The band seem really cool. The band attachment mechanism seems really cool.
Speaker 2:  The entire vibe, just from where I'm sitting when you put different bands
Speaker 2:  on, it seems like the entire vibe of the watch changes dramatically. Yep.
Speaker 2:  In a way that is like not true of the Apple watch actually. That's fair.
Speaker 2:  Like you can put the fanciest band on Apple Watch, it's still an Apple watch.
Speaker 2:  This looks like it actually takes on a new character. That part's fine.
Speaker 2:  The Pixel seven is like, you can't convince me that you did anything to
Speaker 2:  design this to make it look nicer. You were just like, screw it. There's
Speaker 2:  Neils gonna complain about it in the podcast, but this is what we got. We're
Speaker 2:  just doing it again. Like I'm just doing it. I mean it's, were you not,
Speaker 2:  it's
Speaker 5:  An ugly, you weren't swayed by the 15 minutes of telling you about lemon
Speaker 5:  grass and how nice all the human designs are.
Speaker 5:  No, I'm, I'm shocked. The colors are great. I will say yeah, lemon
Speaker 5:  grass and hazel dumb names, good colors, but I'm kind with you.
Speaker 5:  I mean it's just,
Speaker 6:  Wait, which is the lemon grass and which is the hazel
Speaker 5:  Lemon grass is the, the sort of like off green-ish one?
Speaker 6:  That one's good. Yeah, that
Speaker 5:  Is, it's, it's like other companies would call that like sea foam or something,
Speaker 5:  but Google went with lemon grass and Hazel is, I don't, it's the hazel one.
Speaker 5:  I don't, I don't have a good answer for you
Speaker 6:  On that. And then there's like a gray one
Speaker 5:  That might be the hazel one. I, I don't know. None of these make any sense
Speaker 5:  to me. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  There was a part where Isabelle from Google was like, the centerpiece of
Speaker 2:  our warm colors is lemon grass. And then they showed the lemon grass and
Speaker 2:  I was like, that's a, but that's a cool color. And I still don't know what
Speaker 2:  she meant
Speaker 5:  Because
Speaker 2:  Then they're like, and here's the cool colors and they were indeed much cooler,
Speaker 2:  but I was like, just going back to the green. That's it. Okay.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Yeah. The green was nice. The hazel is the kind of gray color and
Speaker 6:  I, I'm not a fan of that one. It felt a little like it's got too much brown
Speaker 6:  in it for me. That's too warm.
Speaker 5:  I could definitely see that. Yeah. But my thing with the pixel design and
Speaker 5:  ne you've, you've never liked the pixel design and I feel like I, I nothing
Speaker 5:  the pixel design, like I don't, I don't, I don't, I wouldn't say that I like
Speaker 5:  it, but I also like, I have no strong Is
Speaker 2:  This how you broke up with people back when
Speaker 6:  You were like,
Speaker 2:  So like, here's the deal. I nothing.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I'm just, I'm WellMed by by this relationship that I have with my
Speaker 5:  seven pro. Yeah. It just feels like it's, it's just like, it's
Speaker 5:  not doing enough for me to like have strong feelings about it. Yeah. But
Speaker 5:  people seem to have really strong feelings about it. I don't
Speaker 2:  Know. I just,
Speaker 6:  I mean it looks, it's shiny. I, I I like that it's, it's
Speaker 6:  very like, it feels luxurious. It looks pretty
Speaker 6:  luxurious.
Speaker 2:  The pixel seven,
Speaker 6:  That's the shiny one, right? No, I'm thinking of the pro.
Speaker 5:  Okay. Yeah. This is what I mean. You, you have strong feelings. How is it
Speaker 5:  possibly We have strong
Speaker 2:  Feelings. Okay, hold on, hold on.
Speaker 5:  We,
Speaker 6:  I have to make sure I'm talking about the right one.
Speaker 2:  Here's what we know. I just wanna put this out there. What we know from
Speaker 2:  our own audience data and from your experience at the event is that people
Speaker 2:  care about the watches more than the phones.
Speaker 5:  Oh unquestionably
Speaker 2:  Your desire to make me dunk on the phones I'm resisting. So we can finish
Speaker 2:  talking about the
Speaker 5:  Watches. Fine.
Speaker 2:  Tell me more about the watches. What's s is updated, How's that working?
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  S actually seems really nice. Google has spent a bunch of time over
Speaker 5:  the years trying to make it less complicated. Like I went back and watched
Speaker 5:  the 2014 io where they actually announced Android wear in the first
Speaker 5:  place and it had this like the mental map of Android wear was insane.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It was like you, you, you were on the screen and then it was like there
Speaker 5:  was stuff to the right and stuff to the left and stuff up top and you could
Speaker 5:  go down farther and it was insane. And so Google has pulled all of that way
Speaker 5:  back and it's basically, you, you get like small widgets
Speaker 5:  and feeds and you can swipe down to get to the control panel. It's like,
Speaker 5:  it feels like teeny tiny Android. Like in a good way. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And at least this watch is I, I confess I'm
Speaker 5:  slightly out of date in my Android smart watch usage. But I, this was my
Speaker 5:  experience and I checked it with V and she agreed that this is like dramatically
Speaker 5:  smoother and better feeling than any Android smartwatch I've ever used.
Speaker 5:  Everything we've used so far for the most part was in like a demo mode. So
Speaker 5:  it's really, it's hard to know what sort of the deep powerful stuff will
Speaker 5:  be like. But even just like little swipes, it was the kind of thing that
Speaker 5:  used to be sort of slow and stuttery and it would like miss when you would
Speaker 5:  flick on the screen and it just didn't seem to do any of that. Like they've
Speaker 5:  done a really good job of actually tuning the thing up to work. And it was
Speaker 5:  one of the things they told me they spent a lot of time on and sort of tacitly
Speaker 5:  admitted in talking about it that like this was a thing they had not done
Speaker 5:  well in the past and eventually realized they should probably get right.
Speaker 2:  So Samsung smartwatches wheres traditionally, like
Speaker 2:  Samsung smartwatches ran ties in for a minute and they merged
Speaker 2:  and where os and then Samsung is doing Samsung stuff, which is like their
Speaker 2:  own riff on it. They barely even mention where os when they introduce
Speaker 2:  new versions of the Galaxy watch, right? Yeah. It's like a flicker
Speaker 2:  of a ghosted image on a slide in the transition between two
Speaker 2:  other slides in their presentations. Right. Subliminal
Speaker 2:  messages like in
Speaker 5:  Between frame white text on a white background that just says Android.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  But you know, Samsung watches have a point of view. Right, Right. That you're,
Speaker 2:  and they, and they're kind of like feature laid in and there's lots of buttons
Speaker 2:  and settings, Samsung stuff this from all counts is
Speaker 2:  much more minimal. Right. But it's still wears. Yeah. Do you feel a split
Speaker 2:  there? Do you feel like they've tried to par it down and focus it?
Speaker 5:  It's gonna be a little hard to tell until we can like really put some apps
Speaker 5:  on it and put the thing through it. Space is, but they clearly have tried
Speaker 5:  to do that. Like I think your, your reaction to what they're attempting to
Speaker 5:  do is, is the right one that like they're, they're trying to not make a thing
Speaker 5:  that you spend a lot of time with. Like I, I'm sure you guys noticed this,
Speaker 5:  but like voice interaction continues to be the thing that Google harp's on,
Speaker 5:  right? They're like with all of their devices, they're like voice is the
Speaker 5:  answer. Speech to text and text to speech. Like that's, that's where we're
Speaker 5:  headed. That's where all of this is gonna go. And then they're trying to
Speaker 5:  make things take fewer taps, which I think is meaningful that like
Speaker 5:  with the the Fitbit stuff, it should just be sort of a quick scroll through
Speaker 5:  information that you want and Maps works much simp much more
Speaker 5:  simply and they're definitely trying to get to the phase where like Samsung
Speaker 5:  wants you to use your watch like a computer and Google
Speaker 5:  definitely doesn't, I think Google that's still doesn't know exactly how
Speaker 5:  you should use your watch, but the answer is not like a computer.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. It feels like this time they've taken more of that
Speaker 6:  Fitbit DNA because for years they, they didn't, they just wanted it to be
Speaker 6:  like a watch that you could also get notifications on because they're like
Speaker 6:  primary person putting wear os into watches was Michael Cores, you
Speaker 6:  know? Yeah. Right. Like they didn't care. Right. And now that they've got
Speaker 6:  the Fitbit, they've got all that fit apparatus behind it and it's like okay
Speaker 6:  we can have a point of view but it's still gonna be software but it's gonna
Speaker 6:  be fitness. It's totally be like that.
Speaker 2:  So that's my, that's my kinda my last big question here. I don't think Apple
Speaker 2:  knows why people are wearing these watches either, really. Right. Like you
Speaker 2:  go back in time David, you were saying like the first wears stuff was just
Speaker 2:  a scatter shot mess of things and like huge ideas.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. So bad. So is the first Apple watch, do you remember when Apple was
Speaker 2:  like, you're gonna send heartbeats to people?
Speaker 6:  I wanna do that right
Speaker 5:  Now. It was the two fingers, right? Put two fingers on it and it sends your
Speaker 5:  heartbeats
Speaker 2:  Somebody else. It truly bizarre idea. Forgot
Speaker 2:  about that. We should all be doing more of, Honestly Apple should bring the
Speaker 2:  heartbeats thing back. Can
Speaker 5:  I, can I send you my heartbeat now? Yes. Still there. That just opened the
Speaker 5:  weather app didn't work. I tried put two fingers on my watch. Nothing happy.
Speaker 2:  I will say that the walkie-talkie bees, right? Apple Watch is criminally
Speaker 2:  underrated, underutilized. I use it all the time. Absolutely. Apple should
Speaker 2:  put all of its development, stop making the carri that watch walkie-talkie
Speaker 2:  better anyhow. But you know like, like all of these devices,
Speaker 2:  Google started a huge idea and they've had to par down Apples sort of a huge
Speaker 2:  idea. And they've had to perton Apple has very much landed on, well
Speaker 2:  the Apple Watch Ultra is like basically a huge computer on your wrist, big
Speaker 2:  screen app store, The whole thing can work
Speaker 2:  independently of the phone now. But really we know that the reason you buy
Speaker 2:  it is like health and fitness. Right. And the Ultra is like the pinnacle
Speaker 2:  of that. Right? They're like, this is for people who dive. Yep. Right.
Speaker 2:  Like you have to pick which band you want depending on what kind of mountaineer
Speaker 2:  you are. And obviously you've already considered that
Speaker 2:  because they know like this is what drives the thing. Google was like, we
Speaker 2:  have to buy Fitbit in order to be competitive. We've added a Fitbit to it.
Speaker 2:  Or there like meaningful fitness features out of Fitbit here. Or is it just
Speaker 2:  a Fitbit?
Speaker 5:  It's basically just a Fitbit. Okay. It seems to be a particularly good one.
Speaker 6:  I feel like that's enough because the Fitbit audience was never the
Speaker 6:  alter audience. It was never the garment audience. It was never like the
Speaker 6:  super fit audience. Right. The Fitbit audience has always been the same audience
Speaker 6:  as the Apple watch where it's like, yeah, sometimes I wanna know my heart
Speaker 6:  rate, sometimes I wanna be able to show my friends that I, I walked outside
Speaker 6:  today so that they stopped shaping me. Like, like that's always kind of been
Speaker 6:  the goal of these products. And this is like, okay finally you have an
Speaker 6:  alternative to Apple if you want. Hopefully if you want just a nice
Speaker 6:  looking watch that does those very basics. And if you
Speaker 6:  wanna get more hardcore than that garment or Samsung or
Speaker 6:  whoever's there. But I think this is really for that that Fitbit audience
Speaker 6:  who's been like dicked around for years. Yeah. With really
Speaker 6:  bad smart watches from Fitbit.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I think that's totally right. Like Google needed Fitbit in a big way,
Speaker 5:  but Fitbit also needed Google to like, people have been asking Fitbit to
Speaker 5:  make better looking devices for as long as Fitbit has
Speaker 5:  existed and Fitbit just basically has not been able to do it. Like the company
Speaker 5:  has sort of intermittently tried. Like I remember doing a story God eight
Speaker 5:  years ago maybe, where Fitbit was like, we're gonna start making fitness
Speaker 5:  trackers that are like jewelry. Yeah. And it was like, all right. And then
Speaker 5:  they were like, look at this one we made. It's six inches long and rock
Speaker 5:  solid and it's just a Fitbit.
Speaker 6:  It was just like a black pill and you put it in a gold bracelet.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And I think, I think the thing we, we, we don't talk about enough is
Speaker 6:  like Fitbit's primary audience for a long time was women. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And and women have been left out oftentimes
Speaker 6:  from smart watches because so many smart watches are these really, really
Speaker 6:  big watches. And a lot of women and a lot of people with smaller love to
Speaker 6:  wear them. I'm wearing one but a lot don't. Yep. And so
Speaker 6:  they've held onto their Fitbits for a very long time or they've just been
Speaker 6:  like, All right, I guess I'm just going to get, you know, a $10 special watch
Speaker 6:  at Walmart just so I have something to wear. And this
Speaker 6:  is like, this is for them, This is for people who are like, I don't
Speaker 6:  need all the big gadgets and stuff. I just want something nice that I can
Speaker 6:  like be in on this too with everybody else. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  No I, I totally, I think that's exactly
Speaker 2:  Right. I just wanna come back to the idea that two things you can do with
Speaker 2:  smart watches now are send your heartbeats to people and then per Alex
Speaker 2:  shame them for not walking enough. Yes. Those are your two choices
Speaker 2:  every,
Speaker 6:  Do not
Speaker 2:  Remember sending direct taps or
Speaker 6:  Like you didn't walk it up, you
Speaker 2:  Were lazy.
Speaker 6:  Do you remember the, when the Fitbit first came out everyone I know was
Speaker 6:  like, Oh yeah I have a Fitbit cause I care about fitness. Yeah. They're like,
Speaker 6:  No you don't need that. That's too performative. And so
Speaker 6:  it is that like performative stuff going on. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Well I think it's neat. I'm curious to see, you know, Google took a couple
Speaker 2:  of hard shots at Apple today. We should talk about them more with the phone
Speaker 2:  in the next section. But this is the point now where they can start to
Speaker 2:  pressure Apple even again even in terms of regulations about
Speaker 2:  hey there's a lot of people that would like to buy this watch instead of
Speaker 2:  your watch and you won't let them.
Speaker 5:  Yep.
Speaker 2:  And I I think it's, yeah it's probably the same. There's probably some Android
Speaker 2:  people that would like to have an Apple watch just like some Android people
Speaker 2:  buy AirPods or
Speaker 5:  Whatever. Well it's like one, one thing Google would really like you to know
Speaker 5:  is that fast pair is a thing that exists and is open to lots of
Speaker 5:  different devices and also that beats headphones use fast pair.
Speaker 5:  Those are two things that I can tell you confidently Googled very much like
Speaker 5:  a lot more people to know. And, and it's like,
Speaker 5:  and I think you're exactly right. Those are the things and that came up even,
Speaker 5:  even during the keynote today was like Google is sometimes
Speaker 5:  quietly and sometimes not particularly quietly, like continuing to push
Speaker 5:  Apple on this idea that like if you make this stuff work better,
Speaker 5:  everyone will be happier and be better. And I don't know that there are
Speaker 5:  a ton of iPhone users who are like mad about the Apple Watch but, and a clamor
Speaker 5:  for a Pixel watch. But it would, I it would be a more fun world if we could
Speaker 5:  find out. I I I tend to think Yeah,
Speaker 2:  Yeah. That that's, I just, I just keep coming back to that idea. It's like
Speaker 2:  I'm not gonna switch my entire life over to Google Services for a
Speaker 2:  $350 watch. Right. It just doesn't seem likely. So
Speaker 2:  the market is already teeny tiny. They can't go compete in the market of
Speaker 2:  iPhone owners too. Just like Apple can't go compete in the market of Android
Speaker 2:  owners. Apple just seems content cuz all the rich people are on their
Speaker 2:  side. Like that's they know it's true. Yeah. And they're like, okay, we're
Speaker 5:  Gonna, Do you think Google's move is, is it more possible that Google could
Speaker 5:  get people to switch from Samsung to Pixel in order to get a 300 and hundred
Speaker 5:  watch watch? Like is that the move?
Speaker 2:  Does Pixel watch work with Samsung phones?
Speaker 5:  I believe so. The thing on the box, we'll have to test this. So I I I reserve
Speaker 5:  the right to be wrong about this, but it just says an Android phone running
Speaker 5:  Android or later. So it should work
Speaker 6:  Fine. It would be really stupid if it only worked with pixel phones.
Speaker 5:  I'm sure there all I'll be pixel specific stuff. Like I think that it's possible
Speaker 5:  that the, the view finder is one thing that seems likely to me probably only
Speaker 5:  works on a pixel, but I'd be it would be, Yeah, you're stupid of Google to,
Speaker 6:  We're forgetting that like the United States iPhone ran Supreme.
Speaker 6:  The United States is just one country in a lot of places. Android
Speaker 6:  ran Supreme and now like, oh a competitor is Samsung. That's
Speaker 6:  nice looking. That's smaller. Like I could see that doing some real numbers
Speaker 6:  in a lot of places. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  That's true. I think so too.
Speaker 2:  All right, we should take a break. That's the watch 3 49 without
Speaker 2:  LTE 3 99 with lte. It's coming out soon We'll have reviews is always
Speaker 2:  we gotta like use the thing before we can talk even more about it. We gotta
Speaker 2:  take a break. We're gonna come back. We're gonna talk about the Pixel seven.
Speaker 2:  Pixel seven Pro. We'll grab back.
Speaker 2:  Okay, we're back. We talked about the watch a little bit. David try to bait
Speaker 2:  me into talking about the phone. Here's what I'm gonna say about the Pixel
Speaker 2:  seven one, just like the iPhone 14. It looks the same
Speaker 2:  as the phone before it, which our YouTube commenters don't
Speaker 2:  seem to have understood that we said about the iPhone 14. So that's just
Speaker 2:  my note to the YouTube commenters out there who all of whom I'm sure listened
Speaker 2:  to this. Yeah. But you will note that our headline on the iPhone 14 review
Speaker 2:  was this is the iPhone 13 s. Yeah, sorry.
Speaker 2:  You could have had what you wanted, you just didn't, didn't Google it from
Speaker 2:  all like I know what to tell you. We gave you the thing you want, you're
Speaker 2:  like, I would like some chocolate chips. And we're like, Yes, they're here.
Speaker 2:  And you're like yelling at us. There's no chocolate chips. This is what get
Speaker 2:  what you want. There's only one skill and it's getting what you want. It's
Speaker 2:  true. That's my life advice for you today. Second, it's still
Speaker 2:  ugly.
Speaker 2:  They're just ugly phones. I don't know what to tell you about them. That
Speaker 2:  camera bump is horrendous. The colors are slightly nicer. They have
Speaker 2:  refined some of the edges or you know, like they've done some things, they're
Speaker 2:  not attractive.
Speaker 6:  I think that they're shiny and maybe I'm just like easily
Speaker 6:  distracted by shiny at this point. But I was like, ooh, that that gold bump,
Speaker 6:  it's so shiny with a glass underneath. Ooh. Like that just,
Speaker 6:  I don't want it. I don't wanna own this device cuz I, I just bought a phone
Speaker 6:  and I don't need another one. But, but I was like that is, that is appealing.
Speaker 6:  That is a pleasing look to my eyes.
Speaker 5:  Yeah this is my thing Mi Eli. Like I just don't get the hatred for
Speaker 5:  it. It's like,
Speaker 6:  Is it because it's so boring? It's
Speaker 5:  Like looking at this like boring white table and being like, that
Speaker 5:  table is so ugly. It's like no it's not interesting enough to be ugly. Like
Speaker 5:  what are we talking about?
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I don't, all phones are kind of boring now. Maybe
Speaker 5:  That's, It's true. I'll give you
Speaker 2:  That. I'm just like the back of this thing, the glass and then the weird
Speaker 2:  surround and the like at least my pixel sixes, there was a like a noticeable
Speaker 2:  ridge between the glass and the metal and I haven't touched the seven. Maybe
Speaker 2:  they ever find it. They're just ugly. Like
Speaker 6:  The bump is bad, the bump is bad but it's not as
Speaker 2:  Bad. This is like someone, like a Google engineer opened one of the AI image
Speaker 2:  generators and was like generic smartphone. And then it's like this
Speaker 2:  sort of like mutated AI version of a generic
Speaker 2:  smartphone got spit out every time. It's, I don't know, it's like the uncanny
Speaker 2:  value of generics fund design, whatever. It doesn't matter. You're gonna
Speaker 2:  put it in a case. Anyway, the cases last year were horrible. Chris Welch
Speaker 2:  says the cases this year are slightly better. Chris
Speaker 5:  Wel, I just, Chris Welch deserves some credit for this. I'm just gonna tell
Speaker 5:  a very short story about Chris Welch. So I'm wandering around the Google
Speaker 5:  store, like looking at the phones, taking video, taking pictures and I walk
Speaker 5:  over and Chris Welch is standing in front of a wall display reaching up to
Speaker 5:  a set of three pixels, about eight or nine feet off the ground. And
Speaker 5:  he's just yanking at one of them. And I'm like, Chris, what are you doing?
Speaker 5:  And he's like, Just hold on, don't just everything. Make sure everything's
Speaker 5:  fine. And he literally just yanks the case off of one of them, pulls it
Speaker 5:  down, takes off his own case, puts them down and goes to those feel any different.
Speaker 5:  And he goes, Nope, it's the same. That sucks. And then just walks away.
Speaker 5:  I was like all Chris just yanking phones off walls. It's
Speaker 5:  like if you did that at an Apple event, they would've killed you like right
Speaker 5:  then and there somebody would've just sniped you from the Steve Jobs theater.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. But at the Google store they don't
Speaker 2:  Care. I will say when I put on the Apple Watch Ultra, the Apple event things
Speaker 2:  were dicey for one moment. They were like,
Speaker 2:  maybe you should be in jail and
Speaker 5:  And at the Google store they're like, you're touching our phone. Hooray.
Speaker 5:  That's all they want.
Speaker 2:  All right, so look, that's the way it looks. You're gonna put a case on anyway.
Speaker 2:  We should talk about the phones new tensor ship, the g2, she's
Speaker 2:  very proud of. What else?
Speaker 5:  New cameras. And I actually, I wanna talk about the cameras because Google
Speaker 5:  talked a lot of shit about Apple and then basically just said we did the
Speaker 5:  Apple camera, but we'll come back to that tensor g2. There's a
Speaker 5:  6.3 inch screen on the Pixel seven and 6.7
Speaker 5:  inch screen on the Pixel seven Pro. Both have variable refresh rate,
Speaker 5:  both go up to 90 hertz. It's all like medium exciting. They did a bunch of
Speaker 5:  stuff with phone calls that I thought was pretty interesting. They're like,
Speaker 5:  one of their big new features was stuff that if you're going through a,
Speaker 5:  like a phone tree to you know, press nine to get to whatever, it'll just
Speaker 5:  show that to you as a menu on your screen now and you can just tap the thing
Speaker 5:  you want. That's awesome. I'll send you where you're going. It's very smart.
Speaker 5:  And they did a bunch of AI work to like improve the quality
Speaker 5:  of phone calls. You can reduce background noise and enhance your own voice.
Speaker 5:  So there's just a bunch of little things like that kind of all over the phone
Speaker 5:  speaker recognition on the recorder app, which is one of those things that
Speaker 5:  no one cares about. But a room full of journalists got really excited about
Speaker 5:  it. Like it got the biggest gasp of any announcement from the reporters in
Speaker 5:  the room. And that is the entire list of people who will use that feature.
Speaker 5:  And then, yeah, just a ton of of little things. They spent a lot of time
Speaker 5:  on the camera. That was obviously the thing. And like Google is, is in the
Speaker 5:  same way that Google is crystal clear that people buy smart watches for health
Speaker 5:  reasons. They buy phones for cameras. Like that just is true. And well
Speaker 6:  They have to like the cool feature this year was that they can take your
Speaker 6:  crummy, blurry photos and make them look better. Right.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I mean that's kind of been Google's thing for a a while, right? Like
Speaker 5:  the, the magic eraser thing works relatively well.
Speaker 5:  They did have the new feature where they'll do it with your old photos that
Speaker 5:  I think is very cool. Yeah. And there was a guy walking around the Google
Speaker 5:  store after the event who was very proud that he thought he was the first
Speaker 5:  person to use the hashtag fixed by Pixel. And he was like, we should make
Speaker 5:  that a thing. And the Google place were like, yeah.
Speaker 5:  Oh boy. So that was fine. But, but yeah that idea that Google
Speaker 5:  can not only like help you take better pictures but actually fix them after
Speaker 5:  the fact is a big part of what they're starting to push on now with all the
Speaker 5:  AI and ML stuff and
Speaker 2:  Well, well so, but that one in particular they announced was you've taken
Speaker 2:  thousands of photos with the cameras in the past phones in the past. You
Speaker 2:  buy a Pixel seven and you have Google photos
Speaker 2:  and then Google photos on your Pixel seven using the
Speaker 2:  tensor G2 will will like upscale your old blurry
Speaker 2:  photos or de blur them or something.
Speaker 5:  That's right. What is a photo Eli? What is a photo?
Speaker 2:  Well, so like the, the what is a photo vibes coming off the pixel
Speaker 2:  event Oh yeah.
Speaker 5:  Are out of control. Oh yeah.
Speaker 2:  Like fully out of control. So just that, why can't Google photos just do
Speaker 2:  that? Right? Like Google Photos runs on Google servers
Speaker 2:  but do you pay for Google photos? Yes. I pay quite a bit of money
Speaker 2:  for Google Photos. Okay. Nevermind. I have like the upgraded storage plan,
Speaker 2:  the whole thing. I mean goo like famously Google gave Google photos away
Speaker 2:  for free. Yeah. Until they destroyed the market for photo services and now
Speaker 2:  they charge for
Speaker 5:  It. Right. That's actually a super interesting question cuz it's not like
Speaker 5:  Google Photos is short of access to processing power. Right? Like
Speaker 5:  Google has data centers, those can do some things. That's really interesting.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. That that is a device specific thing that has to have been just a deliberate
Speaker 5:  marketing choice. There's no technical reason to just not put that into Google
Speaker 5:  photos.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I think it was Dan who said they, they say they need
Speaker 2:  something in the tensor G2 chip to do it, but it's like you make the
Speaker 2:  chip.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And also your data centers are full of tensor chips.
Speaker 5:  That's like a part of the whole thing. Like the tensor came out of all the
Speaker 5:  work they were doing in their data centers. Like these two things are the
Speaker 5:  same.
Speaker 2:  So I just, that's a little confusing. But that's one thing, and I don't even
Speaker 2:  think that like really implicates the what is a photo conversation. Like
Speaker 2:  you have an old photo and you're gonna do some processing on it to make it
Speaker 2:  a better photo. Like I, I understand how that works. Cause you still have
Speaker 2:  the old photo, right? Yeah. Now you just have like this second improved version,
Speaker 2:  like that's just photo editing, right? Like maybe it's a more complicated
Speaker 2:  thing, but you, you're, you've like created a photo, you're, it the camera
Speaker 2:  on the pixel seven is just far beyond like
Speaker 2:  capturing a still image in time. Yes. It just has
Speaker 2:  abandoned that idea of photo that way. Like
Speaker 2:  almost completely. And so the one that really got me was all of the
Speaker 2:  Zoom stuff they're doing. Yep. Where they're like, okay, we have
Speaker 2:  a number of zoom lens, we have an ultra wide, we have a wide, we have a zoom
Speaker 2:  at every point along the magnification
Speaker 2:  from regular to two x to 10 x to whatever
Speaker 5:  Else. 30 is the max, which is bananas.
Speaker 2:  We're gonna merge frames from multiple cameras, run them through
Speaker 2:  the HDR pipeline that we've set up, and then do AI
Speaker 2:  to create more detail. And it's like, yo, like at some point
Speaker 2:  it really is, you're just holding up your phone to reality
Speaker 2:  and giving the AI prompt Yeah. Like recreate this
Speaker 2:  the scene. Like, like it might as well be dolly for reality, right?
Speaker 6:  Like Google interpret reality.
Speaker 2:  Right? Like, and if you just like watch that, I encourage, you're gonna go
Speaker 2:  watch it again and just like come at it from that perspective. Wouldn't you
Speaker 2:  take a photo? You think you are capturing a moment in time, right?
Speaker 2:  You're gonna open the shutter, Some pixels are gonna hit the thing and close
Speaker 2:  the shutter. And there's a lot to be said about how long the shutter is open
Speaker 2:  and how long that moment in time really is and all this stuff. Google
Speaker 2:  is now like literally a computer is looking at reality and
Speaker 2:  it's gonna try to faithfully reconstruct what we think that reality is. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Using more data than your eyes can possibly process at once.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. We've, we've moved away from like optics being the primary way
Speaker 6:  that like the light is gathered and interpreted and now it's like, okay,
Speaker 6:  the optics are gonna gather the light and then we are actually gonna interpret
Speaker 6:  it.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It's like a it's like a rendering engine. Yeah. That is just very
Speaker 5:  lifelike. It, it's kind of wild. Especially I noticed the same thing in the
Speaker 5:  Zoom ones where it's like they're going through and he just is like, okay,
Speaker 5:  it takes, you know, if you want to be at between two and five x
Speaker 5:  zoom, it's gonna take the telephoto lens and the
Speaker 5:  wide lens and actually do some work to comp them together. And it's like,
Speaker 5:  okay, we're still working from images here. And then it's like by the time
Speaker 5:  you get to 30, it's like, okay, we're doing, we're stabilizing for handshake,
Speaker 5:  we're doing all kinds of crazy stuff on the other end. We're pixel bidding.
Speaker 5:  It's like I'm snapping the shutter and that is the beginning of like a
Speaker 5:  16 step process that ends in, I get a thing that looks like a photograph.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. But there's so much happening in between there that Google is in charge
Speaker 5:  of that. It is just wild.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And there's so much that isn't really
Speaker 2:  transparent about what's going on there. I
Speaker 5:  Mean, except at the end you get to see what you see and the photo at the
Speaker 5:  end. Like there's at least a check on what the thing just Yeah. But
Speaker 6:  You're noting seeing those, those processes, like if I'm in Photoshop, I
Speaker 6:  can see every layer, I know what I'm doing. Whereas this, it's like,
Speaker 6:  Right. I mean most people probably like, That's fine though. Like I think,
Speaker 6:  Yeah,
Speaker 2:  I think most people think it's fine. But like what Dave was talking about
Speaker 2:  with the Zoom on the stabilized zoom when you shoot a video
Speaker 2:  and they were like, we know this is noisy so we're just gonna
Speaker 2:  clean it up. And they just showed like adding detail back to the thing the
Speaker 2:  sensor couldn't have captured. That's weird. Yeah. Like you
Speaker 2:  should, there's just something about all of this that's like, we're getting
Speaker 2:  a little, we're getting a little closer to the photo is just
Speaker 2:  a prompt. Yeah. Or a number of systems to just
Speaker 2:  spit out an image that you, that it thinks you will like.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I'm really excited for the Spike Jones movie
Speaker 6:  in like five years where like somebody's running from
Speaker 6:  a crime that their Google Pixel phone
Speaker 2:  Like no, this already. No, no, no, no. This is what I'm saying. Like not
Speaker 2:  to get too dark. Yeah. This was the basis of a
Speaker 2:  completely nonsensical set of objections in the Kyle Written House trial.
Speaker 2:  Oh wow. Do you remember this? Wow. They had all this photo evidence and his
Speaker 2:  lawyers were like, Your honor, like Apple iPhones are, they are known
Speaker 2:  to use AI to interpolate scenes however they want. And
Speaker 2:  like evidence got tossed out because the prosecutors in Kenosha, Wisconsin
Speaker 2:  were not very good.
Speaker 2:  And they were just like not prepared for this objection. Like it's, it's
Speaker 2:  already has happened in a very high profile case that like, Wow. Yeah. The
Speaker 2:  thing that a camera makes is so unknown that you can like, you
Speaker 2:  can undo it, you can undo its validity because you can't, you have to
Speaker 2:  bring in an expert to explain how it works. And like that has nothing to
Speaker 2:  do with family photos. Like I'm very happy that the Google Pixel seven pro
Speaker 2:  can like take a better picture of a child than Yes. The phone that came before
Speaker 2:  or a phone from two years ago. But just philosophically,
Speaker 2:  the thing that happens when you push a shutter button is getting
Speaker 2:  farther and farther away from like
Speaker 2:  centuries of cultural expectation of what pushing a shutter button does.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And there's no like underlying transparency of
Speaker 2:  here is this moment as it existed in time and here is this
Speaker 2:  thing that we made that is the best version of that moment.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I remember Google saying to me a while ago, and I think this was with
Speaker 5:  the, either the first or the second pixel that, Do you guys remember what
Speaker 5:  those phones, you would take the picture and then you would open it up in
Speaker 5:  the photos app and it would show up slightly blurry and
Speaker 5:  then it would sort of resolve. Yeah. They told me at the time,
Speaker 5:  and there's like a 60% chance this was a lie, but they told me at the time
Speaker 5:  that that was deliberate. That it's like it should you, They wanted you to
Speaker 5:  understand that something was happening to the photo that you took as Google
Speaker 5:  was, was like working its magic on it. And
Speaker 5:  that should have gotten better and instead it just went away. And there's
Speaker 5:  like, it's so abstracted away from what users see now
Speaker 6:  It's, it's weird because like camera makers figured this out, right?
Speaker 6:  They said, Okay, you'll get a raw and that's what we're taking. That's optically
Speaker 6:  the thing, right? And then we're gonna give you a jpeg and a can
Speaker 6:  JPEG is gonna be way warmer than it should be because
Speaker 6:  Canon just thinks that's prettier and, and we're gonna do tons of, tons of
Speaker 6:  processing. And so like they, they've already kind of acknowledged that and
Speaker 6:  said, Okay, but we're still gonna give you the raw and apple's finally giving
Speaker 6:  us the raw. And I think like kind of making that connection and making that
Speaker 6:  more common might be part of the solution here to like escape
Speaker 6:  this like kind of wonky, philosophical and
Speaker 6:  potentially legal quandary. Totally.
Speaker 5:  So the, the thing about the camera that really struck me though, it was like
Speaker 5:  in the course of all of these announcements was they just did
Speaker 5:  the apple stuff with the camera, right? Yeah. Like they're doing some of
Speaker 5:  the same pixel bidding. The, the cinematic stuff is very Apple,
Speaker 5:  all of this. And this all came as simultaneously, Google is just taking
Speaker 5:  every opportunity it can to just knife apple about
Speaker 5:  RCS just repeatedly and crash detection coming three years ago and all this
Speaker 5:  stuff. And it's just like, like I had this moment of sitting there and being
Speaker 5:  like, Oh, all phones are the same now. Yeah. And everybody's just gonna yell
Speaker 5:  at each other about everything And all the phones are the same. Like this
Speaker 5:  is just where we are. Yep.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, they made, they have the list, right? It was like they're always on
Speaker 2:  display in car crash detection, lock screen, widgets,
Speaker 2:  night mode. Like they made a list. Like here's all the
Speaker 2:  stuff we did first that Apple picked up and then they, It's true. They got
Speaker 2:  to the camera section, they're like, Here's what we can do. It's a two x
Speaker 2:  zoom and we crop the sensor. And it's like, yeah, we just, I think there's,
Speaker 2:  there's an element where it's, once you have the big pixel bin sensor,
Speaker 2:  there's a handful of moves that you get out of it that are
Speaker 2:  very obvious, right? Yeah. Yeah. You can stop pixel bidding and you can crop
Speaker 2:  in and use the pixels natively. It all comes down to the processing on the
Speaker 2:  backend. So I, you know, I think you all know this way Apple's
Speaker 2:  processing to me it's just like way outta control lately. And pixels
Speaker 2:  traditionally been better. So like, I think we gotta review the phones to
Speaker 2:  see. Yeah, it just, I just keep coming back to this like Google
Speaker 2:  is being so aggressive with letting AI step in and
Speaker 2:  fix the photos that like, it's like, do I even trust this anymore? I
Speaker 2:  don't know, maybe it's just like old
Speaker 5:  School. Yeah, I mean it was interesting being in the room too, cuz the
Speaker 5:  demos that they showed like Apple, Apple is very funny in the sense that
Speaker 5:  there's very clearly like a large team of people at Apple whose job it is
Speaker 5:  to just go to beautiful waterfalls and take the pictures that they
Speaker 5:  use in their slides. Yeah. And they even said during the
Speaker 5:  keynote today that like one of the pictures they used as an example of how
Speaker 5:  good the zoom was was just like a shot. A person who works at Google took
Speaker 5:  and the demos they showed were not great, but were probably
Speaker 5:  substantially more realistic than the stuff that like I'm gonna get out of
Speaker 5:  my iPhone.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Cuz iPhone, The iPhone is like, you know what, are you ever on a
Speaker 6:  dune in a desert at night
Speaker 5:  With 11 professional photographers? You've
Speaker 2:  Been there, you ever worn a sweater at du in Paris with three
Speaker 2:  beautiful people
Speaker 5:  And there's just a
Speaker 2:  Crew of lighting engineers
Speaker 6:  And everyone has very vibrant hats on
Speaker 2:  The next time we review the phone, the hat budget's got gotta interest.
Speaker 6:  Oh, gotta absolutely increase it.
Speaker 5:  But it, it was just striking to me to see like a, these two companies
Speaker 5:  are competing more head-to-head I think than ever because like Google's talking
Speaker 5:  a ton about tensor at the same time Apple is talking a ton about the
Speaker 5:  recent a series and m series chips and it's like these companies are competing
Speaker 5:  along the same lines now. Yeah. And it's gonna be really interesting over
Speaker 5:  the next couple years to see there's so many places they could push it, but
Speaker 5:  they're all betting on,
Speaker 2:  Well there's one line they're not competing on, which is that Apple sells
Speaker 2:  a million phones and carriers will all but pay you to get a
Speaker 2:  new iPhone fair. And Google sells vanishingly few phones. I think
Speaker 2:  Vlad Sav, one of our former ver senior editor, former
Speaker 2:  co-founder, former co-founder, existing co-founder, permanent co-founder
Speaker 2:  now Bloomberg tweeted he asked IDC Google since 2016
Speaker 2:  has sold like 27 million pixels. That's as many phones as Samsung
Speaker 2:  sell in a year. Like Google has to
Speaker 2:  sell. Like, I mean it's just like ridiculous situation.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. So many more phones.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And there was a, there was a line today that Google has like doubled
Speaker 5:  its order for the pixel sevens cuz they're, they're hoping to sell more and
Speaker 5:  it's really, it's like they're going from like a tiny number to a
Speaker 5:  tiny number. Like good job Google. Like, we're proud of you.
Speaker 5:  But it's a long road to
Speaker 2:  Go here. It's a long road to go. We should quickly, we gotta get, we gotta
Speaker 2:  bring Liz and talk about Elon. We should quickly talk about the tablet.
Speaker 6:  Oh yeah.
Speaker 2:  I'm very excited about just because I, I have a Nest hub
Speaker 2:  and we use it for photos and we talk to Google to set timers, all the
Speaker 2:  things. Well the one thing you do, you said timers, you ask for music occasionally
Speaker 2:  you ask it to play YouTube tv, which is very cool when it works. So like
Speaker 2:  having a bigger version of that is cool. But if you can also run Chrome
Speaker 2:  on a fast processor done. Yes. Like kitchen computer
Speaker 2:  solved. And so like, I'm gonna buy one in this dock that lets you turn
Speaker 2:  it into a Nest hub just because having the backstop of like, screw it,
Speaker 2:  I'm just gonna open Chrome. Yeah, sounds great. But
Speaker 6:  Lenovo already did it. Lenovo's been doing it right, Like
Speaker 6:  have
Speaker 2:  You But they put like a garbage media tech processor in their thing.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. With like a, the big bele like
Speaker 2:  Amazon has already done it too. But then you've gotta use Amazon's weird
Speaker 2:  browser on their bad check.
Speaker 6:  Okay. So so what's appealing to you is that it's it's a different form.
Speaker 6:  It's a different processor.
Speaker 2:  What's appealing to me is that Google appears to have cared about processing
Speaker 2:  capability in the tablet by putting in their high end arm chip. Everybody
Speaker 6:  Else has,
Speaker 2:  Right? Like Lenovo has done it, but that like fully cheaped out on this
Speaker 2:  tablet. Yeah. Like bad display, chunky, you know,
Speaker 2:  bad construction, shitty processor. Like life's too short for slow
Speaker 2:  computers, man, you know, like I'm gonna just go get my laptop. How,
Speaker 6:  How expensive is it gonna be? That's, that's because like Lenovo cheaped
Speaker 6:  out because they were like, we wanna get it down to a price that it makes
Speaker 6:  sense. Yeah. And this is like, seems pricey.
Speaker 2:  David, did they have the tablet there? Did you get to play with it? No,
Speaker 5:  We went, we went looking for it and there were, there were several instances
Speaker 5:  of people like wandering around the Google store trying to peel
Speaker 5:  apart a Nest hub Max to try and find it to no avail. That's pretty good.
Speaker 5:  But the, there was no tablet and we don't know what it's gonna cost. We don't
Speaker 5:  know when it's coming. It does from all the videos look very much like
Speaker 5:  a Samsung tablet from like eight years ago. But it seems to be very powerful.
Speaker 5:  And I'm with you on the idea that like a full chrome browser on
Speaker 5:  my Nest hub Max goes a long way. Like I think the big questions for me
Speaker 5:  are like, is the speaker on the dock gonna be any good? Are they gonna do
Speaker 5:  a good job with the farfield microphones so that it feels enough like a nest
Speaker 5:  from far away? And how much does it cost? Are
Speaker 2:  They gonna do the ambient photo mode thing where they do the reflective color?
Speaker 2:  You know, like they gotta do that to make this really work.
Speaker 6:  Yes. Well they they, they gotta release it first.
Speaker 5:  Well there's there's that too. It is very much still vaporware. But I think
Speaker 5:  they, they said this thing during the keynote that was like, a lot of people
Speaker 5:  get tablets and then they're like dead in drawers or charging in corners
Speaker 5:  all the time. And that is, is largely my experience of phoning a tablet.
Speaker 5:  It's like, it is a home device. Like it, it is a thing I use around my house
Speaker 5:  much more often than I use it anywhere else. And so I think they're like,
Speaker 5:  they're, they're on to something smart about how people actually use their
Speaker 5:  tablets. We'll see how well they actually pull it off. But I agree that like
Speaker 5:  fast processor and full chrome browser instantly makes this thing
Speaker 5:  more useful than anything else I've ever put in my kitchen than
Speaker 10:  The KitchenAid.
Speaker 2:  It's true. The
Speaker 5:  Knives, It's the second most sinkful gadget I've ever put in my kitchen.
Speaker 5:  Is the kitchen a
Speaker 2:  Gadget? Do you not have a, we're
Speaker 5:  Talk about this is a kitchen or is a sink a gadget?
Speaker 2:  Here's what I want. I want a 2.3 gigahertz process from my microwave.
Speaker 2:  I want it step All right, that's all the stuff we we're gonna get it.
Speaker 2:  We're gonna get reviews, we're gonna go into it in detail when we actually
Speaker 2:  get to chance to play with this stuff outside of the watchful eyes of
Speaker 2:  Google employees. That's coming up soon. We gotta take a break. Bring Liz
Speaker 2:  on. Oh boy. We gotta talk about Elon and Twitter. We'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  Hey everybody, it's Eli Editor in Chief of the Verge. I am thrilled to announce
Speaker 2:  that after two years of work we're unveiling a brand new redesign
Speaker 2:  of our site@theverge.com. We've got all the basics. We've got a fresh,
Speaker 2:  modern, new logo, we've got really fast and beautiful new article
Speaker 2:  pages. They're bright colors all over the site that highlight our award-winning
Speaker 2:  journalism. But most importantly, we have a brand new homepage.
Speaker 2:  It brings the best of old school blogging to a modern newsfeed
Speaker 2:  experience so we can take the entire noisy world of tech
Speaker 2:  and science all over the internet and have our expert, senior reporters and
Speaker 2:  editors curate it for you all day long. It's a really big change. I like
Speaker 2:  to say that we're gonna revolutionize the media with blog posts and I think
Speaker 2:  we are, Check it out. It's at the verge.com right now.
Speaker 2:  Okay. Whizzle pa, welcome to the Vergecast.
Speaker 10:  Thanks for having me folks. Good to be here.
Speaker 2:  Okay, so let's just be honest, we've been recording for an hour. It's
Speaker 2:  Thursday, October 6th. Has anything happened in the
Speaker 2:  last hour with Elon and Twitter?
Speaker 10:  Yes, of course. So I
Speaker 5:  Of course
Speaker 2:  As is always, okay, so does El does he own it yet? No.
Speaker 10:  Okay, so he filed a thing with the Delaware court saying,
Speaker 10:  hey, we should have a stay of proceedings cause I'm totally gonna buy it.
Speaker 10:  Like I'm totally buying it this time. And then Twitter like filed their
Speaker 10:  own little thing that's like, absolutely don't stay the proceedings. We
Speaker 10:  don't buy this. We think he's up to some mischief. Which, you know what,
Speaker 10:  I kind of agree with Twitter here because like, just given what a
Speaker 10:  week today has been, I think that like, I think that
Speaker 10:  we're, I think we're in for more shenanigans and I also think I'm still
Speaker 10:  going to Delaware.
Speaker 2:  Okay, so let's just back up. When Liz says she's gonna Delaware, what she
Speaker 2:  means is she's going not for like a pleasure visit, although I think you
Speaker 2:  might have a good time. She's gonna go to the trial, which is taking
Speaker 2:  place at the Delaware Chancery Court, right? That's what you might do on
Speaker 2:  in Delaware.
Speaker 10:  That is what I'm going to do.
Speaker 2:  Let's just back up before today in this last hour of surprise
Speaker 2:  news. So Elon said he was gonna buy Twitter for 54 20 a share. It's
Speaker 2:  44 billions April, nice God only knows what. And a
Speaker 2:  bunch of rich people
Speaker 5:  Parent, Wait, wait, wait. Please sum up the entirety of the last six months
Speaker 5:  of Elon and Twitter in the next 60 or so seconds. Just can
Speaker 2:  Start clock. Let's see if I can,
Speaker 10:  All right, the timer going. You've got, you've got 60 seconds starting
Speaker 10:  now.
Speaker 2:  Okay. So in April, Elon tweeted himself into buying Twitter.
Speaker 2:  There's no other way to describe it. For 54 20 a share, which is
Speaker 2:  44 billion. Nice. It turns out a bunch of rich people
Speaker 2:  texted him embarrassing ideas about Twitter, including Mark Benny out the
Speaker 2:  CEO of Salesforce who just said things like Twitter os conversational Os
Speaker 2:  for your life and Twitter. And Elon said, Screw you, then may he gets cold
Speaker 2:  feet. He sues Twitter says, I want out the deal because there's so many bots
Speaker 2:  in your platform. Twitter says, What the hell are you talking about? We'll
Speaker 2:  see you in the Delaware quarter chance Ray. We've been in a lawsuit ever
Speaker 2:  since. Elon's entire bot argument has proven to be a total fraud
Speaker 2:  full of shenanigans. He's losing, losing, losing. We're coming up on trial.
Speaker 2:  He's supposed to be deposed today. Trial starts October 17th.
Speaker 2:  He files a letter with the Security exchange commission, not the court saying,
Speaker 2:  I'm fine, I'm gonna do it. The court puts out a letter yesterday saying,
Speaker 2:  No one has filed a motion to stay this trial. We're continue. Then there's
Speaker 2:  been a lot of shenanigans today leading up to Elon saying to the court,
Speaker 2:  Please stay. Which means pause the trial. I'm actually gonna do it. Twitter
Speaker 2:  won't say yes for an answer. That was the last hour.
Speaker 10:  That's a minute.
Speaker 2:  And now we're here.
Speaker 5:  That was amazing. Well done.
Speaker 10:  So I also wanna say the other thing is, if you weren't paying attention,
Speaker 10:  their reports that Elon, his deposition got moved back, which is what I
Speaker 10:  think all of the shenanigans this week were about was were about pushing
Speaker 10:  back that deposition by saying, Oh Twitter, we're really serious. Come back
Speaker 10:  to the bargaining table because you know this was gonna be a really unpleasant
Speaker 10:  deposition for him because the judge found this week that he
Speaker 10:  may have irretrievably deleted some signal messages that
Speaker 10:  oh, pertained to the deal. Which that great. And then there's also a bunch
Speaker 10:  of questions about the bot stuff because that didn't really show up in the
Speaker 10:  text messages that we saw with, for instance, Paraag
Speaker 10:  Agrawal who had sort of politely asked Elon to stop saying
Speaker 10:  rude stuff about Twitter on Twitter. And Elon was like, What did you
Speaker 10:  do this week? Which like pretty solid burn. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  No, just to be clear, he said stop. I think it was like, what did you get
Speaker 2:  accomplished this week? Or what did you get done this week? Implying that
Speaker 2:  he was,
Speaker 5:  What did you get done this week? Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 10:  In like
Speaker 6:  30 seconds after the text from Pro came
Speaker 10:  In. Again, a pretty solid burn, but like I definitely would not like, you
Speaker 10:  know, go through all of these like court proceedings just to like
Speaker 10:  get a cool burn. But like, yeah, that's me. I don't know.
Speaker 2:  So then Elon puts out this letter, we all kind of bought it, right? He says,
Speaker 2:  I'm gonna buy Twitter 54 20 a share and then we like read the letter and
Speaker 2:  then I'm gonna actually buy, It was like conditional in weird ways. Like
Speaker 2:  you have to pause the lawsuit, you have to drop your claims, I
Speaker 2:  have to get my money out of the banks. And we're like, wait, this
Speaker 2:  is nothing. If you're Twitter, you've already
Speaker 2:  had Elon Promise to buy you for 54 20 a share, right?
Speaker 5:  But
Speaker 2:  This time he means, so why would you believe him? Now he
Speaker 10:  Serious Eli, come on. Oh, and the other thing I'm just gonna add
Speaker 10:  here is that Elon is famously an S sec disrespect,
Speaker 10:  which you may recall from previous shenanigans involving Twitter where
Speaker 10:  he tried to take a Tesla pub or a Tesla private
Speaker 10:  for four 20 a share and then like changed his mind about that. And then
Speaker 10:  there was a tw like a S sec settlement and he was supposed to have like
Speaker 10:  a Twitter sitter, which he may or May does or does not have. Sort of hard
Speaker 10:  to tell. So you know, he's gone on the record saying he doesn't respect
Speaker 10:  the S E C, which makes the s e c letter a particularly funny
Speaker 10:  move to me. Like, yeah, I'm gonna file a letter with this
Speaker 10:  organization that has nothing to do with the Delaware Court and that I don't
Speaker 10:  respect saying that I'm gonna buy Twitter now. You should take it seriously.
Speaker 5:  Well, and it seems like a big part of his whole thing through this whole
Speaker 5:  process has been essentially assuming that the rules don't apply to him
Speaker 5:  because he has lots of evidence that the rules don't apply to him. And then
Speaker 5:  slowly realizing that in the Delaware Court of Chancery,
Speaker 5:  the rules look an awful lot like they're going to apply to him. Yes. And
Speaker 5:  as, as that has become more and more clear, he has gotten more and more nervous
Speaker 5:  about what's gonna happen, especially as it got towards his deposition and
Speaker 5:  the text with his friends came out. Ne the only thing you missed in your
Speaker 5:  description was Jason Kalik Anis, who I now think is the single funniest
Speaker 5:  and most important part of the entire Elon Musk Twitter saga. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Someday we will just do a dramatic reading of all of his texts on this podcast
Speaker 5:  and it will be a great day. But that like the, the vibe I get consistently
Speaker 5:  is is just Elon suddenly going, Oh, like this might actually,
Speaker 5:  I might lose. Like, I don't know that that occurred to him for a long time
Speaker 5:  and it now sort of seems like it has occurred to
Speaker 10:  Him. Yeah, I think that's right. I mean, one of the things
Speaker 10:  that I've been keeping an eye on throughout this
Speaker 10:  trial is that, or these legal proceedings I guess, cause we
Speaker 10:  haven't gotten to the trial yet. This is the mechanism, the forcing mechanism
Speaker 10:  for Twitter, right? And so like, if you're trying
Speaker 10:  to get this done because you want certainty, you can do things like
Speaker 10:  say, hey, we'll forego the trial if, and
Speaker 10:  like maybe knock a buck or two off the deal price if you
Speaker 10:  just do the deal. Yeah. You know? And but as
Speaker 10:  these, these motions have been coming in and over and over again,
Speaker 10:  the court has mostly been ruling in favor of Twitter and finding out things
Speaker 10:  like, you know, at the one of the last hearings that Elon Musk spot
Speaker 10:  experts actually seem to agree with Twitter's spot estimates. That's
Speaker 10:  brutal. Which is something of a problem for Elon Musk's case,
Speaker 10:  just putting it out there as we're finding these things out, his
Speaker 10:  case just looks worse and worse. And although like the lawyers who are working
Speaker 10:  on this case are really serious and frankly kind of scary,
Speaker 10:  this isn't the kind of case that even serious and
Speaker 10:  scary lawyers can be certain they're going to win. Because I don't think
Speaker 10:  the facts are necessarily an Elon's favor. And so the closer we get to
Speaker 10:  this, the more we find this out. And then like the other thing that's
Speaker 10:  going on is the deposition, which was supposed to happen today and got pushed
Speaker 10:  back. So my personal going theory, like everybody tinfoil hats
Speaker 10:  on. Cause I can't see what's happening in these negotiations, I'm just guessing.
Speaker 10:  But my personal theory is that he tried to push back his deposition
Speaker 10:  by filing this letter with the s e c and
Speaker 10:  succeeded in doing so. And there's a really hard deadline coming up for
Speaker 10:  all of the pretrial stuff, which I believe is
Speaker 10:  October 12th. So if
Speaker 10:  Elon Musk's deposition is pushed back, that gives Twitter less time to work
Speaker 10:  with it and less time to prepare for trial because he's super important
Speaker 10:  to all of these events. And that like kind of makes trial
Speaker 10:  a lot more annoying for Twitter.
Speaker 6:  Can he, sorry, can he avoid, can he like
Speaker 6:  push the deposition back even further and be like, Oh, I got a cold today
Speaker 6:  so I can't do it. So Oh, and I guess we're gonna have to push the
Speaker 10:  Whole trial. Well, he's already done that once, so I, I feel like
Speaker 2:  That's
Speaker 10:  Good. I, I feel like the answer is probably no and you end up in a relatively
Speaker 10:  serious situation where your lawyers get sanctioned or something if, you
Speaker 10:  know, he doesn't get deposed before trial. And I
Speaker 10:  don't think his lawyers really want to be sanctioned. So I think he does
Speaker 10:  actually get deposed if we go to trial. I just think that it's going to
Speaker 10:  be in a super annoying and inconvenient way because the entire legal strategy
Speaker 10:  here, I would characterize as the, I'm not touching you
Speaker 10:  legal strategy where it's like,
Speaker 10:  you know, like it's technically within the rules, but it's really
Speaker 10:  annoying and like it's violating the spirit and maybe not the letter of
Speaker 10:  the law. And so that's kind of what I think is happening here.
Speaker 2:  This is my favorite, like it's not even a c plot, it's like a d or an
Speaker 2:  Elott, is that the state of Delaware is
Speaker 2:  the state where all businesses get registered. Like Ved
Speaker 2:  is a Delaware corpor, like just down the line. Any big company, it's a Delaware
Speaker 2:  corporation and they like hold themselves out in the
Speaker 2:  market of states that you might register your corporation in is like being
Speaker 2:  good at corporate law and having this court system that like
Speaker 2:  adjudicates dispute sufficiently and Elon
Speaker 2:  is fucking with that,
Speaker 2:  right? And so like this court like wants none of it. And then the lawyers
Speaker 2:  in this court have other clients in these courts
Speaker 2:  and their rep is like getting screwed with.
Speaker 2:  And you can just see it's like, oh, this is bad. Like look, we got,
Speaker 2:  we have a real nice little country club going here in Delaware. Like
Speaker 2:  get out. Like you can just see there, there there's, there's kind of like
Speaker 2:  the part where the rules apply in the Delaware court is kind of, because
Speaker 2:  the state of Delaware's like image is on the line for where
Speaker 2:  all these corporate disputes happen and all of the players inside
Speaker 2:  those disputes are pretty clubby. Like these lawyers are gonna be back in
Speaker 2:  front of this judge tomorrow on a different case. This judge has a
Speaker 2:  rep with her appeals court, like just up and down the line. This is a group
Speaker 2:  of people that work together to do these things all day long and Elon's
Speaker 2:  desires are sort of like just tangential to
Speaker 10:  It. So the other thing that's worth keeping in mind, Delaware being a
Speaker 10:  center for corporate law, is that there are other Elon Musk suits that are
Speaker 10:  currently pending in Delaware. Of course
Speaker 2:  There are, Oh God,
Speaker 10:  My personal favorite is a lawsuit about his pay package, which
Speaker 10:  incidentally is going to be going in front of this very same
Speaker 10:  judge.
Speaker 2:  That's great.
Speaker 10:  So she's gonna have some feelings about how much she
Speaker 10:  can rely on what he has to say based on what's happened here.
Speaker 10:  So I kind of feel like maybe as an being
Speaker 10:  anno as annoying and it's possible in order to like make Twitter
Speaker 10:  unhappy is not the best strategy here.
Speaker 10:  But I'm not Elon Musk, so who knows, maybe everything works out beautifully
Speaker 10:  for him. Not only does he walk away from the Twitter deal leaving like a
Speaker 10:  smoking crater, he also like gets his amazing pay package
Speaker 10:  and that's the end of that. But I just think strategically it's a
Speaker 10:  really bad idea to annoy judges. That's, that's just
Speaker 10:  my like non, you know, expert thought about the legal
Speaker 10:  system is that maybe don't annoy the judges
Speaker 5:  Well and is it a fair characterization to say that
Speaker 5:  Kathleen McCormick, who's the chancellor in Delaware and is
Speaker 5:  adjudicating this case, basically has made very clear that her general stance
Speaker 5:  is like, I'm not having any of this bullshit. I don't wanna play your dumb
Speaker 5:  games, let's just keep things moving. Like that seems to have been the, her
Speaker 5:  overwhelming response this week was like, cute story. Everybody see you on
Speaker 5:  October 17th.
Speaker 10:  Yeah. Yeah. I mean she said so in one of her filings that she hadn't received,
Speaker 10:  she hadn't received anything. And I just like, I just saw something cross
Speaker 10:  the guys. Hold on.
Speaker 2:  She grant this day
Speaker 10:  It looks like she granted this stay.
Speaker 2:  Okay, we try to do it live. This
Speaker 5:  Is great. Yeah. This is happening live. This
Speaker 2:  Is how we're gonna end the segment. Here you
Speaker 5:  Go. This feels extremely appropriate that this is happening live.
Speaker 10:  This is just what my day has been like. I've been trying to keep up with
Speaker 10:  the court filings and honestly I'm just sort of getting rolled over.
Speaker 10:  Yeah.
Speaker 10:  Okay, let's, let's look at this.
Speaker 2:  Should we read it together?
Speaker 10:  Yes. So the action is stayed until 5:00 PM
Speaker 10:  on October 28th, 2022 to permit the parties to
Speaker 10:  close on the transaction. If the transaction does
Speaker 10:  not close by 5:00 PM on
Speaker 10:  October 28th, 2022, the parties are instructed to contact me
Speaker 10:  by email that evening to obtain November, 2022 trial dates.
Speaker 2:  Okay?
Speaker 5:  And then in all caps, it is so ordered, which is an unbelievably fantastic
Speaker 5:  way to end all communication that I intend to do from now on.
Speaker 2:  I mean, that's what if you, if you're a judge, do you get to do it all the
Speaker 2:  time? I know it rules. So she granted Elon's
Speaker 2:  motion and said, okay, we're giving you a delay for basically
Speaker 2:  11 days, right? The trial was supposed to start on October 17th, right?
Speaker 2:  And she's like, We're giving you 11 more days until
Speaker 2:  October 28th to figure it out with Twitter. And if it doesn't, you have to
Speaker 2:  let me know and we're gonna go to trial in November. Now I know why she
Speaker 2:  did this. Most cases should settle. The correct policy
Speaker 2:  outcome in this case is not the government ordering Elon
Speaker 2:  Musk to buy Twitter, right? Yeah. It just isn't.
Speaker 10:  That's just the funniest.
Speaker 2:  It's the funniest. And that's like, courts don't want to do
Speaker 2:  it. They want people to settle their own disputes. And so she's holding
Speaker 2:  the sword and she's like, I've still got it. I'm just gonna put it away for
Speaker 2:  10, 10 more days. And you figure it out. And I think what they need to
Speaker 2:  figure out is a discount on the price, right? Like that's gotta be
Speaker 2:  what they're holding them up. That's
Speaker 10:  Sort of the question to me. I actually think, given the s e c letter, it's
Speaker 10:  not about an, it's not about a discount on the price at this point. I think
Speaker 10:  it's about the condition for the deal.
Speaker 10:  So
Speaker 10:  what I
Speaker 2:  Like this is live reacting,
Speaker 10:  Like what I, what I think is going on here, given that Elon has said he'll
Speaker 10:  buy the price he previously agreed to, and that the
Speaker 10:  shareholders have already voted for that price, is that a lower price
Speaker 10:  is unlikely. I think instead Twitter wants confirmation
Speaker 10:  this deal gets done. Like they wanna make sure that they're not Charlie
Speaker 10:  Brown and Lucy isn't gonna take the football away again. So my guess
Speaker 10:  is like there's some sort of terms and conditions they wanna hammer out
Speaker 10:  and like that's been part of the hold up in this whole process is that
Speaker 10:  Twitter is saying that Musk has put conditions on
Speaker 10:  this that weren't on the original deal. And I don't blame them
Speaker 10:  for wanting to go ahead with the court case, especially because they think
Speaker 10:  they're going to win and Elon Musk is gonna have to pay all their legal
Speaker 10:  bills in addition to all of his own legal bills. That's said
Speaker 10:  like, I don't know man, I'm, I'm
Speaker 10:  still skeptical about this. We'll see, I, if I'm
Speaker 10:  in Delaware in November, I'm gonna be real annoyed.
Speaker 10:  Let's put it that way. It's very cold.
Speaker 2:  Liz is very excited about being Delaware in October, but once you get past
Speaker 2:  October into November, the research left to do,
Speaker 10:  That's exactly what it is. I live in California, I don't get to see like
Speaker 10:  fall foliage. So I was like, all right, well that'll be really pretty. Like,
Speaker 10:  I'm excited about that. Like maybe I'll go for a hike or something. That'll
Speaker 10:  be
Speaker 2:  Cool. It's over Delaware, November, it's happening for you. So here's what
Speaker 2:  I'll say. So the, the Twitter letter, opposing Elon's motion to
Speaker 2:  stay, which means the delay, they're like, they haven't, he still
Speaker 2:  hasn't accepted his contractual obligations. He hasn't put a timeline on
Speaker 2:  it. He won't give us a closing date. And so the judge here
Speaker 2:  has at least solved one problem. She said, I'm giving you a date if you're
Speaker 2:  not, if this date, you don't hit it October 28th, we're we're gonna
Speaker 2:  trial. So we'll see. I mean, they, they could hit it sooner, but there's
Speaker 2:  the, the threat is still there. And I think that the threat is the most important
Speaker 2:  thing for Twitter. The underlying conditions. We'll see, it's just gonna
Speaker 2:  be weird when, when he ends up in either direction, he ends up
Speaker 2:  like Squiring out of it or he ends up owning Twitter. Both
Speaker 2:  extraordinarily weird outcomes.
Speaker 5:  O obviously you're live reacting here, but like does this, do we have any
Speaker 5:  sense that this makes one or the other of those things any more likely?
Speaker 10:  Oh, I think Elon Musk winds up owning Twitter. I think it's just about all
Speaker 10:  over. But the shouting at this point, like,
Speaker 6:  I have questions about the money because Twitter's lawyers said
Speaker 6:  something earlier today to the judge and, and one of the things they said
Speaker 6:  was like, people from these banks have testified that they haven't talked
Speaker 6:  to him about closing the deal, whereas, and so like, where is the money gonna
Speaker 6:  come from? Doesn't he have to sell Tesla stock? Doesn't he have to still
Speaker 6:  get all of these banks to like do this all in 11 days? And
Speaker 6:  for banks, that's three days as I understand it. So
Speaker 10:  He's definitely already sold a bunch of Tesla stock. Okay. So that, that
Speaker 10:  part is, that part is handled. And then Matt Levine,
Speaker 10:  who I think you all know, we stand here at the Verge,
Speaker 10:  Stan a legend been reading him since deal breaker. He has like
Speaker 10:  the sort of blow by blow of how this kind of thing works. And he doesn't
Speaker 10:  seem to think it's that big of a deal for these lawyers to get it done.
Speaker 10:  Okay. Maybe they haven't talked to each other for in a while. Maybe it's
Speaker 10:  gonna be a little slower than one might anticipate, but he thinks he thinks
Speaker 10:  it happens. And I have no reason not to believe him, Not least of which
Speaker 10:  is that he, like, he's a former corporate lawyer, Like he actually knows
Speaker 10:  how this stuff gets done from the inside. Now do I think that there
Speaker 10:  are, there's a possibility of Elon Musk shenanigans? I do.
Speaker 10:  I always think that there's a possibility for Elon Musk shenanigans.
Speaker 10:  So I'm like, well see, I I will believe the deal
Speaker 10:  is closed when I see that the deal has closed and not
Speaker 10:  before that because I just, there are so, there have been
Speaker 10:  so many like weird like moments in this case,
Speaker 10:  like, you know, for instance involving the All In
Speaker 10:  podcast, which is hosted by Jason Khan and like, I gotta say, like one of
Speaker 10:  the things that I appreciate about the text is that he sounds exactly like
Speaker 10:  he sounds on that podcast. So, you know, he's like legit. Yep.
Speaker 2:  Yes, I've known Jason for a long time. Jason started in Gadget.
Speaker 2:  There's no, The man is, there's no opacity to that man. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  it's his best quality. It's he's he's the same person in every ever
Speaker 5:  The game is the game.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 10:  Yeah. Dude's authentic. So, you know, like there's been
Speaker 10:  a lot of stuff going on, some of which has been goofy, some
Speaker 10:  of which has been ridiculous, some of which has just felt like stalling.
Speaker 10:  Like a lot of the stuff this week to me has felt like stalling, but we'll
Speaker 10:  see, I don't know, like maybe this is like Elon turning over a new leaf
Speaker 10:  and getting really excited about testifying in front of Congress
Speaker 10:  about his social media platform and what he's doing to like oppose the various
Speaker 10:  things that Congress thinks are bad.
Speaker 2:  Oh yeah. Liz assigned me this story when we thought this deal was actually
Speaker 2:  when we thought that letter meant something. She's like, You've gotta write
Speaker 2:  the Elon Musk, Elon Musk content moderation story. I will tell you, I'm gonna
Speaker 2:  write it when the deal closes. Just, I'm not gonna do it before. I'm not
Speaker 2:  gonna do my homework before I have to. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  We've been, we've been played before,
Speaker 2:  But my proposed headline is straight up Welcome to hell Elon Musk.
Speaker 10:  So,
Speaker 2:  Okay. Just a list of things that he's gonna have to figure out that basically
Speaker 2:  no one in history has ever figured out.
Speaker 10:  I just want Verge cast listeners to hold ne Eli accountable to this. Like,
Speaker 10:  I just want you all to make sure that he files on time. I
Speaker 2:  I'm
Speaker 10:  Gonna pure pressure, pure pressure my boss into filing to me.
Speaker 10:  Sorry David,
Speaker 5:  I just, I have found myself wondering, so there was this like, clearly strategic
Speaker 5:  leak that the New York Times and the Wall Journal both had like an exactly
Speaker 5:  simultaneous exclusive story saying that Elon had tried to get a lower price
Speaker 5:  for Twitter and all I've been able to wonder in like the 24 hours since
Speaker 5:  is what is the number that Elon flips from? I will pay this much to not
Speaker 5:  own Twitter, to I will pay this much to own Twitter. And it's like, if Twitter
Speaker 5:  just sits down and it's like the number's $30 billion, like would he rather
Speaker 5:  pay 30 billion and then have Twitter at the end? Or would he rather pay 30
Speaker 5:  billion and then just go about his life and never have to think about any
Speaker 5:  of this again? And I feel like there is a number somewhere where that flips
Speaker 5:  and I have been wondering a about what,
Speaker 6:  It's 53 69.
Speaker 5:  It did ends in 69 for sure. Yeah, that's the only thing we
Speaker 2:  Know. It's definitely, it's definitely 49 or 42
Speaker 2:  69. Here's the question though, like no matter what happens, he's
Speaker 2:  still addicted to Twitter.
Speaker 10:  Yes.
Speaker 2:  Right? Like he can't quit this shit. So even if he pays
Speaker 2:  the money and walks, he's like, you know, he's gonna have that moment where
Speaker 2:  like gets home alone and it's all done and like, you know, and he's still
Speaker 2:  riding high, but there's no one there. Everyone knows this moment, right?
Speaker 2:  And he like, there's a beat and he pulls out his phone, he's
Speaker 5:  Gonna tweet I love cheese.
Speaker 2:  Right? And like, you know, and there's like no one in the house. He's like
Speaker 2:  talked about how it's weird when there's no one in his house. Yep. And he
Speaker 2:  like pulls out his phone and he is like, Oh, what app should I open? And
Speaker 2:  it's Twitter. And then he is like, tweets some insane shit about Russian
Speaker 2:  Ukraine. Again, like, it doesn't matter how much money he loses at
Speaker 2:  the end of the day, Twitter has Elon, Elon doesn't have
Speaker 2:  Twitter.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Like it's just, they're the same thing now. All right,
Speaker 2:  we've gone over my friends as always. Thank you
Speaker 2:  Liz. There's some stuff you should read, Allison, that there's like a lot
Speaker 2:  of things happen today. Yeah, a lot of things happen today, including,
Speaker 2:  I would remind you the reveal of Chris Pratt's
Speaker 2:  liar's mouth in the new Mario trailer. That
Speaker 5:  Feels like it was decades ago now.
Speaker 10:  So long
Speaker 2:  Ago. Allison reviewed the iPhone 14 plus big screen.
Speaker 2:  I'm telling you, big cheap screens the way to go.
Speaker 5:  Long battery life on that thing too big battery life,
Speaker 2:  Long battery life. The steam deck is now available with no
Speaker 2:  reservations, which I can't believe Alex didn't do a whole hour
Speaker 2:  on that on this show.
Speaker 6:  I'm fine. I'm I already have mine. Go get one. You already
Speaker 2:  Have one. Of course. The matter standard is not official. By the way. Twitter
Speaker 2:  rolled out the edit button in the United States for Twitter Blue subscribers
Speaker 2:  today in another time. There was a whole hour of our show, just
Speaker 2:  like it's a huge week. Go look at the site. It's all on there. We got a quick
Speaker 2:  post for days. Yeah, we're over. Go read the website. It's full of Oh,
Speaker 2:  the European Union Pass. Another checkbox. Enfor Apple to
Speaker 2:  use USC just a little closer. All the things. The interview on decoder this
Speaker 2:  week was Pat Gelsinger, the CEO of Intel. That was a pretty good one. We'll
Speaker 2:  be back on Wednesday. Cybersecurity week is kicking off, right David?
Speaker 5:  That's, Yeah, we're, we're gonna do a big cybersecurity episode in a couple
Speaker 5:  of weeks, but it is like, like infrastructure week in America. Cybersecurity
Speaker 5:  week is a couple of weeks long on the vert. So we're, we're gonna have some
Speaker 5:  fun stuff over the next couple of these.
Speaker 2:  All right, you can tweet at us. David is at Pierce. Alex is Alex h Crans.
Speaker 2:  Liz is at Ms. Lato. I'm at Reckless. We love hearing from you. Keep sending
Speaker 2:  notes with the redesign. We're starting to ship little changes here and there.
Speaker 2:  There's some bigger ones coming. We love the feedback. It's great. Love you.
Speaker 2:  That's the Vergecast back home.
Speaker 1:  And that's a wrap for Vergecast this week. Thanks for listening. If you enjoy
Speaker 1:  the show, subscribe in the podcast app of your choice or tell a friend, you
Speaker 1:  can send us feedback at vergecast@theverge.com. This show is produced
Speaker 1:  by me, Liam James, and our senior audio director, Andrew Marino. This
Speaker 1:  episode was edited and mixed by Amanda Rose Smith.
Speaker 1:  Our editorial director is Brooke Miners and our executive producer is
Speaker 1:  Eleanor Donovan. The Verge Cast is a production of the Verge and Box Media
Speaker 1:  Podcast network. And that's it. We'll see you next week.