# Transcript
ID: 290d6cf0-7d1e-11ed-8efc-f10fe3e6582e
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Apple could open up iOS, Elon gets booed, and the golden age of streaming is coming to an end
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-4934119152659798303/-1503655202331307409/s93290-US-5395s-1671180296.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, Alex Cranz, and Richard Lawler break down all the news from this week.
Speaker 1:  Today on the Verge cast, the EU has Apple running scared.
Speaker 1:  Elon Musk gets booed, and the golden age of streaming is coming to an end.
Speaker 1:  That's all coming up right
Speaker 2:  After this.
Speaker 1:  Support for this episode comes from Airbnb. If you've stayed
Speaker 1:  in one of Airbnb's unique homes all around the world, you may be wondering,
Speaker 1:  could my place be an Airbnb? And what could I earn? You could be sitting
Speaker 1:  on an Airbnb right now. That might mean your extra guest room or
Speaker 1:  maybe even Airbnb your entire home while you're away on a long trip,
Speaker 1:  whether you could use some extra money to cover some of those surprise expenses
Speaker 1:  or maybe just a little something for yourself, your home might be
Speaker 1:  worth more than you think. Find out how much at
Speaker 1:  airbnb.com/host.
Speaker 4:  What do your holidays sound like
Speaker 4:  or what about this?
Speaker 4:  Well, now the holidays can also sound like this.
Speaker 4:  No matter what the season brings, smart food has the perfect air popped
Speaker 4:  Popcorn for your holiday party. Try their classic flavors like
Speaker 4:  delicious, white cheddar or sweet and salty kettle corn. And if you're really
Speaker 4:  into the holiday spirit, try their new limited edition Merry Berry
Speaker 4:  Mix. Find your perfect smart food shop
Speaker 4:  now@snacks.com.
Speaker 2:  Hello and welcome to VER the flagship podcast of the
Speaker 2:  Future of Car Sounds. Today in this episode of the Ver,
Speaker 2:  we're all just going to make like bloop bloop sounds and
Speaker 2:  then we're gonna decide what car should sound like in the future. Doesn't
Speaker 2:  that sound nice? Doesn't that sound better than what we usually do on the
Speaker 2:  show?
Speaker 5:  I'm trying to think what my car sound is. I was thinking very, very hard
Speaker 5:  about it.
Speaker 6:  What do you want it to sound like when you're getting run over by a driverless
Speaker 6:  Tesla? Like what would, what would you want to hear? Yeah,
Speaker 2:  It's like Tesla. It's a slide whistle center,
Speaker 5:  1967 Mustang.
Speaker 5:  I wanna feel like I got hit.
Speaker 2:  You want like a dramatic like, like an orchestra hit?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Yeah. I want like
Speaker 5:  that's, that's me going out.
Speaker 6:  Want the ending theme from Buck Rubs High? Like I should be able to select
Speaker 6:  that on my phone and then it just pops up in their car as it
Speaker 2:  Happened. Yeah, like today, like in Minority Report styles, like today, you're
Speaker 2:  gonna get hit by an ev. So if you could just go ahead and
Speaker 2:  pick a soundtrack for that, we'll be, we'll be good. Tom
Speaker 2:  Cruise will be dispatching the third judge.
Speaker 5:  You remember a lot more of that movie than I did.
Speaker 2:  If you haven't seen Minority Report,
Speaker 2:  it's truly, it is truly something else. It's so funny that
Speaker 2:  by the way, they get to the, the name Minority Report. It's so integral to
Speaker 2:  the plot and then it means so little. Yeah, it's, it's very good.
Speaker 2:  You should just go, everyone take a break. Turn off the podcast.
Speaker 2:  Wait, go Watch Minority Report.
Speaker 5:  Why is it it called? Is it called that because one of the three
Speaker 5:  sees the different future. Is that why
Speaker 2:  You're spoiling the movie?
Speaker 6:  No, it's been
Speaker 5:  Out for 20
Speaker 2:  Years. It's
Speaker 6:  Not what? It's definitely,
Speaker 5:  I'm sorry to everyone. I just ruined Tom
Speaker 2:  Cruises. There many problems with predictive policing that we should just
Speaker 2:  immediately begin with. Yeah. And then obviously the targeted
Speaker 2:  advertising, that movie, it just all came true. Like
Speaker 2:  Tim Cook's a minority report and he's like, we have to destroy Facebook's
Speaker 2:  business. Let's do app tracking transparency. He
Speaker 5:  Was just like,
Speaker 2:  One of our has the flagship podcast of talking about Minority Report for
Speaker 2:  no reason 30 years after it came out.
Speaker 2:  We actually have a lot of like housekeeping to do. But first of all, I'm
Speaker 2:  ni Eli, I'm your friend Al Trans here.
Speaker 5:  I'm your friend. Thinking about that one scene between the Gardener lady
Speaker 5:  and Tom Cruise and Minority Report, you know what I'm talking about now you're
Speaker 2:  The memories have all come back, just
Speaker 5:  Just flooded back in. I'm that friend
Speaker 2:  Richard Lawler is
Speaker 6:  Here. I'm your friend who is definitely not under indictment. Say whatever
Speaker 6:  you want.
Speaker 2:  David Pierce continues to be off with his new baby. You
Speaker 2:  know, it happens to the best of us. No, he's great. We wish David
Speaker 2:  well. He'd be back soon enough. We've got a lot going on between now and
Speaker 2:  the end of the year. So obviously we have this episode of the verse has,
Speaker 2:  which will mostly be about the movie Minority Report
Speaker 2:  Buckle. I mean there's, there's actually SPF got
Speaker 2:  arrested. There's this report that Apple's gonna open up third party app
Speaker 2:  stores. Elon continues to just be himself.
Speaker 2:  There's all kinds of GAT news actually. So there's this episode. Then the
Speaker 2:  holiday spectacular is back my friends. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  you might recall that in the waning years of the Trump
Speaker 2:  administration, I said we were just gonna do an entire hour
Speaker 2:  about H D M I to just clear the decks reset.
Speaker 2:  For some reason we did this during the holidays and so
Speaker 2:  now during the holidays we do episodes
Speaker 2:  about specs. This is just a, this is who we are now.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I feel great about it. This year's holiday spectacular
Speaker 5:  For giving a gift to our listeners.
Speaker 2:  I think it's that the joke spectacular is too good to
Speaker 2:  pass up. Yes,
Speaker 5:  A hundred percent.
Speaker 2:  Like in our heart of hearts it's, can I let our producer
Speaker 2:  Andrew Marino do slay bell sounds while we talk about
Speaker 2:  Bluetooth? And the answer is yes.
Speaker 6:  Have we started a new standards group to establish how this will happen?
Speaker 6:  What is the name of
Speaker 2:  It? Spectacular Standards Group. So we've got a, a holiday
Speaker 2:  spectacular. It's about Bluetooth, this year's holiday spectacular. It's
Speaker 2:  about Bluetooth. We've got
Speaker 2:  discussion of the Bluetooth standard. We
Speaker 2:  have holiday sound effects. And my friends, we have
Speaker 2:  Bluetooth Jeopardy, which we have already recorded, I can tell you is one
Speaker 2:  of the most chaotic, I'm incredible, 45 minutes of verge cast
Speaker 2:  history ever put to tape. Liam thought it was gonna take 30 minutes
Speaker 2:  and we recorded for 90. And I'm just guessing they managed to
Speaker 2:  cut that down to 45.
Speaker 5:  They can't cut a single thing every minute of it was perfect.
Speaker 2:  I'll just, I'll just tell you right now. Bluetooth jeopardy is shockingly
Speaker 2:  hard. It is so much harder than you think and I can't wait for you to listen
Speaker 2:  to it. So that's coming out on December 21st. That'll be good.
Speaker 2:  And then actually the biggest news of this week is the fusion
Speaker 2:  breakthrough where a bunch of researchers with the Lawrence
Speaker 2:  Livermore National Laboratory created a fusion reaction, but basically shooting
Speaker 2:  lasers at something that produced more energy than it took to cause the
Speaker 2:  reaction. That's a very big deal, does not get mean free
Speaker 2:  energy, but it's like, it's one of those breakthrough scientific moments
Speaker 2:  we're not gonna talk about in this episode because our excellent science
Speaker 2:  reporter, Justine Comma, is actually interviewing some of the scientists
Speaker 2:  and will have an episode with them coming up very soon as
Speaker 2:  well. So that's really exciting. Just a lot of verge cast stuff to close
Speaker 2:  out the year, including the holiday spectacular
Speaker 2:  about Bluetooth, which I I'm gonna tell you is just one of the
Speaker 2:  finest pieces of technology journalism ever made, ever. Even though we
Speaker 2:  have not made two thirds VI yet
Speaker 5:  Is amazing. Jeopardy.
Speaker 2:  Here's what I think. And if you are a Pulitzer voter,
Speaker 2:  keep this in mind. More journalism should be in the form of jeopardy.
Speaker 5:  I I think, I think it's right because like what are you doing? Someone is,
Speaker 5:  is making a statement and then you're asking a question. You're asking,
Speaker 5:  that's journalism baby. We're doing it. It's true.
Speaker 2:  If also if you are a lawyer with the Jeopardy people,
Speaker 2:  please stop listening to this and turn it off your phone, out the window.
Speaker 5:  Delete us from your feed.
Speaker 2:  You didn't hear any of this Lawyers, the Jeopardy people. Anyway,
Speaker 2:  holiday spectacular Bluetooth coming Fusion episode of Justine coming.
Speaker 2:  And then on video side we have an Apple Watch Ultra
Speaker 2:  Review that's coming next week. It is one of the most over
Speaker 2:  the top videos we have ever made. The video team went all out because
Speaker 2:  how else do you review the Apple Watch Ultra and video. You gotta go do a
Speaker 2:  bunch of stuff. And we have a little note from Becca talking about that.
Speaker 2:  Let's listen to Becca.
Speaker 7:  Hey, it's me, Becca, Versace. Listen, my question for you
Speaker 7:  is, have you heard that I have been working on this honestly
Speaker 7:  insane review of the Apple Watch Ultra because the rumors are true.
Speaker 7:  I have, we have Dove down 130 feet with this watch
Speaker 7:  off the coast of California. We've gotten lost in Yosemite
Speaker 7:  and well, we have people that have been wearing it around New York City for
Speaker 7:  months now and we are doing the most in-depth review that we've ever done.
Speaker 7:  And y'all better check it out. Okay. Especially you David Pierce.
Speaker 7:  Anyway, check it out bud youtube.com/verge.
Speaker 7:  That's all I got.
Speaker 2:  Alright. I am theoretically responsible for everything that happens here
Speaker 2:  at the Verge. Legitimately afraid about this video.
Speaker 5:  I'm, I'm excited about it.
Speaker 2:  No, I'm excited in the way that like, getting arrested is exciting.
Speaker 2:  This is gonna be great. It's gonna be a good time. So that's coming. Apple
Speaker 2:  watch Ultra Videos coming next week. Bluetooth spectaculars coming next week,
Speaker 2:  fusion episode coming soon. All kinds of stuff. And we are obviously gonna
Speaker 2:  take a break for Christmas and New Year's cuz you know
Speaker 2:  it's time to take a break. That's why we made holidays Spectacular for you.
Speaker 2:  Okay, that's all the business. Oh, that's outta the way. Let's talk about
Speaker 2:  some news. I feel like we gotta start with spf. I feel like we gotta
Speaker 2:  start with crypto. We can, we can do it quickly. Richard, you
Speaker 6:  Were there. It's always time to start with crypto. I told you 2023, I'm becoming
Speaker 6:  a big
Speaker 2:  Crypto guy. Tell me what is going on the, by the way, we had this conversation
Speaker 2:  like last week or the week before where we're like, should you interview
Speaker 2:  Sam Bankman Fried? Is that journalism? And it's like, oh yeah, my
Speaker 2:  dude talks so much, he's going to jail.
Speaker 6:  This guy just couldn't stop doing interviews. I was trying to track the interviews
Speaker 6:  that he was doing. I, I was gonna write up some of them, but he just kept
Speaker 6:  doing more. And every time I would, I would take a look at him, say, oh,
Speaker 6:  well just kill a couple interesting things here. He was always live doing
Speaker 6:  another interview as I was thinking about it, write up
Speaker 6:  until he was arrested in The Bahamas now,
Speaker 2:  Right? Until he did his final interview to the police.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Now he's giving very different interviews than en unfortunately are
Speaker 6:  not live streamed. But yes, he has been arrested in The Bahamas. In case
Speaker 6:  you were wondering over the last month after FTX collapsed and they discovered
Speaker 6:  that everyone's money wasn't there like it was supposed to be. It, it happened
Speaker 6:  pretty quickly. I think in comparison as our colleague Liz Pao pointed out,
Speaker 6:  he was arrested a little bit more quickly than Elizabeth Holmes was when
Speaker 6:  Theranos started to go down. And if you've been watching the amount of money
Speaker 6:  that he's responsible for that appears to not be there anymore,
Speaker 6:  is quite a bit more than what the
Speaker 6:  Elizabeth Holmes was, was basically convicted of stealing. So
Speaker 6:  assuming it gets to that point, you can, you can imagine what the possible
Speaker 6:  sentence could be. But let's, let's run it back. Let's just see what happened
Speaker 6:  in November. In kind of mid-November ftx, the second biggest
Speaker 6:  crypto exchange in the world collapsed. Suddenly there was a run
Speaker 6:  on the bank. People tried to get their money out and there was no more money.
Speaker 6:  Pretty ver very quickly. And no one knew what was happening.
Speaker 6:  There was a supposed buyout by the largest crypto
Speaker 6:  exchange Binance. They looked at the books quickly backed off. Fast forward
Speaker 6:  to now, all the regulators, all of the celebrities, everyone who used to
Speaker 6:  be Sam Bankman Free's friend when he was a billionaire, are now running from
Speaker 6:  ftx. They're now pointing the finger and saying that this guy lied. He's
Speaker 6:  everything wrong. And they can't really explain why they didn't see these
Speaker 6:  lies before. But that, that's where we are now. And now we've,
Speaker 6:  we have all of his interviews and we're also getting kind of the, the investigations
Speaker 6:  that have been going on, especially over the last month. We're finding out
Speaker 6:  more, we're finding out real hard information because it's coming out in
Speaker 6:  the bankruptcy filings. It's coming out now in the civil charges and the
Speaker 6:  criminal charges that have been file that been file been filed against Bankman
Speaker 6:  Freed. And it's, it's not good. We found out that a couple of days before
Speaker 6:  the bankruptcy happened, one of his, the executives at F T X was telling
Speaker 6:  the Bahamian authorities that Bankman Fried had moved
Speaker 6:  money that was supposed to be customer funds to his own research firm,
Speaker 6:  Alameda. Which if that is true, then that would be probably a crime.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, that's it. That's just jail. Yeah, like that, that's just
Speaker 2:  a you spot a ticket to jail.
Speaker 6:  So yeah, there's kind of a long list of criminal activities that have been
Speaker 6:  going on and, and we've got breakdowns of the many lies that he's told in
Speaker 6:  the, the charges that he's facing in, in every, everything that's going on.
Speaker 6:  But I've been living the Sam Bankman free interview, life, life
Speaker 6:  for the last few weeks. I, I no longer know what is true or where I am. When,
Speaker 6:  when you guys are looking at this, like what do you see for the case? What,
Speaker 6:  what are you wondering about?
Speaker 5:  Is Tom Brady going to jail?
Speaker 2:  I mean, so a bunch of influencers have been hit with lawsuits. There's a
Speaker 2:  class action lawsuit against a bunch of celebrities, including our boy Tommy,
Speaker 2:  who probably needs to win another Super Bowl just to
Speaker 2:  get a piece of his heart back.
Speaker 2:  I dunno if that's gonna go well for him. I feel like we have to mention that
Speaker 2:  the fact that Tom Brady destroyed his life over Sam Mankin Fried and ftx
Speaker 2:  every single episode,
Speaker 5:  Every single episode.
Speaker 2:  I, you know, here's what I worry about and then what I'm, what I've been
Speaker 2:  thinking about this whole thing is a Ponzi scheme, right? Even their ads,
Speaker 2:  even if you just go back and look at that super ride with Larry David, the
Speaker 2:  ad is about not being left out, which is like
Speaker 2:  the classic Ponzi scheme thing to advertise. It's a pretty good
Speaker 2:  sense. It's like, are you in, like, can you get in at the bottom of the period
Speaker 2:  so the people at the top of your earning cash out? And if you just create
Speaker 2:  that sense of fomo, like the Ponzi scheme will sustain itself
Speaker 2:  a little bit longer. It was never about utility. It was never about what
Speaker 2:  you could do with crypto. And at the end of the day, like what you can do
Speaker 2:  with crypto is still mostly crimes.
Speaker 2:  Like it's basically crimes.
Speaker 6:  Some of them are gambling.
Speaker 5:  You can buy a coffee from like a coffee house in Austin takes
Speaker 5:  Bitcoin.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, the coffee house. I'm sure that coffee house is connected to crimes
Speaker 2:  in some way. I don't know if that's true. Again, if you are a lawyer with,
Speaker 2:  at this point, either Jeopardy or a Austin
Speaker 2:  Coffee House, just stop listening.
Speaker 5:  I didn't name it. It's fine. Yeah. Who knows. Nobody knows which one it is.
Speaker 2:  But like fundamentally the utility of crypto is, is more
Speaker 2:  related to crime than not. Yeah. And there's this
Speaker 2:  piece of the puzzle where all the people who are still in crypto,
Speaker 2:  all the investors, all the technologists, Brian Armstrong from Coinbase,
Speaker 2:  they're like, Sam Bankman, Fried's a liar. No one should be talking to
Speaker 2:  him anymore. Every time he talks, he just makes us all look bad. He pulls
Speaker 2:  the all over people's eyes, journalists are too credible, blah blah blah.
Speaker 2:  He's like, get him in jail so he can move on with our lives. And I think
Speaker 2:  what they're failing to see is there's
Speaker 2:  still no more utility there. And actually putting
Speaker 2:  someone in jail is not easy to do.
Speaker 2:  Right. Like proving a financial crime of this scale
Speaker 2:  past a reasonable doubt and actually winning the
Speaker 2:  case with the lawyers that you know, he's gonna be able
Speaker 2:  to put together and the defenses he'll mount and just the cloud
Speaker 2:  of obfuscation that he'll put together is, it's
Speaker 2:  gonna take a long time. And I think there's this immediate rush to
Speaker 2:  judgment in all of this. Like, he's a fraudster, he should go to jail.
Speaker 2:  Let's close this chapter of crypto history and move on
Speaker 2:  to the next thing, which is not clear,
Speaker 2:  but let's move on to it as fast as we can.
Speaker 6:  Let, let me mention one of my favorite parts of this is that the fall of
Speaker 6:  Sam Nkf Fried and FTX has brought back all of our fields crypto friends
Speaker 6:  from years past Mark Polis who ran Mountain GOs, a
Speaker 6:  crypto exchange that failed in, what was that, 2015 Now that was many years
Speaker 6:  ago. One, one of the first big crypto failures of exchanges that went away
Speaker 6:  and took away everyone's money with it. He's been tweeting endlessly about
Speaker 6:  it. He's been giving advice to Sam Bang Fried about what he should do
Speaker 6:  and how, how mostly he shouldn't talk to anyone. He should only talk to his
Speaker 6:  lawyers. Yeah. And he would know because he has been there and he is,
Speaker 5:  I have a question. Yes. Are there any exchanges, crypto
Speaker 5:  exchanges that are not Ponzi schemes?
Speaker 6:  I don't know how to legally answer that.
Speaker 5:  Like, because all of them basically, they take your money and then they say,
Speaker 5:  now our money grew bigger and we'll give you your money back. But like
Speaker 5:  is the cat is is the US dollar wait,
Speaker 2:  You, is that, wait, are you describing the exchanges of the tokens?
Speaker 5:  The exchanges? Like the exchanges.
Speaker 6:  The exchanges themselves? Are they, because
Speaker 5:  All Ponzi schemes
Speaker 6:  There, there's this weird thing in crypto, like the way that we talk about
Speaker 6:  crypto and the way that people who are in it who, or feel like they're in
Speaker 6:  it, like the real players in crypto talk about it are very different. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Like we talk about cryptocurrency and some kind of theoretical things. The
Speaker 6:  people who are there, who are trying to make some money, who are, who are
Speaker 6:  looking at it and saying, this is going to be my nest egg. This is how I'm
Speaker 6:  going to get rich. They have bought some crypto, they've traded back and
Speaker 6:  forth. They, they own different cryptocurrencies. They have it all in their
Speaker 6:  wallet and they're trying to turn it into something bigger. And what many
Speaker 6:  of these companies offer is, okay, so you can loan, you can give us your
Speaker 6:  crypto and we'll store it and we will somehow increase the value
Speaker 6:  of it. We will do some magical thing, which sounds a lot like, I don't
Speaker 6:  know Bernie Madoff. And then there will be more money and they promise, right?
Speaker 2:  And they all have their own tokens. I think that that's where you're getting
Speaker 2:  at, right? Like ftx,
Speaker 6:  That's, that's where the magical money comes from. When, when you, when you
Speaker 6:  start talking about pay to earn stuff, when you talk, start talking about
Speaker 6:  practically everything and Web three said these companies have their own
Speaker 6:  tokens and that's where they're like, okay, so that's where the money's going
Speaker 6:  to come from. But actually the money comes from other people depositing more
Speaker 6:  money in it. And that's how you can get your money out. Which would
Speaker 5:  Probably be a scheme just kind of feels like they probably need to
Speaker 5:  address that more than even the utility thing.
Speaker 6:  If they address that, they wouldn't have businesses.
Speaker 2:  Right? Cuz they, the utility thing is way hard to address. Like, I just wanna
Speaker 2:  point at, I mentioned Brian Armstrong from Coinbase before and he
Speaker 2:  seems like a smart guy. You know, he's out there, he's public.
Speaker 2:  He even interviewed to our friend Ben Thompson trajectory this past week.
Speaker 2:  It's a good interview. You should read it. It's a lot regulation where come
Speaker 2:  from, who should do it, da da da. But there's this section in it where he's
Speaker 2:  like, all the journalists failed at interviewing SPF F and
Speaker 2:  so Ben is journalist. And I was like, all right, you be the journalist. What
Speaker 2:  question would you ask? How would you defeat SPF F in interview?
Speaker 2:  And like, you know, I don't wanna get too in the weeds or like Naval gaze
Speaker 2:  you about journalism, but like I, I interview people. I, it's like
Speaker 2:  you, if you approach an interview, like you're gonna win it. Like most people
Speaker 2:  A will not talk to you. And B, also what are you gonna win? Like you're not
Speaker 2:  the cops. Like you can just get people to talk to you as
Speaker 2:  openly as they can and like people can judge the answers. But Ben asks him,
Speaker 2:  okay, you're the journalist, so you have all these criticism of media, like
Speaker 2:  what would you ask? And Brian Armstrong's answer is like, I got nothing left
Speaker 2:  to ask this guy. Like we just need to move on. And it's like, well that's
Speaker 2:  the trap, right? Like you just don't want people to scrutinize
Speaker 2:  the fact that all these exchanges are mostly
Speaker 2:  unregulated. You all hated Gary Anser and the S E C and all these
Speaker 2:  other like regulators would be regulators for even daring to think that they
Speaker 2:  should regulate you. And now the thing happened that
Speaker 2:  happens to unregulated financial institutions and
Speaker 2:  you're like, where were the regulators? Why didn't they see these obvious
Speaker 2:  lies?
Speaker 6:  I mean, I've got a question.
Speaker 2:  I think, wait, I just like, until you break that cycle, this this is
Speaker 2:  always gonna feel scam to me.
Speaker 6:  And I know what he could ask Sam Bankman fried, he could ask, why is it that
Speaker 6:  every time there's a run on your business and people try to get their money
Speaker 6:  out, suddenly your site crashes when people can't get money out that day.
Speaker 6:  I'm sorry, that's a question about Coinbase that I would ask to Brian Armstrong
Speaker 6:  if he would answer it. He for some reason hasn't.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, it's pretty, it's weird. It's pretty shaky. It's super weird. All right,
Speaker 2:  we gotta stop talking about crypto. That is like the big news. It's in the
Speaker 2:  background. I'm actually curious to ask the audience this. We got comments
Speaker 2:  on the, on quick post down our site. So when you see this, go find the ver
Speaker 2:  on our site. Leave us comments cuz I want people to engage with us on our
Speaker 2:  own site. I think part of the crypto story is partially tech, right? It's
Speaker 2:  obviously a technology story in its way, but it is quickly becoming
Speaker 2:  some other kind of story. It's quickly becoming a bank regulation
Speaker 2:  story or I don't know, like a politics story,
Speaker 2:  a financial system story. So I'm just curious how people
Speaker 2:  want us to cover it because for the longest time we could cover crypto as
Speaker 2:  tech, right? It was like really interesting tech with massive sociopolitical
Speaker 2:  implications. Like verge strike zone stuff, right? Yeah. And now we're just
Speaker 2:  at the level of like, oh, this guy's just stole money. Like he's,
Speaker 2:  he's just a bank robber. There's like not actually a
Speaker 6:  Lot there. The CEO of FTX said in one of the hearings in Congress
Speaker 6:  this week, just, this is just good old fashioned crime. They they just stole
Speaker 6:  the money. They just took, they just had the money and they just took it
Speaker 6:  and spent it themselves. It's not, you don't have to like try and figure
Speaker 6:  out what the algorithm did. They just took the money and you bought jets
Speaker 6:  and houses and stuff. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  At least Elizabeth Holmes went and she built something. Was it
Speaker 5:  good? Did it work? No, she,
Speaker 2:  No, that did. She built something,
Speaker 2:  she took a, she took another device from another company that
Speaker 2:  worked, took it apart, made it work in a shittier way
Speaker 6:  And gave people bad results on important medical tests.
Speaker 2:  So I dunno about that one. Also, she, I mean she's going to jail. The other
Speaker 2:  guy's gonna jail. A lot of people go to jail. The one part of this that is
Speaker 2:  extremely a verge story. Yeah. Like the most verge story
Speaker 2:  is like the new CEO of FDX is like testifying in in the Senate
Speaker 2:  and he's just like, they fucking use QuickBooks. He's just ex
Speaker 2:  horrified.
Speaker 2:  He's like, what business at this scale uses QuickBooks? And he's just like
Speaker 2:  gesturing it like the panel of senators and the senators have no
Speaker 2:  idea. Like they don't know. They're like, is QuickBooks bad?
Speaker 5:  They're like, I use it for my taxes.
Speaker 2:  It's very good all at that moment also on our site, just go
Speaker 2:  watch it. It's, I mean it is incredible. Okay, so that's SPF F FTX
Speaker 2:  will, whatever other big news from this week, it's kind of in the same
Speaker 2:  zone, right? Like big breaking news would change the whole industry hasn't
Speaker 2:  happened yet. Hard to talk about. It's this report from Markman, Bloomberg
Speaker 2:  Apple might be opening iOS to third party app stores
Speaker 2:  in response to European legislation called the Digital Markets Act.
Speaker 2:  This is another one of those European regulations that is
Speaker 2:  like an inc blot test for how you feel about the
Speaker 2:  power of democracy to regulate big companies. And also an ink block test
Speaker 2:  for how you might feel about the nature of time and deadlines
Speaker 2:  because no one knows when it will actually happen or by which process
Speaker 2:  the various nations of Europe will come together and actually implement the
Speaker 2:  law that they have theoretically passed or not passed or
Speaker 2:  in some manner of, of working have assembled words
Speaker 2:  together.
Speaker 2:  The the EU is just the cutting edge of politics in
Speaker 2:  just the, it's like a probabilistic field of lawyers
Speaker 2:  and like every potential outcome is happening,
Speaker 2:  but no one knows when
Speaker 5:  I like that they kind of like create laws. Like I assign stories
Speaker 5:  just like, you know what, I got an idea run with it. And a
Speaker 5:  bunch of like a billion people are like, okay, it's great.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. But, but yeah. Walk us, walk us through this DEI cuz like
Speaker 5:  this Apple news, I mean I I think it feels kind of big even though there's
Speaker 5:  the whole question of how any of this law and stuff is gonna be
Speaker 5:  enacted.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. So the Digital Markets act is one of these things we've been covering
Speaker 2:  for a long time. Yeah. Again, we've been covering it sporadically as different
Speaker 2:  parts of the regulation get debated, added to the law. Law has
Speaker 2:  to pass, the member nations of the EU themselves have to pass the law, but
Speaker 2:  it is supposed to happen in 2024. And the DMA
Speaker 2:  is, it tracks along a lot of the antitrust bills
Speaker 2:  in this country. You can see that the sort of two legal regimes are
Speaker 2:  playing off of each other. Yeah. And the basics, I, the basic ideas
Speaker 2:  are gonna be familiar to any VIR listener. If you have a dominant
Speaker 2:  position on, if you run an app store or you're another kind of
Speaker 2:  dominant ecosystem player, you are a gatekeeper to all kinds of other businesses.
Speaker 2:  And so app stores in particular, apple and Google are the gatekeepers
Speaker 2:  they are referred to in the act as gatekeepers. And there's all
Speaker 2:  the things that gatekeepers have to do to open up the markets.
Speaker 2:  And so in this case, it's allowed side loading, allow other app stores,
Speaker 2:  it's reduced the in-app payment fees. There's this laundry list, it actually
Speaker 2:  has to happen. And just like the U S P C thing, apple
Speaker 2:  has no choice. If they wanna sell iPhones in Europe, they've
Speaker 2:  gotta comply with the law, right? There's no, they can't
Speaker 2:  send bankman freedom.
Speaker 2:  So it, it's, it seems likely probable
Speaker 2:  a certainty that Apple is building systems that would bring it
Speaker 2:  into compliance with European law. Just like is it a certainty? And we've
Speaker 2:  heard Greg Jos say to Joanna Stern, for example, that yeah, they're gonna
Speaker 2:  comply with the law around us bbc, right? So of course there were of,
Speaker 2:  there's been an iPhone with a U SBC connector inside of an Apple lab for
Speaker 2:  a decade, right? They, they, they're always ready to do these things.
Speaker 2:  But I think what is happening now is Europe in particular is passing the
Speaker 2:  laws to make the things happen. So next year we might see an actual iPhone
Speaker 2:  ship with a U SBC connector and next year's version of iOS
Speaker 2:  will at least have the hooks to allow compliance with the digital
Speaker 2:  markets act in Europe, allow side loading, allow other AppSource, allow other
Speaker 2:  payment systems. The questions are,
Speaker 2:  does that actually mean Apple's gonna stop demanding the money from
Speaker 2:  the app companies? Because that has not been the case in all the other markets,
Speaker 2:  right? In South Korea where they're required to allow other in-app payment
Speaker 2:  systems. They charge a fee in the Netherlands where it's like narrowly
Speaker 2:  tailored to dating apps and they have to allow other payment providers, some
Speaker 2:  dating apps. Very strange. They charge 27%.
Speaker 2:  Addie and McKenna have written a piece about this for our site a couple weeks
Speaker 2:  ago, which we mentioned on the show, you can do the culture war. Elon can
Speaker 2:  do the culture war, get the antitrust bill passed because he's was mad
Speaker 2:  at Tim Cook. But Apple is just gonna say, we, you owe us the money. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  In one way or another, Apple's gonna get its money. They're, they're good
Speaker 2:  at it. Tim Cook is good at it. So, we'll the big questions around the EU
Speaker 2:  bill and the DMA and all this stuff is, is the bill written
Speaker 2:  in a way that closes whatever loopholes Apple might find? Yeah.
Speaker 2:  And just the complication of European law
Speaker 2:  is such that I can't even tell you when this bill's gonna pass,
Speaker 2:  let alone whether all the loopholes are closed. Like if they
Speaker 6:  Have to do it, will it apply? If you don't live in Europe, will will We have
Speaker 6:  two versions of iOS suddenly?
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I mean that's another one, right? Will Apple keep the, the phone locked
Speaker 2:  down in other countries? Now the EU says the latest date
Speaker 2:  gatekeeper companies have to comply is March 6th, 2024.
Speaker 2:  But there's like a gated series of other
Speaker 2:  compliance dates about notifying regulators and
Speaker 2:  disclosing your changes. There's a lot of moments to
Speaker 2:  argue along the way for Apple. And then there's this
Speaker 2:  important piece of the puzzle, which is, you might do this in Europe, but
Speaker 2:  you might definitely not allow this United States or China or
Speaker 2:  your other big markets. And I, that to me is gonna be the, the most
Speaker 2:  interesting piece. Like are we gonna start doing like region locked iPhones
Speaker 2:  like we used to do, like VHS tapes or whatever? Yes. Like, or, or Nintendo
Speaker 2:  games. Oh my gosh. Are there going to be, are there gonna be apps
Speaker 2:  that have more capabilities outside of the United States because they don't
Speaker 2:  have to go through Apple's App Store rules? Is that gonna be a good experience
Speaker 2:  for people? Like I, I have long thought that Apple has sort of
Speaker 2:  tamped down on innovation on its phone because of the app store
Speaker 2:  process. I think they should open it up. But I, I've, I
Speaker 2:  have lived through a mobile phone market where there were multiple competing
Speaker 2:  app stores in independent distributions of apps.
Speaker 2:  That wasn't great. Shout out to my, my friend Dieter Bone who like made an
Speaker 2:  entire documentary about, about handspring. Like that wasn't a great
Speaker 2:  market for those early phones. And Apple actually did innovate by doing the
Speaker 2:  app store. So there are questions to be asked here. I was just thinking in
Speaker 2:  a world where Microsoft can't ship game streaming, cuz Apple won't let
Speaker 2:  them Yeah. We might be losing more than we're gaining by the Apple's control
Speaker 2:  of the store.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I mean, I think we're definitely gonna get region locked iPhones. I
Speaker 5:  think that's like we, we all just need to like make our peace with it. Now
Speaker 5:  we're gonna be importing our phones from Europe so we can have the really
Speaker 5:  good phones. It's always gonna be a nightmare. Like we're finally out of
Speaker 5:  that phase where you had to really think about what network you were on when
Speaker 5:  you bought your iPhone. And we're just gonna go right back to having that
Speaker 5:  weird little question of, okay, do I buy it unlocked from the US
Speaker 5:  or really unlocked from Norway?
Speaker 6:  I think that we're not gonna have so much the hardware difference, which
Speaker 6:  was just a software difference. So now I got a VPN into Luxembourg
Speaker 6:  so that I can play Fortnite on my iPhone.
Speaker 5:  I'm, and that
Speaker 2:  Sounds hot.
Speaker 5:  We're gonna be back to like jail breaking, right? Like in, but
Speaker 5:  instead of jail breaking, just so we can sign stuff onto our things, we're
Speaker 5:  gonna be like, okay, now I'm in Europe and that's just gonna
Speaker 2:  Be your phone. Yeah. The VPN market's gonna explode. Yeah, it's gonna be
Speaker 2:  great. I just, I the phones know where they are. Right? At the end of the
Speaker 2:  day, the phone has a GPS trip and Apple can, can, can read it whatever it
Speaker 2:  wants. And I, I that is, I think that's the big question
Speaker 2:  mark here. There is the other question mark about the nature of the EU
Speaker 2:  regulatory process, which I just, I don't wanna, I don't
Speaker 2:  wanna underemphasize Yeah. Just how nebulous all of it is,
Speaker 2:  but it makes sense that Apple's preparing to comply with it. It's just, is
Speaker 2:  it gonna be effective? Is it gonna mean anything to us here? Is the
Speaker 2:  United States gonna take the cover of this happening, of
Speaker 2:  this report and shove some antitrust stuff into this omnibus bill
Speaker 2:  that appears to be passing in the lame duck session That Congress isn't that
Speaker 2:  like all these things have happened?
Speaker 5:  Oh, I hope they don't, I mean, I want like antitrust stuff, but
Speaker 5:  I don't want it shoved in at the last minute into an omnibus bill that just
Speaker 5:  seems unpleasant. Just
Speaker 2:  You have like a stylistic difference.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It's like, it's like now I have to like read this whole bill because
Speaker 5:  what if there's more than one part of it? Like, that's too many words for
Speaker 5:  me to read. It's Christmas.
Speaker 2:  Well, good news is we have a high-end Pol policy desk with
Speaker 2:  McKenna Addie to, to read it for you. Thank you guys. That happens. There's
Speaker 2:  just rumors that might happen. Yeah. But I, you can see right now how the
Speaker 2:  United States in Europe are kind of bouncing back and forth on
Speaker 2:  antitrust stuff, particularly regulating the big tie companies in, I, I think
Speaker 2:  Elon has provided more cover for antitrust stuff in to
Speaker 2:  Apple because of the perceived content moderation issues at the store
Speaker 2:  than ever before. Right. And you can see how you might scoot some
Speaker 2:  antitrust stuff along because you've got the cover of now both Europe
Speaker 2:  doing it, right. It's already gonna happen anyway over there and you've got
Speaker 2:  the cover of being whatever kind of free speech warrior you think that you're
Speaker 2:  being. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  But I, I think like my, my one concern there is that the G O P has
Speaker 5:  historically been like, yeah, we're for antitrust, but only when it can,
Speaker 5:  only when it like pertains to censorship.
Speaker 5:  Otherwise you can build as big a monopoly as you want. And so
Speaker 5:  I just don't, I don't know, I'm real reluctant with our current
Speaker 5:  congress and their inability to like parse a lot of tech, like
Speaker 5:  really technologically advanced concepts to create, create
Speaker 5:  a a bill with actual teeth to
Speaker 2:  It. Yeah. And that's why they're gonna shove it into a bill at the end of
Speaker 2:  the year and call it a day like, oh,
Speaker 5:  It's
Speaker 2:  Gonna be gross. I think that's why those rumors are out there. Well, I don't
Speaker 2:  know if it's gonna happen. It's just those are the rumors. Yeah. Actually,
Speaker 2:  speaking of Elon, we should talk about Elon quickly before, before I take
Speaker 2:  a break. As always, there's a lot of Elon stuff, most notably Twitter.
Speaker 2:  Blue is back Elon caved to
Speaker 2:  Apple. It's 1199 on iOS. It's
Speaker 2:  8 99 on the web, 7 99 on the web. So he's used
Speaker 2:  paying the Apple tax. Yeah. Even after raging about it, he's
Speaker 2:  paying it. There's the check marks are different colors. I think The Verge
Speaker 2:  has a gold one because we're a media organization. Government
Speaker 2:  organizations get a gray check mark that says official.
Speaker 2:  I will note here that a deeply hilarious
Speaker 2:  situation over the past week is that various
Speaker 2:  members of the Norwegian government, including the Prime Minister, were labeled
Speaker 2:  as Nigerian government officials and just
Speaker 2:  tweeted Elon. And he eventually was like, sorry. And they fixed it. And when
Speaker 2:  I say for a while it was like a day and a half and they were just like, this
Speaker 2:  isn't,
Speaker 5:  This is not where we live. This is not where we do our
Speaker 2:  Work. The tweet was very funny. It was very much like, although we enjoy
Speaker 2:  our diplomatic relations ship in alphabetical proximity to Nigeria,
Speaker 2:  we do not live in Nigeria. That's going great. It's back. We'll
Speaker 2:  see how it goes. A lot of people have stepped back their Twitter usage
Speaker 2:  in the past few weeks. Yeah. I'm one of them. Our friend Casey Newton is
Speaker 2:  one of them. A bunch of our staff has done it. It just feels like people
Speaker 2:  don't want to participate in whatever he's doing.
Speaker 5:  I think it was kind of rough, especially earlier this week when, when he,
Speaker 5:  he made a bunch of transphobic jokes online and then he went and
Speaker 5:  appeared with Dave Chappelle in a very weird, bizarre appearance
Speaker 5:  in San Francisco. And like Chappelle is also kind of
Speaker 5:  notoriously transphobic. And I know a lot of people I know. Were like, I
Speaker 5:  think that's it for me. I think that's my, my moment.
Speaker 2:  So the moment that a lot of people mentioned to me was when Yoel Roth,
Speaker 2:  who was Twitter's former head of safe head of trust and safety yolan, just
Speaker 2:  like basically sick a mob on him. Yeah. So Yoel Roth had written
Speaker 2:  his PhD thesis about the responsibility
Speaker 2:  of sites like Grindr to provide safe experiences for young
Speaker 2:  people who were using the site anyway. Right? Right. So if you are
Speaker 2:  running a site, a grinder, you know that young gay people are on
Speaker 2:  your site. Right. You can't stop them. They there. So his PhD thesis
Speaker 2:  was you have a responsibility to create safer experiences for them.
Speaker 2:  And Elon tweeted an out of context paragraph of the PhD
Speaker 2:  thesis that says that that explains a lot. And he sicked a mob of, you know,
Speaker 2:  the the crazy groomer culture war people on his own former head of trust
Speaker 2:  and safety. Yeah. Who then had to flee his home. And that is just about as
Speaker 2:  bad faith shit box behavior as it gets. And that to me,
Speaker 2:  I think was, I don't need to make free shit for you a hundred percent.
Speaker 2:  Like I'm, I'm like too, it's my birthday tomorrow. Like I'm too old to work
Speaker 2:  for free.
Speaker 5:  Well we also saw, we saw the, the Elon jet stuff. Richard,
Speaker 5:  you, you've been following this is Elon jet back on
Speaker 5:  Twitter or do I only get it on Instagram now?
Speaker 6:  It is at this particular instant as I am talking and I, I can,
Speaker 6:  I can't say anything for beyond that. Still suspended again,
Speaker 6:  It was suspended and then it was back, and then it was suspended again and
Speaker 6:  they changed the rules and they said, no, actually you can release location
Speaker 6:  data maybe sometimes if it's a day after. And
Speaker 6:  there's been a whole saga of Elon claiming that someone was stalking him
Speaker 6:  and attacked a car that had his child in it, which many people can certainly
Speaker 6:  understand and relate to. But his reaction is, I think the problem is this
Speaker 6:  guy who is tweeting public informa publicly available information about where
Speaker 6:  my jet is, is the problem of someone attacking my car that I was not in.
Speaker 6:  So he has to stop. And he took that off of Twitter, which is also something
Speaker 6:  he promised he wouldn't do. But Elon's promises aren't worth anything. You
Speaker 6:  can just ask Twitter the company that he said he would buy and then didn't
Speaker 6:  want to.
Speaker 5:  So it's like TMZ and all of the like
Speaker 2:  Paparazzi? No, this is even, this is farther back. This is like 2000 5, 6 7
Speaker 2:  Gawker Stalker. Yeah. Do you remember this? I don't remember. Yeah. I mean
Speaker 2:  I was a former Geo media employee. You've gotta remember this. I mean,
Speaker 2:  I had this debate, I was there already, like Gawker's stalker, if you
Speaker 2:  don't remember, Gawker is a website.
Speaker 5:  R
Speaker 2:  I p. Many, many, many things have happened. Gawker was a
Speaker 2:  website for a minute. The height of its powers
Speaker 2:  Gawker had, I mean it was crowdsourced. It it was,
Speaker 5:  Yeah. You could just write in and be like, I saw Taylor
Speaker 5:  Swift walking out of,
Speaker 2:  And this feature was called Gawker Stalker and it had a map. And like literally,
Speaker 2:  I mean like the celebrities went crazy. They all hate, my gosh. The map went,
Speaker 2:  we're making it dangerous. This whole debate occurred already. I
Speaker 2:  I promise you in like 2007. Right. What you are at
Speaker 2:  now is Elon as a jet. It has a transponder. The
Speaker 2:  location of the transponder is publicly available. The flight plans of the
Speaker 2:  jet are publicly available.
Speaker 6:  Well they were, they aren't now.
Speaker 2:  Well no, they still are. They still are you, there's just this one Twitter
Speaker 2:  account. It's
Speaker 6:  Not available. No. He filed a thing with the FAA so that he doesn't have
Speaker 6:  to do that anymore because apparently that's the thing
Speaker 2:  He has, he has not succeeded in
Speaker 6:  Such way or is trying to anyway. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And they have to keep the, they have to keep those transponders on
Speaker 5:  because they're used by all of the different air traffic controllers and
Speaker 5:  all those air traffic controllers are paid for by the federal government.
Speaker 5:  Like basically has to do it because it's federal law. He doesn't just get
Speaker 5:  to be special. And he's upset about the fact that he can't just,
Speaker 2:  And the Supreme Court has ruled that the transponder data is not a publishing
Speaker 2:  is not a violation first. I mean it's like he's just like off in the
Speaker 2:  weeds of like, he hates this one Twitter account. I get it. I like, I get
Speaker 2:  it. And like having, he's
Speaker 6:  Now rewriting Twitter policy to say that you can't say where anyone is without
Speaker 6:  their consent. Which if you read it would say that the NORAD Santa
Speaker 6:  Tracker is done, first of all. Second, the people
Speaker 6:  who follow college coaches around to see who's getting hired or fired, their,
Speaker 6:  their accounts are done. Also, you can't live stream anything or post a picture
Speaker 6:  because if you post a picture and someone's in it, you'll know where they
Speaker 6:  are. You've now broken the rules and your account will be deleted.
Speaker 2:  Let me just say this. Lemme say directly welcome to hell Elon.
Speaker 2:  This is what it's like when you make speech regulations.
Speaker 2:  When you appoint yourself to speech police and you start with
Speaker 2:  all legal speech, you quickly discover there's a
Speaker 2:  bunch of shit that is legal that you don't like,
Speaker 2:  that no one likes. And most of this conversation
Speaker 2:  has been focused on whether or not we should let racist
Speaker 2:  people be like the size of people's
Speaker 2:  skulls determines how intelligent they are. Oh. Which is legal. That's just
Speaker 2:  a legal dumb ass thing you can say in this country that most
Speaker 2:  scaled social media platforms are like, well, the problem with doing that
Speaker 2:  all the time is it makes all the cool people go away and then we're left
Speaker 2:  with shitheads. So we don't want the shitheads to do that. So the cool people
Speaker 2:  hang out, this is more or less the calculus that is made on social
Speaker 2:  platforms every day. Do you want cool people? You can't have racists.
Speaker 2:  Do the cool people make us more money than the racist? They do goodbye racist.
Speaker 2:  We want cool people. It's not complicated, but that's where almost
Speaker 2:  all the energy of the conversation is. Right. But the reality of it
Speaker 2:  is that eventually your desire to be around who people always
Speaker 2:  wins. So you just like reduce the reach of the racism or
Speaker 2:  whatever you're gonna do. I
Speaker 5:  Mean, most people's desire, not Elon's,
Speaker 2:  But he wants to turn that knob down. I mean, he, he Right. Freedom of
Speaker 2:  speech, not freedom. He's got all the things. The, the problem is like
Speaker 2:  great, you can turn the knobs on that whatever. Your incentives are always
Speaker 2:  the same and they will always land in the same places. It's when you get
Speaker 2:  into things that are just flat out legal
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Publicly available government data about where planes are that
Speaker 2:  you don't like, you have to start reaching. And I am very
Speaker 2:  sensitive to the notion that people should not know where I am all the time.
Speaker 2:  I think that's bad. I'm I get it, I'm with you. But the
Speaker 2:  proximate relationship to plain in city and
Speaker 2:  guy attacks car does not exist. Right. Right. It's,
Speaker 2:  it's actually not true. You can't, when he, he's he's, he's
Speaker 2:  swore he's gonna, or he tweeted that he is gonna sue this college kid that
Speaker 2:  runs the tracker because his car was attacked and you have to go to court.
Speaker 2:  I hope he files his lawsuit. If the college kid is like any other Gen
Speaker 2:  Z college kid, they've already got a merch store ready to go.
Speaker 2:  This lawsuit gets filed. They've already got a Patreon set up.
Speaker 2:  Like that's just hustle culture with the teens. But he's gonna show up in
Speaker 2:  court and he is gonna have to try to convince a judge or a jury
Speaker 2:  that there is approximate relationship. There's a cause and effect between
Speaker 2:  this Twitter account and this person doing the thing that they did.
Speaker 2:  And the Twitter account, just importantly, does not
Speaker 2:  actually tell you where Elon Musk is. It tells you where his plane is
Speaker 5:  And like it just says it's in this city at
Speaker 5:  this airport. Yeah. Which are, I think they're supposed to be
Speaker 5:  guarded and difficult to get into and do things around. That's my
Speaker 5:  understanding of how airports work in the United States. So like, he
Speaker 2:  Doesn't like it and he's the speech police on this platform. So he is now,
Speaker 2:  he's reached himself. He's seem
Speaker 6:  Like you keep saying these, these legal words,
Speaker 2:  But this is the thing that he's criticizing all of the previous administrations
Speaker 2:  of Twitter for. And I will remind everyone, once again, criticism of Elon
Speaker 2:  Musk administration of Twitter is in no way praise. Right. For the previous
Speaker 2:  dip, shit Twitter administrations, the, the, these things are not
Speaker 2:  opposites. They're, they've all been bad, but he's doing the thing that
Speaker 2:  every other platform ends up doing, in particular Twitter has ended
Speaker 2:  up doing, which is you have an outcome, you have some
Speaker 2:  pre-written set of rules, and then because you control the rules,
Speaker 2:  you can interpret them any way you want to arrive at the outcome you would
Speaker 2:  like. So he's like, this validates my rule
Speaker 2:  against public safety. And it turns out that he's, he both
Speaker 2:  writes the rules and is the judge. And at the end of the day,
Speaker 2:  that's the thing that delegitimizes you is no one believes that
Speaker 2:  the rules mean anything because the judge gets to make up whatever they want.
Speaker 2:  Right. And every platform has arrived at this exact moment and
Speaker 2:  had to make some kind of decision. Facebook notably set up
Speaker 2:  a Supreme Court, like a full on external
Speaker 2:  Supreme court to create the appearance of legitimacy for, its
Speaker 2:  the interpretation of its rules. And Twitter notably
Speaker 2:  did not do that. Right. They just do whatever they want, whenever they want.
Speaker 2:  Every platform just does whatever they want, whenever they want. And Elon
Speaker 2:  has just fallen directly into the trap because of the Elon jet thing.
Speaker 5:  I know we gotta cut to break in a second, but I have one question, one final
Speaker 5:  question. Does this make Elon Musk judge dread?
Speaker 6:  I just wanna know. Okay. So you, you act like he might lose in court
Speaker 6:  and maybe maybe the legal argument doesn't hold up or something like that.
Speaker 6:  But what if the person, person, he's going against hires a lawyer who happens
Speaker 6:  to be big into qan a again?
Speaker 2:  Mm, yeah. It's gonna get messy. It is true that the legal system
Speaker 2:  does not always produce the outcomes. You might think. I I go back to why
Speaker 2:  did it take a little bit longer to arrest St. Penman Fried? Because you had
Speaker 2:  to put together a case. Government's kind of lazy. It's all, I'm not out
Speaker 2:  here being like the government's great at this. Like they
Speaker 2:  routinely fail at getting the right outcome in court.
Speaker 2:  But I think this one is very much you show up and you just have
Speaker 2:  to prove that thing A led to cause B and in this
Speaker 2:  case, there's no connection between the two things. He just doesn't
Speaker 2:  like it. Yeah. And so he, he reached to a conclusion
Speaker 2:  and that's the thing that delegitimizes the regulator. Right?
Speaker 2:  And, and this is why people hate platforms. This is why ultimately it's why
Speaker 2:  people hate judged who makes the content moderation rules. He wishes he
Speaker 2:  was judged Strad. That is the answer to your question, by the way.
Speaker 6:  He's, he's the judge dread sequel that nobody watched with Joel Kenman in
Speaker 6:  it. That's rough. I love, I like Joel Kenman, but I didn't see it
Speaker 2:  By the way. On top of all this, the FTC is out there asking questions like,
Speaker 2:  do you have enough money to pay for the compliance that you are legally
Speaker 2:  required to do with us? It's, it's rough over there. All right, we gotta
Speaker 2:  take a break. We'll be back. Alice is gonna lead us through what's going
Speaker 2:  on in the streaming wars. We'll be right back.
Speaker 3:  Support
Speaker 8:  For our show comes from click up. One key to managing a productive team is
Speaker 8:  efficiency and also great office snacks, but mostly efficiency. And
Speaker 8:  whether you're leading a group of 10 or 110, it's important to get the
Speaker 8:  most out of every hour in the workday. That's where Click Up can help. Click
Speaker 8:  up is a productivity platform designed to save you a full day every
Speaker 8:  week. That means more time for clients, for meetings, and for eating great
Speaker 8:  office snacks. Basically all of the important stuff. Here's how it works.
Speaker 8:  Click up houses, all of your projects, docs, goals, spreadsheets, and
Speaker 8:  anything else you need for work all in one place. Forget wasting Precious
Speaker 8:  times. Switching from app to app or using a multitude of tools to finish
Speaker 8:  a single task. Click up Redefines Productivity by collecting all of your
Speaker 8:  mission critical tools into one fully customizable app. Work the way
Speaker 8:  you work best with Click Up. You can help your team of 10 plus be more
Speaker 8:  efficient and productive with Click Up. Use Code Verge to get
Speaker 8:  15% off click ups, massive unlimited plan for a year. Meaning
Speaker 8:  you can start reclaiming your time for under $5 a month. You can sign up
Speaker 8:  today@clickup.com and use Code Verge. Take your productivity to
Speaker 8:  the next level with click up today.
Speaker 1:  Today's episode is sponsored by Airbnb. Airbnb lets you
Speaker 1:  book comfortable stays all around the world so comfortable, they might even
Speaker 1:  feel like home, which might lead you to wonder could my place be an Airbnb?
Speaker 1:  And if it was, what could it earn? The exciting answer to that
Speaker 1:  question is that right now you could be sitting on an Airbnb and not even
Speaker 1:  know it. Maybe you have a spare room that's already a haven for visiting
Speaker 1:  friends and family. So why not make it an Airbnb and make some extra
Speaker 1:  cash instead of letting it sit empty. Some people Airbnb their entire
Speaker 1:  homes when they're away for holidays or a big trip. That's a great way to
Speaker 1:  help cover the plane tickets. Whether you could use a little extra money
Speaker 1:  to stash away for a rainy day or you're saving up for something fun,
Speaker 1:  your home might be worth more than you think. Find out how much at
Speaker 1:  airbnb.com/host.
Speaker 2:  All right, we're back. Alex Kranz, this week you wrote the following
Speaker 2:  headline, the golden age of the Streaming Wars has ended. I would
Speaker 2:  tell you that I knew this was true. Yes. When h b host started pulling content
Speaker 2:  left and right, including its own
Speaker 2:  marquee hit show, F Boy Island, like
Speaker 2:  HBO Max had a hit show. Yeah, the show was a hit. People wrote about
Speaker 2:  it as like the best rethink of the dating show
Speaker 2:  in forever. Like people
Speaker 5:  Liked
Speaker 2:  F Boy, you should go read the coverage. I would tell you to watch it. You
Speaker 2:  can't cuz HBO O Max yanked it. Yeah, but don't read the coverage. And like
Speaker 2:  Vulture and other places, people
Speaker 5:  Love
Speaker 2:  To show also it's
Speaker 5:  Fun to watch. They upset you in particular. I know because Westworld
Speaker 5:  also got pulled I'm sorry,
Speaker 2:  I I I I was trying not to lead with Westworld.
Speaker 5:  I know. I can feel it in like, I could hear the, the the soundtrack in your
Speaker 5:  head for
Speaker 2:  The show. Yeah. I was like, what's the show with more than five people watching
Speaker 2:  it? And it's a flat Yeah. Westworld is yanked off the
Speaker 6:  Street still. They still have me as a viewer. I'm in. My subscription is
Speaker 6:  still good. It'll it will continue to be good as long as they keep the good
Speaker 6:  content on on HBO Max, which there,
Speaker 5:  Wow, I'm
Speaker 6:  Talking about Arlis, which is what I'm always talking about. Wait, what?
Speaker 6:  Arlis. That is the only show that they need to have
Speaker 5:  Is Arlis on. I thought it was on Showtime.
Speaker 2:  So you're just like deep in the archive. I don't think Zs Live knows Arlis
Speaker 2:  exists first of all. Like that's how you know your section. Sandra
Speaker 6:  Was on
Speaker 2:  The show like head of the class.
Speaker 5:  As long as he doesn't have to pay residuals on it, it's fine. But it, so,
Speaker 5:  so they pulled, they pulled this show, they pulled F Boy Island.
Speaker 5:  I'm so sorry Eli. They pulled Westworld. I'm so sorry
Speaker 5:  Richard. I know you guys both really loved those shows respectively,
Speaker 5:  but, but they yanked a whole bunch of this stuff. And part of this is, is
Speaker 5:  part of the same calculus. They've been pulling a lot of shows over the last
Speaker 5:  year. It's residuals, right? Like we've got a whole bunch of
Speaker 5:  contracts coming up next year, including ones for the Writer's Guild of America,
Speaker 5:  screen Guild, director's Guild, and they're all gonna be negotiating
Speaker 5:  for higher residuals because they want more of this. Like if
Speaker 5:  everything's on streaming, that's where the money is. And they would like
Speaker 5:  a cut of that. And you've seen, you've seen it already. A lot of these writers
Speaker 5:  and stuff are out there complaining right now about like how high their residual
Speaker 5:  checks were with traditional TV where they could support themselves after
Speaker 5:  writing a couple of really banger episodes because they'd go into syndication
Speaker 5:  and they just live on that money and then they can't do that
Speaker 5:  in the streaming world. It's just done like that. That kind of
Speaker 5:  way of, of making a living as a writer is gone.
Speaker 5:  So there's this residuals conversation, but there's also, it turns out a
Speaker 5:  lot of these shows are getting pulled because they're gonna pack 'em together
Speaker 5:  and sell seldom to what I learned is now called a Fast
Speaker 5:  Network.
Speaker 2:  It's good they've tried a few different acronyms for this. What
Speaker 2:  is the acronym?
Speaker 5:  This is, this is my new favorite though. Because used to, I was like the
Speaker 5:  cheap shitty networks, but now they're Fast Networks,
Speaker 5:  free ad supported TV is what that means. And
Speaker 5:  that means like the weird garbage version of plaques when you first
Speaker 5:  download Plex and you haven't put any of your other stuff on other stuff.
Speaker 5:  It's like, look, you wanna watch this movie with other stuff, stuff that
Speaker 5:  I've legally acquired. That's one, that's an example of it. I
Speaker 5:  think Tuby is an example. Pluto I think is an example.
Speaker 5:  Crackle when it existed. I think crackle's gone now. I
Speaker 5:  think it died finally. But but these, these still exist.
Speaker 5:  There's a lot of
Speaker 2:  'em, like the Roku channel.
Speaker 5:  Roku channel that's probably the most active, best known one.
Speaker 5:  And and so he's trying to pack it up and, and sell it there.
Speaker 5:  So someone probably Roku is gonna be like, do you wanna watch Westworld?
Speaker 5:  And a full season of that Jos Whedon show that got
Speaker 5:  canceled right when it got really good and it took way too long. Which was
Speaker 5:  that the Nevers
Speaker 6:  Raised by Wolves
Speaker 5:  Or No, that's a different one. Or that's a garbage show. That was
Speaker 5:  from, that's a bad show, Richard.
Speaker 5:  No, who did that? That was the guy who did the original, I can't
Speaker 6:  Remember who, who made what or which show they
Speaker 5:  Were on. Yeah, he made a TV there, there
Speaker 6:  Are too many shows, which is what your article mentions. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  That's
Speaker 2:  That's
Speaker 5:  He's too many shows. And so, so all of this stuff got pulled.
Speaker 5:  HBO O Max is is like, it's really kind of unclear what he's trying to
Speaker 5:  craft out of HBO O Max or Max, whatever you wanna call it.
Speaker 5:  Shout out to Better Max is in the world.
Speaker 2:  She's very cute. She's, I, I personally think they should just give
Speaker 2:  my daughter the streaming service.
Speaker 5:  I think she'd program it better.
Speaker 2:  It would just be like bluey all day and all night and then whatever garbage
Speaker 2:  YouTube that she watches, which is honestly terrifying.
Speaker 5:  She'd be like, I don't care who has the rights to bluey, but it's coming
Speaker 5:  on my network. Make it happen.
Speaker 2:  It's basically how that would go. There's a, there's a Barbie
Speaker 2:  cover of girls just want to have fun that she loves. Hell yes. And then we'll
Speaker 2:  be in the car and actual girls just wanna have fun will come on. And Becky
Speaker 2:  and I will be like, do you wanna listen to the, the good version of this?
Speaker 2:  And she's like, this isn't Barbie. And then both of us are hearts break
Speaker 2:  in the car. We have to pull over and just cry wailing for hours
Speaker 2:  on end because we can't get our daughter to like Cindy Lauper.
Speaker 5:  Well she's like, play the good one in the back seat.
Speaker 2:  It's very, it's very bad. This is, to
Speaker 2:  Richard's point, Alex, this was your article, right? There was a golden ages
Speaker 2:  streaming when everyone is flooding the zone. Yeah. Honestly in search of
Speaker 2:  like monopoly style prophets. Right? Right. To be the one true
Speaker 2:  streaming network with the most subscribers. They were paying for a lot of
Speaker 2:  things. A lot of interesting stuff got made. And now all that stuff is kind
Speaker 2:  of getting canned. And I think what you're seeing with Warner in
Speaker 2:  particular is some changes that needed to happen
Speaker 2:  in that studio are happening. We should, yeah. Talk about the DC universe
Speaker 2:  or whatever's happening there. But the business model
Speaker 2:  is reverting to traditional television
Speaker 5:  And that's, I mean, it makes sense, right?
Speaker 2:  Right. Where you make some stuff, you run it once and you find a syndication
Speaker 2:  window and sell it again. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And I think a lot of people want those syndication that like syndication
Speaker 5:  to return, right? Like syndication is dead. Used to the business of TV
Speaker 5:  was you go, you get to your fifth season, every season's 20
Speaker 5:  episodes. So you hit your hundredth episode. That means you're syndicated.
Speaker 5:  When you're syndicated. That means you get a really good deal with all these
Speaker 5:  smaller channels that syndicate you. And that means everybody who's working
Speaker 5:  on that show suddenly has like their house paid, like their
Speaker 5:  retirement is set when you hit a syndication deal. And that
Speaker 5:  disappears with streaming because nobody wants to pay syndication forever.
Speaker 5:  Right? Like zero people wanna do that. Nobody can afford that.
Speaker 5:  That's why we see stuff go on Netflix and then go away. And so
Speaker 5:  a lot of people, including probably Zaslav, wanna bring that back and they
Speaker 5:  wanna bring back the market. So in many ways Zaslav is
Speaker 5:  not the villain. He's actually good.
Speaker 2:  Oh boy. This is a big change for you Alex. No, I like this is a big change
Speaker 2:  for you.
Speaker 5:  I hate him. I despise this guy cuz I think everything he's done has been
Speaker 5:  poorly messaged. I just think he's like a bad messenger. But
Speaker 2:  You're just big on messaging. You're like, I don't want an antitrust bill
Speaker 2:  in the omnibus. I was like, as I was doing the right things with messaging
Speaker 2:  it the wrong way, be
Speaker 5:  Gentle.
Speaker 2:  You're just looking for a gentle touch. That's
Speaker 5:  Fine. Yes. Like, yeah, 2020 was hard. Y'all like, like let's be more gentle
Speaker 5:  with how we announce things. But, but I think like his,
Speaker 5:  his calculus here is he wants to, he knows that network TV is
Speaker 5:  dying and that's where he made all of his money. And so he's like, how do
Speaker 5:  I reinvent network TV and bring it here? Meanwhile Disney is like, how do
Speaker 5:  I own all of the IP in the world?
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Period.
Speaker 2:  And that's what, that's what Netflix has been doing as well. I mean, right.
Speaker 2:  That's again the point.
Speaker 5:  Netflix is like trying, I think Netflix is in a weird place because
Speaker 5:  they are so tech focused that they don't quite understand how that
Speaker 5:  TV industry worked before them. And they don't know necessarily want to.
Speaker 5:  And that's why we see things like they, they go and they, they sell ads,
Speaker 5:  but they're only selling ads to people who still pay
Speaker 5:  $8 a month.
Speaker 2:  Meanwhile, the fast trend, by the way we, I I mentioned the other acronyms.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. The one that died was a V O D ads supported video
Speaker 2:  on demand because it was stupid. And I
Speaker 5:  Bad
Speaker 2:  Message it was good because, because it was the opposite of svod, which was
Speaker 2:  subscription video on demand. And people would say these words to
Speaker 2:  us in dead seriousness, they'd be like the a v od market's
Speaker 2:  booming. And I'd be like, you need to reconsider yourself. And
Speaker 2:  they've now arrived at Fast. Yeah. Which is free and ad support tv fine.
Speaker 2:  It's fast. Very good. What you mean is D ads,
Speaker 6:  But it's keeping companies like Visio and Roki in business and the studios
Speaker 6:  and everyone else wants a chunk. They they're seeing that, they're seeing
Speaker 6:  these profits and they're, they want a piece of
Speaker 2:  It. Yeah. What's so, what's fascinating, you mentioned Netflix and they're
Speaker 2:  doing ads report this week. Netflix rolled out
Speaker 2:  its ad, they, they sold a bunch of stuff, right? They're doing the ads in
Speaker 2:  partnership with Microsoft. I don't want to overstate this
Speaker 2:  because even the people involved in the story, we're trying not to overstate
Speaker 2:  it, but Netflix is returning the money to the advertisers
Speaker 2:  because they can't deliver the inventory. Right? So
Speaker 2:  if you are a digital advertiser, this is our business too
Speaker 2:  by the way. Disclosure, I meant Netflix, ep, this show's called the Future
Speaker 2:  of You should go watch it.
Speaker 5:  I'm gonna mention Peacock Quick, do another one, do another one.
Speaker 2:  Comcast is an investor in a parent company, V Media,
Speaker 2:  whatever. Now you know this information, but net the way
Speaker 2:  like the ad business works is I don't like The Verge does like millions of
Speaker 2:  page views a week, right? Right. We have ad slots on the page
Speaker 2:  views. So we have inventory and we like tell advertisers like you
Speaker 2:  come by this inventory, we'll show you some impressions of ads. And there's
Speaker 2:  like a number, Netflix doesn't have the inventory. Like not enough people
Speaker 2:  have signed up for the ad plans and they're not watching
Speaker 2:  enough shows for Netflix to keep its promises about how
Speaker 2:  many ads will be shown to people. Yeah. So they're just returning the money
Speaker 2:  and all the advertisers are basically like, yep, they just started this thing,
Speaker 2:  they ran into it, it's q4, this is the hot time for
Speaker 2:  advertising, this is the holidays and all this other stuff. This is what
Speaker 2:  a good partner would do. So we can put the money against all their platforms
Speaker 2:  or people will actually see the ads. This is all fine. They'll get there
Speaker 2:  in the end. But that's where Netflix is at in growing that
Speaker 2:  side of its business. Which is they don't have the inventory. Like they,
Speaker 2:  they don't have a scaled advertising
Speaker 5:  Just started November 3rd I think was when it launched. So like
Speaker 5:  they haven't had a lot of time to build those subscriptions and they're gonna
Speaker 5:  have to build those subscriptions because most people were probably already
Speaker 5:  pay most people who were paying that $8 when it got bumped up to whatever,
Speaker 5:  is it 11, $12 are probably still on that plan or
Speaker 5:  just not on Netflix altogether. So like yeah,
Speaker 5:  they're gonna take it, it's gonna take a long time I think for them to figure
Speaker 5:  out how to do the ads well and H B O
Speaker 5:  has that headstart in that Des lav knows that
Speaker 5:  business. Super, super, super well
Speaker 2:  You love
Speaker 5:  Him. I do kind of love him. Like I respect him. I respect
Speaker 5:  him. Do I hate everything he does?
Speaker 5:  Yes.
Speaker 2:  I don't want to like get too middle school on this, but like you love him.
Speaker 5:  I love No, I know. I'm gonna like, I'm, what's that? What's that thing, the
Speaker 5:  little paper thing you would do, put his name in there.
Speaker 2:  The
Speaker 5:  Triangles. Yeah. Where's Matt?
Speaker 2:  It's you and Zla.
Speaker 5:  Mev Matt about,
Speaker 2:  He might as well be pulling a hair. Alex, I just want to be clear about this.
Speaker 5:  Call me buddy. Call me Zaslav. But,
Speaker 5:  but he is like, he's, he's trying to, to bring TV
Speaker 5:  back. And that's good in some cases because financially
Speaker 5:  a lot of people are gonna make a lot more money theoretically in that way.
Speaker 5:  Like you bring syndication back, you start selling this stuff to other things.
Speaker 5:  You lean more on advertisers for your profits rather than subscriptions.
Speaker 5:  You're gonna make more money. But that also means
Speaker 5:  you're beholden to those, those like mass audiences, which
Speaker 5:  means we're gonna lose a lot of really cool content.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. The the comparison I think is most interesting here is music
Speaker 2:  and Spotify. So Spotify, apple titled Amazon,
Speaker 2:  whatever, they have the same basic relationship to the music industry more
Speaker 2:  or less, right? The music industry makes a bunch of songs. They put 'em on
Speaker 2:  these services, you pay the services, some money hit play, there's a calculation
Speaker 2:  made and then the artist gets a penny at the end of the day. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Right? But they don't own the content. And every time you the listener
Speaker 2:  consume the content, there is a series of financial transactions that take
Speaker 2:  place in which the artist, the producers or songwriters, whoever
Speaker 2:  receive some benefit. And I, I think it is fair and it, it is very
Speaker 2:  clear, the industry has spent a lot of time arguing about that set of
Speaker 2:  calculations between you hitting play and the pennies that show up in their
Speaker 2:  bank accounts. And I, I think those conversations are fair and honestly that
Speaker 2:  the number of pennies should go up. Yeah. When you hit play on Netflix, there
Speaker 2:  isn't some payout, right? Right. Like you pay Netflix, the money you hit
Speaker 2:  play, they own all the content. That's more or less the end of it. That's
Speaker 2:  the case for Apple as well. It's the case for the the TV streamer. So the,
Speaker 2:  the way that the music market works is like Spotify
Speaker 2:  doesn't really own anything. That's why they care about podcasts so much
Speaker 2:  cuz they get to own the
Speaker 5:  Content. Yeah. Cause that's where they wanna own it.
Speaker 2:  And so they're not, they're not taking a cut of everything. Right. They're
Speaker 2:  not paying out some huge percentage of your subscription fee to someone
Speaker 2:  else. They're making the podcast around the podcast. That's the end of it.
Speaker 2:  They take all the money. That's where Netflix has been, right? They just
Speaker 2:  like pay the money up front and they get 95 Shonda Rhim shows and like
Speaker 2:  Shawnda Rhimes gets a huge check and that's the end of it where you're talking
Speaker 2:  about syndication used to be used to make a show and then you would sell
Speaker 2:  it 500 times.
Speaker 5:  Like that's why Star Trek exists.
Speaker 6:  The other thing is, you'd actually have some idea of how many people are
Speaker 6:  watching it, which Netflix and the others, they're giving out a little bit
Speaker 6:  more information now. But I
Speaker 5:  Mean that's, that's part of the issue. That's part of the issue with Netflix
Speaker 5:  we've seen
Speaker 6:  Is that, you know, you, you, on the other end, you press play and no one
Speaker 6:  knows, right?
Speaker 5:  Like, like they, they've, they've started talking. They have to be a little
Speaker 5:  more open now because they are selling, they're selling ads so they have
Speaker 5:  to be more open. But you're still seeing this really weird thing where they're
Speaker 5:  like, oh yeah, we're gonna give you a top 10 so you can see the show's most
Speaker 5:  watched this month and we're gonna give you all these various kind of small
Speaker 5:  analytics. And then a show will go like this one, I'm gonna talk about it
Speaker 5:  cuz I really liked it and I'm sad it's get canceled. But it is part of this
Speaker 5:  conversation. Warrior Nun gets canceled. It had been in like the top 10 for
Speaker 5:  three weeks. It had, it had done really good numbers theoretically. And then
Speaker 5:  it gets canceled and everybody, like its fans are like, we did all we could,
Speaker 5:  you had people like watching it on four different networks in their house
Speaker 5:  because they heard that that was one of the metrics needed to get a show
Speaker 5:  renewed on Netflix. Like they're just like out there making little prayer
Speaker 5:  circles and stuff, doing everything they can.
Speaker 2:  Four TVs in a circle.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. All in a circle staring at each other. And
Speaker 5:  they still didn't get it renewed. And I think earlier this week one of the
Speaker 5:  executives for Netflix was on, was it Hollywood Reporter Variety, just doing
Speaker 5:  an interview and they're like, Hey, you canceled stuff but it seems to be
Speaker 5:  doing well and you canceled it anyway. What's up with that? And they're like,
Speaker 5:  well, you know, there's a lot that goes into it. We can't get into it right
Speaker 5:  now and keeps on going and that's not gonna work. As,
Speaker 5:  as this industry starts to kind of shift back into that TV space
Speaker 5:  because you used to, you knew your show was gonna get canceled because it
Speaker 5:  was doing terrible in the Nielsen ratings and like there was a whole
Speaker 5:  lot of different signs from the organization that it was gonna do bad.
Speaker 5:  And Netflix doesn't do any of that. Netflix just like spits it
Speaker 5:  out and is like, enjoy. You didn't enjoy it enough. Goodbye.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I would just say like the old model was you would make friends.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And then they, you'd sell it to NBC is the first
Speaker 2:  run and make your first big chunk of money and then you would sell
Speaker 2:  it to whatever next U p n like U
Speaker 2:  P N or the CW Ovation and like syndication and then like
Speaker 2:  you just got to re-up those syndication deals over and over and over again.
Speaker 2:  The example I'll give, which I, I always think about all the time,
Speaker 2:  like I think a lot of people associate Shark Tank with cnbc.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  But CNBC buys Shark Tank in syndication from abc. Like first run Shark
Speaker 2:  Tank is on abc, CBC just buys it and runs it in primetime at night. Like
Speaker 2:  all day, every day.
Speaker 2:  Disclosure on a CNBC contributor, this is disclosure. Every time we talk
Speaker 2:  about TV it's like
Speaker 5:  We, we just have a little ding pup every time you have to do a disclosure,
Speaker 5:  it'll
Speaker 2:  Be great. There's a lawyer, the Jeopardy's lawyers outside my window just
Speaker 2:  waving at me. It's great. But that's a syndication deal and that's, it's
Speaker 2:  a really valuable syndication deal not only for Shark Tank, right, but for
Speaker 2:  cnbc, right. They're getting audience at night and they didn't have to pay
Speaker 2:  to produce it. They don't have to pay to make sure it's hit, it's, they already
Speaker 2:  know it's a hit. They're buying it for a discount cuz it already went out
Speaker 2:  in the first run and they're getting audience at night. And that dynamic
Speaker 2:  has not existed across any of the streaming services. So you're gonna, I
Speaker 2:  think we're just seeing the industry move towards this moment where the content
Speaker 2:  no longer belongs to streaming service forever. The people who make the content
Speaker 2:  are saying we want second, third, fourth bites at the
Speaker 2:  apple. Because making something for one upfront payment does not actually
Speaker 2:  make you rich. Selling, making something once and selling it five times makes
Speaker 2:  you rich.
Speaker 5:  It's coming from the audience too, right? Like, like audiences
Speaker 5:  are already complaining about, oh, you released everything at once and then
Speaker 5:  I have to watch it and it doesn't have time to build audience. I don't have
Speaker 5:  time to like get my friends into it because you're gonna cancel it in four
Speaker 5:  weeks if I don't watch it four times at a circle. And, and so like,
Speaker 5:  like I think everybody has kind of gotten fatigued with this glut
Speaker 5:  of content we've gotten and as much as we've also enjoyed it, right? Like
Speaker 5:  there's a lot of stories we wouldn't have gotten told in, in a world where
Speaker 5:  people were thinking really hard about what to green light and
Speaker 5:  what.so yeah. We're, we're just basically seeing a big
Speaker 5:  contraction I think is about to start and it's gonna be really
Speaker 2:  Yeah. It sounds like we're going back to basic cable. Like we're going back
Speaker 2:  to basic
Speaker 5:  Yeah, we're going back to basic cable, but you have less
Speaker 2:  Power. Dude, Richard, that's where you and I came from, man. Richard and
Speaker 2:  I started as baby cable bloggers and Gadget Richard used to run and
Speaker 2:  Gadget hd. This is your tie. I
Speaker 6:  Talked about more networks than anyone. I I I will never forget
Speaker 6:  I said something uncharitable about one of the
Speaker 6:  channels where they sell stuff and the only note they sent
Speaker 6:  was that they had changed their name and I, and I didn't know. And they,
Speaker 6:  they were just happy that anyone was talking about them.
Speaker 2:  I can't wait for Richard and I to like go to another cable card meeting.
Speaker 2:  It's coming.
Speaker 5:  It's
Speaker 2:  Coming. We're gonna have to do it. It's gonna be great. We should mention,
Speaker 2:  by the way, we did an entire episode of streaming winners and losers, a Charles
Speaker 2:  Plain Moore. We did the whole Go 90 scale. I have a giant note
Speaker 2:  here from Lee that says, don't rehash that episode. So go listen to it. It
Speaker 2:  was great. It was really fun. We did go 90 for everyone. I want to end this
Speaker 2:  segment though by briefly trying to understand what
Speaker 2:  is going on with the DC Universe with James Gun.
Speaker 5:  He's making moves,
Speaker 2:  He's making everybody mad, but he's doing apparently the right thing. What
Speaker 2:  he, what's going on?
Speaker 5:  I mean, he's kinda like EZ love in the way that he's not messaging correctly.
Speaker 5:  I know. He, he's not doing it like my boy's as love.
Speaker 5:  He's my future husband. Don't
Speaker 2:  You know Zzz is the Angelo death man.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Z baby
Speaker 2:  That you said that. I was like gently teasing you
Speaker 2:  Zba
Speaker 5:  Not me. Please, please don't include that.
Speaker 2:  I didn't do that. I want be very clear that I had nothing
Speaker 2:  to do with that.
Speaker 5:  You, you could see it in your, I like I could see it in your head. I could
Speaker 5:  see you coming there like
Speaker 2:  You're Yeah, there's a word cloud right here that says
Speaker 5:  Zba and I had to read it. I'm compelled to read things when I see it.
Speaker 5:  It's what my co-star said today. It said that I needed to read things
Speaker 5:  out loud. Yeah. But anyway, so a lot
Speaker 5:  is happening there. Obviously he was put in charge
Speaker 5:  of the Warner Brothers universe like DC Universe
Speaker 5:  because they have as big an IP as Marvel. Nobody knew
Speaker 5:  who Ironman was when, when that first movie came out in
Speaker 5:  2008, like zero people knew who Ironman was. And now he's one of the biggest
Speaker 5:  superheroes in the world. And DC has been looking at that for the last 20
Speaker 5:  years, 15 years, whatever. Being furious cuz they have Superman
Speaker 5:  and they can't figure out how to do anything with Superman. And so they,
Speaker 5:  they bring in gun. He's like, yeah, I'm gonna change things up. And part
Speaker 5:  of his thing is like the old shared universe sucks.
Speaker 5:  And to his credit, the old shared universe sucks.
Speaker 2:  It's not great. Even the ones that people like, like
Speaker 2:  Aquaman, like if you read The Ringer, I love The Ringer. You should read
Speaker 2:  The Ringer. It's great. The Ringer like, loves Aquaman and they love it.
Speaker 2:  Ironically. Like they're like, this movie is so
Speaker 2:  ridiculous that it's fun to watch and watch movie. Like
Speaker 5:  When Nicole Kidman's movie shows up and she's like, I've been living underwater
Speaker 5:  wearing fish bones for 20 years. And you're just supposed to be like, oh
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I would say that the the Orchestral Fish Rock concert
Speaker 2:  is really when I give up on they recut the Justice League movie in four by
Speaker 2:  three and let people watch it that way. That was a thing. No, that's actually,
Speaker 2:  I might have done this entire segment just to bring up four by three Justice
Speaker 2:  League with your Richard. Look. Say what you will about Zla
Speaker 2:  our new homie. Yeah. Z Baby. See
Speaker 5:  Baby,
Speaker 2:  He's making cuts. He's, he's knifing things. He brought in James Gun.
Speaker 2:  James Gun. You know, he, he clipped Wonder Woman three Patty Jenkins put
Speaker 2:  out a statement saying Wonder Woman three is off. She did not mention that
Speaker 2:  Wonder Woman Two was a a disaster. That
Speaker 5:  Wasn't a good Yeah, it was a horrible film. It was like just
Speaker 5:  horrible. The worst movie. You're like, how do you have so many women making
Speaker 5:  this movie and you're making this horrible, sexist movie.
Speaker 5:  Like it was just obscenely bad.
Speaker 2:  I feel like a movie. It's true. It was sexist in like surprising ways.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  The plot of the movie really centers around
Speaker 2:  taking over someone's body and then having sex with them.
Speaker 5:  Like not a good thing to do. And also Wonder Woman was
Speaker 5:  a terrible friend,
Speaker 2:  Very like, I, I just, I just wanna, that is what happens
Speaker 2:  in that.
Speaker 5:  That's the movie. She's like, how are you in this new body? And he's like,
Speaker 5:  I don't know. And she's like, cool, let's bang. You're like, no,
Speaker 5:  no woman. That's not super heroic at all.
Speaker 5:  Stop. That's really quite
Speaker 2:  Lot. Anyway, so he, he kills Wonder one Three, which seems like the right
Speaker 2:  choice. Henry Caval is a long statement. He is like, I quit the
Speaker 2:  Witcher.
Speaker 2:  Whoops.
Speaker 5:  He quit the Witcher. He gave us like, not even one of the
Speaker 5:  good hymns worth brothers to replace him in Witcher. And then
Speaker 5:  he's like, I'm coming for Superman. And like, actually we don't need
Speaker 5:  you. Yeah. They said they're gonna go with a younger version of Superman.
Speaker 5:  So theoretically Smallville
Speaker 2:  All right, all this is happening. Whatever. It's all very funny in the background
Speaker 2:  ending the Snyder verse, I just, the the Yep. Zla
Speaker 2:  discovery changing all of Warner Brothers changing all this. I just want
Speaker 2:  to rewind the time when the phone company
Speaker 2:  bought Superman. It's a real thing that happened
Speaker 2:  at and t buys Warner Brothers. There is an
Speaker 2:  AstroTurf fan campaign from Zach Snyder and his
Speaker 2:  fanboy army, which led to lawsuits Like
Speaker 2:  crazy things have happened. Oh.
Speaker 5:  And they're furious.
Speaker 2:  They harassed the phone company so much potentially with
Speaker 2:  bots that the phone company was like, we're giving you
Speaker 2:  70 million to remake Justice League. And he was
Speaker 2:  like, cool, it's gonna be in four three,
Speaker 5:  It's gonna be in four three. It's not gonna be good. It's black and white
Speaker 5:  if you wanna watch it that way. But
Speaker 2:  Not a, that part I appreciated that was like, that's when you just like turn
Speaker 2:  the screw all the way. Yeah. You're like, what if, what if it's so gritty?
Speaker 2:  There's no colors in it at all.
Speaker 2:  I will say they improve the effects. The story does make more sense. It was
Speaker 2:  just the first time, I don't know, Richard, did you have this reaction the
Speaker 2:  first time I sat down to watch it and you're like, oh, this shit's a square.
Speaker 5:  The first time I thought
Speaker 2:  My TV was broken, I was like,
Speaker 5:  Neely, how many times have you watched it?
Speaker 2:  I was, I was gonna watch it again because of all this DC universe stuff.
Speaker 2:  I was like, I should just try one more time.
Speaker 5:  Ready to get in. And
Speaker 2:  Then I like this your time remembered that it's in four three and I was like,
Speaker 2:  I can't be doing this. Yeah. And by the way, the point, I'm sure the
Speaker 2:  Zach Snyder verse bots are gonna come at me. They're like, it's more like
Speaker 2:  imax. That's the, that's the stated justification for being in four
Speaker 2:  three.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Is that you're supposed to, you're supposed to watch this movie in IMAX was
Speaker 2:  very tall. And it's like, yeah, but
Speaker 5:  You know what's not imax my phone that
Speaker 5:  I'm gonna watch it on
Speaker 2:  Just despite you. Anyway, just remember the time the phone
Speaker 2:  company bought Superman and then got harassed by fanboy
Speaker 2:  making a three hour square movie.
Speaker 2:  We live through this together as a family. And I, I just wanna thank you
Speaker 2:  all for that.
Speaker 5:  I mean, I feel, I do feel bad for Cal though. Like he had to make the Square
Speaker 5:  movie. He doesn't even get to make a movie when it's theoretically gonna
Speaker 5:  be a good year
Speaker 2:  With, with the like photoshopped mustache. That was
Speaker 5:  So bad. Oh my god, that mustache was incredible.
Speaker 2:  He has suffered for our, since all we gotta end this segment and we're now
Speaker 2:  fully into the c whether or not the CJ mustache was like an important
Speaker 5:  It's whole future
Speaker 2:  Episode. I, all I know is that at and t at and t paid 70 million
Speaker 2:  to make a square movie. The fake
Speaker 5:  Mustache des Love z z Daddy wouldn't have let that happen.
Speaker 2:  You just went too far. I went
Speaker 3:  Too far.
Speaker 2:  We're gonna take a break. We're gonna just reset.
Speaker 5:  I'm gonna go
Speaker 2:  A little bit
Speaker 5:  My respect.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, if you need to pull over and just, just
Speaker 2:  rest, then do it. You know, like take care of
Speaker 2:  yourself. We'll be right back.
Speaker 1:  Support for this episode comes from another bite. If you're a Shark Tank
Speaker 1:  fan or business junkie, then you'll love another bite. Each week the host
Speaker 1:  breaks down the biggest success stories and most disastrous failures
Speaker 1:  to come out of Shark Tank. From the Squatty Potty to the Waken Bacon,
Speaker 1:  they dive into each company's pitch, analyze the deals that were or
Speaker 1:  weren't made and answer the million dollar question. Is that company
Speaker 1:  still a company? Basically they cover all the things you need to know to
Speaker 1:  survive the tank or scale a company on your own. Whether
Speaker 1:  you're an entrepreneur looking for tips or a fan looking to relive the show's
Speaker 1:  most dramatic moments, another bite offers a deep dive into the world of
Speaker 1:  Shark Tank. Just search for another bite and your favorite podcast app
Speaker 1:  like the one you're using right now.
Speaker 4:  Support for this episode comes from the Hustle Daily Show on the
Speaker 4:  HubSpot Podcast Network. If you're anything like us, sometimes
Speaker 4:  you just want someone to round up the business tech and trends, news stories
Speaker 4:  you actually need to know before you're done with your first cup of coffee.
Speaker 4:  The Hustle Daily Show is that someone this show sifts through some of the
Speaker 4:  most pertinent business media stories of the day to save you from scouring
Speaker 4:  multiple news sources and gives you back that valuable time. Nothing like
Speaker 4:  an irreverent, offbeat, informative take on what's going on in all things
Speaker 4:  business. Join the Hustle Daily Crew every day wherever you listen to
Speaker 4:  podcasts. Head to hubspot.com/podcast network to
Speaker 4:  start listening today.
Speaker 2:  All right, we're back. Honestly, we don't have Alex back yet.
Speaker 2:  She's still broken.
Speaker 5:  I'm still looking for self respect.
Speaker 2:  She's gonna be fine. We're back. We've got some guys needs to talk about.
Speaker 2:  Can we start with the Prius?
Speaker 5:  I was like, did you make this entire, it's just cars.
Speaker 5:  This gadget section.
Speaker 2:  I didn't make segment.
Speaker 5:  I was like this is just ne Eli's
Speaker 2:  Time. There's a lot of EV news this week and most of it is about the
Speaker 2:  sounds that EVs might make. So there's a lot of EV news this week.
Speaker 2:  Most of it is about like the sounds that EVs might make and then making
Speaker 2:  it okay for car people to like EVs.
Speaker 2:  So like Hyundai is gonna do like a fake manual
Speaker 2:  transmission for its electric cars. Yeah. So
Speaker 2:  you can feel good about it.
Speaker 5:  Mila, do you remember the time I was talking about how people were gonna
Speaker 5:  be so upset with electric cars because they wouldn't have transmission And
Speaker 5:  you said people still ride horses.
Speaker 2:  Well, Hyundai's doing one and Lexus is doing one. When I think of
Speaker 2:  cars or the rip in manual transmissions, it's Hyundai and Lexus.
Speaker 5:  That's, that's the only ones I think of.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. So that's happening. They're adding sounds to them. You might
Speaker 2:  recall from several episodes ago, Dodge is adding something called the Frazmic
Speaker 2:  exhaust system to its charger ev.
Speaker 2:  They won't disclose what it is, but you know what it is? It's speakers that
Speaker 2:  make exhaust sounds in the back of the car. And then
Speaker 2:  there's like the other side of it where it
Speaker 2:  is true that cars should make sounds to keep people safe.
Speaker 2:  EVs make a bunch of sounds. I have a new plug-in hybrid Grand Cherokee. You
Speaker 2:  can run on ev mode. When you put it in reverse it makes this like whistling
Speaker 2:  sleigh bell sound. It's very odd but it's still like a sound. It like
Speaker 2:  makes sense. I want you to listen to the new
Speaker 2:  Prius because it just, it's evil.
Speaker 2:  It's an evil Prius. Liam, can we run the Prius sound please?
Speaker 2:  That is the sound of being abducted by aliens.
Speaker 5:  I
Speaker 2:  Don't want that. That's what, that's what that is. That's when the, when
Speaker 2:  the, the concentric circles lift you into the space.
Speaker 6:  Why does it sound like that? Why did they
Speaker 2:  Choose that?
Speaker 5:  Can you imagine being high and walking home
Speaker 5:  and hearing that coming down the street?
Speaker 2:  It's a Prius backing up down the whole street. It's a very
Speaker 2:  strange moment in cost. Panic
Speaker 5:  Attack.
Speaker 6:  What was the other choice? What, what, what lost out to that at the last
Speaker 6:  minute? What, what was, what lived they developing that wasn't good enough
Speaker 6:  and they said no, we have to go with
Speaker 5:  This. Yeah, I assume it was like the price is right Sound they make when
Speaker 5:  you get the answer wrong.
Speaker 2:  I will say the Toyota's entire aesthetic for years now has
Speaker 2:  been angry. Robots like ev like even like a Camry, like the ultimate
Speaker 2:  family car is like what if this car transformed
Speaker 2:  the Camry? And so like the sound makes sense the like
Speaker 2:  in in context of Toyota's entire aesthetic, it's like
Speaker 2:  yeah this should sound more like Megatron than not. I
Speaker 2:  imagine that was the meeting. But we have an entire episode of the ver coming
Speaker 2:  up from Andy Hawkins, our transportation editor and Andrew Marino about
Speaker 2:  the sounds of cars because we are in the middle of just a
Speaker 2:  revolution in what cars sound like because they can sound
Speaker 2:  like anything now. Cause they don't sell like engines. I actually was with
Speaker 2:  the Rivian folks a while ago when I test drove the R one s that is a
Speaker 2:  dashboard, it's all screened obviously car makes no sound and they're like,
Speaker 2:  we had to decide what the turn signals would sound like when you click the
Speaker 2:  turn signal to go left or right. People expect a clicking sound that
Speaker 2:  used to be the sound of a relay clicking on and off to turn the light on
Speaker 2:  and off on the dashboard. Now it's just a screen. So we realized we could
Speaker 2:  make it any sound we wanted and they're like, but if it gets too weird people
Speaker 2:  won't know it's working. So we have got a whole episode about this stuff
Speaker 2:  cuz it is wild to think that you could just start car
Speaker 2:  sounds over or people megatron
Speaker 5:  Hacking their cars to make their own sounds. Cuz I would absolutely have
Speaker 5:  the we woo woo anytime I wanted to use my turn signal.
Speaker 5:  Just the most obnoxious sounds.
Speaker 2:  Tesla owners have been doing this for a long time. I will say that
Speaker 2:  I don't try this and obviously, you know Tesla, everything from the horn
Speaker 2:  people like have fart sounds in the horn, but now you're just seeing it get
Speaker 2:  beyond the sort of hacker zone to the industry is competing on
Speaker 2:  it. Right? It's an area of differentiation in in the industry
Speaker 2:  and like cars are getting weirder and weirder because all the drive trains
Speaker 2:  are becoming so similar. It it's neat.
Speaker 5:  Are we gonna have an app store just for the sounds?
Speaker 2:  Ring tones are back. It's yeah, everything comes back Ring tone. Yeah, car
Speaker 2:  ring tones are basically back. So that's really cool. Our friend Tim Stevens,
Speaker 2:  who Richard and I used to work with in Gadget as well, reviewed the Lucid
Speaker 2:  Air Grand Touring for us. This is like one of the e vaporware
Speaker 2:  cars. It's very expensive. He loved it. Go check out that review
Speaker 2:  car looks cool. Lots of screens, lots of software in that
Speaker 2:  car I will say. But he says the drivetrain is great. This is a big competitor
Speaker 2:  at Tesla. We talked about Elon already. I'll just say this is the year
Speaker 2:  that Tesla is gonna face its first real competition. I've complained
Speaker 2:  a lot about vaporware cars in the show, but the Lucid is shoving in like
Speaker 2:  some numbers. Porsche has a new Macon, a new battery powered Macon that looks
Speaker 2:  very normals compete with a model Y. You can just see the
Speaker 2:  competition's coming for Tesla in all kinds of other ways. I think that's
Speaker 2:  gonna be fascinating. If the car ship please actually ship, that would be
Speaker 2:  cool. Be into that.
Speaker 5:  They ship that Cherokee yet?
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I have one. You got it. I have it. We it, it took, I had to go get
Speaker 2:  it blacked out, but we have it now. It is, it is
Speaker 2:  the most Android computer that you have ever driven in your entire life.
Speaker 5:  I don't want that.
Speaker 2:  It's, it runs Android
Speaker 5:  Like Oreo. It
Speaker 2:  Does. No, it's, it's all very skinned. But every now and again it like, it
Speaker 2:  just does something that's like, oh this is a slow Android computer. That's
Speaker 2:  cool. It's nice call.
Speaker 5:  Can you just point at it and shout Android when it does that?
Speaker 2:  Like that's Android.
Speaker 5:  I see it
Speaker 2:  In particular the profile switching. Ooh. So if you push the memory
Speaker 2:  seats, it's like me and then and that switches the, the
Speaker 2:  presets and all the stuff on the tablet in the middle of the car and that's
Speaker 2:  like, oh this is just Android profile switching and it's not going well.
Speaker 2:  This, it doesn't like doing this.
Speaker 5:  They did not spend money on a good processor.
Speaker 2:  Gotta
Speaker 5:  Get a snap in there.
Speaker 2:  They plug it in, we drive it around to the battery all the time. It's great.
Speaker 2:  It's, it's doing its job. We should talk about Max real quick, we should
Speaker 2:  talk about Apple. Oh, 16.2 came out this week Better always on display. I
Speaker 2:  think every reviewer basically complained about the iPhone 14 always on
Speaker 2:  display being too on. So now they've reverted to It was just on Andrew
Speaker 2:  does. Yeah, it was just like on, it was like here's display. It was very
Speaker 2:  confusing. So they've reverted you can go change it. They've added end to
Speaker 2:  end encryption iCloud. They've added the new feature in Apple Music
Speaker 2:  where you can turn the vocals down, which is pretty cool. Ooh. Bunch of cool
Speaker 2:  stuff in there. But you know what, they haven't shipped yet
Speaker 5:  That Pro
Speaker 2:  Mac Pro with an M two chip or M one Max plus
Speaker 2:  they haven't shipped really any other M two max. Right? They did the air
Speaker 2:  in the 13 Inch Pro, but we haven't seen an M M two
Speaker 2:  16 inch Pro maybe next week M two max studio. So I, it
Speaker 2:  seems like yep, there's a lot of supply chain stuff going on. There are protests
Speaker 2:  in China. It just seems like Apple's starting to take the hit of that stuff
Speaker 2:  in a way that in the early part of the pandemic it seemed like wasn't
Speaker 2:  even touching 'em.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Is it, do you think it's that or do you think it's the fact that
Speaker 5:  they just like they, they were moving so quickly with
Speaker 5:  these new processors that if they like released a new M two
Speaker 5:  plus max or something, you know, eight months after the Max
Speaker 5:  Studio, it would feel like cannibalizing their various offerings already
Speaker 5:  out there. Well,
Speaker 2:  No, cuz when they did the Max Studio, remember, and it was Johnny sru, he
Speaker 2:  was like, and there's one more to talk about, but not at this time.
Speaker 2:  And like you just rarely see Apple like wink and nod
Speaker 2:  at the camera Yeah. About unreleased products. Right. But they were,
Speaker 2:  they, they said it was coming. They, they said that these other, these other
Speaker 2:  devices were Yeah, they like said out loud they were gonna do it and they
Speaker 5:  They were gonna finish their transition Yeah. This year. So
Speaker 5:  that's just like a
Speaker 2:  Big ballpark. I think the, the things that are surprising to me are one,
Speaker 2:  the M two is an upgrade over the M one, but it's not a huge upgrade.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And this is what we found in Monica's review of the M two air. It's
Speaker 2:  an improvement to be sure, but it's not this like rocket improvement over
Speaker 2:  the M one, the way the M one was over the Intel chips and then on the
Speaker 2:  sort of GPU side, like Apple still isn't there. It's not like the
Speaker 2:  GPU vendors have slowed down. So if you're gonna do a Pro Mac, like you've,
Speaker 2:  you need high-end GPUs to, to make that case to people,
Speaker 2:  to that customer base. And I, I think, I don't know, there's something there
Speaker 2:  that doesn't seem like it's adding up yet.
Speaker 6:  You can't do weird power per wat graphs against the, the 40 90
Speaker 6:  when you're actually competing against the
Speaker 2:  49. Yeah. You, you've got some real problems there. That's actually a
Speaker 2:  holdup is they're trying to figure out what to label the graphs and they've,
Speaker 2:  they've, they've been working on it for months. That's, I think that's interesting.
Speaker 2:  And then there's a bunch of stuff in Iowa 16.2 that we're kind of waiting
Speaker 2:  on, right. They, they said they were gonna do a classical music thing. There's
Speaker 2:  like just a bunch of features that have not yet arrived.
Speaker 2:  And I think Apples just starting to space out what it announces when instead
Speaker 2:  of like these kind of monolithic releases, which they've been on track to
Speaker 2:  do for years and years and years. But you just see, like, I think it's starting
Speaker 2:  to catch up to them. I, you know, the early part of the pandemic, they was
Speaker 2:  just hit after hit and they were shipping massive numbers of everything.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And now here this weird part where it like
Speaker 5:  They're just tuckered
Speaker 2:  Out. It's over. Is it over? It's like, you know, the, the protests in China
Speaker 2:  are causing some major changes in that country. The covid lockdowns there
Speaker 2:  are just like not gonna work anymore. Like, Apple's starting to feel that
Speaker 2:  hit in a way that I don't think they've been totally open about. And I, I
Speaker 2:  think we're just gonna see that continue for for months to come.
Speaker 5:  Do you think we're gonna get the Mac Pro next year? Maybe.
Speaker 2:  It, it feels like it's such a low volume product for them. Yeah. Like I think
Speaker 2:  they think the Mac Studio is doing that job as much as it needs to do that
Speaker 2:  job for that market. Right. If you're a professional
Speaker 2:  premier user or whatever developer, somebody
Speaker 2:  who's like really needs that power, you have already bought a Mac studio.
Speaker 2:  Right. Or you're on Windows and you're fine. And like Apple can
Speaker 2:  come get you next time. So I don't know if they feel what's
Speaker 5:  Like the differentiator? Is it just like you'll be able to put an a MD GPU
Speaker 5:  in it if you really want to?
Speaker 2:  I think differentiator's gonna be their gpu. Ooh. Making I think it might
Speaker 2:  be the, the holdup. I think they've gotta beat what, what the other folks
Speaker 2:  are doing. Okay. I think it would be really weird to Apple the DAM series
Speaker 2:  chips and named D G P. Like, it just
Speaker 2:  doesn't seem like the way they're gonna go.
Speaker 5:  I mean the big reason that they took so long with the last pro release was
Speaker 5:  they were like, we wanna make it as modular as possible. We wanna make it
Speaker 5:  more like a pc, but we don't like PCs, don't talk about PCs here.
Speaker 5:  And so with their current setup, they really can't do that, that modular
Speaker 5:  thing, right? Like a modular Mac Pro where you
Speaker 5:  can replace the M two with the M three when it comes out and replace the
Speaker 5:  gpu. That's a Yeah. They're never Yeah, they're not gonna do that. So it's
Speaker 5:  like, what, what does a macro pro look like in a world where
Speaker 5:  they, they sacrifice that modularity again?
Speaker 2:  Yeah. No, no. I I I think they thought they had an answer. Right? I think
Speaker 2:  that's why they hinted at it. So like explicitly. Yeah. I think
Speaker 2:  that, I think that answer has changed. And I, we'll say, I, I just think
Speaker 2:  it's interesting that like this was supposed to be in transition and like
Speaker 2:  hasn't been here and it's very rare that Apple
Speaker 2:  misses deadline. This I think the stakes are low. Yeah. I think the stakes
Speaker 2:  are much higher for can you ship enough iPhones, which they're struggling
Speaker 2:  with
Speaker 6:  Are are they recalibrating what power means? Like for a machine like that
Speaker 6:  now now you, you're talking about selling it to someone maybe who's doing
Speaker 6:  AI processing or, or tasks that weren't on those old Mac
Speaker 6:  pros and now maybe they, they are saying, you know what we were doing, we,
Speaker 6:  we were aiming at a market that doesn't exist anymore and now somebody who
Speaker 6:  might buy this is doing something completely different and we need to rethink
Speaker 6:  it.
Speaker 5:  We were gonna sell it to the crypto market, now we gotta sell it to the AI
Speaker 5:  market. Oh
Speaker 2:  My God. There's no way that crypto miners were gonna be buying in
Speaker 2:  Max, like just
Speaker 5:  Spending $30,000
Speaker 2:  On a Yeah. The the whole name of that game was like buying
Speaker 2:  was reducing your cost to run a gpu.
Speaker 6:  Only they could have done crypto mining on old PS three s. That would've
Speaker 6:  been the perfect story just for the content. It
Speaker 5:  Would've been great. All
Speaker 2:  Right. Well Richard, you, you even assigned that story. Can you mine a, a
Speaker 2:  single Bitcoin on a PS three
Speaker 5:  A fraction? We'll give you just a fraction.
Speaker 2:  We'll see you in 10 years.
Speaker 5:  We will not be paying your power bill.
Speaker 2:  You can run Linux. I think my PS three is one of the PS three. You can run
Speaker 2:  Linux on. All right, I'm gonna dig out my old PS three and see if I can get
Speaker 2:  Linux on it. To, to render a Bitcoin, render a Bitcoin, by the way, an old,
Speaker 2:  an old joke from the show. Shut up Paul Miller.
Speaker 2:  Okay, two things we should talk about to wrap up. One Instagram rollout notes,
Speaker 2:  which is, seems like it's like weirdo Twitter competitor. It's great, but
Speaker 2:  it's actually just a way messages and is the funniest thing in
Speaker 6:  The entire world. Nothing goes away forever.
Speaker 5:  I'm fully on board with using it as my communication app now.
Speaker 5:  Like goodbye Twitter dm it. It's
Speaker 6:  The only thing that's made me open Instagram again in like six months. Same.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. They, they
Speaker 2:  Did it. All the olds are goofing. We are told reliably that the Youngs are
Speaker 2:  selling weed. That's very
Speaker 5:  Cool. I'm just doing sound garden lyrics.
Speaker 2:  But you see there is a wave of innovation in social networks again, because
Speaker 2:  of the, the Twitter drum that is actually pretty exciting. And like Instagram
Speaker 2:  rolling out this feature in the old days, right, Instagram would only do
Speaker 2:  things that they thought like a billion more people would sign up for Instagram
Speaker 2:  to do something. No one's signing up for Instagram to use notes.
Speaker 2:  But like, can they capture some minutes of your day back from Twitter?
Speaker 2:  As Twitter goes through a spasm, they can so they they can justify the stuff.
Speaker 2:  It's actually pretty fun. So Instagram's doing that. And then I want to end,
Speaker 2:  of course we're talking about Matter. Google,
Speaker 2:  it happened Iowa 16.2 brought matter support. So
Speaker 2:  Matter is here. The First Eve devices run on thread.
Speaker 2:  Now support matter. Google has announced that Nest hubs
Speaker 2:  and some Android devices support matter. You know, it doesn't though Nest
Speaker 2:  thermostats. It's like the one thing everybody wants. How
Speaker 5:  You doing at Deli?
Speaker 2:  I have a HomeBridge set up. Okay. I switch from Hoos to HomeBridge.
Speaker 2:  I'll, I'm gonna dox my good friend Joanna Stern, she just installed the hoops
Speaker 2:  and texted me about it. Home Hoos is HomeBridge out of box. It's like a,
Speaker 2:  yeah, whatever. It doesn't matter. They're little tamagotchis that you put
Speaker 2:  in your garage to make all the rival systems talk to each
Speaker 2:  other in particular to get a home kit in about three times a year. They fail
Speaker 2:  catastrophically and you have to start over. But it's fine because you have
Speaker 2:  a little tamagotchi that you have to care for a little Linux
Speaker 2:  tamagotchi that you care for and for a while it all works. And if you're
Speaker 2:  a nerd, it's, it's like deeply rewarding to make a raspberry pie. Force your
Speaker 2:  nest thermostat to shov up an oak kit. It's
Speaker 5:  Nice. I use it for my Dyson fan.
Speaker 2:  I'm confident that when Joanne fails I'm gonna be in trouble in some like
Speaker 2:  meaningful way. But for now she's
Speaker 5:  Very happy. Like just block her number for a week after. She's like, I know
Speaker 5:  you can't turn on any of your lights in your home. It's
Speaker 2:  Fine. Yeah. She's like, I just opened my garage with Siri. I've never been
Speaker 2:  happier. And I was like, I'm so like, welcome to my club. It's a good club.
Speaker 2:  This is what it's like to have ta nagashi together but matters here. This
Speaker 2:  is like the thing, it's happening. You are, as you listen to this
Speaker 2:  in your car witness to the birth of a new smart home connectivity standard.
Speaker 2:  It's way better than whatever horny stuff Alex is doing. See
Speaker 5:  Daddy, I'm still just thinking about him.
Speaker 2:  Jen Tuey is covering the hell outta matter. It's great. It's all over the
Speaker 2:  website. Go check it out. But yes, if you have Google stuff, nest stuff,
Speaker 2:  that stuff isn't silently upgraded to support matter. The first devices are
Speaker 2:  out. If you have an iPhone, you now support matter. This is all real. And
Speaker 2:  I think it's gonna be cool if these companies can just be cool,
Speaker 2:  which is a tall order. But I think it's, I think it's gonna happen. I think
Speaker 2:  they, I think the executives
Speaker 5:  At these you like going to ces. Just be
Speaker 2:  Cool guys. I mean if I was gonna Cs I would honestly walk around and be like,
Speaker 2:  be cool. Like, yes, I would do exactly what you're saying. Thankfully
Speaker 2:  after going Cs for like 15 years in a row, I've not, I'm not being made to
Speaker 2:  go this year. But I think we're gonna see a flood of matter
Speaker 2:  devices at CS a hundred percent fly of smart home gadgets that actually support
Speaker 2:  matter that are actually gonna ship. And I, I, I think that
Speaker 2:  enough of the executives of these companies that we have talked to have houses
Speaker 2:  full of things that don't talk to each other and are aware
Speaker 2:  that all their customers are kind of mad at them. So I, there's just
Speaker 2:  a part of me that says the incentive to just like be happy is higher
Speaker 2:  than the business incentive to make money for these people
Speaker 2:  specifically because they want to open their garage doors with
Speaker 2:  Siri without having a Linux Tamagotchi. We'll see. Be
Speaker 2:  cool.
Speaker 5:  Be
Speaker 2:  Cool. All right. Anything else we should talk about? Let's just send it,
Speaker 2:  let's call it a day. Alright, we are way over as always.
Speaker 2:  There's more to talk about. We have Google basically had an all hands this
Speaker 2:  week where they, they said they're not gonna chat GBT yet because of reputational
Speaker 2:  risk. That's a lot because it's always wrong. Yeah, there's
Speaker 2:  all kinds of stuff inside. It was a really fun week on the site. There's
Speaker 2:  all the fusion coverage, which we haven't talked about. Justine's gonna have
Speaker 2:  some interviews on The Verge has coming up about Fusion. Go check it out.
Speaker 2:  It's on the verge.com. This what we do on Wednesday show. What's
Speaker 2:  this Wednesday show?
Speaker 5:  It's spectacular.
Speaker 2:  Okay. Once again, this coming Wednesday 21st,
Speaker 2:  the Vercast holiday spectacular Bluetooth. It's gonna be amazing.
Speaker 2:  It's gonna be amazing. Apple Watch Ultra Review is hitting this week. It's
Speaker 2:  one of our biggest productions ever for review video. That's gonna be very
Speaker 2:  cool. And then like I said, just on the back with Vergecast episode Fusion
Speaker 2:  and we're gonna take a break. So it's been, it's, it's been a ride. It's
Speaker 2:  been a year. But we're gonna take a break. You can tweet at us. Richard is
Speaker 2:  rj. CCC Alex's Alex h Cranz. You're
Speaker 5:  Reckless
Speaker 2:  Patel. Talk to you about you Reckless Patel.
Speaker 2:  And I'm at reckless on Twitter for now. Although please comment on the site.
Speaker 2:  I've been commenting on our site way more often lately cuz I feel like I
Speaker 2:  should work for the place that pays me. I think that's a good plan. Simple.
Speaker 2:  I, it's very easy calculus there. That's it though. That's for chance.
Speaker 3:  Call me.
Speaker 1:  And that's a wrap for Vergecast this week. Thanks for listening. If you enjoy
Speaker 1:  the show, subscribe in the podcast app of your choice or tell a friend, you
Speaker 1:  can send us feedback at vergecast@theverge.com. This show is produced
Speaker 1:  by me, Liam James, and our senior audio director, Andrew Marino. This
Speaker 1:  episode was edited and mixed by Amanda Rose Smith. Our editorial
Speaker 1:  director is Brooke Min, and our executive producer is Eleanor Donovan.
Speaker 1:  The Verge Cast is a production of the Verge and Box Media Podcast network.
Speaker 1:  And that's it. We'll see you next week.