# Transcript
ID: a7286310-236e-11ed-a288-1f11b6cce024
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: The Elgato Stream Deck's endless buttons
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-2321816472442901665/8847063452542101727/s93290-US-2619s-1661319308.mp3
Description: Today’s whole episode is about buttons. We’re talking about the Stream Deck from Elgato, a desk accessory that is basically just a bunch of buttons. We hear how people use their Stream Deck, how to hack it to do even more, and how to turn your old devices into something like it.
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com, we'd love to hear from you.
Call our Vergecast Hotline! 866-VERGE11 (866-837-4311)
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Disabled
Speaker 2:  Welcome to the Vergecast the flagship podcast of mappable buttons. I'm your
Speaker 2:  friend, David Pierce. And I am standing on my back patio in front of the
Speaker 2:  grill. I just bought it's a weird time to buy a grill right before the end
Speaker 2:  of the summer. But I did it anyway because it was on sale. And because this
Speaker 2:  grill, the Weber spirit III three 10 is the one
Speaker 2:  everybody told me to buy. So I bought it. I like it so far, but the best
Speaker 2:  thing about this grill is this button
Speaker 2:  Ignition, which turns on all the burners all at once. I find myself
Speaker 2:  yelling, I have created fire every single time I turn it on. It
Speaker 2:  just feels powerful. You know, today's whole episode is
Speaker 2:  about buttons. We're going to spend the whole show talking about the stream
Speaker 2:  deck, not the game console, the steam deck, but the stream deck from El Gato,
Speaker 2:  which is a desk accessory that is basically just a bunch of buttons. And
Speaker 2:  it turns out a bunch of buttons is a pretty seriously powerful thing.
Speaker 2:  We're going to hear how people use their stream deck, how to hack it, to
Speaker 2:  do even more and how to turn your old devices into something kind of like
Speaker 2:  it. But first let me finish these burgers that I came out here to grill
Speaker 2:  buttons are good and silver burgers. That's the takeaway. This is the, Vergecast
Speaker 2:  see, in a sec
Speaker 3:  With all the news in the financial world lately, how do you understand what's
Speaker 3:  right for your personal money goals? NerdWallet can help you make smart decisions
Speaker 3:  by finding the right financial opportunities for you, looking for your perfect
Speaker 3:  travel rewards credit card NerdWallet lets you compare them. Side-by-side
Speaker 3:  with thorough reviews and objective ratings. So you can choose the right
Speaker 3:  credit card and take advantage of the best rewards available, ready to make
Speaker 3:  financial decisions. Compare top financial products side-by-side on
Speaker 3:  nerdwallet.com NerdWallet the smartest decision for all your financial
Speaker 3:  decisions. NerdWallet compare incorporated NMLS
Speaker 3:  1 6 1 7 5 3 9. NerdWallet is not an investment advisor nor an
Speaker 3:  investment broker information is for educational purposes. Only
Speaker 4:  Process. It's a small word with big implications because whatever an
Speaker 4:  idea starts, a process gets done. It's how big talk drives real
Speaker 4:  action and people achieve their best work at Smartsheet. We're in the
Speaker 4:  process business, the go-to for managers who love pulling in the right
Speaker 4:  combination of data tools and people from across the company to make it happen.
Speaker 4:  One platform, every project, any scale, it doesn't get bigger than
Speaker 4:  that. Smartsheet power, your process visit smartsheet.com
Speaker 4:  forward slash power. Your process.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. So like I mentioned a minute ago, this whole episode is going
Speaker 2:  to be about a single device. The El Gato stream deck.
Speaker 2:  If you've never seen one, it's basically just a panel of buttons, each
Speaker 2:  one with a small square screen inside. It's about as wide as my thumb
Speaker 2:  and you can customize it however you want. It's like having a teeny tiny
Speaker 2:  control panel for your computer. Like you're sitting in a music studio at
Speaker 2:  one of those huge mixing boards except much less chaotic.
Speaker 2:  The stream deck is a pretty niche thing. It was built mostly for people
Speaker 2:  who live stream on Twitch or platforms like that. And thus need to
Speaker 2:  switch between cameras and streaming software and manage comment threads
Speaker 2:  all simultaneously without spending all their time, staring down at their
Speaker 2:  keyboards. It has big, bright buttons that you can feel and press.
Speaker 2:  And that goes a long way towards helping that you see tons of Twitch streamers
Speaker 2:  actually using stream decks. They're really good for that. But the stream
Speaker 2:  deck is actually much more than just a streaming thing because it's
Speaker 2:  just a big blank slate of buttons. It's also one of the
Speaker 2:  most fun hacker friendly tinker rubble
Speaker 2:  things you're ever going to find. You can program it to do almost
Speaker 2:  anything, which is in a way both a little overwhelming to think about
Speaker 2:  and just incredibly fun. There's nothing it can do that you couldn't
Speaker 2:  technically do with your mouse or keyboard or game controller. That's definitely
Speaker 2:  true, but the stream deck takes all kinds of complicated computer
Speaker 2:  stuff and just turns it into a button. And if there's one thing you should
Speaker 2:  know about us here on the Vergecast it's that we believe in buttons,
Speaker 2:  screens are great, but they're complicated. Software is great, but it's
Speaker 2:  often badly designed and hard to figure out, but buttons, buttons,
Speaker 2:  everybody can figure out. So really what this episode is
Speaker 2:  actually about is buttons and how a bunch of people we know and like
Speaker 2:  are finding ways to put more buttons back into their lives because computers
Speaker 2:  are complicated and buttons are not. We're going to get deep into the weeds
Speaker 2:  on how people use their stream deck and all these buttons. But let me just
Speaker 2:  give you a few examples from my own stream deck. I have one button on mine.
Speaker 2:  That's connected to the lamp in my home office and just turns it on and off
Speaker 2:  super helpful. I have one that mutes or unmutes my computer. So I don't have
Speaker 2:  to find the button on my keyboard. Every time I have a page full of buttons
Speaker 2:  that just open links to Google drive to the app, we use to record this podcast
Speaker 2:  to my calendar app, to a bunch of other stuff. I have a bunch of buttons
Speaker 2:  linked to Spotify playlist so I can start playing what I want without even
Speaker 2:  having to open the app. None of these things you might note are for
Speaker 2:  live streaming. The stuff that the stream deck is sensibly meant for it's
Speaker 2:  just useful in my life. I have six buttons on my stream deck mini, but
Speaker 2:  they can be a thousand different things. And I'm really only scratching the
Speaker 2:  surface,
Speaker 2:  But enough about me let's get into the show. The first thing we did was ask
Speaker 2:  a bunch of verge staffers, how they use their own stream decks to see what
Speaker 2:  kind of tips we could get from our own team. We got a lot of good stuff.
Speaker 2:  Let's start with Shawn Hollister.
Speaker 6:  I'm a senior editor at the verge in charge of finding gadgets.
Speaker 2:  Sean has the stream deck mini, which is what I have the one with six buttons.
Speaker 6:  First thing I've got right here is I have a button that will allow me to
Speaker 6:  dim my entire rooms lights because I have homocysteine and hooked up to the
Speaker 6:  stream deck. And so I can go dim. I can go bright. I can be like, oh, I don't
Speaker 6:  want any of that background light when I'm in the middle of the night playing
Speaker 6:  games, that's perfect. Then I have a Berge button that will immediately
Speaker 6:  pop up the verge.com because why wouldn't you do that? Then I
Speaker 6:  have a button that will allow me to not only shut down my computer,
Speaker 6:  but toss it into sleep mode or reboot it or lock it. It's great. The
Speaker 6:  fan will stop running. The lights will turn
Speaker 7:  Off. Cause I got a button right there that does it.
Speaker 2:  Dan Siefert deputy editor at the verge also has a stream deck mini.
Speaker 8:  The story is I bought the big one that has like 30 something buttons on
Speaker 8:  it. And then I realized I don't have 30 something things that do with this.
Speaker 8:  And it takes away too much room on my desk. So I returned it and I went
Speaker 8:  all the way down to the six button. One,
Speaker 2:  Dan actually wrote a while back about how he uses his stream deck.
Speaker 2:  And that story convinced a bunch of other people on staff to buy one.
Speaker 8:  I only ever use it for zoom. And what I do with zoom
Speaker 8:  is there's a zoom plugin for the stream deck. And you can program
Speaker 8:  buttons on there to mute, to turn your camera on and off
Speaker 8:  to bring the zoom window forward. So like if you've
Speaker 8:  clicked off of it and then your boss is like, oh, Hey Dan, what do you think
Speaker 8:  about this? You click that button and boom, the zoom windows right in front
Speaker 8:  of you again. And then I've got a shortcut that runs with Mac
Speaker 8:  S to join my next zoom meeting. But the most powerful button
Speaker 8:  is the leave zoom button, which allows
Speaker 8:  me to just push a button and I leave the meeting and I never have to like
Speaker 8:  struggle with my mouse to find the leave meeting button and then click the
Speaker 8:  little agree window that pops up or whatever
Speaker 2:  You avoid the awkward five seconds. Let's all sort of wave at each other
Speaker 2:  while we look for buttons on the thing.
Speaker 8:  Yes. I just mashed the button and the icon is a little running man. Like
Speaker 8:  he's just running away from the meeting.
Speaker 2:  The fact that the stream decks buttons are also teeny tiny screens makes
Speaker 2:  this even better.
Speaker 8:  So when you are muted, you've got a little line through the microphone, but
Speaker 8:  if you push the button, you'll know that your bike is live. And so, you know,
Speaker 8:  don't say bad things about your boss.
Speaker 2:  Are there versions of this for other conferencing systems? We obviously use
Speaker 2:  zoom. Is there a thing for others?
Speaker 8:  Don't believe there's one for teams. I've not really been able to find one
Speaker 8:  for teams surprise. We know there's not one for WebEx. We just kind of
Speaker 8:  assume there's not, but there is a plugin for Google meet. Okay.
Speaker 8:  So I've got a folder for Google meet on my little stream deck. That's
Speaker 8:  like four pages down. And because we rarely use me at the verge, but when
Speaker 8:  I do need to use it, it does basically the same things. It's got a mute button,
Speaker 8:  a video button, a hang up button, but then it also adds a raise hand
Speaker 8:  button. Cause that's a function that you use a little bit more Google meet
Speaker 2:  Along with the stream deck mini. There is of course the original stream deck,
Speaker 2:  which has 15 hardware buttons that you can customize. What I've learned from
Speaker 2:  this is that I think the 15 button one is the right one, Liam
Speaker 2:  James, the lead producer on the Vergecast has one of those.
Speaker 7:  I cannot imagine how I could possibly fill 32. I'm
Speaker 7:  struggling with 15, but I have just a bit more
Speaker 7:  than what would be comfortable on the six button. One,
Speaker 2:  Liam basically said that in life, as a producer, you tend to do a lot of
Speaker 2:  the same things over and over and over again. So he wanted to automate that
Speaker 2:  clip the stream deck.
Speaker 7:  So I'm making to do items all the time, but they're not always coming
Speaker 7:  from one singular place. So after giving
Speaker 7:  up this idea that two dues need to be titled in a nice way.
Speaker 7:  I found a way to just highlight texts. It doesn't matter where it is
Speaker 7:  and hit a button and it will be added as a new item in my to-do list.
Speaker 7:  That is a huge one. I use it probably 10 times a day.
Speaker 2:  So it copies whatever text it's hovered on, opens up your to-do list app
Speaker 2:  and paste it in as a news ask.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, it's actually like, you know, you don't need any add ons software.
Speaker 7:  And my to-do app happens to have a global shortcut. So it's really
Speaker 7:  just a copy and paste job, right? So it's, you know, copy the text, hit the
Speaker 7:  global command paste hit, enter done. I don't even see it. It's
Speaker 7:  so fast.
Speaker 2:  A lot of what he does on the stream deck is essentially activating an app
Speaker 2:  called keyboard Maestro, which allows you to automate almost anything on
Speaker 2:  your Mac with keyboard shortcuts, which also means apparently Liam spends
Speaker 2:  a lot of time sending emails to developers, asking them for more keyboard
Speaker 2:  shortcuts.
Speaker 7:  One of my favorite ones, which is kind of very in the nerdy category
Speaker 7:  is going to my VNC server. I've got a headless Mac that runs
Speaker 7:  Plex what's up, Alex. You know, I would love to have a
Speaker 7:  keyboard shortcut. If you're the developer of screens for, for Mac, please
Speaker 7:  add a keyboard shortcut to go to your favorite VNC server keyboard.
Speaker 7:  Mainstream just does all the hard work and I can hit one button my stream
Speaker 7:  back, and I've got a window open that is showing me what's going on with
Speaker 7:  that Mac
Speaker 2:  Liam also uses the stream deck pretty often for making this show.
Speaker 7:  I do have a kind of like a podcast recording button, which just as a
Speaker 7:  series of things, turns off my air conditioner,
Speaker 7:  Utes, any apps that are going to make noise. It starts
Speaker 7:  a app that has a count up clock to keep you in the lion line,
Speaker 7:  go too long on the segments never works. So it's just kind of like a smart
Speaker 7:  home parlance, like a scene that I have set up.
Speaker 2:  Okay. Now let's talk about the big kahuna. There's the stream deck mini,
Speaker 2:  the regular stream deck, and then the stream deck XL, which has
Speaker 2:  32 hardware buttons. I talked to Alice Newcomb Beal who works on
Speaker 2:  commerce and deals at the verge who has her own stream deck XL. I need to
Speaker 2:  know what all of those buttons are for
Speaker 9:  Honestly, a lot of the passive buttons on here are just kind of
Speaker 9:  mapped to desktop functions because even though I have
Speaker 9:  three separate monitors and tons of windows sprout
Speaker 9:  across that entire real estate, so I can map
Speaker 9:  different buttons to resize and move my windows or just
Speaker 9:  show my desktop really quick. Currently I have one that just allows me to
Speaker 9:  minimize everything and also just empty my recycling bin
Speaker 9:  whenever I need to. And I also have just a
Speaker 9:  clock, basically, just another clock. I only have like
Speaker 9:  four available to me, but I was like, okay, what else am I going to
Speaker 9:  do with this space? All right. I guess I'll put a clock in there. Sure.
Speaker 2:  Alice also has another profile for when she plays destiny, the hugely popular,
Speaker 2:  hugely complicated video game. And that's where the XL really comes into
Speaker 2:  its own filling. All 32 of those buttons,
Speaker 9:  The destiny community has done a lot to kind of fill
Speaker 9:  gaps in quality of life improvements where Bungie
Speaker 9:  may have potentially dropped the ball. And one of those aspects is
Speaker 9:  just in inventory management. Okay, so you have several
Speaker 9:  characters with different load outs and stuff you want to swap
Speaker 9:  between them. And for a long time, you could do that with a
Speaker 9:  browser based app called destiny item manager. Recently that
Speaker 9:  same functionality was brought to the stream deck with an
Speaker 9:  app exclusively for destiny item manager,
Speaker 9:  which allows you to connect your account, connect your
Speaker 9:  destiny account and program different load outs
Speaker 9:  to different buttons. There are some hiccups in the process,
Speaker 9:  but for the most part, if you want to swap between load outs, all you have
Speaker 9:  to do is press a button, which normally would require a lot
Speaker 9:  of moving back and forth within the game.
Speaker 9:  But instead it's been consolidated into just this
Speaker 9:  single input.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. That's awesome. And actually kind of a perfect example of what the
Speaker 2:  stream deck I feel like is good for.
Speaker 9:  Yeah, frankly. I was a gassed when I
Speaker 9:  first used that app and just like everything worked. I was like,
Speaker 9:  wow, like that actually works. That's pretty amazing. Part of it
Speaker 9:  too, is just kind of exploring and experimenting with
Speaker 9:  what you can do with the steam deck with these
Speaker 9:  optional macros, you know, like it was with me, it was sitting there just
Speaker 9:  kind of idle for a long time. And then I kind of forced myself
Speaker 9:  to explore the different apps and
Speaker 9:  other functions that you can tie to this device that you keep on your desk.
Speaker 2:  Tom Warren, a senior editor at the verge has a stream deck XL as well.
Speaker 10:  I got it pretty early on and I think the folder support back then. Wasn't
Speaker 10:  great. So that's why I got the giant one.
Speaker 2:  He also uses his stream deck to play games just like Alistair.
Speaker 10:  So I have a button on here that basically is my exports mode. It's when
Speaker 10:  I'm streaming on my exports, it'll have all the stuff where I can like change
Speaker 10:  my lights to green, to match the export sort of brand. I would
Speaker 10:  change all my scenes in OBS to certain export stuff.
Speaker 10:  They don't have a PC one, which is PC focused and all that sort of stuff.
Speaker 10:  So I do the sort of basics there and then I'll have like a switch
Speaker 10:  button where I might press it and I'll be able to press, you know,
Speaker 10:  BRB or live or anything on stream.
Speaker 2:  We also uses it in the most like obvious as intended
Speaker 2:  way as a soundboard.
Speaker 10:  So if I'm hanging out and like discord, I have like a bunch of meme
Speaker 10:  sounds I'll play. When people say so much GPS,
Speaker 2:  Give me an example. What are the most used sounds that we're going to hear
Speaker 2:  from you in this?
Speaker 10:  If you want to fall down, I can give you a fast sound. It's stuff like
Speaker 10:  Simpsons characters, it's all very character centric. So there'll be like
Speaker 10:  destiny characters, ninjas saying, you know, what the hell did you say to
Speaker 10:  me? Remember that line? The classic
Speaker 2:  After everyone showed me what's on their stream deck, I asked them what their
Speaker 2:  wishlist was, what do they wish the stream deck could do that it can't. And
Speaker 2:  Shawn's request is either the worst idea or the best idea of the bunch.
Speaker 2:  So let's start with that.
Speaker 6:  I want to make a bubble wrap app. Okay. We are going to
Speaker 6:  make a bubble wrap app for the stream deck where you push a button and it
Speaker 6:  just pops a bubble. Cause it feels like that when you
Speaker 6:  touch the stream deck, all of these little keys, they have this delightfully
Speaker 6:  squishy feeling to them, kind of like power and I'm like, we should go all
Speaker 6:  the way. It should make the sound. It should pop the bubble animation of
Speaker 6:  the screen. I think we're going to build it.
Speaker 2:  And here's Liam's idea, which he made me promise. We would not cut out of
Speaker 2:  the show.
Speaker 7:  Top thing on my list that the stream deck needs is to go to
Speaker 7:  sleep. When my Mac goes to sleep, I don't understand this. I have
Speaker 7:  many devices plugged into my Mac that, you know, they're powered
Speaker 7:  over USB. And when I put my Mac to sleep,
Speaker 7:  they go to sleep to stream. Deck just lit up like times
Speaker 7:  square all night long. That's kind of annoying.
Speaker 2:  Dan had some thoughts as well.
Speaker 8:  We've got two buttons set on one page wonders for the space
Speaker 8:  heater in my office to turn on. And one is for it to turn off because I couldn't
Speaker 8:  figure out a toggle to make it just like switch state.
Speaker 8:  I don't know if it's because whatever smart plug I'm using doesn't work with
Speaker 8:  the stream deck directly or whatever. But I had to like use two buttons.
Speaker 8:  So there's a lot of room to improve on the smart home controls.
Speaker 2:  And Tom had an idea and I've been thinking about it for awhile. And I still
Speaker 2:  can't decide if I love it or I hate it.
Speaker 10:  I would love if it could do notifications or if there was a new stream deck
Speaker 10:  that just had like a notification led bar or something. So it was like,
Speaker 10:  here's an email, you know, like, well that sort of stuff, it would be useful
Speaker 10:  not to have that necessarily on my monitor, but like off to the
Speaker 10:  sides that I can check it.
Speaker 2:  Okay. So we've been through all of this and you might be thinking, David,
Speaker 2:  this is all ridiculous. Overkill. You're just buying a gadget to
Speaker 2:  do stuff your computer can already do. And people in general
Speaker 2:  who don't like or understand the stream deck argue just that. And that
Speaker 2:  actually what you should do is learn keyboard shortcuts and use the mouse
Speaker 2:  like a person and save money. You idiot. People have said all these
Speaker 2:  things to me and I think they're wrong. So I asked my stream, decoding colleagues,
Speaker 2:  how'd they'd respond.
Speaker 6:  Keyboard shortcuts are great. And they have plenty of them every now and
Speaker 6:  then I try to remember what some of them are. I like that the stream deck
Speaker 6:  just shows me the things that aren't baked into my muscle
Speaker 6:  memory,
Speaker 7:  The mental process, to remember what your shortcut key is to do this special
Speaker 7:  thing is already too much for me. I just want to hit a button. You'd be
Speaker 7:  surprised how much that time adds up over the course of a workweek.
Speaker 9:  The app list just keeps growing and all of those apps are totally
Speaker 9:  free after you've purchased the hardware that it needs.
Speaker 9:  So that's kind of refreshing. Actually.
Speaker 8:  Any keyboard shortcut is actually slower for me to do it because I have to
Speaker 8:  pull my hands on my keyboard, get oriented and like faint. Remember what
Speaker 8:  the keyboard shortcut is or whatever the stream deck makes is super easy
Speaker 8:  to like quickly push something that is one action. And you don't have to
Speaker 8:  like worry about your spatial awareness as much.
Speaker 2:  It just comes back to buttons, right? The verge loves buttons. I love
Speaker 2:  buttons. The stream deck is a simple gadget, but it's also a hugely
Speaker 2:  complicated one. And that's the thing that's so much fun about it. It makes
Speaker 2:  those complicated things simple, but it also berries all kinds of
Speaker 2:  functionality behind one press of one button. I think too
Speaker 2:  much of life is spent in menus and scrolling around stuff and trying to
Speaker 2:  figure out where things are. And I'd rather just have buttons.
Speaker 2:  We're going to take a quick break and we'll come right back to talk to a
Speaker 2:  few more people who have taken the stream deck to even more impressive places
Speaker 2:  and done way more than just improve their zoom setup. We'll be right back
Speaker 3:  Today's episode is sponsored by draft Kings draft. Kings marketplace is the
Speaker 3:  place to grab digital collectibles, but this football season check-out draft
Speaker 3:  Kings first ever NFT fantasy game rainmakers football buy,
Speaker 3:  sell and win player card NFTs are the biggest names in the game like Lamar
Speaker 3:  Jackson and George Kittle. Then craft lineups of athletes from your NFT card
Speaker 3:  collection and earn points for touchdowns, receptions, and more just like
Speaker 3:  daily fantasy football. And right now everyone can get their first full roster
Speaker 3:  starter pack for free build your entity franchise and enter free Rainmaker's
Speaker 3:  football contest all season long. Download the draft Kings daily fantasy
Speaker 3:  app now, and sign up with promo code. Vergecast click the rainmakers tile
Speaker 3:  and opt in to get your first full roster starter pack for free plus play
Speaker 3:  for millions and prizes all football season and build the ultimate NFT fantasy
Speaker 3:  franchise with Rainmaker's football that's promo code Vergecast
Speaker 3:  build play wing
Speaker 3:  only@draftkingsentriesdependentontypeandnumberofentitiesheldvoidwhereprohibitedorrestrictedseedraftkings.com
Speaker 3:  for eligibility restrictions in details.
Speaker 11:  This episode is brought to you by Paycor Paycor empowers leaders
Speaker 11:  to build winning teams with Paycor leaders can recruit
Speaker 11:  onboard and train employees, set goals and drive performance.
Speaker 11:  If you're a leader, everyone depends on you. Who do leaders depend
Speaker 11:  on Paycor, learn more at
Speaker 11:  paycor.com/leaders.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. When I started doing research for this episode, I found a lot
Speaker 2:  of people doing a lot of the things we just talked about. The stream deck
Speaker 2:  is a great smart home controller. It's really handy for playing music. It
Speaker 2:  can get you off of zoom, all that kind of stuff all over the place. But the
Speaker 2:  more I dug, the more I found people who are using the stream deck to take
Speaker 2:  some of the most complicated technology that exists and
Speaker 2:  simplify it all the way down to a bunch of buttons. Like here's how
Speaker 2:  Simon a YouTuber who makes a channel called better creating uses his stream
Speaker 2:  deck to make video editing easier.
Speaker 12:  For example, I've got a line of buttons in front of me, which are cut
Speaker 12:  blade, which is just to chop a certain thing, cut the whole timeline,
Speaker 12:  trim to start or trim to end. So when you're going through, you can kind
Speaker 12:  of be skimming through with your mouse and just hitting those buttons,
Speaker 12:  trimming the start of the clip, cutting something in half trimming at the
Speaker 12:  beginning of it and so on. So just that frictionless ability
Speaker 12:  to press those three buttons in a row and zoom in and out on the two buttons
Speaker 12:  below on the time. That means that I, I think I cut the speed that I would
Speaker 12:  edit my a roll down in half.
Speaker 2:  Again, this is one of the things I heard over and over from people, both
Speaker 2:  in and out of the verge using a computer now means constantly
Speaker 2:  poking around menus and looking for options and then doing those same things
Speaker 2:  over and over and over again. So instead of doing the long
Speaker 2:  complicated dance in garage band to split tracks and apply a compressor
Speaker 2:  and add a little warmth in the EEQ and then add a slate reverb, why not just
Speaker 2:  hammer the button on your stream deck and have all of that happen automatically
Speaker 2:  every single time. Sounds great. Right? One of the groups taking this idea
Speaker 2:  to its coolest extreme is this huge community of people who use the
Speaker 2:  stream deck when they're playing Microsoft flight simulator,
Speaker 2:  flight simulator is this like massively complicated game. That's the
Speaker 2:  whole point, right? It's like you're flying a plane in every
Speaker 2:  realistic way possible. That is both really fun. And on
Speaker 2:  a computer kind of annoying. Here's how Robert Vander POS who says
Speaker 2:  he's a big flight simulator fan describes it.
Speaker 13:  When I started applied swimming, it really annoyed me how many buttons I
Speaker 13:  had to press with my mouse to fully control the plane. I was really annoyed
Speaker 13:  by that. So I thought, why not? Because I already had a stream deck, which
Speaker 13:  I used for all kinds of shortcuts and my daily jobs, things like starting
Speaker 13:  teams, opening shortcuts and stuff like that.
Speaker 2:  Robert and a bunch of other flight SIM fans decided to stop relying on
Speaker 2:  complicated controller moves and keyboard shortcuts, and they bought stream
Speaker 2:  decks. Instead. Now Robert is the developer of a piece of software called
Speaker 2:  flight deck, which is actually super popular in the flight SIM community.
Speaker 13:  If you look in the plane, especially the big planes, you've got a lot of
Speaker 13:  buttons, especially on your overhead bent. So you don't have to go there
Speaker 13:  with your mouse to click it. You can just press a button that's right
Speaker 13:  on your desk. And that's a lot quicker because you don't have to move your
Speaker 13:  view. You can still keep your eyes on the sky on the, on whatever's in
Speaker 13:  front of you while executing functions in the plane.
Speaker 2:  Flight tech now has custom stream debt control sets for more than 30 different
Speaker 2:  plants, which means more than 30 different complete button layouts, depending
Speaker 2:  on what you're flying. Robert said, he's created more than 1100 icons,
Speaker 2:  hundreds of buttons and knobs and folders, and you can control every
Speaker 2:  light and flap and camera angle, and even turn on the seatbelt sign and
Speaker 2:  fly your whole freaking plane, right from the stream deck.
Speaker 13:  For example, if I take the 7 37 profile, then you've got an
Speaker 13:  overhead panel, a folder, and that contains a lot of sub folder. So for
Speaker 13:  every part of the overhead, Bentall, there's a separate folder and the folders
Speaker 13:  are in order that you're most likely to use them. So when you're
Speaker 13:  starting up the plane, the things you do first that are in that
Speaker 13:  order, cause I make every profile for the 32 spots in
Speaker 13:  stream deck and the 15 butts and stream deck and the 15 button stream deck.
Speaker 13:  That's always the big challenge because then you've got even space to
Speaker 13:  work with
Speaker 2:  Talking to people like Simon and Robert really started to open my eyes to
Speaker 2:  what a device like the stream deck, which again is just a blank set of buttons.
Speaker 2:  Can actually do we live in a world now where if you think about it,
Speaker 2:  everything is just an point in software. So you can for
Speaker 2:  instance, use a stream deck to navigate around your notes app like Simon
Speaker 2:  does because notion and many other apps treat all of your pages just as you
Speaker 2:  are else
Speaker 12:  You can put in the address of a page, link that to a
Speaker 12:  button. So rather than navigating between pages in your, the
Speaker 12:  sidebar of your notion system, you can create icons that jumped
Speaker 12:  straight to key pages in your system. So actually I can integrate my
Speaker 12:  homepage and notion with my content creation dashboard in ocean
Speaker 12:  and my Google email or jumping to a website or in one page on
Speaker 12:  stream deck,
Speaker 2:  Or you can go even deeper and do what den Della Marcy did, and actually
Speaker 2:  figure out how the stream deck sends information in order to get it to send
Speaker 2:  even more
Speaker 14:  As a developer, I started running into the limitations where I wanted to
Speaker 14:  do things that are developer specific, like connecting to get
Speaker 14:  hub or anything beyond that. And that's when I realized that there was a
Speaker 14:  lot of things that just, you know, I'm not sure if it's, you know, the stream
Speaker 14:  deck is not necessarily tailored for developers, which makes sense. It's
Speaker 14:  stream deck. It's not developer deck.
Speaker 2:  Dan told me he originally bought a stream deck for the same reasons. We keep
Speaker 2:  hearing here to make calls, mute himself, that kind of stuff. But then he
Speaker 2:  decided it wasn't powerful enough and he wanted to write his own software
Speaker 2:  for it. But that required understanding how exactly the stream deck
Speaker 2:  actually works and talks to your computer.
Speaker 14:  I want it to do more without necessarily using the El Gato software
Speaker 14:  because I wanted maybe to connect it to a different device that doesn't
Speaker 14:  support it. So to do that, what I first started doing is there is a tool
Speaker 14:  called Wireshark that basically monitors what happens
Speaker 14:  on your network. So you can capture network packets, but also
Speaker 14:  it's magic superpowers that actually capture the USB transport hurdle. So
Speaker 14:  if you're using a keyboard or the mouse or any USB connected device, it
Speaker 14:  can capture what's happening.
Speaker 2:  Long story short den then built his own software development kit, which lets
Speaker 2:  you build more powerful things for the stream deck. Then Ocado his own tools
Speaker 2:  would let you
Speaker 14:  Tool where the library in this case only basically allows you to
Speaker 14:  connect to the stream deck and send commands to it. But it's up to you to
Speaker 14:  still implement what you wanted to do. For example, I want to
Speaker 14:  see my nest cam and I want to see, well who triggered the alarm
Speaker 14:  or something like that. And I would click the button and it would instantly
Speaker 14:  pop me into like a view or another thing that I did actually fairly
Speaker 14:  recently was when I'd get an alert from nest or something
Speaker 14:  happened, I would just click a button at the base. It says capture. So it
Speaker 14:  would capture the last like 30 seconds of the video and stored in the cloud.
Speaker 14:  A lot of the stuff is entirely customers because it's, it just does not
Speaker 14:  exist. It doesn't integrate yet. But by the power of me knowing how that
Speaker 14:  API works behind the scenes, I just kind of stitched it all together and
Speaker 14:  it's managed by the stream deck. And because every button has
Speaker 14:  basically a mini screen, I can get a snapshot inside
Speaker 14:  that button. However, useless it is. It's very tiny. But to see like
Speaker 14:  what is in front of my door,
Speaker 2:  This goes back to that URL thing, right? Practically everything in our
Speaker 2:  digital lives is an API or an STK or a URL away.
Speaker 2:  Whether it's the button to leave a zoom call or the live feed of your doorbell
Speaker 2:  camera and people like den are funding evermore, clever ways to bring
Speaker 2:  all of that stuff together. Stack enough of those things on top of each other.
Speaker 2:  And you can do just about anything. I should say though, the stream deck
Speaker 2:  software by itself, doesn't make this as easy as it should. And programming
Speaker 2:  your stream deck can still kind of feel like you're programming a computer,
Speaker 2:  but that's going to get better. As developers build more of these plug and
Speaker 2:  play systems. And as more developers break, the whole system liked ended
Speaker 2:  like I did with the verge. I asked almost everybody. I talked to what their
Speaker 2:  wishlist items were, what they want from the stream deck that it can't currently
Speaker 2:  do in this case, almost everybody had hardware ideas. Some people wanted
Speaker 2:  more buttons. Simon wanted one that didn't have any cables and maybe worked
Speaker 2:  over Bluetooth. Robert told me he wanted one where there's no divider between
Speaker 2:  the buttons. So it looks more like a coherent screen rather than a bunch
Speaker 2:  of individual things. And everybody had ideas about how it should be
Speaker 2:  designed. But one thing I heard a bunch of was that this thing is
Speaker 2:  super powerful and versatile already. So what new
Speaker 2:  superpower could it get that might unlock even more,
Speaker 14:  Hopefully in the future or lease of stream deck, we're going to see at least,
Speaker 14:  you know, like throw a raspberry pie in it, like just, you know, put an
Speaker 14:  SD card maybe that does some, you know, save profiles locally, but that's
Speaker 14:  sort of the future for now. We'll have to work around these constraints
Speaker 14:  by creatively writing suffer and decline computer.
Speaker 2:  After talking to all of these people, I honestly love the stream deck even
Speaker 2:  more, no two people use it exactly the same way, but it makes this
Speaker 2:  complicated technology field simple and just gives you more
Speaker 2:  control over how things work and how you use them. You can tinker with it
Speaker 2:  to your heart's content or just set up a few actions, run your computer from
Speaker 2:  your little control panel and never think about it again. There are no wrong
Speaker 2:  answers, right? It's just buttons. Buttons are great. And if you don't like
Speaker 2:  them, change it. Okay. We're going to take a quick break and then come right
Speaker 2:  back and figure out how you can get the best of the stream. Deck all the
Speaker 2:  automation and control and simplicity without actually needing to buy a stream
Speaker 2:  deck. Because remember it's all about buttons. We'll be right back.
Speaker 16:  What did dinosaurs sound like? Here's Jurassic parks tape
Speaker 16:  that roar was mostly made up of mammal sounds, but dinosaurs were a lot
Speaker 16:  closer to huge birds.
Speaker 16:  And instead of a roar, they might've had more of a punk.
Speaker 15:  It's a honk, but it's like a tuba honk.
Speaker 16:  The biggest deepest weirdest haunt you can imagine
Speaker 15:  Get to tubas
Speaker 15:  and having them play two different notes
Speaker 15:  and then they could rumble. And while your body
Speaker 15:  is still shaking from the rumble, they could blast you with two very low
Speaker 15:  notes.
Speaker 15:  He could get real interesting
Speaker 16:  This weekend. Unexplainable, is it possible to figure out what
Speaker 16:  dinosaurs actually sounded like scientists are giving it their best
Speaker 16:  shot, new episodes, every Wednesday, follow
Speaker 16:  unexplainable, wherever you listen.
Speaker 17:  I'm Alex Heath and I'm co-hosting land of the giants. This season
Speaker 17:  Metta the company formerly known as Facebook so far. We've told
Speaker 17:  the story of mark Zuckerberg journey to reaching billions of users from
Speaker 17:  the creation of the newsfeed to the acquisition of Instagram,
Speaker 17:  but such massive scale that comes at a price in our
Speaker 17:  upcoming episodes. We'll examine how the company has had to grapple with
Speaker 17:  the uncomfortable side of its power, from how to reckon with former
Speaker 17:  president Donald Trump.
Speaker 18:  I think mark in the end felt that if you're going to start
Speaker 18:  saying that heads of government, can't threaten to deploy force
Speaker 18:  to restore order, that that sets a really quite a Boris and
Speaker 18:  precedent
Speaker 17:  To the harms, its own technology amplifies
Speaker 19:  Borderline harmful sensational content fundamentally does
Speaker 19:  better under user engage.
Speaker 17:  Well, Zuckerberg is high stakes pivot to building the metaverse work.
Speaker 17:  And if it does, what does that mean for all of us
Speaker 17:  following land of the giants, wherever you listen to hear new episodes every
Speaker 17:  Wednesday.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. Remember how I said at the top that this episode wasn't really
Speaker 2:  about the stream deck. Here's what I mean. The stream deck is many things,
Speaker 2:  many, many, many things, but it's also kind of expensive. The little
Speaker 2:  six buttons stream deck mini I have is 80 bucks. The regular 15
Speaker 2:  button model is 150 bucks and the stream deck XL and it's 32
Speaker 2:  buttons will run you $250. That's a lot of
Speaker 2:  money just to do some stuff your computer can already do. So let's
Speaker 2:  see if there's a cheaper way, maybe a way to repurpose the device you already
Speaker 2:  own or some software that can do some of the awesome automation and
Speaker 2:  simplification that the stream deck does. Even if we lose the button,
Speaker 2:  the feel of the whole thing. Can we at least get some of the goodness of
Speaker 2:  the stream deck for a lot less money? That's the question I pose to Alex
Speaker 2:  Cranz and she went off to try and find out. And now she's back to tell us,
Speaker 2:  hi Alex.
Speaker 20:  Hi David. How are you?
Speaker 2:  I'm terrific. How are you?
Speaker 20:  I'm excited to talk about key remapping software more than you
Speaker 20:  think.
Speaker 2:  I actually, I feel like knowing you as I do, the answer is very high. I feel
Speaker 2:  like I'm on brand with that. Are you a stream deck person?
Speaker 20:  No, but I really, I really want one, but like, I feel like it's a bridge
Speaker 20:  too far. Like socially,
Speaker 2:  You just, you're not ready for the lifestyle is what you're saying.
Speaker 20:  Yeah. Like I'm not ready for somebody to come over to my house and be like,
Speaker 20:  what is on your desk? Because my desk is the first thing people see in my
Speaker 20:  home. So I try to keep it like fairly like useful because I'm giant nerd
Speaker 20:  and I'm sitting at all day, but also like, I don't want people to judge
Speaker 20:  me. And I feel like I'll get judged with a stream deck, no judgment to
Speaker 20:  any of our colleagues and listeners who use the stream deck, including
Speaker 20:  Dan who just uses it for zoom.
Speaker 2:  It's yeah. I mean, listen, these are our people. This is what this episode
Speaker 2:  is about. But your job was to find people away to
Speaker 2:  do the same kinds of things that you want to do on a stream
Speaker 2:  deck without actually having to buy a stream deck, which I feel like
Speaker 2:  is a very useful exercise. And I'm realizing, and especially useful exercise
Speaker 2:  for you who might want to do some of these like nerdy
Speaker 2:  automation things, but don't want a giant piece of hardware sitting on your
Speaker 2:  desk.
Speaker 20:  What I really wanted to do, and I have not yet figured out yet is I want
Speaker 20:  like one that'll work with like a Kindle or an e-reader just like
Speaker 20:  repurpose one of those old E ink devices. So it's like my
Speaker 20:  calendar and also like turns off my zoom camera.
Speaker 2:  Oh, I liked that idea,
Speaker 20:  But that doesn't exist yet. I'm sorry. I'm sorry. I got your, I got your
Speaker 20:  hopes up.
Speaker 2:  Well, the extreme deck is, is a thing that needs to exist. I
Speaker 2:  wasn't going to bring that up, but that is a thing that needs to exist. And
Speaker 2:  I like this idea very much of using an old Kindle. Cause I have like five
Speaker 2:  old Kindles that are just around and I would love to have a
Speaker 2:  better use for them.
Speaker 20:  But for most people you're going to be better off using your
Speaker 20:  number pad because a lot of people have been trying to figure out what to
Speaker 20:  do with the number pad. If you're not like in living in spreadsheets, all
Speaker 20:  of your life. So windows has one called ant softs
Speaker 20:  key re mapper. If you click on the website, you will be like, why
Speaker 20:  did I travel back to 2007?
Speaker 2:  It's bad. It's real bad. The
Speaker 20:  Software is also pretty dense. So, but it's like 15 to
Speaker 20:  $30. Like you get the license, you can also do some revamping just like
Speaker 20:  in windows. So you don't necessarily need to go to that. But if you want
Speaker 20:  like app specific stuff and soft for max, it's a little easier. You
Speaker 20:  can do stuff like I use. I've got Alfred, I'm a huge Alfred fan. I
Speaker 20:  gave up Quicksilver a decade ago and have been Alfred ever since you can
Speaker 20:  also use like the automator shortcuts, like Apple's been building the stuff
Speaker 20:  in from the beginning and then there's like the old
Speaker 20:  school. Yes. Right down to the website, keyboard Maestro. It's like
Speaker 20:  $36. You can do it all. It is much like Ansoff not
Speaker 20:  pretty. This is not a place where like the developers really focusing on
Speaker 20:  UI, which makes sense. Right? Like this is for people who just want like
Speaker 20:  really quick button to turn off their zooms and do other quick automations.
Speaker 20:  So
Speaker 2:  That's fair. Well, and I think I will say the number pad, like off to the
Speaker 2:  right of your keyboard is a very useful place for that. But also what I've
Speaker 2:  heard a bunch of people say is that the function keys are a thing that everyone
Speaker 2:  should be remapping, which I think is very smart. The downside is you have
Speaker 2:  to like, remember what they all are because there's nothing about the F three.
Speaker 2:  He, that like tells you anything of consequence, but you should absolutely
Speaker 2:  remap all of those to be like global universal shortcuts to
Speaker 2:  whatever you want, because otherwise you are never going to touch those keys.
Speaker 20:  I was going to do that, but I'm on a happy hacking keyboard. So I have to
Speaker 20:  already do that just to get to the S3. Like I have to use the function keyboard
Speaker 20:  keys, but it's really good. Cause like on max, it's super easy to be like,
Speaker 20:  oh, I want a universal mute button. I want a universal launch, a
Speaker 20:  specific app button. Like you could just do all of that. Like a lot of this
Speaker 20:  stuff. I think one of the reasons this software you're seeing is so old
Speaker 20:  is because a lot of this stuff you can now just kind of do and windows
Speaker 20:  and Mac. So it's really nice.
Speaker 2:  But if you do want to repurpose an old gadget, like a tablet or a phone for
Speaker 2:  this, there is the stream deck app. It in theory is the stream deck.
Speaker 2:  But for your phone, it is trash. The app is bad. It
Speaker 2:  charges you, I think four bucks a month to use it. It's super slow.
Speaker 2:  It's like the closest thing to what the stream deck could be
Speaker 2:  on your phone, right? Like it's just, it looks like buttons and you press
Speaker 2:  them and things happen, but it's slow and it's bad and it's stupid and you
Speaker 2:  shouldn't use it. Like the stream deck software is not like famously fast
Speaker 2:  and great anyway, but it is the worst version of itself on
Speaker 2:  phones, which is a real bummer. I would not use that unless like forced
Speaker 2:  to, for some reason,
Speaker 20:  Just enough to be like, oh, I get the potential of this. Clearly I need
Speaker 20:  dedicated hardware.
Speaker 2:  There is another app called touch portal. I think, which seems to be the
Speaker 2:  deeply nerdy one that people really like.
Speaker 20:  This is the one that a lot of people enjoy. And they actually like it
Speaker 20:  more than a stream deck.
Speaker 2:  It's just finicky. I feel like it's like mad finicky for all the reasons
Speaker 2:  that people like to tinker with their stream deck. This gives you even
Speaker 2:  more stuff to do. It's like Plex, right in that you like run it from your
Speaker 2:  computer and use it from your device.
Speaker 20:  You're getting a server. And that server is listening for a
Speaker 20:  client software and the client software. You can put it on your old phone,
Speaker 20:  your old Amazon fire tablet that you've had for a billion years. And you
Speaker 20:  probably need to just recycle. You can do them all there. And there are
Speaker 20:  a lot of people like, especially a lot of streamers who are like, oh yeah,
Speaker 20:  touch portal is the way to go. And I think that's just because
Speaker 20:  like, I really want something that I can like dig in and customize and get
Speaker 20:  really weird about and make individually mine and 3d print a little case
Speaker 20:  for my old phone and do all of that. So I'm going to go touch portal.
Speaker 2:  The thing that has going for it is that it works everywhere. It's like it's
Speaker 2:  on Mac and windows. I think it's on Android and iPhone. Like it, it does
Speaker 2:  the thing for all the places, which is great. It's so insane to
Speaker 2:  me that the stream deck has not solved this problem. Like, as we're talking
Speaker 2:  about this, I'm getting angrier at how bad the stream deck app is. Because
Speaker 2:  the thing is like, we've been talking about this for years, right? There's
Speaker 2:  that question of like, what do you do with your old devices? Right. Like
Speaker 2:  I have an iPad from like six years ago that like won't install
Speaker 2:  software anymore, but still runs fine. And like the perfect version of
Speaker 2:  those things is that I like use it as a thing on my wall to, you know,
Speaker 2:  control my smart home or whatever. And if I could have one of those that
Speaker 2:  is like a remote control for my computer. That's the dream. It's so
Speaker 2:  simple. I want that. I would even happily like connect it. Like apple should
Speaker 2:  make this thing. And it would like iCloud into my computer and it would all
Speaker 2:  work fine. You just have to hack it just one
Speaker 2:  step more than it seems like you should have to. And that's frustrating,
Speaker 2:  but people do love touch portal. So what do I know?
Speaker 20:  Yeah. People love touch portal. They've made it work. There's also another
Speaker 20:  one. That's a little easier than touch portal, but it's also only runs on
Speaker 20:  Android. Only runs on windows. This is for the people who are already like,
Speaker 20:  I really like to get in there and customize my
Speaker 20:  entire workflow, the appearance of my workflow, every
Speaker 20:  little bit of it. And that's magic metric.
Speaker 2:  It's like the, the singular of matrix. It's just one matrix, two
Speaker 2:  matrix.
Speaker 20:  The trick that seemed right. Yeah. So it's totally free.
Speaker 20:  It's a little bit more pared down, but because it's more paired down, it's
Speaker 20:  going to be like easier to set up. You're not going to have to worry about
Speaker 20:  like getting all, everything just right. Cause like touch portal. Part of
Speaker 20:  its appeal, I think to a lot of people is that you can do so
Speaker 20:  much. It does give you so many things, but it's kind of like the first time
Speaker 20:  you play, Skyram go back. It's 2011. You've put
Speaker 20:  Skyram into like your PC or your 360 or whatever. And you're like, I'm going
Speaker 20:  to play this game. This is going to change my life. And that it's like so
Speaker 20:  much stuff. And you're like, okay, well, do I like become the dragon person,
Speaker 20:  the dragon born and like, shout my way to victory. Do I go start like this
Speaker 20:  stop? Like these weird Romans who are doing their thing, do I go build a
Speaker 20:  house, stride, adopt a child? Do I become a blacksmith? Like there's so
Speaker 20:  much going on. And you're like, I don't for me. I just like stopped playing
Speaker 20:  for a year and a half. Cause it overwhelmed me when touch portals kind of
Speaker 20:  like that. There's so much choice that you're like, oh, I don't know where
Speaker 20:  to start. So you want to come in like with a plan
Speaker 2:  As we talk to people through this whole show, one of the things that seems
Speaker 2:  like the key is to any of these devices is start with like a
Speaker 2:  thing. And it's like, okay, I'm going to set this up. It's going to do this
Speaker 2:  one thing for me. And then in the process you like learn how to use it. You
Speaker 2:  fix some of the weird bugs and then you just slowly start to add other stuff,
Speaker 2:  but you need like the one problem you're trying to solve because for me,
Speaker 2:  like I bought a stream deck and was like, this seems neat. I wonder what
Speaker 2:  I'll do with it. And then it just did nothing for a long time. But then when
Speaker 2:  I was like, oh, I'll make it run the light in my office. All of a sudden
Speaker 2:  it was like, okay, now I have a reason to put this in front of me. And then
Speaker 2:  it opened up the rest of everything to me, the
Speaker 20:  Fanciest light switch on the,
Speaker 2:  I mean, could I reach six inches out of frame here and turn off the light?
Speaker 2:  Yes I could. But it's much easier when I have mystery Beck,
Speaker 20:  You seem like, did you guys talk about a lot of the different boutique
Speaker 20:  keyboard makers make little number pads and they have little like
Speaker 20:  volume dials on them.
Speaker 2:  I was going to bring this up actually, because one of the things we should
Speaker 2:  say is that for people who are thinking like, oh, maybe I'll do like the
Speaker 2:  keyboard Maestro or the number pad stuff. One thing you can buy pretty cheap
Speaker 2:  is a dedicated number pad that could act as just a set of
Speaker 2:  dedicated buttons for you.
Speaker 20:  Yeah. You could do that. And then you could use one of these like keyboard
Speaker 20:  Maestro, or an soft key wrapper or just honestly
Speaker 20:  Mac and windows do a pretty great job of this stuff nowadays. It just do
Speaker 20:  it. That's been my other way. And that's feels like a little more socially
Speaker 20:  acceptable than the stream deck with its light up keys, which I really love.
Speaker 20:  That's probably like the way I'm going. Cause then like you've got the volume
Speaker 20:  button instead of having like hunt for the volume in my menu bar or
Speaker 20:  hot kit
Speaker 2:  Dial is clutch, but that's a whole other accessory roadmap. We will go down
Speaker 2:  some other day, but
Speaker 20:  It's the same thing. It's it's got the number pad and the dial all in
Speaker 20:  one. So that's kind of where I'm leaning now.
Speaker 2:  That makes sense. And we should say before we go, that if you are a person
Speaker 2:  who wants to use the stream deck for its actual intended use, which is to
Speaker 2:  like live stream yourself, you're actually in much better shape. Cause there's
Speaker 2:  some really good apps out there that plug into OBS, which is the streaming
Speaker 2:  software that everybody use that actually works really well. Cause there's
Speaker 2:  like a big market for that. It's a thing a lot of people do. So if you want
Speaker 2:  to like run your Twitch stream from your tablet, like deck board is supposed
Speaker 2:  to be pretty good. I think upper deck is supposed to be pretty good. Touch
Speaker 2:  portal works really well for this there's one called like stream puppy that
Speaker 2:  I was reading about that I just like inherently don't trust. But supposedly
Speaker 2:  people like it, I don't know that kind of stuff is like more
Speaker 2:  functional. So if you want to stream, you hit you're in good shape. But if
Speaker 2:  you want the like wacky productivity stuff that we're about here at the
Speaker 2:  verge, you're kind of,
Speaker 20:  Where do you think it all wrong? We're like none of us Twitch stream.
Speaker 2:  I know it's really true. Okay. So we're all, we're all buying Inc
Speaker 2:  Kindles and hacking them to run stream decks. And when we do, we will be
Speaker 2:  back and we will report on it. Cause that will change my life.
Speaker 20:  It's going to be a lot of tears.
Speaker 2:  It's going to be amazing. All right, Alex. Thank you. Appreciate it.
Speaker 20:  Thank you. Talk to you later.
Speaker 2:  All right. And with that it's time for me to press the button on my stream
Speaker 2:  deck. That turns off my microphone because I have one of those and it's awesome.
Speaker 2:  That's it for the broadcast this week. Thank you so much for listening as
Speaker 2:  always. There is tons more coverage on the stream deck and everything else
Speaker 2:  we talked about@theburst.com and you can also follow all of us on Twitter.
Speaker 2:  This show is produced by Andrew Moreno and Liam James Noria. Donovan is our
Speaker 2:  executive producer and Brooke Minters is our editorial director of audio.
Speaker 2:  The first cast is verged production and part of the Vox media podcast network.
Speaker 2:  If you have thoughts, feedback, feelings, buttons that will play the Vergecast
Speaker 2:  on your stream deck. Anything else you can always
Speaker 2:  email@vergecastattheverge.com or call the Vergecast hotline
Speaker 2:  eight six six four one one, Alex Neil. And I will be back on
Speaker 2:  Friday to talk about Twitter whistleblowers house of the dragon e-bikes and
Speaker 2:  much more CNN rock and roll.