# Transcript
ID: 49563890-2060-11ed-94b6-ede5d753a4d6
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Android 13 arrives, Galaxy Watch 5 review, and Instagram gets competitive
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/3311101117800270223/-7682134080633405478/s93290-US-5039s-1660983263.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, Alex Cranz, and David Pierce discuss the Android 13 update, the battle between the vertical video apps, and a bunch of gadget news.
Speaker 5:  Hello, and welcome to the vercast flagship podcast of
Speaker 5:  incremental innovation and electron rappers for web apps.
Speaker 5:  Today. We're talking about JavaScript. We're not, we're not gonna do that.
Speaker 5:  I mean, most days we do in a roundabout way, discuss
Speaker 5:  JavaScript, I think, but this is not the show for you. If you're
Speaker 5:  a JavaScript enthusiast, I will tell you that right now, I make no bones
Speaker 5:  about it. Anyway, I'm your friend. Eli. Alex Kranz is here. I'm your friend
Speaker 5:  who just loves Pearl. Very good. It's my favorite. Yeah. You're it's great.
Speaker 5:  You're just doing, you're just doing the command line. You're in there. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  David Pierce
Speaker 6:  Is here. Yeah. I'm definitely your friend who is gonna like give you a long
Speaker 6:  speech about low code and no code. And then try
Speaker 6:  to convince you to optimize all of the apps in your life, to
Speaker 6:  the point where everything immediately breaks. That's my job.
Speaker 5:  My first email client was in a, was in a terminal, like a Unix terminal
Speaker 5:  was pretty good. I missed those days. So it's called pine. I dunno if you
Speaker 5:  remember this, I might be the one old and every now and
Speaker 6:  See like a hacker. Every time you checked your email.
Speaker 5:  Well, no, because it was, it was at school, like in college
Speaker 5:  and they, they just had a bunch of Matt classics at the entryway of the
Speaker 5:  dorm. And everyone stood in a line to log into their, their
Speaker 5:  like shell account to check their email in pine, just cuz we didn't have
Speaker 5:  computers yet typing the I. Then I wrote my steam engine up both
Speaker 5:  ways to college.
Speaker 6:  When you describe that, it sounds like like in, in movies when they show
Speaker 6:  like the line of people in prison waiting to make phone calls, like that's,
Speaker 6:  that's basically what you just described.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, it was, it was a different time. And at no point did we think that
Speaker 5:  democracy would be imperiled by our command line, email
Speaker 5:  clients and things have changed. It's fine. Simpler times
Speaker 5:  here we are now coming to you live over the internet. See it's a thing everything's
Speaker 5:  are improved democracy in peril. The verge cast, you gotta take the good
Speaker 5:  with the bad. You know what I'm saying? Yeah. Lost talking this week,
Speaker 5:  Android 13 came out for pixel phones. A lot of people refreshing eagerly
Speaker 5:  the brewing war between the vertical scrolling video apps
Speaker 5:  is here. A bunch of EV news got a little bit of lightning around. Let's
Speaker 5:  start with Android. We had Samsung reviews this week too. The, the Z fold
Speaker 5:  four, the watch five shout out to the, for an
Speaker 5:  incredible fake out on the watch. Five video review. If you haven't seen,
Speaker 5:  I'm not gonna ruin it for you. But
Speaker 7:  I was like preparing to like, I was writing a DM to her being like, this
Speaker 7:  head is wrong. Why are you saying all of this with this head? You can't do
Speaker 7:  this.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 7:  And then I kept watching. I was like, oh, that's why, that's why they got
Speaker 7:  it.
Speaker 5:  It's fine. Yeah. It's good. Go watch it. It's good. But let's start with
Speaker 5:  it. David, Android 13. It feels like it's like a, like an Android,
Speaker 5:  snow leopard. Like they're just getting a lot of stuff, right?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I think that's basically right. I mean a, the funny thing about Android
Speaker 6:  updates is always that it, Android updates come out and Google's like
Speaker 6:  Android 13 is here. 12 of you can download it. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Cuz it hardly like nobody owns pixels. Mo
Speaker 6:  most people own Android phones that are on somewhere between like last
Speaker 6:  and six versions of Android to go. But Android 13
Speaker 6:  is out for people who want it. It's like it is, it's a snow leopard thing.
Speaker 6:  They're like, they're doing a bunch of little things. This is kind of where
Speaker 6:  we are with smartphones. Right? It's like it's to give you some more control
Speaker 6:  over like how it looks and what kind of access
Speaker 6:  apps can have. And Android, I will say to its credit is doing a really good
Speaker 6:  job of starting to like piece things together. And they're like, you can
Speaker 6:  tell your app what language you want it to run in which photos it should
Speaker 6:  have access to how it should operate all these. Like they're just giving
Speaker 6:  people a lot of knobs to fiddle with, which I actually think like at this
Speaker 6:  moment in smartphones is a really good idea.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. We should describe what snow leopard means. Again, I'm an old head
Speaker 5:  steam engine uphill, both ways. All of us
Speaker 7:  Were, was the best snow.
Speaker 5:  Snowbird was the best version of what at the time was called Macs 10.
Speaker 5:  And they just decided to not do new features for a year and just make
Speaker 5:  it good. And then they immediately were like, and now we're back to weird
Speaker 5:  features and that, but it was per I didn't leave snowbird for
Speaker 5:  three years. I was like, I don't care what you're adding to this operating
Speaker 5:  system. This one's perfect. And every day that I use
Speaker 5:  this computer, I was like, I missed snow leopard. So that's like we're in
Speaker 5:  that moment for a lot of software hilariously, the developers of Madden
Speaker 5:  described it this years as a snow leopard release.
Speaker 5:  And it just feels like Android is in that same place where they're adding
Speaker 5:  things like spatial audio because they need to compete with apple. They're
Speaker 5:  adding things like more personalization maybe cuz they
Speaker 5:  need to compete with apple. But maybe because there's nothing left to do.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I will say the one thing I find very exciting about Android 13 is
Speaker 6:  like Google's big theme for the world right now is
Speaker 6:  like putting all of its many pieces together, which we talked about a bunch
Speaker 6:  in the show and like they're trying to make all their apps and services make
Speaker 6:  more sense together. And so there's this thing now where you can basically
Speaker 6:  stream your messaging apps from your phone to your Chromebook,
Speaker 6:  which I think a is an extremely good idea because like sitting here at my
Speaker 6:  computer and typing on my phone all day to message people is a gigantic pain
Speaker 6:  in the ass that I really am excited for it to go away. But also because it's
Speaker 6:  like, it's just a good idea and that kind of thing where it's like, I should
Speaker 6:  be able to type on my phone from my computer. And that is like how all of
Speaker 6:  this should work. And I like it very much and it feels like that's like the
Speaker 6:  start of something. Very cool. But otherwise all this stuff is like, yeah,
Speaker 6:  these are good things that are not gonna like blow your mind to pieces.
Speaker 7:  Do you think it's like, they just really wanted to hunker down and, and
Speaker 7:  improve on like the stuff they have or was it the
Speaker 7:  pandemic and the development cycles usually take a while and
Speaker 7:  the pandemic kind of screwed up those development cycles or both.
Speaker 5:  I think it's both in like in a serious way. I just, I remember C saying
Speaker 5:  to us on the show, it's kind of the beginning of pandemic. He was like,
Speaker 5:  we're well set up to all work from home and complete our roadmaps. What I'm
Speaker 5:  worried about is the next set of ideas. Yeah. Which think a lot of companies
Speaker 5:  have run into in one way or the other. But I think they were obviously
Speaker 5:  disrupted and no company is really being loud about how, how much its plans
Speaker 5:  were disrupted. But I just also think contextually, if you just look at the
Speaker 5:  state of Android right now at the same time the Android 13 is arriving.
Speaker 5:  We, we have the galaxy Z fold four running Android 12, right? Like
Speaker 5:  the, the new, most complicated fanciest Android smartphone
Speaker 5:  is being released at the same time, running the old version, cuz that's just
Speaker 5:  where Android is. And then they're running this
Speaker 5:  gigantic campaign about RCS because they know
Speaker 5:  that at least in the United States getting people to Levi message and switch
Speaker 5:  to Android is like too hard. So like what is the value of firing dozens
Speaker 5:  of new features into Android at this moment when switching is really
Speaker 5:  hard and your flagship phone provider is just gonna
Speaker 5:  run big speed all day long. Like I think they're in just a tough spot.
Speaker 6:  Well, and I think that comparison is like, it just strikes me
Speaker 6:  as it's behind all of this stuff right now. Right? Like on, on the one hand,
Speaker 6:  the idea that like you can customize the app icons and stuff is like a thing
Speaker 6:  people love on their iPhones that I think Google is very smart to pick up
Speaker 6:  on and sort of keep moving forward. And they're like, we'll automatically
Speaker 6:  change the color scheme of all your icons so that it'll work. But there's
Speaker 6:  also like the, when you ask somebody now like the difference between iOS
Speaker 6:  and Android, they're functionally the same Android actually like has more
Speaker 6:  features most of the time, but iOS just feels better. Like it, it
Speaker 6:  just does. And I think now like Google is
Speaker 6:  pushing really hard on this idea of like, what if we make Android feel better?
Speaker 6:  And, and there's all this little stuff that, that entails. Like I think we
Speaker 6:  were talking on this show about the, the magical thing where you can copy
Speaker 6:  text from one device and paste it onto another with apple. And like now Android
Speaker 6:  does that. Or I guess soon it will do that. If you have two devices
Speaker 6:  that are updated, which you won't, but like you get the idea. But
Speaker 6:  I think like that kind of stuff is like, I think Google is absolutely right
Speaker 6:  to say let's not build insane new stuff that almost no one is going to use.
Speaker 6:  Let's like make Android feel better. Yeah. And I think that is like, that's
Speaker 6:  how you get to where apple is. And then if you can solve RCS, then you might
Speaker 6:  actually be able to convince people to switch. Do
Speaker 5:  You feel like we've had this conversation every year for the past five years?
Speaker 5:  Because I, I feel like we could just do a clip show about that
Speaker 5:  and just rerun ourselves saying Google is focused. True. Do you remember
Speaker 5:  project butter? This is a company that once announced an entire
Speaker 5:  initiative called project butter that was designed to make
Speaker 5:  Android smoother.
Speaker 7:  Oh,
Speaker 6:  Kind of
Speaker 5:  Worked. It worked for a number of reasons. One, I remembered that it was
Speaker 5:  called project butter. Branding achieved two,
Speaker 5:  two, like yes. Android improve. But like, it just feels like that's the gap.
Speaker 5:  And I don't know that Google has meaningfully closed
Speaker 5:  it on these phones and it, then you've just got, well, what is the reality
Speaker 5:  of Android in this country? At least it's all of the Android phones are sold
Speaker 5:  by Samsung. Yes. So then someone else comes in and like does
Speaker 5:  whatever they want with Android. Samsung phones are smooth in their way.
Speaker 5:  It's not that they're not, they're just smooth in like
Speaker 5:  Samsung's way, which is a lot of trying to redirect you into a Samsung
Speaker 5:  lifestyle.
Speaker 7:  Get that big speed.
Speaker 5:  Maybe you are not interested in any way, shape or form or it's like,
Speaker 5:  sure carriers can put apps on this phone. Like there's, there's a different
Speaker 5:  experience to that. That is just more, the business is
Speaker 5:  in your face more with a Samsung Android phone, especially you buy it from
Speaker 5:  one of the major carriers, whereas apple to its credit. It's just like their
Speaker 5:  business is in your face all the time. But like they managed to hide it
Speaker 5:  better.
Speaker 6:  I don't know. Apple is like, and there was some news about this this week
Speaker 6:  that apple is now preparing to put more ads in more of
Speaker 6:  its apps and search results and stuff like that. And it's like, they're kind
Speaker 6:  of creeping towards each other. Right? Like Google is getting a little cleaner
Speaker 6:  and a little simple, simpler. Samsung even has really
Speaker 6:  pulled back over the last couple of years to the point where like, like I
Speaker 6:  used to hate Samsung's UI choices. And my recommendation was always like
Speaker 6:  run away from Samsung software as fast as you can by it's hardware and
Speaker 6:  do some weird stuff and install launchers. And now like Samsung software
Speaker 6:  is good. And it's like, yeah, you're starting to see the business of
Speaker 6:  apple a little more as Android is starting to move, they're just moving towards
Speaker 6:  each other in this really interesting, not necessarily great way all the
Speaker 6:  time.
Speaker 7:  Well, it's also interesting that Apple's like hardware lineup
Speaker 7:  is getting more fragmented. Whereas like Google's been
Speaker 7:  dealing with fragmentation for a decade now they, they know how to deal with
Speaker 7:  it. And Apple's like, I gotta figure this out. I guess we gotta like slow
Speaker 7:  down something.
Speaker 6:  You want old software. We got old software.
Speaker 5:  That's pretty generous on Google having figured out. I mean they have in
Speaker 5:  essentially.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Like they
Speaker 5:  Definitely have these aggregated like place services from Android and they
Speaker 5:  are better at updates and they've signed more aggressive deals to force the
Speaker 5:  updates to, to happen. But really the solution to Android
Speaker 5:  fragmentation is that Samsung won the market. Yeah. And so like,
Speaker 5:  it's not that fragmented.
Speaker 7:  Right. But like they've, they've had to deal with the challenge and like,
Speaker 7:  think about that challenge in a way that apple really hasn't had to like
Speaker 7:  ever in its phone market. Right. Like Apple's never had to think about fragmentation
Speaker 7:  and now it's got what, six different screens or something that it's got.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And then they're, they're gonna delay iPad OS or so we have heard
Speaker 5:  by the way, rumors that I iPhone event or some event,
Speaker 5:  we're assuming iPhone's usually in September or first part of
Speaker 5:  September, it's
Speaker 7:  Gonna be a home pod event.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. September 7th, I think is the date. Mark Garman reported all
Speaker 7:  Home pods and apple TVs get excited.
Speaker 5:  If it's, I mean, I would go to that event with Bellson. I would literally
Speaker 5:  like I'm here. I'm the most plugged in person
Speaker 5:  in this event. Let's talk apple TV the whole time. No one else three hit
Speaker 5:  me, Craig. And it would just be me like alone in the field,
Speaker 5:  looking at the giant screen, being like, come on, did you make a TV?
Speaker 5:  I'd be like, and then it's just Tim cook, come on stage and be like, no,
Speaker 5:  no. And he leaves hi. I would go to that event. Like it's time to
Speaker 5:  change events. What if instead of holding product launches, they just get
Speaker 5:  one person who wants something really badly. And then the CEO of the company
Speaker 5:  just denies that person. What they want. It's really close to the mic. We
Speaker 5:  get more coverage.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Tech company's disappointing one person at a time. That's our new event
Speaker 5:  strategy. I think it'll go really well. Speaking of Samsung
Speaker 5:  phones reviews are hitting. So Allison reviewed
Speaker 5:  the Z fold four V reviewed the galaxy watch five, let's start with the Z
Speaker 5:  fold four. Allison's like pretty into this phone. It's very expensive.
Speaker 5:  But she's like, this is the most gadgety gadget you can get. And you
Speaker 5:  won't be disappointed with it. The camera is improved. The Android
Speaker 5:  tablet ecosystem is still whatever it is. But I think we were saying this
Speaker 5:  last week, like they've just arrived at a they've iterated their way to a
Speaker 5:  workable folding phone.
Speaker 6:  I think the camera thing is super exciting here, actually, cuz that has been,
Speaker 6:  cuz you like, if you're gonna buy a fold, you kind of get into the fold,
Speaker 6:  knowing what you're getting into, right? Like it's gonna be a little more
Speaker 6:  fragile. It's gonna be a little bigger. So you're like, it's very hard to
Speaker 6:  buy that phone and not sort of understand those trade offs, but the idea
Speaker 6:  that you're spending all this money and getting a worse phone than Samsung's
Speaker 6:  other or, or worse cameras rather than Samsung's other high end phones
Speaker 6:  sucks. But now like you kind of get the feeling that like Samsung
Speaker 6:  now has sort of done all that it can. Right? And it's, it's still
Speaker 6:  a little big, it's still a little fragile, but like that just is
Speaker 6:  where we are in like science and materials.
Speaker 6:  Chemistry, Android app are still bad for
Speaker 6:  big screens. You just can't get good tablet apps for most Android apps.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. But otherwise Samsung's kind of put in its best feet forward
Speaker 6:  here, which I find super exciting. It's still $1,800, but it's like, it's
Speaker 6:  a very good phone that also turns into a tablet. And that's like about all
Speaker 6:  you can ask for right now.
Speaker 7:  I like how thorough Allison was in this review. Like she tested the flex
Speaker 7:  mode. She did it. She put it in this stupid. She did it.
Speaker 5:  She put, she heard us talking about tent mode on the show. She's like, all
Speaker 5:  right. The people demand 10 mode. The
Speaker 7:  People, my bosses demand. Then I test it in
Speaker 7:  flexible. I don't think that's what happened. That's not what happened. Listens
Speaker 7:  the
Speaker 5:  Show.
Speaker 5:  No she's in it. I mean like the Samsung has done a number of things with
Speaker 5:  this phone that are legitimately the future of phones, right? Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Folding or not. Right? Yep. The huge pixel bend sensor
Speaker 5:  has been the future for a minute, but they've refined it to a place where
Speaker 5:  it works really well. The under display camera is still a little weird,
Speaker 5:  but it works really well. Like I don't,
Speaker 6:  It works pretty well. Allison's description of it was very funny to me. She
Speaker 6:  described it as the, the visual aura that you get right before you get a
Speaker 6:  migraine headache, which is like not what you wanna hear from your selfie
Speaker 6:  camera. But as an under screen camera is like, it, she kinda landed on
Speaker 6:  like, it does the job, right? Like it's fine. And there are also 40,000 other
Speaker 6:  cameras on this thing that you can turn towards you in various ways. So it'll
Speaker 6:  be fine. But yeah, I agree. That's the kind of thing that like give it a
Speaker 6:  couple years and that's what all front facing cameras are gonna look like.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And Samsung thing is just historically good at
Speaker 5:  throwing things at the wall and then slowly iterating them into
Speaker 5:  until apple steals them and pretends they invented them and like,
Speaker 5:  you know, it's true. And like, I just think this, this
Speaker 5:  phone four versions in is I
Speaker 5:  keep saying this, I don't know. I don't even know if it's true anymore because
Speaker 5:  the software and ecosystem lock-ins are so hard. But if you just want like
Speaker 5:  a new gadget, I can't think of a better gadget at this point in
Speaker 5:  time. And I I've been saying things like phones are the worst gadgets
Speaker 5:  for like five years, like go buy a new TV or upgrade your
Speaker 5:  sound bar. Like that'll make you happy. And then we're looking at all of
Speaker 5:  the sales from all those companies. And it's like, oh, everyone did that
Speaker 5:  already. All it's time to find a new category gadgets. It's like, it's folding
Speaker 5:  phones. Like they're here at the right time. You think
Speaker 7:  It's you think it's folding phones and not like the steam deck and those
Speaker 7:  kind of like little game consoles.
Speaker 5:  I mean, I know how you and Sean feel
Speaker 7:  ING. Yeah. We're Sean, get 'em on, get 'em on the line. Liam.
Speaker 6:  Can you pair Nintendo's Joycons to the fold four cuz
Speaker 6:  there, there it is. There's your magical gadget
Speaker 7:  And then like just get a 3d print, a little case for it, slot
Speaker 7:  it in, make your own switch.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I think the steam deck is a great
Speaker 7:  GA. I actually have something I need to go do. Sorry. Gotta go do this.
Speaker 7:  Somebody get me a 3d printer.
Speaker 5:  Well, I, I think the steam deck is like a great category of GA. I, I,
Speaker 5:  I'm not disagreeing with you. Yeah. I just think it's one of those gadgets
Speaker 5:  where you can screw with it. But at some point you, the gadget playing with
Speaker 5:  the gadget element of it recedes because you just end up playing a video
Speaker 5:  game.
Speaker 6:  Right. Yep.
Speaker 5:  Which is great and fine and fair. But if you're in gadgets for the
Speaker 5:  messing, with the gadget element of it, I think the fold is a superior
Speaker 5:  gadget. Does that make any sense? Yes.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I think that's probably right.
Speaker 7:  I mean, I disagree.
Speaker 6:  It also just gives you more to do like,
Speaker 5:  But, but like at the end of the day with any, any game console yeah. The
Speaker 5:  point is to play video games. Right.
Speaker 7:  That's true,
Speaker 5:  Sean. And the point is to like buy steam deck accessories and then augment
Speaker 5:  the steam deck into a full laptop and then run the version
Speaker 7:  Steam deck. I want my steam deck to like run pie hole, like turn it into
Speaker 7:  a little server, just have it, do all the things like
Speaker 7:  everything. Like there's just so many weird things I can do with it and just
Speaker 7:  mess around with it. And I think it's probably the Linux of it that makes
Speaker 7:  it like Supreme gadget for me. Cause I'm like, it's got Linux. I can
Speaker 7:  just get into Linux. I can just get into the command line. And I can't do
Speaker 7:  that with, with this phone, but also I appreciate that. I can take this
Speaker 7:  phone on a plane and like mess with it as a gadget. And I could
Speaker 7:  not do that with the steam deck. I would just play video games with the steam
Speaker 7:  deck or I would accidentally break it. Those are my, those are my two.
Speaker 6:  I would also point out that I think you could buy all three
Speaker 6:  skews of the steam deck for less than
Speaker 5:  Four costs. Fair enough.
Speaker 5:  I mean, what is the,
Speaker 6:  I agree like I think, and I wrote about this when they announced the, the
Speaker 6:  Z fold for like, I think the thing no one has done is make like
Speaker 6:  the case for why this thing needs to exist. And to some extent, this is like
Speaker 6:  the, the like ongoing question about the iPad is like, why do you need an
Speaker 6:  iPad? And it's like, once you have one, you like kind of get why it's useful,
Speaker 6:  but there's no, if you were like, I have a laptop and a phone, why should
Speaker 6:  I buy an iPad? Like, it's kind of a hard question to answer. And I think
Speaker 6:  the same is true for this. It's like, it's cool to have
Speaker 6:  this big screens are good. You can watch videos dancing for
Speaker 6:  won't shut up about watching all of the halo TV show in bed, on his fold.
Speaker 6:  Like that's all great, but there's no,
Speaker 6:  there's no reason I would like tell you to go out of your way
Speaker 6:  and spend, you know, seven or 800 extra dollars to buy this phone. But if
Speaker 6:  you do, and it's a thing you want, it does feel like infinitely fun
Speaker 6:  to play with in a way that most phones are not fun to play with right now.
Speaker 6:  And this goes back to the Android thing, right? They're just like they're
Speaker 6:  tuning and tweaking and touching. And Samsung is out here just being like,
Speaker 6:  we have some new ideas. We don't really know what they are, but let's see
Speaker 6:  what happens. I'm
Speaker 5:  Like kudos. I will say that after we talked to the Z flip last week,
Speaker 5:  the number of people who hit us up to say that they see flips in the wild,
Speaker 5:  oh, my is very high. Our thesis is correct.
Speaker 6:  I got on a train like three hours after we recorded. And the two
Speaker 6:  people sitting closest to me, both had Z
Speaker 6:  flips. It blew my, it was like a sign from the universe that was like, David
Speaker 6:  people use these phones.
Speaker 5:  I
Speaker 6:  Hear you
Speaker 5:  Understand were like, I've heard about this move called the scroll and flip.
Speaker 5:  And I want you to take it very seriously. I thought everyone, can I see your
Speaker 5:  phone? Yeah, we got a Z flip review yet to come. I think
Speaker 5:  that is an important one, but it's start the watch for a quick second.
Speaker 5:  So watch five is out. Like I said, you gotta just watch the video cuz it's
Speaker 5:  an incredible fake out from V but it seems like the
Speaker 5:  grand Samsung, Google wears
Speaker 5:  experiment is off to an extremely medium start.
Speaker 7:  Yes. That seems accurate. Yeah. Like medium. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  She, she didn't hate this watch. Like she didn't outright hate it,
Speaker 7:  but it's still all the promise is not there. They have not delivered
Speaker 7:  on the big whizbang promises of this collaboration instead.
Speaker 7:  They've done like, well and there's nice things. There's
Speaker 6:  Just a bunch of like really basic stuff that it's like, like I, I, I have
Speaker 6:  made the case for years and continue to believe strongly that truly the
Speaker 6:  only thing that matters is battery life. Yes. Like you, you can, you can
Speaker 6:  add all the stuff you want after you give me a battery that is going to last
Speaker 6:  ideally days, but at least the whole day without ever
Speaker 6:  having to worry about it. And like the fact that Samsung is still
Speaker 6:  not, there is a, is a real bummer and a big problem, I think.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And also, I mean, the fact that they haven't really changed the design
Speaker 5:  at all, like I think she said the only, only way you can tell the difference
Speaker 5:  between these two is the strap colors.
Speaker 7:  That's not great. Sure.
Speaker 5:  The purple's
Speaker 6:  Nice. I like
Speaker 5:  The purple. The purple's nice. It looks pretty. I saw it in the office the
Speaker 5:  other day when we were there, it looks very pretty. I miss the physical
Speaker 5:  bezzle. What are you gonna do? But I there's just this
Speaker 5:  moment for the Android ecosystem where like everything is
Speaker 5:  a two-thirds approach to where apple is and is going, like
Speaker 5:  we are expecting in September or October or whenever these apple events
Speaker 5:  are like a huge next generation of, of smart watches from apple. Right? The
Speaker 5:  big outdoor watch the competitor to garment. Yeah. The big update
Speaker 5:  Apple's chip lead is enabling better battery life. Now this
Speaker 5:  size, if they put out a bigger watch, they can shove a bigger battery in
Speaker 5:  there that lead just seems like it's getting bigger, not smaller.
Speaker 7:  I think you're a hundred percent. Right. I think that's right. And but I
Speaker 7:  do wonder like how much Google actually cares
Speaker 7:  because they, they,
Speaker 5:  I mean, I think they care a lot
Speaker 7:  Then why do they suck so much?
Speaker 7:  Like, yeah. I struggle to think if they really care,
Speaker 7:  they put, put a
Speaker 6:  Resource. That's such a good question to ask Google
Speaker 5:  About, about so many things.
Speaker 7:  Oh, you care. Why do you suck?
Speaker 5:  This is seriously when max like throws a tantrum or like max and you
Speaker 5:  come down and she's like, I'm trying. And it's very adorable. And I
Speaker 5:  appreciate it, but it's like, but you actually have to do.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, you gotta do it. That's a point.
Speaker 7:  Feels like a child, but you
Speaker 5:  Know, no, that's the big Google wait. No, that's the big Google trick. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Google named itself Google. And it put a bunch of colors in its logo. And
Speaker 5:  we think that it's a kindergarten and it's actually like the most ruthless
Speaker 5:  company that you can think of. But because it's called Google, everyone's
Speaker 5:  like, ah, Google. And it's like in the background, like, and we're knifing
Speaker 5:  you like, yeah. But like, like I, they know what they're doing. They know
Speaker 5:  how they make their money. They write like searches a huge business for them.
Speaker 5:  YouTube is a huge business for them. They are very good at running those
Speaker 5:  businesses. It's here where they're not in control of their
Speaker 5:  ecosystem, that they struggle to find a compelling narrative
Speaker 5:  or they struggle to do things like buy HTC and turn the
Speaker 5:  pixel into a competitor's Samsung. And I think, I know, I know they care.
Speaker 5:  We know lots and lots of Google people. Right. We know one very well in particular.
Speaker 5:  I know they care a lot, but it's, I don't think they have the
Speaker 5:  moves. Like I don't think they can directly produce the
Speaker 5:  products like we, maybe they, you know, they've got the pixel, they've announced
Speaker 5:  that there's a pixel watch coming. Maybe those things when they actually
Speaker 5:  take control of their ecosystem will become these competitors. But
Speaker 5:  here where they sign this big deal with Samsung to do wear OS on this watch,
Speaker 5:  like their, their ability to execute like ends. And then Samsung has to take
Speaker 5:  the ball and keep running. And Samsung is not a bad hardware company. We
Speaker 5:  just talked about this phone, like the Z the fold is don't
Speaker 7:  Do this stuff. I mean, I think Samsung is part of the problem.
Speaker 5:  It's like, for some reason in this category, no one
Speaker 7:  Can go. Yeah. I think, I think Samsung is part of the problem because they
Speaker 7:  historically spent years thinking like very much
Speaker 7:  gendering their wearables and being like fitness bands are for ladies
Speaker 7:  and smartwatches are for boys and isn't it qua and cute.
Speaker 7:  And so there's a lot of catch up there that they have to figure out. And
Speaker 7:  there's a lot of like just their design philosophy has to catch
Speaker 7:  up and actually consider apple and not just chase
Speaker 7:  like the ghost Fitbit from six years ago.
Speaker 6:  But it's also the thing I would add to that is Google keeps making the mistake
Speaker 6:  of having an unbelievably short attention span on all of this stuff.
Speaker 6:  And like the thing, like to your point about apple, Silicon ne like that
Speaker 6:  is a long term project that is like really only coming
Speaker 6:  to fruition for apple now. And they've been investing in that forever.
Speaker 6:  And the idea that Google is just gonna decide
Speaker 6:  every six months, whether or not to care about making its own chips
Speaker 6:  or smartwatches or to CA like, it just can't make up its mind
Speaker 6:  long enough to get good at this stuff. And so we're basically back at
Speaker 6:  like the first and second versions of these things, even though it feels
Speaker 6:  like they've tried them a million times before. So like my expectations for
Speaker 6:  the pixel watch are super low because this is functionally like the first
Speaker 6:  ever Google smart watch, even though it isn't, but it's like, you, you
Speaker 6:  don't, at least from what I've seen in a lot of this product development,
Speaker 6:  like you, you can't start stop and then pick up where you left off. Like
Speaker 6:  it actually doesn't work like that. You end up effectively starting over
Speaker 6:  every time. And so Google just keeps shooting itself in the foot here.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I mean, that's true. I think most, most clearly in
Speaker 5:  tablets, right? Where yes, apple spent however
Speaker 5:  long just insisting that the iPad was the future of all
Speaker 5:  computing. And then to slowly realize that
Speaker 5:  people like their laptops and turn the iPad into an
Speaker 5:  expensive laptop. Sure. But they kept at it. Right. They were like, this
Speaker 5:  is what we're doing. We've made this bet. We're gonna keep going with it.
Speaker 5:  It helps some people bought a lot of iPads along the way, but Google made
Speaker 5:  the same bet made the same noise. I was there at CES when they announced
Speaker 5:  Android honeycomb on the Motorola ZY board or whatever
Speaker 5:  it was called. Like I've, we lived through it all together
Speaker 5:  as a family. And then they dropped it. They're like, no one's buying these.
Speaker 5:  No one cares like goodbye. And they let Motorola and Lenovo and Samsung keep
Speaker 5:  putting out $200 Android tablets, mostly for people
Speaker 5:  to use as other content consumption devices or for people to give to their
Speaker 5:  kids. Right. Like that became that market. Like here's a thing you can break.
Speaker 5:  And then they realized that foldables were gonna be big literally.
Speaker 5:  And they're like, we gotta be good at tablets together. They've announced
Speaker 5:  a new tablet project. And it said, well, if you just kept your eye on the
Speaker 5:  ball and made some incremental improvements, you'd be way farther ahead
Speaker 5:  than where you are right now. And like, I don't know if that's quite as true
Speaker 5:  with watches, but I do know that they keep they've now bought
Speaker 5:  big companies that are theoretically good at these products. They bought
Speaker 5:  HTC to make pixel phones. They bought Fitbit to make wearables. And we just
Speaker 5:  haven't seen the results. And maybe that's because HTC was not
Speaker 5:  competitive. That that was not competitive. And
Speaker 7:  I mean, because they don't care, like it's a huge company, this
Speaker 7:  isn't their primary space. Like, as we said, it's YouTube, it's
Speaker 7:  it's ads. This is a
Speaker 5:  It's YouTube and search.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. This is like, this is very much like a side project for them. And
Speaker 7:  until it really shows, returns and shows a reason for investment, it's never
Speaker 7:  gonna be an investment, but it ends up being that chicken and egg scenario,
Speaker 7:  cuz it's like, well, you never invested it. So it can never be really successful.
Speaker 7:  Well, yeah. But if it was successful, we'd invested it and it's like, oh,
Speaker 7:  all right. So we're just gonna argue with each other and, and fart out another,
Speaker 7:  like
Speaker 5:  Sometimes they get a real window into your previous career
Speaker 5:  at a different media company. I'm not gonna say which one
Speaker 6:  Who's to say who's to say, but no, I think that's right. And I think the
Speaker 6:  other thing is, and we should stop talking about this here in a minute, but
Speaker 6:  I think Google has also been a terrible steward
Speaker 6:  of its ecosystem in this sense, right? Like Google has never, for one
Speaker 6:  minute, given any Android developer a reason to think, oh, I
Speaker 6:  should really invest in my where OS app, because where OS
Speaker 6:  basically like ceases to exist once every two years and then
Speaker 6:  comes back as if by magic three years later. And it's the same with large
Speaker 6:  screens. And like apple just relentlessly told developers for like a
Speaker 6:  decade tablet, apps, matter, tablet, apps matter, tablet, apps matter. And
Speaker 6:  then they eventually got all got on board and now apple has this amazing
Speaker 6:  ecosystem of tablet apps that Google has just never given people
Speaker 6:  a reason to care about. And so when it decides to care, it has to like scramble
Speaker 6:  for six months to try and get everybody on board. And then a year later decides
Speaker 6:  it doesn't care again. I don't know.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I, I mean, I would say that I'm not sure that apple made the,
Speaker 5:  I'm not sure that apple finished the turn with the watch and apps,
Speaker 5:  right?
Speaker 6:  Like that's fair.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. In many ways, apps on the watch are still,
Speaker 5:  it's better. Now this is too reductive. I understand that I'm making an
Speaker 5:  UN sort of unfair reductive comment here, but
Speaker 5:  in many ways, apps on the watch are still just remote controls of your
Speaker 5:  phone. Yes, yes. Or extensions of your phone in some other important way.
Speaker 5:  There's, there's, there's a few that are great standalone watch experiences,
Speaker 5:  but like very few and they're very targeted and on the iPad, it's,
Speaker 5:  you know, some of them are great. Some of the really, really great iPad apps,
Speaker 5:  but then you look at the disparity in the iPad line
Speaker 5:  between the, you know, $329 iPad and the pro. And it's
Speaker 5:  like, yep. Some of those apps are designed for this market and a lot. And
Speaker 5:  the iPad is a lot of content in some bottom. And it just, the fact that I
Speaker 5:  can describe that. And a lot of people listen to this, understand what I'm
Speaker 5:  talking about is a victory for apple, right? Even if what I'm describing
Speaker 5:  is not a victory in the context of its own application ecosystem or
Speaker 5:  where it got to with developers or replacing the Mac or all this other stuff,
Speaker 5:  it's a victory that there's enough stuff that I can describe how that breaks
Speaker 5:  down. Whereas I don't know that I can describe to you a single wear a Wes
Speaker 5:  app. That is anything but I remote control of the phone, or even describe
Speaker 5:  a single where app. And I think that's like the problem with
Speaker 5:  Google's like ecosystem. It's a problem, honestly, with the watch five beyond
Speaker 5:  it's like battery life. It's that it's more of an,
Speaker 5:  it's like a feature phone, a feature watch more than it is like
Speaker 5:  a smart watch. That's an old debate, right? Like, is this a true
Speaker 5:  computing? What is a computer? Is this watch a computer? Or is it just a
Speaker 5:  really, really fancy calculator? Watch, it's a feature phone on
Speaker 5:  your wrist. There's someone out there right now, freaking out me that the
Speaker 5:  first generation iPhone was just the feature phone. Cuz it couldn't run an
Speaker 5:  open application, the ecosystem. And I want you to know that I love you.
Speaker 5:  Aw. You're my people.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. We, we all agree with that.
Speaker 5:  Sweet. Alright. We should take a break. We gotta come back. We gotta
Speaker 5:  talk about the war brewing between vertical video editors. It's a real one
Speaker 5:  top. We'll be right back.
Speaker 5:  All right, we're back. We've labeled this segment. Toto
Speaker 5:  Graham. It's
Speaker 7:  Beautiful.
Speaker 5:  David, what does that mean in your mind?
Speaker 6:  So we've come to this beautiful place where all the apps are the
Speaker 6:  same. There is just only, there is one app and it is, it is a,
Speaker 6:  it is a full screen, vertical video on your phone and where it comes from
Speaker 6:  and what you do there. And what it is, is not important. It
Speaker 6:  is it's your phone is just called app now and you open it and it plays video
Speaker 6:  for you and you swipe vertically and that's all that happens. This is the
Speaker 6:  world that we have somehow come to
Speaker 5:  App. I love app. It's
Speaker 6:  Just called app
Speaker 7:  App apps. Hugely.
Speaker 6:  You like to look at app for five hours and I'm like, yes, I would. Thank
Speaker 6:  you.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And the, and the app is like, where, where does, where do the videos
Speaker 5:  come from? I don't know. It's just anywhere.
Speaker 6:  Anything, what do you like dances? And I'm like, yeah, sure.
Speaker 7:  I likes app is I feel like all the subapp really want you to know where the
Speaker 7:  apps videos come from.
Speaker 6:  Oh, it's so important to them. It's
Speaker 5:  Very important. So we should point out just a plug land of the
Speaker 5:  giants this week is Alex talking about the future of Facebook
Speaker 5:  and the discovery engine and the future of the news feed, which is basically
Speaker 5:  Facebook turning Facebook into app,
Speaker 5:  but they're calling the discovery engine.
Speaker 5:  It's a good plug. It's a good episode. You should listen to it. So here's
Speaker 5:  the thing about app
Speaker 5:  TikTok specifically, TikTok, if you just zoom back what
Speaker 5:  TikTok is, is not so much the experience of viewing TikTok. So that's great.
Speaker 5:  That's very important. It obviously is winning and everyone's scared of it
Speaker 5:  and throwing their hands up and rebooting their apps as TikTok. Sure.
Speaker 5:  That's the consumer side, right? That's the watching TikTok side. The part
Speaker 5:  of TikTok that I think is undercover, under discussed under
Speaker 5:  reported on is that it is a video editor that
Speaker 5:  like large groups of college students have all learned to use
Speaker 5:  like expert, video editors. It like guides you into making
Speaker 5:  kinds of content that very few video editors have ever
Speaker 5:  guided anyone into making. Yeah. And like that piece of
Speaker 5:  TikTok success is fascinating to me
Speaker 5:  like the duets and responses. What
Speaker 5:  are they called? The stitch screen one, the stitches. So duets and
Speaker 5:  stitches, like they have developed a language of video communication on
Speaker 5:  TikTok. And then there are TikTok editing challenges. Like you see
Speaker 5:  that TikTok is expressed to its users is as much about
Speaker 5:  creation as it is about consumption. Right. I think that is super cool.
Speaker 6:  I totally agree. I just don't think TikTok invented that. Like I think I
Speaker 6:  would say if you wanna go back and find like a, a house style of vertical
Speaker 6:  video, like Snapchat is the answer. Ooh, not that it was like
Speaker 7:  I had to, I had to bring
Speaker 6:  It up. Don't talk to me about fine. All my favorite TikTok accounts are
Speaker 6:  just old vines and I love it very, but that's a whole separate story, but
Speaker 6:  I think like, and this is part of what, and we should get into some of the
Speaker 6:  news from this week, but I think the, the thing that you're getting at that's
Speaker 6:  super interesting to me is that like we are now in this place where it is
Speaker 6:  just vertical video and everybody's fighting about where it comes from and
Speaker 6:  who sees it and all that stuff. But like the thing they're I think starting
Speaker 6:  to realize is that like, if we can build the best creation tools,
Speaker 6:  that's actually one big, huge way to win. And like Snapchat had the
Speaker 6:  filters and Instagram is starting to build really advanced stuff and TikTok,
Speaker 6:  like I think you're right. That TikTok has like developed this
Speaker 5:  TikTok did its
Speaker 6:  Language of cinema in a really cool
Speaker 5:  Way. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  I'm not. And yeah. And did it in a huge way for sure.
Speaker 5:  But like if you just step back, like apple had iMovie,
Speaker 5:  they had clips, dear sweet clips, which only Deone ever loved.
Speaker 5:  I
Speaker 6:  Forgot about that.
Speaker 5:  Right. They, what apple had was a creation tool that a lot of people liked.
Speaker 5:  I mean, I was an kid again, steam engine uphill, both ways.
Speaker 5:  That was me just like adjusting millimeter footage off of Sony camera
Speaker 5:  on iLink. Remember when sunny tried to rebrand fire wires, iLink, let's do
Speaker 5:  an hour on that.
Speaker 7:  I will do a whole hour with you ne on that it very up upsetting
Speaker 5:  FireWire 800. What happened one hour of the verge cast?
Speaker 5:  Can I just tell you my it and gadget years ago when apple finally
Speaker 5:  killed FireWire I made an entire video montage of fire wire
Speaker 5:  ports set to boys to men. And then this was
Speaker 5:  before TikTok existed, cuz this would've been like a perfect TikTok. So I
Speaker 5:  had to go get AOL's custom video player and be like, I need to
Speaker 5:  upload a video. And they're like, what's the content I was like, I don't
Speaker 5:  want to tell you,
Speaker 7:  Did you edit it in
Speaker 5:  IMovie? I don't want you to watch this. I did. It was great on your anyway.
Speaker 6:  That was the day AOL went out of business.
Speaker 5:  They were like, you should leave and start your own website neon
Speaker 5:  anyhow. But apple had all these creation tools. It never had a distribution
Speaker 5:  platform. Yeah. Right, right. There was not, it was just not their thought
Speaker 5:  that connecting creation and distribution would be important. YouTube famously
Speaker 5:  is still the best, most lucrative preferred video distribution
Speaker 5:  platform for almost every internet creator. It's got the best revenue it's
Speaker 5:  got the biggest community shorts. Is that performing the main thing, shorts
Speaker 5:  again is app as expressed by YouTube.
Speaker 5:  But it, it, it dropped the ball on the creation side.
Speaker 5:  Almost completely like to be a high end YouTuber. You have to give
Speaker 5:  to Adobe premier or final cut or right. Make videos
Speaker 5:  about why final cut is actually good. And then you get a million vs. Like
Speaker 5:  it's you just end up in a place where YouTube doesn't help you create anything.
Speaker 5:  They're starting to do that in shorts because app, but it's weird that the
Speaker 5:  biggest distribution platform never really cared about the creation element.
Speaker 5:  I think what I, when I say TikTok is the winner, is they married those two
Speaker 5:  things in a gigantic way. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Totally
Speaker 5:  Snap in stories with filters did that sort of, but there was no virality
Speaker 5:  associated with snap. TikTok is like virality for days,
Speaker 5:  plus this huge creation tool. But now you're seeing
Speaker 7:  On like the right device too. Right? Like they, they put it on the right
Speaker 7:  device. They didn't put it on your, your computer. They put it on your phone,
Speaker 7:  which is what most younger people are using as a computer.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. No, I think that's all right. It just funny to me that there's been,
Speaker 5:  there's been this historic split TikTok collapses a split. Yeah. But now
Speaker 5:  you've got Instagram, you've got YouTube shorts. You've got
Speaker 5:  TikTok. They've all got these powerful creation tools in them. And they are
Speaker 5:  trying to gate keep the creation tools and lock them to their own
Speaker 5:  distribution cuz that's where their money is. And historically
Speaker 5:  creation tools have not been wedded to or tied or
Speaker 5:  limited to one distribution platform.
Speaker 6:  Does it ever blow your mind to think about the fact that this is like the
Speaker 6:  wireless carriers not wanting to be dumb pipes and this is why all the streaming
Speaker 6:  services don't wanna play with universal search because they all want you
Speaker 6:  to hang out inside of their apps. Like every industry is the same,
Speaker 6:  some of the nouns change, but everybody is like, everybody makes the same
Speaker 6:  stuff and then goes, oh no, we're the same stuff. How do we make sure people
Speaker 6:  don't think of us as the same as everybody else? And then does this and this
Speaker 6:  is where we
Speaker 5:  Are. And the answer is software restrictions and it's like
Speaker 6:  Watermarks.
Speaker 5:  So in watermark. So just this week,
Speaker 5:  YouTube shorts, the editor will now put a watermark. If you export out of
Speaker 5:  YouTube shorts and repost and want to take it somewhere else, how could you
Speaker 5:  Instagram? This is our own social team discovered this, this week,
Speaker 5:  Instagram has a really powerful green screen tool for real. So they were
Speaker 5:  just using it and they would export the video and use it for other
Speaker 5:  stuff. And now Instagram just mutes that video
Speaker 5:  when you export it, it has no audio,
Speaker 6:  Unless this is my favorite part is unless you share it first on reels.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Which is fantastic. They're like, do whatever you want. Just put it on reels
Speaker 6:  first.
Speaker 5:  It's perfect. I mean, I just think that there's something
Speaker 5:  here where the idea of creation tools being
Speaker 5:  locked or tied or limited to distribution
Speaker 5:  is new in the culture. Right? It that's it's
Speaker 5:  meaningfully new because historically again,
Speaker 5:  the creation tools have never had distribution connected to them. And the
Speaker 5:  distribution platforms have never had creation tools connected to them. And
Speaker 5:  now it's like, what if we software lock you into this garden? When
Speaker 7:  Do you think they start charging?
Speaker 5:  My suspicion is that people are gonna react to this extremely negatively.
Speaker 7:  You don't think they're gonna just charge people, be like, oh, you wanna
Speaker 7:  unlock it. You wanna export it wherever for $2 a month
Speaker 7:  to Instagram, you can do whatever you want with the video you make for us.
Speaker 5:  I don't, I think it would have to be like $400 a month. Like the, the lifetime
Speaker 5:  value of the Instagram library getting bigger is bigger than any
Speaker 5:  dollars that you could pay them as a consumer. Like you just gotta do the
Speaker 5:  math, right? Like Instagram is staring down the barrel of a 10
Speaker 5:  billion TikTok shaped gun. Yeah. How are you gonna, how you gonna make that
Speaker 5:  up? You can't, it's not $2.
Speaker 6:  And they all see each other as super zero sum, which I think is really
Speaker 6:  interesting. Like the idea that these apps are not in a position of being
Speaker 6:  able to like just sort of let a thousand flowers bloom and
Speaker 6:  be like, you know, there's enough attention for everybody. People are on
Speaker 6:  our app. They are like directly threatened by each
Speaker 6:  other now, which I think really interesting. And it is like the only
Speaker 6:  conclusion I can draw from that is that they have all begun to understand
Speaker 6:  that these serve the same purpose for the same set of people. And that ultimately
Speaker 6:  only one of them is probably going to win and everybody kind of thinks it's
Speaker 6:  gonna be TikTok. So they are like desperately fighting against
Speaker 6:  that pull away. Cause like if I'm YouTube, I don't know that I would
Speaker 6:  necessarily
Speaker 6:  feel like I'm existentially threatened by TikTok. If I wanted to go do
Speaker 6:  a different thing. But now YouTube is like, no, we have to fight with TikTok
Speaker 6:  and they have to take every advantage they can away from TikTok, which I
Speaker 6:  think is fascinating.
Speaker 5:  So YouTube has the big advantage, which is it
Speaker 5:  has the best revenue share program for all those
Speaker 5:  platforms for actual creators to make money on platforms. Yeah. No one makes
Speaker 5:  money in TikTok. As far as I can tell. I won't say the dreaded
Speaker 5:  DWORD here, but there's another very good podcast where I
Speaker 6:  Was about to bring it up. Hank green was so good on decoder. There you go.
Speaker 5:  And
Speaker 6:  You said a lot of stuff I thought was interesting.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Hank Green's like, no one makes money in TikTok, but that's where the
Speaker 5:  audience is. It's also easier and cheaper for me to get there. And you know,
Speaker 5:  his feeling is like all of that adds up to his YouTube audience growing and
Speaker 5:  his business doing well. But he also said YouTube shorts is growing faster.
Speaker 5:  And once YouTube flips on the money, which they already can do,
Speaker 5:  they've already built the model. So they don't have to like go and explain
Speaker 5:  it to the board of directors or model. Like they already have it. I think
Speaker 5:  they might win because people will obviously go where the money is.
Speaker 5:  And that's great, but it's not gonna solve the like long tail problem of
Speaker 5:  TikTok, which is, there are lots of people on TikTok who are not there to
Speaker 5:  make money. Yeah. Right. And they're just having a good time with a cool
Speaker 5:  video editor that happens to be connected to a distribution platform that
Speaker 5:  might make you go viral at any time and deliver you a hundred dollars from
Speaker 5:  the creator's fund. And that's like a good enough incentive program compared
Speaker 5:  to, to YouTube where everyone wants a career as a YouTuber. And that
Speaker 5:  is a different game to play.
Speaker 7:  I just kind of, I was gonna say, I wonder why people there is this big
Speaker 7:  existential like crisis for a lot of these app makers, because
Speaker 7:  Facebook meta at Google, they have like the ad game unlock.
Speaker 7:  They know how to monetize this stuff and make money. And TikTok
Speaker 7:  does TikTok is TikTok making money, handover fist like
Speaker 7:  to bring up mine again, is it gonna be,
Speaker 5:  They're not sharing it back to creators.
Speaker 7:  Right? And so like,
Speaker 5:  No. So TikTok is a black box is owned by, by dance. We don't know how by
Speaker 5:  dance is doing as a company, but all the reporting suggests
Speaker 5:  that TikTok advertising is effective. They're collecting those ad dollars.
Speaker 5:  And like the music industry loves
Speaker 5:  TikTok. Yes. And TikTok loves the music industry because if you
Speaker 5:  have, if you are Beyonce's record label and publicist,
Speaker 5:  you're like these songs are gonna go viral this week and TikTok will all,
Speaker 5:  but certainly make that happen for you. Yes. And like that's a, that's
Speaker 5:  a revenue generation program
Speaker 7:  Program. So that's so like, that's why they're
Speaker 5:  Scared. Right? Cuz they, they TikTok is the culture like for better or worse,
Speaker 5:  if you're listening to this, you're like, oh TikTok, like TikTok drives a
Speaker 5:  massive amount of the culture now. Yes. Because it's
Speaker 5:  ability to generate virality, it's ability to generate trends and the trends
Speaker 5:  come and go in the blink of an eye.
Speaker 5:  Rebecca Jennings at Vox has written about this very compellingly. Like you
Speaker 5:  don't, it's impossible to be a trends reporter anymore because all the trends
Speaker 5:  are happening all the time. And then they go away like, see shanties, do
Speaker 5:  not say anything about the state of America. Right. But like for one
Speaker 5:  week C shanties were very important to everyone cuz it just happened. And
Speaker 5:  then it went
Speaker 5:  away. I was a Rebecca piece. You should go read it. It's pretty good. But
Speaker 5:  Instagram isn't that thing anymore. And it used to be, and I think they feel
Speaker 5:  it going away YouTube. I don't know if it was ever that thing
Speaker 5:  because it was always everything. Yeah. Right. Like when we were
Speaker 5:  covering YouTube stars and that, that period of YouTube, when
Speaker 5:  we could cover YouTube stars, like they were aliens and we were explaining
Speaker 5:  them to the world. Like that felt like a thing we were actually doing. Like
Speaker 5:  here's a whole culture. You don't see over here on YouTube. Have you heard
Speaker 5:  a Logan? But now they're just like everywhere. You know? Like they they've,
Speaker 5:  they've transitioned into the culture at large and YouTube is still
Speaker 5:  manufacturing some of those moments, but not nearly at the rate of TikTok.
Speaker 5:  And I just think fundamentally yes, it is a zero sunscreen. You only
Speaker 5:  have so many minutes in the day. And if you want app TikTok right now is
Speaker 5:  best app, you know?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I think that's well and I think what's, what's gonna be interesting
Speaker 6:  for me to watch is like the, the upside of
Speaker 6:  shorts for YouTube is that it can then, like, I think the, the company
Speaker 6:  closest to sort of being able to wrap all of this together is probably
Speaker 6:  YouTube. Right? It has the giant audience shorts seems to be taking off.
Speaker 6:  It has the monetization strategy. It's like YouTube is, is sort of the
Speaker 6:  end point. Like even people on TikTok make their TikTok money on
Speaker 6:  YouTube. Like that's, that's where you go to make your money. So tick like
Speaker 6:  YouTube has already solved the hard part of this. What TikTok has not figured
Speaker 6:  out is how to like build home bases for people who do this for a living
Speaker 6:  and really no one other than YouTube has ever figured this out.
Speaker 6:  And so I think, I mean, Twitch has like, we see all these rumors about TikTok
Speaker 6:  Twitch
Speaker 7:  Figured it out,
Speaker 6:  Twitch figured it out. That's fair. Twitch is like a, a specific niche
Speaker 6:  of the world, but has definitely figured it out. That's totally fair. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  But I think other than those two, like Facebook never really figured it out
Speaker 6:  Snapchat hasn't figured it out TikTok hasn't figured it out. And I think
Speaker 6:  like you look at like TikTok music, which I think is, is gonna be a thing
Speaker 6:  that exists and has been rumored forever, but is them trying to build
Speaker 6:  an end point, right? Like you come to TikTok, you go to Lincoln bio and you
Speaker 6:  leave eventually to go make some money for somebody. And TikTok would like
Speaker 6:  to pull more of that back in. And my sense is that's hard, but whether
Speaker 6:  it's harder than getting people to spend three hours just scrolling through
Speaker 6:  videos on your app is gonna be like the big question for you too.
Speaker 7:  I mean, I think it is hard because you're seeing like a lot of these, these
Speaker 7:  fandoms for these, these followers and or these creators and just fandoms
Speaker 7:  in general, you're seeing that, that huge decentralization, like they, they
Speaker 7:  are there aren't hubs for these people anymore. It is all just word of mouth
Speaker 7:  and, and sharing and, and all these back channels. So I think that's really,
Speaker 7:  really difficult for TikTok, which is why I keep coming back to like, is
Speaker 7:  TikTok built to last like yes, anybody can be really good at like creating
Speaker 7:  the culture for a couple of years. We've seen that again and again and again,
Speaker 7:  anybody can do glee was the culture. Glee
Speaker 7:  did not last, sorry.
Speaker 5:  I'm sorry. I, I do not agree with you G it was the culture.
Speaker 7:  It was unfortu very much the culture true.
Speaker 5:  I'm 1000% on a podcast with two like musical theater kids. And I
Speaker 5:  just need to tell you that you're wrong about this situation,
Speaker 7:  But, but there are these things that like, it's not true, regardless of,
Speaker 7:  if you agree with glee, there are these various things that are like, this
Speaker 7:  is the center of culture. This is what we all care about. Yeah. And, and
Speaker 7:  especially for younger people, which is what most of talk's audience is.
Speaker 7:  My dad excluded. He like watches it every night. He calls it like his show,
Speaker 7:  his tos. And he is like, I get in bed and I watch my tos.
Speaker 6:  It's like his stories. Oh, I
Speaker 7:  Love that. It is his stories. It's great. Oh no. But like, for the most part,
Speaker 7:  it is younger people and, and they, they do move
Speaker 7:  around very quickly. And this is like, it is hard
Speaker 7:  to lock people in right now, lock people to like
Speaker 7:  a specific hub. And so I like, I,
Speaker 7:  I'm still not sold that TikTok is gonna be this huge behemoth. I think it's
Speaker 7:  doing very, very successful, very, very right now. But like, I don't see
Speaker 7:  where that long term game is beyond music partnerships.
Speaker 7:  And even then we've heard like Lizzo doing great traction on
Speaker 7:  TikTok. Isn't necessarily translating to sales for
Speaker 7:  Lizzo. So like,
Speaker 5:  Well, nothing translates to sales anymore. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  It's yeah. Then that's the other part it's like where, yeah, I just don't
Speaker 7:  know how, how long this lasts for them before people get fed up with
Speaker 7:  TikTok TikTok, it's canceled by the teens and then they all
Speaker 7:  move on to what discord, YouTube, YouTube,
Speaker 7:  they all just, they just come back to YouTube and they're like, have you
Speaker 7:  heard
Speaker 5:  Of this place? I disagree. I think TikTok TikTok and its current rate
Speaker 5:  is bound to succeed because it is one supported by
Speaker 5:  the Chinese government, which really wants it to succeed. And actually its
Speaker 5:  biggest ex existential threat is that the United States government
Speaker 5:  is aware that the Chinese government supports TikTok and might one day just
Speaker 5:  turn it off, which I will remind you that a previous president decided
Speaker 5:  he was just going to do without a plan and almost sold to
Speaker 7:  Microsoft. Oracle, go buy this. Hey, you, you got some money. Yes.
Speaker 7:  Do it.
Speaker 5:  Oracle is taking over the TikTok data centers. Like it's a weird deal
Speaker 5:  over at TikTok land.
Speaker 6:  There really is a wild like sliding doors moment. Like just to totally
Speaker 6:  derail this just for one quick second, like imagining what this
Speaker 6:  like August of 20, 22 would be like if Oracle or
Speaker 6:  Microsoft owned TikTok. And like the culture had changed around
Speaker 6:  that for the last two years is like, like we're gonna do a 10th
Speaker 6:  anniversary, like science fiction and reverse. Like what if Microsoft
Speaker 6:  owned TikTok thing and I'm, I'm already excited about it.
Speaker 5:  I will remind you that such and Adella. I think it was at the code conference
Speaker 5:  was like, that was some of the weirdest conversations I've ever had
Speaker 5:  was like we had to be in it cuz like how could we not try to buy TikTok?
Speaker 5:  Because like it was weird and then it went away for the best
Speaker 5:  weird. Yeah. I, I don't know. Like, I don't know if it was for the best,
Speaker 5:  like I'm not saying that the operation of that version of our
Speaker 5:  government was ever stable or smooth, but sometimes like they,
Speaker 5:  you know, broken clock twice a day, like they're like TikTok is owned by
Speaker 5:  the Chinese. We should take a harder line about it. Yeah. That might
Speaker 5:  have, that might have been the correct. I think that is coming for TikTok
Speaker 5:  much more than gen Z deciding that
Speaker 5:  what they like is reading long blog posts on Tumblr again,
Speaker 5:  which would be amazing. I would love that if that is the next move
Speaker 5:  it's but I don't, I don't think that's likely.
Speaker 6:  So here's what I wonder about this is like, does this mean that the next
Speaker 6:  thing we're gonna get is like a really powerful
Speaker 6:  cross-platform vertical video creation tool that does all these things
Speaker 6:  like part of me thinks somewhere Evan Spiegel and the snap
Speaker 6:  executive team are just like leaning back in their chairs, being like, come
Speaker 6:  make stuff with us. We don't watermark let's let's hang out.
Speaker 6:  But then I also wonder like is, is the next phase of this? Just
Speaker 6:  that everything silos really aggressively is it that we all get
Speaker 6:  less confused seeing YouTube watermarks in
Speaker 6:  TikTok and TikTok watermarks in YouTube and nobody actually cares. And this
Speaker 6:  isn't really a thing or is there a new thing that comes up?
Speaker 5:  Well, no, the platforms are detecting the watermarks. Oh, that's true. That's
Speaker 5:  the thing. Yeah. So YouTube will detect the TikTok watermark and then downright
Speaker 5:  that video.
Speaker 6:  Yeah,
Speaker 5:  I love it. So there's just a, again, my thesis here
Speaker 5:  is that creation and distribution have never been so tightly tied together
Speaker 5:  and that imposing the business limits of the distribution platform on the
Speaker 5:  creation tool is bad. And that eventually the
Speaker 5:  people who use the creation tools will be frustrated enough to enact
Speaker 5:  some sort of penalty on those platforms. We'll see. But I
Speaker 5:  don't think that the answer is snapping. Like for four bucks a month, you
Speaker 5:  can use the snap video editor cuz they have to keep pace with the
Speaker 5:  coolest tools in TikTok. And talk's greatest success is
Speaker 5:  adding tools that people then use in like
Speaker 5:  viral recursive, conversant ways with one another. And that
Speaker 5:  is I, they have been better at creating that loop than any of these
Speaker 5:  other platforms.
Speaker 6:  So really the company that should be like licking its chops at this is like
Speaker 6:  Vimeo and the other like active creation. I'm serious. Like
Speaker 6:  if, if we, if this
Speaker 5:  Vis like a B to B video, white label hosting service, now I
Speaker 6:  Don't. Yeah, it is now that's fair. But so, okay. So that's the thing like
Speaker 6:  who is it then? Then the thing that's gonna happen is somebody is going to
Speaker 6:  like sit above this and it's like, you remember the thing when they, everybody
Speaker 6:  built like the hoot suites of the world, where it's like, you can publish
Speaker 6:  to all your social channels in an automated way. And it's not such a disaster
Speaker 6:  to manage a hundred different things. Like that's gotta be coming for vertical
Speaker 6:  video. Now
Speaker 5:  Maybe I, well maybe hoo suite for app.
Speaker 5:  If the, who suite people are listening, you can just take that idea, please,
Speaker 5:  please name it. Who tweet for app? We'll we'll know what
Speaker 5:  happened and we won't be mad. I don't know. It's not like there's
Speaker 5:  great upload APIs for these. Like these are
Speaker 5:  very restricted platforms in a way that, you know, Twitter
Speaker 5:  for all of its problems has, has an API that other people like
Speaker 5:  when we post stories from our CMS, they just get tweeted
Speaker 5:  automatically because Twitter is built. That kind of integration. I
Speaker 5:  don't know.
Speaker 6:  So this next phase, this next phase just sucks for cross platform
Speaker 6:  creators then yes.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I think, I think it's gonna get harder. Cause
Speaker 7:  Everything silo.
Speaker 5:  That's what I'm saying.
Speaker 7:  Everybody's
Speaker 5:  Got their, I think eventually creators are going to say this is stupid.
Speaker 5:  We don't wanna live in your walls because Adobe premier
Speaker 5:  is never been gated. Like this iMovie has not gated like this creation except
Speaker 5:  that they be gated to.
Speaker 7:  I figured it out guys. I figured it out Sonology is gonna create a
Speaker 7:  really good widget and everybody's just gonna buy a
Speaker 7:  Sonology and upload their videos. And you're gonna like type in the
Speaker 7:  IP address for the person's house and get your vertical videos.
Speaker 5:  Oh, direct,
Speaker 7:  Direct just, oh, instead of going fully into the cloud,
Speaker 7:  totally siloed. Everybody's gonna get fed up and be like, we all have our
Speaker 7:  little Sonology tos.
Speaker 5:  It's Plex. It's push video.
Speaker 7:  It's gonna be great.
Speaker 6:  All right. Do you think Plex can fix this, Alex? What
Speaker 7:  Are your thoughts? They got this.
Speaker 6:  Okay,
Speaker 5:  Cool. Have you have you install
Speaker 7:  Plex in? No, I need to. I thought,
Speaker 5:  Alright, well we're gonna take a break. Alex is gonna install Plex on her
Speaker 5:  steam deck. We got some car stuff. We got a lightning around coming up. We'll
Speaker 5:  be right back.
Speaker 5:  Okay. We're back bunch of car news, but I'm not gonna start with
Speaker 5:  deadhead car news. I'm gonna start with extremely wonky FCC news because
Speaker 5:  you know how I love some extremely wonky FCC news.
Speaker 5:  Okay. The car industry lost a court case this week. That
Speaker 5:  is like one of my favorite, just dumb conflicts
Speaker 6:  In the world. Wait, like the whole car industry. Does the car industry have
Speaker 6:  like a lawyer?
Speaker 5:  Well, they have an industry group. Oh,
Speaker 7:  So they got wrecked.
Speaker 5:  So yes, they got wrecked. So in like the late
Speaker 5:  nineties, like in 1999, the FCC set aside all the
Speaker 5:  spectrum in a 5.9 gigahertz band for something
Speaker 5:  called V2 V vehicle to vehicle communications. And then they added
Speaker 5:  V to I vehicle to infrastructure communications, and then they make it all
Speaker 5:  sound cool. They started calling it VTX. Yes. Which is very funny.
Speaker 5:  Sure. So the FCC is like car industry make the cars safer, make
Speaker 5:  them all talk to each other, make them talk to stop lights, right?
Speaker 5:  Solve traffic jams. You won't hit each other. Here's a big
Speaker 5:  chunk of spectrum. Like good spectrum for you to figure this
Speaker 5:  out. I have been to like 5,000
Speaker 5:  CES demos of V to V and Vida I stuff.
Speaker 5:  Right. And like car makers would be like with this new technology, the cars
Speaker 5:  can see through each other. We can predict traffic. We can slow you down.
Speaker 5:  We can see what's happening up on the road. We can make sure you hit all
Speaker 5:  the stoplights perfectly on time. It's here. And then none of it ever
Speaker 5:  ships,
Speaker 6:  But it's a, just, this is like the right idea, right? Yes. Like, is, is this
Speaker 6:  just like, okay. Cuz it always, I I've, I've spent less time with car people
Speaker 6:  at CES than you have. But even in the, like I spent a bunch of time with
Speaker 6:  Qualcomm, like four or five years ago and all they talked about was V to
Speaker 6:  V stuff. And it's like, okay, the idea that I don't just have to rely on
Speaker 6:  my phone's CA or on my car's cameras to see everything that's going on, I
Speaker 6:  can actually let my car talk to the other car and to the
Speaker 6:  stoplight and they can all understand what's going on that way. It seems
Speaker 6:  like the right, like in a perfect world, that's how they should work. Right.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. But David, have you considered that these are the same people that
Speaker 7:  make like in car HUDs and, and in
Speaker 7:  car comp, like it's the same people that are like, we need a S Schor
Speaker 7:  version of the car, so you can turn your lights off and on
Speaker 7:  like of course,
Speaker 6:  Yeah. You have to tap on the truck to, to, to change the climate in
Speaker 5:  Your truck. Okay. So to be fair, like a tiny handful of
Speaker 5:  extremely expensive luxury cars shipped with like VTV radios,
Speaker 5:  the 2017 Mercedes-Benz E-Class and S class
Speaker 5:  Cadillac CTS in 2017. Okay. Three
Speaker 6:  Talking to nothing.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Just, just rolling around talking to nothing.
Speaker 5:  And then they started, I mean, all these names are great and then, you know,
Speaker 5:  5g happened. Everyone's like 5g will do it. And they started calling it cellular
Speaker 5:  V two X or CV two X.
Speaker 6:  Yes. Oh my God.
Speaker 5:  Nothing resonates with the consumers like CV two X.
Speaker 5:  Okay. So then 2017 Trump
Speaker 5:  FCC, which was just a wrecking ball of ideas,
Speaker 5:  got rid of a regulation that Obama's FCC had put in
Speaker 5:  saying, all the cars needed VTV stuff, right? How do you get over the hump
Speaker 5:  of no cars having it? You just write the law, saying all the cars need to
Speaker 5:  have it. We all need to do it. Cars are gonna stop crashing into each other,
Speaker 5:  not the Trump FCC, which didn't do it to be fair. It had been
Speaker 5:  17 years, right? Like they, they set us on the spectrum in
Speaker 5:  1999 in 2017, nothing is shipping. So
Speaker 5:  our boy, a Jeep pie is like, screw it.
Speaker 5:  I'm giving a bunch of the spectrum back to unlicensed
Speaker 5:  usage, which is a big trend lately. So maybe we'll have 5.9 gig
Speaker 5:  Hertz wifi now. And you can still keep a little chunk of this
Speaker 5:  for cellular B two X CB two X.
Speaker 5:  So the automakers industry groups are like, don't do this. We need it.
Speaker 5:  If we, if wifi will interfere with our radios, that don't exist.
Speaker 5:  The Alliance for automotive innovation
Speaker 5:  promised 5 million cars would have VV over the next five
Speaker 5:  years, but they wouldn't do it if the FCC gave the spectrum
Speaker 5:  away. Okay. So they file the lawsuit. The lawsuit comes out
Speaker 5:  and the judge is like, what are you talking about? No intelligent
Speaker 5:  transportation systems have been developed as of 2020, no,
Speaker 5:  commercially marketed vehicles used 5.9 gig. It hurts to
Speaker 5:  provide vehicle safety features. And then he's like your argument
Speaker 5:  that you need all this spectrum for new technologies
Speaker 5:  is not great. Noting the petitioners have directed us to no significant
Speaker 5:  developments in the field of yet to arrive technologies.
Speaker 6:  So good.
Speaker 5:  This isn't judge saying your shit's of vaporware. Yes. It makes
Speaker 5:  me so happy.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  The field of yet to arrive technologies yeah. Is like the, the,
Speaker 6:  the beginning of a book title about vaporware that I would very much
Speaker 5:  Read. It's so good. And it's like, this is such a good idea. You guys never
Speaker 5:  shipped it. It was vapor for so long that eventually the United States government
Speaker 5:  was like, we're gonna dunk on you a little bit for a while.
Speaker 6:  The
Speaker 5:  Very good, well, hopefully our wifi riders get better and hopefully
Speaker 5:  5g actually does. It's like they drive robot surgeons to your house and self-driving
Speaker 5:  cars. That, that's what Verizon's ad said. Sure. 5g.
Speaker 6:  So is V2 V like dead now? Like what, what
Speaker 5:  Happens? No, cuz they're, they're they're supposed to put 5g radios in the
Speaker 5:  cars.
Speaker 6:  Oh. So 5g will fix it.
Speaker 5:  They still have a tiny little chunk of this spectrum reserve for that use,
Speaker 5:  but they wanted it all and they, they just didn't use it for 20 years. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  So now it's coming back to unlicensed usage for wifi, which I think is probably
Speaker 5:  the right decision. Yes. But it's like use it or lose it pro like
Speaker 6:  Yeah. 20 years seems like long enough to try to do something
Speaker 6:  functional. Here.
Speaker 5:  It is very good.
Speaker 5:  Other car news, big study, EV owners don't like the
Speaker 5:  broken chargers and bad charging software surprise. More
Speaker 5:  importantly, the inflation reduction act was signed big
Speaker 5:  climate bill, lots of EV text credit news. And that bill on
Speaker 5:  the plus side, Tesla gets the credit again. They'd run out there only 200,000.
Speaker 5:  So Tesla had run out ages ago. GM had run out. I
Speaker 5:  think Ford was about to run out. They get it again. If the cars are made
Speaker 5:  in north America, if the batteries are made in north America after I think
Speaker 5:  20, 24. So that means like the Hyundai
Speaker 5:  ionic five does not get the credit anymore. It's hard. It's confusing. Lots
Speaker 5:  of freak outs in like various car forms about when you assign your contract.
Speaker 5:  Because if you sign your contract, you, if you have a written contract before
Speaker 5:  the date of the thing, you still get the credit. If you don't, you don't,
Speaker 5:  Andy Hawkins is a great explainer about it, which walking through it,
Speaker 5:  the really important piece of the puzzle though, is it's gonna push battery
Speaker 5:  manufacturing to the United States because car makers need the batteries
Speaker 5:  made here to get the credits, which I think is important. And the other
Speaker 5:  important piece of the puzzle, because of this written contract requirement,
Speaker 5:  all these like vaporware car pre-orders yes. Might go away.
Speaker 7:  Yes.
Speaker 5:  Which I think is super fascinating. Like knock on. I don't think anybody
Speaker 5:  was anticipating that this would be the knock on effect, but if you need
Speaker 5:  the contract before, like lucid is shifting from
Speaker 5:  preorder reservations to written contracts now, because they gotta lock
Speaker 5:  in the order to get people the credit before the,
Speaker 7:  Oh man, they're gonna get,
Speaker 5:  Or before the law goes
Speaker 7:  Effect, it's pass. So if these companies that are like shifting so that they
Speaker 7:  can make sure they get the money, don't ship the cars at a timely
Speaker 7:  fashion. Can they get the hell suit out of 'em by the customers?
Speaker 5:  I know it depends on what these, these written contracts.
Speaker 7:  Oh my God, that's fine. Right? So the, I mean, not for the car makers, but
Speaker 7:  like for me personally, I'm opposed to vaporware. Well,
Speaker 5:  See the, the game around the credits is like,
Speaker 5:  it's in a real limbo space right now. Like the law has
Speaker 5:  passed. No one really knows what it means. There's lots of attempts to figure
Speaker 5:  out what it means, how to get the credits at the same time. Ford right.
Speaker 5:  7,500 credit comes back for them, cuz they're not gonna hit the cap
Speaker 5:  anymore. They just raised the price of the truck by $8,000.
Speaker 7:  Cool, cool. Nevermind. I hate this. This is terrible.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So go read that explainer. If you are in the market for a car like
Speaker 5:  me and you can't find a car to buy like me, it's good. It's very helpful.
Speaker 5:  He, Andy definitely wrote the explainer cuz I was like, I don't what to do.
Speaker 5:  So thank you, Andy. And then last we have to call this one out
Speaker 5:  Dodge, dear suite Dodge, part of the FCA Solanis
Speaker 5:  worldwide conglomerate of car manufacturers.
Speaker 5:  They put out their first EV concept. So charger EV sick.
Speaker 5:  It has a fake exhaust sound. Like they were like muscle car buyers,
Speaker 5:  want loud cars. So we just put speakers in this
Speaker 5:  car that make it make loud sounds. And
Speaker 6:  It's the best. It's the best loud sound.
Speaker 5:  Andy Hawkins. When he wrote about it said it sounds like a line getting neutered.
Speaker 5:  And I think that is exactly right.
Speaker 6:  It's pretty good.
Speaker 5:  It's
Speaker 7:  Very
Speaker 5:  Accurate. Something else.
Speaker 5:  They're calling it a battery electric vehicle exhaust noise.
Speaker 7:  Can you turn it off?
Speaker 5:  It's I don't know.
Speaker 7:  I think somebody like is testing it at 2:00 AM outside my window
Speaker 7:  lately. I think I'm hearing it a lot.
Speaker 5:  The name is called the frat Sonic chambered
Speaker 5:  exhaust. No. What? Which can reach 126 decibels
Speaker 5:  making it as loud as a hell. Cat powered Dutch.
Speaker 6:  And am I, am I wrong for thinking that an exhaust is not
Speaker 6:  a thing that needs to exist on an electric vehicle? Am I crazy?
Speaker 5:  It's just speakers. Okay. I don't know what to tell you.
Speaker 5:  It is not an exhaust. It is just a button marked mega.
Speaker 7:  It is legit. Just somebody going as they drive down the road. Yep.
Speaker 7:  But with a really good speaker.
Speaker 6:  So instead of flipping up and hitting NAS, you hit the speakers.
Speaker 5:  And then also if you've ever driven, EV you know, they don't
Speaker 5:  have transmissions cuz they they're just electric motors.
Speaker 5:  The cool part of driving EV is like the instant torque at
Speaker 5:  every part of whatever Dodge decided muscle car buyers
Speaker 5:  need a transmission. So they've added a transmission. I'm not
Speaker 5:  sure how it works, cuz it it's like a confusing idea in an electric
Speaker 5:  car. So we'll see how it works. But they've given it a
Speaker 5:  name and the name is lowercase E yes.
Speaker 5:  R lowercase E I love it. And the name is lowercase E
Speaker 5:  capital letter, R U P T or erupt?
Speaker 6:  No, it's it's erupt.
Speaker 6:  What
Speaker 7:  If it's just like a game?
Speaker 6:  What do you think? VIN diesel thinks that's all I find myself wondering right
Speaker 6:  now is like, did, did van diesel get in the driver's seat to one of those
Speaker 6:  and go, this feels right? Like, is that, is that I just wanna know.
Speaker 7:  I hope it's in the next fast and furious movie and he is like, it could be
Speaker 7:  louder. And like part of the movie is them just trying to make it as loud
Speaker 7:  as possible. Well, he gets really good at the, the gear shifting game.
Speaker 5:  I'm just gonna read you this last paragraph from the CNBC piece KCU
Speaker 5:  he's the CEO of Dodge said some of the design elements and technologies are
Speaker 5:  expected to impact the range of the vehicle, but it's not something
Speaker 5:  Dodge is worried about. And then quote, I don't care. It's
Speaker 5:  badass. It's a muscle car.
Speaker 7:  That's right. That's that's what muscle car owners feel.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, you gotta, you gotta hit the mega base button to go five
Speaker 5:  miles on charge. It's
Speaker 6:  Good. I've been thinking that it's, it's a real bummer that with electric
Speaker 6:  vehicles, the world is gonna get quieter. So I'm really glad Dodge is out
Speaker 6:  here trying to solve that problem for us.
Speaker 5:  It's just a concept. No idea when it will ship.
Speaker 7:  I do like the gear shifting thing. That's fun. Like I was just reading
Speaker 7:  a story the other day from somebody about like how gear shifting is going
Speaker 7:  away and it's not gonna, like, it's gonna be a lost art
Speaker 7:  and these, these EV owners you'll be able to hear them coming and you'll
Speaker 7:  be like a heck guy, Alex,
Speaker 5:  Let me ask you straight up. Do you know how to ride a horse? Yes. You're
Speaker 5:  from Texas. Are you, are you an equestrian of anything?
Speaker 7:  I mean, I've ridden a horse one time. I rode it a gal. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I've ridden a horse too. Would you say you knew how to ride a horse?
Speaker 7:  I feel like it's not hard. You just like get up there, but it's different.
Speaker 6:  That's a no, from
Speaker 5:  That once upon a time, someone was like riding a horse is a lost art.
Speaker 5:  That's just where we are. Like the, the American
Speaker 5:  unicycle Alliance was like, these cars gonna replace uni
Speaker 7:  The part unicycle.
Speaker 6:  This also sounds like they're gonna just put a joystick in the middle of
Speaker 6:  the car that does nothing. Yes.
Speaker 7:  But that's the best part.
Speaker 6:  Make some rumbling noises every time you move.
Speaker 7:  I hope it changes
Speaker 6:  The audio. It's gonna make a bunch of people really happy.
Speaker 7:  They're gonna
Speaker 5:  All, let's try this up. The lighting round and runs erupted.
Speaker 5:  It's horrible. Lots of stuff in line around David, what you got,
Speaker 6:  We're definitely getting an explicit tag on this podcast.
Speaker 6:  I, the thing that jumped out to me the most was snap giving up on the
Speaker 6:  pixie drone. Aw. After, after just four months, this thing feels
Speaker 6:  like it just shipped 15 minutes ago because it basically just did.
Speaker 6:  And the it's kind of a sign of the times,
Speaker 6:  like it's, it's a tough economy. Everybody is sort of pulling back and finding
Speaker 6:  ways to cut down on spending. And like, I don't think anyone thought the,
Speaker 6:  the pixie drone was gonna be a huge revenue driver for snap anytime soon.
Speaker 6:  But if it's indicative of what this next phase is gonna look like,
Speaker 6:  where I think a lot of companies are gonna pull back on anything that feels
Speaker 6:  sort of extraneous as a person who likes gadgets and
Speaker 6:  technology and new things, it just kind of makes me sad. And I think we're,
Speaker 6:  we're gonna get a lot of companies investing in like a very small number
Speaker 6:  of relatively uninteresting things and trying to figure out how to
Speaker 6:  monetize all the stuff you already use and spending less time
Speaker 6:  in the very near future, trying to invent new stuff. And I kind of think
Speaker 6:  that's a bummer. I was never gonna buy a pixie drone, but it's the kind of
Speaker 6:  thing that like, I like that it exists. And I like that snap is the kind
Speaker 6:  of company that makes this stuff. So it's just a bummer to see it give up
Speaker 6:  so fast.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I, I think the flip side of that is one of the big companies
Speaker 5:  look inward in that way. It just creates a lot of
Speaker 5:  opportunity for other companies to make interesting things and not worry
Speaker 5:  that, you know, we are gonna make a camera drone and then like
Speaker 5:  Facebook will make one and kills. Yeah. And so I'm hopeful that there's a
Speaker 5:  little bit of that dynamic in the future where you see the smaller companies
Speaker 5:  do interesting things, cuz it's easier to differentiate when you know, the
Speaker 5:  big companies are focused on monetizing app.
Speaker 6:  That's fair. I think that's, I think that's right. And I hope that is true,
Speaker 6:  but I do think there is a decent chance we're headed into a weird
Speaker 6:  time for hardware. Like supply chain stuff continues to be wonky.
Speaker 6:  Hardware is hard and expensive. There's like people are buying less and less
Speaker 6:  of that stuff. So I, I'm gonna be curious to see what the next like
Speaker 6:  12 to 24 months looks like in terms of interesting new hardware.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Okay. Here's my line around one. It's very good. This is a
Speaker 5:  journalism story in its core, like a perfect journalism story.
Speaker 5:  So there's this platform called trier, which you probably
Speaker 5:  don't know about. It's a TikTok clone run America. They're doing okay.
Speaker 5:  They like raised a bunch of money. They caught some audience. The Dios are
Speaker 5:  involved in some way.
Speaker 6:  Do you guys remember when all the TikTok Trump stuff was happening? And there
Speaker 6:  was,
Speaker 5:  Was like,
Speaker 6:  Come to us, like's gonna die. Were the new TikTok let's go.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And so they raised a bunch of money that time. They spent some of that
Speaker 5:  money on versa, which was a pandemic sensation
Speaker 5:  run by Timbaland and Swiss beats who are megastar hiphop. It's still good.
Speaker 5:  I can't, if you don't, I can't believe I explained don't you don't need to,
Speaker 5:  if you're listening to this, then you don't know Tim like go educate yourselves.
Speaker 5:  I mean, they like created the sound of like at least a decade and a half.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So they paid and they had sold versa. They had licensed
Speaker 5:  it like apple music was streaming versa. It was just them calling their famous
Speaker 5:  musician friends together. And like they would play their songs at each other
Speaker 5:  and talk shit. Yes. And it was great. It was like, it was great. Incredible.
Speaker 5:  It was like, it's really fun to watch. So they sold it to versa.
Speaker 5:  They sold it trier or they sold, they sold. Yeah. They sold versa
Speaker 5:  to trier. And now they're suing trier cuz they say trier owes them
Speaker 5:  28 million and never paid to, to date. Defendants
Speaker 5:  trier have failed and refused to any payment to Timberland and Swiss beats
Speaker 5:  for the past two sums blah blah, blah. Right.
Speaker 5:  Great trier. This is the journalism story part. So that's very funny cuz
Speaker 5:  you know, upstart social platform with no real money, forgot to pay the
Speaker 5:  superstar about producers, funny as face. So we report on this, we get the
Speaker 5:  lawsuit rather complete. We asked trier for a statement.
Speaker 5:  So Mr. Off, who's on asked trier for statement. They reply
Speaker 5:  from an account. That's just like press@triller.com.
Speaker 5:  And it's like, the statement is just on its face. Like not like hilarious.
Speaker 5:  We do not wish to air our dirty laundry in the press, but we have paid SW
Speaker 5:  to millions in cash in stock. No one has benefited mushroom Triller to date
Speaker 5:  Triller helped fuel versus to new Heights, which is just not true. It was
Speaker 5:  already at the Heights like apple music is streaming. The thing it's already,
Speaker 5:  it was already a global cultural phenomenon before sch showed up and they
Speaker 5:  said we made it whatever we hope it's just a misunderstanding. So
Speaker 5:  then we have this background policy where we don't now allow unnamed PR people.
Speaker 5:  So email back, this has to be on the record.
Speaker 5:  She gets even longer statement, which is like,
Speaker 5:  you can just read it. It's very long for it's like randomly capitalized.
Speaker 5:  The whole thing.
Speaker 5:  We think it's a legal shakedown. They have not delivered
Speaker 5:  any episodes of versa. We think their lawyers are over zealous,
Speaker 5:  whatever. It's just like, ah, it's the random capitals are really good. No,
Speaker 5:  no sign though. They still haven't signed it. It came from a different email
Speaker 5:  address from outlook.com and at the bottom it
Speaker 5:  just says, Ryan
Speaker 5:  trier co-founder is stamped Ryan Kavanaugh. So he just like reply
Speaker 5:  like, is this is this you? And they just stopped
Speaker 5:  responding. So we put up this story, we're like, here's what happened? Like
Speaker 5:  here's the sourcing tribute to what you will, we're try to transferring about
Speaker 5:  this. So then they responded yesterday with
Speaker 5:  another version of the second statement, elevating the amount paid to
Speaker 5:  55. Now they're claiming 55
Speaker 5:  billion. Now they're saying this statement can be attributed to our CEO
Speaker 5:  and chairman mahi DeSilva, which they
Speaker 5:  misspelled, which is just perfect.
Speaker 7:  You know, which like when you're out having a good time and you
Speaker 7:  see, you need to respond to the email and you grab your phone and you have
Speaker 7:  to push your drink aside and get it all spelled out. You'll have time
Speaker 7:  to double check the day of your boss.
Speaker 5:  I mean, it's just, it's like the whole time was like, oh, this is why I had
Speaker 5:  this policy.
Speaker 5:  Like we made all this noise about like having you on the record. It's like,
Speaker 5:  because at the end of the day, it's, it's just someone foiling and
Speaker 5:  I dunno, it's good. Hopefully Tim and SOS get paid. They're more important
Speaker 5:  to our culture than thriller. That's that's my position. It's not a position
Speaker 5:  of the verge.com, but I'm confident that if you pulled the staff of the verge.com
Speaker 5:  and asked them who is more important to the culture, Timbaland and Swizz
Speaker 5:  beats or thriller, they will agree with me. Yeah. It's pretty stressful.
Speaker 5:  Encourage someone to
Speaker 7:  What if they misunderstand it as thriller?
Speaker 5:  I think thrill thriller is more important to the culture than thriller
Speaker 5:  name a Michael Jackson song that is less important to the culture than,
Speaker 5:  than thriller. And you
Speaker 7:  Cannot do it. No, it's impossible.
Speaker 5:  All right, Alex, what you got?
Speaker 7:  So Jess weathered, who's one of our new news writers. She's based out in
Speaker 7:  the UK. She wrote about the absolute goofiest
Speaker 7:  set of monitors that are just like two monitors stacked on top
Speaker 7:  of each other and they just, just close up and, and
Speaker 7:  somebody's just like, yep. This, these two very cheap
Speaker 7:  crummy monitors cuz they're, they're both like 1440 P
Speaker 7:  75 Hertz refresh 300 knits brightness. These are not
Speaker 7:  super, super fancy, nice monitors. But I think like the
Speaker 7:  gimmick is that they're on a cool stand so you can close them at the end
Speaker 7:  of the day and then slowly open them up and they
Speaker 7:  just crack me up. I just keep looking at like, there's a GIF in, in this
Speaker 7:  story she wrote and it just keeps the guys just so happy to like just
Speaker 7:  quietly open those monitors and appreciate his monitors. But
Speaker 7:  it's called gems. There's two versions. There's gems. And there's the
Speaker 7:  gems X.
Speaker 5:  Yes.
Speaker 7:  That gives you 1440 P the gems is just 10 80 P at 60 Hertz,
Speaker 7:  250 net brightness. These are like the hundred dollars
Speaker 7:  monitors that you get when you buy like a Dell desktop
Speaker 7:  from 1998. It's those monitors. And they've just
Speaker 7:  like, I mean, I don't know if it's actually those monitors caveat. It may
Speaker 7:  not be those specific monitors, but it's basically those monitors just
Speaker 7:  like, and you just open it up and I just really appreciate Jess is out there
Speaker 7:  writing about it,
Speaker 6:  But like they didn't even do anything to them. Yep. They just added hinge
Speaker 6:  the back. Like they just put two of them together, like super door hinge
Speaker 6:  and that's it.
Speaker 5:  You gotta look, read the story and look at the gift of this dude, opening
Speaker 5:  this monitor. It is incredible. I dunno how to describe this to you.
Speaker 6:  It's fantastic.
Speaker 7:  It's stacked as, as the, the video says,
Speaker 5:  I mean just the, he's got a, he's got a big, you know, top gun mustache.
Speaker 5:  He's got long hair and he's just grinning at unfolding this honor.
Speaker 5:  It's very good.
Speaker 7:  It's very good.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Nothing says it's time to go to work. Like unfoldings
Speaker 7:  Well, it's it's crowdfunded.
Speaker 5:  I don't care what she said. It's crowdfunded.
Speaker 7:  So you might be better off. Just go buying too.
Speaker 5:  I'm I'm crowdfunding the whole thing. What's the goal. Is it $10? I'll give
Speaker 5:  it to him,
Speaker 7:  But it's incredible. I love it.
Speaker 5:  That's great. All right, David, last one. I need you to explain to me what's
Speaker 5:  going on in sports streaming. Cause it sounds like we have to care about
Speaker 5:  peacock now. Disclosure,
Speaker 5:  NBC universals investor in Fox media. But I feel like I just said, we have
Speaker 5:  to pay attention to peacock. Now you should understand the tenor of that
Speaker 5:  relationship. Go ahead,
Speaker 6:  David. We also made a show for Netflix, but that's not important to this
Speaker 6:  particular discussion.
Speaker 5:  Yes, my good friend and co-founder works at Google. What more do you want
Speaker 5:  for me?
Speaker 6:  Most of you should stop listening now because this explanation takes four
Speaker 6:  and a half hours. Basically the big 10, which is a big
Speaker 6:  sports
Speaker 7:  College,
Speaker 5:  Many more than 10 property
Speaker 6:  Teams.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. There's like 35 teams in the bid. Like half of college teams
Speaker 6:  in America are somehow in the big 10 now, but basically they signed this
Speaker 6:  big new deal for their streaming rights is $8 billion of the next seven
Speaker 6:  years. And these are the moments where basically
Speaker 6:  all of these leagues and conferences and whoever get to decide
Speaker 6:  like what we want the future to look like. So like I personally care a lot
Speaker 6:  about these because they decide a lot about what the near future of television
Speaker 6:  is gonna look like. And the big 10 picked like a
Speaker 6:  real sucky way to do it. As far as I'm concerned for the future, they basically,
Speaker 6:  they, they divvied games up between NBC, CBS, and Fox. Some of them
Speaker 6:  will stream some of them won't it's total chaos. What's gonna be where there's
Speaker 6:  also the big 10 network, which will have some games. Peacock just randomly
Speaker 6:  gets eight games that aren't gonna be anywhere else. Like this is just not,
Speaker 7:  Are they gonna make an app?
Speaker 6:  This is just not a good system. And it's like, like
Speaker 7:  An app to just, no, the big 10, the big 10, this is
Speaker 6:  Who's gonna make an app. There's
Speaker 5:  There's you see one
Speaker 6:  App for the big 12 apps, the big 10. So the big 10 has the big 10 network
Speaker 6:  and that will have some games. You would think that if you got the big 10
Speaker 6:  network and paid what it costs, no, that you would be able to watch all the
Speaker 6:  big 10 games on the big 10 network. You'd be wrong
Speaker 6:  because this is the world that we live in. And then it's like, we're just,
Speaker 6:  we're just in this place where sports dictate how all of this stuff works
Speaker 6:  because that's where all the money is. And the big 10 at least is still making
Speaker 6:  this gigantic bet that cable TV is gonna keep mattering for a long time.
Speaker 6:  Which was very funny because the other thing that also happened today was
Speaker 6:  there was a study released that said streaming more people
Speaker 6:  watched streaming TV than watched linear TV for the first time ever.
Speaker 6:  So like, this is, this is a, a thing running
Speaker 6:  against the actual trend of where the world is going, but there's still a
Speaker 6:  lot of money in selling your stuff to, well,
Speaker 7:  Don't worry. NBC
Speaker 6:  Broadcast
Speaker 7:  Channel it's coming. It's gonna change everything.
Speaker 7:  Streaming is streaming. You're looking down a barrel. It's almost
Speaker 7:  over.
Speaker 5:  I feel like the phrase you're looking down a barrel is less threatening than
Speaker 5:  the actual cliche. What
Speaker 7:  Cliche? What is the actual cliche? No, it's not. What
Speaker 5:  Is it? It's the barrel of a gun. Yeah, you're looking like just a like,
Speaker 5:  oh yeah. Someone looking at a barrel is not inherently
Speaker 7:  Threatening. I was thinking, I was thinking of the gun when I said it. I
Speaker 7:  just didn't wanna, you know, a economy of words.
Speaker 5:  Oh look a barrel. You're looking at a barrel.
Speaker 7:  Well, they're not, they're not, they're not winning at broadcast television.
Speaker 7:  If they're looking at a barrel, they're too busy. That's true. They're very
Speaker 7:  busy.
Speaker 5:  If you don't get your shit together, you'll be looking at a barrel.
Speaker 5:  I mean, in a way it works.
Speaker 7:  That's how I start all my threats. Now
Speaker 6:  That's intense.
Speaker 7:  I'm hide.
Speaker 5:  All right, we'll come back next week. We'll do a full hour on FireWire
Speaker 5:  800. What happens next?
Speaker 7:  It also looked at a barrel
Speaker 5:  In ATSC 3.0 it did look at a barrel.
Speaker 5:  He got all the way in the barrel.
Speaker 5:  All right, that's it. That's the, Vergecast the Wednesday show this week.
Speaker 5:  Really fun earbuds test. I will say we got an email about the earbuds test.
Speaker 5:  David. The email was titled Jaybird's erasure,
Speaker 5:  which was not an email about the band erasure on
Speaker 5:  Jaybird headphones. So you gotta take care of that.
Speaker 6:  Ne can I tell you there's a reason for that? It's because I forgot that J
Speaker 6:  bird exists as a company. JBU has not made a pair
Speaker 6:  of headphones in like three years, but I used to love my
Speaker 6:  Jaybirds and we will, we will bring Jor back right
Speaker 5:  With Highwire I'm and broadcast television. Very good. That was really fun.
Speaker 5:  David and I talked about the F150 lightning. What was the third thing? I
Speaker 5:  should probably just scroll up and read it.
Speaker 6:  We answered a bunch of people's questions about in green Oxys. It's good
Speaker 6:  stuff.
Speaker 5:  I love taking the calls. What's the number to call in
Speaker 6:  Green bubbles. Eight sixty six verge. One, one. It is absolutely my favorite
Speaker 6:  thing about the Vergecast like, I love both of you, but it's way more fun.
Speaker 6:  Talking to the people who call the hotline. So eight sixty six version one,
Speaker 6:  one, call us, ask all your
Speaker 5:  Questions. Bunch of stories on site. James Vincent has
Speaker 5:  a big scoop about crypto.com laying off people, and then quietly laying off
Speaker 5:  hundreds of more people. Justine, actually bunch of cryp itself. Justine
Speaker 5:  has a story about carbon offsets for crypto. Then we got a
Speaker 5:  big feature. We didn't talk about much about how archive of our
Speaker 5:  own turned in this like fan fiction mega site. It's great. I
Speaker 5:  love it. Outta site. You can tweet at us. I'm at reckless Davids at
Speaker 5:  Pierce Alex's Alex, H Crans that's it. That's for chess.
Speaker 1:  And that's a wrap for Vergecast this week. We'd love to hear from you. Shoot
Speaker 1:  us an email@vergecastattheverge.com. The Vergecast is a
Speaker 1:  production of the verge and the box media podcast network. The show is produced
Speaker 1:  by me, Liam, James, and our senior audio director, Andrew marina,
Speaker 1:  our editorial director is Brooke mentors. That's it. We'll see you next week.