# Transcript
ID: 962a64f0-78c3-11ed-a49e-595208118ec9
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Kindle 15th anniversary and the problem with US broadband
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-7076994012194407509/8056328861140987212/s93290-US-4164s-1670701610.mp3
Description: This week on the flagship podcast of mounting TVs way too high in the hospital room:
The Verge's David Pierce chats with Russell Brandom about the state of US broadband, and what we learned from 22,000 people’s internet bills.
David also talks with Verge managing editor Alex Cranz about the Amazon Kindle's 15th anniversary, why the Kindle has been so successful, and maybe also why it hasn’t done more. Keep listening for Alex's review of the Kindle Scribe.
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we'd love to hear from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (6 ads detected)
Speaker 2:  Welcome to the Vercast, the flagship podcast of mounting TV's
Speaker 2:  way too high in hospital rooms. I'm your friend David Pierce, and I just
Speaker 2:  had a baby. As you're hearing this, he's about five days old. Everybody's
Speaker 2:  doing well. He has really strong opinions about PS4 and Xbox
Speaker 2:  and iOS and Android and which streaming service is the best, and you're gonna
Speaker 2:  hear from him a lot on this show at some point. I suspect thank you to everybody
Speaker 2:  who heard on the Friday show and sent me nice emails and tweets. I really
Speaker 2:  appreciate it. He is also the reason, this is one of the last episodes you're
Speaker 2:  gonna hear me on for a while. You're in such good hands with Liam and
Speaker 2:  Andrew and Eli and Alex and the whole Verge cast crew, but I'm gonna be gone
Speaker 2:  for a few months. I will miss you all terribly. In the meantime, we have
Speaker 2:  an awesome show for you today. We're gonna talk a lot about ebook readers
Speaker 2:  and Kindles because this is not only right around the 15th anniversary of
Speaker 2:  the Kindle, it's also the time that the Kindle scribe, which you
Speaker 2:  could argue is Amazon's most ambitious Kindle ever is coming out. So we're
Speaker 2:  gonna dig into what all of that means and whether the ebook market is
Speaker 2:  headed in the right direction. We're also gonna talk about a big study we
Speaker 2:  did with some partners where we got 22,000 people's internet bills and
Speaker 2:  tried to figure out what do you get when you pay for your internet? Are you
Speaker 2:  paying the right amount? Are you getting the right speeds? It's all a little
Speaker 2:  bleak and very interesting. All of that is coming up in just a second, but
Speaker 2:  it's just about checkout time for me. So I gotta go figure out how car seats
Speaker 2:  work and then try to steal everything from the hospital. This is the Vergecast.
Speaker 2:  We'll see you in a sec.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. So last year in partnership with Consumer Reports,
Speaker 2:  the Verge asked readers to share their internet bills. Basically
Speaker 2:  we wanted to find out how Americans are getting online and what it costs.
Speaker 2:  We ended up getting more than 22,000 bills submitted to us.
Speaker 2:  The Consumer Reports data team then spent over a year pouring through
Speaker 2:  all of that data and all of those bills because bills are messy and complicated.
Speaker 2:  And together we've assembled a kind of snapshot of how
Speaker 2:  much people are paying for internet access in the United States. Russell
Speaker 2:  Brandham worked on the verges end of that project and he's here to talk about
Speaker 2:  the findings. But before we get into it, I just wanna reiterate something.
Speaker 2:  You're about to hear us both say a bunch. This is not like
Speaker 2:  a scientific paper with peer review and a perfect study of
Speaker 2:  us broadband that's basically impossible to do for a
Speaker 2:  bunch of frustrating and important reasons you'll hear about as we talk here.
Speaker 2:  But this is still a big study and we learned a lot. So we're gonna get into
Speaker 2:  it anyway, let's go.
Speaker 2:  Hi Russell. Hi. Let's just start at the very beginning. So what was the idea
Speaker 2:  behind this big survey that we and Consumer
Speaker 2:  Reports and others did on people's I S P
Speaker 2:  cable bills? Yeah,
Speaker 6:  So there is not a lot of information
Speaker 6:  about the sort of state of broadband. And then to the
Speaker 6:  extent that there is, it tends to be about like coverage. Like is there
Speaker 6:  an accessible broadband connection in this county
Speaker 6:  in Nebraska or wherever the, a lot of the FCC data is
Speaker 6:  self-reported by ISPs and they kind of exaggerate. And so people have a
Speaker 6:  problem with that and I think a lot of people anecdotally probably
Speaker 6:  know about this that just the process of paying for the is
Speaker 6:  P like just paying for access varies a lot from service
Speaker 6:  to service and sometimes is a little like scammy and
Speaker 6:  weird,
Speaker 2:  Right? Sometimes it's also a lot scammy and weird. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  Data caps are the big one and we didn't quite get as much
Speaker 6:  information on that as we wanted from this, but we got
Speaker 6:  sort of general prices and we got a lot of information
Speaker 6:  about fees which like there are just a lot of fees
Speaker 6:  that are made up basically.
Speaker 2:  Right? Yeah. Okay. So I wanna get into all that but, so basically, what was
Speaker 2:  it, 22,000 people sent us their cable bill.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And that wasn't just us, that's consumer reports too. But we put a
Speaker 6:  big thing on the Verge and they put a big thing on consumer reports.com
Speaker 6:  saying like basically send us your, your internet bills. You know, there
Speaker 6:  was a whole secure system for getting them because there's a lot of private
Speaker 6:  information on there. And then also, you know, once they were in the
Speaker 6:  bucket there was a lot of like, we're gonna make sure that this isn't
Speaker 6:  accessible to just random Joe who works at Consumer Reports.
Speaker 6:  And so the process of getting the data from that many bills was
Speaker 6:  a whole elaborate thing that I did basically none of, so
Speaker 2:  I,
Speaker 6:  I always wanna give credit to the people who actually put in the legwork.
Speaker 2:  Okay. And so the, the hedge before we get into what we learned is basically
Speaker 2:  this is not a representative sample of Americans cable
Speaker 2:  bills because like you were saying, that essentially doesn't exist. Right?
Speaker 2:  And I think that's actually like important context behind all of this is
Speaker 2:  we talk a lot about US broadband and access and
Speaker 2:  prices, but the honest truth is we don't know The data sucks. Yeah. The data
Speaker 2:  that exists, like you said, is mostly self-reported. All of it is imperfect.
Speaker 2:  And I just think about it as like the best thing we have is like those maps
Speaker 2:  that T-Mobile puts in commercials where that's just like 98% of America is
Speaker 2:  pink and it's like I like I don't know what to do with that information as
Speaker 2:  far as I can tell on any of this. We don't have literally basically no more
Speaker 2:  granular information than that.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, absolutely. And I mean I think of it in some ways in terms of
Speaker 6:  like what phones should I buy? What TV should I buy? We
Speaker 6:  actually have pretty good information about like what
Speaker 6:  does this particular TV cost, what is a reasonable amount
Speaker 6:  to pay for a 36 inch TV this
Speaker 6:  year? Like we actually know that pretty well and if someone
Speaker 6:  comes along trying to charge another one, they have to put it up publicly
Speaker 6:  and we will be out there saying that TV is too expensive. Right? Right.
Speaker 6:  And it's just very hard to do a similar thing for internet
Speaker 6:  because we're so deep in the weeds of like
Speaker 6:  you just move in to your home or wherever
Speaker 6:  and it's, well who do I pay for internet? It's
Speaker 6:  this guy he's your only options for, for many, many,
Speaker 6:  many people. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Again, not representative sample but big sample. So we learned a lot of
Speaker 2:  useful information here. Let's start with price cuz I feel like that is kind
Speaker 2:  of the big question you should sort of explain how you look at the data cuz
Speaker 2:  you spent a lot more time with it, but to me the range seemed to go from
Speaker 2:  like slightly more expensive than it seems like it should be to massively
Speaker 2:  more expensive than it seems like it should be. That seems like the range
Speaker 2:  Americans live in.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, the sort of middle of our sample was
Speaker 6:  around $75, which I think as someone
Speaker 6:  who has lived many years buying us internet access
Speaker 6:  sort of sounds about right to me. I'm like okay, like that,
Speaker 6:  that's about as much as a person place that is much more than you would pay
Speaker 6:  in many parts of Europe. So this is a different survey, but there's this
Speaker 6:  survey that the Open Technology Institute did that we linked to in the piece
Speaker 6:  that looks at different places all around the world. Extremely expensive
Speaker 6:  in Hong Kong. Interestingly, I don't know why that is, it seems
Speaker 6:  like a densely populated island, so it can't be that expensive to live fiber,
Speaker 6:  but maybe interconnection is weird. Also
Speaker 2:  Everything's expensive in Hong Kong. I went there once and it was like the
Speaker 2:  most expensive vacation I've ever been on in my life. So it might just might
Speaker 2:  have something to do with that. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  But like large parts of Western Europe are much, much lower. And
Speaker 6:  so Paris, London, you're talking 30 or 40 bucks a month. So
Speaker 6:  I mean I think that is the basic thing of just like our
Speaker 6:  expectations are to pay a lot for broadband. I
Speaker 6:  was expecting, I mean I, I looked in the data thinking,
Speaker 6:  is there some class of people who are just paying 150 bucks a month
Speaker 6:  And that didn't really show up. It is true that there are like
Speaker 6:  six bills out of the 22,000 where people are paying more
Speaker 6:  than $200. Wow. Which seems obscene but also it's six
Speaker 6:  out of 22,000. Right. So like the high ends very
Speaker 6:  high. I maybe would be willing to believe that those people are, have
Speaker 6:  special circumstances or like are using some obscene amount of data or
Speaker 6:  they're just constantly sort of streaming in 4K
Speaker 6:  because they run a in-demand YouTube channel and it's just
Speaker 6:  extremely, I mean I don't, I don't know. Yeah. Do we have a lot of
Speaker 6:  YouTubers in the V Verge audience and they're eager to send their internet
Speaker 6:  bills. So true that, but yeah, I was not shocked by the high end.
Speaker 6:  I will say I, it was hard to look at it in a way where it's like actually
Speaker 6:  a, a significant number of people are paying like really
Speaker 6:  shocking amounts that didn't seem like it was happening.
Speaker 2:  Okay. And that's actually somewhat surprising now that I think about it because
Speaker 2:  a another thing that you guys dug into is basically how many choices people
Speaker 2:  have, right? And the, the thing we've railed on a lot on this show is that
Speaker 2:  most people don't get to choose their provider. You need broadband
Speaker 2:  internet. It's like th this is just sort of a a life critical thing now.
Speaker 2:  So it's actually to some extent surprising to me that some of these providers
Speaker 2:  are not out there being like, okay, well you don't have anywhere to go, we're
Speaker 2:  just gonna jack up the prices 40 bucks a month because what are you gonna
Speaker 2:  do?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, absolutely. I mean I also think one of the dynamics
Speaker 6:  that became clear, so we also did a survey of it, it was a little noisier
Speaker 6:  because like we were doing it by zip code and we're like what happens when
Speaker 6:  there's more than one provider in a zip code and the price does go down?
Speaker 6:  We're like, it's a statistically messy because of all the sample issues we've
Speaker 6:  been talking about. But you do sort of see the line going down and it makes
Speaker 6:  sense. The weird thing, so like you
Speaker 6:  need broadband but then what we're measuring is actually providers
Speaker 6:  and there's a lot of situations where there's a single
Speaker 6:  broadband provider but like Frontier DSL is out here
Speaker 6:  or you know whatever DSL provider and they're like, we can give you
Speaker 6:  something that will load a webpage. It's not like
Speaker 6:  really the modern internet speed. And again, I mean that's because
Speaker 6:  that's sort of, you don't have to run a whole fiber optic line over
Speaker 6:  to do it. Right. So I think that's a real pattern in like
Speaker 6:  US availability is that you'll have one good one and then a bunch
Speaker 6:  of crappy ones that are sort of bringing up the rear.
Speaker 2:  Got it. So and then maybe the bad ones, they don't keep the good ones fully
Speaker 2:  in check, but they're at least enough that it's like if my bill went from
Speaker 2:  $70 to $200, that's when you get a bunch of people who are gonna be like,
Speaker 2:  okay, I'll take, I'll take worse internet for a price I can actually afford.
Speaker 2:  So they maybe don't keep it all the way down but they keep it a little bit
Speaker 2:  in touch with reality.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I mean this is a, a sort of big open question is how much
Speaker 6:  they're actually helping us like having the DSL option out there. And I
Speaker 6:  also think another thing that I worry about
Speaker 6:  is, you know the big picture anti-monopoly claim is
Speaker 6:  if you only have one option then they're sort of in a
Speaker 6:  position of power and like they can charge a lot but that's not
Speaker 6:  the only way they could use that power. So the other thing you might see
Speaker 6:  is just like worse service. Hmm. That that I S P
Speaker 6:  doesn't have reason to kind of invest in a
Speaker 6:  good technician to come by when a squirrel chews through your fiber optic
Speaker 6:  line and your internet drops because they sort of know that people
Speaker 6:  in that region are gonna be customers no matter what. And so Right.
Speaker 6:  They can just let that slide, we'd have to do another survey to find out
Speaker 6:  if that's true. True. But I think that is kind of another place for that
Speaker 6:  energy to go.
Speaker 2:  That makes sense. That also brings us to the fees, which I think is the piece
Speaker 2:  of this that actually to some extent surprised me the most because like we
Speaker 2:  pay too much for not very good internet is kind of like an
Speaker 2:  unproven but sort of truism of like anybody who pays attention to this industry.
Speaker 2:  But you went and found that basically we are in addition to all of that just
Speaker 2:  getting nickel and dimed to absolute death. Like what, what did you
Speaker 2:  guys discover?
Speaker 6:  So we gave him a pass on equipment fees. We didn't do that. But this is another
Speaker 6:  thing that Vercast listeners I'm sure know well is that ISPs love
Speaker 6:  nothing more than to rent you a bad router. Ugh.
Speaker 2:  They love
Speaker 6:  It sort of indefinitely. Yeah. And it's like you're paying $5 a
Speaker 6:  month every month for a $15 router and that
Speaker 6:  is in some sense like it's bad and I don't wanna say it's your
Speaker 6:  fault, but you can buy your own router and you probably should
Speaker 6:  and you will, they will stop charging you the rental fee for the router if
Speaker 6:  you buy your own router.
Speaker 2:  Not probably by the way you absolutely a hundred percent should. Like if
Speaker 2:  you are listening to this now and you are renting your router, stop it. Like
Speaker 2:  go buy a router, they're on Amazon, they're very inexpensive, super easy
Speaker 2:  to set up. They all pay for themselves like within a year just go do it
Speaker 2:  bro. I promise it's worth it.
Speaker 6:  So those aren't even represented on the chart. Yeah but it's worth talking
Speaker 6:  about because then so the next level is data
Speaker 6:  caps, which are just bad. Like again it's sort
Speaker 6:  of fair play because they're telling you upfront like this is the amount
Speaker 6:  of thing but it is just not the way internet service should
Speaker 6:  work. No it's not the way any actual things that you use on the internet
Speaker 6:  work. And so that is represented in here because just
Speaker 6:  the fact that people are paying huge amounts for that is sort of
Speaker 6:  a big part of what the story of internet fees is. And then
Speaker 6:  the third thing is they will just make something up that
Speaker 6:  is like internet infrastructure fee, right? DNS services
Speaker 6:  because DNS is famously, if you use more of it, we need to charge you
Speaker 6:  more. Like it's just, I mean one, there's no reasonable relationship to the
Speaker 6:  amount this cost and the amount they're charging you. They're just sort of
Speaker 6:  made up. They named a cost of their business and they were like this is a
Speaker 6:  fee for that. And then also this is not how anything you buy works the line
Speaker 6:  we use in the pieces that it's like you bought a sandwich and they're like,
Speaker 6:  well there's a 50 cent mustard fee. It's like okay.
Speaker 2:  And you're like I don't want mustard. And they're like, yeah it's the
Speaker 6:  Fee I guess I'm paying for mustard. Yeah, you might if there's mustard
Speaker 6:  on the sandwich, you might just include that in the price of the sandwich.
Speaker 2:  No, to me this is like, so I just bought a car a couple of weeks ago and
Speaker 2:  we were sitting there buying the car talking about all the prices and there's
Speaker 2:  a certain set of things right that it's like if I want the leather seats
Speaker 2:  I'm gonna pay more money for that. Like I get that. Yeah but we didn't want
Speaker 2:  the leather seats. And then so we go through the whole line and then we get
Speaker 2:  to the end and it just says $899 processing fee. And I was like,
Speaker 2:  I literally was like we're we're just sitting here filling out paperwork
Speaker 2:  like what is the $900 processing fee? Like if it was
Speaker 2:  $9 I would've been like, okay, it like costs you money to store papers somewhere
Speaker 2:  but like 900 do and the guy selling us the car literally goes, I don't know,
Speaker 2:  that's just what the manager decides. I was like what are we doing here?
Speaker 6:  You don't wanna skimp on the processing because then a year later
Speaker 6:  your processing valve's gonna go out and you're gonna be right back in the
Speaker 6:  shop. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  It's exactly right And there's just nothing you can do about it because again,
Speaker 2:  like I needed a car, the guy knew I needed a car just is what it is. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  He literally goes My mom paid the processing fee. I was like that's true.
Speaker 2:  But anyway, these to me are like the most monopolistic thing that came
Speaker 2:  up in this whole survey because this is just the nonsense you can get away
Speaker 2:  with when there's nobody out there to do better.
Speaker 6:  I will also say, and this is like not to defend
Speaker 6:  enormous telecoms but
Speaker 2:  Bold strategy friend, I
Speaker 6:  Know this is like really like and the ver Verge cast listeners are like what's
Speaker 6:  he gonna say? You see at and t on the logo
Speaker 6:  or Xfinity or any of these huge companies And a big
Speaker 6:  part of what has happened, like at and t probably didn't
Speaker 6:  lay the fiber. They are corporate conglomerates, right?
Speaker 6:  And their is P holdings are conglomerates of other
Speaker 6:  ISPs. So some of it they laid the fiber but some of it, it's like
Speaker 6:  we just bought this business that was a smaller I S P
Speaker 6:  and we are in the process of at and tifying it.
Speaker 6:  But like sometimes that's a long process and so it's a
Speaker 6:  real patchwork. I'm not, I'm using at and t as example. Sure. Like they're
Speaker 6:  not especially like this but any big company you would think okay, there's
Speaker 6:  some basic standard of like the fees they're charging and the sort of service
Speaker 6:  setup and it's really a patchwork based on like
Speaker 6:  the legacy of what I S P used to
Speaker 6:  like how recently another I S P was operating
Speaker 6:  that network And like you have no
Speaker 6:  real way of knowing that. Which is also why like then they don't wanna
Speaker 6:  suddenly stop charging the fee and the ISP becomes unprofitable
Speaker 6:  but they committed to this thing. So like it's not that we could
Speaker 6:  find, this is why it was so important to sort of gather all of these bills
Speaker 6:  because the fees are really all over the place even within one company.
Speaker 2:  Interesting. Okay. So are there any good actors in
Speaker 2:  this space? Like is there anybody out there saying just because you know,
Speaker 2:  we either have to do right by people or we're in a position to,
Speaker 2:  or just because you know we're the rare good guy who gets into the I S P
Speaker 2:  space. Like is there anybody we found who it's like, you know, good job.
Speaker 2:  Random Midwestern, I S P,
Speaker 6:  This is my personal I S P.
Speaker 2:  Oh
Speaker 6:  Okay. And I would not say that my experiences have been
Speaker 6:  spotless.
Speaker 2:  If you're listening, please don't turn off Russell's internet.
Speaker 6:  But Optimum, we had more than 400 bills
Speaker 6:  and the average fee was less than $4. Hmm.
Speaker 6:  Which is like pretty good.
Speaker 2:  Whereas I think Xfinity, which is mine, was something like $31.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And that's more than 250 at and t is was high. But
Speaker 6:  in fairness we have to say we don't have a lot of at and t bills. Sure. So
Speaker 6:  it's like it was 25 bucks but it's only 11 bills. So like maybe someone
Speaker 6:  ran into a lot of data charges and we just got a weird sample of it. The
Speaker 6:  other one I would say, and I don't know a ton about this, but spark light
Speaker 6:  was 300 bills 4 0 1 decent stuff.
Speaker 6:  I, the other one, and this is a whole section in the piece
Speaker 6:  is satellite internet, the fees get really high cuz you have to buy a dish.
Speaker 6:  Sure. I mean that's the equipment fees. But then there's also like, I think
Speaker 6:  HughesNet is one of the big satellite operators and they have a, a lot
Speaker 6:  of like, again I would have to look into the HughesNet offerings, but the
Speaker 6:  average fee for the 20 HughesNet bills we have are like, it's like 70 bucks.
Speaker 6:  So, and I imagine that that has to do with the cost of operating
Speaker 6:  satellites and just like delivering intranet that way that like some of that
Speaker 6:  just gets rolled into the fees.
Speaker 2:  I'm glad you brought up the satellite actually because that is one of the
Speaker 2:  things that the people in this space see as like a potential equalizer,
Speaker 2:  right? That like maybe starlink ends up being everybody's
Speaker 2:  competitor or some of these other companies that satellite becomes the thing
Speaker 2:  where you don't have to lay new fiber, you don't have to deal with all of
Speaker 2:  the bureaucracy of bringing a cable competitor to a new neighborhood. Like
Speaker 2:  their Verizon is installing fiber on my street
Speaker 2:  and they're out there basically right now doing it. And I was like, oh, when
Speaker 2:  do you think it's gonna be live? And they were like, I don't know, we're
Speaker 2:  thinking like two or three years. And so it's like, well this is, this is
Speaker 2:  a whole thing. Whereas like in theory, right, starlink could show up and
Speaker 2:  scale pretty fast, but is there any sort of evidence for
Speaker 2:  optimism that satellite can start to do some of that good work people are
Speaker 2:  hoping it might do?
Speaker 6:  Again, this is tricky. Like I think the scaling fast bit in particular
Speaker 6:  is tricky because they have to like launching satellites is
Speaker 6:  harder than just putting wires in the earth.
Speaker 2:  I don't know, I think these dudes who have been on my street might disagree
Speaker 2:  without assessment but I It's true. You're
Speaker 6:  Probably still right. I mean yeah, but how long would they take if they were
Speaker 6:  launching things into space? So I don't, it's tricky. Like I think the big
Speaker 6:  hopes for satellite internet are largely like about the future that
Speaker 6:  like five or 10 years from now, this will be a much better way rather than
Speaker 6:  being like I can do this right now. You know, this was a survey of
Speaker 6:  what people are doing right now and almost no one is getting satellite internet.
Speaker 6:  Like the of the bills we got, we got like
Speaker 6:  two hundred and seventy, two hundred
Speaker 6:  seventy four satellite internet bills. So like I guess it's around 1%.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it's a little more than 1% but like that's really not a lot. And the
Speaker 6:  other thing is, and this is not gonna shock people who have considered
Speaker 6:  doing it, it's like not cheaper right now. Right? Right. So again, it's possible
Speaker 6:  that it will become cheaper in the future. I think that's part of
Speaker 6:  the idea. But they're also still in the process of building out the network
Speaker 6:  and they have to, they're investing in infrastructure still. So we're not,
Speaker 6:  I don't think anyone's expecting like huge reductions in the cost of
Speaker 6:  starlink in the next year. Actually this is the other one. So
Speaker 6:  41 starlink bills two others
Speaker 6:  with over a hundred. So ViaSat and HughesNet, and this is
Speaker 6:  part of the other thing is like Elon comes in and likes to pretend he invented
Speaker 6:  things starlink does have, they're doing a lower earth orbit thing and it
Speaker 6:  is like a technical advantage over the existing ones, but less than 20% of
Speaker 6:  the actual satellite bills we got were Starling.
Speaker 6:  Right? There are these other bigger providers who have been doing it for
Speaker 6:  a long time and I think are not as aggressively investing in infrastructure
Speaker 6:  and their service is also like not hugely
Speaker 6:  adopted and not wildly better than just terrestrial fiber.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, it's it's gonna be interesting to see if that goes from
Speaker 2:  like will it be readily available? Seems like if you've fast forward far
Speaker 2:  enough, like probably yes, will it solve these existing problems that we
Speaker 2:  have or just be another option that has all the same problems. I would also
Speaker 2:  say probably yes, but hey, maybe we'll be optimistic about it. Is there any
Speaker 2:  prognosis that comes out of this? Like is there anything we can sort of look
Speaker 2:  at and be like, okay, here is a, a problem with a solution or it
Speaker 2:  feels like in a lot of ways this just kind of confirms in a, in a real way
Speaker 2:  what a lot of people have kind of instinctively felt for a long time.
Speaker 6:  So like usually we talk about broadband and we're like, we need more fiber.
Speaker 6:  Like there are these people living in rural areas that can't get broadband
Speaker 6:  and then the telecoms say like, well it doesn't make economic sense to run
Speaker 6:  all this fiber all the way up to them. And, and we go back and forth and
Speaker 6:  it, it does feel like in some ways a political sort of stalemate. We
Speaker 6:  can pass laws about how bills are allowed to work.
Speaker 6:  And I will say they're one thing that's happening right now and this is out
Speaker 6:  of the FTC that we hear about like trying to break up Facebook and
Speaker 6:  Instagram and everything, but they also have much simpler things where they're
Speaker 6:  like, you can't, the rule about surprise billing
Speaker 6:  where you're paying like 40 bucks a month for six months and
Speaker 6:  then it gets suddenly you're paying a hundred bucks a month, is
Speaker 6:  they're passing rules about hey you can't do that. It's very easy to
Speaker 6:  imagine saying, okay, you can rent them a router,
Speaker 6:  you can charge data charges but you cannot
Speaker 6:  do fees beyond that. Those are the only kind of fees that are allowed. You
Speaker 6:  know, we, we wouldn't need an act of congress for doing that. FTC would just
Speaker 6:  have to say, we consider this anti-competitive, you're not allowed to do
Speaker 6:  it anymore. I'm sure we would have fun in the courts with that, but that's
Speaker 6:  like a real thing that could happen. And I think part of
Speaker 6:  the new kind of antitrust consumer protection push,
Speaker 6:  this is like the lower hanging fruit. So it's not as sexy as
Speaker 6:  breaking up Facebook and like, you know, requisitioning, they
Speaker 6:  want to take Mark Zuckerberg's dog and have him owned by the state and it's
Speaker 6:  not as sexy as that, but it is just in a very real
Speaker 6:  way, these fees are annoying. They make a lot of people's lives
Speaker 6:  worse in a very small way and it would be better if we
Speaker 6:  got rid of them. And I think that's if you will it, it is no dream.
Speaker 6:  We can live in that world if we want to.
Speaker 2:  I like it that plus buy your own router. We can at least make the world a
Speaker 2:  little better.
Speaker 6:  Take the lawn your own hands, that's how you can fight fees at
Speaker 2:  Home. Vigilante router ownership. I love it. All right Russell,
Speaker 2:  thank you. Appreciate it as always. Of
Speaker 6:  Course.
Speaker 2:  We're gonna take a break and then we're gonna come back and we're gonna talk
Speaker 2:  about Ein because this is the Verge cast and we like to talk about E Ink.
Speaker 2:  We'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. A couple of weeks ago was the 15th anniversary
Speaker 2:  of the introduction of Amazon's first ever Kindle.
Speaker 2:  It's kind of hard to remember now all these years later, but the first
Speaker 2:  Kindle was a big deal. It's really funny to listen to the videos
Speaker 2:  explaining how it worked from 2007 before anybody knew what
Speaker 2:  this thing was. When you want to pick a new book to read off of your home
Speaker 2:  screen, use your thumb to roll the cursor up or down and then press the select
Speaker 2:  wheel to make your selection. If you need larger letters, change the size
Speaker 2:  of the text by pressing the text key on the keyboard. There are six font
Speaker 2:  sizes to choose from. Use whatever works for you, big or small. The
Speaker 2:  Kindle had a big promise it was gonna change the way that we think about
Speaker 2:  book reading and even the way that books themselves work.
Speaker 2:  So after 15 years, did it, has the Kindle changed reader
Speaker 2:  behavior? Has it changed books forever? I wanted to talk about this with
Speaker 2:  of course Verge managing editor and eing super fan Alex Kranz.
Speaker 2:  Alex continues to be the only other person I've ever worked with who
Speaker 2:  thinks e-readers are interesting and she's right and so am I. They're
Speaker 2:  interesting. There's a lot to get into here. So let's just dive in.
Speaker 2:  Hi Alex.
Speaker 8:  Hello.
Speaker 2:  This is the most Alex possible vergecast segment. I could not be more excited
Speaker 2:  that this is what's happening here.
Speaker 10:  I'm very excited to talk about Ein.
Speaker 2:  So it's the 15th anniversary of Kindle. What was your first Kindle?
Speaker 10:  My first e reader was not a Kindle. Okay. It was the OG
Speaker 10:  Nook.
Speaker 2:  The OG Nook was very good. Underrated had
Speaker 10:  Like the light up screen at the bottom and everything. Loved that. But
Speaker 10:  my original Kindle would've been I think
Speaker 10:  maybe the OG Paper White. Okay. Because I, I was real nook
Speaker 10:  until then.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, there's a definite like how Barnes and Noble blew this
Speaker 2:  so badly story to be done at some point in the future. They're still making
Speaker 2:  nooks, which I think is sort of lovely and charming next
Speaker 10:  Week on the Verge Cast,
Speaker 2:  Eight hours on the new Nook. Yeah, so I think, I think we probably got
Speaker 2:  into it about the same time. The first one I remember having was the Kindle
Speaker 2:  Touch, which was like the first one that had a touchscreen. It just had
Speaker 2:  that little like hamburger menu button at the bottom. But everything else
Speaker 2:  was a touchscreen. And that was the first one I actually like plunked down
Speaker 2:  money and bought. And the thing I didn't realize, and this is one of the
Speaker 2:  things I wanna talk about here, was that by buying that Kindle, I
Speaker 2:  was signing myself up to only buy Kindles for the rest of my life
Speaker 2:  because the Kindle lock in is so, so, so, so
Speaker 2:  strong. And once you're in, you're in and there's no leaving. And I now
Speaker 2:  own, I don't know, hundreds of books on Kindle and I can't use another device
Speaker 2:  even if I want to. And it's 2011. Me was not aware of this
Speaker 2:  and yet here we
Speaker 10:  Are. I distinctly remember being very upset because I was like, I've got
Speaker 10:  all these books on my Barnes and Noble account, I can't, I gotta, I should
Speaker 10:  be able to transfer those over it. And then I found Collibra, which is one
Speaker 10:  of the most powerful and horrible pieces of software ever made. It's
Speaker 10:  ugly. It is a nightmare to use. I
Speaker 10:  hate it with a passion of a thousand sons but it works because
Speaker 10:  I took all of my Nook books and ripped the d r m off,
Speaker 10:  which is totally legal I'm sure. And put them all on my Kindle.
Speaker 10:  It's a lot hard. It's a little harder to do on the other way around. It's
Speaker 10:  possible but it's a little bit more of a
Speaker 2:  Hassle. It's messy And Amazon has never been particularly
Speaker 2:  interested in making it easy for you to leave the Kindle ecosystem.
Speaker 10:  Amazon makes it so easy to do so much, right? Like they make it
Speaker 10:  easy to just get the Kindle you, you turn it on, you download the book,
Speaker 10:  you read it, you're done. That's super super e easy. There's no like
Speaker 10:  weirdness there. If you ever wanna be like explore, you're like oh
Speaker 10:  don't wanna get a book from the library. Oh did somebody send me
Speaker 10:  something to read? No, no. Terror not allowed. You're just gonna be sad.
Speaker 2:  Well and that to me is like the sort of story of the Kindle. So I was going
Speaker 2:  back over all the, all the old Kindles and two things jumped out to me and
Speaker 2:  we, we can dig into whichever one you want to first. But two things jumped
Speaker 2:  out to me. One is that it's very odd that the very
Speaker 2:  first Kindle was by far the most
Speaker 2:  feature rich one. Yes. It had a headphone jack, it had a speaker,
Speaker 2:  it had an SD card slot, you could, it had always on 3G
Speaker 10:  The dial.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Like it was such a powerful thing and all they've done in
Speaker 2:  15 years since is just strip stuff away. And I kind of
Speaker 2:  get why. But I also think that's a bummer. And then the second thing that
Speaker 2:  jumped out to me was that Amazon, it appears never for
Speaker 2:  one second invested in Kindle software. Like it is insane
Speaker 2:  to me how similar it is to what it was 15 years ago on all parts.
Speaker 10:  Amazon doesn't really invest in software across the board, right? Because
Speaker 10:  like you go and you use Good Reads, which is the defacto
Speaker 10:  book tracking software website, whatever you wanna call it that we
Speaker 10:  all use, I now use Story Graph more cuz it's prettier and does the job better
Speaker 10:  and is not owned by Amazon. Yeah But like they bought it and they're like
Speaker 10:  we got it all right. And it feels like the same thing with the Kindle. They're
Speaker 10:  like okay we designed it, it works. We're out to the point that like
Speaker 10:  when they did the merging with Comicology and they merged the two
Speaker 10:  stores and and libraries together, now
Speaker 10:  I go to read a book and it's just like would you like to read this Superman
Speaker 10:  comic you bought three months ago? Cuz that's what we're gonna suggest You
Speaker 10:  read right on your, your beautiful Kindle. It's not a good experience by
Speaker 10:  the way.
Speaker 2:  No, it's terrible. Well and the comics is is a real bummer actually because
Speaker 2:  there have been a couple of moments where Amazon had a really
Speaker 2:  like interesting opportunity to try new things and I think to
Speaker 2:  some extent the the like reason it has gotten less future rich over
Speaker 2:  time I think is because the goal is to have it for reading, right? Like
Speaker 2:  Amazon is crystal clear about this and and Dave Limp even said though to
Speaker 2:  us on this show not that long ago, that like they are not trying to build
Speaker 2:  an iPad, they're not trying to build anything other than a device for reading.
Speaker 10:  And I think that's the right call by the way. I think that's actually like
Speaker 10:  having done the devices that do everything, I totally think this
Speaker 10:  thing just does Reading is the perfect call.
Speaker 2:  Yes. But, but
Speaker 10:  Yeah
Speaker 2:  It just as reading I think is like a slightly larger umbrella than
Speaker 2:  the things that Amazon covers.
Speaker 10:  Just as Amazon's idea of reading. Great.
Speaker 2:  It's for reading.dot dot books on Kindle that
Speaker 2:  have been there for 15 years and no one has touched since because it's like
Speaker 2:  I, I wrote this story five years ago about on the 10th anniversary about
Speaker 2:  like when is Amazon gonna follow through on its promise of like reinventing
Speaker 2:  books? And they've sort of intermittently tried, there was like the Kindle
Speaker 2:  singles thing and there was the Kindle cereals thing and those were basically
Speaker 2:  just shorter books.
Speaker 10:  Remember when they tried to like say just do your fan fiction and we'll
Speaker 10:  give you money for it. Yeah, exactly. And then everybody was like, copyright
Speaker 10:  sir, please
Speaker 2:  I wish they had tried harder. Like could have been great. Like what if every
Speaker 2:  book you read was also like a wacky exploration through the world of the
Speaker 2:  fan fiction of that book? That'd be so fun. I'm into that. Yeah. But then
Speaker 2:  there have been these moments and I think comics is like the most obvious
Speaker 2:  one where to just say we are going to faithfully reproduce what it
Speaker 2:  looks like on a piece of paper is actually like an unimaginative version
Speaker 2:  of the future. And they could have done so many cooler things with comics
Speaker 2:  and they just didn't. And I feel like it drives everyone insane. But
Speaker 10:  It was wild because Comicology, I mean we could turn this entire thing into
Speaker 10:  a rant about Comicology, but Comicology actually did do more right When
Speaker 10:  Comicology app first came out you would read a comic comic book and it would
Speaker 10:  actually be like, okay we're gonna zoom in on this panel and then we're
Speaker 10:  gonna swipe over to this next panel and it would give this additional movement
Speaker 10:  to it and and tell you exactly where your eye needs to go. And that was
Speaker 10:  really exciting and fun. And then when this merging completed earlier this
Speaker 10:  year, they were like, no, no, no, no that's all gone. You read it like a
Speaker 10:  book because this is the Kindle way
Speaker 2:  Which is so it's just weird. Like there there's a
Speaker 2:  religion on the Kindle team that I think is just wrong in that particular
Speaker 2:  case.
Speaker 10:  I think it's partially a religion and I think it's partially a symptom
Speaker 10:  of when you are the biggest player when like the closest
Speaker 10:  competitor in the United States is Cobo, which most people don't
Speaker 10:  know and Barnes and Noble, which most people forgot sells e-readers.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Barnes and Noble's just an empty store at the mall.
Speaker 10:  There's not a lot of competition, there's not a lot of need Right. To go
Speaker 10:  do more because the big competition is happening in other markets that
Speaker 10:  Amazon doesn't really participate in and it doesn't need to. And so it's
Speaker 10:  like, yeah, why do I need to go do all this weird wacky stuff? Why spend
Speaker 10:  the resources on that?
Speaker 2:  This is one of those interesting cases where like I really wish there had
Speaker 2:  been meaningful competition because I think there's so much interesting
Speaker 2:  stuff to do in e-book creators and I also wish there were more competition
Speaker 2:  on the like E Ink and EPA screen side of things because I think that has
Speaker 2:  also held this whole industry back.
Speaker 10:  It's just one company. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  That's exactly right. They're like what if there were other people making
Speaker 2:  this kind of thing instead of just this one unbelievably slow
Speaker 2:  moving company that doesn't seem to be able to ship its good ideas in any
Speaker 2:  kind of meaningful amount of time. And so I think that has held Amazon back
Speaker 2:  its ability to do whatever it wants because it just decimated all
Speaker 2:  of its competitors basically immediately has held it back. And then there's
Speaker 2:  this thing where I think they decided early on
Speaker 2:  that they don't wanna make money on the Kindle, they just wanna make money
Speaker 2:  on selling you stuff through the Kindle. So they yeah basically got to a
Speaker 2:  point where it was like okay, we have to make this thing as cheap as physically
Speaker 2:  possible such that more people will buy it such that we can sell them more
Speaker 2:  stuff and put all three of those two things together. And it's like of course
Speaker 2:  they haven't really innovated in any meaningful way. Like why would
Speaker 10:  They, it's a bummer because it feels like, you know there's the TV brands
Speaker 10:  and there's a lot of TV brands and the one TV brand you never buy is
Speaker 10:  the best buy in-house brand Insignia. Cause it's
Speaker 2:  Like
Speaker 10:  So mediocre that you're just like, well it does the job but what what
Speaker 10:  cost?
Speaker 2:  Right. It is technically a television. It
Speaker 10:  Feels like sometimes with the Kindle that Insignia one
Speaker 10:  like what if all the other TV brands went away and it was just Insignia
Speaker 10:  And so you're like does the job but couldn't it do more? And
Speaker 10:  we've seen that. We've seen it from, we've seen it from Cobo, we saw the
Speaker 10:  original Nook, we've seen it from a lot of these Chinese companies and and
Speaker 10:  German companies like Pocketbook. Like there's more to it and Amazon's
Speaker 10:  just doesn't have interest in that. But it still makes a nice device a good
Speaker 10:  enough advice.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I mean this is the thing, right? Like I say all of this and yet I love
Speaker 2:  my Kindle. I have, I have the latest paper white and it is for the thing
Speaker 2:  that it does, it is terrific, right? Like I do wish it had a speaker
Speaker 2:  so that I could like put it down. One of my, the ways I use my
Speaker 2:  Kindle is I like, I will like read on the Kindle while I'm brushing my teeth
Speaker 2:  or whatever and being able to just be like, yeah play for the next 30 seconds
Speaker 2:  and like put it down on the sink and have it play out loud. Oh that would
Speaker 2:  be magic would be amazing, right? And it's like it's just sitting right there
Speaker 2:  and it drives me nuts. It's just right there. But, so this is the thing that
Speaker 2:  I've always had a hard time with with the Kindle is squaring this idea of
Speaker 2:  like, it's just supposed to be a reading device. They just wanna make something
Speaker 2:  that feels like a paper book and actually like paper books don't have
Speaker 2:  speakers so neither should Kindle. It's like fine with the idea that there's
Speaker 2:  actually all this other interesting stuff out there in the e-reader space
Speaker 2:  that Amazon should have done. So you have used all of these devices, like
Speaker 2:  are there things that you're like if they put you in charge of the Kindle
Speaker 2:  that you would just like lift off of other devices and be like, this needs
Speaker 2:  to be in the Kindle tomorrow.
Speaker 10:  The biggest thing that I like is, is the flexibility of other devices, right?
Speaker 10:  The reason I I keep going back to Onyx books is because they have a really
Speaker 10:  good version of an Android e Ink tablet, which means I, I don't just, I'm
Speaker 10:  not just stuck in Kindle's universe. I can use the Nook, I can
Speaker 10:  use Vis, which is like manga and stuff like that. I can go to
Speaker 10:  all these different apps and just enjoy them and I don't have to worry about
Speaker 10:  like, oh is that, is there a Moby version of this? Right? Like okay
Speaker 10:  I gotta go loading Collibra and like convert it and do all of that.
Speaker 10:  That's the biggest one. And I just don't see Amazon ever doing that because
Speaker 10:  yes we're gonna allow all of our competitors no matter how small onto our
Speaker 10:  device. That's never gonna happen. No, but I do think there's like
Speaker 10:  a thoughtfulness to these other devices with how the page
Speaker 10:  turning buttons work and how like it took how long for
Speaker 10:  Amazon to embrace u s bbc, right? It doesn't experiment with Color
Speaker 10:  E Ink at all. And like Color Ink is not in a place where it's
Speaker 10:  necessarily great but it
Speaker 10:  isn't a place where like having a big color e Ink
Speaker 10:  kindle for kids to read like picture books on Bernstein bears,
Speaker 10:  all of that stuff. That would be great. That would be like an instant winner.
Speaker 10:  And instead they're like how about for $99 we give you the
Speaker 10:  crummiest of Android tablets, just the
Speaker 10:  worst of the worst for your small children. And it's like, or I could
Speaker 10:  give them something for books and just books embrace the actual
Speaker 10:  Kindle ethos with these things. Yep. And so it's a bummer that they
Speaker 10:  haven't embraced it and they're not looking to these other companies and
Speaker 10:  and how they're doing these things and but mostly the companies, the big
Speaker 10:  differentiation is flexibility.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Well to me the middle ground there that I've always hoped Amazon
Speaker 2:  would do is basically give you a useful service for
Speaker 2:  sending stuff from the web to your Kindle. Yeah. And this is the kind of
Speaker 2:  thing that like it technically exists. I used Insta paper for a long
Speaker 2:  time and you could like send a digest of your Insta paper stuff to the Kindle
Speaker 2:  but it was janky and didn't look very good And they have a desktop
Speaker 2:  app that you can like download PDFs and upload them to your Kindle and that
Speaker 2:  doesn't work very well and it formats PDFs terribly and it's like what I
Speaker 2:  always wished Amazon would do is exactly what Cobo did with Pocket,
Speaker 2:  which is basically just, yeah integrate. You can just log into pocket
Speaker 2:  through your Cobo and read all of the stuff
Speaker 2:  that you'd saved on the web in this nice connected synced
Speaker 2:  interface. And that to me is like the simplest thing and the
Speaker 2:  absolute only reason I can think that Amazon hasn't thought to do it is because
Speaker 2:  it knows that's what people want. But it means they would probably buy fewer
Speaker 2:  books. And again that is the whole point of the Kindle is to just give
Speaker 2:  you a thing that is easy to buy books from Amazon because there is no chance
Speaker 2:  that a, they haven't thought of it. Somebody I guarantee has been like, what
Speaker 2:  if people could read the internet? Have we heard of the internet And
Speaker 2:  somebody shot it down because it would lead to fewer books being sold and
Speaker 2:  that's just the only way it possibly could have gone. And it drives me absolutely
Speaker 2:  up the wall cuz it's just, it's just right there.
Speaker 10:  Well and that's why like there's no really streamlined
Speaker 10:  library integration. The Cobo has a terrible That's so true. Library
Speaker 10:  integration by the way. Absolutely nightmarish. I had to help my mom set
Speaker 10:  it up from many miles away and talk to like
Speaker 10:  a librarian in Texas about it. It's
Speaker 2:  Terrible. And Cobos the one that is like proud of itself for this like Cobo
Speaker 2:  throws out of its way to talk about its library integr
Speaker 10:  This trash integration and Lippi knows that people
Speaker 10:  have Kindles and so it's like, okay well we're gonna actually baby step
Speaker 10:  walk you through how to put this on your, your Kindle.
Speaker 10:  We're gonna figure that out for you. And it's like, or Amazon could just
Speaker 10:  do that and they're not going to, because instead they want you to go and
Speaker 10:  buy Kindle Unlimited for every month and put your money
Speaker 10:  in that way. And so like they just constantly like to to gate keep.
Speaker 10:  It's a bummer.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. That's Amazon's whole thing. Like they're super customer first unless
Speaker 2:  you don't wanna buy from Amazon and then get outta your face.
Speaker 10:  Another thing though, I will say, I think that they haven't really embraced
Speaker 10:  it. I think they could and we're seeing it with the, the scribe, right?
Speaker 10:  Is welcome tablet, like that interface because
Speaker 10:  E ink, capacitive touch is a nightmarish thing
Speaker 10:  usually. Yes. You have to really, really tweak it cuz otherwise the time
Speaker 10:  from touch to actually seeing something on that really slow E ink display
Speaker 10:  is super, super long and laggy and you want to kill someone. And some
Speaker 10:  companies have figured this out like the, the Onyx books Leaf too, which
Speaker 10:  I've got a review of that coming up soon on the verge.com
Speaker 10:  has figured out that capacitive touch and made it a lot faster and made
Speaker 10:  it feel snappier. Not as snappy as welcome, but like snappy enough.
Speaker 10:  And Kendall really hasn't done that. Kendall is kind of like, oh yeah, you
Speaker 10:  can type on this but we're gonna make you regret it every
Speaker 10:  step of the way.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I remember. So I, I was listening to an episode of Ezra
Speaker 2:  Klein's podcast a while ago and he was talking about basically like how he
Speaker 2:  gets all his reading done and his thing was like, I read
Speaker 2:  basically exclusively on a Kindle, even if I own the paper
Speaker 2:  book, I will buy it on Kindle because it's easier to take notes that I can
Speaker 2:  then like search for and sync through. And I like really took that to heart
Speaker 2:  and I was like, okay, I too am gonna do this. Right? I wanna have all of
Speaker 2:  my highlights and notes in one place where I can search for them, I can find
Speaker 2:  them later. All this stuff I don't think I have ever once
Speaker 2:  typed out a note on my Kindle that was like not
Speaker 2:  full of typos. Like I it's just impossible.
Speaker 10:  Yeah. Horrible, horrible
Speaker 2:  Experience. Yeah. So now I have to go back through and be like, I typed herm
Speaker 2:  uwf like what did, what did that mean? It was a great idea that I
Speaker 2:  had when I was reading this. Like, all right, cool,
Speaker 10:  You have to like do a couple of steps, you're all right. Yeah. Gotta like
Speaker 10:  plan it pack in the time to interpret what you were trying to write.
Speaker 10:  And it shouldn't be that way. Like it is very, very easy to
Speaker 10:  make it smart, but that would require having a slightly more powerful processor,
Speaker 10:  which would increase the cost of the device. And they're like, no, we're
Speaker 10:  gonna put the most garbage processor in here. We're gonna put good enough
Speaker 10:  capacitive touch screen in here. Like we're gonna do just good enough
Speaker 10:  right across the board and if you want quality, go to China.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. So, okay, so the, the last thing I'm curious about is this
Speaker 2:  idea of like reinventing the book, right? And they, I think with
Speaker 2:  comics and stuff, like, I think we're very much on the same page that like,
Speaker 2:  there's actually a lot more they should do there. But I think for a long
Speaker 2:  time Amazon used to say to me at least that they had all these big interesting
Speaker 2:  ideas about like what a book should be, right? The idea that, oh, it's just
Speaker 2:  a collection of chapters in a row is like an outdated thing and now that
Speaker 2:  it's digital, what if you, what if it was rem mixable and what if you could
Speaker 2:  choose your own adventure through a book and people would read and, and a
Speaker 2:  different, and I, I've sort of gotten to the point where I'm, I'm done waiting
Speaker 2:  for that and now I kind of think like the Kindle will eventually just die
Speaker 2:  at the hand of print books and and we're just gonna go, we're gonna go
Speaker 2:  right back to where we started.
Speaker 10:  I don't think it'll die at the hand of print. I think it's, it's the internet.
Speaker 10:  I think Wattpad and Archive of our own are are
Speaker 10:  where we're seeing that kind of like future and we're seeing that experimentation
Speaker 10:  and we see it trickle down into mainstream books a
Speaker 2:  Lot. Wait, like gimme an example. Like what, what does that look like? I
Speaker 2:  think
Speaker 10:  One of the first examples I saw was when Wattpad and Archive of her own
Speaker 10:  were like, okay, all of our characters are our age and we are 17
Speaker 10:  year old girls writing these, these works of fiction and we text all
Speaker 10:  the time. And so for years when you go and read a book and texting,
Speaker 10:  it's like this person says this italics and it's
Speaker 10:  just like this brutal, excruciating thing to
Speaker 10:  read. And they understood, oh actually this is just how people talk.
Speaker 10:  And so I'll just say I text back and stuff or sometimes I'll do a, they'll
Speaker 10:  do a big text bubble and they'll go and they'll print it out including all
Speaker 10:  the different emojis that they wanna use and put that in there. And when
Speaker 10:  you watch that rendered on a Kindle, you're like Osh, yikes.
Speaker 10:  But when you look at it on the internet you're like, that's sick, that's
Speaker 10:  cool. I didn't even pause to think about it. I just kept reading cuz it
Speaker 10:  made sense.
Speaker 2:  I love that. And that feels like that's the kind of thing that I think is,
Speaker 2:  again, it's right in that zone for Amazon, right? Like it's, if people were
Speaker 2:  like, oh I wanna watch movies on my Kindle, like Amazon, I think it's correctly
Speaker 2:  gonna be like, no that's not what this device is for. But that thing you
Speaker 2:  just described, like that's, that's what books are, that's what books should
Speaker 2:  be like. Yeah, get there, get
Speaker 10:  There. But I I they're just when are they gonna do it? I think
Speaker 10:  it's only when people shout loud enough and they have to shout really, really
Speaker 10:  loud because how long have been people been shouting to improve good reads
Speaker 10:  to improve integration with these other services And Amazon hasn't done
Speaker 10:  it so they have to first listen and I don't know if they're ready to do
Speaker 10:  that.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, that is very fair. And I think the like big goal that they've always
Speaker 2:  had that it should just feel like a piece of paper and be something you can
Speaker 2:  like crumple and roll up and throw around is like exciting and awesome and
Speaker 2:  I desperately also want that. Yes. It's also not up to Amazon, it's up to
Speaker 2:  ein this one company that I am sort of done waiting for
Speaker 2:  to deliver this crazy vision to me.
Speaker 10:  We're starting to see a little bit of change there. Right. Okay. Like ein
Speaker 10:  is, is is starting to improve its development especially in the color
Speaker 10:  E ink space cuz I think that's really where it comes. Like they've hit kind
Speaker 10:  of their limit with black and white e
Speaker 2:  Ink. Like it looks very good now we did it, they
Speaker 10:  Did it like the refresh rate is still really, really bad compared
Speaker 10:  to an LCD screen. But like everything else is good. If they can improve
Speaker 10:  the color then they can come back to improve the refresh rate then I assume
Speaker 10:  they can get enough customers buying the stuff. Cuz right now their market
Speaker 10:  is like Amazon who's like, okay we need like a few dozen to
Speaker 10:  sell Kindles this year. A few of these other smaller ERI Inc companies
Speaker 10:  which are still really, really small compared to phones and tablet business,
Speaker 10:  like this is a very small business compared to them. And then like signage
Speaker 10:  folks, right? That's their customer base. And if you have
Speaker 10:  the resources of an Amazon or an Apple, you could go and invest
Speaker 10:  and really accelerate that development. But Apple doesn't
Speaker 10:  care because they have no interest in ein. And while I'm sad about that,
Speaker 10:  I also understand it. It makes
Speaker 2:  Sense. Yeah. We're on record about that one. Amazon
Speaker 10:  Should care more. They should be putting a lot more resources into this
Speaker 10:  and they aren't, they, they kind of just say, okay, you've got the new displays
Speaker 10:  in Cool. Give us like six months. They, they're really
Speaker 10:  slow on on when they adopt these new display technologies from EIN
Speaker 10:  and I just think it could all be a lot faster, but they would have to again
Speaker 10:  care and not be in this race to the bottom of the price.
Speaker 2:  Right? Yeah. There, there comes a time when you would have to invest in that
Speaker 2:  in a big way. Instead of sitting there and saying, we won this market, we
Speaker 2:  will sit here and collect whatever spoils there are. So, okay, so my
Speaker 2:  actual last question for you is, I have spent a lot of time over the years
Speaker 2:  basically using a Kindle a lot and then saying this is ridiculous.
Speaker 2:  Why do I just have this one device that just says this one thing when I also
Speaker 2:  have an iPad that does that one thing, not quite as well, but pretty well
Speaker 2:  and also 1 million billion other things, including all of the
Speaker 2:  other apps I want to use to read. And I was going back to, you know,
Speaker 2:  2007 and it's like they launched the Kindle into a world in which the iPad
Speaker 2:  did not exist. Right? And tablets just became such a
Speaker 2:  thing not that long after that that like, and Amazon has spent a lot of time
Speaker 2:  building its own tablets and making Kindle apps to support those tablets.
Speaker 2:  And they've said a lot of things about like, we can't control where people
Speaker 2:  read. We wanna be everywhere that people are. Are you And I like the last
Speaker 2:  two people left to think this is a good idea. Is everybody else just using
Speaker 2:  tablets and happy with it?
Speaker 10:  No, I don't think that's true. Right? There's a lot of people who go out
Speaker 10:  and buy these e-readers and they still care about them. And I think
Speaker 10:  it's really important if you wanna read a book, if, if you wanna like immerse
Speaker 10:  yourself in a book because the minute you get a notification you're taken
Speaker 10:  out of the book, the minute you're like, oh I want to just, we all get that
Speaker 10:  urge suddenly to just go look at TikTok or Twitter or whatever and, and
Speaker 10:  like just be like, okay, I've read oh my brain and go over to do this other
Speaker 10:  thing. And it's really, really nice to be like, no, my phone's actually
Speaker 10:  on the other side of the room or whatever and, and go back into
Speaker 10:  the book. And I think that's, there's also the, everybody talks about the,
Speaker 10:  the ease of it on your eyes. Why I, while I think there's zero
Speaker 10:  science to support that, especially as these all now have big front
Speaker 10:  lights on them that are glaring more light at you, it's still
Speaker 10:  really true that it's great to go outside and read
Speaker 10:  an e Ink device and it's miserable to go outside and try to
Speaker 10:  read an iPad. Especially cuz the iPad is also what, seven times more
Speaker 10:  expensive at this point? Something like that. Yeah. And if you can keep
Speaker 10:  like that E Ink super focused device still relatively
Speaker 10:  affordable, it makes sense to be like, okay, this is my, my, my
Speaker 10:  reader, this is what I'm gonna bring when I have to go sit in the doctor's
Speaker 10:  office. My tablet will stay at home cuz my tablet does other things, but
Speaker 10:  I'm going to sit in the doctor's office and wait four hours because
Speaker 10:  doctor's offices never keep appointment times I got my Kindle.
Speaker 10:  Yeah,
Speaker 2:  No, I think that's right. And I, I think the like big galaxy brain take on
Speaker 2:  all of this, right? Is that like maybe we're in a world where Twitter is
Speaker 2:  collapsing and people are starting to think about screen time and there's
Speaker 2:  this idea of like, oh, I maybe shouldn't just sit here and be bombarded by
Speaker 2:  all of my apps all day. And then there's the Kindle, which is this like beautiful
Speaker 2:  quiet space in all of our technology that is actually, and I
Speaker 2:  don't like, I think that's a, that's a life I'd like to lead. I feel like
Speaker 2:  in a lot of ways I'm a very like, aspirational Kindle owner. Like I sort
Speaker 2:  of look at it and I'm like, Ugh, I love books and then I like hold my Kindle
Speaker 2:  in one hand while I just screw around on my phone. But like,
Speaker 2:  it does sort of represent like a slightly better version of our relationship
Speaker 2:  with technology that I think for me has just always been very appealing.
Speaker 10:  Yeah, I, that's what I like the most about it. I, I've even gotten, you
Speaker 10:  know, I go and I get these Android e Ink devices, which has sensibly let
Speaker 10:  me do all of those things, but some of them really poorly, do not watch
Speaker 10:  a video on an e Ink device. Just don't it. You'll be sad. And, and the
Speaker 10:  more I use it I realize like, oh, it's actually nice to just go back
Speaker 10:  to this. Like, I've been connected to the internet since the mid nineties.
Speaker 10:  I've been online all this time and sometimes it's nice
Speaker 10:  to not have all the distractions and just be able to say I'm reading a book
Speaker 10:  and not worry about somebody texting me or, or whatever.
Speaker 10:  Like, we should embrace it more. And I don't wanna be start
Speaker 10:  some weird cult about this. I know a lot of people are always like, yeah,
Speaker 10:  I'm one of those people that logs off and is very performative and proud
Speaker 10:  of it. But like, I think it's good for everybody to sometimes log off and,
Speaker 10:  and think about that. And I think the Kindle is a really great way to like
Speaker 10:  still have that gadget, still have that moment where you're like, yeah,
Speaker 10:  I'm, I'm using the technology but also like not worrying about what
Speaker 10:  Elon Musk is saying on Twitter right now.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And if if he is saying it, it's, it's over there
Speaker 10:  So far over there. It's on the other side of the room. I have to like get
Speaker 10:  up. I have to pull the blanket off. No, too much work. Yeah, just keep
Speaker 10:  reading.
Speaker 2:  I hear that. All right, we gotta go but what, what are you reading? Recommend
Speaker 2:  something for the people.
Speaker 10:  Ooh, what am I reading? Nona The ninth. I am reading
Speaker 10:  Nona the Ninth. It is from Tamir
Speaker 10:  and it is the third in her series about
Speaker 10:  Neros in space. The first one, Gideon and the ninth won a bunch of
Speaker 10:  awards. The second one won some awards. This third one is a delightful
Speaker 10:  romp and I can't wait to see what happens or
Speaker 10:  what happens in the conclusion elect the ninth, which I think comes
Speaker 10:  out next year.
Speaker 2:  Nice. What
Speaker 10:  About
Speaker 2:  Yourself? I'm currently reading a book called The Travelers
Speaker 2:  came out a couple of years ago. I think it's by a guy named Chris, I think
Speaker 2:  Pavone or Pavoni or something. It's basically just like a super puy
Speaker 2:  spy novel, which it turns out is my absolute favorite thing to read. Like
Speaker 2:  yes, anything that involves like a, you know,
Speaker 2:  Renegade, former CIA operative who like
Speaker 2:  went out on his own but is still a good guy. Taking down the bad guys is
Speaker 2:  I'll just, I will read the infinity of those and there are infinity of them
Speaker 2:  and the travelers is really good. I'm a big fan.
Speaker 10:  Well I know what I'm doing next week.
Speaker 2:  There you go. Okay, we need to take a break, but then it turns out
Speaker 2:  we're not done with this subject yet. We'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  All right, we're back. So just to give you a little inside look
Speaker 2:  into how the verge cast sausage gets made. Alex and I recorded that last
Speaker 2:  segment a couple of weeks ago, right around the Kindle anniversary, but
Speaker 2:  then it turned out that Alex had her hands on the Kindle scribe, the
Speaker 2:  most ambitious Kindle Amazon has ever made the whole time. So
Speaker 2:  obviously we needed to talk about it. Is this the next big thing,
Speaker 2:  the revolutionary Kindle that Amazon has so far refused to
Speaker 2:  make for us is this the next 15 years of Kindle. So I called Alex back to
Speaker 2:  ask all these questions. Hi again Alex. Hi. So you had a
Speaker 2:  scribe the whole time we were talking about the scribe the
Speaker 10:  Whole time.
Speaker 2:  That makes me so angry. Like for in, in ways I can't even describe
Speaker 2:  like the rage that I feel in not knowing the whole time
Speaker 10:  I had to keep a secret, you know, I had to respect agreements. Yeah, I really
Speaker 10:  wanted to keep it to myself. I didn't want anyone else to know about it.
Speaker 2:  So let, let's just like lay the land of the scribe because I think my
Speaker 2:  impression of it, I talked to a couple of people at Amazon before it came
Speaker 2:  out and then like I wrote sort of the like look a thing, it exists story
Speaker 2:  and my take on it was basically like this is a big
Speaker 2:  moment for Amazon. They're trying to do like the newest thing with the
Speaker 2:  Kindle. They've done like kind of since the first Kindle, right? Like am
Speaker 2:  I, am I over-hyping this thing to come in here?
Speaker 10:  No, no, I don't think you are. I think this was like a really big moment
Speaker 10:  for the company. I think there was a lot of enthusiasm within the company
Speaker 10:  with people I spoke with about it and, and people were really excited about
Speaker 10:  it. But it kind of is also a product of
Speaker 10:  Amazon and all of the, the annoyances we typically
Speaker 10:  have with Amazon. It not ta paying enough attention to software. It kind
Speaker 10:  of just shoveling things in your face and, and not making any effort to
Speaker 10:  improve experiences is there in this product. And it was just
Speaker 10:  kind of like a bomber in that respect
Speaker 2:  That seemed to be the takeaway, right? Is that like Amazon did
Speaker 2:  roughly what you would expect, which is like make a pretty
Speaker 2:  good e-reader. But like I, I got the sense reading your review that you,
Speaker 2:  you left kind of disappointed even though it's like it's a pretty good thing,
Speaker 2:  but it wasn't what you wanted us to be or what it could have been.
Speaker 2:  You
Speaker 10:  Know, I really wanted to temper my expectations coming into it because I
Speaker 10:  do have a very strong like feelings about Amazon as a company and how Amazon
Speaker 10:  has handled a lot of its products in the past. And I, I tried to like ignore
Speaker 10:  that when I was coming into this device and if I was gonna go get
Speaker 10:  a note-taking device for my mom tomorrow, she suddenly
Speaker 10:  said I want one, I probably get her this because it works well
Speaker 10:  enough. Okay. But it, there's a lot of other stuff out there and it
Speaker 10:  doesn't come anywhere close to being as good as those other products.
Speaker 10:  It's simply like it's Amazon's take on this. So it's just like,
Speaker 10:  did
Speaker 2:  It, but like gimme the, gimme the vibe of it because I imagine like, because
Speaker 2:  you've raved about it a bunch, I got a remarkable just to goof around with
Speaker 2:  and play with. And I have to say the the like feel of taking notes on that
Speaker 2:  thing is so much better than I expected it to be. Just the the like the way
Speaker 2:  it actually feels like you're writing on the screen is really incredible
Speaker 2:  and it seems like Amazon didn't get anywhere close to that feeling
Speaker 2:  like you're actually writing on a piece of paper with a pen. Right?
Speaker 10:  They got close enough. They got close enough, okay. With technological trade
Speaker 10:  offs, right? Because the remarkable two doesn't have any sort of front light
Speaker 10:  on it, right? So it doesn't glow at all. Generally that's fine. You're
Speaker 10:  probably taking your notes in a well-lit environment. But Amazon wants
Speaker 10:  it's device to be able to have those front lights so that you can also read
Speaker 10:  on it at night and stuff like that. And that means you're gonna have this
Speaker 10:  little gap between the, the pin and the actual
Speaker 10:  paper. And so that can be kind of frustrating. Other companies
Speaker 10:  like Onyx books have addressed that by making the pin move a little
Speaker 10:  faster. Amazon didn't really do that so there's feels like there's just
Speaker 10:  this little tiny delay and it's really noticeable versus
Speaker 10:  the remarkable too not as noticeable versus other e Ink
Speaker 10:  devices or something like the iPad.
Speaker 2:  Okay. Yeah it, it makes me think about like do you remember in like the early
Speaker 2:  days of touchscreen phones? Yes. When some of them were like very close
Speaker 2:  and it actually felt like you were touching the thing you were trying to
Speaker 2:  touch and then there were other things where it was kind of like you could
Speaker 2:  sense that you're like touching a piece of glass above the thing and you
Speaker 2:  move and then it reacts and it just like, it didn't feel like the thing on
Speaker 2:  the screen and the thing you were doing were connected. Is this that again?
Speaker 10:  Yeah, it's that exact same thing. Okay. It's not quite as bad as some of
Speaker 10:  those early phones. Like it's passable and they did a really nice job
Speaker 10:  with the texture of the glass and, and the nibs have like a little texture
Speaker 10:  to them like the remarkable nibs do. So you do get that, that
Speaker 10:  sensation of pulling it across paper. It's way better than writing
Speaker 10:  on an iPad or some Samsung tablet or Chromebook or something.
Speaker 2:  Nibs are very important. Alex, if you take one thing away from this Vergecast
Speaker 2:  episode, it's that nibs are very important and you should never, never skimp
Speaker 2:  on the nibs. That's the, that's the tagline
Speaker 10:  Here is the secret. If you're whatever e ink device you get to write on,
Speaker 10:  doesn't matter what, go get the remarkable nibs Ooh and you'll be
Speaker 2:  Fine. Oh that's a good call. That's a really good call. Yeah that pen is
Speaker 2:  is sick. It feels so good to write with that thing. Yeah,
Speaker 10:  I love it. I have my own stylists and I just use the remarkable
Speaker 10:  two nibs on it regardless of whatever e ink device I'm writing
Speaker 10:  on. Yeah. And it's like close enough that I'm like okay, it's fine.
Speaker 2:  No I that, yeah I totally buy that. And the thing I think that bummed me
Speaker 2:  out the most, it's like Amazon software is a weird thing because on the one
Speaker 2:  hand it's not very good in that like, like as an
Speaker 2:  objective piece of software it's like very slow. The everything takes forever
Speaker 2:  to load. It's like filtering the library stuff kind of sucks, but on the
Speaker 2:  other hand it's like it's fine, right? Like in, if its job is to like open
Speaker 2:  up a book and flip pages and find the book that I want to
Speaker 2:  read, like it's fine. It does the job. And for me, you and I are very different
Speaker 2:  in this particular respect. We're like I have been almost exclusively
Speaker 2:  an Amazon book reader for like over a decade. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  You seem to be like actively avoiding sort of throwing in your lot with Amazon
Speaker 2:  as much as you can over time. Whereas I just gave up a while ago and I'm
Speaker 2:  like, all of my books come from Amazon. It sucks. I have a lot of feelings
Speaker 2:  about Amazon as a company and it's relationship with publishers and what
Speaker 2:  it's done to books. But like this is what it is. I own hundreds of Kindle
Speaker 2:  books. I
Speaker 10:  Mean I still own a ton of Kindle books. Like, like
Speaker 10:  I have bought so many books on the Kindle over the year. I like
Speaker 10:  reading on it but over time I just got kind of fed up with
Speaker 10:  particularly library integration. I didn't have any real clean library integration
Speaker 10:  and it was a bummer. And then like I enjoy, I enjoy Fanfic,
Speaker 10:  I'm, I'm an adult who who likes to read about fictional characters like
Speaker 10:  their dolls in a playhouse. So I, that
Speaker 10:  does not work at all for that. And that's kind of what led me to get away
Speaker 10:  from it as much as like Amazon ru the day was like there
Speaker 10:  were needs that the Kindle just doesn't meet. And that's because the Kindle's
Speaker 10:  job is to sell you Kindle books and keep you in the Kindle
Speaker 10:  ecosystem. It has no interest and that's fine. I totally get that.
Speaker 10:  I'm not gonna like knock on them for that element
Speaker 10:  of it. But the experience, even if you are in the Kindle universe
Speaker 10:  isn't super great anymore.
Speaker 2:  I mean let's not forget though that this is the same company that you buy
Speaker 2:  something from and then it advertises that same thing to you all
Speaker 2:  across the internet for the next like several years. So like I
Speaker 2:  agree with you that it's stupid but I am also in no way surprised that Amazon
Speaker 2:  is not good at this. And I
Speaker 10:  Think that's what bummed me out the most is that this felt like a big
Speaker 10:  change for Amazon. It felt like this big turn but it's just a big turn
Speaker 10:  for the hardware division, right? Every other element
Speaker 10:  of Amazon is still Amazon, the software is still Amazon, how it's
Speaker 10:  marketed is still Amazon. Like, and I get it, you can't turn a huge company
Speaker 10:  like that and redirect them to improve things. It's gonna take a lot more
Speaker 10:  work than one kind of crummy e ink tablet
Speaker 10:  release. But it's still like just is such a
Speaker 10:  bummer cuz it's like okay this is it. Like if I wanna
Speaker 10:  be using the best of the best in America, this is what I got.
Speaker 10:  Right. You know like with phones, I've got an I like the iPhone is great.
Speaker 10:  Is there a lot of frustration with its walled garden? Absolutely. But it's
Speaker 10:  still like good software. It's still good hardware and this is
Speaker 10:  like good hardware, terrifically bad software.
Speaker 2:  Yeah and I mean it goes back to the same stuff we were talking about, right?
Speaker 2:  Like it was interesting like reading the stuff even that you compared it
Speaker 2:  to in your review because there's like, like you said, there's the Onyx book
Speaker 2:  stuff, there's the remarkable stuff and there's a lot of things that you
Speaker 2:  kind of slightly sort of overlapping things
Speaker 2:  with. Yeah. The Kindle scribe, right? Where it's like if you want an EIN
Speaker 2:  tablet, this is not the one to buy, right? Like if you, if you want to do
Speaker 2:  lots of things on an EIN tablet and if that phrase even like means anything
Speaker 2:  to you, do not buy the Kindle scribe.
Speaker 10:  Yeah, don't
Speaker 2:  Buy. No. And if you're like a lawyer who wants to read PDFs all day,
Speaker 2:  like buy the remarkable because that thing kicks ass. It's really expensive.
Speaker 2:  But for that specific purpose, like it rules and I cannot recommend it hard
Speaker 2:  enough for that specific purpose. But for Amazon there's nobody doing this
Speaker 2:  thing that Amazon is trying to do. Like this is where I want like Cobo to
Speaker 2:  make something awesome or like Barnes and Noble to make something awesome
Speaker 2:  and it's just like no one has. And so if it's like I'm just like a regular
Speaker 2:  person who reads books and I wanna be able to like take notes and sync them
Speaker 2:  to the cloud and find them later. Like there just isn't any competition.
Speaker 2:  There's just none.
Speaker 10:  Yeah. There, there's no competition. I mean Cobo has definitely done like
Speaker 10:  kind of note taking. They've, they've released a couple of devices I think
Speaker 10:  that have a stylist and everything. But Cobo I also think they're hardware
Speaker 10:  feels really cheap and like yeah, plasticy and annoying and like I feel
Speaker 10:  like a baby when I hold it. And so the K, the Kindle scribe
Speaker 10:  feels gorgeous in your hands and everything and then you're like, okay,
Speaker 10:  I wanna take notes. Okay so I have five pin weights that I can choose from.
Speaker 10:  I can't do pencil at all, which like feels like just easy
Speaker 10:  and then like, okay I wanna sync whatever documents I have
Speaker 10:  and I have to email them to myself and then it emails me
Speaker 10:  a link to my pdf which that that link that you get,
Speaker 10:  if anybody else has that link, they also get your pdf. So if you're like
Speaker 10:  a lawyer, you cannot use the Kindle scribe because you're just creating
Speaker 10:  a security nightmare for yourself. And that's like you've got the biggest
Speaker 10:  cloud computing company in the world in the same building as you.
Speaker 10:  Why didn't, did no one make an effort to try to integrate this better?
Speaker 2:  Nothing makes me crazier than how difficult it is to say like I have a thing
Speaker 2:  on my computer and I would like it to be on my Kindle. There's like a bookmark
Speaker 2:  that they have where you can send web stuff to Kindle or like
Speaker 10:  And it works like reasonably well. Yes.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. It's like I give it like a, like a c plus for like it, it usually
Speaker 2:  gets all the words on the page and puts them on my Kindle. But does it look
Speaker 2:  insane? Yes.
Speaker 10:  Yeah. If you're using like New York Times, you know like if, if you're
Speaker 10:  using like a very well like everybody reads it
Speaker 10:  source, it's gonna transfer it fine. If you're like, I found this weird
Speaker 10:  ass blog and I wanna read it later from this guy who have never heard of
Speaker 10:  it's gonna look like garbage on your Kindle scribe.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. All your like sick Tumblr fan fiction is not going to
Speaker 2:  appear correctly on the Kindle scribe
Speaker 10:  Not looking good. Yeah, I'm gonna be crying. It's fine. I've I've
Speaker 10:  worked through it. That's why I've got the other, the other rereading devices.
Speaker 10:  Yeah,
Speaker 2:  That's fair. So okay, last thing and then, and we will, we will leave this
Speaker 2:  alone for now. My sense is most people's question is do I
Speaker 2:  buy the Kindle scribe or do I buy a different Kindle? Like I feel like ultimately
Speaker 2:  I want there to be more interesting competition in this space but it's kind
Speaker 2:  of not right? It's like, it's like the iPhone question, right? Like people
Speaker 2:  who have iPhones are gonna keep buying iPhones. Do I buy the pro or the regular
Speaker 2:  one? Like this feels like that same question to me.
Speaker 10:  Yeah. So like if you're a person with not great vision, I say as somebody
Speaker 10:  with not great vision, the Kindle scribe makes a lot of sense, right? Like
Speaker 10:  it's really gorgeous device. It, it just works like a Kindle but
Speaker 10:  it's big And so I think that makes sense for a lot of people and I think
Speaker 10:  there are a lot of people that want that bigger device. I personally like
Speaker 10:  a smaller device, I think like seven Inches kind of my platonic ideal for
Speaker 10:  reading.
Speaker 2:  Can you still kind of hold it in one hand and read it it in bed? Cuz that's
Speaker 2:  like for me that's the thing like sometimes I like the two hand but I also
Speaker 2:  need to be able to like lie in bed and hold it above my face and still be
Speaker 2:  able to read.
Speaker 10:  You can, but I'll admit you won't be able to do this David.
Speaker 10:  But I definitely read it in bed but like use my boobs as like a stand.
Speaker 10:  If you don't have boobs that's gonna be harder for you. But a lot of people
Speaker 10:  are listening to this being like, oh my god, that's how I use my iPad. But
Speaker 10:  for everybody else, I'm sorry. Yeah, it like it's, it's very easy to hold
Speaker 10:  with one hand. It's very easy to walk around. Like sometimes you do feel
Speaker 10:  like you're in Star Trek and you're like hold on, let me use my pet, send
Speaker 10:  something to Picard cuz it's just like this big device.
Speaker 2:  It's badass. Yeah but
Speaker 10:  It works fine And I think if you just want a nice Kindle you wanna spend
Speaker 10:  the money cause it's expensive. It starts at like $330. Yeah it
Speaker 10:  works.
Speaker 2:  I kind of came away from it thinking I'll probably buy a scribe too.
Speaker 2:  And for now I like my Kindle fine. I, I would like to have one
Speaker 2:  with more note ticking stuff but like I can live with the keyboard typing
Speaker 2:  notes for a little longer and it, this does feel like the kind of thing that
Speaker 2:  a year from now with a little little bit of software work and maybe
Speaker 2:  this is wishful thinking because we've been waiting 15 years for Amazon to
Speaker 2:  have good software and here we are. But like a little bit more work, a little
Speaker 2:  bit more fine tuning. Especially with like the pen and the display. And it
Speaker 2:  feels like this is the kind of thing where like V2 has potential to be like
Speaker 2:  a lot better in all of these sort of small ways that you're talking about.
Speaker 2:  Is that a crazy takeaway?
Speaker 10:  No, I don't think that's crazy. Even in my conversations with people at
Speaker 10:  Amazon, like after I'd been reviewing this thing for a while and I was
Speaker 10:  kind of like, hey here are some of my issues with it. They're like, these
Speaker 10:  are very good things to know and like pass on to the engineers. I think
Speaker 10:  there is a lot of like appetite there to improve on these
Speaker 10:  devices. I just don't know. I don't know how confident I can be that they
Speaker 10:  will do it because it's a huge company. It's hard to get
Speaker 10:  everybody onto a project and get them like reorient everyone. And I think
Speaker 10:  there's a lot that needs to happen to make this a really great experience
Speaker 10:  instead of like, eh, I get my books, it's fine. Yeah, the Kindle scribe
Speaker 10:  too will definitely be better.
Speaker 2:  This is why I root so hard for Cobo. Like I just root for Cobo. Not because
Speaker 2:  I want Cobos but because I want somebody at Amazon to be like, whoa, that
Speaker 2:  Cobo is good. And then feel like they have to go make better things. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  that's like competition people. This is all I want in the world. Even though
Speaker 2:  I'm gonna keep buying Kindles like, I'm sorry Cobo, I have too many Kindle
Speaker 2:  books. I can't buy Cobos. I literally, it's illegal for me to buy Cobos.
Speaker 2:  I own too many Amazon books, but I want them to be good so that Amazon will
Speaker 2:  make better Kindles. This is all I want in the world.
Speaker 10:  I want Kendall to feel like I want Amazon to feel a little heat. Yeah, I
Speaker 10:  want them to feel like they have to do a little more. Cuz right now it feels
Speaker 10:  like they do the absolute minimum effort and I go
Speaker 10:  through a lot of my life doing the same thing, so I'm not gonna judge him
Speaker 10:  too hard. But come on guys, just put in like a little bit of
Speaker 10:  extra effort.
Speaker 2:  I agree. All right Alex, thank you. I have forgiven you for not telling me
Speaker 2:  how to describe, but I appreciate you coming back.
Speaker 10:  Bye.
Speaker 2:  All right, that's it for the Verge Cast. Thank you as always for listening.
Speaker 2:  There's tons more on everything we talked about the broadband study, ean,
Speaker 2:  Kindle Scribe, all that good stuff on the verge.com. You can also follow
Speaker 2:  all of us on Twitter. Alex is Alex h Cranz. Russell is Russell
Speaker 2:  Brandham and I'm Pierce, as I mentioned at the beginning, this is
Speaker 2:  my last show full-time for a couple of months, but we have a ton
Speaker 2:  planned for you on the Wednesday show. In the meantime, Alex is gonna host
Speaker 2:  a bunch. We're gonna have more Verge staff stopping by and I'm assured
Speaker 2:  by our producers that things are gonna get very weird. So I'm sorry and buckle
Speaker 2:  up and enjoy. Of course the Friday show will remain chaos as always.
Speaker 2:  Don't you worry. And I'll be back in a couple of months to try and do all
Speaker 2:  kinds of new stuff too. This show is produced by Andrew Marino and Liam James
Speaker 2:  Nori Donovan is our executive producer and Brooke Mentors is our editorial
Speaker 2:  director of audio. The Vergecast is a verge production and part of the Vox
Speaker 2:  Media podcast network. If you have thoughts, feedback feelings,
Speaker 2:  newborn sleep tips, or just a long ride home today and want somebody to talk
Speaker 2:  to, you can always call the Vergecast hotline. Eight six
Speaker 2:  six Verge 11. If you don't have a phone or can't call email vergecast
Speaker 2:  the verge.com. We want all your big thoughts, all your questions, all your
Speaker 2:  feelings about all things tech. Alright, I'm off for now. I think my baby
Speaker 2:  just woke up. Happy holidays everybody. Rock and roll.