# Transcript
ID: 9e35e5f0-2505-11ed-88af-395cde21a360
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Twitter is a mess, Apple 'Far out' rumors, and this week in streaming
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-651615539180792038/-3592822962896322039/s93290-US-3676s-1661494086.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, Alex Cranz, and David Pierce discuss this week in tech news.
Speaker 1:  With no fees or minimums banking with capital one is the easiest decision
Speaker 1:  in the history of decisions. Even easier than deciding to listen to another
Speaker 1:  episode of your favorite podcast with no overdraft fees. Is it
Speaker 1:  even a decision that's banking? Re-imagined what's in your wallet
Speaker 1:  terms supply, see capital one.com/bank capital one, and a
Speaker 1:  member FTSE
Speaker 3:  This episode was sponsored by Salesforce. Pivot is coming to
Speaker 3:  TV, sort of with the help of Salesforce. Plus
Speaker 3:  pivot listeners will now be able to watch for video segments of our podcast
Speaker 3:  every week, exclusively on their platform, but that's not all
Speaker 3:  Salesforce plus is a free streaming service that provides live
Speaker 3:  experiences, original series podcasts, and other programming to help inspire
Speaker 3:  business leaders all around the globe. Sign up today to watch pivot
Speaker 3:  and more exclusive content free at
Speaker 3:  salesforce.com/plus that's
Speaker 3:  salesforce.com/p L U S.
Speaker 4:  Hello, and welcome to the broadcast. The flagship podcast of
Speaker 4:  audience measurement, where we get into Dows M Dows. Our
Speaker 4:  Dow is F Dows F Dallas, I think is a real theme of this week. Hi, I'm your
Speaker 4:  friend Nila. The host of the ship. David Pierce is here. Hi,
Speaker 5:  I count as precisely one user. That's the only thing
Speaker 4:  I know. No one's ever monetized you in your life. David,
Speaker 4:  Alex Kranz is here.
Speaker 6:  I'm just feeling bad for David never being monetized.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. What is a daily user? If you're not a monetized double dailies, or
Speaker 4:  do you even have that?
Speaker 6:  We don't want you
Speaker 4:  A lot going on this week. There's an apple event that is officially announced.
Speaker 4:  Now on the seventh, we got to talk about that. Speaking of
Speaker 4:  endows Ilan versus Twitter and reached new Heights of absurdity this
Speaker 4:  week, it was such a gadget news. Chris Welch has a big scoop on any Sono
Speaker 4:  speaker. We should talk about Eve prices are everywhere. The Peloton CEO
Speaker 4:  is doing metaphors about ships. All in all is shaping up to be a perfect
Speaker 4:  for a chest. You know, when the CEOs are doing ship metaphors,
Speaker 4:  you're in for a ride. Let's start though with apple, other streaming
Speaker 4:  news, Alex put a bunch of streaming news in here. I mean, this is
Speaker 4:  just a chef's kiss of a rundown. I love it. Let's start with
Speaker 4:  apple though. The event is called far out. We are assuming
Speaker 4:  based on long historical record, this is the iPhone 14 event.
Speaker 4:  There is a lot of rumors, speculation that feels very solid. That we'll see
Speaker 4:  a watch in the mix. What are we thinking here? Maybe two
Speaker 5:  Or three,
Speaker 4:  Even three. What would be the three?
Speaker 5:  Oh, and I guess it's just too. There's the new watch. And then the, the gigantic
Speaker 5:  new watch
Speaker 6:  It's different sizes. That's why you're thinking three, the
Speaker 5:  Apple watch pro max.
Speaker 4:  Well, wait, so that there's an update to the watches that we know in love,
Speaker 6:  Right? So that's two watches cause it's two different sizes.
Speaker 4:  Okay. Yes, I
Speaker 5:  Was right. Three watches. It's is it one watch or is it three watches?
Speaker 4:  No. Okay. So wait, wait, wait, let me, let me just, this is my, my theory
Speaker 4:  of the case here. The iPhone, every size of the iPhone is a different iPhone
Speaker 4:  model. Yeah. Right? I mean, that's how they've done it. The iPhone mini and
Speaker 4:  the iPhone 10 R and the iPhone promo, and they're all different and
Speaker 4:  they're primarily distinguished on screen size. So the different models,
Speaker 4:  the watch is a, that there is the apple watch for,
Speaker 4:  and then the apple watch se or whatever. And they each come in two sizes,
Speaker 4:  which is actually a very interesting split and Apple's lineup. It's more
Speaker 4:  like the Mac book than the iPad or whatever. So I think it's two
Speaker 4:  watches, right? We're expecting a regular update to the apple watch.
Speaker 4:  And then this like sports, or
Speaker 6:  Like the Garmin competitor, you can shoot it with a gun. Don't
Speaker 6:  shoot it with a gun, please.
Speaker 4:  Some YouTuber right now is taking notes. Being like, I got an idea for a
Speaker 4:  video,
Speaker 6:  Caulking the firearm, getting ready to go
Speaker 4:  Yelling at their brews, like get in the garage, find the guns. We've got
Speaker 4:  to get ready for this apple watch to come out,
Speaker 6:  Find me bullets. But yeah. So, so yeah, there's going to be this other one
Speaker 6:  then it's meant to go after the Garmin folks, it's meant to be for like
Speaker 6:  rugged outdoor enthusiasts who all love their
Speaker 6:  garments, passionately wear these ugly devices. And hopefully
Speaker 6:  the apple device will be a little bit, I'm sorry to every garment user, but
Speaker 6:  you know, your devices are
Speaker 4:  Ugly in a way that now is become a brand
Speaker 6:  Like the, well, even the apple watch, the apple watch, we all kind of thought
Speaker 6:  was maybe ugly. And then we're like, no, the apple watch is cool. So it's,
Speaker 6:  it's very much like that.
Speaker 5:  Did we get, I'm not sure we got to that point. I think it's just like,
Speaker 5:  we just decided it's fine. It's just there. It's just like a,
Speaker 5:  it's like you have a large glass rectangle on your wrist. Like, I don't know
Speaker 5:  that anyone is going to look at it and be like, that is a beautiful object,
Speaker 5:  but like, it's fine. It's good enough. And I feel like Garmin, it took a
Speaker 5:  while to get there, but it now, like it has this connotation of like, yeah,
Speaker 5:  I wear an ugly watch, but like I'm faster than you. You don't want to fight
Speaker 4:  Every time I see a Garmin person I'm like that person can climb a mountain.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Which may or may not be true. I haven't done any research to
Speaker 4:  validate. I don't just walk up to people. And like, I've noticed your watch.
Speaker 4:  What's your top speed.
Speaker 6:  I think every garment owner wants you to assign a climate mountain,
Speaker 6:  regardless of if they have
Speaker 4:  Again, this is like why you buy vehicles for off-roading that don't forgot
Speaker 4:  for it. Like, okay, fine. So we are expecting a big
Speaker 4:  sports watch. Here's my question about that, because I think that is
Speaker 4:  fundamentally more interesting than the iPhone at this point, because it
Speaker 4:  represents an entry into a new category for apple, which is
Speaker 4:  traditionally when apple has the most new ideas. And then over time, they
Speaker 4:  have to whittle those down to reality. I submit to you the
Speaker 4:  apple watch itself, which as you will remember, was announced with
Speaker 4:  enormous fanfare about the digital crown, which Tim cook
Speaker 4:  likened to the mouse. And multitouch in
Speaker 4:  terms of input devices that would revolutionize the world. It's a wheel.
Speaker 4:  It's a, it's an, I never used it
Speaker 6:  Revolutionized
Speaker 4:  Well. I mean, literally I feel revolutionized when I turn the dial,
Speaker 4:  I mean, who hasn't turned the digital crown and thought to myself, this will
Speaker 4:  revolutionize computing on the order of the mouse.
Speaker 4:  Anyhow, the big watch is like a new product category for them. It can't
Speaker 4:  just be more apple watch. Right? They've got to do some new
Speaker 4:  sensors. They've got to do some new activity
Speaker 4:  proofing. They've got to add new sports to it.
Speaker 4:  They've got to make the battery lasts a lot longer. That's the main thing
Speaker 4:  I hear from garment. The garment owners I know in my life say two things
Speaker 4:  about the apple watch one. It just looks too delicate. Even if it's not too
Speaker 4:  delicate for the things they do, right. It's like waterproof. It's dustproof
Speaker 4:  whatever they think it's too delicate. And they've got their garments, which
Speaker 4:  look like tanks. And then to the battery life isn't good enough for camping
Speaker 4:  or whatever it is you want to do with your garment. So those feel like the
Speaker 4:  two things apple has to solve from a hardware design standpoint and on the
Speaker 4:  software side, you've got to make it easier to use while you're running.
Speaker 4:  Like all the things like Garmin's interface is like dead
Speaker 4:  simple compared to an apple watch.
Speaker 6:  I mean, I don't know if they're going to do that. It's got a two inch display,
Speaker 6:  like that's the rumor, right? That it's going to have a two inch display.
Speaker 6:  It's going to be huge. I wonder if Blaby, they're not competing with garment
Speaker 6:  as much as offering a really sturdy counterpoint to garment, like rather
Speaker 6:  than saying, we're going to do everything Garmin does, but better. Maybe
Speaker 6:  they're going to be like, we're going to do everything you want your garment
Speaker 6:  to do, but totally differently. Isn't that cooler.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I kind of think the move here is to make the apple watch, do more
Speaker 5:  stuff. And they're going to like put a big screen on it, which is going to
Speaker 5:  help with battery life just because there's just more place to put batteries.
Speaker 5:  So I think to some extent, like that problem will solve itself with better
Speaker 5:  chips and more space. But then on this big screen, like if I'm apple, I'm
Speaker 5:  going way further down the road of like, how do we make this a totally
Speaker 5:  self-sufficient device with this interesting. You don't need your phone.
Speaker 5:  You don't need anything else. Just like take this thing and climb a mountain.
Speaker 5:  I don't know if that's where they're going, but that's what I would be doing
Speaker 5:  with this. It's like, how do you appeal to like the ultra power users and
Speaker 5:  the ultra fitness people is like, give them this giant thing that
Speaker 5:  does not need another device to be useful. That's what I mean.
Speaker 4:  Let me unearth some David Pierce history from your
Speaker 4:  interregnum between stints at the verge.
Speaker 5:  That dark days we call this
Speaker 4:  David for a long time was one of the most notable
Speaker 4:  traders@theverge.com. And he left us to go to a, a technology
Speaker 4:  oriented print magazine. This is a true story, is a great magazine.
Speaker 4:  We all know it. We all love it. And I refuse to name it like Voldemort.
Speaker 4:  And while he was there, he wrote a big feature on the apple watch. Yep.
Speaker 4:  Whose thesis was? This thing is going to replace
Speaker 4:  your phone.
Speaker 5:  That was not my thesis. That was, that was not my thesis. That
Speaker 5:  was Apple's thesis. That was not some grand theory of
Speaker 5:  the case. That was what apple told me over and over and over on the
Speaker 5:  record was that this device, the headline of that story was
Speaker 5:  iPhone killer and apple hated it. And I was like, do you know what the
Speaker 5:  problem is with this headline is it's the store. It's what you said
Speaker 5:  on the record. Like here are the quotes.
Speaker 4:  I would point out that I didn't even get to the middle of my version of the
Speaker 4:  story before David corrected me, but this,
Speaker 5:  Sorry. Keep going.
Speaker 4:  No, I think you might understand why I brought this up. I have
Speaker 5:  A feeling where you're going with this. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Well, so apple pushed back against the story. After it came up the show read
Speaker 4:  it. It's a good story. David's excellent writer, even though he worked for
Speaker 4:  the enemy, but it has back love. And again, this story came out. It was great.
Speaker 4:  There was pushback from apple. This is not actually what we're doing. The
Speaker 4:  two things are together for obvious reasons, right? Apple saying, they're
Speaker 4:  going to cannibalize the phone when the phone is their biggest source of
Speaker 4:  revenue is not what they want apple thinking in its mind, oh, this thing
Speaker 4:  will grow to be independent of a phone. And then it's
Speaker 4:  total market will be as big as the phone market, as opposed to
Speaker 4:  just a percentage of people who have phones makes all the sense in the world.
Speaker 4:  That's right. But they haven't done that. The watch got a little bit more
Speaker 4:  independent in its app model. Like a little bit the app, something remote
Speaker 4:  controls of your phone apps, but that's kind of where it, they added obviously
Speaker 4:  cellular connectivity. That's kind of where it stopped. And it's been stopped
Speaker 4:  there for a couple of years. So David, your thesis is now big screen. Big
Speaker 4:  battery can go a couple of days. They obviously still have cell
Speaker 4:  connectivity. They're going to make the turn.
Speaker 5:  I mean, it seems like this is a moment you could do it. Right? Like
Speaker 5:  apple, I spent the last couple of years getting developers to move more of
Speaker 5:  their stuff onto the watch. So it's already more self-sufficient than it.
Speaker 5:  Once was like, for the longest time, you couldn't like
Speaker 5:  download Spotify things for when you were away from your
Speaker 5:  phone or on a run, which was just like absurd. Right. But a lot of those
Speaker 5:  problems have been solved.
Speaker 6:  It was like a Spotify thing too. Right? Like it was, it was one of their
Speaker 6:  deals, I think with Samsung where the, the agreement was,
Speaker 6:  you can't, you can only do downloads with us. You can't do it with any other
Speaker 6:  companies. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And, and there were like a million versions of that rate. Whereas like,
Speaker 5:  for me it was podcasts. Like I listened to podcasts when I run and none of
Speaker 5:  my podcast apps would download podcasts onto my watch. And it's just like,
Speaker 5:  this is dumb. But anyway, so they've solved a bunch of those problems and
Speaker 5:  the processor is getting better. And I think like one thing that's really
Speaker 5:  happened is a lot of people now have wireless headphones, which
Speaker 5:  can in theory, correct. Connect directly to your watch and voice
Speaker 5:  dictation is now very good. And I think like the biggest thing you have to
Speaker 5:  solve, if you want this thing to be self-sufficient is communication. Right?
Speaker 5:  Like that is the thing. Most people do most of the time on their phones.
Speaker 5:  And so it's like, if you're ever going to start to push now, it feels like
Speaker 5:  there's more of a case to actually start to do some of that stuff. Then there
Speaker 5:  was,
Speaker 6:  But the problem is the wireless headphones. Aren't very
Speaker 6:  good. Like they're, they're, they're good enough. Right? They're good enough
Speaker 6:  to listen to when you're like going on a run or walking your dog or whatever.
Speaker 6:  I use my AirPods daily. Would they still have a lot of pain points
Speaker 6:  that you don't have with a phone? Right. Like earlier today I was trying
Speaker 6:  to do an airport huddle with our, how tos editor
Speaker 6:  Barbara go. Great. And then we both had on wireless headphones in both of
Speaker 6:  our wireless headphones, decided to stop like connecting to our devices
Speaker 6:  in the middle of the huddle. Like I was easy. I could
Speaker 6:  put them away and just say, Hey, I'm on speaker. Let me continue to make
Speaker 6:  this case a deal while we talk great. If I'm on my watch, I have to be
Speaker 6:  like, hold on, hold on. Like, do I go speaker on my watch that works in
Speaker 6:  the house. Doesn't work in like out in public. Like
Speaker 4:  No speaker works out in public.
Speaker 5:  Yes. Speakers bad everywhere.
Speaker 6:  Right. But you take your phone and you can put it to your ear and then
Speaker 6:  jam your other finger into your other ear and be like, what's that can't
Speaker 6:  do that with a watch.
Speaker 5:  No, that's totally true.
Speaker 4:  By the way, just, just to put this out there for people. If you ever get
Speaker 4:  a phone call, you don't want to take, I'm not saying this ever happens to
Speaker 4:  me. One thing you can say, regardless of circumstance that no one can check
Speaker 4:  is, Hey, I'm on my watch. Can I call you back?
Speaker 4:  And everyone immediately understands that they should hang up the phone.
Speaker 4:  It's pretty good. And then it's just a matter of how badly do you want to
Speaker 4:  burn that relationship,
Speaker 4:  but Hey, I'm on my watch. Can I call you back? Everyone's like, oh yeah,
Speaker 4:  no, please, please. Don't do that. I want to talk to me.
Speaker 6:  This is explaining a lot of our conversations Nila.
Speaker 4:  So I think my question is like, okay, so you add some downloads, right? You've
Speaker 4:  got a big battery. And the apple stated reason for not
Speaker 4:  allowing a lot of these things to happen is we're protecting the battery
Speaker 4:  life. Yes. There are other quieter reason is we want to self
Speaker 4:  preference, the music app instead of Spotify and Spotify tried to
Speaker 4:  turn a weakness into a strength by saying, you can, we've signed a deal to
Speaker 4:  let you download on Samsung. And it's like, you're just dancing,
Speaker 4:  whatever, but that's come to an end. Right? Like the Spotify app is more
Speaker 4:  full-featured you can do things on the watch now that make it feel like a
Speaker 4:  true app platform. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  See, now you got a bigger battery. It can be even true wrap platform. Do
Speaker 4:  you want, when you're going off grid to run up the mountain to have a
Speaker 4:  fully featured slack app on your watch, because that is like,
Speaker 4:  what did I replace this for?
Speaker 6:  I don't want to do that when I'm down on the ground.
Speaker 4:  Right. But what I'm saying is you can put your phone away, your
Speaker 4:  watches on your body. So it's like your solve this problem of getting
Speaker 4:  rid of your phone. And then you've created an entirely new class
Speaker 4:  of notification management problems that are literally strapped to
Speaker 4:  your body.
Speaker 6:  Terrible. Yes.
Speaker 5:  This is like the fundamental problem of the watch, which is the thing that
Speaker 5:  it was originally pitched as is like it frees you from your phone actually
Speaker 5:  sucks because what I can do is leave my phone somewhere else
Speaker 5:  and that's good. And if I don't want to get notifications, I just don't look
Speaker 5:  at my phone. A thing that buzzes my body is harder to
Speaker 5:  ignore in that sense. And this is like going to get even crazier when you
Speaker 5:  start getting into like AR glasses and all that stuff. But I think that is
Speaker 5:  like the fundamental unsolved problem of the watch is
Speaker 5:  basically how to like ratchet it up and down depending on what you want it
Speaker 5:  to do. And you just
Speaker 4:  Can't, that's what the digital crown is for
Speaker 6:  The focus modes. It's all about the focus
Speaker 4:  On my God. If they add focus modes to the crown,
Speaker 5:  Oh God, that's probably coming.
Speaker 6:  It's happening. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  You turn, turn the volume up on life and
Speaker 4:  any rural it back down,
Speaker 5:  I throw an idea. Both of you stage manager for the apple watch and you
Speaker 5:  scroll through the piles with the digital crap.
Speaker 4:  No, you know that I do the thing where, when I'm talking to someone, I want
Speaker 4:  to like indicate that I'm paying attention. I flip my phone over on the table.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It's like, this is how much I'm paying attention to you. It's still
Speaker 4:  here. It's not out of my sight.
Speaker 5:  Right. Cause that would be, but it's
Speaker 4:  Upside down and it's like, you pick up your watch. You just like roll
Speaker 6:  Making eye contact as you slowly roll the crowd.
Speaker 4:  All right. So those are the watches. We, we, I am very curious to see what
Speaker 4:  happens with this bigger sport watch. I think there's a big opportunity there
Speaker 4:  for apple to reinvent a bunch of it, right? Because it's a bigger display
Speaker 4:  is what you do, wacky or things in software. And then this new use
Speaker 4:  case of targeting Garmin means they have to
Speaker 4:  capture those users by trying to appeal to them. So I'm excited about that.
Speaker 4:  We should talk about the phones. It's it's funny that like, they're
Speaker 4:  gonna, what they're gonna fix. The camera's not fixed. Let me say again.
Speaker 4:  It's funny that I'm like, they're going to make the camera slightly better.
Speaker 4:  They're going to processor faster to no purpose
Speaker 6:  Blur, trying to read into the invitations and assume that we're going to
Speaker 6:  get astrophotography
Speaker 4:  And have the invitations that meant anything in the past like five years.
Speaker 6:  No, but what if it does this time? Like I think that's, I think that's the
Speaker 6:  fear it's not ever just like, no, we got to say it's doing something. Cause
Speaker 6:  we want to be able to be like a called it.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I dunno.
Speaker 5:  We should do a retrospective on that. Actually go back through the last like
Speaker 5:  20 invitations and try to figure out if they actually turned into anything.
Speaker 5:  Cause if not, it is a truly masterful, ongoing
Speaker 5:  bit from apple. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And we have to cut this whole part. This is too good. A story.
Speaker 4:  No, keep it. If you're out there and you want to write this, this incredibly
Speaker 4:  tedious story, send us any, we'll pay you to
Speaker 4:  do it.
Speaker 4:  No, it's a great story. I just, it's a lot of invitations to look at and
Speaker 4:  then be like, Hmm, did this blob
Speaker 4:  actually mean anything?
Speaker 4:  It's like, look at all the AR blobs. Once again,
Speaker 5:  It seemed like the phones, there are two things I would say that seemed potentially
Speaker 5:  interesting. I don't know. I think the, the
Speaker 5:  rumor is there's going to be either less notch or no notch and
Speaker 5:  potentially just a smaller, like whole punch for
Speaker 5:  all the sensors and cameras and stuff, which I don't know, people are excited
Speaker 5:  about. I literally, I have reached a point where I absolutely have no feelings
Speaker 5:  about notches and if, if they could make it bigger and I would say, okay,
Speaker 5:  and they could make it smaller. And I would say, okay. And then just move
Speaker 5:  on with my life. The one I think is potentially very interesting is the always
Speaker 5:  on display, which is another one where it's like, I've seen a lot of
Speaker 5:  people start to do interesting stuff with lock screen widgets in iOS
Speaker 5:  16, which I think is going to be very cool. And that plus a display
Speaker 5:  that's always on. It's like, I think there could start to be some interesting
Speaker 5:  stuff that like, what can your phone do when you're not even touching? It
Speaker 5:  is a pretty interesting idea, but that may end
Speaker 5:  up being as much an iOS 16 thing as a iPhone 14 thing. So
Speaker 5:  I don't know, but that's the thing I'm by far, most curious about,
Speaker 4:  So always on screen plus the new widgets and they're doing and Iowa
Speaker 4:  16, which include things like live updating sports scores.
Speaker 4:  You can kind of get a little like always on widget display. You
Speaker 4:  can tie that to a Mac that seems like fascinating to me. I'm assuming that's
Speaker 4:  only coming to the pro models.
Speaker 6:  How is the program to be the one to, by this time?
Speaker 4:  I mean, I always buy the pro because it always has.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I've never been a pro person, but this is the year that seems like
Speaker 5:  it's, the pro is going to be like demonstrably better other than just like
Speaker 5:  the one slightly better camera that didn't normally has.
Speaker 6:  I'm an updated my phone since I'm on, I'm still on the 11. So whatever is
Speaker 6:  coming out, I'm going to be getting some variation of it.
Speaker 4:  The 11 had, I think one of the wackiest iPhone cameras. So all time
Speaker 4:  even taking some extremely Samsung photos this whole time, that was like,
Speaker 4:  that was the first one that had smart HTR. Right. And they just, they were
Speaker 4:  like, what if shadows didn't exist?
Speaker 6:  So it just goes, my dog always looks so surprised
Speaker 6:  that can just doesn't have any like contour to his face in the photo.
Speaker 4:  Every time I look at photos from that year, I'm like, what what's going on
Speaker 4:  with this camera? It's time out.
Speaker 4:  So we just running the rumors are always on display on the pro 48
Speaker 4:  megapixel rear camera that obviously do pixel binning to get it down to 12
Speaker 4:  or whatever, larger sensor to collect more light, great notch
Speaker 4:  situation, maybe a processor upgrade. That is like,
Speaker 4:  if they actually significantly upgrade the camera in that way, add the always
Speaker 4:  on. Sure. It makes sense. Here's the one that I think is actually going to
Speaker 4:  generate all the sales. You all know my theory about big sheet screens. The
Speaker 4:  regular iPhone 14 will come with a max
Speaker 4:  version, 6.7 inch display version. So it will be cheaper, but have the
Speaker 4:  big screen,
Speaker 5:  Big phone.
Speaker 4:  And it's like, oh, this is when they win. Right? Like this is the one, this
Speaker 4:  is going to be the mountain. Like we can all complain about phone sizes,
Speaker 4:  all we want. And then we, I think we have an Alison piece on the site today.
Speaker 4:  Like as we speak
Speaker 6:  It help reinforce the
Speaker 4:  Vote with their dollars man. And they vote for big cheap screens. They
Speaker 4:  can walk into the store and be like that 48 inch old TV looks
Speaker 4:  beautiful in this TCL series four that
Speaker 4:  is never even heard of the word. Black is huge. I'm
Speaker 4:  going with grays. Let's do the grays. Like every time
Speaker 4:  the
Speaker 5:  Motion is so smooth,
Speaker 4:  Like big cheap screens always win. It is a law of the
Speaker 4:  universe. And so to me, that is actually the,
Speaker 4:  whatever you tell people, the pro is a better camera, but they look at bigger
Speaker 4:  screen for less money and they're going to pick the bigger screen every time.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. But like, that's what we're looking at, right? Like, oh,
Speaker 6:  Maybe some AirPods.
Speaker 4:  Oh, I've been on the iPhone. Yeah. Yeah. I was going to bring and come here.
Speaker 4:  But I mean, I find, it looks like that's what we're looking at. And then
Speaker 4:  yes, AirPods,
Speaker 6:  We're getting some new AirPods pro it sounds like maybe
Speaker 5:  I think there's a decent chance. AirPods pro ended up
Speaker 5:  being like the thing people are the most excited about, about the
Speaker 5:  new launches. Especially if they can add some of the like fitness stuff
Speaker 5:  into it and whatever sensors that are going to put into it, it's like
Speaker 5:  they, they might add the fins that are in the beets, which will make them
Speaker 5:  fit in a lot more people's ears comfortably. Like I, that, that
Speaker 5:  might be the kind of thing that everybody comes out being like, oh, those
Speaker 5:  phones are cool. But like all my God, I'm going to buy the hell out of those
Speaker 5:  AirPods. Like I, this might, that might happen.
Speaker 6:  I love the current ones. Like I'm on my second pair of them.
Speaker 6:  Because at some point all AirPods just stop. Right?
Speaker 6:  You all have this experience. They just stop working.
Speaker 5:  Oh, for me, the law is I will lose them on the 90th day that I
Speaker 5:  owed them. They will, they just poof out of existence.
Speaker 6:  I see. I haven't lost them. I'm convinced there's some like
Speaker 6:  cash and Bluetooth that doesn't get automatically cleared.
Speaker 6:  So all Bluetooth headphones have like a limited lifespan because of this
Speaker 6:  cash I've been told, this is probably not true.
Speaker 6:  But I, I convinced because like 18 months in, it's like, okay,
Speaker 6:  time to start looking for some new ones. So I'm very excited because I'm
Speaker 6:  at like 19 months right now. So this is for me personally,
Speaker 6:  huge news.
Speaker 4:  You're extremely made up cash theories pushed to the limit.
Speaker 4:  Yes,
Speaker 6:  I get it. I gotta to make it. I can believe in
Speaker 4:  Me. So these AirPods, you know, some fitness features cause they might have
Speaker 4:  motion sensors in them. Some of this wingtip
Speaker 4:  design holding ears better. Here's the big one. There's hints that they'll
Speaker 4:  support. Lossless audio
Speaker 6:  Title, title. This is your moment.
Speaker 4:  Well, apple music has losses now to do that. You need to
Speaker 4:  get beyond Bluetooth. And this is where apple makes the
Speaker 4:  turn and does proprietary wireless protocol for their pods.
Speaker 6:  If it doesn't suck, like I'm I'm I tend to be totally against
Speaker 6:  proprietary stuff. But apple has made a much better Bluetooth
Speaker 6:  radio than anybody else out there. Right? Like it just is hands down
Speaker 6:  better at communicating with your device
Speaker 4:  Because it is proprietary.
Speaker 6:  Right. And so if they want to go even more proprietary and it means I don't
Speaker 6:  have to be like, hold on, Barbara, let me smooth this huddle over to
Speaker 6:  speakerphone I'm in.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And I feel like apple has made very clear that it does
Speaker 5:  not give one single crap about connecting your
Speaker 5:  AirPods to your Android phone or your windows computer. And I feel like
Speaker 5:  apple is going to be perfectly happy to be like, this thing will work with
Speaker 5:  your apple devices and nothing else. And you all can
Speaker 5:  go screw yourselves.
Speaker 6:  Can you imagine if they cared?
Speaker 4:  They care a lot. They're like Bluetooth is we're serious about it. Anybody's
Speaker 4:  Bluetooth works. They have to pretend to care because European
Speaker 4:  regulators wandering the capitals of Europe are like hall. I
Speaker 4:  constantly, because of inter-operability
Speaker 4:  I don't, I don't know This. I think that's they do
Speaker 4:  codec and codec. It's like, it's great. Everyone loves thing it all the time.
Speaker 4:  That's what they talk about in France. It's cheese and interoperability between
Speaker 4:  codex.
Speaker 4:  Anyhow, they have to pretend, but they've also like
Speaker 4:  insane. Lock-in on the phone because of their headphones. And
Speaker 4:  no one else can compete in the hedge fund market against apple because of
Speaker 4:  the proprietary nature of AirPods. I'm going to tell the audience now that
Speaker 4:  our producer Liam is insistent that we get through the show in an hour
Speaker 4:  this week, but he wants us to do it. And so he's put a timer on the screen
Speaker 4:  that has now turned red, which signals that we have to wrap
Speaker 4:  the iPhone preview segment up. Please address your complaints to Liam about
Speaker 4:  the giant red timer. I think you would love to hear from you.
Speaker 4:  It's okay. We're going to have plenty more time to talk about apple too.
Speaker 4:  Yes. We got to go to the gun. We're sending an army this time. It's like
Speaker 4:  five of us are going, so we'll have much more apple to come
Speaker 4:  when that event hits on the seventh. All right, we're gonna take a break.
Speaker 4:  Come back. We'll talk a little bit streaming and a little bit Elan versus
Speaker 4:  Twitter will be around.
Speaker 3:  Hi, I'm Scott Galloway. And along with Kara Swisher, that jungle cat, I host
Speaker 3:  the podcast pivot. Now, since this is an ad running on a
Speaker 3:  podcast, you might have no idea what I look like.
Speaker 3:  Imagine someone who is very handsome minus the handsome part. Anyways,
Speaker 3:  you're in luck. As we partnered with Salesforce to provide you
Speaker 3:  with bite-sized video snippets of the best content we have to offer
Speaker 3:  every week. Salesforce is new streaming service Salesforce
Speaker 3:  plus will now be the exclusive home for visual
Speaker 3:  highlights of pivot showing four video segments each and
Speaker 3:  every week. What a thrill, but it's not just pivot
Speaker 3:  Salesforce. Plus users can stream live experiences, original series,
Speaker 3:  virtual learning, and other programming to help your
Speaker 3:  business grow. The award-winning shows on the platform. Aluminate the future
Speaker 3:  of technology in the digital first work, anywhere world and Salesforce
Speaker 3:  plus will inspire business leaders like you to learn new skills, pursue
Speaker 3:  new career opportunities and drive change in the world. Sign up today to
Speaker 3:  watch pivot and more exclusive content free at
Speaker 3:  salesforce.com/plus that's
Speaker 3:  salesforce.com/p L U S
Speaker 8:  Process. It's a small word with big implications because whatever an
Speaker 8:  idea starts, a process gets done. It's how big talk drives real
Speaker 8:  action and people achieve their best work at Smartsheet. We're in the
Speaker 8:  process business, the go-to for managers who love pulling in the right
Speaker 8:  combination of data tools and people from across the company to make it happen.
Speaker 8:  One platform, every project, any scale, it doesn't get bigger than
Speaker 8:  that. Smartsheet power, your process visit smartsheet.com
Speaker 8:  forward slash power. Your process
Speaker 4:  We're back got some Elon versus Twitter talking about, but let's start with
Speaker 4:  streaming. Streaming wars are back in full effect because of
Speaker 4:  whatever is going on at HBO and whatever is going on in Netflix,
Speaker 4:  which is real quick. Let's start with HBO, HBO plus
Speaker 4:  discovery, discovery, Warner, media, whatever it's called again, the
Speaker 4:  slogan is the stuff dreams are made of which literally sounds like they found
Speaker 4:  some dirt.
Speaker 4:  If there's there's gold in here, like
Speaker 5:  It's like the corn kid on Tik TOK. Like that's what he would come up with
Speaker 5:  as his tagline.
Speaker 4:  I know the quote is in reference to a classic movie, but just imagine
Speaker 4:  having to walk into that company every day and people are like, the stuff
Speaker 4:  dreams are made of
Speaker 5:  Tap the sign on the wall, that's it? The stuff dreams are made up every morning
Speaker 4:  And it's like, I'm an accountant. Like what am I supposed to do here?
Speaker 4:  Okay. But they're in a really strange spot, right?
Speaker 4:  Tons of debt, firing people more layoffs to
Speaker 4:  come there.
Speaker 6:  One of market cap is down
Speaker 4:  At and T bought Warner brothers like something over a hundred dollars a share
Speaker 4:  like 1 0 9. And right now the combined company is trading at 14. So
Speaker 4:  weird times over at that company,
Speaker 4:  they, I think they're going to, there's a rumor today. I think in puck
Speaker 4:  that the new streaming platform will be called HBO discovery, which is not
Speaker 4:  the right name.
Speaker 6:  It's HBO disco is right there.
Speaker 4:  It's super right there. They could just call it disco.
Speaker 4:  It's horrible. It's like that's 100% the
Speaker 4:  fake version of Disney plus,
Speaker 4:  but they had, they had house of the dragon this last week. It's here,
Speaker 4:  Alex. It says here that it was their biggest ever premiere.
Speaker 6:  It was their biggest ever 10, 10 million people like
Speaker 6:  tuned in to watch it in the United States. I think what's going to be really
Speaker 6:  interesting is how many people tune in for episode two? Like
Speaker 6:  most of the reaction was, yeah, that was some game of Thrones I watched and
Speaker 6:  it wasn't like super enthusiastic, but it also wasn't super like this is
Speaker 6:  horrible. So the CBS made an entire
Speaker 6:  business out of making that kind of content and like being the most
Speaker 6:  successful linear broadcast network in
Speaker 6:  history. So it's certainly possible that everybody can be like, yeah, I'll
Speaker 6:  keep watching this.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I mean, if you can run law and order SVU, basically at the same episode,
Speaker 5:  over and over for 25 years, like why not game of Thrones? And that appears
Speaker 5:  to be where you're headed, but I will say like, did you guys see that video
Speaker 5:  that was going around that somebody shot in New York where they were looking
Speaker 5:  into the windows of an apartment building and you could see all the TVs changing
Speaker 5:  at the same time because everybody was watching house of dragon.
Speaker 4:  So that video was from now and not from actual game of Thrones.
Speaker 5:  It's possible. It's fake. I don't care. Hope it's real. And if it is
Speaker 5:  really it's like, it is definitely true that like the house of the dragon
Speaker 5:  it's, it's been like the stranger things territory of like, there are like
Speaker 5:  a handful of shows. I feel like everyone I know pays attention to, and
Speaker 5:  this kind of got there on the first day, which was pretty impressive.
Speaker 6:  It was pretty weird. Like Charles, our entertainment critic, and I
Speaker 6:  both got screeners for the new house, with the dragons and
Speaker 6:  we both watched it and we were like, yep, we've seen it all. And so
Speaker 6:  we, we watched it, he wrote his review, went upgrade, we completely
Speaker 6:  forgot about it. And so like Sunday night, I was like, why w why is
Speaker 6:  Twitter like kind of quiet? Just cause everybody was watching house of dragons.
Speaker 6:  Like I just forgot the rest of the world was what's tuning in.
Speaker 4:  So that's what you want. Maybe that's HBO's entire promise is we can quiet
Speaker 4:  down Twitter for an hour a week. We will. And that's their service to America
Speaker 4:  and the world.
Speaker 6:  Can we just like, no stop. Don't do that.
Speaker 4:  The one thing about house is already going to say whatever, it's a game of
Speaker 4:  Thrones show. It's fine. There is horrifying scenes,
Speaker 4:  truly disgustingly, horrifying
Speaker 6:  Scenes.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. There's some wig issues. You know, there's a sad guy with a naked
Speaker 4:  lady. Like everything you expect from game of Thrones, like I've just described
Speaker 4:  almost every episode of game of Thrones. You have the CGI
Speaker 4:  budget is like where the show is theoretically more
Speaker 4:  expensive to make the game of Thrones. That's what they've been saying. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  But that opening fly, overseen where the dragon goes around the tower as
Speaker 4:  like, this is a cut scene from a PC game from 2012.
Speaker 5:  I had exactly, literally I would've put the year, like two years later,
Speaker 5:  but I had exactly the same reaction
Speaker 4:  As an
Speaker 5:  Assassin's creed cuts.
Speaker 6:  But like where did the money see? I I'm assuming the money went to the
Speaker 6:  CGI because like, it didn't go like the costuming is like, eh,
Speaker 5:  You got to pay the dragons. Dragons are expensive.
Speaker 6:  Like the wigs are bad. Like this cast is not like, I, I'm
Speaker 6:  not seeing this cast just pulling in big numbers financially.
Speaker 4:  It was one time when they were walking up a staircase and there was like,
Speaker 4:  you know, chandelier burning with fire. It's totally in the background. No
Speaker 4:  one else noticed this. I rewatched it three times
Speaker 4:  because of the fake smoke from the fire was that like blocky, pixelated
Speaker 4:  smoke of like fake smoke. And I was like, I
Speaker 4:  know we can do it's 20, 22. Like this looks like an Eddy
Speaker 4:  64. Yeah. I hope they do better. Although I
Speaker 4:  will say like GPU shortages of visual aesthetic is maybe coming
Speaker 4:  around.
Speaker 4:  All right, David, do you want to talk? I have to surprise you with this YouTube
Speaker 4:  TV story.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So, okay. So there was this YouTube TV story. There was a report that
Speaker 5:  YouTube TV is going to let you watch four channels at a time. And it was
Speaker 5:  a, like a private thing that YouTube told a bunch of its partners.
Speaker 5:  And they had some new ideas about shorts and stuff. But this struck me as
Speaker 5:  one of those things. We like, we put it on the site. I was like, oh, that's,
Speaker 5:  that's neat. And then it was like gigantically popular as a story. This is
Speaker 5:  like one of our most read stories this week about like a relatively small
Speaker 5:  feature that is on YouTube TV. And I don't understand why it was so
Speaker 5:  popular, but apparently you do.
Speaker 4:  I do. Cause I looked college football, Twitter ate
Speaker 4:  the story, breakfast like
Speaker 4:  hundreds and hundreds of people were like F yeah, YouTube
Speaker 4:  TV. This is all I've ever wanted. And they definitely did
Speaker 4:  it for sports fans. Yeah. But it's like this one, sometimes the
Speaker 4:  story finds an audience in a way that you will never expect. And this one
Speaker 4:  just landed on college football, Twitter, and everyone's like, we did it.
Speaker 6:  Is it like specific like divisions? Is it just all
Speaker 6:  college football, Twitter?
Speaker 4:  I didn't look that deeply. I think the thing that's interesting here is
Speaker 4:  college football is a sport. You have access to
Speaker 4:  multiple games at once. All the time on Saturdays. Yeah. Right.
Speaker 4:  So like going from channel to channel to see different
Speaker 4:  games is relatively easy. And then it's an easy jump to, I can
Speaker 4:  see how this feature would help me watch more. College football cannot do
Speaker 4:  that with the NFL. Right. It's very hard to get access to lots of games in
Speaker 4:  the NFL. So Sunday ticket, the steam
Speaker 4:  powered app that I use to watch Packers games as some
Speaker 4:  multi-screen features, the ESPN app has multi-screen features,
Speaker 4:  but they don't actually have the content. It's very rare that you're going
Speaker 4:  to watch. You're going to open the ESPN app, watch whatever they have Monday
Speaker 4:  night football. Now I think it all changed. They have eight men on Monday
Speaker 4:  night football now, right?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, that's right. They just paid him crazy amount of money. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And Joe Buck. So they, it's very rare. They're going to open Monday night
Speaker 4:  football and then also be like, well, what else is on ESPN? And it's like
Speaker 4:  curling. Right. But it just doesn't seem like that's this what screen
Speaker 4:  experience you want. I will say the world Excel championships are an ESPN
Speaker 4:  two, which is something that you can, you can just go watch on television.
Speaker 4:  There is incomprehensible. It's like people being like, did you see that
Speaker 4:  formula? He had that in his back pocket the whole time. It's like Denny.
Speaker 4:  It's a real thing.
Speaker 5:  I felt the same way about watching it, that I did about watching ballet,
Speaker 5:  which is sitting there and being like, I'm confident. This is very impressive.
Speaker 5:  And I don't understand any of what's happening. I'm sure this is good
Speaker 5:  and hard. I just need another beer. If I'm going to keep watching
Speaker 5:  basically how I feel
Speaker 4:  Can we should do a live reactive. You watching both ballet and the world
Speaker 4:  Excel chains
Speaker 5:  And people are
Speaker 4:  Like, what's the look on David's face. All right. So that's
Speaker 4:  streaming. Let's talk about Twitter and Ilan a lot
Speaker 4:  going on with the Twitter deal on this week,
Speaker 6:  Mainly Twitter.
Speaker 4:  Well, there was a hearing on discovery, then there's a whistleblower. David,
Speaker 4:  you wanna take us through it?
Speaker 5:  Sure. So, and to your point, Alex, the one of the big open questions of the
Speaker 5:  week was how much this was about Elan. Cause basically the, the like very
Speaker 5:  short version of what happened is Peter Zico. Who's better known in the hacker
Speaker 5:  community as much this like long-term beloved
Speaker 5:  white hat, hacker who everybody believes in, who was briefly the head of
Speaker 5:  security at Twitter then turned whistleblower. And there was this big
Speaker 5:  disclosure this week in which he basically said Twitter as a company
Speaker 5:  is like a total security disaster. Like too many people have access to
Speaker 5:  too much stuff. A bunch of their stuff is not up to date. They're just not
Speaker 5:  running correctly. He was like this whole thing. And then buried in there.
Speaker 5:  He also said, I think in as many words, Twitter is lying to Elon Musk
Speaker 5:  about its spots. So that became a whole thing. But then sort of
Speaker 5:  aside that there's also this big open question about like Twitter as
Speaker 5:  a security nightmare, which has FTC implications because Twitter has basically
Speaker 5:  promised to get its act together in the past. And it brought back all this
Speaker 5:  stuff from two years ago, when all these famous people's accounts on Twitter
Speaker 5:  were hacked by what turned out to be like a couple of teenagers and then
Speaker 5:  used Bitcoin scams to not make very much money. It was like the worst hack
Speaker 5:  of all time, but they did it. And yeah, he basically was
Speaker 5:  like, Twitter is a mess. And I said so internally and they fired me for it.
Speaker 5:  So I have no choice, but to say it publicly. And then Elon Musk showed up
Speaker 5:  and was like, monetizeable daily active users.
Speaker 5:  And now here we are.
Speaker 4:  Okay. So unpacking that just a little bit inside of Mudges filing
Speaker 4:  with the sec, he did it through a law firm called whistleblower
Speaker 4:  aid. So he gets formal whistleblower protections also means he's really not
Speaker 4:  talking to that many people. Right? Here's the filings you can deduce from
Speaker 4:  them what you will. That means the filings are a fun read. They really,
Speaker 4:  Everything it's here are all of his feelings, including
Speaker 4:  feelings like Twitter is a for-profit company. And it's like,
Speaker 4:  yeah, nailed it. Right. Accurate.
Speaker 4:  So there's this part of the filings where mage talks about
Speaker 4:  monetize well daily active users, which is the number of Twitter reports
Speaker 4:  and its earnings because it's the number that counts and all it's a made
Speaker 4:  up number. No one else uses this metric. Twitter uses this metric
Speaker 4:  because it only makes money on ads. So the number of
Speaker 4:  users that it has that are potentially seeing
Speaker 4:  ads is the number that is related to how much money it can
Speaker 4:  make, which is what investors care about. Right? So that means if you use
Speaker 4:  all their Twitter clients, you're not a monetized daily active user because
Speaker 4:  Twitter ads aren't coming in through there, you're not getting them promoted
Speaker 4:  tweets and all this stuff.
Speaker 4:  It means that bots don't count because bots don't buy anything.
Speaker 5:  Bots don't log into Twitter.
Speaker 4:  And so you just got this like mushy definition of what it
Speaker 4:  monetize with daily active user is right. Twitter's claim,
Speaker 4:  is it 5% of its monetized will daily active
Speaker 4:  users are bots. And it that's the number of cares about right,
Speaker 4:  not 5% of all Twitter users. So there are probably
Speaker 4:  many total, there are more things on Twitter and a
Speaker 4:  huge percentage of those are bots is anybody who has interacted with
Speaker 4:  Twitter can probably attest to
Speaker 5:  It is weird because what it says is basically Twitter is saying out of all
Speaker 5:  of our users who aren't bots, less than 5% of them are bots, which is like,
Speaker 5:  seems transparently accurate. Right? But then Elon Musk is saying,
Speaker 5:  well, other people use Twitter who are bots. And
Speaker 5:  Twitter's like, yes, that's. So like everybody is just
Speaker 5:  sort of talking past each other about different things. And Twitter is saying,
Speaker 5:  well, a is true. And Elon Musk is saying, well, what about B? And Twitter's
Speaker 5:  like, well, I dunno, Hey, we just like,
Speaker 4:  And mage is like the Kool-Aid man, all of your liars
Speaker 4:  and thieves and the bots are everywhere. Right. And one of his lines is
Speaker 4:  like Twitter executives get bonuses for growing
Speaker 4:  users and they don't get bonuses for reducing bots. Right.
Speaker 4:  Which on the first cut seems like a totally reasonable thing
Speaker 4:  to say. And then a second cut. You're like, well of course they get bonuses
Speaker 4:  for growing. The number of monetized users tell it
Speaker 5:  Works
Speaker 4:  Everywhere because that's what makes them the money.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And if they hold it at 5% and then they can have infinity bots, as long as
Speaker 4:  the number of money go, the money number comes up.
Speaker 4:  So Elan obviously seizes on this. He's making a lot of noise. I think
Speaker 4:  fundamentally the, the mage whistleblower
Speaker 4:  complaint, like actually validates Twitter's version of events
Speaker 4:  in terms of bots, not all the other stuff, not all the, the government of
Speaker 4:  India has installed agents inside of Twitter to spy on Indian
Speaker 4:  Twitter users who might be dislike. That's very bad, not the too
Speaker 4:  many Twitter employees have password access to everyone's DMS. That
Speaker 4:  seems very bad by the way, Twitter for its part has said all this as a false
Speaker 4:  narrative in Mike's context, which is what you say. I feel like they could
Speaker 4:  have just searched on Twitter for what executives say when accusations are
Speaker 4:  made against her company and just copied and pasted it. And you say, this
Speaker 4:  is a false narrative.
Speaker 5:  It's a really great way to cast dispersions without actually refuting
Speaker 5:  anything like false narrative doesn't mean anything and lacks important context
Speaker 5:  means like we're trying as hard as we can.
Speaker 5:  Okay. That doesn't
Speaker 4:  To be fair. That's what Twitter is saying. Yeah. And then Ilan is seizing
Speaker 4:  on this being like everything I said is true. And then there was a discovery
Speaker 4:  motion in the Delaware Chancery court or favorite court in America, by the
Speaker 4:  way, there's an amazing Twitter account called Chancery daily, which has
Speaker 4:  just been a daily news account for the Chancery court for years.
Speaker 4:  And they're like welcome to the Thunderdome.
Speaker 4:  Cause it's a Lightspeed hardcore courts. So like this, this Twitter
Speaker 4:  accounts absolutely worth the follow because they think the whole thing is
Speaker 4:  so funny. So they have a hearing about discovery. Elan's
Speaker 4:  lawyers request everything. They're like, we can't
Speaker 4:  trust anything Twitter's ever said. We want all the data from the firehose.
Speaker 4:  Joyner says, that's ridiculous, David. I believe the court said Elan was
Speaker 4:  a big dummy.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. The court essentially cited with Twitter. There's this amazing
Speaker 5:  line where they basically said, if we were to do
Speaker 5:  what Musk and his lawyers are asking for Twitter would have to produce
Speaker 5:  trillions and trillions of pages of evidence and data points
Speaker 5:  on it. It was like every possible thing that 200 million users could have
Speaker 5:  maybe done. And it was basically just like, this is lunacy. We're not doing
Speaker 5:  this. So essentially what
Speaker 4:  The specific phrase, by the way, from the court defendants data requests
Speaker 4:  are absurdly broad.
Speaker 5:  There you go.
Speaker 4:  That's good.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So essentially where they landed is basically like they're going to
Speaker 5:  give Elon Musk and his lawyer, his access to the process that Twitter
Speaker 5:  runs in order to make these determinations, which seems to be,
Speaker 5:  I think probably what Twitter would have expected because Twitter has basically
Speaker 5:  been through this process. Like we do a magical process to
Speaker 5:  figure out how many spam bots there are, but we don't keep any data. And
Speaker 5:  we're not going to tell you anything about it, but you should definitely
Speaker 5:  trust us for real. It's totally fine. So like Twitter has definitely obfuscated
Speaker 5:  in the course of trying to figure out how these numbers work, which I would
Speaker 5:  remind everyone is like actually totally material to what happened. And Elon
Speaker 5:  Musk had a lot of time to do due diligence and waved it. And we don't need
Speaker 5:  to do that again. But
Speaker 4:  Now it's an important to explain that a little bit. That's actually,
Speaker 6:  That's my favorite part of all of this.
Speaker 4:  He's doing a good job of convincing everyone that bots are important, but
Speaker 4:  they are not.
Speaker 5:  No, the crux of this deal is that Elon Musk,
Speaker 5:  who initially said that fixing the bot problem was one of the reasons
Speaker 5:  he wanted to buy Twitter, agreed to buy Twitter and signed a binding agreement
Speaker 5:  that had nothing to do with spam bots. There were no bot
Speaker 5:  contingencies in the agreement Elon Musk signed to buy Twitter
Speaker 6:  Waived like the right to even care about it.
Speaker 5:  Yes. So all of this is totally immaterial and seems to be Elon Musk, basically
Speaker 5:  trying to negotiate down the amount and he's going to have to pay to walk
Speaker 5:  away from this deal. Like I, that seems like by a wide margin, the
Speaker 5:  most likely outcome here is that he will write a very big check and walk
Speaker 5:  away. Who knows because it's Elon Musk always assumed the most insane thing
Speaker 5:  is going to happen. So I assume this will go to trial and he'll end up owning
Speaker 5:  Twitter. Like who knows that is the most insane thing. But anyway, where
Speaker 5:  this landed essentially is what it seems like the judge is saying is
Speaker 5:  Twitter needs to be more transparent about the process it runs, but Elon
Speaker 5:  Musk cannot ask Twitter to basically give him everything that has ever happened
Speaker 5:  to anyone in the history of Twitter, which I think is reasonably,
Speaker 4:  I would point out that most of the Island's wealth is in Tesla stock and
Speaker 4:  we didn't cover, this was not a new with us. Tesla had a three for one stock
Speaker 4:  split like today, which was announced ages ago,
Speaker 4:  but
Speaker 6:  Well, and he just sold them bunch. He sold like billions and it was like,
Speaker 6:  it's, it's it's for reasons to worry about it. Everybody's
Speaker 4:  Got Twitter money,
Speaker 6:  Twitter money.
Speaker 4:  So we'll see. I mean, there's just a lot tied up in finances in the market
Speaker 4:  and all this stuff that is like, oh, it's like my CNBC brain,
Speaker 4:  not my Vergecast brain, but I, David, I agree with you. The outcome
Speaker 4:  here is he pays a lot of money to walk away. Like I don't think he wants
Speaker 4:  to own Twitter in the end. I think Twitter maybe has taken a hard look in
Speaker 4:  the mirror and been like, we are a shit show
Speaker 4:  what I feel on a so we'll see. But
Speaker 4:  Chancery daily anchor, like literally this account is having the most fun.
Speaker 4:  It's my new favorite Twitter and also David and Addie and
Speaker 4:  Liz, right this week in Elan, our pop-up Elon Musk
Speaker 4:  newsletter, which has quickly become a must read because there's so
Speaker 4:  much Elon going on lately
Speaker 6:  So much. Yes.
Speaker 4:  I think today, Starlink and T-Mobile have an event right. Where they announced
Speaker 4:  some kind of partnership
Speaker 5:  And Starling also is randomly lowering the prices for some
Speaker 5:  people. Like, I think Thomas Ricker got an email where Starlink was just
Speaker 5:  like your stuff's cheaper now. And he was like meat. Yeah. And that was the
Speaker 5:  end of that
Speaker 4:  Interaction. I did not get that email from store,
Speaker 5:  But yeah, it just, the Elon Musk chaos is relentless
Speaker 5:  and it's never going to go away. Addie's most recent version
Speaker 5:  of this weekend on which is about all of this modern
Speaker 5:  sizable daily active user nonsense is very good and clear and a
Speaker 5:  good read. We'll put it in the show notes for sure.
Speaker 4:  The clock is red. Again. Liam has turned his camera on. He's smiling, but
Speaker 4:  it's not smiling. That means he's, he's mad at you. You know the
Speaker 4:  smile right before they eat. Yeah, that's fine. We got to take a
Speaker 4:  break. We'll be back with a little bit of a lightning round. We'll be right
Speaker 4:  back.
Speaker 9:  This episode is brought to you by rad power bikes. All fun,
Speaker 9:  no fuel hit the road with an award-winning electric bike from north
Speaker 9:  America's largest e-bike brand rad power bikes pedal. When
Speaker 9:  you want throttle, when you don't, they're versatile, e-bikes are a better,
Speaker 9:  more exciting way to get around. And with flexible financing options, you
Speaker 9:  won't have to save up to start riding, want to try an award-winning model
Speaker 9:  from rad power bikes order an electric bike today and ride risk-free with
Speaker 9:  a 14 day trial.
Speaker 10:  This episode is brought to you by Mowen. If you're looking to upgrade your
Speaker 10:  kitchen, you should look to the Mowen smart faucet with motion control,
Speaker 10:  it's sleek, modern, and a totally touchless experience. Turn it
Speaker 10:  on and control the temperature of the water with a wave of your hand.
Speaker 10:  Plus it comes with voice activation and custom voice enabled presets
Speaker 10:  that allow you to create common commands. So you can make your time in the
Speaker 10:  kitchen, feel more magical, learn more at
Speaker 10:  dot com.
Speaker 4:  All right. We're back sliding around time, Liam. It started the clock. The
Speaker 4:  best part about the clock I have to say is, I don't know how long it's set
Speaker 4:  for. So it just turns red,
Speaker 6:  Yellow. First orange,
Speaker 5:  Whenever Liam gets bored, he just takes it to red and says, shut up
Speaker 4:  Three minutes of this is enough. We're done. Vergecast over. All right.
Speaker 4:  Lightning round Alex, which got
Speaker 6:  Well, Chris Welch found yesterday. I was in the office with Chris Welch and
Speaker 6:  he said, Hey, Alex, check slack. There's a scoop. You need to edit. And I
Speaker 6:  went, oh, and then I clicked. And I was like, Hey Chris, you wrote a scoop.
Speaker 6:  That's what happened? So he got a scoop, a little scoop magnet
Speaker 6:  getting all the scoops. That's not a word. Is it scoop
Speaker 4:  Mac?
Speaker 5:  Chris Welch appears to just live in that
Speaker 4:  Side of size. We're on the clock. Okay. Who knows when this is going to
Speaker 4:  turn red?
Speaker 6:  Sorry, Liam. Any minute he's going to turn a red. I finished talking
Speaker 6:  do speaker. Basically. It sounds like Sonos is going to be Sonus
Speaker 6:  is working on a new speaker. That's all the reporting that Chris Welch got
Speaker 6:  and it looks like it will probably replace the play five,
Speaker 6:  which is the like kind of its flagship speaker that hasn't been
Speaker 6:  replaced in the years. I think it's the only one that hasn't had like a big
Speaker 6:  update and it's going to have a
Speaker 6:  lot of speakers in it, firing in a lot of directions instead of just
Speaker 6:  like speakers, firing one direction. As most of
Speaker 6:  them do this, going to fire, like forward to the
Speaker 6:  sides up. So it'll also have some Atmos support
Speaker 6:  and it looks like it's, there's just going to be a smaller one
Speaker 6:  as well. More like the Sonos one that will do the same thing
Speaker 6:  with the up firing speakers. So it feels very Atmos intense.
Speaker 6:  And it's going to be called right now. It's code named the Optimo
Speaker 4:  Two, which really implies there's an Altima one. Yes
Speaker 5:  It does.
Speaker 6:  We don't know what that is. Unfortunately,
Speaker 5:  I can't figure it out about this speaker is where it goes. Cause it's like,
Speaker 5:  if it's going to do this sort of firing in all directions thing, it's like,
Speaker 5:  it's very sort of home potty in that sense. And so it's like, maybe it's
Speaker 5:  a, you know, you put it next to your TV and use it for music
Speaker 5:  or is it like a semi soundbar thing? And it does surround sound
Speaker 5:  all by itself. Like what is this thing going to be?
Speaker 6:  I think I'm supposed to do all of the things like what he was looking at.
Speaker 6:  A lot of the stuff he's gotten suggests that this is going to be one of the
Speaker 6:  best sounding speakers they've made. Sonus is very good at making speakers.
Speaker 6:  That sound really, really good. And this one is
Speaker 6:  something that you'll be able to put, you know, use it as that soundbar get
Speaker 6:  three of them up front and you and a sub woofer. And you've got 3.1
Speaker 6:  surround sound, right? Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Well, you'll have 3.1 0.2 surround sound,
Speaker 6:  Right? Cause you've got the, the Atmos upward firing speakers.
Speaker 6:  So I think that's the plan here is, is most of the
Speaker 6:  money that Sonos is making nowadays is in that home theater space. That's
Speaker 6:  really where it's moved. It's moved away from speakers in every room of the
Speaker 6:  house to TV. Let's do that better. And this could
Speaker 6:  theoretically help that without having a big ugly soundbar
Speaker 4:  Every now and again, I find myself reading our site like a reader, and then
Speaker 4:  I have these moments. So there's a line here. The verge is viewed early
Speaker 4:  work in progress, images of Optimo too. And I was like, wait, that's
Speaker 4:  me. I viewed this images. You saw the person
Speaker 4:  I hooked them together.
Speaker 4:  So the Kong is like a really interesting like case, right? Cause it had all
Speaker 4:  these, the big home hub, not the little one and all these drivers in it.
Speaker 4:  And apple was really intent on doing beam forming. It would
Speaker 4:  measure the echoes in your room in real time. It would use the
Speaker 4:  walls and like send some frequencies of the walls to create like a full
Speaker 4:  surround sound. And like they said, a lot of things about the home pod
Speaker 4:  in the end, it was just a nice sounding speaker.
Speaker 5:  It did sound good though. It was a ridiculous product, but it sounded really
Speaker 5:  good.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Two of them sounded infinitely better than one, which I think was there
Speaker 4:  miss factually, it was like, it was fine. It that
Speaker 4:  my thing with the home pod was always, if you are the sort of person
Speaker 4:  who has the capacity to listen to a home pod and a
Speaker 4:  Sonos five and whatever the else, like in a line, you'll put
Speaker 4:  the home pod in the top two. But if you are not doing that
Speaker 4:  specific exercise, you cannot tell the difference between them
Speaker 5:  Fair,
Speaker 4:  Right? Like expensive speakers of that class are all just kind of different
Speaker 4:  in all kinds of the same. This feels like not that to me,
Speaker 4:  because I think it is aimed at that big Atmos music market.
Speaker 4:  That is a differentiator for Sonos. Very few products
Speaker 4:  do Atmos music. So we'll see. I don't think it's actually targeted at
Speaker 4:  TV stuff. And then I think that might, yeah, they've got soundbars for that.
Speaker 4:  And that's like their big sandbar sales are down because TV sales are down
Speaker 4:  and you buy a sandbar when you buy a new TV and rarely people upgrade their
Speaker 4:  sound, but the clock turned yellow. I'm freaking out.
Speaker 4:  I think this is a music speaker, like a high end music speaker to do like
Speaker 4:  Atmos audio, which I think is, it will be interesting for
Speaker 4:  Sonos to try to convince, play five customers to upgrade.
Speaker 6:  So now we're going to have led Zeppelin's descend from a wire above
Speaker 4:  Jimmy page to sneaking up behind you. That's all.
Speaker 4:  Anybody's, that's all anybody's ever wanted
Speaker 4:  by the way, USB-C line in potentially on this device, which is
Speaker 4:  wacky. All right, I'll do. What's my lightning round.
Speaker 4:  Oh, I got to talk about Peloton. All right. Let me just read you this quote.
Speaker 4:  There will be no further discussion because the clock's yellow.
Speaker 4:  This is the CEO, the new CEO of Peloton Barry
Speaker 4:  McCarthy. He's writing a letter to shareholders. This is how the letter
Speaker 4:  ends in high school. I spent three months working on a cargo
Speaker 4:  ship after midnight on my second voyage, I was asleep. When the
Speaker 4:  alarm for the general quarters woke me, my reporting station was on the bridge
Speaker 4:  and sentence. Next sentence. Fear is a great motivator,
Speaker 4:  long story. The ship is leaning. The captains, trying to turn the ship
Speaker 4:  around. We saved two men's lives at night. They'd been lost at sea in the
Speaker 4:  Mediterranean for several days of fortunate. Happy ending. Peloton is
Speaker 4:  like that. Cargo ship we've sounded the alarm everyone's at their
Speaker 4:  station. We continue to add new inputs to evolve our go-to market strategy
Speaker 4:  to restore growth. When will the ship respond? Is the question.
Speaker 4:  Our goal is fiscal year 23.
Speaker 5:  Does he think he just invented the idea of a big
Speaker 5:  ship being hard to turn into that that's a useful metaphor for business?
Speaker 5:  Like has he, he just, but he's been on a
Speaker 5:  ship.
Speaker 4:  I just know that when big companies wait, what was the burning? Who is the
Speaker 4:  burning platform? Nokia guy, hold on. Oh my God. The clock's yellow.
Speaker 4:  Ah,
Speaker 5:  Steven ILA.
Speaker 4:  Yes. Longtime Vergecast listeners will remember the last time we
Speaker 4:  discussed ocean metaphors for companies. It was our
Speaker 4:  boy, Steven Elop who left Microsoft,
Speaker 4:  became the CEO of Nokia and then sold Nokia to Microsoft
Speaker 4:  in a move. No one saw it coming.
Speaker 5:  He scared
Speaker 4:  Kenny Elof again, but he sent a memo that was like two people are
Speaker 4:  standing on a burning oil platform in the middle of the frigid sea, and their
Speaker 4:  choices to be engulfed in flames or jump into the frozen ocean.
Speaker 4:  And we Nokia are using windows phone, which in this
Speaker 4:  metaphor was the frozen ocean,
Speaker 4:  big, big burning platform vibes from Barry McCarthy. Anyway, we'll see,
Speaker 4:  Peloton is lost like a billion dollars this quarter. And they're like, we're
Speaker 4:  on track. Very good.
Speaker 5:  It's a real, like, like trust the process move.
Speaker 5:  Like there was this NBA team, the Philadelphia 76, who sucked so bad for
Speaker 5:  like six years. And they were like, trust us. We're going to be good eventually.
Speaker 5:  And then they weren't is this alert at the end of that?
Speaker 4:  That's my process. There was, they threw a lot of games to get draft picks
Speaker 4:  and then blew the draft.
Speaker 5:  Correct?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. You have to do a good thing at the end of the process, which is what
Speaker 5:  Peloton
Speaker 4:  Fear is a great motivator.
Speaker 4:  Got to read this. It's just like the hardest cut in the middle of this paragraph.
Speaker 5:  Terrific.
Speaker 4:  All right, David what's yours.
Speaker 5:  Mine is this news that came out just before we started recording that Ford
Speaker 5:  is hiking the price for the 2023 Mustang Mach II by as much as
Speaker 5:  $8,000. And this is part of a bigger thing where there was a
Speaker 5:  study that the average price of an electric vehicle has gone up like almost
Speaker 5:  50%. And this is bad for like a lot of
Speaker 5:  like climate change. We need more electric vehicles reasons, but it's particularly
Speaker 5:  bad for me because I have to buy a car. And every
Speaker 5:  single day it feels like I just like watch more of my money, disappear into
Speaker 5:  the car buying process. And I haven't even bought a car yet. It's not great.
Speaker 4:  Well, one, you got to buy a card for the end of the year because the tax
Speaker 4:  credit situation next year is going silent. So I'm also like,
Speaker 4:  okay, I gotta do. I gotta go buy an Evie.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Are you deaf doing?
Speaker 5:  I don't know. This is like an ongoing debate with my wife because we don't
Speaker 5:  really, we don't have a driveway. So our like overnight charging infrastructure
Speaker 5:  is less than ideal, but like two years from now, David is going to
Speaker 5:  feel really stupid if I don't buy an Evie. So I don't know. I'm I'm
Speaker 5:  torn.
Speaker 6:  That's why I at least, cause I was like, oh, I really want Eve. But I live
Speaker 6:  in New York city and it's not great.
Speaker 4:  So, oh my God.
Speaker 6:  I'm sorry. I'm sorry. I guess it was great.
Speaker 6:  Nevermind. Keep going.
Speaker 4:  What kind of podcast for nerds is that's wait, it's this
Speaker 4:  podcast for nerds?
Speaker 4:  Well, she got to buy one because we got a great explainer from Andy. That's
Speaker 4:  getting way more complicated. Especially if the cars aren't made like
Speaker 4:  fewer cars will qualify next year because some of them aren't made in the
Speaker 4:  United States, like the V6, the BMWs, and then
Speaker 4:  a few years from now. If the batteries are made in United States, nothing
Speaker 4:  will qualify. So there's like a race. I was at a car dealer today this morning,
Speaker 4:  actually, because I decided that I should not buy it like a $10,000 beater,
Speaker 4:  BMW and buy something that might put my family in.
Speaker 5:  I really like imagining you every morning, just swinging by. And they like,
Speaker 5:  they see you coming and they're like, make me lies here. And you like know
Speaker 5:  all the people at the dealership by name. Now,
Speaker 6:  Hear
Speaker 4:  Him watching a car dealer, go from thinking that I'm an easy mark to being
Speaker 4:  like, oh my God, dude, this guy, Thomas, I have no cars to sell
Speaker 4:  just this week a Jeep, which has still not shipped the hybrid grand Cherokee
Speaker 4:  sent everyone hats. Did
Speaker 5:  They announce it again?
Speaker 4:  They've announced it again. This week they sent everyone hats who had
Speaker 4:  pre-ordered. Some of the clock went from red to blue, which is, I don't know
Speaker 4:  what's going on. It's even worse when it's down, it
Speaker 4:  starts roping. But you got to buy a car
Speaker 4:  before the new year. If you want the credit, because next year it's going
Speaker 4:  to go sideways. But there are no cars to buy also Ford going up
Speaker 4:  by $8,000 when they are now guaranteed to get more
Speaker 4:  $7,500 tax credits, every dealer is going to say, it's the
Speaker 4:  price went up, but just cross it out. You're getting it right back. And I
Speaker 4:  think that's fairly cynical on Ford's part. Yes, we'll see. But
Speaker 4:  the wrong is that you can't buy any of these cars. Like what are we even
Speaker 4:  complaining about?
Speaker 5:  There seems to be no better insight. Like it's it's the chip shortage keeps
Speaker 5:  going. The people are like, everybody bought too much stuff. It's like,
Speaker 5:  we're this doesn't seem like it's going to get any better. Like shortly.
Speaker 4:  The problem with EVs is not so much the trip shortage it's battery shortage.
Speaker 4:  Ford has no battery capacity. That's the problem that needs to solve. That's
Speaker 4:  actually why the future tax credits are pegged to battery manufacturing.
Speaker 4:  The United States, because the government's like, we know you need battery
Speaker 4:  capacity. You better put it here. If you want these credits, you have the
Speaker 6:  Chip shortage. I started to go away. Right?
Speaker 4:  That's tough. I don't know the answer. I ask people. The
Speaker 4:  CEO of arm is going to be indicators in the podcast that we don't talk about
Speaker 4:  it. The show
Speaker 5:  Never heard of it.
Speaker 4:  It took me the whole episode. This time, Liam. Lena's not just on the clock.
Speaker 4:  Right?
Speaker 6:  Good. Where did you work? What was the magazine you worked at that we're
Speaker 6:  not allowed
Speaker 5:  To name? I don't know who, who can remember.
Speaker 4:  Let's see if anybody can sell me an electric car, please play
Speaker 4:  whatever it is. As long as I can plug it into something
Speaker 6:  On the Dakota,
Speaker 4:  We're a new whole episode where a car salesman just has to deal with me.
Speaker 4:  It'll be maybe our best episode.
Speaker 5:  So I love
Speaker 4:  It. Like listening to the sound of a car salesman or
Speaker 4:  salesperson, listening to the sound of a car salesperson's voice. When I
Speaker 4:  ask exactly which version of adaptive cruise control the car has
Speaker 4:  is, they're just like, I don't know, man. And then I say something like,
Speaker 4:  can you take a picture of the cruise control stock and send it to me? And
Speaker 4:  they're like, what? Because that's the level on habits.
Speaker 5:  And then you say things like, oh, well, when the Ford CEO was on decoder,
Speaker 5:  he told me and they're like, what?
Speaker 4:  It's real bad. Anyway, that's our show. The clock is turning all
Speaker 4:  kinds of colors. Now Liam's gone from smiling to frown and God
Speaker 4:  he's very cute from, yeah, that's it.
Speaker 4:  That's the show you can tweet at us. David is at Pierce. Alex is Alex H
Speaker 4:  Kranz I'm at reckless. You can go read that story. The
Speaker 4:  iPhone killer, which David just had another emotional reaction to when I
Speaker 4:  said it, you really were in a world of shit for like a month after that store.
Speaker 5:  Oh it was it. Yeah. Yeah. It was. It helped to have quotes.
Speaker 5:  I'll just say that
Speaker 4:  From the record.
Speaker 5:  I didn't say it. Yeah. Kevin Lynch
Speaker 4:  Did. Why are we, why do we hammer home about being on the record so much?
Speaker 4:  Cause it's not our fault. All right. That's it. There's a bunch of
Speaker 4:  great stuff on the verge. Love more coverage coming up of the upcoming apple
Speaker 4:  event. What's next week on the Wednesday episode, David
Speaker 5:  We're off next.
Speaker 4:  Okay. What was this week on Wednesday episode David,
Speaker 5:  This week we spent the whole episode talking about the stream deck and
Speaker 5:  buttons because the Vergecast let's button and it was a
Speaker 5:  very fun episode. And Eva, did you wanna have a stream deck? You should listen
Speaker 5:  to it. Although there's like a 40% chance you will end up buying a stream
Speaker 5:  deck at the end of it. Yes.
Speaker 4:  It's very true. Someone sent us a picture of a rack Mount street back in
Speaker 4:  now. That's all I want in the world and crap again. All right, that's it.
Speaker 4:  We did it Leah
Speaker 1:  And that's a wrap for verge cast this week. Thanks for listening. If you
Speaker 1:  enjoy the show, subscribe in the podcast app of your choice or tell a friend,
Speaker 1:  you can send us feedback@vergecastattheburj.com. This show is
Speaker 1:  produced by me, Liam, James, and our senior audio director, Andrew marina.
Speaker 1:  This episode was edited and mixed by Amanda Rowe Smith. Our editorial
Speaker 1:  director is Brooke mentors and our executive producer is Eleanor Donovan.
Speaker 1:  The verge cast is a production of the verge and box media podcast network.
Speaker 1:  And that's it. We'll see you next week.
Speaker 3:  This episode was sponsored by Salesforce. Pivot is coming to
Speaker 3:  TV, sort of with the help of Salesforce. Plus
Speaker 3:  pivot listeners will now be able to watch for video segments of our podcast
Speaker 3:  every week, exclusively on their platform, but that's not all
Speaker 3:  Salesforce plus is a free streaming service that provides live
Speaker 3:  experiences, original series podcasts, and other programming to help inspire
Speaker 3:  business leaders all around the globe. Sign up today to watch pivot
Speaker 3:  and more exclusive content free at
Speaker 3:  salesforce.com/plus that's
Speaker 3:  salesforce.com/p L U S.