# Transcript
ID: 76dea4a0-3eec-11ed-8638-0ff4f927588c
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Handheld gaming, scooter subscriptions, and a Techtober preview
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-2306468513241337010/8631451108938126955/s93290-US-3493s-1664342007.mp3
Description: Today on the flagship podcast of low-latency controller input:
02:12 - David Pierce talks with Tom Warren about the trend of handheld gaming devices like Valve's Steam Deck and the Logitech's G Cloud Gaming Handheld.
21:20 - David tries subscribing to a scooter rental service and starts to rethink the concept of ownership.
33:40 - David chats with Nilay Patel and Alex Cranz about the ten big tech events happening this October.
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we'd love to hear from you.
We are conducting a short audience survey to help plan for our future and hear from you. To participate, head to vox.com/podsurvey, and thank you!
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (5 ads detected)
Speaker 2:  Welcome to the Vergecast, the flagship podcast of Low Latency controller
Speaker 2:  input. I'm your friend David Pierce and I am currently on a
Speaker 2:  scooter riding around my neighborhood trying to find a place that will sell
Speaker 2:  print magazines. It's a long story, but basically if you see a copy of New
Speaker 2:  York Magazine with a full page vergecast ad in it, send me a picture. I
Speaker 2:  really wanna see it. Anyway, we have an awesome show for you today. We're
Speaker 2:  gonna talk to Tom Warren about the steam deck and the Nintendo Switch
Speaker 2:  and the Logitech G Cloud gaming handheld, which is the worst
Speaker 2:  name ever. But there's all kinds of interesting stuff happening with handheld
Speaker 2:  gaming consoles and we're gonna get into all of it. We're also gonna talk
Speaker 2:  about scooters and how the way that we ride and try and buy them
Speaker 2:  is changing because it is changing. And we're gonna talk about all of the
Speaker 2:  tech events coming up in the next several weeks because there are a ton of
Speaker 2:  them. Product announcements, trials, other product announcements. It's gonna
Speaker 2:  be a big one. We're gonna figure out what's interesting and what is it all
Speaker 2:  that's coming up in just a second. But first I gotta get this scooter home
Speaker 2:  because I'm down to one bar of battery and things could get bleak pretty
Speaker 2:  quickly. Here. This is the Vercast scene in a sec.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. So one of the most interesting things happening
Speaker 2:  in the gaming world right now is that handheld consoles are making
Speaker 2:  a big comeback.
Speaker 2:  The steam deck and the Nintendo Switch have both been big hits and now
Speaker 2:  there's the new Logitech G Cloud gaming handheld, which is a terrible
Speaker 2:  name, but seems to be a very interesting product. These are all an
Speaker 2:  interesting confluence of a bunch of things. Faster chips, which mean you
Speaker 2:  can do more with less hardware, new kinds of games and maybe
Speaker 2:  most of all, a really big push toward cloud gaming. The idea
Speaker 2:  that most of the work done to show you video games should happen somewhere
Speaker 2:  else and then just stream it to you like Netflix. It's a really interesting
Speaker 2:  moment and there's a lot more to come over the next few years in this space.
Speaker 2:  So Tom Warren is here to talk about all of it.
Speaker 2:  Hi Tom. Thank you for being here. Hello,
Speaker 1:  Good to see you and good to meet
Speaker 2:  You. There's like a bunch of things going on here simultaneously, which is
Speaker 2:  kind of what I wanted to talk about. But I think the place I wanna start
Speaker 2:  is this weird new Logitech thing, the
Speaker 2:  G Cloud handheld, which is I think like the all time worst game
Speaker 2:  console name.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Put this thing in context for me, like why does this thing exist? What, what
Speaker 2:  is it here for?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, that's, that's probably my biggest question as well actually.
Speaker 5:  So it's, it's essentially an Android tablet
Speaker 5:  that will basically run any Android mobile game within
Speaker 5:  reason, you know, cuz it doesn't have like the best chip inside, but really
Speaker 5:  that's not how they're marketing it. They're marketing it as a, as a device
Speaker 5:  that will connect up to cloud gaming streaming services like in
Speaker 5:  video GForce now and obviously exports cloud gaming and stuff and
Speaker 5:  they've worked with video and Microsoft for this, but when they say they've
Speaker 5:  worked with these two companies, it's pretty light work. Okay, let's put
Speaker 5:  it that way. But either way it's, it's basically an Android tablet that connects
Speaker 5:  up to cloud gaming and that's the way that they kind of see the vision of
Speaker 5:  the future of handheld is that you know, you're not necessarily gonna be
Speaker 5:  doing local compute and local gaming that you might wanna play triple eight
Speaker 5:  games. You know, the games that you don't typically get on mobile but that
Speaker 5:  you don't wanna do that on your phone with, you know, one of those clipon
Speaker 5:  cases that's just gonna drain your battery life and all this sort of stuff.
Speaker 5:  So it's, it's kind of a bet but it's an interestingly timed bet I think.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, let, let's talk about the timing of this cuz I think that sort of overarching
Speaker 2:  vision you just described makes tons of sense to me, right? I think the,
Speaker 2:  the idea that like a video game should be an 80 gigabyte thing on a hard
Speaker 2:  drive somewhere in my house, like just can't be the future. Like it just
Speaker 2:  seems wrong to me that that is where all of this is headed. So in theory
Speaker 2:  the idea of cloud gaming, especially as these things become more sort of
Speaker 2:  massively multiplayer and like, like Fortnite should be a cloud game, that
Speaker 2:  makes total sense to me. Yeah. But it does seem like to some extent
Speaker 2:  this all might be happening before the world is
Speaker 2:  ready for it. Whether it's like the gaming industry or even like the internet
Speaker 2:  bandwidths, but everybody seems to be betting on it like right this minute.
Speaker 2:  So like what do you make of the timing of all this?
Speaker 5:  That's definitely the best way to describe it that it's not quite there
Speaker 5:  yet. And I think with Logitech they've obviously gone all in on the marketing
Speaker 5:  of this being a cloud handheld and, and really not even really talked about
Speaker 5:  like the local installing Android games like you would on a bunch of this.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, it's like on the side they're like, oh also it has YouTube. Yeah
Speaker 5:  It's like,
Speaker 5:  so the marketing's a little bit, a little bit wonky there. I think it all
Speaker 5:  comes back to how we perceive cloud at the moment. So I think
Speaker 5:  a lot of the success that we're seeing with cloud gaming is where it's an
Speaker 5:  add-on, it's an optional thing. It's like a bonus, let's put it,
Speaker 5:  put it that way, but it's not the center of a service. So obviously Google
Speaker 5:  tried with Stadia to put that as the center of your gaming, the stadium
Speaker 5:  basically of your, all your cloud gaming's visions essentially. But it
Speaker 5:  didn't kind of work because people weren't really ready just to be always
Speaker 5:  connected, always online to play these things. And that kind of comes back
Speaker 5:  to, to Logitech, this thing only has wifi so it doesn't have a sim
Speaker 5:  card inside. So you know, you hop on a plane or a train or in your car
Speaker 5:  or whatever instantly you don't have connectivity so it's, you fall back
Speaker 5:  to whatever's installing device, right? So I think until
Speaker 5:  that's all there, these kind of devices are a little bit too early. I think
Speaker 5:  I get the vision of them but I think also the pricing here is a little bit
Speaker 5:  of an awkwardly priced sort of model cuz it is, it is 2
Speaker 5:  99 if you pre-order it, but in reality it's 3 49 which sits
Speaker 5:  perfectly in between and tender switch at 2 99 and then the
Speaker 5:  the steam deck at three nine. So it's like who is this exactly for
Speaker 5:  like right now in five years? It makes sense maybe and and probably the
Speaker 5:  pricing will change but yeah like the infrastructure's not quite there and
Speaker 5:  just I think the general selling of something is just
Speaker 5:  cloud or like primarily cloud. It's just not quite the the best way
Speaker 5:  to market something right now.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, it's an interesting thing cuz I think even if it's true that
Speaker 2:  most games people play require them to be online, which yeah
Speaker 2:  it's probably not like all the way true but it's definitely more true than
Speaker 2:  it was even a few years ago. The idea that all of a sudden my device
Speaker 2:  is useless if I don't have an internet connection, it's actually, it's like
Speaker 2:  Chromebooks in a weird way, right? It's like do you need the internet to
Speaker 2:  do anything useful on your laptop? Like yes of course. Does it still feel
Speaker 2:  weird that your laptop is an absolute useless piece of junk if you don't
Speaker 2:  have an internet connection also? Yes. And so I feel like we're in this sort
Speaker 2:  of weird middle space where like even if it's true, the
Speaker 2:  experience as you would get it, it just feels bad.
Speaker 5:  The finger chrome boots is that we probably all laughed at them like 10 years
Speaker 5:  ago is just a browser and all that sort stuff, but like now you live in the
Speaker 5:  browser like everything, right? Browser technology's got so much better that
Speaker 5:  that you don't need those outside apps. So it's, it's less of a problem but
Speaker 5:  like a Chromebook I'm not necessarily using in the back of a car but like
Speaker 5:  a kid who wants to play games, it's probably using that at the back of a
Speaker 5:  car so that like this sort of device just isn't quite there for that. For
Speaker 5:  like where the Nintendo switch and even the, the steam deck has has really
Speaker 5:  sort of risen and in popularity and really proved that these powerful
Speaker 5:  handheld gaming computers basically are on the way. This thing
Speaker 5:  is kind of putting away from that, that vision. But like I think it is, you
Speaker 5:  know, in 10 years sure that's the way things are heading. Like cloud gaming
Speaker 5:  at the moment. I think in videos GForce now with the RTX
Speaker 5:  30 80 edition or whatever they call it, that thing is probably the closest
Speaker 5:  that we get to like actually like I, I play that on my gaming
Speaker 5:  here and like it's the closest thing to actually being s to
Speaker 5:  competitive to that, which is quite a feat for cloud gaming at the moment.
Speaker 5:  But until we, until we get that like really aligned and the infrastructure
Speaker 5:  and everything like that, it's just, it's just a little bit too early to
Speaker 5:  rely on that I think right now.
Speaker 2:  So with cloud gaming in general, one of the reasons I wanna talk to you is
Speaker 2:  like I think you are a much more intense gamer than I am. So like I play
Speaker 2:  cloud games and I play like I play a lot of like FIFA and like
Speaker 2:  fall guys, the kinds of games where like teeny tiny bits of input
Speaker 2:  lag don't bother me. Yeah. And the story I've heard from people over and
Speaker 2:  over and over again is that like actually input lag is not as hard a problem
Speaker 2:  as you think because it's just this tiny piece of data that actually as long
Speaker 2:  as you have pretty good downstream video, which increasingly lots and lots
Speaker 2:  of people do then, then your input is actually not gonna be the hold up over
Speaker 2:  time. I have also heard and seen a lot of people who play much
Speaker 2:  like faster twitch, more intense games say that that is a marketing lie
Speaker 2:  and actually input lag is still a real problem and it's kind of holding
Speaker 2:  this whole experience back. What do you make of it?
Speaker 5:  So I think it all depends on what games you play and how you play them.
Speaker 5:  So if you're used to playing on like a a, you know, PS4 or an Xbox One
Speaker 5:  or a TV that isn't o led and you are used to that latency, then
Speaker 5:  there will actually be very little difference between moving to cloud gaming
Speaker 5:  because that TV has a bunch of latency anyway and those, those consoles do.
Speaker 5:  So when you, when you add up all that system latency versus all the network
Speaker 5:  and displayed latency on cloud gaming, sometimes it's about the same.
Speaker 5:  So it's all what you perceive. So like imagine you have a one gig
Speaker 5:  internet connection and that's what you're used to and then someone else
Speaker 5:  has, you know, a hundred meg and that's what they're used to. You obviously
Speaker 5:  have different expectations of the quality of your internet whereas those
Speaker 5:  people won't have those expectations until they have that one gig. So it's,
Speaker 5:  it's, there's also the same, so if you're a PC gamer and you have low latency
Speaker 5:  super quick games for special shooters, you go play cloud
Speaker 5:  gaming, you're probably gonna hate it cuz you're used to such low latency
Speaker 5:  that like anything just feels laggy. But if you're the other way around you
Speaker 5:  are a console gamer, you don't have no LED tv, which you know is super low
Speaker 5:  latency, it's all what you perceive and then those games like yeah like
Speaker 5:  platformers, all those sort of games that you usually use controller for,
Speaker 5:  you're not really gonna notice latency as much but you, if you're playing
Speaker 5:  a twitchy first person shoot you're playing fortnight, you'll probably notice
Speaker 5:  it more or call you.
Speaker 2:  As always the rule is don't buy nice things because it ruins everything else
Speaker 2:  for you. So that's basically, that's basically the play here.
Speaker 5:  But yeah like if you, if you do have an old consult and you're thinking,
Speaker 5:  you know, should I upgrade to get enough consult? Should it go cloud gaming?
Speaker 5:  Like it is surprisingly good now it's getting there, it's just, it all
Speaker 5:  really does depend on your, your latency at home, your internet connection,
Speaker 5:  how far you are away from these services as well where you live in the world
Speaker 5:  like that makes the biggest difference really. So,
Speaker 2:  And then on the handheld front, your point about the G-Cloud handheld, which
Speaker 2:  is again just the worst name being right in the middle of the switch and
Speaker 2:  the steam deck is really interesting cuz I do think like that seems to be
Speaker 2:  sort of the spectrum. The switch is like the simple thing
Speaker 2:  with some kind of online capability. The steam deck is like the massively
Speaker 2:  powerful PC in your hand and the G-cloud handheld is somewhere in
Speaker 2:  the middle. And if I were a betting man I feel like I would bet on the stream
Speaker 2:  deck getting, sorry, the steam deck, God these
Speaker 5:  Names
Speaker 2:  I would bet on the steam deck getting smaller and cheaper and
Speaker 2:  better quicker than some of these other devices can go in the other
Speaker 2:  direction. What do you
Speaker 5:  Think? Yeah, I think that's fair because the steam deck is pretty, is pretty
Speaker 5:  chunky. The battery life is not very good. That's one thing that Logitech
Speaker 5:  is, is kind of really honing in on is the bachelor they have like 12
Speaker 5:  hours, which is kind of insane for a handheld That'd be amazing. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  like that, that's, that's great. But obviously it's all, you're just basically
Speaker 5:  streaming video on it. So, which
Speaker 2:  Is part of the appeal, right? Like the whole upside of cloud gaming is, it's
Speaker 2:  just all you need is a screen and a battery and all the hard work is being
Speaker 2:  done somewhere else.
Speaker 5:  But with the steam deck I have a steam deck and I can do all this cloud gaming
Speaker 5:  on there anyway. So like I, I get the benefits of that. It's, it's not as
Speaker 5:  obviously as easy to set up. It's, it's a bit of a process cause it's all
Speaker 5:  Linux based and it's all just, you know, you feel like you're hacking sort
Speaker 5:  of thing. Yeah and it's not, it's not as easy to use but like it is definitely
Speaker 5:  interesting that this, this G Cloud gaming handheld thing is in the middle
Speaker 5:  of those two price points. Cause I think if the pricing was a little bit
Speaker 5:  less, there'd be less of a, I've seen like a kind of reaction to it like
Speaker 5:  whoa the price, you know, cuz it is a surprising price when you put it in,
Speaker 5:  in context of those two devices as well. And like on the, on the street side
Speaker 5:  it's very portable is very usable and easy, you know the usability is
Speaker 5:  easy for anyone to pick up and install stuff. But the steam deck, you know
Speaker 5:  like that's, unless you're playing just pure pc, you know,
Speaker 5:  steam games, then you wanna load on emulators or you wanna get to cloud gaming,
Speaker 5:  that gets a little bit more complicated right now. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  Yeah. The steam deck's a lot of work.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, they've got some work to do there on improving the user experience.
Speaker 5:  But I dunno what Logitech would do to then go in the other way to sort of
Speaker 5:  like more support local gaming. So they'd have to like beef up the processor
Speaker 5:  a little bit and that obviously adds to the expense. So yeah, it's a little
Speaker 5:  bit tricky in both directions but it is just definitely interesting where,
Speaker 5:  where it is in the middle.
Speaker 2:  Totally. And the thing that amazes me the most is that Microsoft and Sony
Speaker 2:  are, for all intents and purposes, nowhere to be found here. I mean it's,
Speaker 2:  yeah you've gotta figure there's a handheld Xbox
Speaker 2:  or like the PS VTA is gonna come back, right? Like these have to be coming.
Speaker 5:  Yeah like I think we've, with Sony's case, their cloud gaming
Speaker 5:  platform isn't quite there yet. You know, they, they've still got some work
Speaker 5:  to do to to to make that a little bit better and a bit more usable. But
Speaker 5:  Mo's case, this is basically their exports handheld in a way like, I
Speaker 5:  mean they've kind of co-market with Logitech. It's like
Speaker 2:  Oh
Speaker 5:  Interesting. Yeah, it's interesting they've used a bunch of their marketing
Speaker 5:  channels to sort of back this up, which they do a lot of the time with like
Speaker 5:  close partners and stuff. But there is rumors of exports, handhelds there
Speaker 5:  has been for like as, I dunno like 10 years, you know, like it's just a constant
Speaker 5:  rumor and you have to imagine that if Microsoft was gonna do an export handheld,
Speaker 5:  it would probably be similar to what Logic text vision is there with
Speaker 5:  you know, a focus on cloud gaming. Cuz it, it just makes sense.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. What is your sense within Microsoft? Cuz I think there's a sort of
Speaker 2:  outside sense that cloud gaming and Game Pass are what Microsoft
Speaker 2:  sees as like the future. Like that is, that is the big bet of all of this.
Speaker 2:  But then obviously we're still in a point where contracts are complicated
Speaker 2:  and the way that video games get made is having to change. And also Microsoft
Speaker 2:  is actually like buying every gaming developer can find. So if, if
Speaker 2:  Microsoft is gonna like lead the charge here and it kind of seems like it
Speaker 2:  is, where are we headed? What, what's the next like year or so gonna look
Speaker 2:  like, do you think?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I mean in the short term I think it's very much of, of what it
Speaker 5:  has been the last couple of years, which is their big focus on Game Pass,
Speaker 5:  which is kind of what they've been pushing. But I think in the longer term
Speaker 5:  you can see where it's lining up. They want the industry to move to a model
Speaker 5:  where they basically support game developers and studios. They'll come
Speaker 5:  to them and say, look, if you put it on day one on Game Pass, we'll you know,
Speaker 5:  invest this amount of money into your game or help you with this amount of
Speaker 5:  marketing. All that sort of stuff. Which is deals that they've done traditionally
Speaker 5:  in the past to have exclusivity or some sort of marketing rights over the
Speaker 5:  game or even publishing it in all this sort of game industry
Speaker 5:  mechanics. And I think that's where they're ultimately trying to push the
Speaker 5:  industry towards. And I think Sony's obviously pushing back on that they
Speaker 5:  believe in their generations, they believe in $70 games and
Speaker 5:  you're paying for the game. They obviously have launched their own subscription
Speaker 5:  service, but it's not quite matching the export so they don't have day one
Speaker 5:  releases there so they, you know, they're still generating their revenue
Speaker 5:  individually on those big launch titles. But I think it will push the
Speaker 5:  industry in a interesting new way. And also I think like not a lot of people
Speaker 5:  have really talked about it, but is is it good? Like, is it good not to have
Speaker 5:  ownership of your games? Like in the way that we don't really have ownership
Speaker 5:  of music and
Speaker 2:  Fair question and
Speaker 5:  Movies and everything else like that ownership going away has never really
Speaker 5:  been fully addressed in the digital space for like MP3s
Speaker 5:  and, and music and, and movies and everything else. So like I can't
Speaker 5:  sell you my copy of an album, can I, like, I can't transfer it to you like
Speaker 5:  easily. Right? So I think there's a lot of things, a lot of questions around
Speaker 5:  that and like we're gaming will head as a result of that but I think in the
Speaker 5:  near term for Microsoft is getting the game pass numbers up, right? And,
Speaker 5:  and Xbox Cloud gaming, it's just like an add-on on top of that. So it's like
Speaker 5:  we everywhere, you know, as long as you got a browser you can play our games
Speaker 5:  and that's, that's kind of their approach right now. And I think ultimately
Speaker 5:  it'll end up with like, there'll be an exports app on the PlayStation. There'll
Speaker 5:  be a PlayStation app on the exports. Oh interesting. That's kind of the way
Speaker 5:  we must be heading surely like this vision is true and they put billions
Speaker 5:  of dollars into it. That's the end goal I think for, for all of them to have
Speaker 5:  their own apps across, over where you get your exclusive content just like
Speaker 5:  you do with Disney plus Netflix, you name it.
Speaker 2:  That's true. If, if Apple will make Apple TV apps for other platforms,
Speaker 2:  anything as possible. Yeah. So we're gonna be okay. Yeah. I will also say
Speaker 2:  you just made, you came dangerously close to like making the case for why
Speaker 2:  the blockchain will fix video games and I almost led you there but we'll
Speaker 2:  just, we'll we'll stay away from that for a
Speaker 5:  While and fts will save us a
Speaker 2:  Yeah but the last thing and then, and then I'll let you go is the
Speaker 2:  appeal of cloud gaming again is that like anything you have with a screen
Speaker 2:  suddenly becomes a thing and I feel like these controllers that attach to
Speaker 2:  your phone have felt like a good idea to me for
Speaker 2:  so long and they don't really feel like they've caught on and like Backbone
Speaker 2:  has made these things their very nice razor is making them Now is this a
Speaker 2:  real market? Are people gonna start to buy these in droves as cloud gaming
Speaker 2:  picks up?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I think they will become more popular but I do feel like,
Speaker 5:  I mean Alex wrote about this on the site like a few months ago before the
Speaker 5:  Logitech g Cloud gaming Christ trying to say that together. It's just,
Speaker 2:  It's
Speaker 5:  Terrible. Yeah, before Logitech announced their hand out and she
Speaker 5:  basically was arguing that, you know, these devices are great, you know,
Speaker 5:  it's great access to to cloud gaming through your phone and stuff, but it
Speaker 5:  takes your battery, the screen size isn't always perfect. Like there's, you
Speaker 5:  get a notification, you're out of the game, someone tries to phone you all
Speaker 5:  these considerations, which I think are very irritating if you actually do
Speaker 5:  play cloud gaming on your phone regularly. So I think the
Speaker 5:  hardware is interesting, it's, it's a good stop gap but we probably are heading
Speaker 5:  towards, you know, these, these dumb devices, even pucks in the living room,
Speaker 5:  you know like an Xbox, Microsoft working on one of those already. They have
Speaker 5:  an xbox's TV app and I think there's a clear vision for the
Speaker 5:  future of where things are going and I think handhelds will definitely be
Speaker 5:  a part of that.
Speaker 2:  So like dedicated hardware but cheap simple hardware might be where
Speaker 2:  a lot of this is headed.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I think dedicated hardware that has like the UI of that particular
Speaker 5:  streaming service mixed in with you know, some other third party apps like
Speaker 5:  YouTube and all your sort media content, that sort of stuff is, is
Speaker 5:  kind of interesting. Particularly if they get the harder right, you know,
Speaker 5:  the controls and everything's quite lightweight, you can see why they want
Speaker 5:  to do something like that. So I would not be surprised within the next couple
Speaker 5:  years we see an exports hand.
Speaker 2:  It's just gotta happen. Like it's just got to happen. It seems so
Speaker 2:  obvious to me that that would be a thing Microsoft to do. It's like they
Speaker 2:  already make the surface. It's like it's this, take the surface, go and make
Speaker 2:  it an Xbox. It's like there it is, we did it, we fixed it for you.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, like it just seems inevitable at this point. But it's just the timing
Speaker 5:  I think would be when, when it makes sense. Cause they, they got a lot of
Speaker 5:  work to do also on the back end for like Xbox Cloud gaming to make it
Speaker 5:  stream at 4K on the TV and stuff it's still 10 ap so
Speaker 5:  they've got a lot of platform work to do as well to to get it to a certain
Speaker 5:  point. But I mean that doesn't necessarily impact your handheld so much those
Speaker 5:  resolutions but they still, they still got some latency work to do for sure.
Speaker 2:  Okay, fair enough. All right, well thank you Tom. We're gonna take a quick
Speaker 2:  break and then we're gonna come back and I'm gonna tell you why I love scooters.
Speaker 2:  We'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. I have to start at this next segment by admitting something.
Speaker 2:  I'm a scooter guy.
Speaker 2:  This is still a slightly embarrassing fact to admit about myself. My
Speaker 2:  wife in particular really likes to remind me of this one day when she
Speaker 2:  saw me on the street and I was wearing sunglasses and AirPods and riding
Speaker 2:  a bird scooter and the fly on my pants was down and I rode
Speaker 2:  right past her and her friends and I think that moment was
Speaker 2:  probably the most she ever regretted marrying me. But the thing is scooters
Speaker 2:  have been a huge help in my life. I was in San Francisco when Bird
Speaker 2:  and Lime first showed up a few years ago and I immediately started riding
Speaker 2:  them almost every day. My apartment was a mile from the train and on
Speaker 2:  the other end it was about a mile and a quarter to the office. And by
Speaker 2:  scootering on either side, instead of walking, I shaved like a half
Speaker 2:  hour off of my commute each way every day for just a couple of dollars.
Speaker 2:  It was amazing. And when I was done riding, I just got off the scooter and
Speaker 2:  walked away. It was the perfect setup.
Speaker 2:  But over the years the whole ride share scooter thing
Speaker 2:  got to be less convenient. As they got more popular and more people
Speaker 2:  started riding them. The scooter I left outside my office in the morning,
Speaker 2:  stopped being there at the end of the day. And then even when I found
Speaker 2:  ones, it seemed like half the ones I found were out of battery or
Speaker 2:  broken in some way or just not where the apps said they were. But
Speaker 2:  the biggest problem was scooters just got more expensive. The companies
Speaker 2:  that made them needed to find ways to make more money, especially as they
Speaker 2:  went public or got acquired by bigger companies. I actually went back through
Speaker 2:  some of my recent rides and the numbers really add up.
Speaker 2:  I had a six minute 0.8 mile ride to my friend's place, which was
Speaker 2:  $5 and 59 cents. And the 1.7
Speaker 2:  mile ride from there back to the train was
Speaker 2:  10 28. I'm paying about five bucks a day just to ride
Speaker 2:  from my house to the train a little less than a mile away. And I actually
Speaker 2:  got a $20 fine from Bird the other day for apparently incorrectly
Speaker 2:  locking my scooter. This all gets really expensive, really fast.
Speaker 2:  So I started looking around, should I just buy a scooter for my
Speaker 2:  commute? And for all those quick runs to the grocery store and to pick up
Speaker 2:  dinner, I found this company Unagi, which makes a scooter called the Model
Speaker 2:  One that I think is generally considered to be the best scooter on the market.
Speaker 8:  Unagi Scooter, a scooter with Soul.
Speaker 2:  But Unagi doesn't really wanna sell you one, at least not at full price.
Speaker 2:  It would much rather you subscribe to one for about $55 a month.
Speaker 2:  I thought that whole setup was kind of odd. So I called up David Hyman, the
Speaker 2:  CEO of Unagi to convince me that renting a scooter, it's the move
Speaker 8:  We kind of envisioned our subscription service. It's like mailing a
Speaker 8:  giant Netflix DVD mailer. They're so like wait. That's kind of
Speaker 8:  what helps make the model work. It shows up at your door in under
Speaker 8:  72 hours if anything happens to it, we send you a new
Speaker 8:  one. If you threw the box away, we send you an empty box and you send
Speaker 8:  yours back. We don't make you wait to get yours repaired, you
Speaker 8:  get a new one right away. People's transportation, they want it to be effortless.
Speaker 8:  They don't want hassle, they don't want downtime. Car down tab
Speaker 8:  sucks.
Speaker 2:  David told me that this idea is really working. About 20
Speaker 2:  people subscribe to a Unagi scooter for everyone that buys it
Speaker 2:  outright and the Casey makes is pretty convincing. I don't want to
Speaker 2:  care about maintenance. I don't even know that I'm gonna want this scooter
Speaker 2:  forever. So spending a thousand dollars on it seems crazy, but I do know
Speaker 2:  that $55 a month is actually a lot less than I'm spending on scooter
Speaker 2:  rides right now. More broadly, this is a real trend in the industry.
Speaker 2:  Bird will happily sell you one of its scooters for instance, and has tried
Speaker 2:  a similar thing where you can pay extra to make sure there's always a burden
Speaker 2:  nearby. But the thing I couldn't shake was the convenience part.
Speaker 2:  It's so nice to just get off a scooter, lock it up and then
Speaker 2:  never think about it again. Not my problem. And now I'm supposed to lug
Speaker 2:  this thing around and charge it myself and like carry it
Speaker 2:  into the coffee shop with me. David said, yeah, it's a
Speaker 2:  trade off but he thinks it's worth it.
Speaker 8:  I always put it down next to me in a cafe. I bring it into a movie
Speaker 8:  theater and put it in the aisle, throw it in the shopping cart at the
Speaker 8:  supermarket. That's how I handle it. It's not ideal
Speaker 8:  really when I go into a restaurant nobody cares. But one day if
Speaker 8:  everyone were to do this, restaurants would start going, No, we're not gonna
Speaker 8:  have 20 scooters in the restaurant.
Speaker 2:  You know what this means, right? This means valet scooter parking is going
Speaker 2:  to be a thing. What a world we live in, my friends. Anyway, I ended
Speaker 2:  up giving a shot. I went to Una's website and
Speaker 2:  forked over $55 a month plus a $50 setup fee to get a scooter.
Speaker 2:  This was I think 4th of July weekend
Speaker 2:  or thereabouts. I've been riding it around all summer and I have to say,
Speaker 2:  I think Unagi is onto something here. Yes it is in fact a
Speaker 2:  little annoying to have to carry the scooter onto the train. And the person
Speaker 2:  at my hair salon the other day was very confused about why I wanted to bring
Speaker 2:  my scooter inside. But it feels like a worthwhile trade just to have
Speaker 2:  the scooter there whenever I need it. It weighs about 28
Speaker 2:  pounds, which will sound like a lot to some people and not much to others.
Speaker 2:  But to me it's been okay to carry around, at least for small bits
Speaker 2:  of time. I'm more of a scooter guy than ever after the last few months and
Speaker 2:  I'm still a pretty happy Unagi subscriber. $55 a month
Speaker 2:  sounds really steep, but it's been easily worth it for me. The math
Speaker 2:  totally pans out in my case.
Speaker 2:  And now Unagi also has a new scooter called the Model one Voyager,
Speaker 2:  which David told me he hopes will convince even more people to buy into the
Speaker 2:  scooter lifestyle. It's a little heavier but it's faster and works better
Speaker 2:  and has more range. And the idea is it's much more of a commuter vehicle.
Speaker 2:  More broadly though, the idea of vehicle subscriptions is totally
Speaker 2:  fascinating to me and I think we're gonna see a lot more of it
Speaker 2:  going forward, especially as new kinds of vehicles keep being
Speaker 2:  introduced into our lives. Like here's Lee Hang Long, the CEO of a
Speaker 2:  mobility company called Nimbus.
Speaker 9:  The ability to use a vehicle like this and not have to
Speaker 9:  commit to an ownership is like really appealing. Combine that with the convenience
Speaker 9:  of getting the vehicle delivered to you. You don't have to think about like
Speaker 9:  when you buy a car, you have to go to the dmv, you have to get insurance.
Speaker 9:  All that stuff that's taking care of for you as well. That's like really
Speaker 9:  convenient and really nice.
Speaker 2:  Makes a vehicle called the Nimbus one, which is this futuristic
Speaker 2:  looking thing that's kind of a cross between a tricycle and
Speaker 2:  a car. It's this super skinny thing with
Speaker 2:  one seat and three wheels and you sit inside it and drive it with a steering
Speaker 2:  wheel, but it tilts as it goes like a motorcycle.
Speaker 9:  We call it a pod, p o d because we
Speaker 9:  don't think it's a card. We wanna stay away from that paradigm,
Speaker 2:  Whatever you call it. It's not available for sale yet, but when it is, you'll
Speaker 2:  be able to buy one for about 10 grand or subscribe to one for
Speaker 2:  a couple hundred bucks a month. Or if you don't wanna do that, just grab
Speaker 2:  one off the street whenever you need one for a few minutes. Nimbus wants
Speaker 2:  to do all the things, all the ways,
Speaker 9:  Rent by the minute free floating. That's really convenient, but it's gonna
Speaker 9:  cost a little bit more because you're basically paying someone to like
Speaker 9:  move it for you, right? And charge it for you. So that's gonna add a little
Speaker 9:  bit more to the cost. But if you're in a hurry, you don't really care. If
Speaker 9:  you're using something day to day, then you want that vehicle to be yours.
Speaker 2:  There's a big Galaxy Brain take in there somewhere about
Speaker 2:  the end of ownership and the fact that people are increasingly willing to
Speaker 2:  pay for convenience rather than having something that's permanently theirs.
Speaker 2:  I tend to agree with Lee Hank's take though that the answer is actually lots
Speaker 2:  of business models and lots of different systems for lots of different things.
Speaker 2:  And weirdly over the last few months I've now been thinking about that
Speaker 2:  subscription spectrum with almost everything in my life.
Speaker 2:  What do I want to own? What do I want to rent and what do I want to just
Speaker 2:  be there Occasionally when I need it, I should probably just buy the
Speaker 2:  office because I watch that constantly. I'll subscribe to YouTube TV
Speaker 2:  in the fall because they need football and then I'll cancel that and then
Speaker 2:  I can just pay $10 for a month of showtime when a new season of Yellow
Speaker 2:  jackets drops and then cancel when I'm done. I don't even really own my
Speaker 2:  phone, but I pay $50 or so a month and I get one and then I
Speaker 2:  can upgrade it every year. So that works. I don't know that I need to own
Speaker 2:  my phone, but I do own my computer because that thing better last me a decade.
Speaker 2:  And I also want to keep it around just in case even after that,
Speaker 2:  in so many places in our lives there's gonna be a spectrum of ways to own,
Speaker 2:  subscribe, rent, borrow, everything else, and then also a lot of
Speaker 2:  companies competing to help you manage all that stuff in a way that makes
Speaker 2:  sense. This all feels new and different and expensive, but I kind of think
Speaker 2:  it's fascinating And I asked David from Unagi
Speaker 2:  how far he thinks this'll go. He's been in subscriptions forever.
Speaker 2:  He was early in the streaming music game. He founded mog, which became Beats
Speaker 2:  Music, which became Apple Music. And he's seen a lot about how
Speaker 2:  people's feelings about music ownership and everything else. Ownership has
Speaker 2:  changed. People don't buy CDs anymore. So is everything going
Speaker 2:  that way?
Speaker 8:  I don't think it works across all hardware. There's a whole bunch of numbers
Speaker 8:  involved, like the cost to acquire a customer, what the churn rate is,
Speaker 8:  cost of servicing, the fact that the scooter is lightweight and
Speaker 8:  that we can ship them small parcel back and forth is kind of a
Speaker 8:  cornerstone to making our model work. I don't think it works for
Speaker 8:  electric bikes, they're too heavy. The cost to ship them back and
Speaker 8:  forth and the fact that they have so many moving parts with
Speaker 8:  Derailers and Gears, I think both for shipping and
Speaker 8:  servicing them, those costs will break the model. You
Speaker 8:  know, I think it's gonna be very industry specific. We're really at
Speaker 8:  much the forefront of this hardware as a service category
Speaker 8:  that's going to I think grow a lot in the next 10 to 20 years.
Speaker 2:  I'm still torn about all of this honestly because part of me thinks it is
Speaker 2:  just too expensive and complicated and that maybe we should just go
Speaker 2:  back to buying things and taking care of them and just a
Speaker 2:  simpler idea of how we think about our stuff. But I also like the
Speaker 2:  idea that when it gets cold here in DC and I don't wanna ride this
Speaker 2:  scooter for six months, it won't cost me a nickel until I want
Speaker 2:  to get back on only paying for things when you actually use them.
Speaker 2:  I like that a lot.
Speaker 2:  Okay, we need to take one more break and then we're gonna come back and go
Speaker 2:  through all of the tech announcements that are coming in the next several
Speaker 2:  weeks because there's a lot coming. We'll be right back.
Speaker 10:  This episode is sponsored by Hulu in their comedy series called
Speaker 10:  Reboot. Reboot is about a dysfunctional Sid Comcast
Speaker 10:  returning for a revival of their early 2000 show. Step right
Speaker 10:  Up. When a writer successfully pitches the show to studio execs, the
Speaker 10:  cast finds themselves reunited not only with each other but all
Speaker 10:  their unresolved issues in baggage. And a new team of writers are forced
Speaker 10:  to find a way to collaborate with their original writing team. Reboot starts
Speaker 10:  Keegan, Michael Key, Judy Greer, Johnny
Speaker 10:  Knoxville, Paul Riser, Rachel Bloom, and Kris Marie. You
Speaker 10:  don't miss the new series reboot. Now streaming
Speaker 10:  Tuesdays exclusively on Hulu
Speaker 11:  From National Geographic and executive producer James
Speaker 11:  Cameron comes a new Disney plus original series
Speaker 11:  Supernatural narrated by Benedict Cumberbatch. You'll meet creatures that
Speaker 11:  appear ordinary but possess superpowers. We are only beginning to
Speaker 11:  understand did you know trees can talk to each other to help fend off invasion?
Speaker 11:  And did you know burrowing owls his like snakes to scare off predators?
Speaker 11:  If you think you know nature, think again. Supernatural
Speaker 11:  now streaming on Disney Plus.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. So today, September 28th is
Speaker 2:  the beginning of just a crazy run of tech events over
Speaker 2:  the next several weeks. And honestly my head is totally spinning
Speaker 2:  about what's coming, whether any of it matters, what I should buy, what I
Speaker 2:  should care about, and what I should be watching out for. So I brought in
Speaker 2:  my co-hosts ne i Patel and Alex Crayons to help me figure it out ne
Speaker 2:  And Alex, thank you for coming to me in this trying time of mine.
Speaker 2:  I appreciate it.
Speaker 12:  I'm here for you buddy.
Speaker 2:  We're here. I didn't tell you either of you what we're doing here because
Speaker 2:  you would not have come if I told you. So. The the shtick of what we're gonna
Speaker 2:  do here is I have a list of 10 product producty launchy
Speaker 2:  things coming in the next four weeks. Oh boy. And we're just gonna blast
Speaker 2:  through them and we will talk about them in as much or as little detail as
Speaker 2:  we want to.
Speaker 12:  So we're gonna read your calendar together.
Speaker 2:  Yes. And I'm gonna tell you which flights I'm taking for each one.
Speaker 2:  Okay. And the good news is we're we start very quickly cause I think we can
Speaker 2:  get past this one pretty fast. The first one coming up is today the
Speaker 2:  day a lot of people will be hearing this episode Wednesday, September 28th
Speaker 2:  is Google's big search on search event. This is the thing they do every
Speaker 2:  year where they talk about search. Do we care? Are we interested? Do
Speaker 2:  either of you have anything you're interested or curious about from this
Speaker 2:  event this year?
Speaker 12:  I always want to know how many search results Google is gonna keep
Speaker 12:  for itself. And I feel like they should just announce that at the top of
Speaker 12:  the search on event.
Speaker 13:  Ooh, interesting.
Speaker 12:  Be like we're sending less traffic to people who use our search engine
Speaker 12:  every day and this year we've turned the knob and now we're keeping 80%
Speaker 12:  of the traffic.
Speaker 2:  They probably do have that number don't they? Like that is somewhere that
Speaker 2:  they know they
Speaker 12:  Have to have that number. Cause
Speaker 13:  That's how like they make money, they keep the traffic.
Speaker 12:  And David, you just wrote the piece about using TikTok as your primary search
Speaker 12:  engine and it was like fine. And I think Google knows this.
Speaker 12:  Yes. And a huge problem with the experience of using
Speaker 12:  Google right now is everybody is trying to game the search engine.
Speaker 12:  So you search for how to do something, you end up with a page
Speaker 12:  that has been written for a robot instead of a person. But the classic example
Speaker 12:  is if you search for a recipe, you end up with like a personal essay. Yeah.
Speaker 12:  It's there to game the search engine.
Speaker 2:  Right. And the people who make those pages will tell you that. I actually
Speaker 2:  wrote a story about that a couple of years ago where I was basically like,
Speaker 2:  why are all recipe webpages awful in exactly the same way? And every single
Speaker 2:  one of 'em was like, oh it's just seo. Like if I don't do it, literally no
Speaker 2:  one will find me. So I have to write 2000 words about how my day went before
Speaker 2:  I get to the recipe. Or else Google literally will pretend I don't exist.
Speaker 12:  Yeah. And then you like search the recipe and TikTok and someone's like,
Speaker 12:  Here it is in two minutes. Exactly. Pause if you wanna see the ingredients.
Speaker 12:  But how
Speaker 13:  Do you know if those recipes are good? That's why I like the, I like the
Speaker 13:  little essay I'm, I'm like, I'm why Google does this. Yeah. I wanna
Speaker 13:  know, I wanna know how much love your mom put into that biscuit recipe.
Speaker 12:  What was up with the pioneer woman this week?
Speaker 13:  Tell me more.
Speaker 12:  Yeah, but I think this is like the real challenge for Google because the
Speaker 12:  more of it they keep and the more they synthesize the result, the directly
Speaker 12:  the thing, the more it cuts against oh decades of how people have thought
Speaker 12:  about Google's a search engine and how to participate.
Speaker 2:  And in a real way, like the, the thing I'm curious about is like Google as
Speaker 2:  the homepage of the internet is a thing that I think Google has always
Speaker 2:  tried to play down, but every time like for that TikTok thing, I went and
Speaker 2:  looked at a bunch of studies and it's like the most popular search terms
Speaker 2:  are like the word Facebook and the word Google and the word YouTube. And
Speaker 2:  that's just, that's like how people explore the internet. They like type
Speaker 2:  the thing they want into Google and then go that way. And that is like a
Speaker 2:  level of power, especially as Google starts to pull that stuff back for itself
Speaker 2:  that it's gonna get even crazier.
Speaker 12:  People typing TikTok into Google and getting YouTube shorts is whew.
Speaker 12:  Yeah.
Speaker 13:  Ooh,
Speaker 12:  I love it. It's gonna be a game that gets played.
Speaker 2:  It's coming. That's
Speaker 13:  Beautiful.
Speaker 2:  Okay, next one. The same day also today is Amazon's
Speaker 2:  whatever product announcement it's going to be. I call this one the the traditional
Speaker 2:  like spaghetti throwing day by Amazon where they're just like, here's some
Speaker 2:  things that exist that have Alexa inside
Speaker 13:  Like 48 different microwave that all have Alexa.
Speaker 12:  It's always hard to know they're gonna change the echo. The holidays are
Speaker 12:  coming. So last year it was a sphere. This year I'm hoping for cube.
Speaker 13:  Why not really sharp edges.
Speaker 12:  This one's called a rambus. Like what? Which is do whatever you want to
Speaker 12:  do. Like, I mean that's the thing, they haven't added capabilities to it
Speaker 12:  year and I don't think they will cause it's still hardware and then it's
Speaker 12:  like whatever else they can put Alexa in and maybe some marine cameras.
Speaker 12:  Right.
Speaker 2:  I just assume they're gonna talk a lot about football.
Speaker 13:  I mean a robot, we could get another robot.
Speaker 2:  Does anyone have the astro? Did that work? Like has this thing
Speaker 2:  resurfaced at all since it was initially announced?
Speaker 13:  I think the only people who have Astros are people who had to review them.
Speaker 13:  Yeah,
Speaker 12:  I think some people want them. But the example, look, Amazon has to solve
Speaker 12:  the problem of what is Alexa good for? Beyond sending a timer and maybe
Speaker 12:  some smart home motivations, I'm hopefully we hear a bunch of stuff about
Speaker 12:  matter which expands that universe of smart home stuff. But we'll see.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I do think of all of these. It was very funny because Amazon is the
Speaker 2:  one that literally could go absolutely any direction which kind of
Speaker 2:  makes those events fun because you just, you just never know. Like it it,
Speaker 2:  they could announce anything and it would not surprise me
Speaker 13:  Except for every year I'm like, this year they will announce a Kindle at
Speaker 13:  this event and every year they were like, we will not announce a Kindle
Speaker 13:  at this event.
Speaker 2:  Okay, next one is on Friday I believe is
Speaker 2:  Tesla's ai day, I assume more robots.
Speaker 12:  So Elon has promised they're gonna show up for prototype with the robot,
Speaker 2:  Right? Oh he has. Oh okay.
Speaker 12:  The hype machine is like off to the races. Will
Speaker 2:  It be a person dancing pretending to be a robot again?
Speaker 12:  Last year was a guy in a, in like a bunny suit. Not a bunny suit. What's
Speaker 12:  the thing called the unitard?
Speaker 13:  Yeah. He was just in a unitard. Like just in a unitard and a mask
Speaker 13:  doing his little dance.
Speaker 12:  It was very confusing. I mean in, you know, in the classic Huon way
Speaker 12:  also hilarious. Like Elon knew it was a guidance. Yeah.
Speaker 12:  What was he fooling? Anyone who knows we're supposed to see it
Speaker 12:  and it's supposed to do like, We'll see I don't think they're actually gonna
Speaker 12:  show a robot that can do anything other than stumble. Like how many
Speaker 12:  Honda robots have we seen in our lives?
Speaker 13:  I do not think we will see a robot that does anything more
Speaker 13:  substantial than maybe wave. Yeah. Cause like walking is really
Speaker 13:  hard for robots and if they do the like the Honda
Speaker 13:  Sony robot that looks like it's pooping itself, like Tesla can't
Speaker 13:  afford to do that.
Speaker 12:  Yeah. I mean look the bar here is Boston and Annex is like these robots
Speaker 12:  can dance and maybe murder you, right? It's like this, this robot dog
Speaker 12:  can run up a flight of stairs, open a door and then like do a full
Speaker 12:  choreographed dancer team also. We're not saying we
Speaker 12:  haven't put a gun on it, right? Like that's the bar of robots.
Speaker 2:  This one doesn't have a gun. But here's where it would go.
Speaker 12:  Exactly.
Speaker 13:  The little hand
Speaker 12:  We'll see it. Elon's gotta hit the Boston dynamic special. This is what
Speaker 12:  I'm saying before, Before we can say we're so, so impressed.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. The the verges official stance on this is that it is absolute
Speaker 2:  vaporware until proven otherwise. Right? Like I, I remember the stories from
Speaker 2:  last year that were basically like, just to be clear, everybody, this is
Speaker 2:  probably nothing. Yeah. Let's all move on with our lives.
Speaker 12:  Yeah, we'll see. Yeah,
Speaker 13:  It's the hyperloop of robots.
Speaker 12:  Remember when they announced a full hyperloop in the city of Chicago and
Speaker 12:  they're like, this will get you to the airport so fast. Everyone's like
Speaker 12:  the blue line. Just make the blue line good. There's no hyperloop in Chicago.
Speaker 2:  Surprise. Okay, next one. October 6th, like a week from
Speaker 2:  now is Google's Pixel seven pixel watch event. And
Speaker 2:  I feel like that one, we know everything about Google has just resorted to
Speaker 2:  the strategy of just like leaking its own things to death. Yeah
Speaker 12:  It's just announced the, It's like making videos for the pixel you can go
Speaker 12:  watch. Yeah. So V thinks that the videos are hiding the world's biggest
Speaker 12:  bele. Oh
Speaker 2:  Is that why they're all dark. All the backgrounds are always dark.
Speaker 12:  She's like I guarantee there's a world's biggest bezzle on this thing. So
Speaker 12:  that's one thing I'm curious about. I'm
Speaker 13:  So, Oh
Speaker 12:  Wow. They've got a differentiating against Samsung which is running the
Speaker 12:  same operating system now. Which is curious, right? Like how are they gonna
Speaker 12:  do it without pissing off their partner? Who knows? I just wanna see what
Speaker 12:  the battery life on this thing is like. Cuz wheres does not have a great
Speaker 12:  history here.
Speaker 13:  I'm kind of excited about the tablet. It's been a while since they made
Speaker 13:  a tablet and that one was bad. Maybe this one could be good. I don't like,
Speaker 13:  I think, I think promos and Android both make sense for a tablet.
Speaker 13:  So I like, I want it to succeed just because it seems like a
Speaker 13:  a normal place for a tablet to exist but it has to actually not suck.
Speaker 13:  And that's been historically very, very difficult for
Speaker 13:  all the different parts of Google to do.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Part of me wonders like with with the news about the Pixel book from
Speaker 2:  a couple of weeks ago, like if Google hadn't announced all of this stuff
Speaker 2:  already in June, if it would still be planning to ship all of these things
Speaker 2:  in their current form. Like the tablet in particular seems like it would
Speaker 2:  be a very easy one for Google to just sort of Nope out of, except that it
Speaker 2:  already announced it's doing it and they can't bail again. At least not yet.
Speaker 2:  They'll bail again in a year and a half. But I am curious to see how much
Speaker 2:  they talk about the tablet and how much it feels like a thing they care about
Speaker 2:  as opposed to like, Oh and also look it's a tablet. You can have one.
Speaker 13:  I will be surprised if they spend more than five minutes on the tablet.
Speaker 12:  All right. Over under. They spend more time on the tablet or more time on
Speaker 12:  rcs.
Speaker 2:  I bet on rcs. I think. I bet on rcs. Yeah. Cause it's also
Speaker 2:  like it's a fun knife that Google gets to twists now and especially after
Speaker 2:  what Tim Cook said a couple weeks ago at Code. This is a moment like
Speaker 2:  Google does not get a lot of like moral high ground moments in the fight
Speaker 2:  against Apple. And this is one that I suspect's gonna just absolutely
Speaker 2:  milk the hell out if that'll be fun. It's
Speaker 12:  A bold prediction that they're gonna spend more time making fun of Apple
Speaker 12:  than announcing their own product. But I'm with you. I think that's true
Speaker 12:  as well.
Speaker 2:  That might just be hopeful rather than an actual
Speaker 12:  Prediction,
Speaker 2:  But I'm definitely hoping for it. Okay, so next up, another thing that I
Speaker 2:  think we actually know quite a bit about is October 11th there's, I
Speaker 2:  believe it's called Meta Connect now. It used to be Oculus Connect, now it's
Speaker 2:  Meta Connect and I think the thing that we know is coming, there will presumably
Speaker 2:  be other stuff, but we know that this is when Project Cambria, their high-end
Speaker 2:  VR headset is coming, right? Yeah. You think we know?
Speaker 12:  Yeah. I mean we've seen the thing. Yeah. This has also been, it was left
Speaker 12:  and making the most sarcastic of quotes with my fingers. It was
Speaker 12:  left in a hotel where someone found it and that someone was
Speaker 12:  Mark Zuckerberg on the Joe Rogan experience. Like
Speaker 12:  so it was left, people found it to showed up on Reddit separately.
Speaker 12:  Zuckerberg went on the jewelry experience and Joe and got to play with it.
Speaker 12:  It appears that's what they made it sound like. Okay they did kickboxing
Speaker 12:  together.
Speaker 2:  Are we interested? Do we care about this? I can't decide on the spectrum
Speaker 2:  of like those crazy like Microsoft
Speaker 2:  prototype headsets that they were like, these cost a million dollars and
Speaker 2:  six people ever buy them. But they have cool technology all the way down
Speaker 2:  to like a Quest three, which I would be very excited about. Like where on
Speaker 2:  the spectrum I feel like we should be,
Speaker 13:  I mean I think it depends on how good the fidelity, the visual
Speaker 13:  fidelity of the thing is, right? That's the point where people who have
Speaker 13:  adopted vr, which is what more than 4 million people have, have picked
Speaker 13:  up a Quest had said at this point like that's a decent little market of
Speaker 13:  folks. And if they can make something that is visually interesting, that's
Speaker 13:  a step up. Kind of like consoles used to be a step up every time you bought
Speaker 13:  a new console. That's a deal. That's cool.
Speaker 12:  We're going into the holidays. Yeah. And this is a thing that you can
Speaker 12:  buy a tech person in your life that they probably don't already have. Which
Speaker 12:  is I think why the Quest two was so successful. Cause it was reasonably
Speaker 12:  cheap. A hundred percent. And if you have like a gearhead in your life,
Speaker 12:  you like buy them and it's cool. Like the thing works. It's a great, I think
Speaker 12:  the Quest two is a great product. I agree. I think the question is, is the
Speaker 12:  Quest Pro going to be like the same size and more capable,
Speaker 12:  like have more features, more visual fidelity or did they make
Speaker 12:  it smaller and better? Right? Cause you leave at the same size, you could
Speaker 12:  do a lot in that case, but that it's the quest too is still pretty big.
Speaker 12:  Yeah. Like it's not comfortable where for a long time, but if you add a
Speaker 12:  bunch of features to it, then you're like, you should wear it for a long
Speaker 12:  time, but then it's still too heavy. So like there's a little trade off
Speaker 12:  inside of the size and it's, it's like horsepower that you gotta make
Speaker 12:  then I don't think Facebook is figured out. Yeah. That's the thing I'm most
Speaker 12:  curious about.
Speaker 2:  Well, and as Facebook has, as beta I guess has talked about all these different
Speaker 2:  prototypes they're working on and stuff, they're pushing in every direction
Speaker 2:  of that all at once, right? It's the like how do we do more in the space?
Speaker 2:  How do we make it smaller? How do we make it the same size but lighter? And
Speaker 2:  it's gonna be interesting to see which one they picked to actually be a thing
Speaker 2:  that people put on their hits. It's a real like statement of intent, which
Speaker 2:  direction they want to go with this. What
Speaker 12:  I think they should do is come out with a ceiling map that holds your head
Speaker 12:  up while you're wearing the heavy headset and you're just kind of like tethered
Speaker 12:  to the ceiling, just kind of floating along.
Speaker 13:  Wasn't that the original, the, the original headset, Like the
Speaker 13:  very first VR headset was tethered to the ceiling, but
Speaker 12:  With like a cable, I don't think it was like being held.
Speaker 2:  So like it basically, it's like a chandelier and you just sort of get
Speaker 2:  into it. Yeah,
Speaker 12:  Exactly. And then you've got, and you're doing like a, like a wire F kind
Speaker 12:  of thing just like floating around in space.
Speaker 2:  Oh, I love this. It solves all kinds of problems. You can have legs then
Speaker 2:  who needs legs? You're floating.
Speaker 12:  You're just kicking, you're just doing kicks.
Speaker 2:  That's good. Okay, well you heard it here first. That's what's coming.
Speaker 2:  Okay. And then the following day, Microsoft is having a surface event.
Speaker 2:  And I believe if my math is not mistaken, this is the 10 year anniversary
Speaker 2:  of Surface, which I think presumably means this is going to be something.
Speaker 2:  I feel like Microsoft is a company that likes anniversaries, so I would not
Speaker 2:  be surprised if there's like some real meaningful new hardware here.
Speaker 2:  Yeah,
Speaker 13:  They've kind of given up on the dual screen, they've flirted with dual screen
Speaker 13:  and then they stepped back from
Speaker 2:  It. Dan Seafer loves his duo but
Speaker 13:  Not as his main phone.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, it's just the most expensive e-book reader of all time. It's perfect.
Speaker 13:  He could never make fun of any of the e-readers I've bought this year given
Speaker 13:  that he owns that one e-reader. But yeah, no I think like
Speaker 13:  we're, we're do a refresh on the duo, but I think the surface is, you know,
Speaker 13:  Microsoft give him credit. They did create this entire new form factor,
Speaker 13:  like this whole new category of computing devices. Are they gonna do
Speaker 13:  something weird there or is it just gonna be like even sleeker, even thin
Speaker 13:  and nicer but also a full Windows machine?
Speaker 12:  Well and and the thing they're pushing up against is that there was the
Speaker 12:  big PC market acceleration in the pandemic two years ago. Yeah. That
Speaker 12:  is now just slowed down. Right. So a lot of people who are gonna buy laptops
Speaker 12:  and PCs over a long timeline all bought them at the same time
Speaker 12:  and now it's like they all have them. So convincing someone to upgrade from
Speaker 12:  the great laptop they bought last year is actually pretty challenging. So
Speaker 12:  we'll see. Yeah. But I bet they do something cool for the, I mean, you know,
Speaker 12:  know Panas is gonna have a time
Speaker 13:  The surface go maybe that was their, their really small one. That's cool.
Speaker 13:  And I feel like there's a lot of room for improvement on that device.
Speaker 2:  That's the one I feel like the Surface Pro is like great and we'll just keep
Speaker 2:  getting sort of it upgrades forever. Same with the Surface laptop Surface
Speaker 2:  book you could do some cool stuff with. But I agree. I feel like the go is
Speaker 2:  the one that is like just not nearly as good as it ought to be and
Speaker 2:  could be much more interesting. Well
Speaker 12:  The thing I want is a kick ass surface studio. The big desktop that folds
Speaker 12:  down. Yes. They keep Ning the processor in that thing.
Speaker 13:  One with a processor that actually came out this year. Yeah,
Speaker 12:  That's basically what I'm looking for. Yeah, it's,
Speaker 2:  It's a lot to ask for. Okay, next up we have four more to get through, but
Speaker 2:  I think a couple of these we'll do very quickly. I wrote down there's the
Speaker 2:  Samsung Developer Conference the same day as the surface thing. Does
Speaker 2:  anything ever come out of the Samsung Developer Conference? I have honestly
Speaker 2:  no memory of this
Speaker 13:  Big speed.
Speaker 12:  This is the year boys,
Speaker 13:  This is the year. Come on.
Speaker 12:  No, I, I declined to engage. There
Speaker 2:  We go. Okay. And then October 17th, this one only
Speaker 2:  half counts but we're gonna cover it a lot so we're gonna talk about it anyway,
Speaker 2:  is when the Elon Musk Twitter trial, if it's gonna happen, starts. And I
Speaker 2:  feel like every day we get closer to it, it seems more likely that it's actually
Speaker 2:  gonna happen. We're all moving to Delaware. It's gonna be a whole thing.
Speaker 2:  Did
Speaker 12:  We redesign our entire site to better cover the Elon Musk Twitter trial?
Speaker 12:  Maybe not
Speaker 2:  Entirely untrue. Who can say, do we have any inkling
Speaker 2:  that this trial isn't gonna happen? I feel like this is, it has slowed down
Speaker 2:  the last few weeks. It has like it's sort of the column before the storm.
Speaker 2:  It feels like
Speaker 13:  It's absolutely happening. Like they want him to buy it, he
Speaker 13:  doesn't wanna buy it. Nothing's changed there.
Speaker 2:  The economy has not gotten better.
Speaker 13:  Nothing's going to change there.
Speaker 12:  And the people who on Twitter seem less and less interested in running Twitter
Speaker 12:  by the
Speaker 2:  Day that's
Speaker 12:  Real. It's definitely going to trial. Will they settle after the first
Speaker 12:  day, right? Like he's being deposed this week or next I think. Right. His
Speaker 12:  deposition happens. I mean I think he's gonna wanna fight it but at some
Speaker 12:  point money solves this case. Yes. And so
Speaker 12:  it's just a question of how much money Elon pays for What
Speaker 2:  My only ask is that if this does settle, it would be a real bummer from like
Speaker 2:  an interesting story perspective if it settles ahead of the trial. But if
Speaker 2:  it does, my only request is that he pay with one of those like
Speaker 2:  big giant novelty checks. Just because that feels,
Speaker 12:  That feels like Elon. Yeah. Delivered by a guy in the robot suit. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Right. Delivered by a guy in a robot suit. In a
Speaker 2:  self-driving car that doesn't really self-drive but just sort of like
Speaker 2:  flings past the Twitter office in San Francisco. This all sounds good. Okay.
Speaker 2:  Then there is Adobe Max, which I would not always include
Speaker 2:  on this list cuz it tends to get very sort of arcane in this stuff. But I
Speaker 2:  feel like after the the Fig Mac acquisition, Adobe is probably gonna talk
Speaker 2:  an awful lot about the internet at Adobe Max and all the stuff that they're
Speaker 2:  doing to make their stuff more accessible to more people. And I think this
Speaker 2:  might be a really interesting year for creator tools.
Speaker 13:  That event is always kind of cool because they'll be like, here's something
Speaker 13:  that will maybe come to Photoshop four years from now and
Speaker 13:  isn't it incredible we can replace your, your grandmother
Speaker 13:  with your grandfather in this photo. All you have to do is click.
Speaker 13:  And I always like, I love all those demos. They, they're just wild. And
Speaker 13:  then occasionally they come and they are nothing like what I saw in the
Speaker 13:  demo and it's much harder to do but it's great. But if they can start
Speaker 13:  bringing those tools, a lot of the, like a lot right now, Photoshop, the
Speaker 13:  online kind of versions of Photoshop, the the ones on iOS and everything
Speaker 13:  else still have nowhere near the same amount of
Speaker 13:  features as what you get with the full, the whole shebang. And they need
Speaker 13:  to close that gap.
Speaker 12:  This was a, a thing that Scott Besky who's a chief product officer at
Speaker 12:  Adobe was saying, cuz people aren't reasonably mad about
Speaker 12:  Photoshop pushing you towards Photoshop cloud files now instead of
Speaker 12:  spitting out PSDs and like you can still get the PSDs but it like it wants
Speaker 12:  you to do the cloud thing. And he was like, in order to make Photoshop on
Speaker 12:  iPad and the web more powerful and then compete with things like Figma,
Speaker 12:  you need the files to live in the cloud. And it's just like okay cool.
Speaker 12:  That's a big battleship to turn right? Like this is the Microsoft Excel
Speaker 12:  tool bar. Like every button that you might wanna remove there is 10 million
Speaker 12:  people who are gonna be mad at you
Speaker 2:  And who use your tool literally for a living. Yeah,
Speaker 12:  Yeah. You can't, can't mess with it. We'll see if they talk about Figma,
Speaker 12:  I think my prediction for Adobe Max I agree with you Alex. Adobe Max and
Speaker 12:  CI Graph are like my two favorite shows the year. Just like watching what
Speaker 12:  people can do with creative tools is amazing. They're gonna talk a lot about
Speaker 12:  AI art, right? They have to. It's the, it's the thing right? They're gonna
Speaker 12:  talk about stable diffusion and Dolly and all the rest of it. I think that's
Speaker 12:  gonna be really fun.
Speaker 2:  It does seem like at some point it would be weird for Adobe not to do that,
Speaker 2:  right? Like that is the next obvious turn for Adobe here is like, oh you
Speaker 2:  don't wanna learn how to use Photoshop? No problem. Just tape into this prompt
Speaker 2:  in Photoshop and we will do
Speaker 12:  It. Yeah, exactly. Be like family who loves me, push
Speaker 12:  the button, spits it right out at Niagara Falls. Great. Done.
Speaker 12:  And then you're like sell it as an NFT and like you're just a one
Speaker 12:  man night band all on the comfort of your own home.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, that sounds about right. Okay and then last one, and I put this one
Speaker 2:  at the end because we don't really know when it's happening or if it's happening
Speaker 2:  or in what way it's gonna happen. But there is a bunch of Apple stuff that
Speaker 2:  we are assuming is yet to launch some more iPads, maybe imax,
Speaker 2:  maybe some other headphones, I don't know. But then there was the report
Speaker 2:  for Mark Erman at Bloomberg saying that instead of an event in October, Apple
Speaker 2:  might just do a trickle of press releases and stuff.
Speaker 2:  Is there anything exciting left this year that we think we're waiting for?
Speaker 13:  I mean it's mainly gonna be processor upgrades, right? Like the
Speaker 13:  iPad Pro will go from an M one to an M two I would assume. Same
Speaker 13:  with the imax. The iPad is do something but
Speaker 13:  they haven't redesigned it. Like they seem very content with how the iPad
Speaker 13:  is. So when when he wrote that piece I was like yeah that makes sense.
Speaker 12:  Well so, but there's no Mac Pro with an M series chipping it yet. There's
Speaker 12:  Mac Studio, which is people love but there's no MAC Pro and
Speaker 2:  They've hinted towards the Mac Pro, which makes us think at some point that
Speaker 2:  is coming,
Speaker 13:  Aren't we owed the Mac Pro? Didn't they say they were finishing the switch?
Speaker 13:  Yeah,
Speaker 2:  He said like the only one left is the Mac Pro and then it was like, but that's
Speaker 2:  for another day or something like that. Yep. So like it's coming.
Speaker 12:  The fact that you can just like buy a 18 core zon tower from Apple right
Speaker 12:  now is like very funny. Yeah. Like you can definitely just buy I'm specing
Speaker 12:  one out right now. Yeah, I mean look, the MacBook Pros, my M one Pro, MacBook
Speaker 12:  Pro is like the best computer I've ever made there. There's almost nothing
Speaker 12:  you could add to that machine that would make me upgrade more battery life.
Speaker 12:  But like it's great. So I, I think like M two pros as
Speaker 12:  an upgrade or M two Maxes is an upgrade for those machines. I think that
Speaker 12:  does seem press releasee, right? Like that's a benchmark story. Okay.
Speaker 12:  Then I think the iac, you could build a bigger
Speaker 12:  screen iMac, that might be an event, but you could also just send those
Speaker 12:  out to a bunch of people.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, you just say look, the iMac we have it's, it's bigger now. Although
Speaker 2:  I do know a number of people who are anxiously awaiting the return of the
Speaker 2:  27 inch iMac, which I don't know if it's ever gonna happen or if it's gonna
Speaker 2:  happen in October, but that would be big news in, in certain circles
Speaker 12:  Again, is the person who's currently recording this on a 20
Speaker 12:  15 27 inch my Mac, Woo, it's great. It
Speaker 12:  has 32 gigs of ram and if you're, I'm just telling you everyone this,
Speaker 12:  if you just shove as much RAM into the computer as you can get at the outset,
Speaker 12:  it will last forever.
Speaker 2:  That's basically true.
Speaker 12:  You can't kill this machine cuz it has 32 gigs of ram. But yeah,
Speaker 12:  I think all this stuff, even an M two iPad Pro where in the heart
Speaker 12:  of that product's design cycle, right, they're not gonna change the way
Speaker 12:  it looks. Yeah. So I think fundamentally you get the new stuff when the
Speaker 12:  way it looks changes.
Speaker 2:  All right. Out of all of this, is there any one thing you're like most
Speaker 2:  anticipating curious about looking forward to, excited about? Alex,
Speaker 2:  do you have anything?
Speaker 13:  The iPad Pro, because I need to update mine and I didn't want the first
Speaker 13:  generation, because the first generation always makes me
Speaker 2:  Sad. You just want stage manager so bad,
Speaker 12:  This is why they're not doing an event. They know they can't demo stage
Speaker 12:  manager in person to a group of people. Yeah. They can't have us in the
Speaker 12:  Steve Jobs theater trying to use stage manager. Craig
Speaker 2:  Federer steadfastly refused to say piles on stage ever.
Speaker 2:  So they can't do it.
Speaker 12:  He's like, We're not doing this. That's a good one. I would say that's exciting.
Speaker 12:  I'm, I would say I'm excited for the Pixel event. Okay. I, I wanna see how
Speaker 12:  they're gonna, you know, for the 50th time, how they're gonna convince us
Speaker 12:  that they're for real this time. This
Speaker 13:  Is
Speaker 12:  The year. And instead of writing that story for us at the Verge, Dieter
Speaker 12:  is now at Google to preemptively shape that story. So
Speaker 12:  we'll see. But I'm excited. I've been, the watch is a big deal. Like they
Speaker 12:  bought Fitbit, but promise of this product was an entire acquisition. So
Speaker 12:  I'm curious.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, that's mine too. The, the watch and specifically the fitness stuff
Speaker 2:  they try to put into it because like Fitbit has meant a lot to a lot of
Speaker 2:  people for a really long time and whether Google a can be good stewards of
Speaker 2:  that and B like push that along in useful ways is gonna be super
Speaker 2:  interesting.
Speaker 12:  I mean that's really what I wanna know. That's like why am I excited
Speaker 2:  If the bezel on the tablet is any indication, the watch is gonna be like
Speaker 2:  two thirds bezel, one third screen is what seems to be, that seems
Speaker 2:  to be Google's move for a lot of it's first gen stuff. It's really, it's
Speaker 2:  good times.
Speaker 12:  I mean honestly like why am I excited for this event so I can hear the from,
Speaker 12:  you know, a hundred miles away screaming. I told you
Speaker 2:  So.
Speaker 2:  Okay. As you can tell, there is a lot coming in the next few weeks. But that's
Speaker 2:  it for the Vergecast today. Thank you so much for listening. As always, there
Speaker 2:  is a lot more coverage on everything we talked about at our still newly
Speaker 2:  redesigned website, The verge.com. You can follow all of us on Twitter. Tom
Speaker 2:  is Tom Warren. Alex is Alex h Crayons. Neli is Reckless
Speaker 2:  and I am Pierce. This show is produced by Andrew Marino and Liam James.
Speaker 2:  No, Donovan is our executive producer and Brook Mins is our editorial director
Speaker 2:  of audio. The Vergecast is a Verge production and part of the V Media podcast
Speaker 2:  network. If you have thoughts, feedback, feelings, jingles,
Speaker 2:  scooter ideas, you can always email
Speaker 2:  us@vergecastfirst.com. Also, we are getting an episode
Speaker 2:  ready all about cybersecurity for later in October and we're gonna
Speaker 2:  do a full on call in show answering all of your weirdest
Speaker 2:  cybersecurity questions. So if you have something you can't figure out or
Speaker 2:  better yet have a crazy internet cybersecurity mystery you can't
Speaker 2:  solve, call us eight six six Verge one one or send
Speaker 2:  us a voice memo to vergecast@verge.com and we'll get back to you if we think
Speaker 2:  we can help. Alex, Neil and I will be back on Friday to talk
Speaker 2:  about Google, Amazon, and a whole bunch of other stuff. We'll see you then
Speaker 2:  rock and roll