# Transcript
ID: 678e9380-597b-11ed-bd99-79e3fdef36c0
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Apple's new App Store tax, Microsoft Surface reviews, and Meta's earnings
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/4945190199681351560/-8322897807388547651/s93290-US-5236s-1667262104.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, David Pierce, Alex Cranz, and Tom Warren discuss Microsoft Surface reviews, Apple's new App Store tax, and Meta earnings.
Speaker 1:  Today at the Verge cast, Tom Warren joins us with news and reviews for
Speaker 1:  Microsoft and its earnings season Meta is in pain. Jim Kramer is
Speaker 1:  crying, but Apple is selling a lot of MacBook errors. That's all coming up
Speaker 1:  right after this
Speaker 2:  Hello
Speaker 4:  And welcome to Vergecast the flagship podcast of
Speaker 4:  crying on television. Who hasn't cried on television?
Speaker 4:  Every time I go on television, I'm crying inside. I've
Speaker 5:  Yet to cry on
Speaker 4:  Television. The next time I get some like local news pitch and be like, You
Speaker 4:  know who you need talk to is Alex Kranz just
Speaker 5:  Softly weeping.
Speaker 6:  He's like, Can I do iPhone Something
Speaker 7:  Little
Speaker 4:  Tear. Yeah. Lots to cry about this week. Lot's be happy about. It's a
Speaker 4:  cocktail of emotions. I'm a friend Eli, that's Alex Kranz. Hello.
Speaker 4:  David Pierce is
Speaker 3:  Here. Hi. I'm always in a cocktail of emotions. This is what the verge cast
Speaker 3:  is like that. Can we just recall rename the Verge cast a cocktail of technology
Speaker 3:  emotions?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I think that's what people expect for us. Also deep in his cups. Tom
Speaker 4:  Warren is here.
Speaker 7:  Hello? I only cry when people are mean to me on Twitter.
Speaker 3:  Aw. Luckily that never happens.
Speaker 4:  Never. What time is in England Tom? It
Speaker 7:  Is core past nine.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, you're hammered. Let's be honest,
Speaker 7:  Like a couple of teas past dinner time,
Speaker 4:  Here's what I know about British people. It's 3:00 PM they're drinking, especially
Speaker 4:  lately is my understanding of the state
Speaker 7:  We drinking. If it's 3:00 AM we're just in bed drinking.
Speaker 4:  Like wake up, open the paper. Who's, Who's the monarch? Who's
Speaker 4:  the prime minister different today? Throw a couple back. Let's see what
Speaker 4:  happens.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, you have to be careful. You have to be nice to all of us now all British
Speaker 7:  people. Cause you never know when one of us is to become Prime
Speaker 7:  Minister.
Speaker 4:  I saw that video of Rishi Sak partying and I was like, this
Speaker 4:  shouldn't be a scandal. More world leaders should be forced
Speaker 4:  to rage on video before they become world leaders. So they
Speaker 4:  are reminded that at any point they can be taken down by their own
Speaker 4:  actions. That's true. It was good. It was a good video. It reminded me of
Speaker 4:  a thing that Casey Newton has said to me for years on unknown. We are quickly
Speaker 4:  approaching the day when world leaders will have just commonly have sexted
Speaker 4:  in their, in their teens. Oh yeah. And like we're just, we're just coming
Speaker 4:  to that moment and he's like, that's the singularity of all politics and
Speaker 4:  culture.
Speaker 7:  It's definitely coming.
Speaker 4:  It's the default expectation, not a scandal. Well about Casey on to unpack
Speaker 4:  that in great detail. Instead what we're gonna talk about in the show is
Speaker 4:  GA gadgets, tech companies, products. They make the
Speaker 3:  Things you use to sex to other people. Yeah. Devices for
Speaker 4:  Sexting Surface pro nine with the arm ship. Good for sexting. Yay or
Speaker 4:  nay. The Verge cast,
Speaker 7:  It has port chip blurs. So maybe that's
Speaker 4:  True. All right, so we got Surface Pro reviews. They hit Tom, you wrote about
Speaker 4:  10 years of Surface. You talked to Pans Panay, Microsoft Head
Speaker 4:  earnings. Facebook had earnings. Apple is gonna have earnings while we record.
Speaker 4:  You'll hear us live. React to Apple either making billions of dollars
Speaker 4:  or slightly less billions of dollars depending on how the economy went this
Speaker 4:  quarter. Google had earnings. There's lots of earnings, lots of economic
Speaker 4:  shakiness meta in a free fall cuz they're spending a lot of money in the
Speaker 4:  metaverse and we got some gadgets. And then here's the thing I want to tell
Speaker 4:  you. We're recording this the day before Elon closes the deal
Speaker 4:  to buy Twitter. So we're not gonna talk about that on this episode of the
Speaker 4:  Verest tomorrow when he closes the
Speaker 4:  deal, assuming he does, which we all think he's gonna
Speaker 3:  Do. I was just about to say that's a lot of confidence Eli. Like given what
Speaker 3:  we know so far with 24 hours notice to say you know what's gonna happen.
Speaker 3:  It's like a truly, truly bold clamp to
Speaker 7:  Make. You've just gotta let it sink in that he, he's got Twitter now. He's
Speaker 7:  the, the TWI chief or whatever he calls himself,
Speaker 4:  Assuming that happens, will have another episode tomorrow with Liz
Speaker 4:  to just unpack the Twitter situation. The thing I wanna say about
Speaker 4:  the sync, the number of people who
Speaker 4:  willfully did not get the joke, the dumbest
Speaker 4:  joke in the world of Elon tweeting. I just,
Speaker 4:  I'm gonna close Twitter, Let that sink in. And him walking in Twitter headquarters
Speaker 4:  with a sink I e letting the sink in. See what I'm saying?
Speaker 4:  The dumbest joke in the world. I have fully appreciate this joke.
Speaker 5:  He like doubled down on the dad joke by also bringing one of
Speaker 5:  his children with him just to be like, if you didn't know this was a
Speaker 5:  dad joke, there's my kid.
Speaker 4:  But it's like CNN's like Elon Musk shows up at Twitter headquarters with
Speaker 4:  the sink and it's like, yeah he tweeted, let that sink in. And the joke
Speaker 4:  is he let the sink in. It's not a
Speaker 4:  complicated idea. The word sync has two
Speaker 4:  meanings. That's the whole joke.
Speaker 3:  And now it's in
Speaker 4:  And now it's in. And I'm just like, it's like
Speaker 4:  you guys, this is he's, he's just being a clown. Like
Speaker 4:  it's pretty funny actually. Like he's a billionaire. He
Speaker 4:  showed up in an office with a sink so that he could tweet, let that sink
Speaker 4:  in and none of you got it.
Speaker 5:  Where is the sink now though?
Speaker 4:  We just like dropped it on Praga girl's desk. She's like
Speaker 4:  dropped it through the desk. All right. That's enough Twitter for this
Speaker 4:  episode. Like I said, when the deal closes, assuming it closes tomorrow,
Speaker 4:  we'll have another whole episode with Liz
Speaker 4:  Emergency episode. We'll put it in the feed. It'll be right there for you
Speaker 4:  if you want Twitter stuff. But you know, other things are happening in the
Speaker 4:  world and the deal hasn't even closed yet. Who knows It's gonna happen. Let's
Speaker 4:  talk Microsoft. So Tom, you wrote a great piece about 10 years of
Speaker 4:  surface. It has been 10 years. You and I have talked about this many
Speaker 4:  times. The surface line effectively rescued the Windows
Speaker 4:  market. Yeah, it's one of the only examples I can think of, of the OS vendor
Speaker 4:  making the hardware and competition with its partners where everyone actually
Speaker 4:  became a success and now we're in this moment where it's like they made some
Speaker 4:  more surfaces and they're right back where they started with like an arm
Speaker 4:  surface and it's just as crappy as it was 10 years ago. It's like weirdly
Speaker 4:  full circle.
Speaker 7:  Yeah and it's, it's at the point where it's where does it go next? I think
Speaker 7:  that's, that's the big question because obviously they had before the pandemic
Speaker 7:  and I think this is the most important bit of the surface history is that
Speaker 7:  they were really pushing for this jewel screen. Yep. Future, you know, they,
Speaker 7:  they, they show that stuff super early, which is kind of unusual for Surface
Speaker 7:  as well. And then obviously the pandemic hit and they, you know, they completely
Speaker 7:  just went the opposite way cause everyone was wanting to work from home.
Speaker 7:  They were focused on laptops so they kind of scrapped that idea. But it's
Speaker 7:  like, does that come back at some point? Like who knows? I don't know. Like
Speaker 7:  so I visited the, the headquarters spoke to P Pernet and the whole
Speaker 7:  Surface team and we were in this like room, which is like their roadmap room,
Speaker 7:  which is essentially a room with Windows but they're all blanked out.
Speaker 7:  They have like essentially free sort of rows of
Speaker 7:  tables where they'd have products. So it's like the current, the next version
Speaker 7:  and then the next version after that. Now obviously they didn't have those
Speaker 7:  laid out when I went in cuz you know, they thought they'd, they'd get rid
Speaker 7:  of those but that's essentially what that room is for. But I thought it was
Speaker 7:  kind of interesting that the Neo was still in the room when I visited. So
Speaker 7:  it was like obviously they had shown off some of the history, some of those
Speaker 7:  devices and all that sort of stuff. But I feel like that's Dell will come
Speaker 7:  back at some point.
Speaker 5:  Why did they stop? Like why did it go away?
Speaker 5:  Because all their partners were working on it too. I remember Dell and Lenova
Speaker 5:  were both like, wanna see this? Yeah And they would like always kind of like
Speaker 5:  pull you into a room and show it to you and be like cool. And then everybody
Speaker 5:  was like, No we don't do that anymore.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, I think it was partly because it just wasn't really ready the software
Speaker 7:  and then it was like a big demand for, for Windows
Speaker 7:  itself to be better. So then they were like, okay, let's just
Speaker 7:  take the stuff that we were doing, the simplification, all the design
Speaker 7:  work and this, roll this into a new version. Windows will try and capitalize
Speaker 7:  on that for our OEMs. And let's be honest, look at some of the specifications
Speaker 7:  for Windows 11. They, they pushed the CPU stuff up. So it's trying to
Speaker 7:  be a bit of a moment to have that old glory of windows where they would,
Speaker 7:  you know, a cycle of new hardware and and that sort of moment.
Speaker 7:  So I think there's, there's a so many different factors into why, why they
Speaker 7:  kind of paused that or cancel it, whatever you wanna call it.
Speaker 3:  Well I think one of them also is just there was this massive
Speaker 3:  leap in the number of people who suddenly wanted and
Speaker 3:  needed very straightforward, very functional pieces and the idea of
Speaker 3:  like sell me something new and insane, like goes out the window when it's
Speaker 3:  like I have to go to school tomorrow. Like I need a thing that works. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  And Microsoft was I think correctly also dealing with, there's like
Speaker 3:  a chip shortage and the stuff guitar to make and there's supply chain issues.
Speaker 3:  So it seems, it seems like Microsoft, like a lot of other companies was like,
Speaker 3:  okay we, we make this lineup of very good products and then this
Speaker 3:  lineup of like bonkers experimental, we think the future but
Speaker 3:  definitely not ready products. And I think like probably correctly made the
Speaker 3:  choice to like center back on some of that stuff. But now the question
Speaker 3:  is when do you get back to it? Cause like Tom, you
Speaker 3:  and I both have been talking that Panos about folding in dual screen devices
Speaker 3:  for like a decade now. Like that dude is in on this idea. Like I don't know
Speaker 3:  if he's right but he will, he that man will spend every dime Microsoft
Speaker 3:  has trying to make dual and folding screens a thing if they let him do
Speaker 3:  so.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, he, he always pretty much comes back to the idea of the device like
Speaker 7:  will mold to you, you know, like the different mode switching and, but like
Speaker 7:  that's his, that's his big thing. It's whenever the hardware's right for
Speaker 7:  that I guess. But the piece that I wrote was like obviously the history there
Speaker 7:  but then the, whether they can really nail what's next or or whether
Speaker 7:  like in 10 years we're still on the Surface Pro like, cause it's kind of
Speaker 7:  become their sort of MacBook Air like devices very
Speaker 7:  similar to what it started at. It's, it's got a form factor that's kind of,
Speaker 7:  you know, everyone's familiar with and they refine it every year essentially.
Speaker 7:  So like this year's one isn't really that different. The thing that's very
Speaker 7:  different is that they've got an intel or an arm chip that you can pick between,
Speaker 7:  which is I think that whole arm stuff is still not, is still
Speaker 7:  not there you know like it is still very early on and whether you wanna blame
Speaker 7:  Microsoft for that or Qualcom or developers or whatever
Speaker 7:  or the whole, the whole lot I think, I think you probably blame both but
Speaker 7:  if you do run Windows on an M one on M two it runs quite
Speaker 7:  well. So
Speaker 4:  Wait, how do you run Windows on an
Speaker 7:  M two? Some people have been able to to hack it and get it running.
Speaker 7:  The problem with the Qualcomm stuff is they just don't have the performance.
Speaker 7:  Like Yeah even in the single, single Freddie performance is pretty bad.
Speaker 7:  They're like basically offering up I five chips from like two, three years
Speaker 7:  ago in terms of performance And then on the operating system side you don't
Speaker 7:  quite have the apps that are obviously they're all emulated
Speaker 7:  essentially if you wanna run run Chrome. Although you could Google cause
Speaker 7:  they don't let anyone who uses chromium compile it for Arm.
Speaker 7:  So there's another, there's another aspect to that as well. Obviously Microsoft
Speaker 7:  does cause they've put in all the work and and they, they can go and do that
Speaker 7:  but like brave only just put out a preview build because they went and put
Speaker 7:  in all the work that Google for some reason is refusing to do. So
Speaker 7:  there's, there's a whole lot of things that that go into making that a a
Speaker 7:  thing. But I mean Mike's was trying, been trying to do this for a decade
Speaker 7:  now. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  This is what I mean if you recall the Surface line launched
Speaker 4:  with the Surface and the Surface rt. Yeah. And they have
Speaker 4:  been trying to make Windows Onar a viable
Speaker 4:  competitor in so many ways for
Speaker 4:  so long and we, it's 10 years later and they're like
Speaker 4:  here's a surface with an arm chip in it and God bless them. They
Speaker 4:  didn't put Windows RT on it. Like the most ill-fated version of Windows
Speaker 4:  to ever exist still has a start button still looks like Windows theoretically
Speaker 4:  seems like run whatever app, but it's just as limited it feels like as Windows
Speaker 4:  rt, right? It can't run every app. The apps runs an emulation are slow and
Speaker 4:  the underlying arm chip is
Speaker 7:  Slow. I wouldn't say it's just as limited as RT but like, cuz it's basically
Speaker 7:  just Windows 11. The main problem is the non arm apps are slow.
Speaker 7:  So you really do need developers to actually port those apps across. And
Speaker 7:  if you're using stuff like, you know, Slack, all those sort of apps that
Speaker 7:  haven't been compiled in arm, then you're gonna notice it hugely. But then
Speaker 7:  if you think about it as just being a, a really expensive, like really expensive
Speaker 7:  Chromebook, then it's like if you start using most of the stuff out the
Speaker 7:  actual browser out of edge, which which is arm then it's not so bad. And
Speaker 7:  then you get the battery life improvements, all that sort of stuff so you
Speaker 7:  can see where the future is. It's just, they're not there yet at all because
Speaker 7:  they need those developers to really buy into Arm. And to be honest, there's
Speaker 7:  not enough OEMs that are really buying into it and and putting these devices
Speaker 7:  out at a reasonable price.
Speaker 5:  But do they actually need those developers? Cuz that was one of the things
Speaker 5:  that was really good about when Apple did it, is they had that emulator to
Speaker 5:  just do it, to just speed it up for these people. Cuz they're like,
Speaker 5:  Yeah we want everybody to do this and it'll be way better if you do, but
Speaker 5:  we're just gonna do this other thing for most of you because we
Speaker 7:  Can't. Yeah. I do wonder what the performance would be like on the Windows
Speaker 7:  simulator if the chips were better. Yeah. If they were at the sort
Speaker 7:  of M one, M two level. I don't know. It's hard to say really. Yeah, like
Speaker 7:  I, I dunno for sure. I think there's, there's a mixture of it,
Speaker 3:  Right? That's the thing I keep coming back to too is like all of these things
Speaker 3:  and I think you're right that there's a lot of blame to go around and Microsoft
Speaker 3:  is clearly doing more now to try and get developers interested
Speaker 3:  in building these things. They're putting out nicer dev kits that run arm,
Speaker 3:  like there are good signs and instruction. It took them way too long to like
Speaker 3:  make any real moves in this way. But it, it does seem like Apple's move was
Speaker 3:  like, oh your app is not perfectly optimized. Here is infinity
Speaker 3:  processing power. We will solve all of your problems with just
Speaker 3:  brute force and like reading your story and then reading
Speaker 3:  Monica's reviews of the Surface Pro nine and the Surface laptop. Like all
Speaker 3:  I could think the whole time is like if Microsoft is not deep down the road
Speaker 3:  of making its own chips to solve some of this problem for itself, like what
Speaker 3:  in the hell are they doing? But it
Speaker 4:  Did like that's the SQ three. It's a qual Qualcomm chip
Speaker 4:  that Microsoft says it helped design.
Speaker 5:  It's like a souped up Qualcomm chip.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. All they do is they take, they take the chip with an extra
Speaker 7:  call and then they do some driver work with Qualcomm and then that's
Speaker 3:  It. They go to San Diego and they say, can you make it faster? And, and Qualcomm
Speaker 3:  says no and Microsoft says okay and then they leave.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. But like who makes faster arm chips? Apple.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. And soon probably Microsoft, like the rumors of Microsoft
Speaker 7:  building arm chips have been around for like the last couple of years for,
Speaker 7:  for servers and surface. So I think we'll be talking
Speaker 7:  about surface devices in five years and then we've let Jim, when they were
Speaker 7:  so crappy, like the Surface Pro nine and then
Speaker 7:  they'll all be on Microsoft chips and then hopefully they would've actually
Speaker 7:  nailed the actual chip work there. Because I think Microsoft has proven
Speaker 7:  that relying on like Invidia in the early days of Tegra and relying on
Speaker 7:  Qualcomm has just not really got them anywhere of Windows and on, even though
Speaker 7:  they have done a lot of the operating system work.
Speaker 5:  How would that work with their OEM partners though? Because if they start
Speaker 5:  making their own chips Yeah, then that just makes it really,
Speaker 5:  really messy with those OEMs.
Speaker 7:  It does, yeah. I mean who knows who they partner with to do it, but
Speaker 7:  I feel like it's the next phase of it though, isn't it? Like maybe they license
Speaker 7:  those chips out a lot of the, the stuff that Surface does,
Speaker 7:  like they license the pen technology out but they don't actually charge for
Speaker 7:  it. Yeah. And then they share the, the whole, you know, the kickstand design,
Speaker 7:  all that sort of stuff with Intel and, and all the OEMs. So they've all benefited
Speaker 7:  from it in one way or another. That's why basically every device looks like
Speaker 7:  a surface because they've shared those designs
Speaker 4:  And once took a very memorable walk around CES with
Speaker 4:  ps. We just looked at all the OEM tcs and he was like, this is all
Speaker 4:  the stuff, like this is why this is successful. Like when I give them credit
Speaker 4:  and I want to give them a lot of credit, they took a more abundant PC
Speaker 4:  industry that could not compete above $700
Speaker 4:  and and created one out of thin air with the
Speaker 4:  surface. Like that's legitimately exciting and legitimately no
Speaker 4:  other OS vendor has ever managed to compete with its licensees.
Speaker 4:  And the way they made it work is they just gave, they did the innovation,
Speaker 4:  they spent the money. I've been in the room with all the prototypes and sty
Speaker 4:  like we did that story every year for like five years. Like
Speaker 4:  we're gonna go to the surface styrofoam room. Then they gave it away, right?
Speaker 4:  They did not keep the engineering benefits to themselves. They, they
Speaker 4:  accelerated the ecosystem by giving away
Speaker 4:  the engineering the OEMs themselves were not doing or could not afford
Speaker 4:  to do. That's cool. Like there's real business strategy
Speaker 4:  and model innovation that went into all of that. And now there's at the hard
Speaker 4:  wall that they've been at for years of, they cannot go
Speaker 4:  on, they cannot go beyond the form factor of the surface
Speaker 4:  into folding screens, into thinner designs, into whatever else
Speaker 4:  because you have to get away from Intel to do it. And Arm and windows
Speaker 4:  are just, they just hate each other. It's like when you're watching your
Speaker 4:  favorite show and the writers are like, All right, now these two characters
Speaker 4:  are gonna get together. And you're like, no, they, they don't belong together.
Speaker 4:  That's Windows and Arm. I don't know how else to
Speaker 5:  Describe it. It's Joey and Rachel.
Speaker 4:  That's what I was thinking but I didn't wanna say it out loud.
Speaker 5:  I'll say it out loud. It's Joey and Rachel.
Speaker 7:  I'm curious if there's a world where Microsoft makes its own arm
Speaker 7:  chips licenses them out for some, you know, nominal fee
Speaker 7:  to to OEMs and Intel builds them.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. That's a future that like Intel will be super happy about.
Speaker 3:  That seems like a gigantic win for Microsoft too. Like even if, if it
Speaker 3:  can like kick off this next flywheel of like that's how you compete with
Speaker 3:  the iPad in a meaningful way in terms of like battery life and connectivity
Speaker 3:  that tell you compete with the New Max. That's like, that's how you win
Speaker 3:  as an ecosystem. And as long as they keep caring about Windows
Speaker 3:  more than they care about making money from Surface, which continues to be
Speaker 3:  the case as far as I can tell. That's just a huge win. Like I I I assume
Speaker 3:  that's where Microsoft's going. The intel part of it I hadn't thought about
Speaker 3:  which would be sort of fascinating and they'd make a lot of like America
Speaker 3:  First Noise in a way that would be really interesting. That seems to me
Speaker 3:  like where Microsoft ought to be going if they're
Speaker 4:  Not No we look, we had, we had Pat on the other show that I'm not allowed
Speaker 4:  to mention,
Speaker 3:  We don't have another podcast. Nobody listened to Eli. There is no other
Speaker 3:  podcast.
Speaker 4:  I'll happily put an AMD logo on the side of a chip fab in Ohio.
Speaker 4:  I'll happily put another logo. Right. And like he knows that
Speaker 4:  he's gotta make his foundry business real. If he's making
Speaker 4:  five nanometer arm chips, 18 Angstrom arm
Speaker 4:  chips or whatever, whatever they're
Speaker 5:  And like lower than five nanometer, lower than five nanometers, you're
Speaker 4:  Gonna make a look. If he's making them for Microsoft and there's a Microsoft
Speaker 4:  logo in an ARM logo, he doesn't care cuz he's, he's just getting the volume
Speaker 4:  and the foundry that he needs to like save the business. Yeah. While
Speaker 4:  they desperately try to catch up on the, on the processor design side. All
Speaker 4:  of that is three years away. Like they just broke ground on this
Speaker 4:  foundry, you know, like they're not even close to it right now.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. But if, if they time it right, it could be the perfect time for Intel
Speaker 7:  with like the geopolitical tensions trying to compete with
Speaker 7:  tsmc. Like if they get it at the right time, you know,
Speaker 7:  they should build for, for anything really.
Speaker 4:  Do you think that the surface line, you know the, the new Surface
Speaker 4:  laptop, the Pro nine is just like an evolutionary step. Are these
Speaker 4:  like upgrade worthy devices? Are they just there? Like have you
Speaker 4:  gotta buy one? You buy one? Yeah.
Speaker 7:  I don't think like, this year's a bit weird because it's 10 years you thought,
Speaker 7:  oh they're gonna do some crazy device, you know, but they, they kind of weren't
Speaker 7:  thinking in that way from when I was talking to them and it wasn't really
Speaker 7:  like a big fanfare for them. It was like, you know, a point to sort of reflect.
Speaker 7:  But in terms of the actual devices, yeah they're just, they're very incremental.
Speaker 7:  Right. The Surface Studio two plus the Fuller
Speaker 7:  $4,300 or 4 5 4 4,500
Speaker 7:  if you get the keyboard as well and the mouse and the sign. It's
Speaker 5:  Got a 30 60 in it.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, it's got 30, 60 and an 11th Jen Chip
Speaker 3:  Wwa.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. And we're on, we're on 13th Jen at the moment. Well not those mobile
Speaker 7:  chips, but they're about to drop. The interesting part of
Speaker 7:  about, of the whole of these surface devices this year is the pronoun
Speaker 7:  with the, the arm and the internships that we've just been talking about.
Speaker 7:  But they are very incremental. But I think more interesting is that
Speaker 7:  these three devices a decade from when they first started
Speaker 7:  releasing the, the Surface RT tablet on, on, on Arm,
Speaker 7:  on Invi Tera back in the day it's come,
Speaker 7:  it's come full circle because Panos actually told me that
Speaker 7:  they originally were planning to actually release a pc,
Speaker 7:  a laptop and a tablet for, for Windows eight for Surface,
Speaker 7:  which is something he hasn't really talked about before. And he said those,
Speaker 7:  those other two devices dropped off cuz they, you know, they bit off more
Speaker 7:  than they could chew so they, they weren't quite ready to launch
Speaker 4:  Them well. So like Michael Dell showed up and was like I'll kill you if
Speaker 4:  you put out a desktop. Yeah, that's my whole business. They wouldn't do a
Speaker 4:  laptop for years, right?
Speaker 7:  Well yeah but apparently they were always planning to,
Speaker 4:  John Lenovo was like outside with a knife.
Speaker 5:  Old John
Speaker 5:  Lenovo,
Speaker 4:  It's Michael Dell, John Lenovo, Steve hp
Speaker 7:  But the, the OEMs famously didn't know until, I think
Speaker 7:  Bulmer called them like a couple of days before or something that, so I feel
Speaker 7:  like they were probably still planning to do the laptop early on
Speaker 7:  and maybe there was a bit of om pressure so it probably pushed it out
Speaker 7:  even further than maybe they were expecting. But then they were obviously,
Speaker 7:  obviously Surface RT landed a bit rough Surface Pro was,
Speaker 7:  you know, the form factor was there, but it wasn't quite until the Pro Free
Speaker 7:  came when everyone was like, okay this makes sense.
Speaker 4:  That was the one where they, they really got the the kickstand right?
Speaker 7:  Yeah, yeah the kickstand, it went free two
Speaker 7:  as bit ratio biggest display. It was really feeling light.
Speaker 7:  It was, it was like a bunch of different hardware things came together
Speaker 7:  and it kind of made sense for everyone. So, and I think probably after that
Speaker 7:  device and they were like okay we can go ahead and do the laptop now. Cause
Speaker 7:  they were probably focused on getting that pro free. Right.
Speaker 4:  They had given away enough Hinge Engineering to be
Speaker 4:  like, all right, can we do a regular laptop now? And they were like, yes
Speaker 4:  we've we've taken enough hinges from you.
Speaker 5:  I was gonna say it's while that the laptop has been kind of like
Speaker 5:  boring it's entire ti this entire time
Speaker 3:  I would but like in the best possible way, I'm totally convinced that the
Speaker 3:  Surface laptop is the like most underrated surface by a million
Speaker 3:  miles because it's just like they do such cool stuff on the Surface
Speaker 3:  Studio and the Surface Pro three has like a great form factor but like if
Speaker 3:  you just want a laptop, the Surface laptop is a great laptop and it
Speaker 3:  has been for a while now. It was, it was kind of
Speaker 3:  has its fits and starts at first but like the last couple have been very
Speaker 3:  good and I feel like it doesn't get nearly the shine I guess Alex, because
Speaker 3:  I think you're right. It's like they're not breaking any new ground there.
Speaker 3:  They're just like, would you like a good laptop? We made one of those
Speaker 7:  But do you, do you remember the early days though, like putting Fabric,
Speaker 5:  Loved that
Speaker 4:  Fabric, right? Again that's, they did that at Knife point. John
Speaker 4:  Lenova was like, here's what I want you to do. Upholster the
Speaker 4:  laptop, right.
Speaker 5:  Make sure it's stains really nicely.
Speaker 7:  But act actually that reminds me of, of an anecdote that I didn't actually
Speaker 7:  include in the story but like Ralph Groan who's like
Speaker 7:  their, I can't remember his exact title but he's, he's basically Windows
Speaker 7:  and Devices does a lot of the design work. He recounted
Speaker 7:  like that idea of like trying to put the fabric on the
Speaker 7:  laptop and and how difficult it was cause they thought oh we're just gonna
Speaker 7:  slap the Surface Pro keyboard on top of a laptop and glue it and it'll be
Speaker 7:  fine. But it wasn't. And he said that it greatly reduced
Speaker 7:  the repairability, which is why I fixed it, gave it like a zero when they
Speaker 7:  first tore it down. And he said that if they were gonna make that trade off
Speaker 7:  again he probably wouldn't make it.
Speaker 4:  I think that makes sense. That is, you know, that was before Microsoft
Speaker 4:  went to Repairability as a virtue. I think right after that I
Speaker 4:  think they woke them up in some way cuz they started making a lot of noise
Speaker 4:  about it right after that happened.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. And last year they partnered up with iix it
Speaker 7:  to, to do some like kits for technicians and stuff to be able to repair
Speaker 7:  surface devices and their schools have obviously creeped up as well, especially
Speaker 7:  on the laptop side. And then they did the, I can't remember the name of it
Speaker 7:  now. It's the, the laptop go. They have so many
Speaker 7:  different names. The really cheap one, that's what I say and that thing is
Speaker 7:  like super repairable for technicians. Like you can pull the display off
Speaker 7:  and change the ram and everything is essentially repairable in it.
Speaker 7:  So that's, I think that's the kind of hint of where they might go with surface
Speaker 7:  devices as well. But on on the arm side, the stuff that they've done with
Speaker 7:  like the new processing chip on there and the AI stuff, I think
Speaker 7:  that's kind of a hint of where they really want to go or they see how
Speaker 7:  computing's changing. Especially like, you know like on Discord
Speaker 7:  or on on Zoom or Teams, it does like the background removal, like
Speaker 7:  if your dog barks and that sort of stuff. The difference with what they're
Speaker 7:  doing is they're actually using this separate chip so that it doesn't even
Speaker 7:  use your CPU or gpu. So that's, that's kind of interesting if we're gonna
Speaker 7:  offload productivity tasks and all that sort of stuff to a separate
Speaker 7:  chip in the future. Kind of like what's what Apple's doing.
Speaker 4:  That's, so back to the future man I had a, I had a Mac in like
Speaker 4:  the nineties that had a separate DSP chip in it for things like that.
Speaker 4:  Like everything old is new again like all the time. By the way I, the Mac,
Speaker 4:  I had the shortest lived Mac in history. It was called the Centra six 60
Speaker 4:  av. It was on sale for like 68 days and somehow I
Speaker 4:  had one but it had a DSP in it.
Speaker 7:  That's what we call a British Prime Minister sort of time.
Speaker 4:  That's one Liz Trusts. It was, it was the macro
Speaker 4:  head of lettuce and somehow the lettuce was a much more reliable school
Speaker 4:  computer. Microsoft also had earnings this week. It seems like
Speaker 4:  things are fine for Microsoft
Speaker 4:  ish.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, I mean like so their revenue was okay, their profits weren't and
Speaker 7:  everything else, but I think it's more their outlook that's quite surprising.
Speaker 7:  So when does OEM revenue drop by like 15%, which you know, PC sales
Speaker 7:  have dropped by 15% so it all kind of like lines up but then they're
Speaker 7:  saying OEM revenue next quarter is gonna drop the high
Speaker 7:  thirties percent. Wow. And devices revenue, which includes Surface
Speaker 7:  and HO HoloLens and PCE accessories now is gonna drop by
Speaker 7:  30%. So like that's, that's some big heavy drops that they're
Speaker 7:  forecasting and alongside that zero growth has slowed down.
Speaker 7:  So they're getting hit sort of like three times with
Speaker 7:  some of the market stuff. So I think next quarter is gonna be very difficult
Speaker 7:  for them and probably met and Amazon and everyone else who's, whose profits
Speaker 7:  are, are hurting at the moment. So it's their forecast that have really got
Speaker 7:  their stock wobbling at the moment. So
Speaker 3:  It seems like cloud gaming though is starting to
Speaker 3:  tick up and win in in a pretty interesting way. Like it's, what was
Speaker 3:  the number that like 20 million people have tried it at some point, which
Speaker 3:  is one of those like meaningless numbers. It seems big but like what has
Speaker 3:  used it mean? I don't know. Yeah but it does seem like they're, they're pretty
Speaker 3:  optimistic about where this is headed I feel like.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, like they shared 10 million earlier this year and that was just
Speaker 7:  before they signed that deal with Epic Games to bring Fortnight to exports
Speaker 7:  cloud gaming. So that's clearly made the the numbers double.
Speaker 3:  Oh that's right and that you don't even have to pay for it, right? You can
Speaker 3:  just do it. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Okay. Exactly. That's the only game. Yeah you could play for free. So I think
Speaker 7:  that's like their experiment to see what if they let free to play titles
Speaker 7:  on there, how much revenue they're gonna donate from in game purchases and
Speaker 7:  stuff. But yeah, like I, it's still really early though Cloud and
Speaker 7:  he was, he was kind of interested listening to Phil Spencer speak at the
Speaker 7:  Wall Street Journal live last night. He was talking about how game
Speaker 7:  past is 15% of the exports content and services revenue and that how
Speaker 7:  he thinks that's gonna remain the same. So obviously the revenue will grow
Speaker 7:  overall, but he thinks that it's, it's gonna account for that 10
Speaker 7:  to 15%. So and it sounds like Gain
Speaker 7:  pass is is kind of hitting some slow down in growth in, in
Speaker 7:  terms of the console side. I think their long bet is that Apple and Google
Speaker 7:  will be both be forced to make changes on mobile and that's their, their
Speaker 7:  like sort of in in the future. But that's a long, that's a long big bet
Speaker 7:  and they're spending billions of dollars on that. So it's still the growth
Speaker 7:  that they really need for for Game Pass is isn't quite there yet. And I think
Speaker 7:  there was, there was a report today from Axios where
Speaker 7:  Satin the benefits he gets for his salary and all that sort of
Speaker 7:  stuff, he gets them based partly on you know, game pass growth and
Speaker 7:  they were supposed to hit 75% and they hit 20 something
Speaker 7:  percent instead. So you can see that they were clearly expecting a lot more
Speaker 7:  growth in Game Pass this year and it wasn't quite there. So it's just
Speaker 7:  some interesting dynamics going on with Game Pass and they're bet on
Speaker 7:  gaming then it's definitely a clear case that it's slowed down a little bit
Speaker 7:  more than they were expecting.
Speaker 3:  It seems like to some extent Microsoft's bet there is like
Speaker 3:  a bet on Congress getting something done and changing things cuz it seems
Speaker 3:  very unlikely to me that they're like Apple is just going to suddenly change
Speaker 3:  its mind and be like nevermind Microsoft, welcome back to the app store
Speaker 3:  and betting on Congress to get things done so that Satya and can make more
Speaker 3:  money is a dangerous game to be playing right now.
Speaker 5:  Well it's not just Apple and Google that needs to change like it is
Speaker 5:  also the ISPs in the United States need to actually
Speaker 5:  deliver internet that can support this product. Like part of me
Speaker 5:  is thinking that's one of the reasons that they did Fortnite is that's got
Speaker 5:  a huge audience, a wide variety of people are using that. It's not
Speaker 5:  just those people who can afford an Xbox Series X and live in a house
Speaker 5:  with like 200 megabits down so they can test it and see how it's running
Speaker 5:  on these other things and probably not as great as they would
Speaker 7:  Like. Yeah, they get, they probably get some some really good data out of
Speaker 7:  that. Also, Phil said last night, you know, the Keystone device, their
Speaker 7:  export streaming console that appeared on his shelf that you tweeted a
Speaker 7:  couple of weeks ago, he now says that that is not coming for like a few years.
Speaker 7:  So you could tell that that that cloud stuff is still a little bit early
Speaker 7:  and and they're not quite sure where they're gonna go with it. So yeah,
Speaker 4:  Wait, hold on. There's like a lot to unpack with this whole thing. First
Speaker 4:  of all, like betting on Congress is one idea and to some extent,
Speaker 4:  you know the, they did a bunch of stuff recently. Did they do all
Speaker 4:  the things? They did not do all the things. Had they confirmed Gigi Stone
Speaker 4:  to the fcc? No, I don't know what they're doing. Got a whole episode
Speaker 4:  of that other podcast coming with that. Have they passed the antitrust films?
Speaker 4:  They have not. Is there whatever, I dunno what they're doing. Apple, we'll
Speaker 4:  talk about this later, but Apple just this week was like, guess how in charge
Speaker 4:  we are of the iPhone the most in charge.
Speaker 4:  Here's all these new app store rules, here's new ads in the app store. Like
Speaker 4:  yeah, we're just in charge of this product and no one stopped us yet. There
Speaker 4:  was all this noise last summer and we don't care. Here's
Speaker 4:  here's the new app store rules by the way, we're gonna, the 30%
Speaker 4:  fee now extends even more things like Apple's the most in
Speaker 4:  charge there unless Microsoft can figure out how to get over that wall and
Speaker 4:  deliver a game streaming app on iOS, which they have not done and
Speaker 4:  we've heard about at various hearings and trials and whatnot. Like they
Speaker 4:  can't do it. The other piece it's fascinating to me is
Speaker 4:  Microsoft was so close to announcing that
Speaker 4:  game streaming product. Like Phil Spencer was on decoder
Speaker 4:  and told me it was coming. He said it out loud, It's coming
Speaker 4:  soon. Tom, you and I both were like ready for
Speaker 4:  the announcement. Like
Speaker 7:  Yeah that was like a last second switch.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, like we, we just like heard the rumbles like we were like, all right,
Speaker 4:  this is gonna happen. Like we're ready. And then like it went away and now
Speaker 4:  he's like, it's years away. We've decided to partner with Samsung, by the
Speaker 4:  way Wall Street Journal Tech live that conference perhaps to Joanna. She
Speaker 4:  got good stuff out of Phil Spencer. She got good stuff out of Jaws and Credit
Speaker 4:  Figure 80. We'll talk about that stuff too. But Joanna's a co-founder. You
Speaker 4:  gotta throw it out to her. That's just the Verge family. It's really what
Speaker 4:  is the Wall Street Journal Tech Live conference but an extension of the first
Speaker 4:  time. That's how I feel about our alumni network. We reverse colonized
Speaker 4:  Bloomberg. Let's just take it over. It's, it's mine now. So like
Speaker 4:  it's just weird. Like that whole product was their future and the brick wall
Speaker 4:  still exists and the idea that they're just gonna like put apps on Samsung
Speaker 4:  TVs is not gonna grow that market. I'm like pretty
Speaker 4:  confused about all because they were like, they were rip Roar and ready to
Speaker 4:  go and now they're in neutral.
Speaker 5:  I fundamentally do not think it's Apple or Google. That's the hold back here.
Speaker 5:  I I like Spencer has repeatedly talked about this, Microsoft as
Speaker 5:  a whole has talked about the internet is the barrier here. Like Microsoft
Speaker 5:  has been doing these internet reports for years now being like, the FCC
Speaker 5:  is failing on this. Everybody is failing on this, the internet is bad in
Speaker 5:  this country and they're financially incentivized to do that both because
Speaker 5:  of cloud gaming and Azure and like that's what's holding
Speaker 5:  them back. Like I don't think it's a coincidence that they open up cloud
Speaker 5:  gaming to Fortnite. They get a ton of new users and then they're like whoa,
Speaker 5:  whoa, whoa, let's hold back on the next big cloud
Speaker 5:  push. Because they're seeing probably over and over and over again that
Speaker 5:  the internet just can't support it as everyone who tries cloud gaming
Speaker 5:  sees, despite the mini Stadia fans insistence
Speaker 5:  on their Reddit to this day.
Speaker 7:  I also think a lot of it those that they went pretty quick with experts cloud
Speaker 7:  gaming. Like they weren't intending to launch it when they did.
Speaker 7:  As far as I'm aware, Google came out with, it was the Assassin Creek game
Speaker 7:  in the, in the browser. They had that working in people in press hands
Speaker 7:  playing with it. Microsoft announced like the day after that or
Speaker 7:  two days after it we're doing X Cloud, but we weren't have public trials
Speaker 7:  until a year later. So they, they, I think Google really
Speaker 7:  spooked them in many different ways and so they, they pushed
Speaker 7:  ahead with this, but they made it an optional thing. They put actual Xbox
Speaker 7:  consoles in the cloud rather than, you know, PCs or infrastructure like
Speaker 7:  that. And they're kind of held up by that in a way because
Speaker 7:  they're streaming architecture isn't quite as good. It's, it never was quite
Speaker 7:  as good as Stadia. Definitely not as good as G Force. Now they're still at
Speaker 7:  10 80 p 60 frames second they can't, they can't do 4K
Speaker 7:  streaming at the moment. So if you're gonna go to TVs and you're gonna launch
Speaker 7:  a streaming stick or device or whatever you wanna call it, you kind of need
Speaker 7:  that 4k I think. I think you do now I think, I think there's an expectation
Speaker 7:  for that even though it's cloud, I think it's still an expectation.
Speaker 4:  I have a much, much more cynical read of this vastly more
Speaker 4:  cynical read of this.
Speaker 5:  Give it
Speaker 4:  To us. The game stream market is unproven. No one knows how the economics
Speaker 4:  work. The Xbox console market super proven and they have
Speaker 4:  the chips now and it's the holiday quarter and they can just sell a lot of
Speaker 4:  Xboxes. And that is a, that is a safer
Speaker 4:  economic bet in the current climate with the rocky waters ahead
Speaker 4:  for Microsoft to just be like, you know what, pump the brakes in your weird
Speaker 4:  experiment sell a lot of Xboxes this quarter. Gaming
Speaker 4:  is quote unquote recession proof. That's what people always say. There's
Speaker 4:  still all this pent up demand cuz we weren't able to sell them for the past
Speaker 4:  year and a half. Just flood the market with Xboxes. People will buy
Speaker 4:  games. We know how that money works and I, I have to imagine some
Speaker 4:  combination of don't take the risk on the future, like
Speaker 4:  just extract the money from the present for as long as we can.
Speaker 5:  Well, especially with, I was gonna say with the economy, with the fact that
Speaker 5:  they're seeing these like, look our, our outlook's not so great for the next
Speaker 5:  couple of quarters. Like yeah, let's just huddle up, let's do
Speaker 5:  what we know how to do best and make, make money consistently
Speaker 5:  rather than get really big and experimental.
Speaker 4:  All right, so we're gonna go to break, but we come back, we're gonna talk
Speaker 4:  about a company doing the exact opposite of that
Speaker 5:  Idea,
Speaker 4:  Which is meta. We'll be right
Speaker 4:  back.
Speaker 4:  All right, we're back. So let's talk about meta real
Speaker 4:  quick. There's a lot going on with this company. We
Speaker 4:  started the show by saying it was flagship podcast on tv. What I'm referencing
Speaker 4:  is Jim Kramer CBC Anchor who told people, I guess last
Speaker 4:  quarter, quarter before you should invest in meta. And then this quarter
Speaker 4:  the stock has tanked. Meta's business is like falling apart
Speaker 4:  and they're throwing money at the Metaverse. And today he apologized to everyone
Speaker 4:  for that this be he said he trusted management too much and it was pure hubris
Speaker 4:  the metaverse. And he said it's almost a rogue situation, which is an incredible
Speaker 4:  thing to say about Meta, which I will remind everybody
Speaker 4:  is fully controlled by Mark Zuckerberg. He can just do whatever. You can't
Speaker 4:  fire him. He owns the whole company. He has super voting share
Speaker 4:  every year. This is a true story. Every year the stockholders of meta
Speaker 4:  vote to somehow limit Mark Zuckerberg's power. But
Speaker 4:  because he has super voting share, he just votes no and wins. This happens
Speaker 4:  every year. It's crazy.
Speaker 4:  So I don't know, but meta's in like a really tough
Speaker 4:  spot. They had horrible earnings. The Apple ad
Speaker 4:  tracking transparency prompt ruined their ability to track it hurt
Speaker 4:  the advertising market. They've tanked there, they're losing, shared a TikTok
Speaker 4:  and then they are just blowing money on reality
Speaker 4:  labs. Just 10 billion gone
Speaker 4:  against the metaverse. And I would say effectively no one's
Speaker 4:  happy.
Speaker 3:  You could say that. I mean the numbers are really insane. Like I'm just looking
Speaker 3:  at these now. Like just the, my favorite part is, so Meta's
Speaker 3:  reality Labs division, which is the one overseeing all the Metaverse stuff,
Speaker 3:  all the o all the, the artists formerly known as Oculus stuff, all the Quest
Speaker 3:  stuff, The Quest Pro, it made 285 million
Speaker 3:  in revenue for the quarter, which was down 50%, which
Speaker 3:  they're saying mostly is due to lowering sales of the Quest
Speaker 3:  two, which makes sense. It's relatively old, it's got a big price hike.
Speaker 3:  That division which remember $285 million in revenue
Speaker 3:  lost 3.7 billion this quarter and
Speaker 3:  9.4 billion for the year so far. So this company is going to
Speaker 3:  spend what looks like 13 or $14 billion
Speaker 3:  on the Metaverse this year. Meanwhile
Speaker 3:  it's hemorrhaging money because of Apple and some of the ad tracking
Speaker 3:  stuff and some of it's like core revenue drivers
Speaker 3:  like Facebook are not the sort of unstoppable
Speaker 3:  juggernauts that they once were. And so it's like, it, it just seems like
Speaker 3:  all at once this week everybody looked at this and was like, Hey Mark,
Speaker 3:  no,
Speaker 4:  But
Speaker 3:  We are not interested in this company doing this thing anymore.
Speaker 5:  But David, you you gotta spend money to make money. That's,
Speaker 5:  that's, that's, that's what's sucks out there saying
Speaker 3:  You have to spend all your money,
Speaker 5:  You'll make money, it's gonna be fine
Speaker 7:  While your lunch is being stolen by TikTok.
Speaker 3:  Exactly
Speaker 4:  Right. So this is the thing. So they, they did report some of their user
Speaker 4:  numbers. So all these numbers are crazy. They all just
Speaker 4:  have crazy names and they just make people on Facebook seem
Speaker 4:  like robots. Like Facebook doesn't know you as a person. It only knows you
Speaker 4:  as something called a daily active people.
Speaker 3:  That's
Speaker 4:  Me. It's, I refuse to be a daily active person.
Speaker 4:  Never.
Speaker 5:  How dare
Speaker 7:  You? I haven't been daily active since the pandemic.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I'm more of a three times weekly active person.
Speaker 4:  So daily active people up 4% monthly active
Speaker 4:  people, right? Daily active users. The difference between a
Speaker 4:  family daily active person and a daily active user, who knows, they're
Speaker 4:  saying these numbers are up and, but they're up like 2%,
Speaker 4:  3%. And this is after they were like,
Speaker 4:  turn on the jets, compete with TikTok, everything's real now
Speaker 4:  and this is the best they've been able to do. And then here's the main
Speaker 4:  piece of the puzzle. They've delivered
Speaker 4:  17% more ad impressions here over year. But because the
Speaker 4:  tracking isn't as effective because Apple refuses to let
Speaker 4:  them track. Like when you say tracking, there's like lots of tracking.
Speaker 4:  There's whatever scary tracking you're thinking of your head. But very
Speaker 4:  specifically what Facebook has long promised
Speaker 4:  people is we can show people an ad on Facebook,
Speaker 4:  we can target their interests so precisely. And then later on
Speaker 4:  when they buy something from you, we can attribute it to that ad.
Speaker 4:  Cuz we can track people from the app onto the web onto wherever else they
Speaker 4:  are. All the stuff we can do. Apple's ad tracking, transparency broke
Speaker 4:  those links. So Facebook can't track you outside of its app anymore. It can't,
Speaker 4:  when you buy something on the web, it can't attribute, Hey, you saw this
Speaker 4:  ad a bunch of times how you bought something outta the
Speaker 5:  Web just on iPhones
Speaker 4:  Stuff. Just on iPhones. But you know,
Speaker 5:  There's like 12 people who are using their little Chromebook and being like,
Speaker 5:  I'm gonna see what, what Dottie's doing today on Facebook.
Speaker 4:  The money, the money is on the phone. And the, the, the people who spend
Speaker 4:  money, famously there's a lot of data about this. People on iPhones spend
Speaker 4:  more money. So add impressions went up
Speaker 4:  17% year over year. The price per ad, because Facebook
Speaker 4:  can no longer guarantee success went down
Speaker 4:  18% year over year. So delivering more ads that are cheaper,
Speaker 4:  that means their revenue went down 4%. And that's like,
Speaker 4:  that's a death spiral. Like, I don't know how else to describe that. The
Speaker 4:  value of the product they sell for money is going lower even
Speaker 4:  as they deliver more of them. And it's like as like whatever ads are free,
Speaker 4:  like digital advertising is your, like there's not someone in
Speaker 4:  like the Facebook ads factory like hammering out bespoke ads
Speaker 4:  like it's software, but you're making more of a thing
Speaker 4:  for tiny user increases that you're selling for cheaper.
Speaker 4:  Wow. Over here Mark Zuckerberg is just the lighting cash
Speaker 4:  on fire to give people legs in the metaverse. Like
Speaker 4:  it's just a bad situation all around.
Speaker 3:  Well, and and I think that the like macro thing going on here for me
Speaker 3:  is that it's super, super clear that everybody's
Speaker 3:  out on the metaverse. Like there there was that moment where everybody was
Speaker 3:  all in on the metaverse and there was like a Metaverse ETF and all these
Speaker 3:  companies went public and it was a whole big thing. And now what's very
Speaker 3:  clear, like this big meta investor, Ter Capital, their ceo
Speaker 3:  whose name currently escapes me, Brad Gertner wrote this whole thing
Speaker 3:  basically being like, we still think Facebook is a strong business and
Speaker 3:  Instagram is a strong business and WhatsApp is a strong business and we wish
Speaker 3:  you'd stop paying attention to this stupid thing where nobody has legs
Speaker 3:  and focus on the thing where you actually know how to make money. And that
Speaker 3:  was really fascinating to me cuz like there's, there's this one line of thinking,
Speaker 3:  like you're saying that like all of that stuff is sort of has peaked
Speaker 3:  and is now just going to be sort of slowly managed to climb for a long time.
Speaker 3:  And thus what meta needs to do is find this next thing.
Speaker 3:  But that I thought was really interesting that it's like, no, there's still
Speaker 3:  a good successful company in here. You just won't pay attention to it because
Speaker 3:  you're so obsessed with this idea of the metaverse because you'd rather not
Speaker 3:  talk about content moderation anymore. And so you're, you're like running
Speaker 3:  away from the company that works towards one that increasingly people think
Speaker 3:  just doesn't, If that has really flipped in people's minds, it's gonna be
Speaker 3:  really hard for meta to pull out of any of this.
Speaker 7:  I thought it was interesting that Phil Spencer last night called it the metaverse
Speaker 7:  poorly, poorly coded or poorly created video games, something like that.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, yeah. When when Microsoft like there teaming up with meta to do that,
Speaker 7:  it works.
Speaker 4:  I was like, Yes, Phil Spencer go nuts man.
Speaker 4:  But
Speaker 7:  He's being honest, right? Like he's he's telling you how it
Speaker 4:  Is. So Yeah, he's like, I make kick ass video games. Do you make a good video
Speaker 4:  game? Yeah, chances are we'll just buy your shit.
Speaker 8:  I'm Phil Spencer.
Speaker 4:  And then he's like looking at, at these avatars in the metaverse seems like
Speaker 4:  what are you doing? Or are these polygon counts
Speaker 4:  five by Xbox series X? Like do
Speaker 4:  it like there's like a whole thing there that is like worth thinking about
Speaker 4:  because Microsoft has all but abandoned tolerance.
Speaker 4:  Like it's
Speaker 7:  Dead. Yeah, pretty
Speaker 4:  Much. Right? And they're like, screw it, me can take all this risk and we'll
Speaker 4:  just deliver Outlook to their headset when it's time.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And I think that's like perfectly smart for Microsoft in
Speaker 4:  like the current economic conditions they're in. Whereas Zuckerberg is like,
Speaker 4:  we're sticking with it. Well he has a quote. The first part is, I get
Speaker 4:  that a lot of people might disagree with this investment, but from what I
Speaker 4:  can tell, I think this is going to be a very important thing. There's
Speaker 4:  the confidence you want, it's like what?
Speaker 8:  But a fake,
Speaker 4:  So a backdrop of all this should note we have Quest
Speaker 4:  Pro review units. I have one, Alex Heath has one. Eddie Robertson has
Speaker 4:  one. The embargo time in this review was incredibly short.
Speaker 4:  It was like four days, whatever. So people have them in there out in the
Speaker 4:  world. I'm sure you've seen other reviews. We are just taking our time. I
Speaker 4:  think it is impossible to know whether the Metaverse is going
Speaker 4:  to work or Zuckerberg from what he can tell, this is gonna be an important
Speaker 4:  thing without a thorough review of this product. Like
Speaker 4:  this product is the payoff right now. It's the state of the
Speaker 4:  art. Yeah. That meta can deliver against this vision.
Speaker 4:  So we were like, we're not gonna rush this out in four days. We've taken
Speaker 4:  a couple meetings in Horizon Worlds. We we're doing the stuff my here's my
Speaker 4:  preview. I think you all know that I was a big fan of the Quest two, I remain
Speaker 4:  a big fan of the Quest two. The Quest two is an excellent consumer product.
Speaker 4:  Agree it under promises and over delivers. And
Speaker 4:  so, and it, and for a while there it was cheap. So you like bought
Speaker 4:  this thing that you didn't feel like you were blowing a lot of money on,
Speaker 4:  you had put it on. You're like, this is cool. Grandma's in the
Speaker 4:  metaverse, she's freaking out. There's stuff to do in there. It's like a,
Speaker 4:  it's a game console. It's a cheap game console that can do a lot of things.
Speaker 4:  And it, like I said, under promises over delivers. My preview
Speaker 4:  of the Quest Pro is this thing promises a
Speaker 4:  lot.
Speaker 8:  Tune in next time. Our review of the Quest
Speaker 8:  Pro
Speaker 4:  Boy that's a lot of promises at $1,500.
Speaker 5:  And they also announced that they were gonna like, they
Speaker 5:  confirmed the Quest three is coming next holiday
Speaker 5:  season.
Speaker 4:  But the Quest three is more game console. That's fine. I don't think that
Speaker 4:  like,
Speaker 5:  Well that's gonna, like anybody who is like anybody who is like, maybe I'll
Speaker 5:  get a Quest two this holidays. Like why, why, why am I gonna go spend more
Speaker 5:  money for the Quest two with a Quest three is next
Speaker 4:  Year? Well they've already, from these earnings, we can tell they have, people
Speaker 4:  have stopped buying a question, like they raised the price and everyone's
Speaker 4:  like, well I'm done with this idea. Because again, it's a toy. Like
Speaker 4:  I, it was competitively priced like the Nintendo Switch,
Speaker 4:  right? Right. And you now it's, it's 3 99, it's
Speaker 4:  competitively priced with the PS five. Like it's just
Speaker 4:  in a different zone and you just get way more out of it.
Speaker 4:  You get way more out of its competitors. So I just don't, I don't think the
Speaker 4:  1500 Quest Pro, which is marketed at business use
Speaker 4:  cases, right. Like it's like do Zoom is a
Speaker 4:  cartoon. It has nothing to do with whether you're gonna like play games in
Speaker 4:  it. Like the Quest two. It Yeah, I just, they're just in a weird spot. So
Speaker 4:  we've got that review. We're working on it. Addie's writing it. Keith and
Speaker 4:  I are just helping. I don't knows. Cause the idea is that you're doing
Speaker 4:  it together, the point of this product is not to be alone, it's to be together.
Speaker 4:  So we're, we're trying to like hang out together. The metaverse,
Speaker 5:  Right? It's trying to answer for like Slack and Zoom
Speaker 5:  in everything. It's just trying to be like the office is done,
Speaker 5:  $1,500 instead of a real office.
Speaker 4:  Go. Yeah. The the, the one thing I will say without trying to give too much
Speaker 4:  away, the first time we all met in Horizon with
Speaker 4:  the face tracking was just one of the funniest 15
Speaker 4:  minutes of my entire life. Cuz it was just us making
Speaker 4:  faces at each other as cartoons. Like I was like, I'm making a kissy
Speaker 4:  face. Can you see the kissy face? And a is like, yes. And then she's just
Speaker 4:  waving her cartoon hands around and that was legitimately some of the
Speaker 4:  funnest, funniest moments with a computer
Speaker 4:  I've ever had.
Speaker 3:  Is it an HR violation to make a face tracking kissy face
Speaker 3:  at,
Speaker 4:  In a, in
Speaker 5:  A meeting?
Speaker 3:  Is that, I dunno.
Speaker 4:  Fish face. I was wearing a fish face. Many cops are on this. It was a fish
Speaker 4:  face. We gotta take a break. We'll be back. Apple earnings are out. We
Speaker 4:  gotta get into that. We'll be right
Speaker 4:  back.
Speaker 4:  Okay, we're back. Bunch of Apple News to talk about.
Speaker 4:  Mac West 13 Ventura hit iPad review, iPad Pro
Speaker 4:  Review. Apple confirm the iPhone's getting usbc.
Speaker 4:  There's a rumor of a 16 inch iPad, which is deeply
Speaker 4:  hilarious. But we should start with earnings. Cause earnings literally hit
Speaker 4:  while we were doing the last segment, right? Apple made a bunch of money
Speaker 4:  in a way that other tech giants are not making a bunch of money right now.
Speaker 4:  Alex was threat.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, no. So services are up are like 5%.
Speaker 5:  Tom's been helping me do the math off screen. You guys can't hear him do
Speaker 5:  it all. I think the big surprise here is that Max are
Speaker 5:  up what, 20%? Which is
Speaker 7:  Just 25. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  25%. Which is just a big number.
Speaker 4:  That's a new MacBook error. That's that number.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It's just that that that MacBook Air jump
Speaker 3:  Counter that to what just happened to Microsoft and Microsoft's
Speaker 3:  guidance. And it's like we, we've seen this like tank in the PC industry
Speaker 3:  over the LA and Chromebooks have been collapsing over the last
Speaker 3:  few quarters and Apple is just like, here, would you like a
Speaker 3:  very fingerprint heavy MacBook Air? And people are like, Yes I do.
Speaker 4:  Thank you. Well, so they they won't tell us we don't know that it's the MacBook,
Speaker 4:  it could be the Mac studio. Like we don't know. You
Speaker 3:  Only have to sell 12 of them and it it that that's all your
Speaker 3:  revenue.
Speaker 7:  So these, these max sales are more than what Apple for. Cuz they,
Speaker 7:  they forecast 9.3 billion and it was actually 11.5
Speaker 7:  billion and they forecast 20.1 billion for
Speaker 7:  services and it was actually 19.2 billion. So like their forecast
Speaker 7:  seemed to be a little bit all over the place at this time. But the, the max
Speaker 7:  sales are super surprising, especially in the light of like
Speaker 7:  15% down PC market overall at the moment.
Speaker 7:  The Mac is like wow
Speaker 5:  Above. I think what we're seeing here is that
Speaker 5:  everybody went out and they rushed out. They bought a computer cuz everybody
Speaker 5:  needed a computer because of the pandemic. And now everybody's like, Wait,
Speaker 5:  but I want a computer that just works. And so they're going a bite
Speaker 5:  back.
Speaker 4:  Sorry, I don't, I think they, I think this was
Speaker 4:  the first year that a bunch of kids like physically
Speaker 4:  went back to school and they already had their Chromebooks but then they,
Speaker 4:  there was a new MacBook error and it was available to buy for a bunch of
Speaker 4:  college kids. Went back to school. Like there's just a thing
Speaker 4:  happening in the market for laptops where Yep, people
Speaker 4:  bought sort of what they needed to get by for work from home. But then
Speaker 4:  we're kind of just like back to the laptop market as it
Speaker 4:  was. So it's just normalizing down. And whenever Apple releases
Speaker 4:  a new mainstream model like sales go up except
Speaker 4:  this quarter when they release new iPhones and everyone
Speaker 4:  was like, yes, iPhone sales are up quarter over quarter. It's
Speaker 4:  beneath estimates but there's just all this chatter that
Speaker 4:  people don't care. And like that's the weird part to me
Speaker 4:  because all of that services, I think the reason Apple bets so heavily on
Speaker 4:  services and then constantly forecast services is cuz they're just trying
Speaker 4:  to squeeze more money out of existing iPhone owners because they
Speaker 4:  can't, they've sort of lost the ability to tell what will be hits and what
Speaker 4:  won't be hits.
Speaker 7:  I'm one of the suckers that bought an iPhone full team pro and I had a 13
Speaker 7:  pro and I was like, as soon as I got it, I was like, why,
Speaker 7:  why did I buy this? Yeah. Like it's
Speaker 7:  just, it's just like, it's not that radically different
Speaker 7:  and
Speaker 5:  I think more people are like me. I bought an 11 pro year when it came
Speaker 5:  out years ago and I bought the 14 pro this year and I was like, oh wow, this
Speaker 5:  is a big, this is a big change for me. But these, these
Speaker 5:  changes are so incremental that most people are like, Do I wanna spend
Speaker 5:  the money on that? Do I wanna spend the money on my ever increasing rent?
Speaker 5:  Do I wanna buy a MacBook Air to replace this Chromebook? I panic bought
Speaker 5:  at Best Buy in March, 2020. Like
Speaker 5:  where's my money gonna, I have finite money. Where does it go when
Speaker 3:  You factor in the fact that the pros are the only exciting phones in the
Speaker 3:  lineup? And like even the, the earnings seemed to confirm that, that the,
Speaker 3:  the 14 and 14 plus didn't do anything for anybody. Which I think was
Speaker 3:  more or less the correct response to the 14 and 14 plus.
Speaker 4:  No, no, the 14 plus wasn't in there man.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. But there have been, there have been reports that the demand is not
Speaker 3:  what Apple hoped for. Like, I don't know, I don't see a lot of 14 pluses
Speaker 3:  floating around. I'll just say you that
Speaker 4:  How could you even tell they all look the same
Speaker 4:  like this. David's like walking up to people like you've got a big phone.
Speaker 4:  Can I see how many cameras he got on the back of that thing? Cause I, I've
Speaker 4:  been collecting some data.
Speaker 7:  He's been using these Quest Pro to scan their phone, find
Speaker 7:  out
Speaker 4:  Big, cheap, big cheap screens always works. I'm just holding onto this in
Speaker 4:  my heart.
Speaker 3:  Well, we'll see, I I believe in you when I believe in big cheap screens.
Speaker 3:  But I do think like it as the price of these things gets more
Speaker 3:  expensive. Like one, one thing I have sort of held
Speaker 3:  onto for a long time is that Apple believes its users are not at
Speaker 3:  all price sensitive and that it can raise the prices of everything into Infinity
Speaker 3:  and that will always work. And until now it has always worked.
Speaker 3:  But it does make me wonder like if the only interesting phone is the
Speaker 3:  $1,100 one, are people going to wait one
Speaker 3:  extra year now to upgrade because now the good phone is
Speaker 3:  $1,100.
Speaker 4:  Yes. Yeah. And the thing that's interesting about it by the way, is the dynamic
Speaker 4:  island, which Tom, I don't know you feel about it, but I've had this thing
Speaker 4:  now I feel the same way about it when I did the review, which is, and
Speaker 4:  iOS sixteen.one came out this week with live activities.
Speaker 4:  There's a bunch of apps.
Speaker 7:  But, but I tell you what, it's one of those things that although it doesn't
Speaker 7:  feel like it's fully complete, I feel like if I went back to an iPhone without
Speaker 7:  it, I'd miss it. It's, it's one of those, those things you get, you get
Speaker 7:  used to and you sort of, I love the time of
Speaker 3:  It. The timer's great. I use it for playback controls. I like that a lot.
Speaker 5:  The confirmation of face ID is just like so
Speaker 5:  soothing and satisfying. I'm like ooh, that's a nice
Speaker 5:  feeling.
Speaker 4:  I just wanna point out, and I'm just gonna say this, think about how
Speaker 4:  many like major technologies have come out
Speaker 4:  in the past five years where at the end of it we're
Speaker 4:  like, boy that was really useful for timers, right?
Speaker 4:  Like
Speaker 7:  Alexa,
Speaker 4:  All of Alexa, all of Google assistant, all of
Speaker 3:  Siri, not Siri sir. Sucks at timers. Siri does not get credit for
Speaker 3:  timers.
Speaker 7:  Seriously. Pardon?
Speaker 4:  Seriously, I can't do two things at once. The entire dynamic,
Speaker 4:  like great for timers
Speaker 7:  I'm gonna be happy. The dynamic on and once it tells me the A score,
Speaker 4:  There you go. Right? So the, the API for live activities just hit like this
Speaker 4:  week in 16.1, you know the flighty app, which is the
Speaker 4:  number one app they were showing off. It has been released, it uses the thing.
Speaker 4:  There's some really interesting cooking apps that are doing like the
Speaker 4:  recipe steps on the lock screen with the live
Speaker 4:  activities api. That's cool.
Speaker 5:  The best Reddit app has a little puppy dog
Speaker 5:  that runs around the dynamic island.
Speaker 3:  It's pointless but it's very charming.
Speaker 5:  And for a while it was destroying the battery life. It
Speaker 4:  Was great. But none of this makes you buy a phone. It's like all I'm saying
Speaker 4:  no it's, it's none of it is enough to upgrade. And there's
Speaker 4:  probably another year of iteration innovation before it becomes a must
Speaker 4:  have. Whereas I think for a lot of people with the iPhone 11
Speaker 4:  big cheap screen, that's the, that's the thing that will make them upgrade
Speaker 4:  if they have the money to upgrade. Which is I think a lot of people are like,
Speaker 4:  I don't need to spend this money right now. My phone works just fine. And
Speaker 4:  so what Apple's betting on is they can shove ads in everyone's
Speaker 4:  faces or squeeze more money out of more companies
Speaker 4:  by adding fees to more things and increase their money that
Speaker 4:  way. And that's just like, I don't know man,
Speaker 5:  This is kinda like the thing that happened with Meta where these companies
Speaker 5:  both have known this is coming. MEA knew that it was gonna get
Speaker 5:  absolutely bodied when it tossed all of its money into the
Speaker 5:  metaverse and it was trying to prep people for it and it did a terrible job
Speaker 5:  clearly by evidence of Jim Kramer crying on
Speaker 5:  television. But Apple knew has known for a
Speaker 5:  while now that that upgrade cycle is getting longer and
Speaker 5:  longer with its customers. People don't wanna do a one year
Speaker 5:  upgrade, they don't wanna do a two year upgrade. They're doing three years,
Speaker 5:  they're doing four years, they're doing five years and they're getting really,
Speaker 5:  really comfortable doing that because these devices are no longer like
Speaker 5:  gadgets that are having these huge amazing technological
Speaker 5:  advancements every year. They're pretty iterative. It's, I think it's the
Speaker 5:  same thing we've seen with laptops. It's the same thing we've seen with TVs
Speaker 5:  and honestly appliances.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Do you know what's gonna make you upgrade next year?
Speaker 4:  Say it. That's what I was gonna say. The eu. The eu,
Speaker 4:  yeah. European bureaucrats are gonna drive the greatest
Speaker 4:  iPhone upgrade cycle of all time.
Speaker 7:  They will.
Speaker 4:  So
Speaker 7:  Unless Apple just makes like what they did in the US this time
Speaker 7:  with the EIM stuff, unless Apple does, you know, a
Speaker 7:  sim train Europe plus years we see and enlightening in
Speaker 7:  America. I don't know like
Speaker 4:  I hope they do that. So let's explain what we're talking about. Notable
Speaker 4:  Verge trader, Joanna Stern again at the Wall Street Journal Tech live conference
Speaker 4:  had Greg Jos cred pedigree on stage like half an hour you should go watch
Speaker 4:  it. Great interview. She, great job. She asked them straight up what's she
Speaker 4:  gonna do about the eu, her new rap single,
Speaker 3:  You know she's gonna make a video where she raps about the eu. Now this is
Speaker 3:  your fault, you just spoke this into
Speaker 4:  Existence. So she said the EU is gonna mandate usc, what are you gonna do
Speaker 4:  about it? Jaws react. And actually John Gruber pointed us out. Craig
Speaker 4:  Fe looks at Jaws and just starts laughing cuz he doesn't, he's the software
Speaker 4:  guy. He have to answer that question. Jaws react has to answer that question.
Speaker 4:  So Jas Rack, a friend of the Verge and friend of the VER has Greg
Speaker 4:  Jaak says obviously we have to comply, we have no
Speaker 4:  choice. Which is incredible.
Speaker 4:  He looks super pissed about it, just so salty. Janet ask
Speaker 4:  when and Ja says the Europeans are the ones dictating timing for
Speaker 4:  European customers. And then she says, Well you do it everywhere. He says,
Speaker 4:  I'm not gonna talk about future products. Which is of course what he would
Speaker 4:  say. So it's true app laws to comply with all local laws,
Speaker 4:  but it's gonna happen. Like they're saying it has to happen and they're not
Speaker 4:  happy about it. And he gave some examples of things they're not happy about.
Speaker 4:  He was like, our solution was the power bricks would have removable cords.
Speaker 4:  Sure. It's just so not the right answer. But like that seems
Speaker 4:  like that's what we wanted. He's like the government tried to mandate all
Speaker 4:  this hearing aid stuff and it was a disaster and we finally just did it our
Speaker 4:  way and we gave the government what they wanted with all these pesky regulations.
Speaker 4:  And these are all the arguments that we've heard every time. And it is
Speaker 4:  also true. I would point out that Apple invented us
Speaker 4:  bbc, everyone forgets about this. U
Speaker 4:  BC was a standard effectively developed and pushed by
Speaker 4:  Apple because they wanted a single port on that first MacBook
Speaker 4:  ages ago. And now their argument is, what if we invent something that's better
Speaker 4:  than usbc? And it's like, well you could have put USBC on the phones
Speaker 4:  the whole time and then you could invented a new thing and then we could
Speaker 4:  have all just move to that but you won't. So we're just like stuck with
Speaker 4:  lightning. I don't know, it was a, it was a good exchange. You watch the
Speaker 4:  interview, Joanna did a, like I said, a great job pushing on
Speaker 4:  it. But Tom, I agree with you. That's the thing that drives the huge upgrade
Speaker 4:  cycle is this thing got way more convenient to charge.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. And I, I think Apple's annoyed at the fact, I don't
Speaker 7:  think they're annoyed at the fact that they have to do USBC cause that that
Speaker 7:  was probably in the plans at some point. But they're probably just annoyed
Speaker 7:  that they're getting dictated on the timing of it. So cuz cuz
Speaker 7:  they probably could have gone another couple of years with, with Lightning,
Speaker 7:  but now now they're like, we kind of probably have to do this next year year
Speaker 7:  because the legislation comes in for 2024. We don't know exactly
Speaker 7:  when it, when it sort of cuts in, but yeah, like they kind of need to get
Speaker 7:  something rolling probably next year on, on the iPhone 15 or
Speaker 7:  whatever it'll be. So I I don't think that they, they're very happy that
Speaker 7:  they had to do it then. I mean that's, that's the thing. Like it's not the
Speaker 7:  fact that they're being, that they have to do PBC cause they probably were
Speaker 7:  planning to do that. It's it's more being forced to do it at their inconvenience
Speaker 7:  essentially.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, I think if, if you're like reading applet leaves here, there was a,
Speaker 3:  there was a moment where Joss could have made a case about
Speaker 3:  connectors and what people want and instead he picked a fight about
Speaker 3:  timing. Right. So like, I I think you're exactly right Tom, that like this,
Speaker 3:  this is less about Apple not wanting to do usbc, which is
Speaker 3:  like basically every other device Apple makes charges via USBC
Speaker 3:  now, which is super irritating when I'm in the car or on a plane. That's
Speaker 3:  a whole different story. But yeah, Apple just does not like being told when
Speaker 3:  and how to do things. It seems to be like in the, in the
Speaker 3:  bylaws of going to work at Apple that if anybody tells you to do something
Speaker 3:  you have to be mad about it for two or
Speaker 7:  Three years. Yeah. And and I can appreciate some of their arguments where
Speaker 7:  it's like, you know, let's not forget Lightning was a good connector for
Speaker 7:  its, its time. Like they sold a lot of the problems that obviously USBC came
Speaker 7:  along to solve like reversible a lot smaller, all that sort of stuff.
Speaker 7:  So if they hadn't have done that, if they weren't free to do that, which
Speaker 7:  is kind of like what they're saying, you know, if there's, there's regulation
Speaker 7:  around this, it's gonna prevent them from doing this in the future. And I
Speaker 7:  think that's necessarily a hundred percent true, but I could see where they
Speaker 7:  wouldn't want governments to step in and say you have to have this on this
Speaker 7:  device, you know, for five years or whatever. Cuz it
Speaker 7:  does kind of hold that back if they do wanna do that. But
Speaker 7:  again, it's proprietary
Speaker 4:  That what Apple's really mad about is the EU did this again and they closed
Speaker 4:  the loophole. So the EU mandated micro usb
Speaker 4:  but then Apple just shipped a micro USB to lightning
Speaker 4:  adapter. It was like this little thing they shipped in the box
Speaker 4:  and that got them out of it because technically you could use all your
Speaker 4:  micro USB accessories and now so the EU said okay we're updating the
Speaker 4:  usbc. Every other manufacturer is like, great, we were already there. Like
Speaker 4:  who gives shit? And the EU also said you can't ship your stupid
Speaker 4:  little adapter and Apple is furious
Speaker 3:  Apple's. Like have you seen how many Dons we have?
Speaker 4:  Like our entire business is $29 doggles. I don't
Speaker 7:  The wearable accessories revenue
Speaker 4:  Just
Speaker 7:  Just gonna plummet.
Speaker 4:  So I, they closed the loophole. I I just think fundamentally I agree
Speaker 4:  with you David, they just hate being told what to do but they're so behind
Speaker 4:  on this. Like they invented this connector. It is they
Speaker 4:  connector they should, they should A done this a long time ago and B,
Speaker 4:  that next thing you're gonna do is take all the ports off the phone.
Speaker 4:  Which is, I don't like, I really like MagSafe, I just bought it yet
Speaker 4:  another MagSafe charger for my car. I'm like addicted to this
Speaker 4:  thing every time anyone makes it like 5% smaller.
Speaker 4:  I'm like I'm there for you. But the idea that I'm gonna get a really long
Speaker 4:  meg safe puck to like use at my house is just ridiculous. Like
Speaker 4:  that part of it is absolutely not ready and cannot charge
Speaker 3:  Fast enough. Wireless charging is like self-driving cars in that it's been
Speaker 3:  like 90% done for a really long time and it's gonna be 50 more years before
Speaker 3:  it actually works the way that it's supposed to.
Speaker 5:  Well it's also like wireless earbuds. Like the AirPods are
Speaker 5:  great. They are not, they, they don't compare to wired
Speaker 5:  headphones.
Speaker 4:  I know you guys talked about the new iPad review on Wednesday.
Speaker 4:  The thing that kills me about it is they took the headphones jack out of
Speaker 4:  the thing. Yep. Like again, it's just like they don't even make the
Speaker 4:  product. Like if you these humans greed, it's like
Speaker 4:  well then make kid headphones make AirPods for kids that
Speaker 4:  work seamlessly instead of being like, now your children will
Speaker 4:  get insecure Bluetooth headphones that suck
Speaker 4:  cuz that's what people are gonna buy. They're gonna buy $30 Bluetooth headphones
Speaker 4:  so kids it suck. And it's like well just be greedy all the
Speaker 4:  way, like all the way greedy Tim just make the kid headphones
Speaker 4:  you own beats. What are they doing Beats for kids. That's, that's
Speaker 4:  have at it. What does Dr. Dre think kids' headphones should look like? I'll
Speaker 4:  buy him as long as they pair seamlessly. And I, I think
Speaker 4:  there's just, there's a little bit of, I mean they look, they just made a
Speaker 4:  lot of money. They're selling everything all the time. But doesn't it feel
Speaker 4:  like they just like lost the plot just like a tiny little bit. Yes. Like
Speaker 4:  with the, by the way iPad sales are down, I'm guessing cuz people
Speaker 4:  like look at the iPad lineup, they're like, I don't know what the hell is
Speaker 4:  going on here. Can I have a MacBook error? And they leave the store.
Speaker 5:  Well the iPad was also their first product where they saw,
Speaker 5:  oh wait, we can't force people to buy a new one every year. Like
Speaker 5:  that was the very first one where everybody was like, I have one, I'm gonna
Speaker 5:  hold onto it for a decade.
Speaker 4:  I mean I think Mac have been like that for a long time.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, that's cause they never upgraded the processors on the Mac.
Speaker 4:  That's
Speaker 3:  True. Well the Mac has recaptured the plot is the funniest thing
Speaker 3:  about all of this. To me it's like the line is relatively straightforward.
Speaker 3:  The like Mac Pro's existence continues to be weird, but I think
Speaker 3:  we'll eventually figure that one out. Like the products kick ass, like
Speaker 3:  the MacBook error is like, it's very easy for me now to tell people what
Speaker 3:  computers buy. I just tell people to buy MacBook errors, which was true for
Speaker 3:  a long time and then not true and now it's true again. And as Apple has really
Speaker 3:  figured out how to do this again, it like surprised surprise
Speaker 3:  it's growing really fast and is massively successful again. But then in every
Speaker 3:  other lineup, especially with the iPad, they're just like, here's some
Speaker 3:  things. It's just like we, we, we had some parts so we
Speaker 3:  we like closed our eyes and threw them all at the wall and whatever stuck
Speaker 3:  together, we gave it a name and now you can have it if you want for $500
Speaker 3:  more than you spent and here's a dongle. Yeah and here's some
Speaker 5:  Dons. So how many years are we gonna see like the a
Speaker 5:  15 just recycled over and over again in these things?
Speaker 5:  Like those, those, those Haswell chips were for a while there.
Speaker 3:  I forever apparently. Yeah. And great news. It's more expensive.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Oh, so the the other piece of the puzzle, which we have not talked
Speaker 4:  about a lot and we don't have to dwell on too much, right? The Mac
Speaker 4:  is doing really well. It's Apple's most open platform in its way.
Speaker 4:  There's so I'm sure people can quibble about it, but the Mac is like, you
Speaker 4:  usually run an app on it, right? It's like the most open platform you can
Speaker 4:  do anything you want on it. The idea that apple's there to stand over your
Speaker 4:  shoulder and just like take 30 cents out of every dollar you spend, like
Speaker 4:  doesn't exist on the Mac, right? Super exists on iOS
Speaker 4:  and iPad os, right? It's totally closed platforms. Everyone knows about the
Speaker 4:  app store this week with iOS 16.1, Apple
Speaker 4:  updated it's app developer guidelines. The app store
Speaker 4:  rules Spotify head earnings this week too. Basically Spotify's on the
Speaker 4:  warpath. They're like, Look, we thought we were gonna do an audiobooks vertical.
Speaker 4:  We would sell audio books directly in Spotify. We had lawyers on
Speaker 4:  the product team reading Apple's rules as the product team
Speaker 4:  developed this, we thought we were in compliance with these rules. Apple
Speaker 4:  rejected our app like three times and then this week they just pulled
Speaker 4:  the feature and the thing that they pulled was
Speaker 4:  merely telling people that you could buy audiobooks
Speaker 4:  somewhere else.
Speaker 5:  Well they were sending a link, they were sending an email link,
Speaker 4:  Right? So you'd push the button and you're like, I want this audiobook. And
Speaker 4:  Spotify would send you an email with a link to where you could buy it,
Speaker 3:  Which is itself like a ludicrous solution to this problem. Like that
Speaker 3:  the fact that that's what Spotify had to do to comply with the rules is
Speaker 3:  ridiculous.
Speaker 4:  Yes. This is the, this is like the lead story in a miniseries called When
Speaker 4:  Lawyers Develop Products, Right? Like great, but they had to do it whatever.
Speaker 4:  And so Apple boots 'em outta the store and they say you can't do it. Then
Speaker 4:  this week Apple says if you have an app where you
Speaker 4:  can boost your social media posts, that's an an app purchase.
Speaker 4:  We wanna piece that pay up beyond 30% of that. This is like a direct
Speaker 4:  targeted meta because people boost Instagram posts and Facebook posts. You
Speaker 4:  just like do it right in the app. Apple's like this has always been our rule.
Speaker 4:  They gave a quote to Heath, he followed up and said,
Speaker 4:  why'd you have to clarify it then if it was always the rule,
Speaker 4:  No response. Meta is like they're directly taking a shot at your business.
Speaker 4:  Like Apple is building its own weird ads business and they're trying to undercut
Speaker 4:  hours by doing this. They already took be with app tracking hints, like this
Speaker 4:  is just a direct shot at me. Like Apple wants to knife meta, which
Speaker 5:  We saw that ad business grow this week. And then kind of like
Speaker 5:  immediately be like, Oh our bad, our bad. Because they started saying, okay,
Speaker 5:  now you can advertise your app alongside
Speaker 5:  other apps in the app store. And so there's like, here's my app to
Speaker 5:  stop gambling addiction next to would you like to gamble a whole lot
Speaker 5:  advertisements? And it's like, oh, that's how bad move Apple.
Speaker 4:  By the way, this is what happens when you aren't good at tracking. Like if
Speaker 4:  you don't build the ad business with some amount of
Speaker 4:  tracking and sophistication, what you do is you do
Speaker 4:  blunt force keyword targeting. And so
Speaker 4:  people type in gambling and you get the gambling
Speaker 4:  addiction recovery app and the gambling app and it's like
Speaker 4:  this is what makes, makes internet advertising hard, right? You you want
Speaker 4:  these like fine grain controls, they're required know more about people on,
Speaker 4:  on and on,
Speaker 3:  Whatever. Marco Armand was tweeting about how basically the targeting does
Speaker 3:  work. And the idea is that you can advertise your app in three
Speaker 3:  ways. You can do similar categories, which is basically like show people
Speaker 3:  who like things like my app, my app, you can do all
Speaker 3:  ca at all categories, which is all relevant app categories, which is how
Speaker 3:  you get the like gambling addiction equals gambling
Speaker 3:  mess. And then you can do other categories, which is just like show some
Speaker 3:  people my app. Like I just, it is just not a good system.
Speaker 3:  Like it's, it's this is suddenly you understand why
Speaker 3:  targeting advertising is like a useful and good thing that people
Speaker 3:  do to make money.
Speaker 5:  And it's like there's two very good ways of doing advertising.
Speaker 5:  There's have people curate it and that's a lovely usually nice
Speaker 5:  way of advertising. And then there's invade people's
Speaker 5:  lives so much that you know what they want before they do
Speaker 5:  and advertise that. And Apple was like, we're gonna do a
Speaker 5:  half-ass middle road, which is very un apple.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Apple was like all of our playlists are made by humans, but our ads,
Speaker 3:  we don't really know, we just kind of make it up as we go along.
Speaker 7:  But they, but they've been gradually creeping towards this sort of scenario
Speaker 7:  for, for a couple of years. Like right, the ads that they actually put into
Speaker 7:  iOS that so, you know, get Apple Arcade or get Apple Music,
Speaker 7:  they're, they're kind of gross as it is. They're terrible. But then they,
Speaker 7:  they also have started allowing developers to push their notifications as
Speaker 7:  as basically as marketing ads. Some of them you can't even disable.
Speaker 7:  So like, like Uber does it a lot. Uber Eats and Uber. You have to dig into
Speaker 7:  the settings and disable their, their crappy marketing notifications.
Speaker 5:  Uber keeps telling me that I have 250
Speaker 5:  Taiwanese dollars credit that I can use at any
Speaker 5:  point. Never gonna use it.
Speaker 4:  I will say the ads in the setting screen, they
Speaker 4:  have somewhat improved them and made them a little less grish in I was
Speaker 4:  16. There's still a red bubble that says too when you open settings
Speaker 4:  but it's, it is now inside of a line that says
Speaker 4:  services included with a purchase instead of just the straight up tout that's
Speaker 4:  like you can play games on your iPhone four ninety nine.
Speaker 5:  They're just kind of undercutting their own arguments over and over and over
Speaker 5:  again on advertising because they've been going after meta for a long time
Speaker 5:  being like, we don't do what they do, we're better. We don't
Speaker 5:  track you. We are honest and ethical.
Speaker 5:  Ignore all these kind of scummy, borderline unethical things we're doing
Speaker 5:  to get you to like buy Apple Arcade. That's different.
Speaker 5:  That's us. We just care.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I think the app store, there's like a lot of fine arguments in
Speaker 4:  like the notification like in the marketing, the
Speaker 4:  services and the platform they own. Yeah, okay. Like very fine grain, very
Speaker 4:  nuanced arguments. We rolled out an ad platform in the app
Speaker 4:  store that we totally control where your only point of contact with your
Speaker 4:  customer is your app page on the app store and now
Speaker 4:  we're gonna sell parts of that page to other people to try to get
Speaker 4:  them away from your thing into their thing. That's just
Speaker 4:  rude, right? Like that's just like straight up. Like
Speaker 4:  there are very few other retailers who will just openly undercut
Speaker 4:  you to make a little bit more money. But Apple's now at the
Speaker 4:  scale where that's the choice they have to make. This is like meta is like
Speaker 4:  meta is like way out over at skis. I'm not saying Apple's anywhere close
Speaker 4:  to this. They're just at the point of I'll put Google
Speaker 4:  search in this category. There's just a handful of these companies
Speaker 4:  that are so big that they don't really have to
Speaker 4:  care about the user experience. And I'm not saying that's everywhere with
Speaker 4:  Apple. I think that's true. Like the Max are really good in a
Speaker 4:  max super competitive environment all the time. The phone
Speaker 4:  generally is very good in a super competitive environment all the
Speaker 4:  time. But when Apple has to market apps who, there's nothing
Speaker 4:  there, they can just be whatever kind of rude Goliath they want. When
Speaker 4:  Google is like, what should the search page look like? Yeah, it's whatever
Speaker 4:  useless garbage Google wants to put there, right?
Speaker 4:  Facebook is feeling it. Like the products got so big they
Speaker 4:  took them for granted, TikTok showed up with a better user
Speaker 4:  experience for the stuff and now everyone's like, yeah I'm just gonna use,
Speaker 4:  it's like more fun than whatever garbage is happening on Facebook. And I
Speaker 4:  that that is like, you know, this is the argument against antitrust laws
Speaker 4:  is eventually the Giants will just collapse on their own because they're
Speaker 4:  monopolies and people will be like, screw this, the products are bad. But
Speaker 4:  it's also like you could just make them compete. You could just do a little
Speaker 4:  work to make them compete a little bit more. And Apple, right now at the
Speaker 4:  app store, I hope they see like the danger is
Speaker 4:  they did another one, another one of their apps
Speaker 4:  rules updates was they clarified this rule
Speaker 4:  that NFTs or digital purchases, which like, I
Speaker 4:  don't whatever, but like, but if you just like do the math on that,
Speaker 4:  right? So let's say you're playing a game and the whole promise of an NFT
Speaker 4:  is that you would like buy a skin in the game, right? You would buy a skin
Speaker 4:  in, in Fortnite, not iOS, but use Fortnite example, you're gonna buy a Fortnite
Speaker 4:  skin and now you own it and you can sell it, right?
Speaker 4:  This is the whole promise of the NFT marketplace is that you would just like
Speaker 4:  buy a digital item and then you own it and you could like sell it. So let's
Speaker 4:  say you buy it from Fortnite, you B you buy a Fortnite skin from Epic
Speaker 4:  for $10 and now you own it and you wanna sell it on
Speaker 4:  another marketplace. Well you've automatically lost
Speaker 4:  30% of the value of the thing, even if you sell it for $10
Speaker 4:  back to someone else. Because Apple is now saying in their
Speaker 4:  rules, and if t sales are in at purchases, you gotta give them
Speaker 4:  30% so that apple's just like flatly,
Speaker 4:  just like effectively removed this from existing on iOS.
Speaker 3:  Well what's crazy is like the math on that particular transaction means
Speaker 3:  Epic would've made $7, you would've
Speaker 3:  lost $3 and Apple would've made $6 in
Speaker 3:  that transaction. Like Apple. It's insane.
Speaker 3:  Like the the and all all of the like, you know, Web
Speaker 3:  three nft people I follow on Twitter and stuff are like up in arms about
Speaker 3:  this because they're, they're like, you just basically just like
Speaker 3:  obliterated the liquidity of this market because now buying and selling is
Speaker 3:  now dangerous because you've just devalued everything by at
Speaker 3:  least 30%. It
Speaker 4:  Will definitely not happen on the phone. The very least they've guaranteed
Speaker 4:  that whatever innovation happens in this area, assuming the innovation happens
Speaker 4:  where it's good or useful, whatever. Right. They've
Speaker 4:  guaranteed it will not occur on the phone. Yeah, right. It's just like what
Speaker 4:  happened there. The same way they've guaranteed that whatever innovation
Speaker 4:  happens in game streaming will not happen on their phone. And that's,
Speaker 4:  to me these are like, these are the ideas whether you love them
Speaker 4:  or hate them, These are ideas that people are very excited
Speaker 5:  About. I was gonna say, I wanna know what like what Apple and Google, but
Speaker 5:  especially Apple knows about Congress that the rest of us don't. That they
Speaker 5:  can be so confident this week with all of these deeply, deeply
Speaker 5:  unpopular rules that they were like scaling back on last year when they thought
Speaker 5:  they were gonna get regulated into oblivion and now they're like, Nope, we're
Speaker 5:  firing both barrels. We're going balls to the wall.
Speaker 3:  It's just scoreboard, right? Like it's you, you, it's what it is.
Speaker 3:  Like he walks in and it's like the, the sort of overarching assumption
Speaker 3:  is that like Congress is gonna be taken by the Republicans, which means there's
Speaker 3:  probably gonna be less energy focused in this direction. Like any, like Tim
Speaker 3:  Cook just walks in and he's like, What do you have to show me from the last
Speaker 3:  four years of energy around this? Like, let's just keep pushing. I, I feel
Speaker 3:  like it's just the, it's like the pragmatic decision to make at some point.
Speaker 7:  What do you guys think about TikTok getting games? Cause that's,
Speaker 7:  that's apparently that's gonna be announced next week.
Speaker 3:  TikTok is like edged into this space for a while now and I feel like
Speaker 3:  it's one of those things that TikTok is either going to
Speaker 3:  try to do so much stuff. It like breaks the thing up that makes the app fun.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Or it's going to win in a big, huge way. And I feel the
Speaker 3:  same way about Netflix getting into gaming. It's like there's an adjacency
Speaker 3:  there that makes total sense to me. And there's also a thing that's like
Speaker 3:  maybe you fundamentally misunderstand why people are coming to your app and
Speaker 3:  I don't know which one of those it is and I think it's gonna be fascinating
Speaker 3:  to find out, but TikTok is like, it's another one that it's like, oh remember
Speaker 3:  how you were gonna ban us over and over and over and over every single day
Speaker 3:  for like four years? Remember how we're still kicking all y'all's asses?
Speaker 3:  Like, come at me bro. Here comes games. That's
Speaker 3:  like, that's how I imagine TikTok
Speaker 7:  Tick's fascinating for the future of wherever there's mobile innovation.
Speaker 7:  Because obviously Apple doesn't want rival app stores, which is
Speaker 7:  exactly why cloud streaming isn't there. Cause they don't, they don't want
Speaker 7:  those, those stores of stores cuz it frightens them obviously, but
Speaker 7:  is like a platform within itself. And it is, it's
Speaker 7:  basically everyone's just using it. Like people use it to search their
Speaker 7:  recipes. You know, like he kids aren't going to Google search,
Speaker 7:  they're staying within the Ward gardens of TikTok.
Speaker 3:  You know, who can cut all that stuff off at the knees? Is Apple like's gonna
Speaker 3:  do, music's gonna do games and Apple time it feels like can just
Speaker 3:  be like, No, no, we'll take 30% of that. Thank
Speaker 4:  You. So at the code conference, you know, Tim Cook was on stage with
Speaker 4:  Lauren Powell jobs and Johnny Ivan, it was Kara's last code and the
Speaker 4:  vibe was not be mean to tick Tim Cook. Like they were all there to talk about
Speaker 4:  Steve Jobs, but I'm still me. You know, So like ask him like what do
Speaker 4:  you think about TikTok? Like the Chinese app TikTok by the way is burning
Speaker 4:  cash. Like this is not a public company. We have no idea how much
Speaker 4:  money bite dance is spending to make TikTok the winner. How much money the
Speaker 4:  Chinese government is spending to make TikTok the winner. Like there's an
Speaker 4:  element of this whole competition is deeply unfair cuz we can't, we can't
Speaker 4:  see if TikTok is profitable or if the Chinese government just thinks it's
Speaker 4:  a good investment to have every American teen in their algorithm or
Speaker 7:  How accurate those view counts are.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. We just dunno. But whatever. It's popular, it's growing. There's
Speaker 4:  all this noise about bite dance. So I asked Tim Cook like, what do you think
Speaker 4:  about TikTok? And he is like, I'm not an expert on TikTok. And
Speaker 4:  I have been thinking about that answer ever since. Like, I
Speaker 4:  regret not immediately following up and saying, you have not
Speaker 4:  used the most popular app on your platform because it's wild to
Speaker 4:  me that that was his answer. That he was like, I don't know what's going
Speaker 4:  on with this app. It seems fine because it is closer to
Speaker 4:  the everything app that like Elon Musk wants to build Twitter
Speaker 4:  into. It does have all these like weird data
Speaker 4:  concerns. I have heard, this is completely unsourced, don't take this
Speaker 4:  for real, but like yeah, I've definitely heard about TikTok employees who
Speaker 4:  put their phones in airplane mode when they like leave the office. Like,
Speaker 4:  like there's like a thing with TikTok, like there's a weirdness about
Speaker 4:  it. I can't source that. I don't know if that's real, but it's under
Speaker 4:  scrutinized and Apple has the, the power to
Speaker 4:  scrutinize it and they like won't take it. That's weird, right?
Speaker 4:  Meanwhile they're like, meta let's kill it.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Just destroy it. Well I think they, they are obligated to
Speaker 5:  work with China and China has made it very clear every single time.
Speaker 5:  And I've spoken with like experts on, on on how, how
Speaker 5:  China works on this. When I was doing a story about Huawei before Huawei
Speaker 5:  got bodied by the American government,
Speaker 5:  and if you are operating in China and your business is based in China and
Speaker 5:  China wants you to do something about your business, you do it. It's not
Speaker 5:  like, let me think about it. It's like you do it or you get fond, bing
Speaker 5:  binged away for a couple of months until you, you come back
Speaker 5:  and you do it like authoritarian regime. You just,
Speaker 5:  you do what they say and TikTok existing there is
Speaker 5:  a little like unnerving and Apple just being like, Yeah, whatever is,
Speaker 5:  because Apple needs China. Yeah. Desperately.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I mean, and this is a, every time we do earnings, we have to go look
Speaker 4:  at their exposure to China, how well the cells are doing in China. So like
Speaker 4:  there's just all this stuff throwing around Apple. But I again, I would just
Speaker 4:  put some of this iOS stuff, these rule changes, these unhappy
Speaker 4:  developers Google search getting sort of like increased. You know
Speaker 4:  why people use TikTok search instead of Google search? Cause you get just
Speaker 4:  faster results on a TikTok. David, you did it for a while, right?
Speaker 3:  Yeah. It's, it's just more fun. Like it's,
Speaker 3:  which is, which is half of what searching is, right? You're like, I don't,
Speaker 3:  I'm not trying to figure out like, but
Speaker 5:  How many of the recipes end in an air fryer?
Speaker 3:  Oh, like three quarters of them. And, and the other quarter is terrible
Speaker 3:  recipes that other people are telling you not to make, but making
Speaker 3:  funny jokes about like it's, it's just wins all the way around. And it's
Speaker 3:  like, if I just wanna like watch some videos about a band I like,
Speaker 3:  TikTok is infinitely better at that than Google. But still, like Apple is
Speaker 3:  in this place where it, it is so in charge of how this stuff works on its
Speaker 3:  own platform that I don't know. It it, and it is coming from such a place
Speaker 3:  of confidence that it kind of feels like Apple is just going to
Speaker 3:  keep tightening and tightening and tightening the ropes until somebody makes
Speaker 3:  it stop. And it sure doesn't seem to think anybody's gonna make it stop.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Or it's like we gotta squeeze as hard as we can so when someone
Speaker 4:  makes it stop, we've collected all the money we can.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. It's it's probably both of those, right? Like it's, it's a win-win
Speaker 3:  for Apple at the moment.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. All right. We have gone way over also, I will just point
Speaker 4:  this out as we've been recording, apparently Twitter sent an email to all
Speaker 4:  staff saying there's an all staff meeting at 7:35 PM tonight West Coast.
Speaker 4:  So all you East Coast Twitter employees, you're gonna find out what's going
Speaker 4:  on at 11:00 PM tonight. We've got an entire emergency
Speaker 4:  episode of The Verge has coming. When that deal closes or doesn't
Speaker 4:  close, we'll do that tomorrow. We wanted to get this one out. Thank you for
Speaker 4:  listening Tom, thank you for joining us. No worries. We have forgotten to
Speaker 4:  talk about the EIN display with a 16 megapixel rear camera. That's
Speaker 5:  For next week. That's
Speaker 3:  For next week. Yeah. This is why we have two verge casts a week. We have
Speaker 3:  plenty of time to talk about
Speaker 5:  That. 5 99. It's the Onyx books. Don't get it. That's a bad idea.
Speaker 4:  Amazing. Josh Jeza, who many of you will
Speaker 4:  remember from our Fox phone coverage has a huge feature this week
Speaker 4:  about the fight in Puerto Rico to turn the power back on. It
Speaker 4:  is a complicated adventure of a tale through the
Speaker 4:  bureaucracy with real stakes. Go read that. It's just excellent
Speaker 4:  work that's on the site. We'll be back on Wednesday and then,
Speaker 4:  you know, like in like several hours because of Elon, you can call us. You
Speaker 4:  can call the Virgin House hotline. Eight six six Verge 11. That's (866)
Speaker 4:  837-4311. I love those phone calls. So like the most fun you can tweet at
Speaker 4:  us. David's at Pierce. Alex is Alex h Kranz. I'm at Reckless and
Speaker 4:  Tom is at Tom Warren. That's it. That's the Vercast Rock and
Speaker 4:  roll.
Speaker 1:  And that's a rap for Verge Cast. This week we'd love to hear from you. Shoot
Speaker 1:  us an email@vergecasttheverge.com. The Verge Cast is a
Speaker 1:  production of The Verge and the Box Media Podcast network. The show's produced
Speaker 1:  by me, Liam James, and our senior audio director, Andrew Marino.
Speaker 1:  Our editorial director is Brooke Mentors. That's it. We'll see you next
Speaker 1:  week.