# Transcript
ID: e8b3b2b0-3bdf-11ed-8237-550b67c49416
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: GTA leaks, TikTok search, and Apple reviews hotline
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-2421021433284833022/6996701724687672453/s93290-US-3590s-1664006772.mp3
Description: Welcome to the flagship podcast of measuring changes in gravitational force.
02:13 - David Pierce chats with video game reporter Ash Parrish about how footage of Grand Theft Auto VI has leaked online.
GTA 6 gameplay leaks online in 90 videos
Rockstar confirms hack, says work on GTA VI will ‘continue as planned’
19:40 - David tries to use TikTok's search feature as a replacement for Google.
31:40 - Nilay Patel, Allison Johnson, and Victoria Song answer listener questions about the new iPhones and Apple Watch.
Apple iPhone 14 Pro review: early adopter island
Apple iPhone 14 review: meet the iPhone 13S
Apple Watch Series 8 review: if it ain’t broke
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we'd love to hear from you.
We are conducting a short audience survey to help plan for our future and hear from you. To participate, head to vox.com/podsurvey, and thank you!
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (10 ads detected)
Speaker 2:  Welcome to the Vergecast. The flagship podcast of measuring changes in
Speaker 2:  gravitational force. I'm your friend, David Pierce. And I am recording this
Speaker 2:  into the apple watch series eight that I bought myself on Sunday. That doesn't
Speaker 2:  sound like particularly exciting news, but it does mean I've started leaving
Speaker 2:  my phone at home, connecting my headphones to my watch, downloading a bunch
Speaker 2:  of podcasts and then going on screen free adventures everywhere.
Speaker 2:  It's great. I'm not gonna lie to you. And I actually think this mic sounds
Speaker 2:  pretty good. I'm sort of impressed. Anyway, today on the show, we have a
Speaker 2:  bunch of big things to talk about. We're gonna dig into the huge grand theft
Speaker 2:  auto six leak from over the weekend and what we know about both the
Speaker 2:  game and what happens to it now as a result of the leak, we're
Speaker 2:  also gonna see if there's anything to this whole idea, that TikTok is the
Speaker 2:  search engine of the future and is gonna replace Google for young people.
Speaker 2:  And we're gonna answer some of your Vergecast hotline questions about the
Speaker 2:  new iPhones and new apple watches, big show, all that is coming in just a
Speaker 2:  second. But first I actually have to charge this apple watch because it has
Speaker 2:  a lot of good things going for it, but the battery still kind of sucks. This
Speaker 2:  is the verge cast. See in a
Speaker 2:  sec,
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. So over the weekend, somebody who goes by the screen
Speaker 2:  named teapot, Uber hacker posted a three gigabyte file
Speaker 2:  with 90 videos to a grand theft auto forum that they
Speaker 2:  claimed show to footage from grand theft auto six, a game that has been
Speaker 2:  rumored and talked about for a while, but is reportedly at least two
Speaker 2:  years away from coming out. But it's grand theft auto. It's a huge deal.
Speaker 2:  It's one of the most popular games on the planet. So
Speaker 2:  with all of this stuff out there now, what do we know about the game
Speaker 2:  and what happens now? That so much has leaked. That's what the
Speaker 2:  verges Ash perish is here to tell us, hi Ash. Hi David,
Speaker 2:  how are you? I'm good. I'm torn about how I feel about this game. And it's
Speaker 2:  causing me to feel a lot of feelings, but we're gonna come. We're gonna come
Speaker 2:  back to those in a minute, but let's talk through this leak a little
Speaker 2:  bit, because like in the video game world, like we see leaks all the time.
Speaker 2:  Everybody has sort of there's different stuff coming out about different
Speaker 2:  games. Everything is always rumored and reported. It seems like a very small
Speaker 2:  industry that is full of people who like to talk, give me a sense of like
Speaker 2:  how big a deal, something like this GTA six leak
Speaker 2:  is in the scheme of things.
Speaker 4:  So leaks are never good. From a development
Speaker 4:  standpoint, gamers have a reputation of being
Speaker 4:  extremely hostile. They get very emotional
Speaker 4:  about the things that they love and it
Speaker 4:  manifests in this weird like hostility, because you realize that
Speaker 4:  these, these games that they love, the people that they're making it, they
Speaker 4:  make their lives like harder because they believe, at least some of them
Speaker 4:  believe they have some kind of like entitlement issue with these things that
Speaker 4:  they don't make or whatever, and have no idea how they're made. So
Speaker 4:  leaks, especially like the one with the GTA six leak where it's clearly
Speaker 4:  in development assets, it was like over 90 videos. It
Speaker 4:  was like debugging. Like the developers were going through and debugging,
Speaker 4:  mission scripts and things like that. So in the videos that you could see,
Speaker 4:  like a lot of textures haven't been added, there's a lot of like placeholder
Speaker 4:  assets, placeholder text, things like that. It's not the most
Speaker 4:  polished of looking things. So people
Speaker 4:  see this and they, they see that this is like still a work in progress,
Speaker 4:  but they don't really like conceptualize that this is still in progress.
Speaker 4:  So they believe like, oh, this game looks like ass. It's gonna be terrible.
Speaker 4:  And then, you know, people are, are talking about this on social media
Speaker 4:  and the stock price tanks, like, like the stock price for take two,
Speaker 4:  I believe like took a little dip by this because people are having all these
Speaker 4:  negative opinions about this game that is still like two or three years out
Speaker 4:  from being released because you know, children can't don't
Speaker 4:  realize that this is something that still is being worked on. It wasn't meant
Speaker 4:  to be seen like this. So it's a big deal. Developers
Speaker 4:  hate it. They get on social media and they say like, this makes
Speaker 4:  everybody's job harder. Like this is counterintuitive to what you
Speaker 4:  guys want. You know, the way that this leak was happened and the way
Speaker 4:  people respond to it, it's just, it's just this big negative thing.
Speaker 4:  And that's, that's what we're dealing with right now.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And I feel like I have a really hard time imagining any world in which
Speaker 2:  it goes the other way, where like elite comes out like this and everybody's
Speaker 2:  like, ah, looks awesome. Great job rockstar. Keep doing what you're doing.
Speaker 2:  It's just like, not how this world of gaming works. That like,
Speaker 2:  of course, as soon as something comes out, like this, people are gonna find
Speaker 2:  things to be mad about in part, because it's like in progress code and in
Speaker 2:  part, because that's just how people react to this stuff, right? Like, it's
Speaker 2:  like you were saying, I think with video games, it more than almost anything
Speaker 2:  else, people feel this sense of like ownership over everything
Speaker 2:  and anything that comes out that is this much different from
Speaker 2:  what they think they want or expect or whatever people
Speaker 2:  are gonna freak out. So there was, I can't imagine a world in which this
Speaker 2:  went better, even if it was some like totally different kind of game or footage
Speaker 2:  that leaked. Right.
Speaker 4:  Right. But it's really funny that you said that because
Speaker 4:  not too long after the GTA six leak Diablo four,
Speaker 4:  the game that blizzard is working on also leaked with like 43 minutes of
Speaker 4:  footage. And I feel like people had a much more positive reaction
Speaker 4:  to that than they did to DTA six. Yeah. I mean, it still like
Speaker 4:  had the same issues that GTA six did like it, there was still
Speaker 4:  like assets that hadn't been loaded in. But I think because of the way that
Speaker 4:  the leak was like perpetrated, like the GTA six leak, somebody
Speaker 4:  hacked into rockstar servers and stole like in
Speaker 4:  development footage, the Diablo four leak was because I guess
Speaker 4:  somebody was granted access to like a friends and family beta and
Speaker 4:  they streamed it to not on like Twitch or anything like that. But through
Speaker 4:  discord and somebody recorded that footage and then leaked that footage.
Speaker 4:  So it might be because like Diablo four looks like a little bit more further
Speaker 4:  along in the development cycle. I mean, it should be, the game is supposed
Speaker 4:  to come out sometime next year. Maybe that's why people are responding more
Speaker 4:  positively to it. So there are cases as slim as it is where people
Speaker 4:  can see like, oh, okay. Yeah, this looks cool.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Okay. I mean, that's, that's sort of encouraging actually. And it does
Speaker 2:  feel like the fact that this is happening to grant theft auto specifically
Speaker 2:  is sort of fascinating. Cause GTA is this like legendary
Speaker 2:  series, tons of people. Like it it's very popular, but it also,
Speaker 2:  the last time I had this very funny moment when this league happened of,
Speaker 2:  I haven't played GTA in a long time, but I had a pretty like when GTA five
Speaker 2:  first came out, which was good Lord, like a, almost a decade ago.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Nine years
Speaker 2:  I played a bunch of it and it was grand theft auto, but like, it was fun.
Speaker 2:  And I enjoyed it for the same reasons running around and punching strangers
Speaker 2:  in the face in a video game is fun. Like it's cool. And then I went back
Speaker 2:  and I was like, oh, I wonder what's, you know, really changed in the game
Speaker 2:  since I, I stopped playing it, if there's a bunch of, and it was like, Nope,
Speaker 2:  nothing has changed. It's just, they're still selling you grand theft auto
Speaker 2:  five. And this is just where we are. So is this like, are people
Speaker 2:  just so pent up waiting for this new game? That seems like it's been out
Speaker 2:  and debated and rumored for so long that everybody is like desperate
Speaker 2:  for this thing to come out. So they have very strong feelings about it.
Speaker 4:  I think so. Yeah. There has been a very long lag time between
Speaker 4:  GTA five and now GTA six, we've only just heard that GTA
Speaker 4:  six was in development maybe a couple years ago. And you know, GTA
Speaker 4:  five has become like rockstar Skyrim. Right. They re-release it
Speaker 4:  for every console. I believe you can play it on mobile
Speaker 4:  now. Like it, it came out when the Xbox 360 was still a thing. Right. That's
Speaker 4:  wild. So it's gone through two console generations in that meantime between
Speaker 4:  time and now because people are like anxious and desperate for
Speaker 4:  something more, they've probably built up this idea in their heads of what
Speaker 4:  they expect, you know, GT six to look like. And, you know, they have high
Speaker 4:  expectations on rockstar because generally speaking rockstar delivers
Speaker 4:  Fantastics like narrative and gameplay experiences. So
Speaker 4:  yeah, like these people like expect it to be something. And maybe
Speaker 4:  because it's not meeting that expectations because we're looking at stuff
Speaker 4:  that's been in development that is at least two years old that they're, they're
Speaker 4:  having a hard time coping. Right.
Speaker 2:  Are you a grand theft auto person?
Speaker 4:  Absolutely not, not my wheelhouse.
Speaker 4:  Sorry. Why not? It's just not the kind of game that appeals to me personally.
Speaker 4:  Like I that's fair, appreciate it like aesthetically and from a distance.
Speaker 4:  And I understand that a lot of people have a lot of emotions tied into it
Speaker 4:  and a lot of other rockstar games, because I know people love red, dead redemption
Speaker 4:  too, to death. And just not for me, just not for me,
Speaker 4:  which is fine.
Speaker 2:  So what did we learn about this actual game that's coming from this footage?
Speaker 2:  We, we kind of had heard reportedly that there was gonna be a, a female protagonist,
Speaker 2:  which seems to be confirmed. Now, did we learn any new stuff about what this
Speaker 2:  game is gonna be?
Speaker 4:  So Jason Schreyer at Bloomberg reported on this early in the
Speaker 4:  year that there would be a female protagonist. The, there there was, I think
Speaker 4:  there's supposed to be like two protagonists, like a male and a female. And
Speaker 4:  they're supposed to be based on Bonnie and Clyde. I think we got a little
Speaker 4:  bit of that. We also got the fact that this is gonna be set
Speaker 4:  somewhere in Miami. I believe Jason's reporting also spoke
Speaker 4:  something about it. Reviving the vice city setting
Speaker 4:  that happened with like GTA three. I believe it was. So it seems
Speaker 4:  like that's where the setting is, but I don't think beyond that
Speaker 4:  we have much more information other than, you know, it's, it's vice
Speaker 4:  city again or something vice city adjacent, and we're gonna be able to play
Speaker 4:  as a woman.
Speaker 2:  It was funny watching some of the leaked videos because on the one
Speaker 2:  hand, it like, it feels very grand theft auto. Like there's a, there's a
Speaker 2:  whole scene where they're driving down the street in a stolen cop car with
Speaker 2:  the, the driver door sort of swinging open into stuff. And then there's like
Speaker 2:  that whole weird punching style that they it's like. It feels very grand
Speaker 2:  theft auto. And I wonder if that's one of the things people are responding
Speaker 2:  to that it's like, if, if we, if it's been a decade and you're still giving
Speaker 2:  us a game that just feels like slightly newer, grand theft auto, like what
Speaker 2:  have we been waiting for all this time? But then again, this is all like
Speaker 2:  debug footage from at least two years ago. And it's just, it's very
Speaker 2:  hard to sort through kind of what we know and what we don't even
Speaker 2:  from a leak this big,
Speaker 4:  Well, I guess I would say personally, like if it ain't broke, don't fix it.
Speaker 4:  Right. There's a reason why we're, you know, doing NBA two K
Speaker 4:  2023, because it makes billions and billions of dollars,
Speaker 4:  right? GTA three and four and five
Speaker 4:  we're, you know, they were different stories, but they kind of like all did
Speaker 4:  the same thing. And with GTA five, being able to be sold across
Speaker 4:  two different console generations and still making gobs and gobs of money
Speaker 4:  as it does, same with GTA online, which is like the same thing. But
Speaker 4:  online where it's like a shared world or whatever, if it ain't broke, don't
Speaker 4:  fix it. Right? Like you can add some new adoration in it to it. But like
Speaker 4:  as long as it's fits that traditional GTA formula, people are gonna buy it.
Speaker 4:  They're gonna eat it up. So, I mean, I'm not saying that GTA six, isn't
Speaker 4:  innovative cuz you know, we don't know anything about it, but from, you know,
Speaker 4:  an academic standpoint. Yeah. It makes sense that this is like the
Speaker 4:  same-ish. I mean, I guess we'll
Speaker 2:  See. No, that that's totally fair. And part of me wonders like big picture
Speaker 2:  for a company like rockstar when something like this happens, what
Speaker 2:  goes on internally? The, the response they've given so far is basically like,
Speaker 2:  bummer. This happened, we're still moving ahead. Right? Like, do we have
Speaker 2:  any sense of what happens in a company like that after a leak like this?
Speaker 4:  So not really. I mean, it's terrible. Like
Speaker 4:  the developers feel awful. I feel like more than anything, it's a huge
Speaker 4:  hit to morale because now the poor community managers and whoever has the
Speaker 4:  keys to the social media have defend off like thousands of Twitter,
Speaker 4:  anime profile avatars, like tweeting abuse at them because their game,
Speaker 4:  which is unfinished and clearly in development, looks like crap to
Speaker 4:  them. But it seems like there's like, not much you can
Speaker 4:  do about this. Like from a, like a public standpoint,
Speaker 4:  you can't really do anything, but keep on keeping on. Right? So they put
Speaker 4:  out their statement saying this was the result of a hack. It sucks that you
Speaker 4:  learn about this game before we were ready to show you, but this hasn't
Speaker 4:  deterred our ability to get this game to you at all. Like, I don't
Speaker 4:  think they said anything about it being delayed or anything like that. But
Speaker 4:  the sense that I get is that this is far more like an internal morale thing,
Speaker 4:  more than anything else. But Jason Schreyer again at Bloomberg also brought
Speaker 4:  up the fact that this might have a problem or this might impact
Speaker 4:  Rockstar's ability to have their employees work from home because of
Speaker 4:  the way that this hack happened. Because the way that I understand it, the
Speaker 4:  guy who hacked Uber is claiming responsibility from this and the way that
Speaker 4:  he hacked Uber was through social engineering. And so while
Speaker 4:  he hasn't like said like, or rockstar, didn't say like this was social engineering
Speaker 4:  specifically, people are kind of like drawing the connections. If this guy
Speaker 4:  really did do Uber and rockstar, it stands to reason that he might have used
Speaker 4:  the same tactics of social engineering, like impersonating it or something
Speaker 4:  like that, to get somebody to give up their login so they can get into the
Speaker 4:  servers and take whatever they want. So it might impact employee's ability
Speaker 4:  to work from home because you know, rockstar wants to lock it down a little
Speaker 4:  bit better. And it's hard to do that when you've got employees far flung
Speaker 4:  across wherever. Totally
Speaker 2:  Well, and I think there's also this bigger picture that if I, if I really
Speaker 2:  like put on my galaxy brain hat, this is all happening at this really
Speaker 2:  interesting moment in the games industry, right. Where there's been this
Speaker 2:  reckoning over the last couple of years about like the internal cultures
Speaker 2:  of these companies and companies are starting to unionize and, and the whole
Speaker 2:  sort of concept of crunches coming to real scrutiny. So there's this, like,
Speaker 2:  this industry feels like it's changing and there's like this internal tension
Speaker 2:  of a lot of these companies. And I certainly don't have any evidence that,
Speaker 2:  that is like connected to the fact that it seems like these companies are
Speaker 2:  also getting leakier. But part of me wonders, like if I were to sort of play
Speaker 2:  the 10 dimensional chess here, if these things might be connected, but maybe
Speaker 2:  I'm trying too hard on that one.
Speaker 4:  That's interesting. I never really associated this like kind of,
Speaker 4:  I don't, I don't wanna say loosening with the idea that these companies might
Speaker 4:  be opening themselves up to more dramatic breaches like this.
Speaker 4:  I mean, I'll say that we didn't need to be in this like kind of work from
Speaker 4:  home culture to have leaks like this happen it's happened before when
Speaker 4:  everybody was in the office crunching, you know, 14 hour days and
Speaker 4:  it's happened now. So it's always gonna be a thing. So I don't think, think
Speaker 4:  you can say that, you know, these new work from home policies and this lack
Speaker 4:  of crunch policies mean that more of this will happen. I mean,
Speaker 4:  just the other day, like, you know, leaks are happening because this guy
Speaker 4:  was breaking NDAs left and right. And he was just doing it for the cloud.
Speaker 4:  So it's like, it doesn't, it doesn't really matter, honestly, where people
Speaker 4:  are, this is gonna happen if determined individuals want it to happen. But
Speaker 4:  yeah, people are shining way more of a light on how
Speaker 4:  these big ticket AAA games are being made. And at least
Speaker 4:  the people that I follow are saying like, take the time that you need, we
Speaker 4:  don't need this. Like right now we would prefer your employees. Get these
Speaker 4:  games done safely. Healthly if that means it takes a
Speaker 4:  little bit longer, that's fine because nobody wants to do this anymore. Like
Speaker 4:  nobody wants to crunch. Nobody wants to hear stories of like people losing
Speaker 4:  their families or whatever, because they had to work 17 hours a day. So
Speaker 4:  yeah. I mean, that's, I guess the thing that I'm seeing.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, no, it makes total sense. And it seems like at the same time, and this
Speaker 2:  is kind of what you're talking about. Like these industries are just so sprawling
Speaker 2:  now that it's like just the sheer number of people involved
Speaker 2:  with building a game, like GTA six across like
Speaker 2:  different companies and partners. And it's like, there are people who work
Speaker 2:  for like cloud services who know all the video games that are coming in the
Speaker 2:  next few years. Right. And that's never been a thing before. I wonder if
Speaker 2:  this is gonna continue as this industry and these companies get bigger,
Speaker 2:  it's gonna get harder and harder for them to keep stuff like this under
Speaker 2:  wraps over time. I mean, it's like, it's like consumer devices, right? It's
Speaker 2:  like, it's always the accessory makers that leak them. And now in the world
Speaker 2:  of video games that are on streaming services and are on, on a million different
Speaker 2:  partners and have to sort of trickle out into the world in all these complicated
Speaker 2:  ways. I wonder if we're gonna start to see more of this happen rather than
Speaker 2:  less over time.
Speaker 4:  I mean, we'll see, it happens a lot. You know, some
Speaker 4:  storefront in Brazil will accidentally leak like the release date of some
Speaker 4:  game because of, you know, whatever. So you know, it it's
Speaker 4:  it's anybody's guess, but I don't think it'll be anymore any less than what
Speaker 4:  we've seen in the past. Being honest.
Speaker 2:  Fair enough. Alright. Well, what game are you playing right now? If you're
Speaker 2:  not playing GTA?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, no, I'm not playing GTA right now. I am playing metal health singer,
Speaker 4:  which is a rhythm shooter. So it is it's
Speaker 4:  on Xbox game pass. It's also on steam. You play as like a
Speaker 4:  Demonn who lost her voice, who is fighting through like the realms
Speaker 4:  of hell to get her voice back. And the way that it works is that like there's
Speaker 4:  metal like heavy metal tracks in a playing in the background and you have
Speaker 4:  to shoot on the beat. And when you shoot on the beat, you get a higher score
Speaker 4:  multiplier and you do more damage. It's a lot of fun.
Speaker 2:  Oh, that sounds awesome. All right. Sold for who needs GTA six. I'm gonna
Speaker 2:  go play that instead. You
Speaker 4:  Should.
Speaker 2:  All right, Ash. Thank you. Appreciate it. Thank
Speaker 4:  You so much for having me.
Speaker 2:  Okay. We're gonna take a break and then we're gonna go deep down the TikTok
Speaker 2:  search engine rabbit hole. There's this idea out there that young people
Speaker 2:  are using TikTok instead of Google. And I'm suspicious
Speaker 2:  of that. We'll be right back.
Speaker 1:  Welcome
Speaker 2:  Back. I wanna talk now about something I heard a few weeks ago and had
Speaker 2:  been thinking about basically constantly ever
Speaker 2:  since. So in July, there was
Speaker 2:  the fortune brainstorm tech conference, which is one of those fancy
Speaker 2:  thinky tech conferences for fancy people. It's held in Aspen and
Speaker 2:  it's designed to be one of those places where people come to talk about big
Speaker 2:  ideas and the future and whatever. And in the middle of the conference,
Speaker 2:  provoca Raghavan who is in SVP at Google and is for all intent
Speaker 2:  purposes. The guy in charge of search at Google said this on
Speaker 2:  stage
Speaker 7:  Younger people don't come with preset expectations
Speaker 7:  in our studies, something like almost 40% of young
Speaker 7:  people. When they're looking for a place for lunch, they don't go to
Speaker 7:  Google maps or search. They go to TikTok or Instagram. So the journey
Speaker 7:  begins in different forms than before in visually rich forms.
Speaker 2:  Again, this is the guy in charge of Google search, one of the
Speaker 2:  most powerful and popular products on the internet, the source of billions
Speaker 2:  and billions of dollars in revenue for Google every year saying
Speaker 2:  essentially that the search engines of the future might be TikTok and Instagram,
Speaker 2:  not Google Provo's point
Speaker 2:  made a lot of headlines in part, because it also seems to confirm the way
Speaker 2:  that younger internet users use the internet. More videos, more
Speaker 2:  photos, less typing. What Google likes to call keyword, ease
Speaker 2:  into text boxes. I'm really not convinced that the world is
Speaker 2:  as provoca makes it sound here though. There's no doubt that search is changing
Speaker 2:  and becoming more multimedia. I mean, just look at the fact that YouTube
Speaker 2:  has long been the second most popular search engine on the planet, just behind
Speaker 2:  Google and even Google is using lens and voice to become
Speaker 2:  more multimedia
Speaker 8:  Soon. You'll be able to point lens at something and ask questions about what
Speaker 8:  you see,
Speaker 2:  But you know, who has a huge incentive to make it sound like Google
Speaker 2:  is not the only company that matters in search
Speaker 2:  Google.
Speaker 9:  Good morning. We welcome everyone to this. Morning's hearing on
Speaker 9:  transparency and accountability, examining Google and its
Speaker 9:  data collection use and filtering practices.
Speaker 2:  If it can convince the world that TikTok and Instagram are real
Speaker 2:  threats, it can maybe make regulators in particular,
Speaker 2:  just slightly less concerned about what it's doing on its search engine.
Speaker 2:  But it's definitely true that TikTok in particular is
Speaker 2:  investing in search. It's starting to offer search ideas on your, for you
Speaker 2:  page and you can actually even see in the content that people are
Speaker 2:  starting to do stuff that's more designed to be helpful and evergreen
Speaker 2:  rather than like dance challenges.
Speaker 10:  Here's the tutorial on how to tie your tie the easiest way. First you're
Speaker 10:  gonna place it in your hands like
Speaker 2:  This. So I decided to try this out and see if TikTok is actually
Speaker 2:  a good search engine. For a few days, I tried to search almost
Speaker 2:  everything on TikTok before I looked for it on Google. And I started
Speaker 2:  with the thing that provoca mentioned at the conference, looking for lunch.
Speaker 2:  I searched the phrase, restaurants in my neighborhood and got just nothing.
Speaker 2:  It turns out TikTok, doesn't know where I live and doesn't know what I'm
Speaker 2:  looking for. But then I searched for restaurants in Delray VA, which is where
Speaker 2:  I live. And I got some useful stuff, Matt and Tony's is a good spot. So
Speaker 11:  We do American comfort food breakfast all day.
Speaker 2:  So is Delray cafe hungry
Speaker 12:  In Virginia, check out Delray cafe when
Speaker 2:  Visiting, make sure you have the next result was one in Delray beach, which
Speaker 2:  is in California and literally thousands of miles from me. Then I
Speaker 2:  got pork barrel barbecue, which is near me and also pretty good.
Speaker 13:  Here's one of their most favorite platters. It's a barbecued
Speaker 13:  rib sausage and they've got
Speaker 2:  This whole thing kind of works right. Then it was another Matt and Tony's
Speaker 2:  recommendation. Then back to California, then more California.
Speaker 2:  And then Matt and Tony's again, we
Speaker 14:  Are at Matt and Tony's and yes, the snow did not stop us from trying
Speaker 2:  To, I don't know that the information density here is super high. It took
Speaker 2:  a really long time for me to basically get three names of restaurants, but
Speaker 2:  it does work. And while we're on the subject of food, TikTok is actually
Speaker 2:  an amazing tool for recipes. You type in like chocolate chip
Speaker 2:  cookies and you can spend the rest of your life. Watching people
Speaker 2:  make delicious looking chocolate chip cookies.
Speaker 15:  My holy grail, cookie chocolate chip cookie bars are the
Speaker 2:  Goat. A lot of those videos move really fast. So you have to watch them a
Speaker 2:  bunch of times and take notes, but there is a ton of good information here.
Speaker 2:  Just listen
Speaker 16:  To, despite
Speaker 2:  They're eating talkers who go through other Toks to find the best
Speaker 2:  chocolate chip cookie recipes from TikTok to show you on TikTok.
Speaker 15:  And I scoured the seemingly endless collection of chocolate chip cookie
Speaker 15:  recipes on TikTok to bring you
Speaker 2:  These it's bananas today,
Speaker 17:  We're making soft banana chocolate chip cookies. So grab your dusty ass,
Speaker 17:  ripe bananas coffee.
Speaker 2:  What doesn't work here at all is actually the number one
Speaker 2:  thing people use Google for opening webpage. The
Speaker 2:  main reason most people go to Google search is to get to
Speaker 2:  like Facebook and YouTube and Amazon. They type in those words into
Speaker 2:  the search box. TikTok just won't help you there. It's also not at all
Speaker 2:  useful for answering basic questions. Like what time is it, which is number
Speaker 2:  four on the list of most asked questions in Google. According to one study
Speaker 2:  I found and how manys in a cup, which is number five on that list.
Speaker 2:  But the number one question on Google, according to that same study is what
Speaker 2:  to watch. People just want to know what TV and movies to watch. And TikTok
Speaker 2:  is pretty interesting there. It was
Speaker 18:  Literally called Devilman cry baby, which is like the hardest title I've
Speaker 2:  Ever heard. The first video I got when I searched was bunch of recommendations
Speaker 2:  for stuff to watch on Netflix.
Speaker 18:  This is a show for the dudes and the guys.
Speaker 2:  Another was the new shows coming out on streaming, but that video
Speaker 2:  was several weeks old. So they weren't that new anymore. The
Speaker 19:  Resort will be coming out on peacock. It's a black comedy,
Speaker 2:  But it still was kind of helpful.
Speaker 19:  And it stars William Jackson,
Speaker 2:  Harper film. Another one was stuff to watch after you finished the summer,
Speaker 2:  I turned pretty, which I did watch and did very much enjoy.
Speaker 20:  My top recommendation has to be Dawson was
Speaker 2:  Creek. This is actually a really helpful set of results. Early
Speaker 20:  Two thousands, one of my
Speaker 2:  Top 10. Okay. Let's keep going. Music is all over the most popular
Speaker 2:  Google search results as is people looking for broad topics, Googling
Speaker 2:  things like Fortnite, well damaging Alma, build your ASMR. What's your favorite
Speaker 2:  color. And Billy Eish in that world, you're not looking for anything
Speaker 2:  in particular, just something in that genre and
Speaker 2:  TikTok is like an endless supply of all of that.
Speaker 21:  Here's one for all you Billy Eilish fans.
Speaker 2:  Also movie trailers are a good one. Mortal combat movie. 2021
Speaker 2:  was one of the most search things on Google. I am
Speaker 22:  Sub zero
Speaker 2:  And Godzilla versus Kong was also at the top of that list.
Speaker 2:  TikTok covers all of that really well though. You don't usually get
Speaker 2:  full songs or full trailers. And a lot of times you get remixes and jokes
Speaker 2:  before the actual content you might be looking
Speaker 2:  for.
Speaker 2:  You can imagine, by the way, why TikTok might be interested in making
Speaker 2:  a full music app to give people easier paths to this kind of
Speaker 2:  stuff. It seems to me that Google really
Speaker 2:  shouldn't be worried about TikTok as a search engine. You look at the stuff
Speaker 2:  people search and it's us PS tracking and weather tomorrow. And what
Speaker 2:  time is the super bowl? Google is obviously lots of things to lots of people,
Speaker 2:  but it's mostly a glorified question and answer service or
Speaker 2:  a way to find more information on the internet. TikTok is just not set up
Speaker 2:  to do that, but you know, who should be afraid of TikTok search is YouTube.
Speaker 23:  Okay. So a common problem I hear from people when making rice is that it
Speaker 23:  gets stuck to the bottom of the pot.
Speaker 2:  One thing that jumped out to me is hashtag TikTok taught me, which is a huge
Speaker 2:  success story. And it goes right at the kind of DIY, how
Speaker 2:  do I change a tire or kind of content that YouTube is so well known for
Speaker 2:  personally. One thing I keep searching for is back stretches because I have
Speaker 2:  back problems and I sit in front of computer all day and it's just overall
Speaker 2:  bad news. TikTok is perfect for this and the videos don't
Speaker 2:  come with those long preambles you get on YouTube. I don't need 14 minutes
Speaker 2:  of personal history before you show me the stretches. It's just 32nd video
Speaker 2:  of stretches after 32nd video of stretches and it rules,
Speaker 24:  I'm going to grip into the door frame with my hands slightly below chin
Speaker 24:  level. Let's take our chin towards our chest
Speaker 2:  As far as quick, helpful visual information. TikTok is
Speaker 2:  actually a much more efficient system than YouTube. I don't think the results
Speaker 2:  are always as good, but TikTok does make it easier to just flip through your
Speaker 2:  options to find one that works. It's less of a search engine and more of
Speaker 2:  like a choose your own rabbit hole adventure story, which
Speaker 2:  is a new, but kind of fun way to think about
Speaker 2:  search. I will say though,
Speaker 2:  if search really is a long term focus for TikTok, the platform is
Speaker 2:  definitely going to need to change a bit right now, for instance, creators
Speaker 2:  only get the one link in their bio. So there are tons of folks who are just
Speaker 2:  like, I posted my new recipe and make a video to show it off. But
Speaker 2:  then by the time you get to that video, that link is gone. Also,
Speaker 2:  TikTok is still all about the, for you page, which means people are using
Speaker 2:  sounds and doing challenges and generally doing everything they can
Speaker 2:  to show up, right? When you open the app longer in depth,
Speaker 2:  evergreen, helpful how to change a tire content.
Speaker 2:  Isn't really gonna work in that space. So TikTok is going to have to find
Speaker 2:  a way to incentivize people, to make more search friendly stuff.
Speaker 2:  If it really wants to take on YouTube that way, all of this is to
Speaker 2:  say, I don't think Google is under any actual threat here. I don't
Speaker 2:  think 40% of people are gonna keep using Instagram and TikTok, even
Speaker 2:  if that was ever the case, but it is not the only search engine worth using
Speaker 2:  anymore. For a lot of things, 10 blue links is still the right
Speaker 2:  answer, but for a lot of others, it turns out an endless stream of vertical
Speaker 2:  video might be even better. I don't know that I'll ever end
Speaker 2:  up actually making these chocolate chip cookies that I've been staring at
Speaker 2:  for hours and hours and hours, but it's really fun to watch other people
Speaker 2:  make them. And that might be just good
Speaker 2:  enough.
Speaker 1:  Welcome
Speaker 2:  Back now that we've posted our reviews and had a chance to test some of
Speaker 2:  Apple's new phones and watches. We asked you to send in your biggest, most
Speaker 2:  burning questions about the new stuff to our Vergecast hotline, which don't
Speaker 2:  forget is it's six, six verge one, one, and you can also always record a
Speaker 2:  voice memo and send it to vergecast@theverge.com. That works too. Thanks
Speaker 2:  to everybody who called in. We really love hearing from you and please keep
Speaker 2:  calling with all of your burning tech questions about apple or otherwise.
Speaker 2:  We got a lot of questions about apple, so I'm sorry. We're not gonna be able
Speaker 2:  to get to everyone's voicemails, but we are gonna try to answer some of the
Speaker 2:  most common ones and some of the most fun ones let's dig into the
Speaker 2:  phone a bit first, which means I should bring in Allison Johnson who reviewed
Speaker 2:  the iPhone 14 and Eli Patel who reviewed the 14 pro hi
Speaker 2:  Eli. Hey
Speaker 1:  Buddy. How you doing?
Speaker 2:  I'm good. Hi Allison. Hello, fresh off of iPhone
Speaker 2:  reviews. Everyone has recovered ish. I tried to buy an iPhone this weekend
Speaker 2:  and I failed. I'm devastated about
Speaker 26:  It. Oh no. Just from watching football on Sunday, every carrier
Speaker 26:  in America will just throw an iPhone at you. If you get anywhere near their
Speaker 26:  stores. From what I understand,
Speaker 27:  It's very difficult to pay for one.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I managed to get my dad an iPhone Promax, which
Speaker 2:  he's very excited about. And my mom, an iPhone pro, which she's very excited
Speaker 2:  about. And literally those were the last two that apple had available in
Speaker 2:  the store. And so they were just like, David, you get nothing. Okay. But
Speaker 2:  anyway, we have a bunch of hotline questions. Let's just dive into them.
Speaker 2:  So I think Andrew let's just play the first one.
Speaker 28:  Hey, David in vercast team. So I've been a long time user of Android for
Speaker 28:  the last five or six years. So originally was an iPhone user and with the
Speaker 28:  new iPhone 14 in the dynamic island had me considering
Speaker 28:  switching back to iPhone. I originally switched because it was customizable,
Speaker 28:  but I wonder now is iPhone more customizable than Android? Can
Speaker 28:  you crash that itch if you need it really curious about your thoughts. Thanks.
Speaker 2:  I have thoughts on this, but ne you made a face while we were listening to
Speaker 2:  that question. Why did you make a face?
Speaker 26:  Because the answer is flatly. No, the iPhone is not more customizable for
Speaker 26:  Android. It is more customizable than iPhones
Speaker 26:  in the past, and it's getting closer to Android,
Speaker 26:  but your average Android phone, I mean, you can just replace the app
Speaker 26:  launcher. I mean, you do anything. You want an Android phone, so it, it
Speaker 26:  just depends on what itch you are trying to scratch, I
Speaker 26:  guess. But if you're like an all out customizer, I think Android's still
Speaker 26:  where it's at.
Speaker 2:  Allison. Is that your take two?
Speaker 27:  Yeah. And it's, it's gotten better. It's gotten, there's a lot more you
Speaker 27:  can do now than in the past apples slowly, adding
Speaker 27:  more things we can do. Like, you know, the lock screens are fine, but
Speaker 27:  you're still definitely playing within the realm of what apple thinks
Speaker 27:  looks good. They do not want you to walk around with an
Speaker 27:  ugly iPhone lock screen, cuz that would embarrass them
Speaker 27:  Android. You can make it as ugly as you want, if you wanna do that.
Speaker 27:  So yeah. Yeah. I agree with that. It's more fun. You can have more fun
Speaker 27:  with it. Now.
Speaker 26:  I would say also the dynamic island is not customizable at all. It
Speaker 26:  is the appearance of customizability, but apple is
Speaker 26:  deciding what happens in that island.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I was actually gonna ask about this because we talked about this a
Speaker 2:  few days ago and we're still in this sort of like, who knows what's gonna
Speaker 2:  happen here. And now it's like been a few days. I opened up my phone. I had
Speaker 2:  25 app updates this morning. So it's like, everybody's sort of on the iOS
Speaker 2:  16 train have either of you seen anything that is like dynamic
Speaker 2:  island sparking something cool here. Yeah. Okay.
Speaker 26:  No. Cause the big update is the live activities API, which isn't out yet.
Speaker 26:  So I don't think third party apps will be able to use the island until that
Speaker 26:  API is out.
Speaker 27:  I did the exact sequence of things to get two things in the
Speaker 27:  dynamic island at once. Just like naturally I was
Speaker 27:  listening to a podcast and I set a 15 minute
Speaker 27:  timer to take a COVID test and it was magical for a
Speaker 27:  second. Yeah. But that's as exciting as it gets right now.
Speaker 2:  It's all of our dreams coming true at once. Okay. So this, this feels good.
Speaker 2:  It's, it's more customizable than it once was. But if you switch to Android
Speaker 2:  because it's customizable, stay on Android. I feel like you can make it as
Speaker 2:  ugly as you want was like five years of Samsung ads and it's still, it's
Speaker 2:  still true. But
Speaker 26:  If you switch to Android, cuz you wanted a customize at lock screen and
Speaker 26:  put widgets on the home screen, you know apple, Apple's got you now
Speaker 2:  That's true. Like
Speaker 26:  If you wanna change the default messaging app on the iPhone, Android
Speaker 26:  will let you do that. If you wanna add a third party app store to an
Speaker 26:  Android phone, you can do it and apple will not let you do that.
Speaker 2:  Right. All right. Let's move on to the next one. Andrew, what do we have
Speaker 2:  next?
Speaker 29:  Hey guys, this is DS. And one question about the
Speaker 29:  iPhone 14. I have been a longtime Android
Speaker 29:  user and I think my friends might actually get to me this year and I may
Speaker 29:  or may not switch to an iPhone, but I don't want to be that guy
Speaker 29:  that gets the iPhone the one year before it goes to type C. Do you think
Speaker 29:  this year is the time to make that call and switch? I really appreciate
Speaker 29:  the input. Thank you.
Speaker 2:  So I just wanna say on one hand, this was a trend of the voicemails that
Speaker 2:  we got from people. This idea that I have been an Android user for a long
Speaker 2:  time. And now I'm tempted back by the iPhone 14, which I
Speaker 2:  find fascinating because I think our takeaway is like, this phone is cool,
Speaker 2:  but it's not gonna like blow your mind out of your head. But there are a
Speaker 2:  lot of people who are like, I have been an Android fan for a
Speaker 2:  long time and maybe now it's time to get back into Android.
Speaker 2:  But USBC is this. The last year is our friend D
Speaker 2:  stupid to buy an iPhone this year. Cause they're gonna switch next year.
Speaker 26:  Well, it depends on where you live because every carrier
Speaker 26:  now it will just give money to you to switch
Speaker 26:  every year.
Speaker 2:  That is true.
Speaker 26:  If you live in the United States, it feels like you can scheme
Speaker 26:  your way into getting a new phone every year for no money. Right. And you're
Speaker 26:  kind of just gonna end up signing a new tier, your contract over and over
Speaker 26:  again. But I like I've come to peace with this idea because when am I gonna
Speaker 26:  not have carrier service?
Speaker 2:  Right.
Speaker 26:  That said it does feel like the USBC change is coming to the phone. I
Speaker 26:  don't know if it's next to your, the year after.
Speaker 27:  I think he'd be okay for a while. I don't know. There's still like, there
Speaker 27:  will still be tons of support for lightning many years. They
Speaker 27:  come many, many hotels will have some weird lightning
Speaker 27:  connector, you know, doc to play your
Speaker 27:  phones.
Speaker 26:  But it's the other way around, right? If he was an Android person, he's
Speaker 26:  probably got a bunch of USBC cables.
Speaker 27:  Oh that's true.
Speaker 26:  Buying a bunch of lightning cables for one year seems done. I would
Speaker 26:  wait if that's like, if that's what you're describing, like I'm fully invested
Speaker 26:  in USBC. I'm kind of tempted by this phone, but I'll feel dumb if I
Speaker 26:  buy, you know, a life's worth of cables and then what the next year they
Speaker 26:  go. Yeah, you should wait.
Speaker 2:  The answer is Don. I can't believe we didn't get her yet. The answer is by
Speaker 2:  a bunch of lightning to USBC converters and your life
Speaker 2:  will just be terrific. No, I think that's right. I would wait. But I also,
Speaker 2:  I think you're right NEI that the like, can I buy this year's phone? And
Speaker 2:  also next year's phone is not as hard a question as people
Speaker 2:  think actually, especially in the us where people will just fall all over
Speaker 2:  themselves to give you giant amounts of trade in money
Speaker 2:  for whatever phone you bring them.
Speaker 26:  Yeah. The carrier marketing for the new iPhone is out of control.
Speaker 26:  Like it's wild. Verizon is running ads with celebrities in them being like
Speaker 26:  buy a new iPhone 14. And it's like, everyone knows about the iPhone
Speaker 26:  14. Do you need to hire celebrities to do this? All
Speaker 2:  Right, let's move on. So next one is from John in New York. Andrew, what
Speaker 2:  do we have?
Speaker 29:  Hey verge. This is John from New York. Really love. The show would love
Speaker 29:  to know more about the decision behind the digital SIM seems like the
Speaker 29:  us was the only place that really adopted this. And I wonder what it means
Speaker 29:  for cell phones and global travel. If this is going to be the
Speaker 29:  future of mobile usage, it was actually really challenging
Speaker 29:  for me to get my digital Sims started on my iPhone, 14 pro. Really curious
Speaker 29:  to see what you guys would think about it.
Speaker 2:  I like this one because this is also a thing that was kind of floating around
Speaker 2:  the internet all weekend was that people were having trouble activating.
Speaker 2:  I saw a bunch of people who were saying like Verizon was having a hard time
Speaker 2:  with the EIMS in it. It's just a, a lot of questions of like, is this a good
Speaker 2:  idea? Or are we just solving a problem that doesn't exist by like throwing
Speaker 2:  more technology at the problem, Allison, what's your sense of
Speaker 2:  this? Is there. Where are we in the EIM world right now?
Speaker 27:  It's weird because I feel like half the people I follow are really into
Speaker 27:  it and think it's pro consumer in the other half are like, I hate
Speaker 27:  ease them with a fiery passion. I had no
Speaker 27:  trouble with it. I don't do a lot of international travel. So it's
Speaker 27:  not really my use case, but I feel like the people who I know who
Speaker 27:  do travel are the ones who are more amped up about ease IM
Speaker 27:  and that it'll make it easier to kind of swap when you get to
Speaker 27:  another country. I don't, I can't speak to it too. Well, I set this phone
Speaker 27:  up in the back of an Uber on the highway and it worked
Speaker 27:  fine.
Speaker 2:  It's a bold strategy. Yeah,
Speaker 27:  It was, it was real exciting. Yeah.
Speaker 26:  I feel like you can, you can describe sort of abstractly the pro-consumer
Speaker 26:  argument, which is, it should be really easy to sign up a phone for a
Speaker 26:  network service and thus compare plans and pricing
Speaker 26:  faster and switch faster. And all of that. If you make all that switching
Speaker 26:  faster and easier, the carriers will have to compete more. Cuz you might
Speaker 26:  switch away from them.
Speaker 2:  It's like switching webpages at that point, essentially rather than switching
Speaker 2:  devices. That's, that's the idea, right? You don't have to go into a store.
Speaker 2:  You just say that one's cheaper. You press a button and you have it. That's
Speaker 2:  how that's supposed
Speaker 26:  To work. But then that kind of runs into reality. Like
Speaker 26:  at least here in the United States, it runs into like pretty brutal reality,
Speaker 26:  pretty fast, which is the reason they could do in the United States is cuz
Speaker 26:  there's only three carriers. So they could get the three main carriers on
Speaker 26:  board. And then every other carrier minus a few regional carriers like cellular
Speaker 26:  or whatever. But every other carrier is basically an MV and O like they're
Speaker 26:  basically just like reselling and most cases T-Mobile service or
Speaker 26:  Verizon service. And so you, you hear like people on like
Speaker 26:  visible had like real problems, but that's, it's still, it's still like
Speaker 26:  a different cut at like Verizon's network. I think. So they're able to do
Speaker 26:  it here cause they only had to make three deals around the world. They can't
Speaker 26:  just, they haven't made all the deals yet. So they still need a physical
Speaker 26:  SIM tray. The other thing that's really weird is that when you go to add
Speaker 26:  an EIM, it doesn't just show you the available networks and let you sign
Speaker 26:  up for them. You need to like scan a Q you need to go get an EIM kit
Speaker 26:  and scan a QR code or at least go to a website and scan a QR code, which
Speaker 26:  is really weird. Cuz the iPad works as you would expect. If you have an
Speaker 26:  iPad and you go to add a cell plan to an iPad, it'll pop up a
Speaker 26:  screen of available data plans. And just like you sign up for one on the
Speaker 26:  iPad. So it's like they're halfway there. But then the brutal
Speaker 26:  reality, the uncompetitive American market is right in front of
Speaker 26:  you. And then the, they haven't like built the rest of the functionality
Speaker 26:  that would make that pro-consumer vibe like work. And then
Speaker 26:  as we just said, like you're locked into a two year contract in the United
Speaker 26:  States anyway. So like you're not switching as much. I dunno. Like it's
Speaker 26:  the beginnings of something. I think most people do not interact with their
Speaker 26:  SIM cards at all. But if you could travel internationally and just like
Speaker 26:  open your phone and be like, I've landed in Europe and like hit the button
Speaker 26:  and see all the networks and sign up for the cheapest one for, you know,
Speaker 26:  a month, that would be amazing. They just haven't built any of that yet.
Speaker 2:  I mean, it goes back to the like theoretically pro-consumer argument, right?
Speaker 2:  Where you can like, you can see why somebody thought this was a very good
Speaker 2:  idea. And at the end of this, it's like, okay, this is the intended behavior.
Speaker 2:  But like you were saying, like, this is a lot of work for three carriers
Speaker 2:  in the us with apple who has more leverage in this space than any other
Speaker 2:  company to pull this off, forget going to Europe where there's a million
Speaker 2:  carriers in a million countries with vastly different ideas
Speaker 2:  about how all of this is supposed to work. It just feels like the idea that
Speaker 2:  any company including apple is gonna be able to sort of exert its authority.
Speaker 2:  That way is just like basically non-existent. So then what you have is you
Speaker 2:  have the European phone and you have the American phone and those two things
Speaker 2:  are like borderline interoperable. So if I'm a person who
Speaker 2:  lives in the us, but travels a ton internationally is the move to buy the
Speaker 2:  Europe phone, like is that fly to London, buy a phone there and don't tell
Speaker 2:  anybody, you still have a physical Sam when you're in the us. You'll
Speaker 27:  Miss out on millimeter wave big bummer.
Speaker 2:  I feel like I can live with that. Like I'm, I'm good of all the trade offs
Speaker 2:  here. I, I can live without millimeter wave.
Speaker 26:  Well, I think it is just the it's sort of the behavior that matters, right?
Speaker 26:  It sounds like a lot of people fly to Europe and then just buy a burner
Speaker 26:  SIM for a weekend and throw it away and come back. Like that seems to be
Speaker 26:  what people are describing to us. Like I just show up and I buy a SIM card
Speaker 26:  at the airport and I throw it in my phone and I use it until it's done.
Speaker 26:  And then I fly home and the next time I show up and do it again. So there's
Speaker 26:  an answer that is you show up at the airport and instead of buying a physical
Speaker 26:  SIM card, you buy a QR code and you use that till it's done and you walk
Speaker 26:  away. But I think that just has to all get teased out into practice.
Speaker 2:  All right. We have one more before I let you two go and we're then we're
Speaker 2:  gonna talk about the watch. This is not about the phone, but it's about cameras
Speaker 2:  and you two are by T camera nerd. So let's hear the next
Speaker 2:  one.
Speaker 30:  My name is Z. I run the JZ tech YouTube channel and I
Speaker 30:  was wondering what has the apple made a camera? Cause it seems like
Speaker 30:  that would be a really obvious place to put their money into. Like
Speaker 30:  I know like pretty much everyone has a Sony eight sevens S three these days.
Speaker 30:  So like why isn't there an apple camera? And thanks
Speaker 30:  for answering my question.
Speaker 2:  I love this question so much because a, I desperately wanna live in a world
Speaker 2:  where everyone has an a seven S like, this is just, this is, these are our
Speaker 2:  people. I love it. The answer is apple does make a camera and it's called
Speaker 2:  the iPhone, right? Like that's, that's just what this is.
Speaker 27:  It is the, is the most popular camera in the country for
Speaker 27:  sure.
Speaker 26:  In the world.
Speaker 27:  Probably. Yeah.
Speaker 26:  The question here is why hasn't apple made a mirrorless camera for
Speaker 26:  creators because apple makes a camera, several models of camera. If you
Speaker 26:  think about the iPhone that way, but why haven't they made an awesome camera
Speaker 26:  for creators? Right. And I think like many things with apple,
Speaker 26:  they have probably looked at that market and said, that's not even a
Speaker 26:  10th of the size of AirPods in terms of money. That will, it will make us
Speaker 26:  so no, and those cameras exist. And you know, there's a
Speaker 26:  long history with them and to enter a market like that, you
Speaker 26:  have to commit to creators. And I'm just leading up to saying,
Speaker 26:  have you used final cut pro because Apple's history in that market
Speaker 26:  is actually not one of great success. So I
Speaker 26:  get why you'd want them to do it. On the other hand, I don't
Speaker 26:  know that you want apple making the kinds of aesthetic decisions in
Speaker 26:  that kind of camera that it does in the iPhone. And sure you can shoot in
Speaker 26:  pro. Now you can shoot in ProRes and back off the aesthetic decisions,
Speaker 26:  but it's apple, right? Like they're gonna be on by default. The apple look
Speaker 26:  will be on by default and I'm, I'm not sure that's that
Speaker 26:  philosophy is compatible with that user base.
Speaker 27:  If my a seven C put out JPEGs where everybody was
Speaker 27:  orange, like previous iPhones have, I would be so
Speaker 27:  pissed.
Speaker 26:  Yeah. Like the worst built in light preset of all time. Yeah.
Speaker 26:  Yeah. There's just, there's weirdness there, but I, I get like why does
Speaker 26:  an apple make, just make a great camera is a question that's been asked
Speaker 26:  for years and years and years now. And kind of the answer is it's the market
Speaker 26:  is just not big enough.
Speaker 2:  I think that's right. Yeah. I mean, in, in the last year or so, a lot of
Speaker 2:  people have been talking about wanting apple to make a webcam again, because
Speaker 2:  suddenly the webcam market was hot for, you know, nine months. I do think
Speaker 2:  going super heavy on the camera would be a really fun future for the iPod
Speaker 2:  touch that they're just like, this is our cheaper camera. It doesn't have
Speaker 2:  all the other cool stuff, but we put the best camera in it.
Speaker 26:  Do they even still make the iPod touch?
Speaker 2:  No, I don't think so. If I'm being completely honest with you, I forgot.
Speaker 2:  Which is sort of the point, right? This is
Speaker 27:  Bring
Speaker 2:  It back. The, the iPod camera, just to confuse everybody
Speaker 27:  Pro max,
Speaker 2:  It's an 11 inch. It's just a television with a camera on the back.
Speaker 27:  Yes.
Speaker 2:  Thank you both. We're gonna talk about the, watch it and bring on V, which
Speaker 2:  means you both have to go, but thank you both. Appreciate it. Thanks.
Speaker 27:  Thank you
Speaker 2:  V. Hello? Hello. Thank you for being here. No problem.
Speaker 2:  All right. We have a bunch of watch questions. People have a lot of feelings
Speaker 2:  about watches so we're just gonna go through a couple of them. Andrew, you
Speaker 2:  wanna play the first one for us?
Speaker 31:  Hi, Vergecast Derek here from New Zealand. So I
Speaker 31:  charge my apple watch in my car, on my commute
Speaker 31:  so that it's charged all day. And then it's charged at night for sleep tracking.
Speaker 31:  But if I have to wear my apple watch for the crash
Speaker 31:  detection to work, I mean,
Speaker 31:  what,
Speaker 2:  We're gonna actually answer this question, but I just have two things I have
Speaker 2:  to say before we do one, the official pronunciation of Vergecast is now in
Speaker 2:  a New Zealand accent. So I'd just like everybody to know that. And two, how
Speaker 2:  did I never think about charging my apple watch in the car? It that's a genius
Speaker 2:  plan. It's like the one time it's totally superfluous to my life and
Speaker 2:  I can just charge it. This feels like a good idea, right?
Speaker 32:  Yeah, no, it's an excellent idea. I just think, you know, I
Speaker 32:  don't actually commute by car much, so I've just
Speaker 32:  never thought about it cuz you know, I'm in New York city. So when am I
Speaker 32:  gonna like, I don't, I'm not really commuting by car much, but for long
Speaker 32:  trips now I'm just like, oh, because it's totally intuitive to
Speaker 32:  charge your phone in the car, but I've just never thought about charging
Speaker 32:  my watch in the car.
Speaker 2:  I know I love this. I'm all in. Okay. But let's, let's talk about the, the
Speaker 2:  crash detection thing here, which is like, I sort of wanted to do this question
Speaker 2:  just because it's representative of a lot of questions we've gotten about
Speaker 2:  like how does crash detection actually work? What is it trying to do? How
Speaker 2:  does it know I'm wearing the watch? How does it know I've been in a crash
Speaker 2:  and I'm assuming the answer to, if you're in the car and you're not wearing
Speaker 2:  the watch and you get in a crash, it probably won't register. I don't know.
Speaker 2:  But what, what do you, what can you tell us about how all of this actually
Speaker 2:  works?
Speaker 32:  So I actually asked apple about this earlier today
Speaker 32:  because I also was like, oh, I don't know. I don't know the answer
Speaker 32:  to this, but they basically told me that it was,
Speaker 32:  you know, intended to be worn on the wrist. That doesn't mean it
Speaker 32:  won't necessarily work. It just means like
Speaker 32:  they've done a bunch of testing with like dummies where you're
Speaker 32:  putting, you know, the apple watch in various parts of
Speaker 32:  their body and whatnot. So they've done a lot, a lot of testing on this,
Speaker 32:  but it's all on human bodies cuz I think the assumption is if you have
Speaker 32:  the watch on the car, you're probably wearing it. Obviously the rest of
Speaker 32:  us have not gotten on Derek's level and realizing that commuting
Speaker 32:  with the watch. It's like the perfect it's legitimately the perfect time
Speaker 32:  to charge the watch. If you're commuting by car, he gets it. He's
Speaker 32:  on a level that we're not on. So crash detection works because it
Speaker 32:  has a new accelerometer that can detect up to
Speaker 32:  256 GS. The previous watches could only detect up
Speaker 32:  to 32. So that's like orders of magnitudes different. And
Speaker 32:  it also has an improved gyroscope and all of these things are working with
Speaker 32:  the barometer GPS. And I think the
Speaker 32:  microphone to detect whether you've been in a, in a severe car crash, but
Speaker 32:  it's, it's a really fascinating feature because it does seem like
Speaker 32:  Apple's thought really hard about it in terms of how the
Speaker 32:  watch interacts with your phone. So like if
Speaker 32:  you crash the car and you know, you have your phone and your watch
Speaker 32:  on you, it'll route the call through your phone cuz it's got the better
Speaker 32:  antenna, but it's gonna gonna appear on your watch because
Speaker 32:  that's more likely to be on you and you don't know where the phone is
Speaker 32:  during your, you know, like in the aftermath of crash, you have no idea
Speaker 32:  where that might have gone. So it's, they've thought a lot about
Speaker 32:  it. It's just, I don't think we really know how it's gonna
Speaker 32:  work until unfortunately people get themselves in
Speaker 32:  that situation. Like I've been in really bad lift rides where
Speaker 32:  it was so stop and go. I felt like I was gonna hurt. Yeah. But that
Speaker 32:  doesn't actually trigger it. And New York drivers or New York drivers and
Speaker 32:  I went hiking this weekend. So there were a couple of close calls, but no
Speaker 32:  actual like trigger. Right?
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I would. The part of it that gives me hope like instinctively,
Speaker 2:  it seems like it would make sense that if it wasn't on your body, it wouldn't
Speaker 2:  be looking for that stuff just because it's like, why would it be sort of
Speaker 2:  operating if it, if you weren't wearing it. But then I think about the fact
Speaker 2:  that the iPhone 14 now has crash detection and it's clearly
Speaker 2:  not meant to be worn on your body. So it is like you're saying able to do
Speaker 2:  some of this sensing even when it's not on
Speaker 2:  your body and the apple watch might be treating it differently, but it at
Speaker 2:  least seems like technically it's possible for this stuff to work. Even
Speaker 2:  when the device is not physically like being on your body,
Speaker 2:  watching you like thrash around in the back seat.
Speaker 32:  Yeah. So it's designed to detect like extreme impact and
Speaker 32:  changes in speed. So you have to really hit a certain
Speaker 32:  threshold for that to, to really kind of trigger it's in
Speaker 32:  quote unquote testing, cuz I can't really test it in an
Speaker 32:  ethical way that doesn't risk my life. At least we haven't
Speaker 32:  figured that out just yet. You know, in testing this it's very,
Speaker 32:  it reminded me a lot of testing fall detection. So like back when fall
Speaker 32:  detection was a thing myself and a bunch of other reviewers would just,
Speaker 32:  you know, leap off a bed into a bunch of pillows to
Speaker 32:  see if we could trigger it. And I have yet to trigger it in real life. I've
Speaker 32:  eaten it while running as well, but I wasn't injured enough to
Speaker 32:  be lying their prone, which is part of like the fall detection works.
Speaker 32:  So I think you're not really gonna get false
Speaker 32:  positives, which is, you know, which is a big thing. Some, some other
Speaker 32:  similar safety features like garments fall detection. You
Speaker 32:  could just have a really hard stop and your loved ones are gonna be told
Speaker 32:  you've had an incident. So I have hope because it sounds like
Speaker 32:  it's very sensitive and I haven't triggered it yet with my terrible driving.
Speaker 32:  So there you
Speaker 2:  Go. It's for the best. Yeah. If you, if you have been in a car crash and
Speaker 2:  you have gotten crash detection, call the hotline and tell us about it because
Speaker 2:  I, I am very curious, do not crash your car on purpose to do this,
Speaker 2:  but if it has happened to you, we we'd love to hear about it. All right.
Speaker 2:  Let's move on to the next question we have Andrew, you wanna play it for
Speaker 2:  us?
Speaker 33:  Hey guys. Just wondering if it's really worth
Speaker 33:  getting here is a for the se basically
Speaker 33:  for the always on display. Cause I don't know if I really need
Speaker 33:  the other sensors. Thanks.
Speaker 32:  Okay. So don't get the se that doesn't have an always on display. So
Speaker 32:  that's one of the things, things about the se you're missing some of the
Speaker 32:  advanced sensors and the always on display. That's why it could be cheaper
Speaker 32:  than the other watches. But I used to just very, gung-ho say
Speaker 32:  that everyone should just be getting the apple watch se because
Speaker 32:  you know, I wasn't 100% sold on the need for an always
Speaker 32:  on display, but after a few years, I really do like
Speaker 32:  it. I, I think it's an excellent feature. It makes it more
Speaker 32:  like an actual watch in that you can always see the time. And the other
Speaker 32:  thing about it is it's just so much easier
Speaker 32:  when you're in a workout because like when I'm running and I wanna
Speaker 32:  check a certain metric or like this weekend when I was on a hike and I wanna
Speaker 32:  see the compass, you can, you can look down and glance at certain
Speaker 32:  things. It's not going to be, it's refreshing at a much slower rate. So
Speaker 32:  you're not gonna see some detail, but you don't necessarily have to bring
Speaker 32:  your wrist up and flick it in just the right way to see the things that
Speaker 32:  you need. It wakes up like a half second faster and it
Speaker 32:  it's like not necessary, but it's super nice. It's like
Speaker 32:  now I'm a team always on display.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I always have been. And I honestly think even since the
Speaker 2:  first one, like it it's, it's not a watch. If it doesn't show you the time
Speaker 2:  like that, it just, that's just the rules and apple still has not
Speaker 2:  solved that arm gesture. You're talking about like, if I just sort
Speaker 2:  of like flick my wrist over the screen, doesn't turn on. You still have to
Speaker 2:  do this. Like very exaggerated, like bring your arm up to your face.
Speaker 2:  And if you have to do that every time you wanna look at your watch, that
Speaker 2:  is bad to me. It's like always on screen or
Speaker 2:  don't get an apple watch. Like I genuinely believe that.
Speaker 32:  Yeah. Well, you know, when you've been in the wearables game, as
Speaker 32:  long as I have you, you kind of master the
Speaker 32:  flick. Like I, I get the flick every single time. It
Speaker 32:  almost never not, you know, wakes up in what I needed to, but
Speaker 32:  this is just like five, six years of having to do this. The muscle memory
Speaker 32:  is, is there. So if he's upgrading from the series
Speaker 32:  four or earlier, you know, and you don't need the other
Speaker 32:  sensors, I think it's totally fine to just go for the se because
Speaker 32:  you've never had the always on display. You don't know what you're missing.
Speaker 32:  I went from the apple watch series five to the se when I
Speaker 32:  was testing and I knew what I was missing that made me so happy to
Speaker 32:  go back to the watches with the always on display after. So if you
Speaker 32:  don't know what you're missing and it really is something where you're prioritizing
Speaker 32:  budget, you know, you can't miss what you don't know. So that's one thing
Speaker 2:  That's fair. But then back to the question, what they're saying is like,
Speaker 2:  if the always on display isn't enough, is it worth upgrading? And in that
Speaker 2:  case, I feel like the answer's probably not right. Like there's nothing.
Speaker 2:  So sort of dramatically spectacularly better
Speaker 2:  in these that if you're happy with the one that you have, you should upgrade,
Speaker 2:  right.
Speaker 32:  Definitely for the series four or later, I think if you
Speaker 32:  have a series three it's time, it's time to put this watch to rest. It's
Speaker 32:  five years old, which, you know, in terms of gadgets, that's ancient,
Speaker 32:  but there are some things where I actually do think the
Speaker 32:  software is worth upgrading for. It just depends on your individual use
Speaker 32:  case. So the new redesigned compass app is
Speaker 32:  bomb. I love it. It is so good. It is finally
Speaker 32:  really useful for hikers or like trail runners in a way that
Speaker 32:  like, it was just a compass before. And you're like, cool. I have no idea
Speaker 32:  what a bearing means. Like this doesn't help me. I'm terrible with
Speaker 32:  directions. I like, it's just really sad, but this was a major
Speaker 32:  upgrade. The thing is, is that the redesign compass app isn't coming to
Speaker 32:  the series four, you'll get it on the series five, but it's not gonna have
Speaker 32:  the really nifty stuff, like backtrack or way points. So if you
Speaker 32:  do want that stuff and you think it'll be useful for your life,
Speaker 32:  you're gonna need to get at least a series six, the first gen
Speaker 32:  se or later. So, you know, that's one thing where if you're
Speaker 32:  an outdoors person and you really like that stuff, it's definitely one thing
Speaker 32:  where I think actually, yeah, that is worth upgrading for
Speaker 32:  you. If you stay inside all the time. Nah,
Speaker 32:  you're good. Don't, don't worry about it.
Speaker 2:  Fair enough. That is good advice right there. All right. Thank you to everybody
Speaker 2:  who called in. We got tons of questions. I'm sorry. We can get to them all
Speaker 2:  V. Thank you. Appreciate it. Super helpful.
Speaker 32:  No problem.
Speaker 2:  Okay. And that's it for the Vergecast this week. Thank you so much for listening
Speaker 2:  as always. There is tons more coverage on everything we talked about at our
Speaker 2:  newly redesigned website, verge.com. There's also a bunch more apple stuff
Speaker 2:  coming in the next few days. So keep it locked over there. You can also follow
Speaker 2:  all of us on Twitter. Ash is ad Astra. Allison
Speaker 2:  is Allison Joe one. Eli is reckless V is V M
Speaker 2:  song and I'm Pierce. This show is produced by Andrew Marino and Liam James
Speaker 2:  Norie Donovan is our executive producer and Brooke mins is our editorial
Speaker 2:  director of audio. The Vergecast is a verge production and part of the V
Speaker 2:  media podcast network. If you have thoughts, feedback, feelings,
Speaker 2:  buried treasure, or want to help us crash in cars and test GForce, you can
Speaker 2:  always email vergecast@theverge.com. Also, we're getting an episode ready
Speaker 2:  all about cybersecurity, and we're gonna do a full on call in
Speaker 2:  show answering your questions. So if you have a cybersecurity thing, you
Speaker 2:  can't figure out or better yet you have a crazy mystery. You
Speaker 2:  can't solve call us at eight, six, six verge one, one, or send us
Speaker 2:  a voice memo to vergecast@verge.com. And we'll get back to you. If we think
Speaker 2:  we can help Alex Neil and I will be back on Friday to talk about more apple
Speaker 2:  stuff, pelotons new rowing machine dislike buttons on YouTube, and much more.
Speaker 2:  See you then rock and
Speaker 2:  roll.