# Transcript
ID: 5e8b4b70-597b-11ed-82bf-5321e0c0f2e5
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: The two cryptos and the future of the iPad
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/5944523861378180278/5979232053912240708/s93290-US-4029s-1667262104.mp3
Description: Today on the flagship podcast of all-screen designs:
02:38 -Verge senior audio director Andru Marino dives into the world of a different type of crypto community.
17:51 - David Pierce examines iPadOS 16, Stage Manager, and Apple's attempt at task managers.
iPadOS 16's Stage Manager is not the future of multitasking you were hoping for
34:05 - Dan Seifert and Monica Chin join David to discuss and explain Apple's confusing iPad lineup.
Apple iPad (10th gen) review: stuck in the middle
The new iPad makes no sense
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we'd love to hear from you.
We are conducting a short audience survey to help plan for our future and hear from you. To participate, head to vox.com/podsurvey, and thank you!
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (6 ads detected)
Speaker 2:  Welcome to the Verge Cast, the flagship podcast of all screen designs.
Speaker 2:  I'm your friend David Pierce, and if I sound kind of hoarse this morning,
Speaker 2:  it's because I just spent all weekend in Texas at the Formula One
Speaker 2:  United States Grand Prix.
Speaker 2:  Normally, that's not really a tech thing, but this year Apple's CEO
Speaker 2:  Tim Cook, waved the checkered flag,
Speaker 4:  Possibly the worst checkered flag waving in Formula One history
Speaker 4:  by the Apple boss Tim Cook.
Speaker 2:  So the good news is I think this is all technically a business expense now.
Speaker 2:  That's how that works, right? This worked out great for me and not so great
Speaker 2:  for Tim Cook. Anyway, we have a great show for you today. We're gonna go
Speaker 2:  deep inside the world of crypto, but not the crypto
Speaker 2:  you're thinking of. Then we're gonna talk about the new iPad OS and
Speaker 2:  the new iPads, and we're gonna try to make sense of Apple's whole tablet
Speaker 2:  strategy because it seems like Apple's kind of losing the plot. All of that
Speaker 2:  is coming up in just a second. But first I need to go practice my flag waving
Speaker 2:  skills, because honestly, you never know when it'll be your turn and I'm
Speaker 2:  not gonna blow it like Tim Cook did.
Speaker 4:  So in all the iPhones and iPads and everything, can't give you a sort of
Speaker 4:  strong wrist and nice action to to do that. So come on, Tim Cook. You can
Speaker 4:  do better than that. Yeah, rather than, But anyway,
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. Our first segment for today is a segment. If I'm being
Speaker 2:  completely honest with you, I know almost nothing about. So here
Speaker 2:  to help us explain what's about to happen is our senior audio director Andrew
Speaker 2:  Marino. Hi Andrew.
Speaker 5:  Hi David.
Speaker 2:  Let me tell you what I know about what's about to happen on this podcast.
Speaker 2:  It has to do with crypto. Yeah, but it doesn't have to do with Bitcoin. If
Speaker 2:  it, if this has to do with Bitcoin, you and I are gonna have a fight.
Speaker 5:  It kind of does. Okay.
Speaker 2:  Oh
Speaker 1:  No,
Speaker 2:  Tell me. Tell me what we're about to hear you. You went to investigate a
Speaker 2:  different kind of crypto world as I have come to understand
Speaker 5:  It. Yeah, Crypto, what that means is someone
Speaker 5:  who goes out and tries to discover new and
Speaker 5:  unknown animals
Speaker 2:  And then convince them to buy Bitcoin.
Speaker 5:  No. And however, a lot of that is associated with
Speaker 5:  creatures like the Moth man. Ah, Big Foot Chupacabra
Speaker 5:  Cobra. So there's crypto zoology, which was also
Speaker 5:  shortened to be crypto, but crypto is a whole
Speaker 5:  different thing now, right? So I wanted to talk to Crypto Zoologists
Speaker 5:  to see what they think about the new crypto,
Speaker 2:  What happens when you stop being the wildest crypto out there,
Speaker 2:  right? I love it. All right. Anything else we should know before we get into
Speaker 5:  It? I don't think so.
Speaker 2:  All right, let's do it.
Speaker 5:  The mention of the word cryptocurrency can be exhausting,
Speaker 5:  especially in the past year or so, the television advertisements,
Speaker 5:  I'm
Speaker 7:  Getting into crypto with ftx,
Speaker 5:  You in the memification of digital currency investments like
Speaker 5:  NFTs, everyone
Speaker 8:  Gets an yes. Everyone,
Speaker 2:  Everyone gets an energy.
Speaker 5:  The ups and downs of the price of Bitcoin, Dogecoin, Luna,
Speaker 5:  and others, all that stuff is often shortened to the word crypto,
Speaker 5:  a catchall term for any sort of blockchain technology.
Speaker 5:  But before it was the hottest topic in tech. Crypto had a
Speaker 5:  much different meaning in the English vernacular, at least in a certain
Speaker 5:  community.
Speaker 9:  Crypto to me met crypto zoology.
Speaker 5:  That's Lauren Coleman, a crypto zoologist and founder of
Speaker 5:  the International Crypto Zoology Museum in Portland, Maine. Lauren
Speaker 5:  has been writing about crypto zoology or the study of hidden and unknown
Speaker 5:  animals for over 40 years with books like Creatures of
Speaker 5:  the Outer Edge, Bigfoot, the True Story of Apes in America
Speaker 5:  and cryptozoology A to Z, the encyclopedia of
Speaker 5:  Lochs monsters, Sasquatch, Chupacabras, and other authentic mysteries of
Speaker 5:  nature. Lauren has been called the modern popularizer of the word
Speaker 5:  cryptozoology, though it's origins go back. Before he got
Speaker 5:  started in the field,
Speaker 9:  Crypto zoology was being bannered around
Speaker 9:  in correspondent between French I French
Speaker 9:  writers in 1959. Then in
Speaker 9:  1961, Ivan Tea Anderson wrote the first use
Speaker 9:  of crypto zoology and English. What Sanderson
Speaker 9:  did was really examine a Bigfoot Yeti critter
Speaker 9:  reports from around the world.
Speaker 5:  So then crypto has often been used as shorthand for crypto
Speaker 5:  zoology.
Speaker 9:  I mean, even my mother-in-law does ever call me Lauren. She calls
Speaker 9:  me crypto
Speaker 5:  Crypto. The shorthand for cryptocurrency and the
Speaker 5:  blockchain and the web three stuff we hear about was adapted from the
Speaker 5:  practice of cryptography, the study of techniques for secure
Speaker 5:  communication, and looking into both cryptos, I started to realize
Speaker 5:  they were more closely related than I thought, but the first thing
Speaker 5:  I needed to know has this double meaning of the word crypto
Speaker 5:  caused confusion between the world's.
Speaker 5:  Lauren says he has experienced a bit of that confusion on
Speaker 5:  the internet, especially since his Twitter handle is at crypto. Lauren,
Speaker 9:  I have to constantly spend my precious
Speaker 9:  time doing tweets saying Crypto Lauren
Speaker 9:  is not out. Crypto coin, it's about cryptozoology.
Speaker 9:  I get tagged to, you know, news about a new
Speaker 9:  crypto bitcoin or this or that.
Speaker 5:  This happens not to just Lauren, but many people in the cryptozoology
Speaker 5:  community. Lauren says that his followers now pick up on this and
Speaker 5:  start threads campaigning that crypto means crypto zoology.
Speaker 5:  I've talked to a few people in the space who are podcasters or
Speaker 5:  bloggers who use the word crypto to mean crypto zoology, and
Speaker 5:  they're often met with pitches about Bitcoin and NFTs in their email.
Speaker 5:  But then again, who doesn't get those emails?
Speaker 10:  First of all, it's going to ruin your Google searches, right?
Speaker 5:  That's Sharon Hill, a researcher and writer of paranormal phenomena.
Speaker 5:  She also runs the blog Pop Goes the Crypted, which covers the way pop
Speaker 5:  culture has interacted with crypto zoology.
Speaker 10:  I studied the social phenomenon of paranormal investigation
Speaker 10:  groups of all kinds, so ghost hunters, bigfoot seekers,
Speaker 10:  ufologists to find out why they did what they did, and if
Speaker 10:  they said they used science and if they said yes, how
Speaker 10:  did they use, or if they actually did use scientific processes
Speaker 10:  in their work.
Speaker 5:  I asked her a bit about the interaction between crypto zoology and
Speaker 5:  cryptocurrency communities on the internet.
Speaker 10:  It certainly caused some consternation for the people in the cryptozoology
Speaker 10:  community and, and me too. You know, there are social tribes that are
Speaker 10:  based on specific interests, and the crypto zoo scene was
Speaker 10:  fairly small, and if you were actively involved, you knew everybody
Speaker 10:  that was participating. It was kind of a closed circle,
Speaker 10:  and it's easy to understand that that tribe or that group
Speaker 10:  would adopt the prefix crypto for some things, you know,
Speaker 10:  their websites, their usernames, et cetera, and then suddenly out of their
Speaker 10:  control comes this ragingly, popular new use of crypto
Speaker 10:  that doesn't relate it to them, and I think it perturb some people. They
Speaker 10:  felt a sense of ownership with that original usage, that prefects and
Speaker 10:  then their words and concepts are being used for something completely different,
Speaker 10:  especially when it's related to money and for profit
Speaker 10:  projects. They resented it, so they're just guarding their boundaries.
Speaker 5:  For the most part, the crypto zoology community has been using the word
Speaker 5:  crypto instead of crypto to talk about unknown creatures,
Speaker 5:  which helps steer away some of that confusion. For example,
Speaker 5:  cryptocurrency conventions are called crypto cons, while crypto
Speaker 5:  zoology conventions are called crypto cons. But make
Speaker 5:  no mistake, Web three crypto enthusiasts have attempted to bridge
Speaker 5:  the two communities together.
Speaker 9:  I was approached by one in the cryptocurrency
Speaker 9:  field that wanted to take advantage of
Speaker 9:  my notoriety and being a museum director, and they wanted
Speaker 9:  to start, I can't remember the term it's What's the
Speaker 9:  nf?
Speaker 5:  Oh, NFTs.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. They said, Would you sell NFTs for us?
Speaker 9:  We'd have one that was Yeti and one that was a, you know, they'd take over
Speaker 9:  the names of Crys and make them and whatever that
Speaker 9:  works. You just
Speaker 5:  Said that. Yeah, NFTs, non fungible tokens.
Speaker 9:  Right, right. And we talked for a while, a couple times
Speaker 9:  on the phone and I just backed off. I said,
Speaker 9:  Is there anything that I can get out of this to have as a
Speaker 9:  physical artifact, because that's what we are
Speaker 9:  basing our medium on, but this makes no sense to me. He said, No.
Speaker 9:  I said, Well, I don't think we're checking in the same world.
Speaker 5:  Lauren says he has no plans currently to start accepting
Speaker 5:  Bitcoin or other cryptocurrencies for admission, not the crypto zoology
Speaker 5:  museum, but he clarifies no hard feelings against the other crypto
Speaker 5:  people.
Speaker 9:  Well, there seems to be a little battle. I don't care. I really am
Speaker 9:  not antagonistic against cryptocurrency people. I mean,
Speaker 9:  it's just a phantom type of currency. But then
Speaker 9:  when we think about it, I mean in general is all
Speaker 9:  phantom,
Speaker 5:  So are the two worlds continuing to stay separate? Are the
Speaker 5:  cryptozoology people in one corner of the internet and the
Speaker 5:  cryptocurrency people on the other corner? Not necessarily.
Speaker 5:  There certainly are some crypto zoologists investing in crypto
Speaker 5:  coin.
Speaker 12:  My name is Stephen t Major and I am the founder and director of
Speaker 12:  Operations of Extreme Expeditions Northwest llc, which
Speaker 12:  is an outdoor venture company that specializes in guided
Speaker 12:  bigfoot research expeditions and crypto coin
Speaker 12:  is a division of extreme expeditions. Northwest llc.
Speaker 5:  Stephen Major started getting into cryptocurrencies on his own, but
Speaker 5:  then realized that he could try to use its potential to support his quest
Speaker 5:  to track down undiscovered creatures in the world, which led to
Speaker 5:  crypted coin.
Speaker 12:  We believe that we could capture a Bigfoot, but it's all a matter of money.
Speaker 12:  One of the things that Bigfoot research or Crypted research and
Speaker 12:  investigation suffers from is a lack of funding. My ultimate goal
Speaker 12:  with it was to pitch it to people globally that are
Speaker 12:  into crypted research and investigation or fans of it, and by
Speaker 12:  purchasing some crypted coin, they would be able to
Speaker 12:  support crypted research and investigation.
Speaker 5:  You know, I was curious what exactly would the funding go toward?
Speaker 5:  Steven told me it's all about the latest technology.
Speaker 12:  We've got night vision cameras, we've got drones, we have motion sensor,
Speaker 12:  we have audio recorders, we have all the stuff that is
Speaker 12:  readily available within our budget. However, we would like to start
Speaker 12:  raising enough funding to get more, what I should I say,
Speaker 12:  advanced devices, military grade thermals, things like
Speaker 12:  that. You know, one of those incredible, you know, like flare gear that
Speaker 12:  they have on the Apaches and some of that stuff.
Speaker 5:  While talking to Steven, I started to see a similarity in the
Speaker 5:  discussions about both Bigfoot and Bitcoin. You know, like
Speaker 5:  if we had this amount of money, we can definitely hunt down Bigfoot.
Speaker 5:  If we figure out the layers in the payment stack, we can definitely make
Speaker 5:  Bitcoin work better. And Steven picked up on this too.
Speaker 5:  He said that when he talks to people about either subject, he gets similar
Speaker 5:  reactions.
Speaker 12:  Dude, I get rad all the time. You know, I get Raz all the time
Speaker 12:  about Bigfoots your fantasy. They're not real. They're a joke and this and
Speaker 12:  that thing. And then on the other hand, it's the same thing when I talk
Speaker 12:  to people about either crypto coin or cryptocurrency in general.
Speaker 12:  They think it's a joke, it's fake money and this and that,
Speaker 12:  and so there is a lot of that. They're just as skeptical about it because
Speaker 12:  they just think it's a flash in the pan.
Speaker 5:  In both crypto zoology and cryptocurrency, there are the
Speaker 5:  skeptics, there are the believers, and of course, not all believers of
Speaker 5:  one thing are believers of the other. Lauren Coleman is proof of that.
Speaker 5:  He's not minting messy NFTs. I also reached out to a few
Speaker 5:  cryptocurrency people on Twitter who use the word crypto in their names,
Speaker 5:  asking if they're also interested in crypto zoology finding
Speaker 5:  Bigfoot or the study of hidden or unknown animals.
Speaker 5:  No one replied to my query, but Sharon Hill who has
Speaker 5:  been tracking those spaces says it makes sense that people like Steven Major
Speaker 5:  are heavily invested in both cryptos.
Speaker 10:  Probably the most interesting similarity of these two crypto
Speaker 10:  communities is the significance, or I
Speaker 10:  might even say a comfort level in dealing with what we would
Speaker 10:  call liminal spaces. So that's the gap between the real and the
Speaker 10:  unreal, the light in the dark, the tangible and the abstract or
Speaker 10:  symbolic and how you comprehend that as part of your worldview. For example,
Speaker 10:  you know you have a crypted report. Is that report indicative of
Speaker 10:  people seeing a real animal or is it a hoax or is it
Speaker 10:  supernatural magical or ethereal, if you will?
Speaker 10:  Characteristics of popular crys are symbolic
Speaker 10:  and they manifest complex social concerns too.
Speaker 10:  So similarly, you've got cryptocurrency. Are these NFTs
Speaker 10:  real even though they are in tangible or are they
Speaker 10:  ephemeral that will vanish when you blink? So people
Speaker 10:  are are concerned about kind of similar factors of
Speaker 10:  these cryptos versus cryptocurrency things. Maybe both groups
Speaker 10:  have quite an unusual interest and ease about the
Speaker 10:  unknown and the hidden and what could come in the future.
Speaker 5:  So far, crypto coin has not taken off as well as Steven
Speaker 5:  had hoped. He told me he's pitched a lot of investors,
Speaker 5:  but with no luck of funding. But he still believes
Speaker 5:  cryptocurrency is the wave of the future and the technology is
Speaker 5:  here to stay. In the meantime, he continues his expeditions
Speaker 5:  into the wilderness of the Northwest United States and Canada
Speaker 5:  and producing documentaries about Bigfoot.
Speaker 12:  If I could get people that are really into cryptocurrency to get
Speaker 12:  interested in this, I think it would work. We wanna make believers
Speaker 12:  out of people, not only about Bigfoot being real, but cryptocurrency being
Speaker 12:  real as well.
Speaker 2:  All right, Andrew, thank you. Is cryptocurrency the big foot
Speaker 2:  of money? I don't know what that means, but it sounds good. Anyway, we're
Speaker 2:  gonna take a break and then we're gonna come back and we are going to talk
Speaker 2:  an awful lot about the iPad. We'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  new. You could imagine the world in which the iPad is like
Speaker 2:  the future of everything, but I don't think that's gonna happen, and
Speaker 2:  I think that that's because Apple specifically has absolutely
Speaker 2:  no idea what to do with the iPad to explain what I mean. We have to
Speaker 2:  talk about iPad OS and Stage Manager. Actually, no, hang on. Before
Speaker 2:  we do that, let's set the scene a little bit. I'm gonna talk a lot about
Speaker 2:  Stage Manager in a minute, but first I wanna play you a clip from the iPad's
Speaker 2:  original launch in 2010.
Speaker 14:  Is there room for a third category of device,
Speaker 14:  something that's between a laptop and a smartphone?
Speaker 2:  You can sort of picture it, right? Steve Jobs standing on a stage, he's in
Speaker 2:  jeans and a black turtleneck just like always, and he's explaining why Apple
Speaker 2:  wanted to build a tablet in the first place
Speaker 14:  In order to really create a new category of devices. Those devices are
Speaker 14:  gonna have to be far better at doing some key
Speaker 14:  tasks better than the laptop, better than the
Speaker 14:  smartphone. What kind of tasks? Well, things like
Speaker 14:  browsing the web. That's a pretty tall order. Something that's better at
Speaker 14:  browsing the web than a laptop. Doing email, enjoying and sharing
Speaker 14:  photographs, watching videos, enjoying your music collection,
Speaker 14:  playing games, reading eBooks. If there's gonna be a third
Speaker 14:  category of device, it's gonna have to be better at these kinds of tasks
Speaker 14:  than a laptop or a smartphone. Otherwise it has no reason for being.
Speaker 2:  And then a minute later, jobs sat down on stage in this
Speaker 2:  big comfy armchair and just started playing around with the device.
Speaker 2:  It was very comfortable and relaxed and he kept talking about how big the
Speaker 2:  screen was and how immersive it felt
Speaker 14:  Using this thing as remarkable, it's, it's so much more
Speaker 14:  intimate than a laptop and it's so much more capable than a
Speaker 14:  smartphone with this gorgeous large display.
Speaker 2:  Okay, to be fair, that was 12 years ago and a lot about the
Speaker 2:  iPad has changed mostly in good ways. The iPad is orders
Speaker 2:  of magnitude more powerful now. It has more apps, it has more accessories
Speaker 2:  including keyboards and Silas. And as it's gotten more powerful,
Speaker 2:  people have naturally wanted to do more with it because like Job
Speaker 2:  said, in some ways it is the best of both smartphone and laptop.
Speaker 2:  The iPad was initially this chill, immersive device for
Speaker 2:  browsing the web and playing music, but eventually the power users wanted
Speaker 2:  more. They wanted the iPad to be more like their laptop to even
Speaker 2:  replace their laptop. And that brings us to iPad o s 16
Speaker 2:  and brings us to Sage Manager. Sage Manager is,
Speaker 2:  how do I describe it? Let me just tell you what the screen looks like. The
Speaker 2:  feature is off by default, but when you turn it on, you get the app you're
Speaker 2:  looking at in the middle of the screen taking up, I don't know, three quarters
Speaker 2:  of the display. That space in the middle is known as the stage your dock
Speaker 2:  lives down at the bottom and off to the left, there are four thumbnails representing
Speaker 2:  the four apps you most recently used. These thumbnails are what Apple calls
Speaker 2:  piles, which is an amazing name for it, and you can have up to four apps
Speaker 2:  in each pile. Here's how Apple Software Chief Craig
Speaker 2:  Federighi described it at WWDC this year. He had just finished
Speaker 2:  introducing stage manager for Mac and then explained why it works on the
Speaker 2:  iPad too. Today,
Speaker 15:  On iPad when you use apps, you get the full screen
Speaker 15:  experience that we're all familiar with. Like in photos here
Speaker 15:  with Stage manager activated, I can now resize
Speaker 15:  Windows exposing a powerful new way to work with apps
Speaker 15:  on iPad and the doc is visible so I can easily get to all
Speaker 15:  my apps. Let's open music. You'll notice
Speaker 15:  that all my recently used apps appear on the left, so switching
Speaker 15:  between them is really fast and Stage Manager gives
Speaker 15:  me powerful new layout capabilities to create my ideal workspace
Speaker 15:  for the first time on iPad, I can work with overlapping windows.
Speaker 2:  The idea behind all this, if I'm gonna be really charitable to Apple here,
Speaker 2:  is to give you a quick way to move between the apps you use most. You can
Speaker 2:  have a pile with Slack in your email and then with one Tap jump to
Speaker 2:  another with your browser and Excel. That's a couple of taps faster
Speaker 2:  than swiping to go home or even swiping and holding to get to the app switcher.
Speaker 2:  And that's something. But here's the thing. The way Stage Manager works
Speaker 2:  makes absolutely no sense. Like none at all.
Speaker 2:  I've spent months now trying to figure out the mental model
Speaker 2:  of what goes where and I've got nothing for you.
Speaker 2:  Okay? So you open an app and it opens in Stage Manager that
Speaker 2:  kicks the fifth most recent pile out of stage manager because you can only
Speaker 2:  have four open at a time, but then if you reopen an app from that
Speaker 2:  old pile, it comes back into Stage manager along with the rest of its
Speaker 2:  pile. So that pile wasn't gone, it was just hidden and you
Speaker 2:  weren't allowed to find it. Somehow. If you have an app open in two piles,
Speaker 2:  there's no way to know which pile will open if you click a link to that app
Speaker 2:  and if you click a link in a pile, it might just take you to another pile
Speaker 2:  for no particular reason. You can't rename a pile or pin a pile and you
Speaker 2:  can't put one in your dock. You can't see piles by command tabbing between
Speaker 2:  them. They just kind of come and go and there's no rhyme or reason
Speaker 2:  to any of it.
Speaker 2:  The one exception is the app switcher, which interacts with Stage Manager
Speaker 2:  in a way that actually works. You swipe up and hold to open the view of all
Speaker 2:  your windows, which includes both your full screen apps and whatever piles
Speaker 2:  you've created. This works, this makes sense to me, but that view doesn't
Speaker 2:  match what's on the left side of stage manager and it should, I could
Speaker 2:  keep going on this forever, but let's just do a couple more. Say you decide
Speaker 2:  you wanna full screen a window, so you tap on the three button at the top
Speaker 2:  and you select Zoom. Sometimes nothing happens, just nothing, which is
Speaker 2:  weird, but even when the app does snap to full size, it still stays in
Speaker 2:  the pile. The only way to get it out of the pile is to tap on the three dots
Speaker 2:  and hit Minimize, which effectively hides the app. And then you go open the
Speaker 2:  app again and it's now separate, not minimizing, but sure,
Speaker 2:  but if you minimize a non full screen window, it sends that
Speaker 2:  app to its own pile but leaves it in stage manager. But it only
Speaker 2:  does that if there are other apps in the pile that you were currently using.
Speaker 2:  Does any of this make sense to you? Because it doesn't make any sense to
Speaker 2:  me at all. All of this is not even to mention
Speaker 2:  all the stuff about Stage Manager that is just fully broken. Apple
Speaker 2:  actually delayed the launch of iPad OS 16 in order to get it right, which
Speaker 2:  is why the public launch is actually version 16.1 and it's
Speaker 2:  still missing one of Stage manager's core features, which is using the software
Speaker 2:  on external displays. Big screens in theory would be even more useful for
Speaker 2:  Stage Manager, but we don't get that yet. And even after
Speaker 2:  all that extra work, it's nowhere close to ready. I've had
Speaker 2:  the onscreen keyboard randomly appear when I resized an app. I've had
Speaker 2:  apps crash as soon as I touch the bottom corner to resize them. There are
Speaker 2:  a million hilarious bugs everywhere. Apple's camera apps switches from landscape
Speaker 2:  to portrait as soon as you shrink the window and if you take your
Speaker 2:  iPad and you turn it to go from landscape to portrait mode and then back,
Speaker 2:  it resizes all your windows for some reason. Since you can resize apps,
Speaker 2:  developers have to make sure they look good at lots of different sizes. Some
Speaker 2:  of them really do imagine going from a landscape iPad to a portrait
Speaker 2:  iPad to an iPad mini to a big iPhone, to a small iPhone.
Speaker 2:  Some apps can handle all of those different sizes, but a lot of them
Speaker 2:  can't including a bunch of Apple apps. So you get this just
Speaker 2:  scrunched up view and it just looks bad. Again, I could keep
Speaker 2:  going on this for a really long time, but if you haven't figured it out by
Speaker 2:  now, I really don't like Sage Manager. It doesn't work very well and most
Speaker 2:  importantly it just doesn't make any sense. But the weirdest
Speaker 2:  thing about Sage Manager is that for the people who want more control over
Speaker 2:  how their apps appear on the screen, there is a better answer.
Speaker 2:  Users have been asking Apple for true free form multitasking
Speaker 2:  on the iPad like a Mac where you can just have windows wherever you want
Speaker 2:  them since basically the beginning of the iPad. And every time
Speaker 2:  Apple has even made so much as a gesture in the direction of
Speaker 2:  helping people do more at once, they freak out. Just listen to the
Speaker 2:  crowd in 2015 when Fedi mentions multitasking at
Speaker 2:  wwdc,
Speaker 15:  But now I want to turn to the big one and that's
Speaker 15:  multitasking.
Speaker 2:  They're cheering for multitasking. What a world
Speaker 2:  For a long time Apple's excuse for not offering true
Speaker 2:  do many things at once. Multitasking was that it was about performance and
Speaker 2:  battery life, which was fair enough. But now the iPad pros
Speaker 2:  run chips as powerful as MacBooks and they have plenty of battery life to
Speaker 2:  spare that excuse performance battery life just doesn't work
Speaker 2:  anymore. So what gives, here's my theory and it's the
Speaker 2:  only one that makes any sense to me. It's just that Apple doesn't want to
Speaker 2:  12 years after that first iPad. I think Apple still holds tightly
Speaker 2:  to the idea that the iPad is about focus, it's about simplicity. It's
Speaker 2:  about making your computing life easier, even if that means not letting you
Speaker 2:  do some things. One thing you have to understand is that when Apple talks
Speaker 2:  about multitasking on the iPad and iPhone, it doesn't mean what you think
Speaker 2:  it does. Apple has always used that word not to mean doing a bunch
Speaker 2:  of things at the same time. Actually, Jobs hated that idea. He believed
Speaker 2:  in focus above all else. He liked the idea of full screen apps.
Speaker 2:  What jobs in Apple actually meant by multitasking was quickly switching
Speaker 2:  between things and making sure those things were up to date. Here's jobs
Speaker 2:  introducing iOS four for instance.
Speaker 14:  So let's get into it. Let's start off with the first one, which is
Speaker 14:  probably going to be the biggest one and that is multitasking.
Speaker 14:  Tasking,
Speaker 2:  Again, the cheering people want multitasking Anyway, sorry,
Speaker 2:  back to
Speaker 14:  It. So here I am in mail. I'm gonna look at a mail message. This mail message
Speaker 14:  has a, has a URL to a website. So I'm gonna go to that website and I
Speaker 14:  just click on it and I'm taken to the browser, right? So far this is what
Speaker 14:  we do every day on an iPhone and here I am at this Mount Kilimanjaro website.
Speaker 14:  Now I wanna go back to reading my mail. I'm done looking at this website.
Speaker 14:  What do I do? I can navigate back to the home screen and then click on mail
Speaker 14:  again. But rather than that I can just double click the home button and
Speaker 14:  the window raises up and it shows me all the apps that are running. These
Speaker 14:  are all the apps that are running and I wanna go back to mail and I go right
Speaker 14:  back to where I left it. I wanna go back to that webpage. There I am
Speaker 14:  right back at the webpage. Very simple.
Speaker 2:  What jobs describes there is not multitasking, it's not even
Speaker 2:  close. That is task switching and that is what Apple has
Speaker 2:  always meant when it says multitasking. Things like getting calls when you're
Speaker 2:  in other apps or playing music in the background, that's the closest to true
Speaker 2:  multitasking Apple ever wanted. Actually Apple talked about
Speaker 2:  Siri as a big multitasking win. It's a way to do quick things without losing
Speaker 2:  focus on the thing you're actually doing. And over the years, even as Apple
Speaker 2:  has embraced the idea that the iPad is a productivity tool that you can and
Speaker 2:  should use it to do real work, whatever that means to you, it's still
Speaker 2:  trying to hold on to that same idea. The iPad can't
Speaker 2:  multitask, truly multitask because Apple thinks it shouldn't,
Speaker 2:  but it also kind of thinks that it should and a lot of people want it
Speaker 2:  to. And so everything is kind of a mess. Let me go back to Fedi for a
Speaker 2:  second at an interview he did for John Gruber's talk show podcast right after
Speaker 2:  this year's wwdc because he says something I think is incredibly
Speaker 2:  telling. Stage Manager was built for the Mac, he says, and only came to
Speaker 2:  the iPad later.
Speaker 15:  The Mac experience is messy by default, right? You open one thing
Speaker 15:  and then you go to get the next thing and it piles on top of that mess and
Speaker 15:  you go the next thing, you pile on top that mess. And so,
Speaker 2:  Okay, let's skip ahead of it. He talks about this for a while. Here's the
Speaker 2:  iPad explanation. It
Speaker 15:  Was truly coincidental. I have to say that we found
Speaker 15:  ourselves coming from a completely different direction with
Speaker 15:  iPad and realizing they arrived at the same place. And
Speaker 15:  it was, it was almost weird when that happened. But we realized with iPad
Speaker 15:  you had what was a clean experience by default, single window at a time.
Speaker 15:  Time, but where you wanted to be able to bring in more, have more
Speaker 15:  access to things, more multitasking. So we were able to capture part of
Speaker 15:  the spirit of the iPad and yet open it up in such a huge way
Speaker 15:  to overlapping windows. That broader sense of access for
Speaker 15:  multitasking.
Speaker 2:  One half of that equation makes total sense to me. The Mac does
Speaker 2:  get messy. It's true. And giving you some structure on top of that
Speaker 2:  can be useful. It's why people like spaces or think of like the
Speaker 2:  Stacks feature on the Mac, the one where you can right click on your desktop
Speaker 2:  and have it automatically make folders for all the different types of files
Speaker 2:  you have. It's great, right? It doesn't force you to work a specific way,
Speaker 2:  it just kind of helps you clean up. That doesn't work on an
Speaker 2:  iPad. The iPad is already much more iPhone than Mac.
Speaker 2:  It's already controlled and structured and it has so many guardrails
Speaker 2:  that actually stage manager is just more structure on all of that
Speaker 2:  structure. Now you have a million different ways to do everything and none
Speaker 2:  of them just give you control. Yes, Stage manager lets you have
Speaker 2:  overlapping windows and that's nice, but it's too complicated for simple
Speaker 2:  use cases and it's not nearly powerful enough for the real power
Speaker 2:  user stuff because Apple is trying to make the iPad all things
Speaker 2:  to all people because it can do so much, so many different ways.
Speaker 2:  It tried to make something that is both super focused and simple and
Speaker 2:  super powerful and versatile and that just turns out to be
Speaker 2:  impossible. And so Stage Manager is kind of a bad idea, badly
Speaker 2:  implemented and as you'll see with the iPad lineup this year,
Speaker 2:  confusion is a bit of a theme. What is the iPad?
Speaker 2:  Who is it for? How are you supposed to use it? Apple's answer
Speaker 2:  used to be very clear. Now it's all about choice and
Speaker 2:  versatility and you can do anything with it any way you want. I think
Speaker 2:  that's a bad answer and I think Apple needs better ones quickly. But
Speaker 2:  we'll get to all of that in just a second. First a break, we'll be right
Speaker 2:  back.
Speaker 18:  Everyone is raving about my policeman to all
Speaker 19:  Of us. To all of us
Speaker 18:  Critics call it a powerful story of forbidden love.
Speaker 19:  Come with me just you and I,
Speaker 18:  I dunno what's happening. You have to be careful. An emotional journey of
Speaker 18:  desire and regret. He's trying to destroy our marriage, sweeping
Speaker 18:  and romantic. So how does
Speaker 19:  It make you feel? I pity people who dunno what it feels like to be this
Speaker 19:  in
Speaker 18:  Love. My policeman ready are on 17 nine, The Middle Without Pair
Speaker 18:  in select theaters October 21st and on Prime video November 4th.
Speaker 20:  Look, robots do a lot of great things. They serve as dim sum like
Speaker 20:  super fast. They do a B minus job vacuuming our homes. They
Speaker 20:  even help our parents remember that all of their passwords are well password.
Speaker 20:  One thing robots aren't great at though finding your next favorite song.
Speaker 20:  If you're ready to discover music picked by real humans, not algorithms
Speaker 20:  or robots you're going to love and it's a new live radio app with
Speaker 20:  tons of creators hosting shows on anything and everything. Dive into an
Speaker 20:  endless stream of new tunes, sports talks, shows hitting culture and
Speaker 20:  so much more. There are even shows hosted by iconic creators like Joe
Speaker 20:  Button and Lil Yacht where you can call in and chat with them directly,
Speaker 20:  Tune in, call in or step up to the plate and host your own show from anywhere,
Speaker 20:  right from your phone. Discover your next obsession with Amp
Speaker 20:  download today on the app store or just as selected to play Amp. Hey robots
Speaker 20:  are still good for something. Download amp from the app store or head to
Speaker 20:  on amp.com to learn more.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back Apple is about to start selling a couple of new
Speaker 2:  iPads. There's the 10th generation iPad model, the base model which has some
Speaker 2:  new colors
Speaker 2:  lineup is kind of losing its mind. The verges Dan Seifert
Speaker 2:  and Monica Chin have been writing about and viewing these devices over the
Speaker 2:  last couple of weeks. So we're gonna get into trying to make sense of this
Speaker 2:  lineup and which one might be for you. Dan? Hello.
Speaker 2:  Hello Monica. Hello. Hello. Thank you both for doing this.
Speaker 2:  I feel like we've all been in insane iPad chaos hell
Speaker 2:  for the last week or so. So I'm sorry for putting you through this again,
Speaker 2:  but thank you for being here. Anything for you David? So my
Speaker 2:  goal here is basically like I just wanna try and help people
Speaker 2:  figure out if you wanna buy an iPad, which one should you buy?
Speaker 2:  And I feel like I've had a bunch of like heuristics for this over the years
Speaker 2:  where it was like okay if you, if you just wanted an iPad but you wanted
Speaker 2:  it only for very simple things, I was like perfect, just buy the base level
Speaker 2:  iPad $329, you'll be very happy, it'll be great if you wanna like
Speaker 2:  do stuff. I mostly recommended people by the air and then if
Speaker 2:  it was like if you are a person who knows you wanna pro buy a pro, you'll
Speaker 2:  probably love it. Now I feel like everything is like wildly
Speaker 2:  massively up in the air.
Speaker 21:  Everyone should just own an iPad mini end of story.
Speaker 2:  We're done if I'm honest, that's my actual answer. It's the
Speaker 2:  wrong answer but, but that is how I feel in my heart. But Dan let's start
Speaker 2:  with you actually cuz you just reviewed the iPad 10th generation which is
Speaker 2:  like yes ostensibly the default iPad. It should be
Speaker 2:  the one that if it is like I want an iPad and I want to answer no follow
Speaker 2:  up questions, the answer should be the 10th generation iPad
Speaker 2:  but you, you just reviewed it, what's the verdict? How do you feel
Speaker 21:  The verdict is? It should be the default iPad but I don't think it's
Speaker 21:  the right iPad for basically anyone that's not really a knock
Speaker 21:  against the device itself because in a vacuum the Tension
Speaker 21:  iPad is a really great tablet, performs really well, it's got reliable Battery
Speaker 21:  Life has all the iPad apps, the screen is good if not perfect,
Speaker 21:  it's got a new updated design, the sound is really good, all that kind of
Speaker 21:  stuff. And so like it's hard to like knock the device itself but when you
Speaker 21:  put it in the context of like Apple's iPad lineup, it's like
Speaker 21:  too expensive for what it is if you are really price sensitive
Speaker 21:  and then it is like not nice enough to
Speaker 21:  put up a good fight against the iPad air, which is like the next level up.
Speaker 21:  So it's like kind of this weird in between spot and I'm
Speaker 21:  sure Apple wanted to bring that in at a lower price but like right
Speaker 21:  now the way it's priced at it's just a really tough sell.
Speaker 21:  Especially because the entry level iPad that you just mentioned, it's still
Speaker 21:  available, it's still being sold. So if you're really price sensitive
Speaker 21:  there's a lot of reasons to just buy that one, which is still a really good
Speaker 21:  tablet. Like it's not a bad tablet at all. It's a great iPad.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Monica, I'm curious what you think too cuz your perspective on this
Speaker 2:  is super interesting and that you come at it from like a should you buy a
Speaker 2:  $500 laptop or should you buy an iPad kind of thing. And I feel like
Speaker 2:  like reading your reviews always it's been like well if you just wanna do
Speaker 2:  basic stuff like maybe you should consider buying an iPad and you wrote last
Speaker 2:  week and my sense would be having now like seen these things in the wild
Speaker 2:  and dance review experience and all that stuff that like this has sort of
Speaker 2:  confirmed your priors that this is now like a mid-level laptop that is maybe
Speaker 2:  not the mid-level laptop you should buy.
Speaker 22:  Yeah, what I would say David, is there is a big difference and I recognize
Speaker 22:  that some amount of this difference is psychological but it is there
Speaker 22:  nonetheless between $329 and
Speaker 22:  $449.
Speaker 2:  Oh absolutely
Speaker 22:  $329 to me is a very fine, I will
Speaker 22:  buy this for my kids or I will buy this to just like watch
Speaker 22:  the watcher on but like everything else I do on my computer,
Speaker 22:  $329 for that is fine. $449
Speaker 22:  just seems like too much. And like if that were just me, that'd be
Speaker 22:  one thing. But I think most people think that $449
Speaker 22:  is getting to the point where that is too expensive for a device for
Speaker 22:  which like those two things are the primary use case and
Speaker 22:  that's without adding the keyboard. Which like if you wanna buy the
Speaker 22:  keyboard that's another $250 at that point you're at 700.
Speaker 22:  Like I can give you like tons and tons of laptops you can buy for 700.
Speaker 22:  Right? You know it's like the three $29 iPad nine has been a
Speaker 22:  real like pain for me as a reviewer frankly because every time I
Speaker 22:  review a budget thing I have to caveat like well you could buy this or you
Speaker 22:  could buy $329 thing. And when someone asked me like Oh I want
Speaker 22:  something under you know $600, what should I buy? It was hard for me to
Speaker 22:  come up with an alternative to that $29 iPad nine. The more
Speaker 22:  you increase the price because price is like the main benefit of these things
Speaker 22:  when you put them up against laptops, right? The higher that price goes,
Speaker 22:  the easier it is for me to come up with something else that I can recommend
Speaker 22:  to you as a budget shopper and especially at 450
Speaker 22:  but going up to 700 it is way easier for me to come up with small alternatives.
Speaker 21:  Yeah and it's important to note that like these iPads are great
Speaker 21:  tablets but not great laptops. Like you can add
Speaker 21:  the keyboard to them and you can get keyboard cases for them, but ultimately
Speaker 21:  it's a really small screen to try and like spend a lot of time
Speaker 21:  working on. They are limited in how many, you know, apps
Speaker 21:  you can run side by side and things like that. And so the, the higher end
Speaker 21:  iPads do have things like stage manager which we kind of have
Speaker 21:  established as not in a great position now. Yes. But it's an idea for better
Speaker 21:  multitasking. They have the ability to scale their screen down differently
Speaker 21:  so you can fit more stuff on the screen and makes it easier to multitask
Speaker 21:  and stuff like that. These are really like if you're trying to like do laptop,
Speaker 21:  like work with it, it's very light laptop work, sending a few emails, reading
Speaker 21:  a couple of things, you know stuff like that. Not really like spending
Speaker 21:  all day
Speaker 22:  On it. I do wanna add to that too that this, I'm not trying to say here
Speaker 22:  that the fact that the iPad is so limited like is an insult to anyone who
Speaker 22:  loves the iPad cause this is like something that's been a big deal on Twitter
Speaker 22:  with some people. Like I have lots of devices that I own that I love that
Speaker 22:  I think are great and I also don't think they should cost $700.
Speaker 2:  Yes a hundred percent. Well this goes to like my basic conundrum which is
Speaker 2:  like my, my general stance on most technology now
Speaker 2:  is like buy the best thing you can afford and upgrade as rarely as possible,
Speaker 2:  right? Buy the nicest thing you can figure out and then keep it as long as
Speaker 2:  you possibly can and that is like a happy way to live your technological
Speaker 2:  life. Whereas if you just keep buying crappy stuff you're just gonna have
Speaker 2:  to keep buying crappy stuff and that sucks. But I'm kind of at a point now
Speaker 2:  where it seems to me like last year's
Speaker 2:  $329 iPad is probably
Speaker 2:  still the right choice If you're just a person who wants an iPad.
Speaker 2:  Like I, I certainly don't imagine there's any particular like
Speaker 2:  performance issues. It has a now two generations old chip or
Speaker 2:  maybe more than that Jesus if you include the Amchis but like it's still
Speaker 2:  faster than you need Dan to your point to like check your email and browse
Speaker 2:  the internet. The camera's pretty good. It has touch ID and Lightning, both
Speaker 2:  of which are old And so I end up like spinning out of control where it's
Speaker 2:  like okay this thing is going to be obsolete faster than some of these other
Speaker 2:  devices. So I'm like reluctant to tell people to buy it but also for
Speaker 2:  all the things most people want to do on their iPads, it's still
Speaker 2:  plenty right now and I think the new iPad is both
Speaker 2:  too expensive and in certain ways like overkill for that
Speaker 2:  stuff. I don't know, this is the part I can't figure out.
Speaker 21:  There's multiple like components here. Right? So you mentioned the processor
Speaker 21:  in performance. One thing that really struck me with reviewing this
Speaker 21:  iPad 10.9 or 10th gen iPad recently is that I
Speaker 21:  typically use an M one iPad Pro that's like my personal iPad. I
Speaker 21:  use it all the time. I'm very familiar with how it works. I reviewed earlier
Speaker 21:  this year the iPad air with the M one and then I'm reviewing the iPad
Speaker 21:  10th gen with an A 14, an arguably lower end ship.
Speaker 21:  But I couldn't find an appreciable difference in performance
Speaker 21:  in all the things that I do on my iPad. Whether I'm zooming with colleagues
Speaker 21:  or I'm in Slack or I'm bouncing between tasks or I'm opening multiple
Speaker 21:  tabs or I'm writing the review on the iPad itself, whatever it is,
Speaker 21:  all of my typical office productivity work is like not limited
Speaker 21:  by the processor, it's limited by the OS but it's not the processor. So
Speaker 21:  it's like you have all these different levels of processor performance in
Speaker 21:  the iPad but I'd be very hard pressed to be if most people could be able
Speaker 21:  to tell the difference between the different iPads. There are other quality
Speaker 21:  of life things, the air and the pro have nicer screens and that's immediately
Speaker 21:  noticeable and I think that's, if it is something that you care about, it
Speaker 21:  is a very important thing. That screen is arguably the most important part
Speaker 21:  of a tablet. It's the thing you're looking at the most and interacting with
Speaker 21:  the most. It's the whole
Speaker 2:  Reason it exists.
Speaker 21:  Yeah it is worth paying for a little bit nicer screen if you care that much
Speaker 21:  but then like if you're not particular about that then
Speaker 21:  the ninth gen has a little bit of a smaller screen but it's so
Speaker 21:  much less expensive And I, there's other things that it does have that
Speaker 21:  the 10th gen doesn't have and I think a big one at this price point for
Speaker 21:  this type of device is the headphone jack. We've kind of like gotten away
Speaker 21:  from like complaining about no headphone jacks on phones because we had
Speaker 21:  to accept that there are basically no phones without with headphone jacks
Speaker 21:  anymore And like we have to live in that reality. But tablets are a very
Speaker 21:  different product and they have a different type of consumer
Speaker 21:  or user and a lot of the users of a base iPad are kids
Speaker 21:  whether they're at home or they're at school or whatever it is
Speaker 21:  and they don't have their own AirPods and their own Bluetooth headphones
Speaker 21:  and things like that. They're using wired headphones because it's easy.
Speaker 21:  You can get sound limiting ones, which is a big thing for a lot of parents
Speaker 21:  that you can limit the volume with and so kids aren't blowing their ears
Speaker 21:  out and you could do that over a standard 3.5 millimeter headphones jack
Speaker 21:  if schools are sharing an iPad, I know that I can speak for like my kids,
Speaker 21:  we send them to school with their own headphones and they use share devices
Speaker 21:  and plug their headphones into them. Right. You can't do that if you don't
Speaker 21:  have a headphones Jack. You can't give everyone a dongle or expect everyone
Speaker 21:  to pair their headphones to it. Yeah, like it just, it's like a really frustrating
Speaker 21:  limitation. So in this context I think a headphone jack is actually a lot
Speaker 21:  of value. The other part of it is if you're giving this device to a kid,
Speaker 21:  they're probably gonna break it at some point. Yes. And that goes back to
Speaker 21:  Monica's point about the price that $450 price
Speaker 21:  versus $329 and realistic in the real world, most people are
Speaker 21:  not paying $329 for that iPad. It's been out long enough that it's easy
Speaker 21:  to find for 2 79 or maybe even two 50 if you hunt a little bit. That's a
Speaker 21:  huge difference. If you think, you know, this kid's gonna break it in a
Speaker 21:  year and I gotta replace it or repair it or whatever it is. Like it just
Speaker 21:  doesn't make sense to be spending that extra money If you're buying something
Speaker 21:  for yourself, that's a different story if you're like, you know looking
Speaker 21:  for yourself. But then I would say look at the iPad air, it's that much
Speaker 21:  closer in price to the standard, the 10th gen iPad and has a nicer
Speaker 21:  screen and we didn't even talk about like the pencil situations got nicer
Speaker 21:  accessories options there and it has an even faster processor which
Speaker 21:  might last longer in terms of like future support and updates
Speaker 21:  and other new features coming down the
Speaker 22:  Road. What I would add to that too from the perspec, from like the childless
Speaker 22:  adult perspective is I think there's maybe something to be said for like
Speaker 22:  there's probably some constituency of people who's interested
Speaker 22:  in paying a premium for like a slightly more modern look and
Speaker 22:  speaking between the ninth gen and the 10th Jen, I do think though that
Speaker 22:  if I were a budget shopper myself who was in the base iPad's target
Speaker 22:  audience, I'd be buying the 3 29 over the 4 49 right now. And I also think
Speaker 22:  another option I'd have would be to wait for the 4 49 to come down
Speaker 22:  to 3 29 because that's something to, to dance point about. Being able to
Speaker 22:  find deals currently on the 3 29 1, like the 4 49 ones
Speaker 22:  price is very likely to fall in the future.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, it doesn't make a lot of sense to me. Like I'm sitting here trying
Speaker 2:  to figure out how to play devil's advocate and like advocate for the
Speaker 2:  more expensive iPad. Cause I think one of the things I have had to learn
Speaker 2:  the hard way over time is that Apple buyers are less price sensitive than
Speaker 2:  I think they are And Apple has like continued to press that fact
Speaker 2:  over and over and over again. They're, they're raising the prices of services,
Speaker 2:  they're raising the prices of hardware and like people just keep buying their
Speaker 2:  stuff because they make good stuff and people like it and, but even in this
Speaker 2:  case, like I just, I'm not sure other than the design which I think
Speaker 2:  is noticeably better from the ninth gen to the 10, I can't really think of
Speaker 2:  a thing that is going to be like meaningfully better in people's lives in
Speaker 2:  the new one.
Speaker 21:  Yeah, I mean this screen's a little bigger. Yeah, it's, it's 0.7 inch bigger.
Speaker 21:  So that kind of goes hand in hand with the design. But I don't think that
Speaker 21:  the processor difference is appreciable. I don't think having 5G is an option
Speaker 21:  is appreciable because most people buying this level iPad are not adding
Speaker 21:  cellular because that's another $150 surcharge. Plus you have to pay for
Speaker 21:  the service. So if you are in the type that is going to pay for
Speaker 21:  cellular connectivity on it, you're probably looking at an error or above
Speaker 21:  anyways cuz you're in that higher end market. So these other features are
Speaker 21:  just like not adding value outside of the design is
Speaker 21:  nicer and the screen's a little bigger and for the price difference, that's
Speaker 21:  a really tough sell.
Speaker 2:  All right, so let's talk about the error actually because when these things
Speaker 2:  first came out, my immediate reaction was like, why does
Speaker 2:  the air still exist? Because it was always the like a
Speaker 2:  little bit of a tweener and a little bit of the best of both worlds depending
Speaker 2:  on how you looked at it. It was like it, it was right in that middle spot
Speaker 2:  of like it's, it's pretty good and pretty expensive and do it that would
Speaker 2:  you will now it's $150 more
Speaker 2:  than the iPad 10. But like you said Dan, it has this better screen,
Speaker 2:  it has support for the newest pencil. It has I
Speaker 2:  think the same camera, it has the M one chip instead of the A 14 bionic
Speaker 2:  chip, which a lot of people got really up in arms again about. But again,
Speaker 2:  I think there's like, this isn't, these things aren't gonna be meaningful
Speaker 2:  to most people. Like the A 14 bionic is gonna be plenty and so is the M one,
Speaker 2:  the M two, like God help you if you are maxing out the performance of the
Speaker 2:  M two M two chip on the new pro. But we'll get to that. Is there a, is there
Speaker 2:  a case for the air as kind of still that like good tweener?
Speaker 21:  I think the air is actually the most compelling iPad
Speaker 21:  for a lot of people and I think that if you are are buying an iPad, you're
Speaker 21:  falling into two brackets, you're, you're falling into the one that we've
Speaker 21:  discussed extensively. The budget buyer who is just buying a basic iPad
Speaker 21:  for iPad things or you are, you are that customer that you mentioned earlier
Speaker 21:  that is like not as price sensitive, is willing to pay more and the air
Speaker 21:  actually gives you noticeable, appreciative, better experience and better
Speaker 21:  options for the future. Whether you want to add the pencil or add the better
Speaker 21:  keyboard or there are features coming down the road that will support
Speaker 21:  the M one but not the A 14 processor. So like if
Speaker 21:  you are in that space, I think the error is actually a really good value.
Speaker 21:  It gives you basically the same performance as the pro. It gives you the
Speaker 21:  same size as the pro. It gives you the same ability to connect
Speaker 21:  to external displays as the pro. It gives you the same ability to connect
Speaker 21:  peripherals as the pro and it has the same accessory ecosystem as
Speaker 21:  the pro and it has almost as good of a screen. Really the only difference
Speaker 21:  between the screens, between the air and the PRO is promotion, which is
Speaker 21:  the higher refresh rate, but you're still getting laminated display, you're
Speaker 21:  still getting P three color gamut. It's noticeably nicer. You put it side
Speaker 21:  by side with a 10th gen iPad and it's very obvious which one is a better
Speaker 21:  screen. And so like all of those things are much better quality of life.
Speaker 21:  If you are going to buy an iPad, maybe you're considering, you know, replacing
Speaker 21:  your iPad or your laptop with it, maybe you're looking for a third device
Speaker 21:  they use on the go commuting. Maybe you are buying the cellular connectivity,
Speaker 21:  maybe you're planning to keep it for five years or more. I think that the
Speaker 21:  air is actually a really compelling option at this point. And especially
Speaker 21:  as we were just saying, like you can get the ninth gen on sale, you could
Speaker 21:  get the air on sale too, and it's a lot closer to the 10 gen price when
Speaker 21:  it's on sale. So it's like a $70 difference. And at that point it's a no
Speaker 21:  brainer to me by the air. Forget about the 10 gen,
Speaker 22:  I mean, I agree that the big benefit of the air is better accessory compatibility.
Speaker 22:  I just wish they would give that to the iPad 10 and at that point I think
Speaker 22:  it would make more sense as a buy.
Speaker 21:  Yeah, it's, it's kind of a weird position though, right? Because like it's
Speaker 21:  super weird that the iPad 10 does not support the second gen pencil. Like
Speaker 21:  it supports the first gen pencil and has this weird umbilical charging situation.
Speaker 21:  It's a mess. And then the keyboard accessory for it is a $250 keyboard
Speaker 21:  accessory that's only compatible with the tension air. It's not compatible
Speaker 21:  with the air or attention iPad, excuse me, not compatible with the air or
Speaker 21:  the pro, but that keyboard accessory is already really expensive
Speaker 21:  and the keyboard accessory for the air and for the pro is even more expensive
Speaker 21:  and the second gen pencil is even more expensive. So now it's like if you
Speaker 21:  are wanting to kid out your iPad and like do the whole thing,
Speaker 21:  get the whole experience, are you gonna spend $300 on a keyboard for
Speaker 21:  a $450 tablet? That doesn't seem like a great equation to me. Or
Speaker 21:  $130 on a pencil for your $450
Speaker 21:  tablet. Like it just makes sense to me that like if you're adding those
Speaker 21:  accessories, you're adding them to the nicer iPad. I agree that it would
Speaker 21:  be great if these were all cross compatible, it would eliminate a lot of
Speaker 21:  confusion, but I just can't see a lot of people actually going for that
Speaker 21:  deal on the 10 gen iPad.
Speaker 2:  I agree. But the keyboard lineup to me is the single most insane thing
Speaker 2:  about the way that the iPads work right now. There are smart keyboards and
Speaker 2:  there are magic keyboards and there are folios and there are non folios.
Speaker 2:  And the fact that there is a thing called the magic keyboard folio that only
Speaker 2:  works on the iPad 10 and nothing else is stupid like to
Speaker 2:  your point, it's ridiculous and, and Apple has this very simple
Speaker 2:  opportunity to unify some of the things that it has going on and like
Speaker 2:  there were a bunch of people who, you know, wrote these stories explaining
Speaker 2:  that where the magnet would go for the Apple Pencil two on the iPad 10
Speaker 2:  generation is actually where the camera is in the center
Speaker 2:  on in landscape mode now and all these things and it's like this is all well
Speaker 2:  and good but this is just like, this is so deeply like un
Speaker 2:  apple-like to be this complicated and make me like draw a diagram
Speaker 2:  of which keyboard works for for which thing. The
Speaker 21:  Strangest part of that is that the 10th gen looks identical to the air
Speaker 21:  and basically identical to the pro. And so you would look at
Speaker 21:  it and you'd be like, oh these can use all the same things together. Like
Speaker 21:  the ninth gen looks different and you could be like, oh I can understand
Speaker 21:  it doesn't fit that keyboard case because it looks different and it's a
Speaker 21:  different size. This is like within a millimeter of the size of the air
Speaker 21:  in every dimension has the same size screen as the same overall design.
Speaker 21:  It doesn't make a ton of sense that they did not make it compatible with
Speaker 21:  the same accessories.
Speaker 2:  Agreed. If Apple could figure out how to get the new pencil on the iPad mini,
Speaker 2:  they could have figured out how to do it on the iPad tent generation. But
Speaker 2:  Monica, here's my thing about the air. So the air is 5 99, but
Speaker 2:  if you go, if you go all in and you, you like get the Apple pencil and the
Speaker 2:  magic keyboard, this thing is 1020 $7
Speaker 2:  and you, the other thing you could buy for that money is a MacBook heir.
Speaker 2:  And I think a lot of the people who are just making this particular decision
Speaker 2:  are literally going to be deciding between those two things. I, I don't know
Speaker 2:  what's your sense of how you would even explain that to people? Like if you're
Speaker 2:  gonna spend a thousand dollars, are you gonna spend it on like what feels
Speaker 2:  like kind of a super expensive tablet or Apple's
Speaker 2:  like increasingly extremely good entry level laptop?
Speaker 22:  I mean I'd just get an air,
Speaker 2:  To be fair, that could have meant either one that's the MacBook Air and the
Speaker 2:  iPad Air.
Speaker 22:  I would get the MacBook Air. Okay. Just because I think at that price you
Speaker 22:  should get an operating system that can do what Mac
Speaker 22:  Os can do. Again, this doesn't mean that I, I'm not trying to insult people
Speaker 22:  who love to use iPad os like I think it's great, I love to use it myself.
Speaker 22:  I think there are great use cases for it but Mac OS can just do
Speaker 22:  a lot more and I think the two are not worth
Speaker 22:  the same amount of money.
Speaker 21:  I think it's very interesting that if we were having this conversation three
Speaker 21:  years ago, it'd be a very different dynamic and the thing
Speaker 21:  that's happened is MacBooks got good again and now that they are
Speaker 21:  so good it's made the iPad a lot less compelling. Yes. So we had all these
Speaker 21:  years where it was like, oh the iPad is the future of computing. Apple's
Speaker 21:  really pushing the iPad as it's as it's like next level
Speaker 21:  and it's getting all the features before they, the MacBooks would and the
Speaker 21:  MacBooks had terrible battery life and they ran hot and things like that
Speaker 21:  and then the arm transition happened and MacBooks got good again, whether
Speaker 21:  you got the air or the pro, you know you're getting a really great computer
Speaker 21:  that has the same battery life as an iPad as you know, the same quiet silent
Speaker 21:  performance as an iPad it's nearly as light or if you add a keyboard to
Speaker 21:  an iPad, the iPad is heavier than an air. So it's like
Speaker 21:  all of those reasons to go with an iPad have evaporated. And so now
Speaker 21:  it's like well where does this iPad sit? And I think for a lot of people
Speaker 21:  it really is not their only device, it is a secondary or tertiary
Speaker 21:  when you count the phone, the comp, the laptop and the tablet and then it's
Speaker 21:  like okay well how valuable is this thing to you? And then it's like well
Speaker 21:  if it's a tertiary device, buy the $300 one and watch your Netflix
Speaker 21:  on the couch and like you know, don't try to even think that you're gonna
Speaker 21:  replace your laptop with
Speaker 2:  It. It is really interesting that there's been this big picture iPad
Speaker 2:  transition, like it's almost coming full circle back to what it
Speaker 2:  initially was, which was like the thing that sits between your computer
Speaker 2:  and your phone that is like, it's good for consumption, it's nice for sitting
Speaker 2:  on the couch, it's more immersive than your phone and less chaotic than
Speaker 2:  your laptop and like it has a place that it exists but I think, but I think
Speaker 2:  you're right, we spent a decade being like, well my laptop kind of sucks.
Speaker 2:  What if we could get this thing that is like smooth and fast and
Speaker 2:  last all day to get up to the laptop level of things And
Speaker 2:  with things like stage manager as we've talked about, I'm not super confident
Speaker 2:  that's possible. I'm also not sure that's what we want anymore.
Speaker 2:  It's like and this we can, we can have the like should there be a touchscreen
Speaker 2:  Mac debate all day? And I would very much like to because yes there should
Speaker 2:  be but I do think you're right that like the the distance between those two
Speaker 2:  things, especially again for what we're talking about for like most people's
Speaker 2:  everyday computing, it is just not that different. Like if you're the type
Speaker 2:  who is like oh I want to do the manipulate, the 3D models
Speaker 2:  like the stuff that Apple likes to show on stage to show the new chips, knock
Speaker 2:  yourself out by an iPad, you'll be very happy.
Speaker 21:  Use that pencil and and draw those drawings And which
Speaker 2:  Brings us to the pros because these are the pros I feel like
Speaker 2:  are actually the easiest one for me to understand because it feels very self
Speaker 2:  selecting to me. It's like this is for people who either just want the best
Speaker 2:  thing because it is the best thing or have some specific use case they know
Speaker 2:  they're gonna like beat the hell outta their iPad with and want it for that
Speaker 2:  specific purpose. Is that that fair? Is that the right read?
Speaker 21:  Yeah, I think like especially when we talk about the 12.9 Pro, I think the
Speaker 21:  12.9 Pro is like for the person who wants the absolute best
Speaker 21:  is like actually going to commit to replacing their laptop with it. It's
Speaker 21:  got a big enough screen where it's like it's not as cramped as the 11 inch
Speaker 21:  models and you can do multitasking and things like that And there's a lot
Speaker 21:  of people out there who are willing to go through a lot of hoops to work
Speaker 21:  around iPad OS limitations to make it their daily driver machine.
Speaker 21:  They'll plug it into a display, they'll plug in hubs and dongles
Speaker 21:  and everything to it and and use it like it's a real computer and
Speaker 21:  and that makes sense. I think that the 11 inch pro is kind of like a forgotten
Speaker 21:  step child now and it's like we see the 12.9 inch pro push
Speaker 21:  forward each year. Last year it got the mini l e d screen
Speaker 21:  which is like a tremendous display. It matches the display that's on the
Speaker 21:  MacBook Pros at a significant high higher price. So you're getting
Speaker 21:  a better screen with that and that's absolutely important but like the 11
Speaker 21:  inch didn't get that, it didn't get it again this year. So like what's going
Speaker 21:  on with the 11 inch? Like is it was one gonna stick around? Like why not
Speaker 21:  just have base model air and then 12.9 inch Pro
Speaker 21:  like that's like seems like to be the mix of that makes sense. And I say
Speaker 21:  this as a person that owns the 11 inch iPad Pro, like I'm the weirdo that
Speaker 21:  bought it but like if I were shopping for a new one right now and I was
Speaker 21:  not looking at secondhand or special deals or anything like that, it would
Speaker 21:  be a really tough sell to get the 11 inch over either the air which offers
Speaker 21:  basically the same experience at a lower price or the 12.9 which offers
Speaker 21:  a meaningfully different experience even though at a higher
Speaker 22:  Price. Yeah, my thing with few of the pro is basically like if you wanna
Speaker 22:  buy it, you know who you are and more power to you. There are some like
Speaker 22:  features on the pro that are very clearly the pro features like the ultra
Speaker 22:  wide, the promo, the M two. If you need like one or more of
Speaker 22:  those then you're someone who should buy the pro. I'm with you David that
Speaker 22:  that one to me is very easy to sort of understand who would be
Speaker 22:  buying that versus who would be buying the other ones.
Speaker 2:  Yeah that one I feel like one easy question I find for people is like how
Speaker 2:  aggressively are you? Are you gonna use the pencil? And if people are like
Speaker 2:  the pencil is very important to me, it's like that get the pro right, it's
Speaker 2:  like you, you want the higher refresh rate, you want the bigger screen.
Speaker 2:  I will say I was on a plane last night and this woman sat down next to me,
Speaker 2:  took out a 12.9 inch pro, had like a clip thing
Speaker 2:  that went on the seat back in front of her and literally it was like she
Speaker 2:  had hung up like a projector screen on the screen in,
Speaker 21:  She had a whole TV with
Speaker 2:  Her. It was the coolest flex I've ever seen and it was over the like crappy
Speaker 2:  little seat back display. She was like no, no and hung up her 12.9 inch iPad.
Speaker 2:  It was the most amazing thing I've ever experienced. I've never wanted one
Speaker 2:  of those things more than I did in that moment. But yeah, I think that's
Speaker 2:  right and Dan, this is kind of where I'm at now too is like in a certain
Speaker 2:  way, like we have these new models and I'm not actually sure the iPad
Speaker 2:  lineup just changed very much. It's like we have,
Speaker 2:  the ones I'm inclined to tell people to buy are the 329 inch
Speaker 2:  iPad that already existed, the iPad Air that already existed
Speaker 2:  and the pro which I guess got upgraded but not in like an earth shattering
Speaker 2:  way. So buy the pro whenever you feel like buying the pro and you'll probably
Speaker 2:  be very happy or
Speaker 21:  Buy last year's model of the pro. It's like basically my recommendation
Speaker 21:  to everybody.
Speaker 2:  That's what I was just about to ask like is is this where we're gonna be
Speaker 2:  with iPads for the foreseeable future? It's like there's so much performance
Speaker 2:  headroom, these things don't change all that much year to year because they
Speaker 2:  can't really, it's just a screen that you hold.
Speaker 21:  Yeah, I mean I think what we're seeing actually is because of this
Speaker 21:  performance headroom because of what I was saying earlier that like during
Speaker 21:  like normal tasks, you really can't perceive a difference between this,
Speaker 21:  these different levels of iPads we're seeing Apple add artificial
Speaker 21:  separators to them and so the first one was oh stage
Speaker 21:  manager's only gonna be for the M one iPads or newer. So that was
Speaker 21:  limited to the air and the pro, they ended up backtracking on that and adding
Speaker 21:  it to older pro models that had older chip sets but limiting it and saying
Speaker 21:  that it won't do external support and maybe that's accurate, maybe that
Speaker 21:  is like, you know it, the hardware there just can't handle it for whatever
Speaker 21:  reason. A, you know, 2020 MacBook Air with eight gigs of RAM and an
Speaker 21:  M one processor can let you do all the windows you want, but we're gonna
Speaker 21:  limit it on this one and now we're seeing it with the M two. They are
Speaker 21:  limiting this new pencil feature which allows you to hover over the screen
Speaker 21:  and get a little bit more precise actions with the pencil that's limited
Speaker 21:  to the M two For some reason it's not clear to me why that's limited to
Speaker 21:  the M two. They're not back boarding it to the M one pros. So if you bought
Speaker 21:  one last year, you don't get that feature. If you buy an air, you don't
Speaker 21:  get that feature. They are limiting it to the M two and it, it's just starting
Speaker 21:  to feel more and more like they are trying to find different things to
Speaker 21:  segregate these and, and segment them but that aren't really based on hardware
Speaker 21:  limitations. It's just more like we wanted to add this feature to the pro
Speaker 21:  model because it makes it more compelling as a pro device.
Speaker 2:  You know what this reminds me of is every other Apple device right now,
Speaker 2:  I mean we, we talked about this a few months ago with the MacBook error with
Speaker 2:  M two, which is like, it has a couple of upgrades but then it's also like
Speaker 2:  you can pretty easily land in a place where it's like, well the the M one
Speaker 2:  MacBook error is still a terrific computer that's still gonna last you a
Speaker 2:  long time with the iPhones. It's like, okay the, the iPhone 14 has some stuff
Speaker 2:  going for it, but it's not functionally all that different in your day-to-day
Speaker 2:  life than the iPhone 13. Like we're at this funny moment with a lot of Apple
Speaker 2:  products where it's like, especially with the M series, they got so good
Speaker 2:  so fast that it's like, I mean the jump from I, I still, I'm on a
Speaker 2:  I I just switched maybe six months ago from an Intel-based
Speaker 2:  MAC Mini to an M one Mac mini and like once a day I just
Speaker 2:  reach over and just touch it and the fan is not on and it's not hot and it
Speaker 2:  just makes me happy. Like still
Speaker 21:  With all of those examples that you gave, there are hardware differences,
Speaker 21:  right? So like the M one air and the M two air
Speaker 21:  run, all the same apps, all the same things, they've all the same core
Speaker 21:  features. The M two s difference is it has a bigger screen and a better
Speaker 21:  front facing camera and so like those are hardware differences where
Speaker 21:  we're seeing segregation in the iPad line is like, okay so it's got an M
Speaker 21:  two chip but like the feature difference doesn't feel like a hardware difference.
Speaker 21:  It feels much more like a software feature difference. And that's where
Speaker 21:  the weirdness is really kind of coming in to the iPad because like you said,
Speaker 21:  how much can they go on the hardware that they haven't gone already? It
Speaker 21:  is a slab alas that you hold in your hand. I really would like them to move
Speaker 21:  the camera on all of the models. Yes, weirdly the 10th gen iPad is the first
Speaker 21:  one to have the camera in the right spot. Okay. I assume they're gonna move
Speaker 21:  it on the rest of them eventually, but like beyond that like I don't know
Speaker 21:  what what further can they do with the hardware? So now it becomes a different
Speaker 21:  type of segmentation through the feature set and the software, which is
Speaker 21:  not the experience that you have on the Mac. The Mac you can run, if you
Speaker 21:  have an M one chip or an M two chip, you can run all the same apps. They
Speaker 21:  might run a little faster on the M two but it's all the same ones.
Speaker 2:  You're right. And I think it's gonna be interesting to see if this line gets
Speaker 2:  any smaller over time because part of me feels like Apple is now like deeply
Speaker 2:  invested in 50 different iPad product lines and this is all just gonna
Speaker 2:  keep getting weirder. Or as some people have theorized, like maybe this
Speaker 2:  is a sort of awkward in between moment for a lot of reasons, like the
Speaker 2:  chip shortage is real and the world is weird and we're in the middle of a
Speaker 2:  lot of like economic changes and all that stuff and that maybe whatever,
Speaker 2:  it'll be like the 2023 iPad, they'll, they'll just like blow it all up
Speaker 2:  and be like, look we have an iPad, it's called iPad.
Speaker 21:  Well yeah, I, I have a feeling like the 10th gen or whatever that
Speaker 21:  successor is will eventually get down to like the $350 price.
Speaker 21:  It will knock the, the old model out of contention and like it'll
Speaker 21:  disappear and then we'll have a much more like obvious type of
Speaker 21:  good better, best lineup in the iPads. You know, not counting the mini,
Speaker 21:  which is kinda a weird outlier, but like right now it is kind of a weird
Speaker 21:  transition. We have a weird transition where the 10th gen iPad has
Speaker 21:  some features that the pro iPad doesn't have that are better, like the better
Speaker 21:  camera placement, the the keyboard case is more flexible, gives you more
Speaker 21:  options, things like that has a function row, which the $350 keyboard
Speaker 21:  for the 12.9 inch iPad does not. So we're, we're in this weird
Speaker 21:  transition. It's interesting that Apple decided to roll it out when it did
Speaker 21:  instead of just waiting, but you know, that's what they do over time
Speaker 21:  I think it will smooth out. I can't imagine that they're gonna keep adding
Speaker 21:  more models to this lineup because I don't though I will say there's
Speaker 21:  long been rumored a 15 inch iPad some point down the road. So maybe that'll
Speaker 21:  show up at the top end and, and and we'll be like, oh man,
Speaker 2:  The iPad Promax will get a full hour of this podcast I
Speaker 22:  Promise. But yeah, that's sort of been my read on it too. It's like if the
Speaker 22:  iPad 10 appeals to you and like there, like we've been saying there are
Speaker 22:  reasons it might appeal to you, just like give it a little bit, it will
Speaker 22:  get down to around 3 29 ish and like, especially if you're buying
Speaker 22:  something for kids, I really don't think anyone should be spending more
Speaker 22:  than that.
Speaker 2:  I think that's right. So Monica, for you what is now the like default
Speaker 2:  iPad to compare stuff to? Somebody asks you the, I I want a laptop but
Speaker 2:  I don't wanna spend a thousand dollars on a MacBook and you're like, well
Speaker 2:  have you thought about an iPad? Which iPad is the one they have to think
Speaker 2:  about?
Speaker 22:  Oh well right now I, for me it's still the 3 29. Okay. I mean I as they're
Speaker 22:  still selling that so that's still the one that's gonna give me problems.
Speaker 22:  I mean I might now have to, you know, mention the 4 4 89 but the
Speaker 22:  3 29 1, as long as they're still selling it is still I think a problem for
Speaker 22:  people who are making budget laptops that are really bad.
Speaker 2:  That's fair. Yeah, you just need like a keyboard shortcut that just inserts
Speaker 2:  like four paragraphs explaining the iPad line into every review that you
Speaker 2:  do of a, of a Windows laptop. Alright, we should go. But thank you both.
Speaker 2:  This is, this is very helpful and I'm gonna go back to my iPad mini, which
Speaker 2:  I feel very good about buying and we'll never give up for any other iPad
Speaker 2:  no matter
Speaker 22:  What. That's an easy one. If you want a small one by that one.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, it's the best and it is. You trust me. Even if you don't know you want
Speaker 2:  a small iPad, you want a small iPad. All right, thank you both.
Speaker 2:  Thank
Speaker 22:  You.
Speaker 2:  All right, that's it for the Verge Cast today. Thank you so much for listening.
Speaker 2:  As always, there is tons more coverage on everything we talked about@theverge.com.
Speaker 2:  Monica wrote a great piece about the iPad in particular that you should definitely
Speaker 2:  read. We'll put that in the show notes and would have reviews of all the
Speaker 2:  new stuff. You can also follow us all on Twitter. Andrew is on
Speaker 2:  Merna, which sounds insane, but is actually just Andrew Marino backwards.
Speaker 2:  Dan is DC Seifert. Monica is mc squared
Speaker 2:  96 and I'm Pierce. This show is produced by Andrew Marino and and
Speaker 2:  Liam James Nore. Donovan is our executive producer and Brooke Mentors is
Speaker 2:  our editorial director of audio. The Vergecast is a Verge production and
Speaker 2:  part of the Vox Media podcast network. If you have thoughts, feedback, feelings,
Speaker 2:  or you want to draw me a map of how Sage Manager works, you can always email
Speaker 2:  vergecast@verge.com and if you have questions, call the hotline.
Speaker 2:  Eight sixty six Verge one one. Tell us all of your big thoughts and
Speaker 2:  questions and feelings about all things tech. Alex, Neil and I will be back
Speaker 2:  on Friday to discuss the new surface reviews, GPU's, watch bands, and a whole
Speaker 2:  bunch of other stuff. We'll see then. Rock and roll.
Speaker 23:  This episode was brought to you by brx, the corporate card and spend
Speaker 23:  management software teams actually love. No one likes doing
Speaker 23:  expenses. That's why Brx can help make life easy for those who
Speaker 23:  are tired of doing an expense for things as small as a coffee
Speaker 23:  to as large as a five star meal. Brx is an integrated
Speaker 23:  solution of corporate cards and spend management software that drives
Speaker 23:  100% compliance in zeroed chasing in over 100
Speaker 23:  countries, which means less time worrying about expense
Speaker 23:  reports and more time focusing on stuff that really matters.
Speaker 23:  Learn more at br.com/podcast.
Speaker 24:  Hey, it's Kenny Mae. I'm the host of Hey Ma. The Kenny Mae talks to
Speaker 24:  famous people, podcasts, season one's out there in universe. You can go
Speaker 24:  back in time, find anybody you want as long as I interviewed them.
Speaker 24:  Season two is coming up Thursday, October 13th. We got Keith
Speaker 24:  Overman and Dan Patrick together Again, Sue Bird is involved.
Speaker 24:  Rex Chapman, Dan LeVar, Katie Nolan, Allison
Speaker 24:  Becker. Sorry for all the others I interviewed who I left out. Oh yeah,
Speaker 24:  Solo Dad O'Brien. She was good. Get it on the Odyssey app or wherever you
Speaker 24:  get your podcast.