# Transcript
ID: 654aca70-512a-11ed-bea9-bb9b95efb175
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Confusing new Apple products, Netflix password sharing, and NFT cults
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/7716918394205722723/-1574518226015927429/s93290-US-5205s-1666347701.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, Alex Cranz, and Richard Lawler discuss the announcements from Apple this week, HDR video standards, and all the news out of Netflix and Tesla.
Apple launches redesigned iPad with a bigger screen and USB-C
Logitech updates Crayon stylus with the USB-C port missing from the Apple
The new Apple TV 4K has a remote with USB-C and a lower starting price
Apple’s new iPad only supports the old Apple Pencil–and need an adapter to do so
Apple’s Magic Keyboard Folio for the new iPad has a 14-key function row
The new iPad makes no sense
Apple announces new iPad Pro with M2 chip and Wi-Fi 6E
Netflix password-sharing crackdown will roll out globally in ‘early 2023’ – and here’s how it could work
Netflix announces Profile Transfers – for when it forces you to finally pay up
Netflix is all-in on binge-watching
Netflix is ‘seriously exploring’ a cloud gaming service
Can Netflix reclaim the ‘Netflix for games’ crown from Xbox Game Pass?
Elon Musk is “excited about the Twitter situation”
Tesla is “smoothing is vehicle process to avoid bottlenecks”
Elon Musk’s frisky earnings call touched on the Cybertruck, Twitter, and teh future of Tesla
Elon Musk says Starlink will keep funding Ukraine’s government ‘for free’ despite losing money
Help, Foxconn has gone from AI 8K+5G to ‘3+3=∞’
Google adds replies and stars to Messages — and is taking the RCS fight to iPhones
Lightroom is (finally) all I need for photo editing
I went all in on eSIM and I have regrets
The next generation of Thunderbolt seems nice but less necessary than ever
Adobe’s latest AI prototype gives even the worst dancers some impressive moves
GMC Sierra EV Denali revealed: plug-in-powered pickup goes premium
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we'd love to hear from you.
We are conducting a short audience survey to help plan for our future and hear from you. To participate, head to vox.com/podsurvey, and thank you!
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (6 ads detected)
Speaker 2:  Today on the Verge Cast, the crew tries to explain the weird products out
Speaker 2:  of Apple. This week we'll break down the news from Netflix and Tesla and
Speaker 2:  a lightning round that gets a little spicy that's coming up right after
Speaker 2:  this
Speaker 5:  Hello and welcome to our chest flagship podcast. I'm dongle
Speaker 5:  town. It's a lonely place, but we're all in it together.
Speaker 5:  That's really the experience of using modern technology. You're
Speaker 5:  alone in your house. The things aren't gonna plug into one another unless
Speaker 5:  you engineer a solution. But you know that you're connected to
Speaker 5:  millions of people worldwide who are going through the exact same frustrating
Speaker 5:  problem
Speaker 6:  Who all know what a dongle is.
Speaker 5:  Who all know what a dongle is? It's a real,
Speaker 5:  How do we end up here man?
Speaker 6:  I don't know man. I love a dongle though. I'm excited to talk about Dons
Speaker 7:  Mistakes were made, standards were organized, and standards
Speaker 7:  organizations are the
Speaker 5:  Problems. Oh my gosh. All right, well that voice you hear is
Speaker 5:  Richard Lawler. What's up Richard?
Speaker 7:  It's going on. Good to
Speaker 5:  Be back immediately joining the show with a spicy take. I love it
Speaker 5:  about standards organizations. That's how you know it's Avir has everybody.
Speaker 5:  Hell yes. Richard is here in place of David Pierce, who I believe
Speaker 5:  is in Texas.
Speaker 6:  What he went without
Speaker 5:  Me. I don't know. I just got a slack from him today and said I'm getting
Speaker 5:  on a flight in Texas. There was no shocking preview of this
Speaker 5:  slack. There was no follow up from this slack.
Speaker 6:  He's just the Texas now.
Speaker 5:  He's just in Texas now. It's big
Speaker 6:  State. It could be anywhere.
Speaker 7:  Everybody's getting into Formula One. That's that's what it
Speaker 5:  Is. So hopefully David comes back at some point.
Speaker 5:  I wish him well in Texas. I don't even know what part of Texas he's in. He
Speaker 5:  just said he was in Texas. But anyway, Richard's here. Alex Kranz is here.
Speaker 6:  Hello. I am very curious to know where in Texas David
Speaker 5:  Is. Well, if anyone in Texas sees David, let Alex know.
Speaker 6:  Let me know. Don't say hi to David. Just like be like, Hold on, I have to
Speaker 5:  Dm. Just take his picture on the street and send it to him.
Speaker 5:  It's surveillance. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  It's fine. That's, I've consented so it's okay.
Speaker 5:  It's not from above. It's from with it. It's surveillance. Yeah, right.
Speaker 5:  I'm your friend Eli. Welcome to Vergecast. There's a lot going on this week.
Speaker 5:  I was looking at the rundown before we started. Boy, this is gonna be a verge
Speaker 5:  cast. That's all I can say about this episode of the show. It's gonna be
Speaker 5:  one of the most a vergecast, a verge casts of all time. That's what I got
Speaker 5:  for you. We got new Apple stuff. Apple more committed to
Speaker 5:  dongles than ever. Yeah. I think Apple has decided to react to governments
Speaker 5:  around the world attempting to standardize ports by saying, Fine. Now
Speaker 5:  our shit will be more frustrating than you could possibly imagine. You
Speaker 6:  Want us to do it, we're gonna do it. And there'll be dongs. Hundreds of
Speaker 6:  dongs.
Speaker 5:  What combinations of magnets and Dons do you want
Speaker 5:  Europe? Cause you've never seen one like this. So there's a lot going on.
Speaker 5:  New iPads, new pet pro, new Apple tv, 4k, new
Speaker 5:  remote, new keyboard cases for these iPads,
Speaker 5:  the whole thing. Then Kanye West decided to buy
Speaker 5:  Parlor. Who knows why Netflix is really on password sharing.
Speaker 5:  Tesla had an earnings call. Foxconn did some Foxconn
Speaker 5:  stuff and Richard confidently told us before the show began that he's been
Speaker 5:  crypto pilled
Speaker 7:  And get everybody eventually.
Speaker 5:  Who knows what that means? I don't know. I don't
Speaker 5:  know if that's true. I think the future, I think that's a complicated reverse
Speaker 5:  troll. Richard Lawler, just a ton going on.
Speaker 5:  Let's start Obviously with Apple. I wanna say it's a weird
Speaker 5:  move, but Apple has done this before. They did not have an event. They just
Speaker 5:  issued a bunch of press releases and we were off we go.
Speaker 6:  They all, I mean they did do a video. You, you can go out and you can watch
Speaker 6:  a, like a 20 minute video and I guess if you like hunch
Speaker 6:  forward and watch it really closely, you'll feel like you're watching the
Speaker 6:  normal like stream.
Speaker 5:  I didn't watch this video. Did you watch this video?
Speaker 6:  I watched part of it and then I was like, I don't have to watch this video.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Cause I just go on the website and look at the stuff.
Speaker 6:  I got the press release. Yeah, I, I'm good, I'm ready to go. But they did
Speaker 6:  do a video this year.
Speaker 7:  We're practically in range of having the things in our hands. I I think I
Speaker 7:  can skip the video this time if I have the spec sheet. I'm good. I've seen
Speaker 7:  an iPad. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Right. So this is the, this is the the weird
Speaker 5:  zone all these companies are in. You can have the big event, maintain
Speaker 5:  all the surprise, show the stuff to us in person. We love that.
Speaker 5:  Right. I'll sit through a video in your theater just to see the stuff in
Speaker 5:  person right away. That's a fine trade. And, and obviously like talk to executives
Speaker 5:  on the people and take pictures. All the stuff. Yeah, I'll, I'll good trade.
Speaker 5:  Then there's what Apple has been doing, which is virtual events where we
Speaker 5:  all watch the video together short from the comfort of our homes.
Speaker 5:  And then we all look at the spec
Speaker 6:  Sheets, the hold hands in the metaverse. Then
Speaker 5:  There's this, which is what if you would just put out all the spec sheets
Speaker 5:  right away and then also make this video in case what you you wanted was
Speaker 5:  to watch a video at home. And I would say this is the least effective of
Speaker 5:  the approaches to the modern product announcement.
Speaker 6:  A hundred percent.
Speaker 5:  But please don't go back to making us all stream the video first. I think
Speaker 5:  just put out the press releases. So they put out all the press releases.
Speaker 5:  Like lot lots of stuff.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, a lot of stuff. It's like a shocking, I was,
Speaker 6:  I was expecting like an iPad.
Speaker 7:  There was real
Speaker 6:  Surprise that we got two iPads. We got the Apple tv,
Speaker 7:  A lot of their events recently. I feel like we haven't had the surprise come
Speaker 7:  in. Yeah. But this time I, I was, I was actually shocked by some of the things.
Speaker 7:  It was good to have that back.
Speaker 5:  What were you shocked by? What shocked you the best?
Speaker 7:  I didn't see a new Apple TV coming this week or two
Speaker 7:  New. That's, that's double. Okay. It's, it's not Okay.
Speaker 7:  It's, it's a new processor. Apple tv. It has a new, changed everything
Speaker 7:  from a newer iPhone. It is still the same. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  So yeah, the Apple TV is basically still the same. It has a 15 now
Speaker 5:  they've removed the fan, which most people did not even know the Apple TV
Speaker 5:  had a fan. But more recent Apple TVs have gigantic slow
Speaker 5:  fans in them now they don't have a fan. Here's the weird part about the app.
Speaker 5:  Well two weird things about these Apple TVs. This is what shocked me. One,
Speaker 5:  it's still expensive. They lowered the price to 1 29 for the base model
Speaker 5:  but it's still incredibly expensive. Like Rokus are
Speaker 5:  more or less free.
Speaker 6:  They, they Frisbee them to you when you walk into Walmart. Amazon is
Speaker 6:  just like automatically shipping them. You just sneeze in Amazon's
Speaker 5:  Direction. If you have Amazon Prime, you can get a fired TV stick for
Speaker 5:  nothing. Apple's at 1 29. So lower the price at 1 29. But that
Speaker 5:  1 29 model is really weird, right? It has it,
Speaker 5:  it's 64 gigs of storage. No ethernet.
Speaker 5:  So it's like, it's just a weird, it's like a more expensive cheap thing.
Speaker 6:  No fan.
Speaker 5:  No fan. They put an A 15 ship in it. People don't even know that. The old
Speaker 5:  Apple TV four case had fans and big slow fan at bottom and some meds. Now
Speaker 5:  they don't. Whatever. So that's 1 29 64 gig of storage wifi
Speaker 5:  only. Who is that for? Because for $20 more
Speaker 5:  you get double the storage. You get an ethernet port, which
Speaker 5:  if you are actually serious about streaming forecast, you probably want this
Speaker 5:  thing near some sort of hardwired connection. And then you get a
Speaker 5:  thread radio so you can support matter and have it be your home home. This
Speaker 5:  is like the easiest $20 you should spend. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  I
Speaker 5:  Like the most future proof $20 that you can have in your home.
Speaker 6:  I keep wondering why they didn't drop the price of the base model. One more.
Speaker 6:  Like if that had been a hundred dollars, $50 difference. I would,
Speaker 6:  I would still be, I would be here saying this is an outrageous price difference.
Speaker 6:  How dare they. But also it would make like more business sense for
Speaker 6:  Apple cuz they'd be pushing
Speaker 7:  It. It feels like they Motorola Oh yeah. Where it exists to go
Speaker 7:  on sale for $99. But like they don't
Speaker 7:  expect you to buy it for 1 29. They're just, they're gonna put it on sale
Speaker 7:  and they're gonna say, Hey man, we give you a discount.
Speaker 6:  This is the Ted lasso discount. You gotta watch season $300.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. If you sign up for Apple tv, you get one of these for for free, right?
Speaker 5:  Like or for in Bucks. Okay, maybe I'm still saying that 1 49 model,
Speaker 5:  you're you're gonna spend this much money in streaming box and you're not
Speaker 5:  getting an Nvidia Shield from My Shield people out there, of which Alex is
Speaker 5:  one. Definitely.
Speaker 6:  It's still the best
Speaker 5:  One. Yes. Super. Not the best.
Speaker 6:  Cause it it it, because you can do pass through, you can do audio pass through
Speaker 6:  to your receiver, which the Apple converts. The Apple
Speaker 6:  TV converts the audio. And so if you're really serious about your
Speaker 6:  home theater audio. That's true. That's the only reason to get the shield.
Speaker 6:  I like, I love them both. I still get the, I still use the Apple TV because
Speaker 6:  I also use a Sotos bar. I don't care about pass through.
Speaker 8:  It's truly the only way to, to do plex.
Speaker 5:  Oh my god. That's not
Speaker 8:  True the right way.
Speaker 5:  And and did you know it can gently warm your weed for you while you run
Speaker 5:  flexible? Yeah,
Speaker 6:  It could do everything. It's a magical device.
Speaker 5:  Anyhow. See I believe its good. It's really expensive.
Speaker 5:  I, I like it but you should just spend the money for the really good
Speaker 5:  one because it's $20. So
Speaker 6:  Like
Speaker 5:  It's just a bizarre situation.
Speaker 6:  It's super weird. And also the storage, I keep coming back to
Speaker 6:  like why do I need so much storage on my Apple tv? I can
Speaker 6:  understand like Ram, you know, and I could understand like wanting to load
Speaker 6:  up more of the movie or whatever that you're streaming so it can serve directly.
Speaker 6:  So it's not like I get that but
Speaker 5:  It's games people, Some people put games on Apple tv. That's what I got for
Speaker 5:  you. It's
Speaker 6:  How many, if
Speaker 7:  If you did gaming on Apple TV then I guess it would matter. I just think
Speaker 7:  it's so strange that now it supports both Doby vision and HDR 10 plus.
Speaker 7:  I can't, I can't think of exactly how many devices have
Speaker 5:  That. Oh this is the Samsung. The
Speaker 7:  Samsung hdr,
Speaker 6:  Samsung H
Speaker 7:  Hs, Doby vision. Usually you have to choose. Yeah there there are a few
Speaker 6:  But HS has HDR 10.
Speaker 5:  Well so if you just, if you just look at it So boy talk
Speaker 5:  about standard bodies Richard. This is why standards bodies should be abolished.
Speaker 5:  I should be in charge just the feudal lord of all
Speaker 5:  tech standards. Ne I Patel vote Patel but really in sort of a dictator
Speaker 5:  way
Speaker 6:  It's a great glow up.
Speaker 5:  So Adobe Vision is a standard. Apple supported huge fanfare. Apple's
Speaker 5:  one of the biggest supporters of Adobe Vision. They put in the Apple tv.
Speaker 5:  The iPhone supports it. Max support it. Apple loves Adobe vision.
Speaker 5:  You can record Adobe Vision on an iPhone. Samsung has never supported
Speaker 5:  Adobe Vision. Yeah it's always supported HDR 10 and then HDR 10 plus
Speaker 5:  the difference between HDR 10 and HDR 10 plus is effectively
Speaker 5:  the difference between Adobe Vision HDR 10. So
Speaker 5:  HDR 10 has the same wider dynamic range. Bright,
Speaker 5:  bright things get brighter, things get darker. Is Adobe vision same
Speaker 5:  wider color gamut? To a certain extent Adobe Vision has
Speaker 5:  dynamic metadata so it moves the dynamic
Speaker 5:  range along with the scene. That's how the compression works. HDR 10 is
Speaker 5:  fixed 10 plus metadata. Now you can
Speaker 5:  argue about the fine dis distinctions between all of
Speaker 5:  these things. I think Adobe vision looks better than HCR 10 plus other people
Speaker 5:  can't see it. Whatever. But now the technology is the same. Samsung just
Speaker 5:  refused to support Adobe Vision, any of its TVs. They were totally committed
Speaker 5:  HDR 10 plus as was Amazon
Speaker 6:  Because they didn't wanna pay because Doby vision you have to pay
Speaker 6:  to like use their product. You have to pay to like master all of your stuff.
Speaker 6:  Like you have to go through a process with Doby vision and HDR 10
Speaker 6:  plus they can just be like oh bam, that's HDR 10 plus baby
Speaker 6:  enjoy
Speaker 5:  There. And there's like just weird mafia level licensing
Speaker 5:  shenanigans in the background of all this whatever. But Samsung sells a lot
Speaker 5:  of TVs so at some point it was just who was gonna blink
Speaker 5:  first? Was the industry gonna just support HCR 10 plus cuz it's on all the
Speaker 5:  Samsung TVs or Samsung gonna be like screw it, we're paying the money and
Speaker 5:  we're gonna support Adobe vision. Cause all the services are on Adobe vision
Speaker 5:  and it looks like Samsung won like just, they just flatly won
Speaker 5:  And now Apple, the biggest booster of Adobe vision is shipping HDR 10 plus
Speaker 5:  in the Apple tv.
Speaker 6:  I don't know if they won because they still have to get like all of the
Speaker 6:  different people making content have to start mastering in HDR 10
Speaker 6:  plus. And most a lot of them are still mastering in
Speaker 6:  Doy vision in HDR 10. They're not doing that. That metadata.
Speaker 7:  They do have like Netflix and Amazon had at least some
Speaker 7:  HDR 10 plus stuff I believe. Or at least I know Amazon did. I can't remember.
Speaker 7:  Netflix
Speaker 6:  Was actually TV is now gonna be doing some, like everybody is slowly
Speaker 6:  kind of doing it but they're all irritated cuz they still have to like go,
Speaker 6:  okay now they have to do an HDR 10 master. Now they have to do an HDR 10
Speaker 6:  plus master and Adobe Vision Master.
Speaker 5:  But I think if you get the HDR 10 plus master, it's easier to go.
Speaker 5:  It's easier to go fall back to H Tier 10 for sure. It might
Speaker 5:  be easier to go back and forth between Adobe Vision. I just, this is what
Speaker 5:  I said, I told you'd be the ver caste vercast of all time, but
Speaker 6:  It'll be ugly. Here you go. It won't be as pretty as Doby vision.
Speaker 7:  How many profiles of Doby Vision does your TV support? Let's get into it.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, we'll see, I mean I'm, I'm dying to see Apple never really
Speaker 5:  figured out this big plan. They had to run everything
Speaker 5:  in Adobe vision including the user interface and then dynamically
Speaker 5:  remap into SDR and now potentially in
Speaker 5:  HCR 10 plus because that's what Amazon's app supports. That was
Speaker 5:  what the Apple TV shipped with this. Yeah. Where the whole thing
Speaker 5:  permanently ran in Adobe Vision and they would dynamically
Speaker 5:  remap content. It's just like didn't work. So that's where you get match
Speaker 5:  content and frame rate and that's how you should run your Apple tv. Now you
Speaker 5:  can now that now there's another thing to switch to. So we'll see if they
Speaker 5:  can get to a place which is where everybody wants to be, where you're doing
Speaker 5:  this seamlessly without blinking the TV to black.
Speaker 6:  I do wonder though, Apple's always had kind of an issue with the hand shaking
Speaker 6:  on Doby vision and like it's this thing called edited and
Speaker 6:  it's basically when your your set top box handshakes with
Speaker 6:  your TV and says this is the kind of signal I'm gonna send. Apple can sometimes
Speaker 6:  be really wonky about that. And you have to very specifically set up your
Speaker 6:  Apple TV to get the handshake right. To get it in Doby vision. And I
Speaker 6:  wonder if like we're gonna see some weird HHA issues with these new ones
Speaker 6:  where it's like HDR 10 HDR Doby vision. Who
Speaker 6:  knows? Yeah. Because that's been like a big frustration
Speaker 6:  for new Apple TV users
Speaker 5:  When they roll out new TVs and new versions of the H G M I standard. Every
Speaker 5:  year they have plug parties. Usually you'll listen to the HTM I
Speaker 5:  spectacular episode of the VER Chance. They talk about this. All the manufacturers
Speaker 5:  show up, all their engineers show up with all their stuff and they just plug
Speaker 5:  things into one another. It's great to make sure it all works. I've always
Speaker 5:  wanted to go to one
Speaker 6:  But it almost never does.
Speaker 5:  Well that's why
Speaker 6:  They, the eat it is like really like Apple's kind of notorious for having
Speaker 6:  one of the best ed like that handshake. But it's also still
Speaker 6:  kind of like wonky. Everybody's kind of crummy at it. It's great.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I love it.
Speaker 5:  All right, well if you are attending an HG m I plug party, let me
Speaker 5:  know May I'll just come with you. Yeah, I'll just pretend I work at your
Speaker 5:  company.
Speaker 6:  You'll be your their
Speaker 5:  Plus one at the HT I plug party. So
Speaker 7:  We're gonna talk about this thing for 10 minutes and not talk about the most
Speaker 7:  important development.
Speaker 5:  All right,
Speaker 7:  Go ahead. The remote has usbc now I'm
Speaker 5:  Just worried. I'm like, I'm like you can't feel it. There's an anxiety building.
Speaker 5:  I'm not. It doesn't crypto
Speaker 6:  Richard, go ahead. Why? What's
Speaker 7:  Exciting? The remote has USBC now it doesn't have
Speaker 5:  Like talk about your plug parties. So
Speaker 5:  this is the year where
Speaker 5:  Apple's bullshit about USBC is catching up to it. Yeah, it is
Speaker 5:  fully the year. Like all of these devices are
Speaker 5:  all over the place because Apple didn't just go with the standard
Speaker 5:  and they shipped lightning all over the place. So the Apple TV remote for
Speaker 5:  years has been a lightning. I'll tell you you don't have to charge it very
Speaker 5:  often. It's like every six months.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I've been charged mine in like a year.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So then, and this year with the update, now it's usbc, this is fine.
Speaker 5:  People probably have USBC connectors in their homes. Now
Speaker 5:  Europe has mandated USBC for new devices.
Speaker 6:  Apparently they don't include a USBC cable, but
Speaker 5:  There's no cable in the box. And this is what I mean
Speaker 7:  Unless, unless you live in Brazil, then you can get a USBC cable in the box
Speaker 5:  Because the Brazilian government is like, what are you doing? You have to
Speaker 5:  put cables in the box. This is what I mean like apples just like got its
Speaker 5:  middle finger in there. It's like you want usbc, it'll be the most annoying,
Speaker 5:  most difficult implementation of this possible. So no cables in the
Speaker 5:  box. It's different than all your other stuff. We didn't do the phones this
Speaker 5:  year. Whatever.
Speaker 6:  Wait Richard, I dunno man. Does the box have like a different layout?
Speaker 6:  Like how do they fit the cable in there? They don't know. Like does it just
Speaker 6:  come taped on the side with a big middle finger?
Speaker 7:  I, I think people figured this out by looking at the website spec sheets.
Speaker 7:  So I don't know if anyone's actually seen the packaging yet.
Speaker 6:  Somebody sent Richard, not me a photo but
Speaker 7:  I I bet there's just an empty slot in every other global
Speaker 7:  release and you're like, Huh, what's
Speaker 6:  That for? That's for the Brazilians.
Speaker 5:  All right. So that, but the Apple TV going to USBC is kinda
Speaker 5:  like neither here nor there, right? Like yeah it's remote, you plug it in
Speaker 5:  once a year, you probably one of these cables in your house. So be it. Unless
Speaker 5:  you're like deeply in the Apple ecosystem and all you have is
Speaker 5:  lightning
Speaker 6:  And like one micro USB cable, you're just like,
Speaker 6:  no, have fun going
Speaker 5:  To micro. It's very funny. There's no way to charge this thing unless you
Speaker 5:  have USBC already in your house. Like you just get it and your remote doesn't
Speaker 5:  work and you're screwed. So it goes, that one's fine. It's the iPad. So
Speaker 5:  wait, that's so that's the The Apple tv. Yeah. Right. The, It's surprising
Speaker 5:  how the prices work. It's surprising that Apple caved on
Speaker 5:  HDR 10 plus. It's a little surprising on usbc but like whatever.
Speaker 6:  It's a surprising they announced it. We were It's surprising it. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  If anyone thought we weren't gonna start with the Apple tv, I don't know
Speaker 5:  what show you thought you were listening to. Of course we like deep in the
Speaker 5:  Adobe vision profiles. It's the VER cast. Right? Then there was the stuff
Speaker 5:  we were expecting, which was new iPads and I think we were
Speaker 5:  all expecting the new iPad Pro, which we can get through very quickly I think.
Speaker 5:  But we should come back to, because it's also caught up in this USBC noise.
Speaker 5:  So the new iPad has an M two chip has wifi six E, which is Apple's first
Speaker 5:  wifi six E device. It's a great, unless you
Speaker 6:  It's wonderful.
Speaker 5:  Use more wifi channels in your home if you have wifi six e router, which
Speaker 5:  I just bought. I pro six s. They're great. Super
Speaker 5:  stupid expensive. And I only bought them because I
Speaker 5:  podcast from home twice a week.
Speaker 6:  You look wonderful today. I was, I was thinking there was something a little
Speaker 6:  different about you today and it's
Speaker 5:  Easy. An extra 50 megahertz of bandwidth on
Speaker 6:  The
Speaker 5:  Hell. Yeah, that's, I don't know what that is. It's the sun's low in the
Speaker 5:  sky.
Speaker 6:  It's a 50 megahertz difference.
Speaker 5:  It's a 50 megahertz, not bandwidth of spectrum. That's what I'm doing.
Speaker 5:  It's, yeah, I'm not even doing that. There's IMAX from 2015. This thing is
Speaker 5:  probably on 2.4 gigahertz. I just have routers that don't crash in two minutes.
Speaker 5:  That's, I bought new ones. That's all that happened. Anyway, so the iPad
Speaker 5:  Pro has M two wifi 60, otherwise same design, same
Speaker 5:  features,
Speaker 6:  Same displays.
Speaker 5:  Yep. Same Boulder rolling down the hill of stage manager when
Speaker 5:  iPad OS 16 comes out. Same, Same displays, right?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Lc displays no changes. Just
Speaker 6:  Display the micro L e D display in the the iPad. The
Speaker 6:  12 inch.
Speaker 5:  Yep.
Speaker 6:  That I remember Chris Welch wasn't a great fan of last year. He thought
Speaker 6:  there was like some weird roll off for
Speaker 5:  The light. There's living with those in weird ways. Yeah. But I've always
Speaker 5:  liked them. It's weird but the 11 does not get micro. That's
Speaker 6:  What I was holding out for. I was so excited for an 11 inch with Micro and
Speaker 6:  I was like, oh well I won't spend way too much money on an iPad
Speaker 6:  Pro I don't need now. It's a whole reason.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Take that Tim Apple.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I really
Speaker 5:  Showed him Instead I'll be buying Dons from you at $29 a
Speaker 5:  pop. Okay, so that's say I've had pro but
Speaker 5:  then there's a new iPad, right? Which is totally redesigned.
Speaker 5:  Bigger screen. Us bbc, the camera has been moved so
Speaker 5:  it's at the top in landscape, new keyboard cover, old pencil.
Speaker 6:  But it was redesigned. The weirdest pencil.
Speaker 6:  Like everything about this kind of shocked me. One, I didn't expect a total
Speaker 6:  new redesign because normally we, that's like, like Apple for these
Speaker 6:  press releases is usually like here's a little, the M two and the iPad Pro
Speaker 6:  go. And I'm like okay, I get that. I don't need to see that in person. This
Speaker 6:  is a whole new device. So I was expecting like I would've expected a lot
Speaker 6:  of big things. Yeah. But then I think about that pencil and I
Speaker 6:  think about like all of the pictures in the apple in the jobs
Speaker 6:  theater of people playing with that dongle and that pencil.
Speaker 5:  Beautiful pencil. Oh
Speaker 6:  My god. Of course. Yeah. Yeah. Okay. I get it. I get why you couldn't do
Speaker 6:  an event for
Speaker 5:  This guy. You just wanna hide the pencil from people. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  Don't
Speaker 5:  Look, this device is full of compromises. So a
Speaker 5:  10.9 inch display new, the new flatter edges to the same kind
Speaker 5:  of dis same kind of design language. They had air and the pro, they
Speaker 5:  updated the cameras. Like I said, they moved the front camera to landscape
Speaker 5:  wifi six. So Apple's finally like adopting wifi six across its
Speaker 5:  line touch id in a power button. I complained about this
Speaker 5:  on Twitter and people were like, you know ly mad at me. Apple keeps
Speaker 5:  saying this is an all screen design.
Speaker 6:  It's got a bezzle
Speaker 5:  Dude, the bes on this thing are like, go watch the video. This is a reason
Speaker 5:  you should watch the video. Like, cause they show the thing a lot and you're
Speaker 5:  like, oh those bezels are huge. Like you could, like,
Speaker 6:  You could
Speaker 5:  Live in that. And I understand that they're not calling it edge to edge now
Speaker 5:  they're saying it's all screen. What is the difference between all screen
Speaker 5:  and edge to edge display? Those things mean the same thing.
Speaker 7:  This has HP touch pad bezels.
Speaker 5:  Well, okay, just close your eyes. Pull over in your car, close your eyes.
Speaker 5:  Imagine this. Let's just go through this exercise. Okay,
Speaker 5:  imagine the bezels were 10 times
Speaker 5:  thicker. So it was like a little tiny display in lots of
Speaker 5:  bezels, right? But otherwise the same. Would you call
Speaker 5:  that an all screen display or an all screen design?
Speaker 6:  I, I mean I would if I worked at Apple,
Speaker 5:  Right? I'm saying, but people are like, I'm like this is not all screen.
Speaker 5:  And people are like, yeah it is. There's nothing else with screen. Okay.
Speaker 5:  Just like push it out. Imagine the screen was four
Speaker 5:  inches but it was the same size case and there was just that much bezzle
Speaker 5:  around it. And I was like, this is an all screen design. Would you agree
Speaker 5:  with me? I mean no you wouldn't cuz you're not bonkers.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, no.
Speaker 5:  Cause words have meanings. Now imagine the screen, there's no
Speaker 5:  bezel. And I was like, this is an all screen design. Would you agree? Yes,
Speaker 5:  of course you would. Yeah. So there's at some point between
Speaker 5:  filling to the edges in a little postage stamp with five inch
Speaker 5:  bezels where you can no longer get to say it's all screen
Speaker 5:  somewhere in
Speaker 6:  The middle. And this is where you, you, you are at the point right now where
Speaker 6:  you're like, this is not all screen. Richard are, this is not all screen.
Speaker 6:  Do you feel it's all screen?
Speaker 7:  You gotta hear both sides. You gotta hear both sides. You gotta hear both
Speaker 7:  sides. The screen is all screen,
Speaker 7:  right.
Speaker 5:  I agree that the screen is all screen,
Speaker 7:  The screen is nothing but screen. There's nothing but screen where the screen
Speaker 7:  is. There's no notch, there's no porthole. Little for the front facing
Speaker 7:  camera, nothing like that. It's just screen. That's all. It's all screen.
Speaker 5:  Okay, so you're saying it's what you mean by it's an all screen screen
Speaker 5:  design. Yes.
Speaker 7:  Got
Speaker 5:  It. Yes. By the way, even the thing is an all screen cuz there's a camera
Speaker 5:  there like definitionally, it's
Speaker 5:  an all screen end camera design. Ah,
Speaker 5:  right. So that's the I that they've added USBC data. But
Speaker 5:  because they went with the old pencil, the old pencil charges with lightning
Speaker 5:  in a famous Johnny Ive design decision, you charge the old
Speaker 5:  pencil by plugging it into the lightning port of the old iPad.
Speaker 6:  It's
Speaker 5:  Beautiful. But now, so now what you do is you plug a
Speaker 5:  USBC cable into the, your new iPad and then you plug a
Speaker 5:  $9 dongle, which is female usbc. So you
Speaker 5:  plug your cable into that and then female lightning. So you plug your lightning
Speaker 5:  pencil into the other end. And my god man,
Speaker 6:  I, so I actually like the dongle.
Speaker 5:  Okay.
Speaker 6:  I'm, I'm sorry. I like, I don't like the dongle in that. I want to
Speaker 6:  own one. But I like that they were like, okay, we only
Speaker 6:  wanna use the old pencil. Why? Well so now we've gotta plug it in
Speaker 6:  and we wanna go
Speaker 5:  Usbc. They make a new, they've made it for years, but
Speaker 6:  It'll be charged by magnets. And they're like, we can't do the magnets cuz
Speaker 6:  cuz it's gonna mess with like the camera or something. And so we can't, no
Speaker 6:  magnets. So we gotta use the old pencil that has the goofiest way of charge
Speaker 6:  and we gotta plug it in. But we can't just sell somebody a cord
Speaker 6:  cuz they would've sold you a cable. They wouldn't have included a cable.
Speaker 6:  They would sell you a cable that's female lightning on one
Speaker 6:  side and USBC on the other and like that's a terrible
Speaker 6:  cord. You can never use that again. And now you just like, you got your little
Speaker 6:  dongle and you plug it into your USBC cable and you're good to go.
Speaker 5:  My theory is when Apple rolled out this Apple pencil years ago,
Speaker 5:  they were like, people are gonna love this thing. And they made like 10
Speaker 5:  million of them. Yeah. They were riding high. Maybe Tim Cook
Speaker 5:  pressed the zero on his number pad one too many times.
Speaker 5:  He just made too many of 'em. And they're all in warehouse. They're like,
Speaker 5:  you know what, we're just gonna get rid of them over time. But they could
Speaker 5:  just
Speaker 7:  Keep you one. I'm, I'm going to absolutely purloin to take from news reporter.
Speaker 7:  I'm a Shakira who pointed out that one, one explanation
Speaker 7:  and I think it holds some weight, is that a lot of schools have have iPads,
Speaker 7:  the base model iPad that we're talking about. And they have a lot of those
Speaker 7:  pencils already. So making it work with the old pencil, they don't have
Speaker 7:  to replace the pencils.
Speaker 5:  Why can't you support both things?
Speaker 7:  Amen. Technology's
Speaker 6:  Well, they're already gonna be all of those. They're gonna want all of those
Speaker 6:  schools to go and update to the new iPad, which is now what,
Speaker 6:  $150 more. A hundred dollars more.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So we gotta talk about the pricing because it, this thing is really
Speaker 5:  expensive.
Speaker 6:  Really expensive
Speaker 5:  For, for what? It's, so it's 4 49 for the 64 gig model. The old
Speaker 5:  version started 3 29. The three 20 iPad was like this
Speaker 5:  close. I don't think it was an impulse buy, it was still too expensive for
Speaker 5:  that. But it was like teetering on the edge.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it
Speaker 5:  Had like had 2 52 99 is like, I'm gonna buy this my kid that can break it.
Speaker 5:  Right. 3 29 right on the other side, frequently discounted. Right? You could
Speaker 5:  buy a resource when you buy used one or whatever. 4 49 is no longer in that
Speaker 5:  territory. That's
Speaker 6:  Just a hundred dollars less than an iPad Air.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, it's it's weird. It's weird. And then the keyboard is another
Speaker 5:  $250. We should talk about this keyboard. They, it's what's it called? The
Speaker 5:  magic smart Folio. Yep.
Speaker 6:  Magic or the 10.9 inch iPad, like
Speaker 6:  the,
Speaker 5:  It's magic keyboard for the, the 10.9 inch iPad. It's got a
Speaker 5:  track pad, it's got buttons, it's got function keys.
Speaker 6:  Oh
Speaker 5:  I love that. Which is another really interesting addition from Apple to the
Speaker 5:  iPad line, this thing. And it's got a kickstand so it
Speaker 5:  effectively turns the new iPad into a surface, you know, and there's,
Speaker 5:  there's an arm surface, but
Speaker 6:  Only this cheapest iPad has the function
Speaker 6:  keys.
Speaker 5:  Right. So the iPad Pro still has the same keyboard
Speaker 5:  case with no function keys and no kicks stick. I can't defend that one.
Speaker 6:  I believe you mean the magic keyboard folio for 12.9 inch iPad Pro.
Speaker 6:  We have to use the right names.
Speaker 5:  Oh my god. I dunno. There's
Speaker 5:  something here where Apple is just caught in the middle. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  right. They didn't update the new iPad. If they had
Speaker 5:  just moved the camera to the side and added function keys to the
Speaker 5:  keyboard would've made a little sense. They didn't do any of that to that
Speaker 5:  iPad. They just bumped the processor. This iPad's like a
Speaker 5:  substantial redesign. It is clearly designed to be used in
Speaker 5:  a laptop mode, right Landscape, front facing camera keyboard
Speaker 5:  case with function keys. A surface like Kickout
Speaker 5:  design, slightly more expensive. This is the
Speaker 5:  iPad is the low end laptop replacement. This is the iPad that goes up against
Speaker 5:  the 500, 600, $700 cheap Windows pc High end Crow
Speaker 5:  book I guess. Yeah. It's weird. It's a weird product but
Speaker 6:  It's $700
Speaker 5:  And they're keeping the 3 29 model in the lineup. It's not going away like
Speaker 5:  it usually does. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  No, I thought Monica did a wonderful story this week,
Speaker 6:  just like trying to wrap her head around why this thing exists
Speaker 6:  and pointed out that okay, if you get it, you have to get the key like, and
Speaker 6:  you wanna use it as a laptop, you have to go get the keyboard. So now you're
Speaker 6:  spending two, $700 so now you're spending $700 on this
Speaker 6:  thing. And for that you can get a really nice Windows
Speaker 6:  machine that does all the things and isn't like the iPad os,
Speaker 6:  which we all enjoy. But also it is not a laptop
Speaker 6:  os
Speaker 5:  I will say Monica put a line in this piece, which is very good.
Speaker 5:  It's called the new iPad. Makes no sense. You'll read it but in the middle
Speaker 5:  of she's like, it's not a computer. I don't care what you say. And I was
Speaker 5:  like, wow. Strong words for ver.com.
Speaker 5:  The website founded on the notion that we should just argue about what words
Speaker 5:  mean for the rest of our lives. But I get what she's saying.
Speaker 6:  Monica was like, no line in the sand.
Speaker 5:  She was like, it's not a computer. Our laptop reviewer was like, this garbage
Speaker 5:  isn't a computer but they're obviously trying to get it to compete.
Speaker 5:  She's she's earned, she's earned the take. She's earned the take. She's she's
Speaker 5:  earned the take. But it's weird right? Because the surface, the arm
Speaker 5:  surface is this form factor. Exactly. This is Microsofts form factor.
Speaker 5:  And the arm surface is also limited in what apps can run. Right. Because
Speaker 5:  Windows on arm, we'll see what it's bad life is like, but this new iPad
Speaker 5:  is more of a head up competitor to the surface than ever before. It's just,
Speaker 5:  it's cheaper but then they can't do as much cuz it's iPad os it can't run.
Speaker 5:  This one can't run stage manager. Cause it's not an iPad Pro. Just a
Speaker 5:  weird product all the way around. Like, I'm not sure what Apple is doing,
Speaker 5:  doing. I'm not sure why they went USBC on this one and then didn't do the
Speaker 5:  first
Speaker 6:  I forgot about the piles. I'm sorry, I forgot that. It doesn't do the piles.
Speaker 5:  It doesn't do piles.
Speaker 6:  No piles.
Speaker 5:  One thing I'll say log check updated it's crayon, which is also what's
Speaker 5:  what schools by USBC port. You just plug USBC cable right
Speaker 5:  into this thing. That's
Speaker 6:  The way to do it
Speaker 5:  Out done. But
Speaker 6:  Maybe they can just break off that lightning part of it. Snap it
Speaker 6:  off.
Speaker 5:  I don't get it man. And here's, there's somebody who has given a ninth
Speaker 5:  gen iPad to a child. Actually not having a home button is
Speaker 5:  gonna be is weird. It's gonna be weird for a lot of people.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  So we'll see. We got a whole episode whenever David comes back
Speaker 5:  from wherever he is in Texas, he's gonna do a whole Wednesday episode on
Speaker 5:  the iPad. How to even pick one. David has more feelings about stage manager
Speaker 5:  than anybody.
Speaker 6:  The most
Speaker 5:  Feelings today before he DMed me about being in Texas, he,
Speaker 5:  he had dug up a story that I had written for End Gadget in like
Speaker 5:  2008 where Steve Jobs was talking about task managers and
Speaker 5:  what they represent to people. I was like, I don't remember writing this.
Speaker 5:  David's like, I found it. I'm like, God. So that's coming Wednesday very
Speaker 5:  good. But yeah, just a weird set of products
Speaker 5:  from Apple and this USBC moment for Apple is coming
Speaker 5:  and it just feels like the company hasn't grabbed onto
Speaker 5:  it yet. You know what I mean? Like it, it didn't go all the
Speaker 5:  way. It seems like it's fighting. It is like what I would say.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I don't think Apple wants to do usbc. I think this is
Speaker 6:  shocking. But they're,
Speaker 7:  They're being dragged through the door kicking and screaming and flowing
Speaker 7:  into the floor.
Speaker 6:  I don't think they wanna do it.
Speaker 5:  I want to be clear about this. Apple invented usbc. The
Speaker 5:  standard exists because Apple wanted it to exist for that 12 inch
Speaker 5:  MacBook. They were so proud of it when that MacBook came out and now they're
Speaker 5:  like, How dare you force us to use the standard that we
Speaker 5:  invented.
Speaker 6:  Sometimes your children portray you and this is one of those moments. I'm
Speaker 6:  sorry Tim Apple. Let's roll
Speaker 5:  That. All right, we gotta take a break. Told you. This is ver Cassie vs.
Speaker 5:  We'll be right
Speaker 5:  back.
Speaker 5:  Okay, we're back. Lots of other news this week. So Netflix had a
Speaker 5:  bunch of news. They had earnings, Tesla had earnings. Elon Musk said
Speaker 5:  he was never gonna be on an earnings hall again. Guess what? He was
Speaker 5:  on this earnings hall, talked a bunch, both started Netflix. Richard walks
Speaker 7:  Through it. Netflix has had an interesting pandemic.
Speaker 7:  They, when everyone came home, suddenly
Speaker 7:  everyone subscribed to Netflix and their subscriber numbers exploded
Speaker 7:  way beyond their projections. Just really, they kind of gobbled up
Speaker 7:  what they expected the next few years to take within the next few months.
Speaker 7:  And the downside of that has been that as the pandemic
Speaker 7:  has has kind of progressed and we've, we're now years removed, they aren't
Speaker 7:  growing anymore. They already added all the customers. They can't find
Speaker 7:  more people to sign up for Netflix. People are leaving Netflix because there
Speaker 7:  are other streaming services. Other Stu, the Hollywood studios and the big
Speaker 7:  companies have gotten into streaming and they're spending a lot of money
Speaker 7:  to do it. And earlier this year, Netflix lost customers for the first time
Speaker 7:  in 10 years. So they came out with their earnings report this week and we
Speaker 7:  finally got news that the password sharing crackdown that they have talked
Speaker 7:  about to try and turn around and reverse this trend will roll out globally
Speaker 7:  in 2023. They've been using it in a few Latin American countries. Whether
Speaker 7:  or not people like it depends on who you ask. If you ask Netflix, everyone
Speaker 7:  loves it and it's great if you ask people in those countries, they say
Speaker 7:  it's confusing and they don't like it. So
Speaker 5:  It's weird cause Netflix has to frame, this is like a
Speaker 5:  feature addition. They can't frame it as, Hey,
Speaker 5:  we've noticed you've been stealing for a number of years. Right? They can't
Speaker 5:  come at it that way. They've gotta be like, Hey, you're sharing your account,
Speaker 5:  we love it. Would you like to pay some more money to keep doing it? And I
Speaker 5:  I I just don't think that makes sense to anybody. Like, I think most people
Speaker 5:  like intuitively understand that they're being shaken
Speaker 5:  down
Speaker 6:  And it's like not a little amount. It's not like, Hey, do you wanna spend
Speaker 6:  99 cents a month to share this password? No, you'll have to spend 7
Speaker 6:  99, which used to be what Netflix costs. And also you're gonna have to watch
Speaker 6:  ads and they may or may not suck.
Speaker 5:  That's brutal.
Speaker 7:  That's so, And if you wanna watch Netflix on a tbu that's not at your
Speaker 7:  house, it could get complicated now, especially if you're there for more
Speaker 7:  than a month or, and stuff like that. Like suddenly the rules have have changed.
Speaker 7:  It's not just, Oh hey, you know what? I'm here. I'm gonna sign in with my
Speaker 7:  Netflix account and watch stuff. It's not going to be like that anymore.
Speaker 5:  If they talked about how they're gonna figure that out for people who are
Speaker 5:  traveling, they
Speaker 7:  Have de they detailed that a bit on their support
Speaker 7:  page. They,
Speaker 6:  It's partially like if you're signed into the app and stuff, I think is part
Speaker 6:  of it. Like if you sign into the app on your home network, right?
Speaker 7:  It really only applies if you are signing in on a TV I think is what they
Speaker 7:  said. Okay. So like, you know, if if you're watching on your, your
Speaker 7:  phone or something, you're traveling you, you've gotta, you gotta whole different,
Speaker 7:  different kind of thing. But essentially what you are, are dealing with is
Speaker 7:  you're gonna, you're going, you may run into this. If you are trying to sign
Speaker 7:  in on a tv, that's somewhere not where you live.
Speaker 5:  All right? So you gotta tell all your exes to watch Netflix on our phones
Speaker 5:  and use airplay. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  I to tell my mom she's just not gonna have Netflix ever again.
Speaker 6:  Yeah,
Speaker 5:  But for your mind, you just like pay the money. She
Speaker 6:  Can pay the money. I'm not
Speaker 5:  Paid. The password sharing thing is complicated with like the number of people,
Speaker 5:  like roommates and old friends and ex-girlfriends. Like, Yeah,
Speaker 5:  here's what's gonna happen. I'm gonna like not talk to you anymore. This
Speaker 5:  is over where you're on the account by the way. And you
Speaker 5:  start Venmo $7 a month where your Netflix is gonna have ads.
Speaker 5:  Those are your choices.
Speaker 6:  Wait, don't you ever just do like the hard cutoff where one
Speaker 6:  day, like one day I, I signed on and I was like, why am I getting all these
Speaker 6:  recommended recommendations for shows about babies?
Speaker 6:  I do not have a baby. Yeah. And I remember my old roommate had a baby
Speaker 6:  and was just using my account and I was like, I don't talk to this person
Speaker 6:  anymore and just annihilated
Speaker 7:  It and they're gonna make that easier.
Speaker 6:  So just like took change the password, demanded sign
Speaker 6:  out, no more baby content.
Speaker 5:  Wow.
Speaker 7:  So if, if what you wanna do is to be petty with your ex roommate
Speaker 6:  Yes. Or your, your ex your ex-boyfriend,
Speaker 6:  ex-girlfriend, like I think everybody should be just a little more petty.
Speaker 6:  That
Speaker 7:  Is a feature. That's
Speaker 5:  A feature.
Speaker 7:  Yes. But yeah, I think essentially if you are, what it comes down to is
Speaker 7:  verify the idea of verified devices. It's sort of like your home Xbox. If
Speaker 7:  you have like an Xbox or a PlayStation, which one is your home one? So if
Speaker 7:  you're watching on a device that you've already verified for, they, they,
Speaker 7:  they don't, they don't exactly have all the details. But like if for a month
Speaker 7:  or so, if you are away from home, you won't get prompted for a code
Speaker 7:  or to like a, a text message or something to verify who you
Speaker 7:  are. But if you stay away from home for a while, suddenly it's going to ask
Speaker 7:  you to verify the device again. Or maybe it'll ask the people who are, who
Speaker 7:  are back at your, your home location to verify their devices. It's gonna
Speaker 7:  get real complicated for you is what I'm saying.
Speaker 5:  I'm very excited for the cat and mouse game of people trying to break Netflix
Speaker 5:  password sharing rules. It's, it's going to happen. It's gonna be incredible.
Speaker 6:  I was gonna say, it sounds kinda like screeners and with screeners you have
Speaker 6:  to verify a lot of times and then your friend will be like, Can I have the
Speaker 6:  screeners? And you're like, no, I don't wanna be like getting a verification
Speaker 6:  code at 3:00 AM and having to just text it to you. So I'm not doing that.
Speaker 6:  So a lot of people are just gonna gonna
Speaker 5:  You mean screeners for review movies and
Speaker 6:  Stuff like that? Yeah. When you're reviewing movies, when you, when you're
Speaker 6:  reviewing TV shows, they'll send you, like, you'll have to like log in
Speaker 6:  and you'll have to get a two-factor authentication and it's a whole thing
Speaker 6:  and it's fine, but you can't do it with your, your friends ask for the password
Speaker 6:  and you're like, No, it's two complicated, it's two-factor. So if they're
Speaker 6:  doing like a two factor kind of deal here, that prob that like that
Speaker 6:  complication will probably push more people to be like, man, get your own
Speaker 6:  account. I'm not texting you codes at 2:00 AM
Speaker 7:  Some friendships are gonna fall apart over this. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  We're gonna see friendships fall apart. It's gonna be great.
Speaker 5:  I'm excited. I I can't wait to write 500 rights about Netflix password car
Speaker 5:  town. But there's all this back to what Richard is saying, right? Netflix
Speaker 5:  is sort of like out of human beings to sell Netflix too, so it needs to get
Speaker 5:  more of them by kicking more people off password
Speaker 5:  sharing. So as like created more Netflix customers can sell than sell
Speaker 5:  to and then needs to basically raise prices and cut costs
Speaker 5:  like they're at mature company saturated market moments and like here
Speaker 5:  we are
Speaker 7:  And it, it is really interesting to see them in, in this mature company era
Speaker 7:  of theirs because they have suddenly turned into the cable company. Yep.
Speaker 7:  On their earnings call. The only thing they want to talk about is how they
Speaker 7:  are profitable and none of their competitors are they. They just wanna remind
Speaker 7:  everyone that they make money and hbo, Max Peacock,
Speaker 7:  you name it, Paramount, they're all just
Speaker 7:  plowing millions or billions of dollars into, into
Speaker 7:  a hole and setting it on fire and it's going away.
Speaker 5:  Okay, well two things. One, to be fair, if I was competing against
Speaker 5:  Peacock and the at and t implosion of H bmx,
Speaker 5:  I would point out that I was profitable all the time too. I'd be like, you
Speaker 5:  know what's true, they're just lighting in money on fire.
Speaker 5:  Two, I am now compelled to disclose Comcast
Speaker 5:  Universal's NBC unit, which is the proprietor of Peacock is a
Speaker 5:  minority investor in V Media. I assure you they did not
Speaker 5:  like what I just said about Peacock. We ever said about them ever.
Speaker 6:  Didn't we also make a Netflix show?
Speaker 5:  Two, we've made a Netflix show. It's great. You should go watch it. It's
Speaker 5:  called The Future of It will single handedly save the company in this time
Speaker 5:  of turmoil and strife. Our company also makes TV
Speaker 5:  shows all over the place. There's a a Chad
Speaker 5:  mom, our, the creative director of Oxia Studios are very excited about
Speaker 5:  partnering with the people who make F F1 Drive to survive to make a show
Speaker 5:  about the PGA Tour. These are been tweeting about golf for, for months
Speaker 5:  now. I know what goes on over there. I just see the golf tweets. There's
Speaker 5:  a conflict of interest. Everybody. Golf tweets from a my my buddy the end,
Speaker 5:  that's the disclosure this week. The
Speaker 7:  Other things that Netflix talked about, they announced the profile transfer
Speaker 7:  Transfer so that you know when you get kicked off someone's account, you
Speaker 7:  can take your your account and and walk and create a new account that you
Speaker 7:  will hopefully pay Netflix for. They, they hope, but you can't merge accounts.
Speaker 7:  Like, like don't they know that people get married sometimes and you have
Speaker 7:  multiple Netflix accounts?
Speaker 5:  Oh no, it's all over man. You gotta decide who are you now? It's like changing
Speaker 5:  your last name but it's your Netflix. I'll go, I
Speaker 7:  I gave up, I gave up my Netflix,
Speaker 5:  Other interesting things, Netflix Hall. So they're all in on binge watching.
Speaker 5:  I think there's been a lot of this conversation, especially cuz House the
Speaker 5:  Dragon is out issue. Max really all in on sort of these week by week drops
Speaker 5:  other Hulu does week by weeks for its big shows. Like all, most of the
Speaker 5:  streamers are at week by week. Netflix still just drops 'em all at once,
Speaker 5:  does not get the water cooler conversation, does not get the sort of
Speaker 5:  weekly ringer podcasts about what's gonna happen next. It just all
Speaker 5:  happens at once and they're committed to it. They say this is what creates
Speaker 5:  the value for Netflix subscribers. I don't know about this. Here's the quote.
Speaker 5:  We think our binge release model helps D drive substantial engagement, especially
Speaker 5:  for newer titles. I feel like it's the opposite. I feel like they lose out
Speaker 5:  on that sort of week by week anticipation.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I think this is one of those situations where they're gonna have regret
Speaker 6:  in a couple years because these other companies have all figured out the
Speaker 6:  water cooler situation. Like these are mature entertainment companies that
Speaker 6:  have been doing this in many cases for decades and decades. And while like
Speaker 6:  viewership habits have changed some stuff, haven't, people still only have
Speaker 6:  a limited amount of time to watch shows every day. And that like
Speaker 6:  getting ahead and everything is really frustrating for people. It's like,
Speaker 6:  I don't wanna binge watch, I don't wanna watch a show, a group watch a show
Speaker 6:  with my friends on Netflix cuz then I'm gonna have to be like, okay, I can't
Speaker 6:  watch it. It's
Speaker 7:  A conversation that they're having internally where they have some debate
Speaker 7:  and they just released or they're going to release this new Ryan
Speaker 7:  Johnson movie in theaters. And there's a Wall Street Journal article about
Speaker 7:  kind of the, the debate the executives had over whether or not they should
Speaker 7:  do theatrical releases and how that would affect the kind of movies that
Speaker 7:  they can get and put on their service. And also the
Speaker 7:  release, the release strategy. My guess on this,
Speaker 7:  my, my personal guess based on basically nothing is that Reed
Speaker 7:  Hastings was forced to give up his position on the ad thing. He, he
Speaker 7:  had to, he he kicking and screaming. They were losing customers. The investors
Speaker 7:  were scared they had to do something. They they added ads. Yeah. They're
Speaker 7:  gonna take binge releases from him and from Ted from their cold
Speaker 7:  dead hands. So until they have new CEOs, they're gonna still do binge
Speaker 7:  releases because that's what they want. And and that's, and that's when you'll
Speaker 7:  see it change. I
Speaker 5:  Agree with you with the ad thing. This is like right, Netflix is out of people.
Speaker 5:  So you got two choices to make more money. You gotta create more people,
Speaker 5:  which you can do by kicking people off of their password sharing. And then
Speaker 5:  you gotta make more money from the people you got, which is showing some
Speaker 5:  of those people ads. Those are, that's it. That's what you got. The binge
Speaker 5:  thing to me is just Right. They're already starting to break. Right. Stranger
Speaker 5:  Things was in two drops. The new gear, they of
Speaker 5:  things a couple of drops, Right. Like they're getting there
Speaker 5:  where they realize they got like here know, here's another disclosure. The
Speaker 5:  new show, the new series, The Watcher on Netflix based on New York Mag story.
Speaker 5:  New York Mags, part of Box Media. Yeah. Whole thing. It's good. You should
Speaker 5:  watch it. Any anything Bobby Convo. I'll watch it. It's great. He was in
Speaker 5:  Mr. Robot, You know how I feel about Mr. Robot? Great. That
Speaker 5:  show would be better if it was week by week. Right? It's a cliff hanger show.
Speaker 5:  It's a thriller. They should stop it every week and make people try to figure
Speaker 5:  out the mystery instead of you. Everybody watched it all once and everyone's
Speaker 5:  like mad about the ending, which I won't spoil, but it's a New York Mac story,
Speaker 5:  which you could've read. So I'm like, how much can you possibly spoil it?
Speaker 5:  But that's weird, right? To get everybody focused on the end and
Speaker 5:  like whether or not the thing com completed itself successfully versus over
Speaker 5:  a long period of time making everybody focus on the twists and turns of the
Speaker 5:  mystery inside of the store. Yeah. At some point they're just gonna have
Speaker 5:  to deal with it. Well
Speaker 6:  I think they also have to deal with the fact that at some point right now
Speaker 6:  they're profitable. Competition is increasing. I mean I don't
Speaker 6:  think most of these streaming channels are gonna survive, but the competition
Speaker 6:  is there. They're, they're having to fight other people for, for some of
Speaker 6:  these dollars and some of these subscriptions and you can't
Speaker 6:  just keep churning out content at some point that the kinda like infinite
Speaker 6:  content has to become finite. And so if they're the only
Speaker 6:  ones in that binge mode being like we are just shoveling
Speaker 6:  stuff in your faces while Disney's over here doing, we do two shows a
Speaker 6:  week, that's it and it's Thursday night and have fun.
Speaker 6:  Like they're just gonna run into a problem of money. That's why Disney's
Speaker 6:  doing so well is it's being very cautious about it. It's rollout. That's
Speaker 6:  one of the reasons that HBO Max and some of these other ones have struggled
Speaker 6:  is because they weren't cautious and they were shoveling money at
Speaker 6:  people and just being like, yeah, make as much content as possible. And like
Speaker 6:  Netflix is the worst offender there and
Speaker 6:  you're seeing that burnout in Hollywood. You're seeing those ramifications
Speaker 6:  in the entertainment industry and at some point I think that's gonna catch
Speaker 6:  up with Netflix itself.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, we'll see. We'll see. The other thing Netflix is doing, right?
Speaker 5:  They gotta get rid of people. They gotta create more customers. You fire
Speaker 5:  the people from password sharing, make them pay you a ads. Those are your
Speaker 5:  choices. You also make new products. So they are now quote,
Speaker 5:  seriously exploring a cloud gaming service, which makes sense.
Speaker 5:  Netflix is very good at streaming video over the internet. Its simplest
Speaker 5:  form cloud gaming is just streaming some video to you over the internet
Speaker 5:  accepting some input back from you. Adjusting that video
Speaker 5:  right in a, you know, performant in low latency
Speaker 5:  way. They gotta do it though, right? I mean it's harder than it sounds
Speaker 5:  actually getting the games. Maybe
Speaker 6:  You think at the games. Jay Peters did this great story this week called
Speaker 6:  Can Netflix Reclaim the Netflix for games Crown from Xbox Game
Speaker 6:  Pass. And he, he spoke with a bunch of different people about like what
Speaker 6:  are the actual challenges there? And Richard Gillette like that was one of
Speaker 6:  the biggest challenges is they don't have all those relationships that Nvidia
Speaker 6:  and Microsoft have with game developers to make games. Like
Speaker 6:  they've got a lot of games on their platform, but they're primarily indie
Speaker 6:  games from indie developers. That's for mobile.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Yo, but off is like, you want Assassin's cre we'll stream
Speaker 5:  it anywhere.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, Give off will do that for anyone. We could probably have, we could
Speaker 6:  probably have Assassin's Creed on the Verge website at any point if we want.
Speaker 5:  Here's what I'm saying. Look, I, we've got big updates to the redesign coming
Speaker 5:  and soon biggest update of all, which is the entire Verge
Speaker 5:  will just be a level of assassin. We're gonna bring back stadium and you'll
Speaker 5:  have to do the eagle dive to find a new
Speaker 5:  story. That's a bird
Speaker 5:  noise for today. I can't make the
Speaker 6:  Bird. That's the noise they make in the game. I've never played these games.
Speaker 6:  I don't know what they do. You
Speaker 5:  Gotta play at least one assassin screen. What are you doing?
Speaker 6:  I played, I played the Vike one. Okay.
Speaker 5:  But I didn't finish. That's not the best one by far. I mean, it's like the
Speaker 5:  most like beautiful one.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  But like, what's,
Speaker 6:  What's the good one?
Speaker 5:  They all blur together. The, the, the one in Italy, The Eio.
Speaker 6:  Okay. That's like an early one. I was, I was always told never to finish
Speaker 6:  one.
Speaker 5:  They made, I think, No, I made, they made three with him. I think
Speaker 6:  I'm really up to date on my assassin Creed board.
Speaker 7:  Sorry. Good. I had, I had assassin.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. There's people listening to us right now who are hardcore
Speaker 5:  assassin Creed fans still, I'm so sorry. They're right in the slash fix and
Speaker 5:  like, Please don't email us. Like I just, I'm sorry. But Eio was the I
Speaker 6:  Know they don't have the middle finger. That's like, there's my lo knowledge.
Speaker 6:  They don't have their middle finger.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Cuz they've got knives,
Speaker 6:  Which is way cooler.
Speaker 5:  It's true. My wife used to be like, Are you playing the game where you stab
Speaker 5:  people in the face and I'd be like, I am playing the game. I am.
Speaker 5:  And that is a totally accurate description of this game, but Ustar will be
Speaker 5:  anywhere, right? Yeah. The problem is Ubisoft is one of the last large
Speaker 5:  independent game studios with, you know, a
Speaker 5:  triple a title like Assassin's Creed to drop
Speaker 5:  on everyone. All of the other studios are getting
Speaker 5:  bought by Microsoft. Whoops.
Speaker 6:  In just Microsoft,
Speaker 5:  It's pretty much just Microsoft. You get
Speaker 7:  Into this weird, you get into this weird space because you, you build a service
Speaker 7:  that only people who are hardcore gamers would want. And then you don't have
Speaker 7:  the games for those hardcore gamers. Like, you don't have a reason for those
Speaker 7:  people to turn off the PS five and the Xbox Series S or X or s or gaming
Speaker 7:  PC that they already
Speaker 5:  Have. Wait, do you think that cloud gaming is only for hardcore gamers?
Speaker 7:  No, but it's hard to sell to someone who isn't a hardcore gamer. Like if
Speaker 7:  someone who plays mobile games on their phone, maybe they should try cloud
Speaker 7:  gaming. But how would you convince them to do it?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I think it's a, the, like hardcore gamers want triple A games, generally
Speaker 6:  speaking, right? And you're, you're just regular person who
Speaker 6:  doesn't own any consoles but would probably wanna play a game, is gonna wanna
Speaker 6:  play those same triple A games. Those are the ones that are in the marketplace.
Speaker 6:  The call duties of the world, the Destiny twos. And so like, they're gonna,
Speaker 6:  you're gonna have to have support for those. If you wanna get those people
Speaker 6:  who are like, Yeah, I don't want one, but I wanna like mess around with my
Speaker 6:  friend who who plays this game a lot and like see what they're doing and,
Speaker 6:  and experience it. So you have to like, you still have to have those triple
Speaker 6:  A games because that's where the audience is. Whether they're
Speaker 6:  hardcore or cash. I think
Speaker 5:  Every time I talk about gaming on this show, people yell at me. So I'm just
Speaker 5:  gonna lean directly into it. This is my personal, they
Speaker 6:  Can all
Speaker 5:  Yell at me. This is my personal cultural war trolling.
Speaker 7:  Either you have Madden or you don't. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  I play a lot of Madden and now Chris Grant, the publisher of the ver the
Speaker 5:  group publisher of the Virgin Polygon is trying to get me to play control.
Speaker 5:  That's where I'm at with gaming lately. I buy all the games I just bought
Speaker 5:  Cyberpunk. Haven't played a minute of it. No
Speaker 6:  Fifa.
Speaker 5:  That's, I buy 'em all. I don't play 'em. But here's my, here's my thing.
Speaker 7:  If you didn't play when it was broken, you didn't really play
Speaker 7:  it.
Speaker 5:  I watched all the videos of the weird map clipping and I was like, this looks
Speaker 5:  amazing. And then I just never played it. If you are a Netflix binge
Speaker 5:  watching subscriber, right? You sit down in front of Netflix, you want 16
Speaker 5:  hours of content to fill the empty hours of your
Speaker 5:  day. Sure. What you could sell to that
Speaker 5:  audience is like a great single player story driven
Speaker 5:  narrative game. Those don't exist. Right. Start playing this game. Experience
Speaker 5:  this long story. You'll come to the end of it. It'll be whatever the
Speaker 5:  entire modern games industry is like veering away from
Speaker 5:  that, especially with the AAA titles into, you know, GTA five is
Speaker 5:  like an extremely long running massively
Speaker 5:  multiplayer world that asks you for money in one way or the other every
Speaker 5:  five minutes,
Speaker 6:  Right? They're all MMOs because they just wanna like get as much
Speaker 6:  of your money as possible. They're trying to create their own subscription
Speaker 6:  services effectively. So yeah, I I think Netflix
Speaker 6:  is gonna have to figure that out. How do they, are they gonna make a strangers
Speaker 6:  thing game? Do you wanna play a strangers thing game
Speaker 6:  like a aaa?
Speaker 5:  Why do you keep calling it Strangers thing? I think that's a
Speaker 5:  fanfic that is not
Speaker 6:  Officially licensed. It's the evening.
Speaker 5:  The strange thing is, I don't know if you've heard about this
Speaker 6:  Strangers
Speaker 5:  Thing, it's a 60 hour, extremely dark, gritty
Speaker 5:  reboot of perfect
Speaker 5:  strangers and
Speaker 6:  It's went in
Speaker 5:  Aist wandering rated
Speaker 6:  Of I was gonna go
Speaker 5:  It's thing
Speaker 6:  Well cause just like, Hey guys, what's up? I can't even try the accent.
Speaker 5:  Cousin. Larry's a drug dealer, it's strangers thing. Everybody,
Speaker 5:  There's like 90% of the office has no idea what I'm talking about. Perfect
Speaker 5:  Strangers was a show in the eighties that I am guessing based on
Speaker 5:  having watched a lot in the eighties and not anytime recently. I'm just
Speaker 5:  in nineties. Guess it didn't hold up just based on what
Speaker 5:  I remember a stranger,
Speaker 6:  Me cousin bulky who held a lamb and was like,
Speaker 6:  I'm from another country. In other countries we don't have things.
Speaker 6:  We just have our little ghost.
Speaker 5:  But can you be racist against a fake country?
Speaker 5:  The Verge cast everybody. I think I know the
Speaker 5:  answer. All right, so that's
Speaker 5:  Netflix. Rebooting Perfect Strangers is a dark,
Speaker 5:  gritty, 60 hour single player video paint
Speaker 6:  Gonna be incredible.
Speaker 6:  They're all gonna have like the little five o'clock shadow.
Speaker 5:  Oh it's great. It's
Speaker 6:  Some large gun. It's gonna be great. Oh,
Speaker 5:  It'll be rights race. It's gonna, it's gonna look fantastic. It's, yeah,
Speaker 5:  it's just cousin Larry walking. Yeah, it's gonna be great. And then Cousin
Speaker 5:  Larry's gonna do the eagle dive from top of the Sears Tower
Speaker 5:  Stab people on the streets of 1980s Chicago. I don't know why this game
Speaker 5:  hasn't been made. I would play the tell out of it.
Speaker 5:  Sorry Li All right, let's talk about Tesla. Is that a good segue
Speaker 5:  everybody? Speaking of diving off of skyscrapers and stabbing people
Speaker 5:  in the face. Tesla had earnings.
Speaker 5:  They're doing okay. Walk us through Alex.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I mean they're, they're doing all right. I think the big thing
Speaker 6:  that kind of jumped out at me was Elon talking about Twitter again and saying
Speaker 6:  he's excited to buy it and he's sure definitely gonna buy it in a couple
Speaker 6:  of weeks, right?
Speaker 5:  No, they've gotta close on 28th. They're eight days away.
Speaker 6:  So they've got next week. Yep. Yeah. So this time next Friday
Speaker 6:  he has to have purchased Twitter and he's currently saying he's very
Speaker 6:  excited to buy it. Yeah. But he also like they're, they're shipping
Speaker 6:  cars. They're shipping almost too many cars, right? They're
Speaker 5:  Not shipping too many. They're shipping everyone they can make and they're
Speaker 5:  just running too hot. So they're trying to create efficiency in how they
Speaker 5:  make cars and in particular for whatever the next car
Speaker 5:  is. Elon is saying for all the effort we put into making one
Speaker 5:  model three, we should be able to produce two of whatever the new car is.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  But I, I would like kind of want them to first go back and figure
Speaker 6:  out how to make the cars not fall apart when somebody sneezes in
Speaker 6:  one.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I, that stuff has gotten a little better, but it's still the thing
Speaker 5:  that plagues Tesla. Like I was looking into buying a used
Speaker 5:  model three. Yeah. For this like commute to New York that I'm doing once
Speaker 5:  a week and all of the forms like you should buy used model three, the best
Speaker 5:  car I've ever had. Tesla's changed my life. Also make sure you buy
Speaker 5:  an extended warranty and reserve at least two weeks of time a year for the
Speaker 5:  inevitable repairs. And it was just like, it just stated
Speaker 5:  as fa like it's just part of that community now in a way that is a little
Speaker 5:  too normal. But it's, Yeah, the door might fall off. There's still, but
Speaker 5:  they'll, they'll fix it eventually. It'll be fine. The door latches on the
Speaker 5:  model three in particular. You can live with that. Yeah. So yeah, I mean
Speaker 5:  I think Elon's still got some quality control too. I think he said they're
Speaker 5:  putting out a cheaper car. He promised the cyber truck will hit next year.
Speaker 6:  Okay. Okay.
Speaker 5:  He did not reveal the design for the windshield wipers.
Speaker 6:  They're still working on it to, it's gonna actually be 12 different wipers
Speaker 6:  all
Speaker 5:  Around the wipers in a triangle. I'm telling you,
Speaker 6:  It's gonna be incredible. But you know, they also did like in the earnings
Speaker 6:  they, they said that like they're making money. I think that was kind of
Speaker 6:  one of the little concerns everybody had is that Elon had to sell a bunch
Speaker 6:  of stock to buy Twitter and that hurt Tesla
Speaker 6:  stock. And it's like, okay, but are they still making money? Like was this
Speaker 6:  always just a stock rich company or can they still keep going and still
Speaker 6:  produce these cars when he's off spending everybody's money on Twitter
Speaker 6:  and
Speaker 5:  They're doing it and frankly being distracted by Twitter.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Super distracted by Twitter. So they're doing it and
Speaker 6:  I'm really curious to see if he's like, I don't know, I keep thinking, is
Speaker 6:  Elon gonna stay the CEO of all these different companies? Because ever since
Speaker 6:  I learned that he has 20 direct reports at Tesla,
Speaker 6:  like my brain just screams at that knowledge every
Speaker 6:  day.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. But he's not like doing like best practice one-on-ones with them. He
Speaker 5:  just shows up and it's like, did you do, did you make the car drive itself?
Speaker 5:  Not yet. Okay. We'll say it's next week.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, that's true.
Speaker 5:  So you know, analysts did not like Tesla's quarter and the thing that you
Speaker 5:  are saying about their deliveries, they made too many, they can't deliver.
Speaker 5:  They can make the cars, but they don't have the transportation capacity to
Speaker 5:  deliver all of them. Turns out their layoffs actually let go some of those
Speaker 5:  people. That's true. Oops. So we'll just see, I mean,
Speaker 5:  I think Tesla's in a strong position, but this Twitter thing like looms over
Speaker 5:  Tesla in a real way. And it will be, like I said, if it
Speaker 5:  actually closed the deal, my headline is like, Welcome to hell Elon Musk
Speaker 5:  because owning Twitter is gonna suck for him. Like he
Speaker 5:  is too easily trolled into doing and saying dumb
Speaker 5:  things. And when it's like state actors in
Speaker 5:  weirdo politicians on both sides trolling you into
Speaker 5:  moderation decisions that they favor, it's, it's just, it's welcome to
Speaker 5:  hell. That's like literally he should run away screening. But now he's saying
Speaker 5:  he is excited about it.
Speaker 6:  I hope he just bans all governments and
Speaker 6:  politicians from having Twitter.
Speaker 5:  Oh, I don't think he's gonna do that. I think he's, he's
Speaker 6:  Gonna do the opposite.
Speaker 5:  He's gonna, he's he's gonna sell it to the government for $50
Speaker 5:  billion Twitter employees. Bloomberg reported Twitter locked its
Speaker 5:  equity grant. So it's not handing out equity in anticipation. The deal will
Speaker 5:  close. So we'll see next week. Yeah. Then speaking and then
Speaker 5:  more Elon News. Just an absolutely bizarre back and
Speaker 5:  forth about Starling and Ukraine. Obviously Elon started shipping
Speaker 5:  startup units to the Ukrainian military and to Ukrainian citizens.
Speaker 5:  The government was paying for summit, the United States government, other
Speaker 5:  governments around the world were paying for some of it. Turns out Ukrainians
Speaker 5:  are doing crowd funding to pay for some of their own service. Other people
Speaker 5:  were setting up crowdfunding has to pay for some of their own service. Elon
Speaker 5:  claims that he had been paying for it out of pocket. Starling is like not
Speaker 5:  a profitable thing. And like actually the biggest challenge for Starling,
Speaker 5:  he said this many times before all this happened, right? Based on for Starling
Speaker 5:  is just not going outta business. Cuz usually everything goes outta business.
Speaker 5:  Like satellite based internet companies got business. So then he
Speaker 5:  said we can't keep funding this forever. The government should pay for it.
Speaker 5:  That got leaked. That turned into a political football especially cuz Elon
Speaker 5:  keeps tweeting about Russia and peace plans and he's
Speaker 5:  just making a bunch of bad decisions there. And then there was a lot of pressure.
Speaker 5:  Hey you're threatening the access to the Ukrainian military is relying on,
Speaker 5:  you're obviously puppet of Putin, which of course took
Speaker 5:  exception to. And now he says he will keep funding Starling for
Speaker 5:  the Ukrainian government for free despite losing money. Which I would just
Speaker 5:  note the United States government, other governments around the world were
Speaker 5:  already paying for some of this. So it's just deeply unclear what is going
Speaker 5:  on here. Yeah. Also just one of those, if you take free stuff from a
Speaker 5:  billionaire boy do you end up beholden to the billionaire?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Yeah. I think like this is one of those situations where I have a rule
Speaker 6:  of thumb where I try not to tweet about international politics. And I
Speaker 6:  think Elon should also try not to tweet about
Speaker 6:  international politics,
Speaker 5:  But soon he will own Twitter. Yeah. This is what I'm saying. This is gonna
Speaker 5:  be, he is too easily trolled into responding
Speaker 6:  Like he got in like a Twitter war briefly with the president of Ukraine
Speaker 6:  who is at war. It's just he should not tweet in
Speaker 6:  this space. It's bad. Like I think he got a lot of good will with starlink
Speaker 6:  did really well for him and now he
Speaker 6:  needs to just like be quiet like Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Or he could do nothing. Right? He could. He could. It's, I think it's
Speaker 5:  legitimate for money losing business that's providing a critical, critical
Speaker 5:  infrastructure service to an American ally a hundred percent.
Speaker 5:  To ask the American government to fund that service. I think that is a totally
Speaker 5:  reasonable request that it gets reported. Should you
Speaker 5:  should, you could just not react to it. Be like, yes, in fact we did ask
Speaker 5:  the United States government to pay for this service the same way the United
Speaker 5:  States government is like paying for missiles and ammunition to go to
Speaker 5:  Ukraine. Like great. Like that's Boeing does not get controlled into
Speaker 5:  responding to, its to criticisms of its defense contracts.
Speaker 7:  But that's the Elon story is that no one else, no, no other CEO ever operates
Speaker 7:  this way. And there are reasons and we just keep finding out the reasons
Speaker 7:  why they don't.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, well what he owns Twitter, it's all gonna get
Speaker 5:  stupider. Especially cuz right? He's up against
Speaker 5:  Kanye West buying parlor, which is gross and
Speaker 5:  weird. Kanye tweeted a bunch of antisemitic
Speaker 5:  things. He got kicked off the platforms and then he basically got conned
Speaker 5:  into buying parlor, which is bleeding money Mechanically has a great story
Speaker 5:  about how Parlor was basically dying and they conned
Speaker 5:  Kanye to buy it. There's no other way to describe it. And then obviously
Speaker 5:  Trump and Truth Social, which is falling apart in a series of
Speaker 5:  extremely chaotic recriminations, including its own former executives going
Speaker 5:  to the Washington Post and providing all of the evidence that he'd given
Speaker 5:  to the s e c Badly Truth Social is
Speaker 5:  run. So at the end of it, just like in this flaming
Speaker 5:  pile of alternative social service wreckage, there's an Elon
Speaker 5:  owning Twitter with nothing to stop him. It's gonna be weird. I
Speaker 5:  mean, we can all stop using Twitter. Why do you think we redesign the whole
Speaker 5:  website? Why do you think I'm needed a Twitter key up? Because I'm ready
Speaker 5:  anytime you want. Ready,
Speaker 7:  Ready to pull the escape
Speaker 5:  Edge. You gotta start tweeting on a website more. All right, we gotta take
Speaker 5:  a break. I'm, it's gonna, We'll see, I mean
Speaker 5:  I'm, I'm as addicted to it as anybody, but at least we have an escape hatch.
Speaker 5:  You know what I'm saying? All right, we gotta take a break. We're gonna come
Speaker 5:  back. Richard's gonna tell us about his crypto obsession. I can't
Speaker 5:  believe how excited I about this. We'll, right
Speaker 5:  back.
Speaker 5:  We're back Richard Lawler, this week you fell
Speaker 5:  deep down an NFT rabbit hole because as everyone
Speaker 5:  remembers, CNN decided it would start selling NFTs and then they
Speaker 5:  decided they would stop, Tell, tell us what happened here. My
Speaker 5:  friend,
Speaker 7:  I will have, you know, that their NFC marketplace lasted 16 times as long
Speaker 7:  as CNN Plus first of all, that just first of all, Yeah, okay.
Speaker 7:  Like let's, let's, let's take the win, let's take the W there, the
Speaker 7:  CNN Vault, which tried to sell moments because who doesn't wanna
Speaker 7:  buy digital tokens attached to news articles about famous
Speaker 7:  events and trade them or sell them with your friends? That
Speaker 7:  that's a thing people do. It's it's something that everyone wants. I I,
Speaker 7:  I was sitting at home hoping someone would launch a service like that and
Speaker 7:  then CNN did. No, I actually spoke to someone who had spent more than
Speaker 7:  $10,000 on Wow. That
Speaker 7:  that was what they thought. You know, kind of looking at what they own on,
Speaker 7:  on these moments. Like there, there are, when you take a look at these things
Speaker 7:  that these, these brands launch, these web three, these NFT things, you think,
Speaker 7:  okay, nobody's buying that. There is someone who is buying it. There
Speaker 7:  are, there are are not. There is a certain number of people who have the
Speaker 7:  money and have decided, yes, I am going to go ahead and invest cuz CNN
Speaker 7:  sounds sounds like a, a reasonable company. They're not gonna rug pull and
Speaker 7:  just disappear overnight like some of these shady and FD operators.
Speaker 7:  And that's exactly what they did. 16 months later they were like, Yeah, no,
Speaker 7:  we're not doing this anymore. And the community is,
Speaker 5:  Wait, there's a community
Speaker 7:  Unsurprisingly not really pleased about it. They, they, CNN said that they're
Speaker 7:  going to give some refunds. I was like, how
Speaker 11:  Many
Speaker 5:  People besides
Speaker 7:  This one person, Every NFT project has a community. Every NFT project has
Speaker 7:  a discord and there are at least five people who come on there every morning
Speaker 7:  and say good morning to each other. And they talk about their days. It's,
Speaker 7:  it's beau it's actually
Speaker 5:  Beautiful. Stop trying to curtail me. You should join
Speaker 7:  A few, you
Speaker 5:  Should, you should get into NFTs. No, I'm not coming in. This is like the
Speaker 5:  end of the fun. First of all, you're trying to get me in at the end of the
Speaker 5:  party when all the streamers are falling down, people are sweeping like,
Speaker 5:  no, come over and help clean up.
Speaker 7:  I I've got some really nice NFTs that I can sell you at a good
Speaker 7:  price. I'm just saying
Speaker 5:  I have stayed out too late with you in my life before, sir. And I
Speaker 5:  am not doing that again. Especially when there's crypto
Speaker 5:  involved.
Speaker 7:  Everyone's survived.
Speaker 5:  It's true. Everyone's survived. Where where's your, you've, you are
Speaker 5:  notably, we are joking. Richard is notably skeptical of
Speaker 5:  NFTs and crypto Now that you've talked to these folks, where, where's your
Speaker 5:  feeling at?
Speaker 7:  It's, it's really unfortunate and I, I feel like these people have been taken
Speaker 7:  advantage of. Like you, you had these brands just kind of grab at these,
Speaker 7:  these projects and they, they launched and they had these promises. They
Speaker 7:  said, We're gonna give you utility, we're gonna give you special experiences.
Speaker 7:  We're going to give you access, we're going to allow you to do this and to
Speaker 7:  do that. And then none of those things happened. They sold, they sold you
Speaker 7:  magic beans and then they said, Okay, stay tuned with our
Speaker 7:  social channel and our discord. And then they waited a year until
Speaker 7:  everybody forgot about it. And then they said, Yeah, we're we got your money
Speaker 7:  and we're just gonna
Speaker 5:  Leave now. Yeah. And they rugged everybody super hard.
Speaker 7:  Right. We, we don't have any bigger plans here. We it, it never got big,
Speaker 7:  it never scaled to a level where we're going to continue doing it. I think
Speaker 7:  there was a report earlier this year that CNN had made $300,000 from it,
Speaker 7:  which you know, is a small number amount of money for a person. But for Warner
Speaker 7:  Brothers, discovery isn't enough to stay in the business.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It was not even enough to fund one extra day of CNN
Speaker 5:  Plus they were like, we can't even, not even an extra hour.
Speaker 5:  That's not to
Speaker 7:  Do it for us. And CNN is far from the only brand like this. Like I,
Speaker 7:  I'm, as I said, I really am in a lot of nft discords.
Speaker 7:  Every company that you can name has tried to do web three
Speaker 7:  things. I'm, I'm in one for the Gap. And many of them have
Speaker 7:  either completely abandoned their communities or they just
Speaker 7:  keep dropping things to sell to these same people who already bought in.
Speaker 7:  And the people are, are hoping that the company will do something that will
Speaker 7:  bring in new people so they can bring it so they can sell the tokens that
Speaker 7:  they bought early at a profit, but they just keep pumping money outta the
Speaker 7:  same people over and over again. And that, that's really where the cycle
Speaker 7:  is.
Speaker 5:  That's fertile. Well, I'm gonna continue avoiding it. I'll just
Speaker 5:  keep getting my updates from you from this. Wait,
Speaker 6:  But you, you talk to this person who spent $10,000. Did they have a reason
Speaker 6:  besides like, just speculation?
Speaker 7:  They just, they're into nds and you know, they, they get into the community.
Speaker 7:  They, when you, when you are in one of these things, and I compare it
Speaker 7:  very much to a cult because that's really what it is. You, you have this
Speaker 7:  like magical belief that things are going to go up and everyone shares it
Speaker 7:  and you can get in and you can kind of log in and every day
Speaker 7:  you'll have maybe five or maybe 500 people telling you how great
Speaker 7:  things are and how you're in the right place and you're doing the right thing
Speaker 7:  and you're going to win eventually. And, and that, that sense
Speaker 7:  of com, that community is really what people are there for. But to be in
Speaker 7:  the community, you have to buy things. And some,
Speaker 7:  some people buy a little bit more.
Speaker 5:  All right, well I can't wait to start our NFT collection. Oh, next
Speaker 7:  The hill turn is coming. I'm doing it.
Speaker 5:  It's coming right out. When we redesign the entire site is an assassin's
Speaker 5:  CRE level. It's the future of all media
Speaker 5:  futures. Speaking of nonsensical future ideas,
Speaker 5:  I'm, I'm gonna try to get through this as quickly as I can. I told you it
Speaker 5:  was gonna be vir chasity, vergecast.
Speaker 6:  Are you gonna, are you gonna talk about Wisconsin?
Speaker 5:  I'm gonna talk about Wisconsin. So the Packers are bad this year. Look very
Speaker 5:  bad. I'm sorry. No, I'm not gonna talk. They're very
Speaker 5:  bad. I predict that Aaron Rods will destroy at least
Speaker 5:  two more surface tablets by the end of the year. That's my personal prediction
Speaker 5:  about the state of Wisconsin. No, the state of Wisconsin, there's a company
Speaker 5:  called Fox on, which you may have heard about on the show before. They were
Speaker 5:  supposed to build an LCD factory in Wisconsin. They have not built that.
Speaker 5:  It's mostly empty buildings. They did build a dome, which they continue to
Speaker 5:  claim is a data center. It is not a data center. The data center is located
Speaker 5:  outside the dome in a shipping container at the porta potty next to it. This
Speaker 5:  is true information.
Speaker 6:  I mean is that technically
Speaker 5:  And even that isn't data center, it's just a shipping container with some
Speaker 5:  Dell servers in it.
Speaker 6:  It's like the Apple version of the It's like the Foxcon version of the all
Speaker 6:  screen. Yeah. Right. Like it's close enough that it counts.
Speaker 5:  There's some screen. Yeah, there's some screen,
Speaker 6:  There's some data
Speaker 5:  Center, there's some, there's some data center around the dome.
Speaker 6:  They plugged it in in the do into the data into the dome.
Speaker 5:  All right. So Foxconn, when it goes into Wisconsin like 20
Speaker 5:  16, 17, they, there's do whatever they're doing. And one of
Speaker 5:  the enduring mysteries of what Fox Homem was doing in Wisconsin was they
Speaker 5:  kept talking about something called the AI AK plus 5G
Speaker 5:  ecosystem. This is a real phrase they said
Speaker 5:  in my belief to just bamboozle
Speaker 5:  dumb local politicians in Wisconsin into thinking they were doing something
Speaker 5:  cool. Like they just fired buzzwords at these
Speaker 5:  hapless dummies and they got a huge tax break. Right.
Speaker 5:  Scott Walker was like, I love AI eight K and 5g. I sound great
Speaker 5:  now. Yeah. What Welcome to the Wisconsin Valley.
Speaker 6:  They just went to ces. Yeah. They saw what was like on the little
Speaker 6:  banners around and they're like, that's it. At
Speaker 5:  One point they set up what was essentially a CES in Wisconsin.
Speaker 5:  Like a fake trade show. Yes. With
Speaker 5:  like big TVs and drones, like all the CES stuff that
Speaker 5:  we go to and ignore to like find the real products. They set up
Speaker 5:  one of those. So aia, so Josh Jesu who did most of our Fox
Speaker 5:  reporting won awards for that FoxTown recording. We've spent years
Speaker 5:  alternately trying to figure out what Foxcon means by AI AK plus
Speaker 5:  5g and laughing at it and in, in one very notable
Speaker 5:  instance, receiving just anonymous threats from Foxcon
Speaker 5:  executives to tell, telling us to leave them alone. And
Speaker 5:  then in the same breath trying to explain what AK plus 5G is.
Speaker 5:  It was very confusing. None of this matters anymore because
Speaker 5:  Foxconn just announced a new plan to make electric vehicles. They were like,
Speaker 5:  we, our ambition is to make EVs for
Speaker 5:  Tesla. I dunno if you just heard us. Tesla's making every
Speaker 5:  car at Tesla's very good at making EVs. It
Speaker 5:  does not need a contract manufacturer. It makes the cars. I don't know why.
Speaker 5:  Anyway, Foxconn announces two reference designs of its new EVs and
Speaker 5:  then the, the president of Foxconn says, We have a new strategic vision.
Speaker 5:  Are you ready for it? Yes. It's three plus three equals
Speaker 5:  infinity.
Speaker 6:  Well you said is it three plus three equals infinity or an infinity
Speaker 6:  symbol? It's like
Speaker 5:  The symbol. It's it's a symbol. So then the, the
Speaker 5:  FOXCON and Wisconsin website has been scrubbed of all
Speaker 5:  references of A I A K plus 5g. Oh no. And it has all
Speaker 5:  been replaced with three plus three equals infinity. So I, I don't know man.
Speaker 5:  Three plus three by the way, it's three industries. Electric vehicle digital
Speaker 5:  health and fee robotics. Who knows what that is. It's not the same as
Speaker 5:  they're
Speaker 6:  Gonna make the robot. They're not gonna make the the cars, they're gonna
Speaker 6:  make the robot.
Speaker 5:  It's, I can't even begin to explain what fee is. Fee is
Speaker 5:  a subsidiary of Fox on, they set up to take over what's
Speaker 6:  Whatever they're gonna make the Tesla robot.
Speaker 5:  It's three things. The three is electric vehicle, digital health and field
Speaker 5:  products. And then the plus three is technology. It's
Speaker 5:  5G solutions. Semiconductors by the way, the logo for semiconductors is just
Speaker 5:  the USB logo. So I don't know what's going on there. And then industrial
Speaker 5:  ai, which Fox on has branded iai.
Speaker 5:  This is a real thing with a link to something called the IAI Institute and
Speaker 5:  that link just doesn't work. So I dunno what that
Speaker 5:  is. I tried, I clicked all the links
Speaker 5:  on this one website.
Speaker 6:  Can we, can we all list ourselves as just employees of the IAI
Speaker 6:  Institute? Like Richard you're now chairperson. I always was the I
Speaker 5:  You should sell some I I NFTs Richard, why
Speaker 7:  Didn't they go with you plus me equals us. It was right
Speaker 7:  there.
Speaker 7:  It's a deep bet. It's gonna miss some people but for those who appreciate
Speaker 7:  it,
Speaker 5:  Here's what I got is first of all three plus three six. I dunno, I
Speaker 5:  just want to put that out there as a thing that I know Infinity is the,
Speaker 5:  as the father of a four year old, I'm really confident that three plus three
Speaker 5:  equals six. This is, this is something we're working on actively
Speaker 5:  in our
Speaker 6:  House. You're just not looking at it in the foxcon way.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Second of all, you can't just list industries and
Speaker 5:  technologies and be like, here's what you do. You take these three industries
Speaker 5:  and you just throw some 5G solutions at it and arrive at
Speaker 5:  infinity. Don't know what that means. Third of
Speaker 5:  all, none of this is gonna create jobs in Wisconsin. Right? Like
Speaker 5:  at the end of the day they have an empty building, they've got a dome. The
Speaker 5:  website has been updated to brag about the dome. Yes.
Speaker 5:  In the, But the brags are like the dome is
Speaker 5:  nearly 100 feet tall, which I would note is not 100
Speaker 5:  feet tall. So you've built like an eight story dome. It's
Speaker 5:  just not impressive. And they're like, you can see it
Speaker 5:  from the highway, which I dunno if you've ever driven through
Speaker 5:  Wisconsin. Wisconsin's mostly cornfield are they? So like
Speaker 5:  being able to see an eight story building from the highways is
Speaker 5:  really not that big of deal.
Speaker 6:  But you know, people go out of their ways to like find the
Speaker 6:  largest ball of twine.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And people are there. Is there just a vendor sitting out there next to
Speaker 6:  the data center with like a bunch of little ball, little
Speaker 6:  globes selling them to people who pass by, who drove off the highway to
Speaker 6:  be like, what's that globe over there?
Speaker 5:  No. You don't understand if you drive by there and your parents' house is
Speaker 5:  like right by there. Yeah, they built just
Speaker 5:  huge roadways. Okay. To support what they
Speaker 5:  thought would be 13,000 jobs building
Speaker 5:  like hundred inch TVs. So they built
Speaker 5:  roadways and water and power to support
Speaker 5:  manufacturing on this massive scale and to move these like giant
Speaker 5:  TVs. Yeah. And none of it exists. Like
Speaker 5:  if I was still a teenager in Wisconsin, like I would be,
Speaker 5:  I would only be drag racing by the dome all day long because
Speaker 5:  it's just like six lane roads that are dead empty.
Speaker 6:  Are there, are there people in any of the buildings?
Speaker 5:  Sometimes that's why
Speaker 5:  sometimes the dome is apparently like an event
Speaker 5:  space. There are no pictures by the way of the inside of the dome.
Speaker 5:  And Fox continues to claim the dome is a data center. They say there's gonna
Speaker 5:  be a network operations center there and I believe but what network, there's
Speaker 5:  one day center shipping container,
Speaker 5:  there's like a power strip that shuts down the shipping container and turns
Speaker 5:  it very off. It's not, it's just truly bizarre. But
Speaker 5:  anyway, so AI look A i a K plus 5G is out three
Speaker 5:  plus three equals infinity is in you. Let me know if you know what that means
Speaker 5:  cuz I, I'm working on it.
Speaker 6:  I'm really excited about
Speaker 5:  It. It's, it's real bad but the, you gotta just, everybody gonna read the
Speaker 5:  website cuz the part about the dome where they just consistently, you
Speaker 6:  Can see it from the
Speaker 5:  The dome and it's like, it's incredible. Have you ever
Speaker 5:  looked at an eight story circle from the highway? Because now you can
Speaker 5:  foxcon some of the things to talk about. David wrote a big
Speaker 5:  piece about Google and rcs. They're adding
Speaker 5:  replies and stars to messages and
Speaker 5:  they're doing it in a way that's super annoying. So if you're in a group
Speaker 5:  chat with an iPhone user and they fall back to SMS and you do a tap back
Speaker 5:  in Android messages, they're gonna start getting the annoying sms. It's like
Speaker 5:  so-and-so did a so and so lecture thing.
Speaker 6:  Yeah it's so petty.
Speaker 5:  It's good. It's so petty.
Speaker 6:  It's so petty. It's so good.
Speaker 5:  But that's a good piece. Interviews some Google PMs who worked on the thing
Speaker 5:  Chris Welch wrote about the new feature in Lightroom content of where Phil
Speaker 5:  is coming to Lightroom. So now you kind of don't eat Photoshop of your photo
Speaker 5:  edits, which is kind of amazing. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  We had, we had Adobe max this week. They announced
Speaker 5:  It was Adobe max this week. Yep. They,
Speaker 6:  They did this big update in Chris is like super, super excited because we're
Speaker 6:  finally like, Lightroom is super annoying. I was really shocked. Like I was
Speaker 6:  honestly shocked when I see saw this pop up on the website. Cuz when I first
Speaker 6:  got in this business I was told if you use Lightroom, you're punk and
Speaker 6:  you don't know anything. Only pros use Photoshop. And
Speaker 6:  I'm not a pro but I wanted to pretend I was one. And so like
Speaker 6:  to see actually that Lightroom is good now and see somebody
Speaker 6:  who's a really good photographer like Chris Wells say it. I was like, oh
Speaker 6:  dang, that's that's big
Speaker 5:  News. It's good. It's expensive, which is its problem but it's good. It's
Speaker 5:  been getting better. It's really good on
Speaker 6:  The iPad. Is it subscription based?
Speaker 5:  It is. Okay. And what you get for the subscription, it's a bunch of storage
Speaker 5:  right? Yeah. So it works out but it's really good on the
Speaker 5:  iPad. All the jokes about U S C C aside Light room on an iPad
Speaker 5:  Pro with the second generation pencil, like the whole thing
Speaker 5:  choice. And you know, especially with the newer chips
Speaker 5:  super fast before the MacBook went to m m one
Speaker 5:  chips, I preferred Lightroom on my iPad cuz it was so much faster than my
Speaker 5:  Intel MacBook Pros. Wow. It's it's a thing. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  I mean it just looks really, really cool. The, the other big news that came
Speaker 6:  out of Adobe Max was that like, you know every year they do something
Speaker 6:  wacky and they're like this is the future. And this year they were like,
Speaker 6:  if you give us a picture of someone we can make that
Speaker 6:  we can turn them into a puppet and make them dance.
Speaker 5:  I mean that's pretty cool.
Speaker 6:  And yeah, there's like Jess Weathered who's a
Speaker 6:  new reporter, she's on our international team. She's lovely. She watched
Speaker 6:  all of the Adobe Max stuff, paid attention to it and she's put a
Speaker 6:  Jiff into this thing and it's just these two cutouts of people
Speaker 6:  doing the Oppa gun gum style.
Speaker 5:  The Gunga style. Yeah. If
Speaker 7:  You haven't seen this, you should,
Speaker 5:  It's
Speaker 6:  Worth it. It's a really, it's like they're deeply unsettling images.
Speaker 6:  Adobe has not figured this out yet. I've
Speaker 6:  rarely been more terrified.
Speaker 5:  This is my TikTok strategy is I'm just gonna do an AI version of myself
Speaker 5:  doing TikTok dances. Watch
Speaker 7:  This and then watch the trailer for Megan.
Speaker 5:  You'll get that movie looks bonkers. Allison
Speaker 5:  Johnson has a big piece on EIM and what that's like.
Speaker 5:  Alison obviously is a phone reviewer so she switches from iPhone to enter
Speaker 5:  it all the time with physical sim card. Just do it. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  with an Ssim card. You gotta get corporations involved in your
Speaker 5:  situation and that sucks. Turns out that sucks.
Speaker 6:  She was actually at the office when, when she did the switch and
Speaker 6:  we just, everybody just heard an oh no
Speaker 6:  because cause she's like, I gotta call Verizon because
Speaker 6:  she's like on the phone with the Verizon doing the switch. But they did the
Speaker 6:  switch and because they did the switch, the phone she was on no longer worked.
Speaker 6:  So it just connected her but then the new phone didn't work.
Speaker 5:  This is the promise in the peril of ssim, right? The promise is
Speaker 5:  you can provision your phone onto anyone's network at any time
Speaker 5:  without a piece of plastic. Yeah. Things like push the buttons and see
Speaker 5:  it. That promise is, I would say halfway realized. Right? The real and say
Speaker 5:  that promise is you open the cellular settings on your phone, you see all
Speaker 5:  the available networks in your area. There's speeds, their prices there
Speaker 5:  plans you pick and choose and switch
Speaker 6:  It. Oh that's a way better promise than what I heard about ems. I want that
Speaker 6:  one.
Speaker 5:  But that there're nowhere close to that. That's just me saying here's some
Speaker 5:  cool shit that could happen. What's the process? I
Speaker 6:  Think that would be really cool. I want that.
Speaker 5:  You can kind of do that on iPad. What's the promise? You heard?
Speaker 6:  I just heard that. Oh are you traveling internationally now? You don't need
Speaker 6:  to find one of those stupid little sim card removers to switch your sim
Speaker 6:  out. You can just be like bam. Internet.
Speaker 5:  So your promise to vSim was will reduce paperclip usage. Yes.
Speaker 5:  Worldwide. All right. So it's a spectrum. Spectrum on the high end of
Speaker 5:  the spectrum is free and open competition. A more informed
Speaker 5:  consumer making better and more rational choices. A little couple ticks
Speaker 5:  below that. You won't need a paper clip. And then there's where
Speaker 5:  we are, which is, oh shit, the carriers have locked you in and
Speaker 5:  actually switching your account from one phone to another got
Speaker 5:  substantially harder because it's not just moving piece of plastic, it's
Speaker 5:  moving someone else's software authorization for piece
Speaker 5:  of hardware. Which is exactly what it sounds like. Bad. So we'll
Speaker 5:  see. Maybe it'll get easier. We'll see. But that piece is really good. You
Speaker 5:  should read it. It it is really the promise in the apparel. Like the promise
Speaker 5:  is apparent. We all know what the end state should be. The reality is very
Speaker 5:  different. And then there's a new generation of Thunderbolt that Mitchell
Speaker 5:  Clark wrote about it. This is really interesting. So Intel gave up the basis
Speaker 5:  of Thunderbolt or the basics of Thunderbolt for USB four. So now
Speaker 5:  Thunderbolt and USB are kinda the same thing. I dunno, I kind of don't understand
Speaker 5:  why Thunderbolt exists anymore.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I think it, it really struggles to exist now because USB
Speaker 6:  four is like gonna be really fast when we start seeing it in actual
Speaker 6:  products.
Speaker 5:  I can't wait until it comes to Apple TV remote.
Speaker 6:  It's gonna be amazing in 2035.
Speaker 7:  It brings us right back around to where we started. The problem is standards
Speaker 7:  groups. We need a standards groups focused on getting rid of standards groups.
Speaker 7:  Are you guys with me? Are you in, Let's create it.
Speaker 6:  NE's starting it. He's
Speaker 5:  Interviewed the heads of many standards groups over the past many
Speaker 5:  years. They're, they're that they're the most politician politicians I interview
Speaker 5:  cuz they, their job is to make sure no one's mad,
Speaker 6:  But everybody ends up mad. But
Speaker 5:  Everyone's always mad.
Speaker 6:  They suck at their jobs.
Speaker 5:  They can't, but they're, it's like an impossible job. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  But so it seems like the difference is the, if you have the USB
Speaker 7:  four V2 device or cable, then certain features are optional.
Speaker 7:  But if you are, if you have Thunderbolt, then those optional features are
Speaker 7:  definitely in there. Is what it sounds like on some of them.
Speaker 6:  I mean that's kind of what we've seen so far with Thunderbolt in usb. Right?
Speaker 6:  Like I can, I can run my, my monitors off of a
Speaker 6:  USB port on my computer, but they're gonna run a lot nicer off the
Speaker 6:  Thunderbolt one because it's got a higher bandwidth guaranteed. And
Speaker 6:  USB's always struggled with being like, yeah, you can pick and choose everything.
Speaker 6:  Oh no your, your laptop exploded because you used the wrong charger. Sucks
Speaker 6:  for you, it's gonna take
Speaker 7:  10 minutes to transfer that video file because you are using the wrong
Speaker 7:  cap. But
Speaker 6:  It's very, it's very Doby vision HDR 10 plus where it's like, yeah,
Speaker 6:  one of these is good but the other is actually way better. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  I think
Speaker 6:  That's great. It's more expensive in every way.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And one involves paying until licensing fee. Yeah, fair enough.
Speaker 5:  Some other things to call out. Our Homeland series continues. That's our
Speaker 5:  big series about TSA and security in America. It's the 20
Speaker 5:  year anniversary of the tsa, which is frightening to think about that Sarah,
Speaker 5:  John and Sergio almost have a piece about the Portland van abductions in
Speaker 5:  2020, which is just a thrilling caper. So I encourage you to go read that.
Speaker 5:  Nicole Wetsman has been paying a lot of attention to the fertility features
Speaker 5:  that are being added to all kinds of tech products, including the Apple Watch.
Speaker 5:  All these things are getting added. They're filling a void that exists in
Speaker 5:  the context of the dobs decision that overturn Roe v. Wade. So
Speaker 5:  like this incredible collision of tech
Speaker 5:  companies seeing a market, the culture war
Speaker 5:  and a politics of abortion changing dramatically for the
Speaker 5:  worse. Yeah. And people kind of not knowing what to do or what to believe
Speaker 5:  or how to use these, these products or what data's collected. She's doing
Speaker 5:  an amazing job reporting all that.
Speaker 6:  There's also this weirdness she and I have talked about a bunch about is
Speaker 6:  that like the research isn't there, All the research now isn't being
Speaker 6:  done by, by scientists with no financial, no real financial
Speaker 6:  incentive. It's being done by these companies who do have a financial
Speaker 6:  incentive and they're like, these fertility products are
Speaker 6:  pushing really weird things. Like we have, we
Speaker 6:  have way methods of birth control that we know work that
Speaker 6:  don't require you to own an Apple watch and be like, Oh,
Speaker 6:  not this week honey. So like that's
Speaker 6:  Yeah, she's doing just a tremendous job on this stuff.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I mean this is I think one of the biggest
Speaker 5:  verge stories you can think of. Like what it all the,
Speaker 5:  the colliding themes inside of it, right? The law, the culture
Speaker 5:  of the United States, the politics, bodily autonomy, the
Speaker 5:  tech industry, data privacy. It's all colliding in
Speaker 5:  a really extraordinarily messy and somewhat depressing way. And
Speaker 5:  Nicole's just doing a great job covering it. Yeah. Last few things right,
Speaker 5:  is we have been talking, Andy Hawkins covered the launch of the
Speaker 5:  new GMC Sierra Ev Denali horrible name.
Speaker 5:  It literally just happened. So I basically have no idea about anything except
Speaker 5:  it gets 400 miles of range can power a whole house for to 21 days
Speaker 5:  and it looks ridiculous.
Speaker 6:  I was thinking it looks kinda cool. It
Speaker 5:  Doesn't look, Is
Speaker 6:  It the headlights? The headlights look like
Speaker 5:  It's the headlights, the headlights look Grow lab. I mean it looks like
Speaker 5:  the Silverado, they just GED it up a little bit. Yeah. And the inside has
Speaker 5:  a vertical touch screen with touched controls for climate.
Speaker 6:  I have never wanted to control the seat in my car while I'm driving
Speaker 6:  more than on a giant vertical touch screen.
Speaker 5:  It's ridiculous. It's gonna cost $107,000. So
Speaker 5:  cool.
Speaker 6:  Oh, but they, they changed the name of the front in it.
Speaker 5:  What's the name of the
Speaker 6:  Front? They're calling it the E trunk.
Speaker 5:  The E trunk.
Speaker 6:  Just watching your face as you, you realize that was, I'm
Speaker 6:  sorry.
Speaker 5:  It all, it all just happens. And then lastly,
Speaker 5:  Charles play and Moore reviewed black Adam, which I haven't already yet just
Speaker 5:  went up, but I think it's bad.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, he told me, he told me earlier today it was not very
Speaker 6:  good and it's kind of mean, but not in a fun
Speaker 6:  way.
Speaker 5:  Oh good. Well I'm trying to get the rock in decoder. So if you know the
Speaker 5:  Rock send to me,
Speaker 6:  He can answer for his crimes.
Speaker 5:  He should answer for his crimes. All right. That's it. That's a verse ask.
Speaker 5:  We have as always gone over, if you have eyes on David
Speaker 5:  Pierce, just take a picture, send it to Alex. You can tweet at her. She's
Speaker 6:  All I want
Speaker 5:  Please. Alex h Kranz. Richard is at RJ c I am
Speaker 5:  at Reckless. We love hearing from you. What's Wednesday
Speaker 5:  is iPad. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  All about the iPad and the piles
Speaker 5:  And the David's so mad about Station Manager. Look for that on Wednesday.
Speaker 5:  Dakota this week was Meredith Whitaker, the President's Signal. She talks
Speaker 5:  some shit about RCS two. Ooh, that was a good one. All right. That's it.
Speaker 5:  That's for her
Speaker 5:  chest.
Speaker 2:  And that's a wrap for Vergecast this week. Thanks for listening. If you enjoy
Speaker 2:  the show, subscribe in the podcast app of your choice or tell a friend, you
Speaker 2:  can send us feedback at vergecast@theverge.com. This show is produced by
Speaker 2:  me, Liam James, and our senior audio director, Andrew Marina. This
Speaker 2:  episode was edited and mixed by Amanda Rose Smith. Our
Speaker 2:  editorial director is Brooke Miners and our executive producer is Eleanor
Speaker 2:  Donovan. The Verge Cast is a production of the Verge and Box Media
Speaker 2:  Podcast network. And that's it. We'll see you next week.