# Transcript
ID: 5650b930-33ed-11ed-9a7f-3fa463c053a4
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Websites are back: inside The Verge's redesign
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-808058508291357046/3394783188819406238/s93290-US-3967s-1663132916.mp3
Description: David Pierce and Nilay Patel discuss the ideas behind The Verge's brand new redesigned website, which officially launched on September 13th.
David also chats with senior product manager Tara Kalmanson and senior engineer Matt Crider, who worked on the redesign, about what went into implementing those ideas.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Disabled
Speaker 2:  Welcome to the Vergecast the flagship podcast of Sarah fonts. I'm your
Speaker 2:  friend, David Pierce. And it is currently 5 51 in the morning on
Speaker 2:  Tuesday, September 13th, which means that a, I have to be quiet cuz
Speaker 2:  no one else is awake yet. And B it means we're about nine
Speaker 2:  minutes away from the launch of the new verge.com. We've been working on
Speaker 2:  this for two years. It's a redesign. We have a new logo. It's
Speaker 2:  a totally new way of thinking about how the verge actually works.
Speaker 2:  And so that's actually what this episode is gonna be about. We spent two
Speaker 2:  years on this, like I said, and it made us think some pretty philosophical
Speaker 2:  thoughts about how the internet works and how platforms work and
Speaker 2:  what it means to just be a person on the internet. Now I will
Speaker 2:  warn you. This episode is very Naval gazey. We talk a lot about the verge
Speaker 2:  and a lot about our feelings about the verge, but I think it's really interesting
Speaker 2:  and it was cool to go through the same kind of stuff that a lot of the companies
Speaker 2:  we cover are going through all the time. So we're gonna get to all of that
Speaker 2:  in just a second, but first I'm gonna go refresh our website about 300 times.
Speaker 2:  Cause I can't wait to see it. See, in a sec,
Speaker 2:  Renting a car can be an expensive hassle, but it doesn't have to be
Speaker 2:  TRO is the world's largest car sharing marketplace. They have a wide
Speaker 2:  selection of vehicles ready for you to browse available across the UK,
Speaker 2:  Canada and the us perfect for a variety of budgets
Speaker 2:  and needs. And many, two row hosts can even deliver your car
Speaker 2:  right to your location, whether your road tripping or your everyday car is
Speaker 2:  just out of commission. Every two road trip is backed by liability insurance
Speaker 2:  term conditions and exclusions apply ditch boring rental cars and find your
Speaker 2:  drive@tworow.com
Speaker 4:  With no fees or minimums banking with capital. One is the easiest decision
Speaker 4:  in the history of decisions. Even easier than deciding to listen to another
Speaker 4:  episode of your favorite podcast with no overdraft fees is an
Speaker 4:  even a decision that's banking reimagine what's in your wallet terms
Speaker 4:  supply, see capital one.com/bank capital one, a member
Speaker 4:  F D I C.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. So before we get into the show, just a quick
Speaker 2:  heads up next week, we're gonna be answering all of your questions about
Speaker 2:  Apple's new stuff, all the new phones, new watches, new software,
Speaker 2:  anything you wanna know, all you have to do is call in to the verge hotline,
Speaker 2:  which is 8 66 verge one one, and ask us any of
Speaker 2:  your most burning questions, the weirder, the better, and we will do as many
Speaker 2:  as we can on the show next week. Okay, let's get into it.
Speaker 2:  As I mentioned today, we're gonna focus on websites, mostly one
Speaker 2:  that we made and have spent the last two years, making the new verge, just
Speaker 2:  launched it's new and exciting. And in the process of launching
Speaker 2:  this, I learned a surprising amount about how web CAEs work turns out.
Speaker 2:  They're very complicated. I just came back to the verge in April when the
Speaker 2:  new website was already deep in progress. So I wanted to know where
Speaker 2:  it started, where it came from and why it felt like this
Speaker 2:  was the future of the verge. So I grabbed who else? NEI Patel
Speaker 2:  to talk about it. He's been thinking about this forever. He's been literally
Speaker 2:  like running around V media, talking about revolutionizing the media
Speaker 2:  with blog posts and over the course of his career and the verge
Speaker 2:  we've seen the future of the internet seem like it's changed a hundred
Speaker 2:  times. So we have a lot to talk about here, especially as we look at the
Speaker 2:  next decade, let's get into it.
Speaker 2:  Eli. Hello?
Speaker 6:  Hey man, how's it going?
Speaker 2:  We have a new website.
Speaker 6:  We have a new website. It is two years in the making. I could not be more
Speaker 6:  excited about it.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. So I wanna talk about like what it is and all the implications and
Speaker 2:  the like taglines you've been using obsessively for like as long as I've
Speaker 2:  been here, but this redesign predates me. So I think like I wanna know the
Speaker 2:  story and I think people will too, cuz it's an interesting story. Like start
Speaker 2:  at the beginning. How do we decide to redesign the verge.com? Well,
Speaker 6:  First I just wanna point out that I recruited you back to the verge by showing
Speaker 6:  you the redesign and you quit your job the next day and came to work
Speaker 2:  Here. That is precisely correct. Yes.
Speaker 6:  Which is very good. And that's how I knew it was gonna work. So the redesign
Speaker 6:  it's very simple. Actually our last redesign was six
Speaker 6:  years ago, five years ago. And we did that redesign for
Speaker 6:  what we thought was the era of what you might call distributed publishing
Speaker 6:  Google amp and Facebook instant articles. So we tried to make this thing
Speaker 6:  that could travel everywhere and we put a lot of our emphasis
Speaker 6:  into elements that would say the verge or feel like the verge, no matter
Speaker 6:  where they were. So that's where you got like bright pink pull
Speaker 6:  quotes. That's where you got a lot of our photo styles.
Speaker 2:  So you're saying like, how do we let people share screenshots or videos?
Speaker 2:  And like, have it still be the verge? Like how do we look like the verge
Speaker 2:  even when you're not on the verse.com?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And I think that was really the prevailing wisdom in media
Speaker 6:  back
Speaker 2:  Then websites were dying, that
Speaker 6:  Websites were dying and that Facebook, instant articles take over the media.
Speaker 6:  There was a lot of writing about it, which I won't go into, but there was
Speaker 6:  just a, that was the conventional wisdom of the industry was that the platforms
Speaker 6:  would suck all media into them and we would never open safari
Speaker 6:  again. And we would just read everything in apple news. And to some
Speaker 6:  extent that happened, like it really happened to a lot of publishers.
Speaker 6:  I just think that era is kind of over in one way. If you just look at our
Speaker 6:  traffic, like Facebook, instant articles doesn't exist anymore. Apple news
Speaker 6:  is big, but like we can't feel it. A lot of our stories like hit huge
Speaker 6:  in apple news, but we just like, don't see it. We don't feel it. Like we
Speaker 6:  don't have a community there.
Speaker 2:  I think of apple news as like the print newspaper of 2022 where it's like,
Speaker 2:  I know it's there and I know people consume it. I just don't know
Speaker 2:  anything about what happens there. It's just like a magical other place where
Speaker 2:  people read news.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And I think the most important piece is there's no feedback loop from
Speaker 6:  that platform in particular people read it. They can't talk to you.
Speaker 6:  And then you just look at the other broader trends, where do people talk
Speaker 6:  to us? Like I think the verge has, is a really important part of the verge.
Speaker 6:  It's what we started with. Yeah. I think old time listeners will, will know
Speaker 6:  this. We started the whole site with a podcast was
Speaker 6:  called, this is my next podcast. Cuz we had left in gadget. We, we needed
Speaker 6:  a new podcast and that was the name. Then the site was called, this is my
Speaker 6:  next. And then the first thing to launch with the verge was the Vergecast.
Speaker 6:  So we knew that our success was built on a community of
Speaker 6:  our, our readers and our listeners. And I just was
Speaker 6:  thinking really hard. Like how do I get that back instead of
Speaker 6:  giving it to Twitter or giving it to YouTube or giving it
Speaker 6:  to Reddit or Twitch or discord, all the other things people are doing, which
Speaker 6:  are smart and good, but we happen to have a gigantic website.
Speaker 6:  So we should probably build on our own platform in some way.
Speaker 2:  One of the things I think is really interesting about this moment of time
Speaker 2:  that we're in is like a lot of people are looking at that exact same thing
Speaker 2:  you just described and saying, oh, the thing I need to do is lean deeper
Speaker 2:  into those platforms to say like, this is where this is happening. Like,
Speaker 2:  what I actually need to do is start a discord and try to get people in there
Speaker 2:  or like become a editor. Like you see the, the Washington post strategy is
Speaker 2:  like, how do we build full communities in all of these places? Right. And
Speaker 2:  I think it's very interesting to me that you and the team looked at this
Speaker 2:  and said like, okay, how do we pull some of this back towards us rather than
Speaker 2:  falling into those holes again, for
Speaker 6:  Sure. And I, I think those strategies are actually smart. It's not that we're
Speaker 6:  not gonna do it. You know, we've started publishing this show as a series
Speaker 6:  of talks, right? Like we know that there's audience on those platforms, you
Speaker 6:  have to go to those audiences. I just think the big move
Speaker 6:  is where are you gonna bring those audiences back to? Where are they gonna
Speaker 6:  find you first? And I, we have an asset at the verge that we really
Speaker 6:  haven't taken advantage of in some time, which is our homepage. Our homepage,
Speaker 6:  right, is the single most popular page at V media. The most popular
Speaker 6:  webpage at Vox media on any given day is the verge homepage. So a lot
Speaker 6:  of this was how do I make that page really, really valuable for more people.
Speaker 6:  And then what we coupled that with was de and I were
Speaker 6:  routinely frustrated that we weren't on our own homepage enough. We
Speaker 6:  were both busy. We were running the site, we were making podcasts,
Speaker 6:  we were off shooting videos. And so when the barrier to
Speaker 6:  entry to our own homepage was a 500 word article
Speaker 6:  about something we had seen. It was too high. Like we weren't publishing
Speaker 6:  enough and we were driving ourselves crazy. And we found ourselves using
Speaker 6:  Twitter, which is someone else's platform. Yep. And a good platform. Lots
Speaker 6:  of people use Twitter. They build great communities around themselves. But
Speaker 6:  if you look at what they tend to do with those communities, they convert
Speaker 6:  them to something else that makes them money. And we were like not doing
Speaker 6:  a great job with that.
Speaker 2:  Or they just let them languish and nothing ever happens to them is generally
Speaker 2:  Twitter's move.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. You know, I think a lot of the sub stack writers, right. Their
Speaker 6:  audiences on Twitter and they convert them into paying subst customers. I
Speaker 6:  think that's great. I have no beef with that whatsoever. I just, I'm looking
Speaker 6:  at the gigantic website we run and saying, why am I finding it easier to
Speaker 6:  publish on someone else's platform instead of my own, I'm the boss,
Speaker 6:  that's a weird outcome. Right. But then it's like, you get into
Speaker 6:  what, what a 500 word article or a thousand word article or 10,000
Speaker 6:  word review means to people and you have to deliver the quality
Speaker 6:  bar. So if I was like, I'm just excusing myself from the
Speaker 6:  publishing process or our standards or whatever. So I can just yellow
Speaker 6:  out things that look like tweets in our, our article page one. I think that
Speaker 6:  staff would mute me. I think I would very quickly stop being the boss. I
Speaker 6:  think that's just the end of that. And two, I think we would do disservice
Speaker 6:  to our audience, right? We would, right. We would be sending them the signal
Speaker 6:  of what a product looked like a journalism product looked like, but then
Speaker 6:  not actually over delivering on the product, which is what you wanna do.
Speaker 6:  So we just started having the deed and I were talking to this for a long
Speaker 6:  time and we came up with a phrase which actually I think is too
Speaker 6:  reductive for what our new site is, but we just wanna be able to tweet onto
Speaker 6:  our own website. Right. That was like the first thing we said to our designers
Speaker 6:  and what had happened was Vox media had just merged with New York magazine.
Speaker 6:  So we got all these new designers onto our design team that were the
Speaker 6:  great New York magazine designers. And so we had our existing great design
Speaker 6:  team that we loved. We had these new New York mag designers and we just got
Speaker 6:  to think from a clean sheet, what unearth does tweet
Speaker 6:  onto the website mean? And our first prototype dealer. And I made it
Speaker 6:  in the same life blog tool that we use for apple events. Right. We just
Speaker 6:  were like, we're not gonna think about our technology product. We're just
Speaker 6:  gonna blog the news for ourselves for a day and just see what it feels like.
Speaker 6:  Even that was too much. So we made another prototype in Google docs.
Speaker 6:  So we weren't thinking about other people's software at all. And we were
Speaker 6:  just kind of like figuring it out. And we gave those prototypes over and
Speaker 6:  we ended up with our site where we kind of solved a bunch of problems at
Speaker 6:  once. Like how do most people experience the news in a
Speaker 6:  newsfeed? So our site should just look like a newsfeed.
Speaker 6:  How do we make it easier for our reporters to talk to the audience? Well,
Speaker 6:  you give them the tool they're already used to using to do that, which is
Speaker 6:  something that looks like posting to a newsfeed, like a Twitter or our Facebook.
Speaker 6:  And then how do you, re-promote our own stories without just doing the boring
Speaker 6:  thing that we do now, which is like pin them to the top. You let us write
Speaker 6:  about them like human beings. And then you get to, we turn the next
Speaker 6:  corner, which was, oh, we should be able to embed anything from anywhere.
Speaker 6:  So there's a cool TikTok. We don't have to write a whole article about it.
Speaker 6:  We can literally just say, here's our cool TikTok. It turns out our video
Speaker 6:  team makes a lot of cool talks and they had no access to our own homepage.
Speaker 6:  So now our video team has access to our homepage in something that looks
Speaker 6:  exactly a good news feed. It's familiar. We don't have to like teach anybody
Speaker 6:  how to use it and you just keep stacking it up. And then you get to
Speaker 6:  me saying, I'm gonna revolutionize the media with blog post, which I think
Speaker 6:  we're gonna do.
Speaker 2:  Part of me has wondered through this whole process. If the thing that we're
Speaker 2:  doing is just reinventing the internet circa like 2004
Speaker 2:  back when everybody's theory was like, I'm gonna have my own
Speaker 2:  site and we're, I'm gonna have a blog role and we're all gonna come to each
Speaker 2:  other's websites. And you know, you're gonna sit on my homepage and refresh
Speaker 2:  it a hundred times a day. And there's like a, there's a subset of people
Speaker 2:  who I think like really missed those days. And that was like when RSS readers
Speaker 2:  were big and that was great. And then there's a subset of people who are
Speaker 2:  like, you know, actually Twitter and Facebook are like pretty successful
Speaker 2:  platforms at showing me stuff that I'm interested in and care about.
Speaker 2:  And I think, I don't know, I'm, I'm torn between those two worlds. Like I
Speaker 2:  got started in this world at like the middle of that transition
Speaker 2:  between like the blogging world and the like digital news
Speaker 2:  world. I don't know. Is it like, is this just you wishing it was, was
Speaker 2:  2005 again and you were just like writing a million posts a day.
Speaker 6:  A little bit. Okay. I can't, I can't say no. You know,
Speaker 6:  I got my start in all this when I was sitting in law school and I would refresh
Speaker 6:  the end gadget homepage a hundred times a day. And then I quickly realized
Speaker 6:  like I should get an RS reader. And then I would refresh the RS reader a
Speaker 6:  hundred times a day. And I remember my friends and I used to say,
Speaker 6:  we've run out of the internet. We have to like start paying attention in
Speaker 6:  class because we, we had like read all the blog posts that day. Right.
Speaker 6:  And that feeling was actually like, fine, like looking back on it, that feeling
Speaker 6:  was fine. And now we live in this like world of infinity. Right. And I, I
Speaker 6:  think a lot of people would like the internet to come to an end every day.
Speaker 6:  So yeah, there's a part of it. That's just what I want to feel like
Speaker 6:  is that our site is a conversation that's ongoing and you can come join
Speaker 6:  it. And it does not have the toxicity of a Twitter
Speaker 6:  associated with it. It does not have the chaos of a Facebook
Speaker 6:  newsfeed associated with it. It's where we are. And just like, I,
Speaker 6:  I think the Vergecast audience feels about our show. Our site should feel
Speaker 6:  like you're hanging out with us. It just so happens that we
Speaker 6:  are really excellent journalists who are smart and know, know what we're
Speaker 6:  talking about, but like what, the way it should feel is that it's a
Speaker 6:  community. Right. And that, that I think is missing from so many places on
Speaker 6:  the internet.
Speaker 2:  I think that's right. And I think the thing to me that really jumped out,
Speaker 2:  like when you first showed me, I think it was just a bunch of like Figma
Speaker 2:  pages that you were just like, look, here's, here's some things it was like
Speaker 2:  to me, the internet is so uncurated now in really crappy
Speaker 2:  unpleasant ways where like I go, I was thinking about this the other day,
Speaker 2:  like when you have five minutes to kill, where do you go? Right. And I like,
Speaker 2:  I go to Twitter and it makes me angry or I go to TikTok and then it's been
Speaker 2:  like 50 minutes and I'm still in the bathroom and that's awkward. And then
Speaker 2:  I say, that's not any good, like Instagram is just the same thing.
Speaker 2:  Now, YouTube, all the videos are too long. I don't know. So it's like, there
Speaker 2:  just, isn't like a, a place to go and find stuff that I'm interested
Speaker 2:  in. And even news websites, like there's tons of them. Lots of them are very
Speaker 2:  good, but they all just like have their own stuff and pretends like the rest
Speaker 2:  of the world doesn't exist. And one thing I've always liked about the verge
Speaker 2:  is that it like acknowledges that the internet is a large place full of people
Speaker 2:  who don't work at the verge and that sometimes they do interesting things
Speaker 2:  and that's all well and good. But I feel like the cool thing about the thing
Speaker 2:  that we're trying to do is like, we're just gonna tell you about all the
Speaker 2:  stuff you should know about and not in like a businessy sound
Speaker 2:  smart in your first meeting way, but like a, the, Internet's like a
Speaker 2:  cool, interesting place and we're good at finding it cause we do it for a
Speaker 2:  living. And there's just not a lot of that. Like I used to spend a lot of
Speaker 2:  time on long form and like old dig and Reddit is still very good at
Speaker 2:  this, but there's just like, not that many places where I'm just like, I
Speaker 2:  have five minutes to kill, show me some cool stuff from people I like and
Speaker 2:  trust. And that's like, I wish more of the internet felt like that.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And I, I do think there's an element of that. That was that old
Speaker 6:  blogging experience. Yeah. I'll give great credit to our friend, John Gruber,
Speaker 6:  daring fireball during fireball, is that still he's built an entire
Speaker 6:  career doing that. Certainly there's some inspiration from that in our site.
Speaker 6:  But I think there's also just another turn of it, which is you've gotta,
Speaker 6:  gotta actually reconceptualize that into the product that people are familiar
Speaker 6:  with, which is a newsfeed. There's a little bit of the old blog ideas in
Speaker 6:  there, but we didn't inherit all of them. Right. This isn't in gadget from
Speaker 6:  2006 or whatever, where we used to say like read more after the jump,
Speaker 6:  like there's a whole set of moves. We could glue back
Speaker 6:  onto this product. But really I think the audience
Speaker 6:  now is just like used to newsfeed. So we actually made it more like a newsfeed
Speaker 6:  and more like, Hey, we're just pointing you at other stuff instead of,
Speaker 6:  Hey, there's more here. And one of my biggest goals, like one of our, the
Speaker 6:  big number that I'm looking at is how much traffic we send out. I
Speaker 6:  think we will be a huge success if we are sending a meaningful amount of
Speaker 6:  traffic to other people, right. And they can see it and we can see it cuz
Speaker 6:  that relationship between publishers and platforms has
Speaker 6:  gotten totally outta whack. Most publishers get their traffic from Google
Speaker 6:  and their newsrooms are paying attention to Twitter, which actually sends
Speaker 6:  nobody any traffic. We can very quickly send a lot of people more traffic
Speaker 6:  than Twitter. I think. So if we can just get back in the game where we're
Speaker 6:  like, Hey, you can build your own communities on your own
Speaker 6:  platforms. Once again, in a format that feels both very modern
Speaker 6:  because it's a newsfeed, but inherits the best parts of what people
Speaker 6:  loved about blogging. And you're like a good citizen of the internet
Speaker 6:  because you're sharing the wealth. I think that let lets you
Speaker 6:  kind of reset that whole relationship a little bit and then potentially build
Speaker 6:  whatever the next things are without constantly scrambling against whatever
Speaker 6:  algorithm update, whatever platform is gonna roll out to up or down
Speaker 6:  rank, whatever content.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Well, okay. So I wanna come back to Google because you have mad spicy
Speaker 2:  takes about Google that we're gonna get to in a second. But I think the,
Speaker 2:  the community aspect of this is I suspect gonna be a thing. A lot
Speaker 2:  of people like press against and try to figure out, especially cuz like the
Speaker 2:  first version of the feed that we have, doesn't have comments
Speaker 2:  and it's, it's a thing I know you've been thinking about for a long time
Speaker 2:  and like, are we gonna have like retweets, but they're called like
Speaker 2:  refuges and something happens there and you can like super verge
Speaker 2:  something for 9 99 a month. And like, I don't know, do we end up like
Speaker 2:  algorithmically personalizing these newsfeed, right? There's just like, when
Speaker 2:  you call something a newsfeed, there's this like long road you can trip down
Speaker 2:  into good, but also like deeply weird stuff. And then like
Speaker 2:  three years from now, the verge is just like vertical scrolling video on
Speaker 2:  the homepage. And that's all that we are. This is how it goes. Like we've
Speaker 2:  seen this over and over and over again,
Speaker 6:  Here are all of David Spears. I would like to get to the point where the
Speaker 6:  verge is responsible for the outcome of American democracy. I think we'd
Speaker 6:  be excellent stewards of it. Just to be honest, like we, if we have a goal,
Speaker 6:  that's
Speaker 2:  It I'll take that on. I'm ready for it.
Speaker 6:  You know, I don't know what we're gonna do next. The reason we don't, we,
Speaker 6:  we want to have comments. The reason we don't have comments now is because
Speaker 6:  we are very good at covering platforms and content moderation and we should
Speaker 6:  have a plan for how to grow a healthy community. Before we just light up
Speaker 6:  comments on a hundred more posts today,
Speaker 2:  We've written the like, what if they had thought about this ahead of time,
Speaker 2:  story enough that we should probably think about it ahead of time.
Speaker 6:  Right? And I, I wanna flip it on and see if it works. I want, you know, I
Speaker 6:  I think think the best place to be is for other people to
Speaker 6:  tell us what things they think are obvious, right? Here's this product.
Speaker 6:  And here's what we think is the obvious next step for you. And then you deliver
Speaker 6:  the thing that's obvious to a lot of people that makes them happy. Right?
Speaker 6:  And like, I think there's a relationship with our community there where we
Speaker 6:  want to build that thing together. Just like I, again, I think there's a,
Speaker 6:  the success of the verge in one tiny way
Speaker 6:  is that the verge cast audience is a community, right? And that
Speaker 6:  community for better or worse wants us to take
Speaker 6:  interesting shots at how to cover tech. And so we can take some risks that
Speaker 6:  maybe a more traditional brand, like the times or whatever we can't
Speaker 6:  take. I think we can do that with our website too. I just want, I just wanna
Speaker 6:  make sure that, you know, we have enough moderators or they're sufficiently
Speaker 6:  prepared for the influx of new content or we have a new commenting
Speaker 6:  platform it's called coral, which is very cool. It's part of the V media,
Speaker 6:  but it's powers comments on all kinds of sites all over the world. I wanna
Speaker 6:  make sure people are initiated into coral the correct way. And they're they
Speaker 6:  know how to use the tool and it feels empowering. I can see us getting to
Speaker 6:  a place where in our newsfeed, we might have top commenters.
Speaker 6:  We might be able to promote comments into the newsfeed and say, here's a
Speaker 6:  great comment from a story. You can see all the things we might be able to
Speaker 6:  do. I think we just have to be very judicious at how we
Speaker 6:  grow that and how we do it step by step. Because if we get it wrong,
Speaker 6:  like we know what happens. Like we're really good at covering that story.
Speaker 2:  Well, and I think to me, honestly, the comment side of this is one of the
Speaker 2:  things that's gonna be most interesting to watch because like again, to,
Speaker 2:  you know, rewind a generation of internet media, don't read the comments
Speaker 2:  just became like a truism of anyone who writes online, right? Like the comments
Speaker 2:  was either a thing you got rid of, or just like a cesspool where people
Speaker 2:  were horrible that you were trained to ignore and that no good came of reading
Speaker 2:  the comments. And then eventually everybody sort of outsourced the comments
Speaker 2:  to Twitter and that has its own messy problems.
Speaker 6:  And then they all got addicted to reading Twitter. Right? It's like, it's
Speaker 6:  a weird cycle that happened there. So
Speaker 2:  I guess like the, the thing that I'm curious about is to see like the,
Speaker 2:  obviously the content moderation thing is crucial. And as we've seen over
Speaker 2:  and over anyone who does that at any size beyond like six people, it's a
Speaker 2:  lot of work and it's hard to get. Right. But can we start to solve some of
Speaker 2:  this stuff with product, like as a person on the internet? I think it's fascinating,
Speaker 2:  but especially like to get to watch it within the place that I work is gonna
Speaker 2:  be really, really interesting. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  I mean, people can go check out coral, it's a product you can just use. It's
Speaker 6:  there for you. That team is amazing. They have lots of ideas on how product
Speaker 6:  might build healthier communities.
Speaker 2:  The team at explanation, we should say with all the team blogs, they use
Speaker 2:  the hell outta coral and do some really interesting stuff. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  That all just runs in coral. Polygon uses coral for its comments, like lots
Speaker 6:  and lots of sites outside of oxygen. You use coral, coral is a product, right?
Speaker 6:  It's a product that you can go sign up for and use on your site. So you
Speaker 6:  know, that team has a lot of ideas. I think we have a lot of ideas. I've
Speaker 6:  said content moderation. And you said content moderation. Now I, the game
Speaker 6:  here is not, we're gonna have a bunch of keywords that are bad and then delete
Speaker 6:  the comments. The game actually is how do you build a community?
Speaker 6:  How do you make that space worthwhile? And the reason most publishers were
Speaker 6:  like, don't read the comments, whatever we'll, we'll just turn 'em off. Just
Speaker 6:  cause you have to invest a lot into it to make that good. And it turns out
Speaker 6:  just the math of every publisher is the people who comment are
Speaker 6:  the tiniest fraction of your audience. So you're, you're pointing the most
Speaker 6:  dollars at like the smallest segment of the audience. Right? I think that's
Speaker 6:  actually still valuable to do because hopefully that section of the audience
Speaker 6:  is one that loves you the most. So I, I think we just need a, we need a good
Speaker 6:  plan for how we're gonna grow these communities and how we're gonna make
Speaker 6:  it valuable. I will tell you right now, I know that the women on our staff,
Speaker 6:  the people of color on our staff, the non-binary folks on our staff, social,
Speaker 6:  media's not great for them. Yeah. You know, like we launched with a big feature
Speaker 6:  on star base and you should read it. Lauren Gresh wrote it for us before
Speaker 6:  she went off to Bloomberg. And just like in the middle, she's like being
Speaker 6:  a woman covering star base means people on the internet call me a bitch a
Speaker 6:  lot. Just a fact for her in her life. Well, I think our community should
Speaker 6:  have a higher standard of that. And so our writers, the reason you don't
Speaker 6:  pay attention to comments is like, it's still this, it has the same dynamics
Speaker 6:  of the internet on the comments of the New York times, which is weird. It
Speaker 6:  is weird. And I think we should be able to build a healthier community where
Speaker 6:  we actually get a closer relationship to our writers and our writers are
Speaker 6:  more incentivized to participate because it's a good place to be.
Speaker 6:  That's hard. Right. We had to like ship the first thing first
Speaker 6:  and get to a place where people are telling us what the next obvious thing
Speaker 6:  is. And then put as much thought into that and then ship that.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I buy that. Okay. We need to take a break
Speaker 2:  and actually you and I, and Eli are gonna take a quick pause because
Speaker 2:  I wanna dig into a few of the things about the state of the internet that
Speaker 2:  you've been talking about. So I'm gonna grab a couple of folks on our product
Speaker 2:  team and dig into that. And then you and I will pick back up in a few minutes,
Speaker 2:  we'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  If you run an e-commerce business, you might be laser focused on
Speaker 2:  acquiring new customers, which makes sense at face value until you realize
Speaker 2:  that this isn't necessarily the best business model. According to a Harvard
Speaker 2:  study, acquiring new customers can be anywhere from five to
Speaker 2:  25 times more expensive than retaining existing ones. That
Speaker 2:  same study also found that increasing customer retention rates by 5%
Speaker 2:  increases profits by up to 95%, keeping your customer base engaged
Speaker 2:  and happy is a good way to grow, which is what the Clavio platform can help
Speaker 2:  you achieve. Clavio's email and SMS marketing platform brings all your
Speaker 2:  customer data into one place. Over a hundred thousand e-commerce brands
Speaker 2:  grow their businesses and drive revenue with real time, data segmentation
Speaker 2:  and automations that the Clavio platform offers. So you can now
Speaker 2:  know what your customers want and when they want it. Plus Clavio allows you
Speaker 2:  to drive successful marketing campaigns with pre-built behavior triggered
Speaker 2:  automations. So you can develop long-term customer relationships. It's time
Speaker 2:  to talk to your customers like you know them because you do with Clavio,
Speaker 2:  learn more@clavio.com. That's K L a V I
Speaker 2:  Y o.com.
Speaker 7:  Any job at Amazon can turn into a high paying career for
Speaker 7:  employees looking for security today, Amazon offers good pay and healthcare
Speaker 7:  on day one, new parents also get up to 20 weeks of fully paid leave.
Speaker 7:  So they have the flexibility to spend time with family while making a living
Speaker 7:  for opportunity. Tomorrow, Amazon is investing 1.2 billion
Speaker 7:  into free technical training. That's available to over 750,000
Speaker 7:  associates across the country. With these programs, hourly
Speaker 7:  employees have the opportunity to move into higher paying highly skilled
Speaker 7:  jobs in fields like software engineering and robotics learn
Speaker 7:  more@aboutamazon.com.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. Like we've been talking about building a new website in
Speaker 2:  2022 is a complicated thing, but like
Speaker 2:  I know that, but I really have no idea what that means
Speaker 2:  or what it entails. And also after weeks of testing
Speaker 2:  our new site, I'm desperate to know specifically why TikTok
Speaker 2:  embeds are so terrible. This just keeps coming up over and over again. So
Speaker 2:  I grabbed two people on our product team who know Matt Kreider.
Speaker 8:  I'm a senior engineer working on the verge right
Speaker 2:  Now. And Tara Cosson,
Speaker 9:  I'm a senior product manager in charge of the verge redesign and
Speaker 9:  platform launch for the front end of the website
Speaker 2:  To help me figure it out.
Speaker 2:  What is it like to develop on the web right now with all of the things
Speaker 2:  that the web is? And all of the things we were trying to like pull into this
Speaker 2:  platform is the open web, a good place to develop for right
Speaker 2:  now. How does that feel?
Speaker 8:  Developing on the web is complicated these days I've been
Speaker 8:  building websites since like the Geocity days and professionally
Speaker 8:  for, I don't know, 15 years or so. And it used to be, yeah, just a
Speaker 8:  PHP server, maybe you're running WordPress or ju or something. And
Speaker 8:  there wasn't too much complexity, especially on the front end right now.
Speaker 8:  So much complexities on the front ends in the browser. And there's so many
Speaker 8:  options for what sort of tools you use and people battling
Speaker 8:  which, which one is the right tool to use, to use react or view
Speaker 8:  or whatnot. So there's lots of opinions out there and lots of complexity
Speaker 8:  in deciding what the right tool for the job is. So
Speaker 8:  there's a lot gonna have to keep yourself up to date all the time.
Speaker 8:  And it's, it's a lot, lot of work to be on the cutting edge of, you know,
Speaker 8:  what's good on the web right now. And I think our platform for the verge
Speaker 8:  is a lot of cutting edge stuff. So it's really exciting to kinda work
Speaker 8:  with these new tools, but you're constantly having to learn new things.
Speaker 2:  Give me an example, cuz that's actually one of the things I was gonna ask
Speaker 2:  about, which is like, you guys have been doing this for a long time and I
Speaker 2:  can imagine a world in which like a, a bunch of new stuff crops up as you're
Speaker 2:  working on it. And you're like, no, no, no, we don't. We don't have time
Speaker 2:  to deal with this. We've we know what we're gonna build based on the stuff
Speaker 2:  that we decided to build it with two years ago, or I can imagine there's
Speaker 2:  like a shiny object syndrome where like, somebody's like, like loading a
Speaker 2:  GitHub page, being like, look at this crazy new thing I found every meeting
Speaker 2:  that you possibly have and Tara's laughing like I'm like maybe a little bit
Speaker 2:  right on that one a hundred percent. Right. Is there a right answer on that,
Speaker 2:  on the spectrum between those things? Definitely
Speaker 8:  A spectrum, cuz there are shiny things out there that I'm looking at like,
Speaker 8:  oh this will be really great, but there's so much risk with, you know, technology,
Speaker 8:  right?
Speaker 9:  The beauty of websites in general is, you know, if you're a product manager
Speaker 9:  working on an app or software, you know, you release inversions
Speaker 9:  and it's kind of a serious waterfall process
Speaker 9:  and you cut off at some point. And then all of a sudden, if a feature wasn't
Speaker 9:  included, you're, it's like you're never getting it back. Whereas the web
Speaker 9:  has a short memory and you can at any given moment kind of stare at staging
Speaker 9:  and stare at production. And if staging is better than what's on production,
Speaker 9:  you can choose to ship it and continue to do that every day forever, which
Speaker 9:  is why it's, in my opinion, at least so much more fun than working on an
Speaker 9:  app or software. And it's a little easier then to maybe hedge with your
Speaker 9:  stakeholders to say like, okay, maybe we wanna prioritize
Speaker 9:  shipping faster. And you know, some of these shiny new features can come
Speaker 9:  later and we can test as we release them and iteratively do so.
Speaker 9:  And it kind of gives us a little bit more freedom in that respect.
Speaker 2:  What are some of the shiny things behind the scenes at the verge for, for
Speaker 2:  like the web dev nerds who are gonna be poking around the verge, trying to
Speaker 2:  figure out what's new, what are, what are the shiniest things? I
Speaker 9:  Don't know if it's web dev nerds so much as editor nerds, but some
Speaker 9:  there's some new article leads and article formats that we'd love to
Speaker 9:  introduce, especially in the age of podcasting. And you know, some of our
Speaker 9:  third party tools are not as flexible as we'd like them to be, to really
Speaker 9:  get creative with embeds and things like that. But the way that we tell stories,
Speaker 9:  I think there's a limit to how creative people want the article
Speaker 9:  to be that they're reading. But at some point we can still create
Speaker 9:  something fun on a webpage.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Is that a tricky balance? Cause I was actually thinking about this
Speaker 2:  the other day cuz we, where it was like that brief moment, like when snowfall
Speaker 2:  happened at the York times where everybody was like, the future of news on
Speaker 2:  the internet is like massive bespoke design and everything is
Speaker 2:  gonna feel new and weird and crazy. And that is, I
Speaker 2:  would say mercifully not where we landed generally speaking, there's still
Speaker 2:  some room for some of that. And like we do a lot of really cool bespoke design
Speaker 2:  on the verge, but this idea that like most people on the internet, we, they
Speaker 2:  have like come to expect a certain thing when they come to a site like ours.
Speaker 2:  And part of the job is to like deliver some of that as you guys are building
Speaker 2:  this, like, is that useful constraint? Is it annoying? Is there, is there
Speaker 2:  a tendency to just say like what if we blew up everything and all the texts
Speaker 2:  went like bottom to top just to, just to change things cuz we want to,
Speaker 9:  I think the product and engineering answers are gonna be different for this,
Speaker 9:  but on the product side, it's, it's hugely beneficial because I think
Speaker 9:  most of our readers prefer a simple experience that loads really fast.
Speaker 9:  And I think the Virgin particular does a great job of designing something
Speaker 9:  that facilitates the storytelling and allows the page to still load fast.
Speaker 9:  I think when design becomes a part of storytelling, you know, the magic happens
Speaker 9:  at, at that intersection, but the whole trend of Google amp and Facebook
Speaker 9:  instant and apple news, they're not necessarily going away. They are a different
Speaker 9:  form now than they, they were when they started, but they still rest on the
Speaker 9:  same hypothesis that users want faster loading webpages that have less
Speaker 9:  JavaScript and just are a lot simpler and Google still prioritizes
Speaker 9:  or ranks better. All of those sites that kind of fit that same
Speaker 9:  philosophy. And so it's forced us to think a lot more
Speaker 9:  seriously about page speed and the trade offs with, you know,
Speaker 9:  the really fancy design stuff and the animations and stuff shooting across
Speaker 9:  the page. You know, that's, it's really not easy to prioritize things like
Speaker 9:  that anymore.
Speaker 8:  I think there's a time and a place for those snowfall que articles. I mean
Speaker 8:  the verge does some really great ones. That was my job before I came to boxes,
Speaker 8:  building those sorts of articles. But yeah, I think in general when people
Speaker 8:  want the news, they don't always want, you know, an insane interaction.
Speaker 8:  They just wanna read some content.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. That's very fair. Terry, you just brought up speed, which is a thing
Speaker 2:  I think is really interesting that like it does seem like you can do a
Speaker 2:  lot of stuff on the web. There are sort of lots of options for how to do
Speaker 2:  anything, but the like single most important thing you have to get right
Speaker 2:  as your website has to be fast. And if your website is not fast, users will
Speaker 2:  hate you and Google will hate you and you will fail. I'm like oversimplifying
Speaker 2:  it. But I think like only slightly, is there anything else in the process
Speaker 2:  that is as important as like making the website fast?
Speaker 9:  Definitely the content and as much as the product and engineering teams don't
Speaker 9:  own that that is like 100% more important than speed. I think the quality
Speaker 9:  of the content is the most exciting thing as like on our side to be able
Speaker 9:  to build a site that has quality content is awesome. But aside from that,
Speaker 9:  I think that's kind of the trifecta is content speed and
Speaker 9:  design or usability. I feel like if we get those three things, right, we're
Speaker 9:  in really good shape, but users will excuse speed. If the content is that
Speaker 9:  good and vice versa, you know, it's not a totally gloss cause if you have
Speaker 9:  slow website, but it definitely helps. And that's like one metric that we
Speaker 9:  can affect. So very much our job to like make that, make that happen.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. I dunno. Content is king and that's the most important thing for Google
Speaker 8:  too. So that knows you have good content. Maybe it's pick two content design
Speaker 8:  or speed. They're all important. There's certainly like, you know, great
Speaker 8:  websites out there and that are terribly designed, but yeah, they all kind
Speaker 8:  of were contented on those three
Speaker 2:  Things. Yeah. The fact that Dr. Report is successful means there are a lot
Speaker 2:  of ways to do this stuff correctly, I suppose.
Speaker 8:  Totally. But let,
Speaker 2:  Let's talk about the sort of embed code internet, which is like how I've
Speaker 2:  come to think about it. Cuz part of what I think is an interesting challenge
Speaker 2:  and it comes back to kind of the building for the open web thing is like
Speaker 2:  one of the things you all set out to do is build a site that can sort
Speaker 2:  of consume and display all these other things. And like
Speaker 2:  YouTube is famous for having very good and bed codes and making that process
Speaker 2:  very easy for people to like bring other content onto your platform. I don't
Speaker 2:  know that any other platform is like well known for being sort of
Speaker 2:  famous to tap into and use this way. But we also live in a time where like
Speaker 2:  everything is APIs and you can start to call APIs and sort of integrate
Speaker 2:  other stuff into your own platforms. And I don't know, there's a lot of things
Speaker 2:  kind of all happening simultaneously. Like is it as hard as I would think
Speaker 2:  to build a thing that can sort of be a responsible
Speaker 2:  displayer of all of these different things all over the internet,
Speaker 8:  It's super easy to build it. It's super hard to build
Speaker 8:  it well. Okay. There's so many platforms that provide an
Speaker 8:  API or some sort of way of embedding their content into your site.
Speaker 8:  And it's pretty easy to kind of to figure that out.
Speaker 8:  Most of them use an open standard called oh embed, which
Speaker 8:  is basically you can put in a URL and the service will respond with like,
Speaker 8:  this is how you should embed me to your site, but once you get it in there,
Speaker 8:  there's so many problems as far as performance. And
Speaker 8:  then you gotta ask yourself like why is the service allowing their
Speaker 8:  platform to be used outside of, you know, where they can make money off of
Speaker 8:  it? So there's definitely some risk involved in putting in these
Speaker 8:  third party services, but just generally doing it in a performance
Speaker 8:  way is pretty tricky.
Speaker 9:  In addition to performance and speed. There's also the design question. Like
Speaker 9:  these things are really not that flexible. And so if you're trying to do
Speaker 9:  something really creative, it can be really hard to help them play well.
Speaker 9:  And then there's privacy concerns which Matt was alluding to. And you know,
Speaker 9:  if these embeds are trying to track their users on other sites on the internet
Speaker 9:  and dropping cookies on our site, you know, with the increasingly
Speaker 9:  expansive GDPR, CCPA and privacy laws all over the world,
Speaker 9:  that's just a lot of cookies to find, identify and treat properly.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I was, I was actually gonna ask about that cuz I do think one of the
Speaker 2:  things that people are increasingly sensitive to largely thanks to Facebook
Speaker 2:  is the idea that like wherever Facebook appears in my web
Speaker 2:  browsing universe, Facebook gets data about me. And it's obviously not just
Speaker 2:  true about Facebook. It's true of lots of these platforms. Have you guys
Speaker 2:  thought through kind of what our job is and what it means like as the
Speaker 2:  verge to be a, to handle that the correct way, what is the right answer there?
Speaker 9:  It's a little bit binary. If the ed appears they can track you
Speaker 9:  so users can, should, and legally should be in many
Speaker 9:  places allowed to opt out, but it often means that we can't display the ed.
Speaker 9:  And a lot of times that is a huge part of the storytelling or the content.
Speaker 9:  So it's the user's choice, but it comes with a, a trade off for them, which
Speaker 9:  is unfortunate. A lot of times the reporting will say something about what
Speaker 9:  the tweet said, which can be hard when someone then deletes the tweet and
Speaker 9:  legally we're supposed to delete a tweet, but it's pretty binary, which,
Speaker 9:  which sucks a little
Speaker 8:  Bit. I think that's an interesting concept that is worth exploring. I mean
Speaker 8:  you can opt out of ads like with the CCPA laws in
Speaker 8:  California, you're legally supposed to be allowed to opt out of an ad. We
Speaker 8:  may have to do the same thing for end embeds because I mean, I'm no expert
Speaker 8:  on each platform and what sort of tracking they use, but the major ones like
Speaker 8:  Twitter, Facebook, Instagram, TikTok, they inject like third party
Speaker 8:  Java script on onto your page, which can be like, they have a lot of
Speaker 8:  power through that little end embed window. They, they have one ability to
Speaker 8:  do tracking if they so choose. So I think, yeah, that's kind of a,
Speaker 8:  kind of a privacy gray area that is worth exploring more
Speaker 9:  As a user. You can reject ad tracking and personalized ads, but you
Speaker 9:  can't necessarily reject the ability to like see an ad unless it's through
Speaker 9:  an ad blocker. I dunno it would be nice if embeds were the same.
Speaker 2:  Well, and I think it's, it's part of, what's interesting about it is like
Speaker 2:  we all had this, you know, long sort of internet wide debate about like the
Speaker 2:  Facebook tracking pixel that was in everybody's site. And then there was
Speaker 2:  the like, is it worth having the sign in with Google thing in
Speaker 2:  exchange for, you know, the data that you're giving? And it feels like embeds
Speaker 2:  in a certain way are like the most complicated version of that. Because even
Speaker 2:  if I don't want access to the platform, like if there's a video I wanna watch,
Speaker 2:  I wanna watch the video. And I sort of understand why YouTube is like, well,
Speaker 2:  if you wanna watch the video, you have to like engage with all the pieces
Speaker 2:  of our platform, but then on the, on the flip side, like that sucks. And
Speaker 2:  so I just like where all of that is supposed to shake out and will,
Speaker 2:  I think is really complicated and interesting. And is the kind of thing that
Speaker 2:  is just like not put in front of users. Like I don't know that most people
Speaker 2:  think about the fact that like when I see an embedded tweet on a website
Speaker 2:  like that is in a certain way, I am now engaging with Twitter, the platform,
Speaker 2:  it's just a thing that is happening. And I think most people are like, just
Speaker 2:  not even aware of that or sort of thinking about what that interaction
Speaker 2:  actually looks like, which is really interesting.
Speaker 8:  And you don't even have to be a Twitter user or like a Facebook user, like
Speaker 8:  they're able to, to track you through the entire internet
Speaker 8:  regardless of your log in or not. I always wonder what the motivations are
Speaker 8:  for companies to open up these platforms. And like, it's pretty clear, like
Speaker 8:  they're getting some really useful data from folks
Speaker 2:  To that point. Actually, one of the things that has surprised me in the course
Speaker 2:  of testing our new site before it went live is how awful some of these embed
Speaker 2:  codes are. Because to your point, a lot of these companies have like a really
Speaker 2:  large incentive to do this really well, especially with video, which is this
Speaker 2:  like massively competitive space. And everybody's trying to get you to
Speaker 2:  post on reels instead of shorts, instead of TikTok, whatever you would think
Speaker 2:  everybody would be competing to like make the best, most
Speaker 2:  shareable thing. But then we put a TikTok in bed on our site and it's like
Speaker 2:  400,000 pixels tall and just randomly breaks. And autoplay is when
Speaker 2:  it feels like it, are these things getting better over time? Or is this just
Speaker 2:  a crappy thing that everybody seems to have kind of forgotten to make better
Speaker 2:  in the process?
Speaker 8:  Historically they, everything has been getting worse. I
Speaker 8:  mean, it's kind of risky to depend on a third party in
Speaker 8:  be because there's been so many examples of something of a platform
Speaker 8:  opening up their service to developers and then completely changing
Speaker 8:  how it works or shutting down. I mean, I have plenty of old websites
Speaker 8:  around that had a Google map embedded in it or, you know, an
Speaker 8:  Instagram feed and they just don't work anymore because they changed the
Speaker 8:  rules of their API. Do you all remember Vinny? Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Wow.
Speaker 8:  Video embedding service. I won't get too deep into that, but
Speaker 8:  like some other company bought it and completely changed what videos were
Speaker 8:  being accomplished on a lot of major media outlets. So there's
Speaker 8:  a lot of risk with embedding third party scripts or embeds.
Speaker 8:  A lot of like benefits, like Neil said that he's, we want to use the
Speaker 8:  entire web as a CMS, a content management system, which is really, really
Speaker 8:  cool. But as a developer has seen a lot of these things go bad.
Speaker 8:  It's, it's a little scary. Sometimes there's, there's a bit of re to throw
Speaker 9:  A bone to the poor product managers who are in charge of embeds at like Instagram
Speaker 9:  and Facebook. I feel like they're evaluated on probably two things. And one
Speaker 9:  of them is how much traffic are they driving back to their own feeds and
Speaker 9:  their own sticky experiences or retention based experiences. And then the
Speaker 9:  second is how much data are they collecting, which then also enables them
Speaker 9:  to increase signups or increase retention or whatever their other metrics
Speaker 9:  are. So by those respects, I'm sure that they're doing great. And I think
Speaker 9:  probably the, you know, our use of embeds for the redesign is probably an
Speaker 9:  edge case. Like it's a lot more creative than your average, you know, drop
Speaker 9:  an Instagram post in a, a story and, and let it take over the
Speaker 9:  whole width of the column and, and be a little annoying. So in defense
Speaker 9:  of those product managers, I'm sure that they're hitting their metrics, but
Speaker 9:  it would be really nice if there were just a couple more options
Speaker 9:  for like max widths that you could set that were a little bit smaller.
Speaker 9:  Ah-huh any product managers listening. I will happily send you a really
Speaker 9:  fancy, fancy gift basket. If in the next year you can
Speaker 9:  ship something like that for us would be awesome. The poor
Speaker 9:  publishers need some help.
Speaker 8:  Dark Mo toggle would be good. Ooh.
Speaker 2:  Yes. Dark Mo toggle. Okay. This is good. We're just gonna, we'll end this
Speaker 2:  with just like a long list of things that we'd like people to build for us.
Speaker 2:  That seems, that seems like it'd be good. No, the last thing I wanna talk
Speaker 2:  about before I let you go, is the future proofing kinda like you, you were
Speaker 2:  talking about Matt, because I think one of the interesting moments that we're
Speaker 2:  at right now, like you guys are saying is like the web is changing really
Speaker 2:  fast. The platforms are changing really fast. The odds that all
Speaker 2:  the platforms we're using and embedding right now are gonna be here or
Speaker 2:  relevant in 10 years when we do this again is like vanishingly small. So
Speaker 2:  as you guys are going through this process, I guess a how far out
Speaker 2:  into the future, is it even sort of useful to think given how quickly
Speaker 2:  everything changes and then also like, is there stuff you can do in this
Speaker 2:  process to sort of give it the longest possible shelf
Speaker 2:  life? Part of developing for tech to me just seems like you just have to
Speaker 2:  get comfortable with the idea that every two years you're gonna have to throw
Speaker 2:  everything out and start over because everything just seems to change all
Speaker 2:  the time. Is there stuff that you can and have done to mitigate any of that?
Speaker 8:  The short term problem is kind of working with some of the performance issues
Speaker 8:  that are coming with embedding lots and lots of third party content onto
Speaker 8:  site long term. It's a really interesting question. One of the recommendations
Speaker 8:  like by, by Google is to use an image of
Speaker 8:  DM embed. So like an image of a tweet, they call it, I think they call it
Speaker 8:  a facet. And only when you interact with that image, like hover over,
Speaker 8:  it will actually load the content. So that's kind of a best
Speaker 8:  practice that is really hard to do, but I think is really worth looking
Speaker 8:  into with the side effect that third party ed stopped
Speaker 8:  working in a couple years. You still have that image,
Speaker 9:  Which is definitely illegal and you can definitely get sued for that.
Speaker 9:  I definitely don't speak from experience.
Speaker 8:  I don't worry about that part.
Speaker 2:  Tara, what about you? What are you thinking about as, as you think about
Speaker 2:  like the next 1, 2, 5 years of this project, like has, have you
Speaker 2:  had to think about that stuff over the last couple of years?
Speaker 9:  Definitely. And I'll kind of answer your question with a question, which
Speaker 9:  is how long should some of this stuff live anyway. And I
Speaker 9:  think in, in one respect to play a part in the public record, it it's important.
Speaker 9:  And it's important that this stuff live forever, at least in some way,
Speaker 9:  but it doesn't mean that like every Instagram post should live forever. Every
Speaker 9:  TikTok should live forever. I think the law maybe made the right call that
Speaker 9:  people should be able to take down their Instagram posts and actually disappear
Speaker 9:  from the internet instead of having like screenshots of things everywhere.
Speaker 9:  Although I really still to this day, I don't know how lawyers like find these
Speaker 9:  screenshots sprinkled everywhere, but two years feels like a great shelf
Speaker 9:  life for like the end embeds in an article. And if people take them down,
Speaker 9:  I feel like that's totally fair. And, and it makes some sense. And by then,
Speaker 9:  hopefully we've moved on to newer and better things and people can,
Speaker 9:  whatever the next social network is.
Speaker 8:  I don't think there's a technological answer to this because otherwise all
Speaker 8:  these, all my old websites would still be working, but content people
Speaker 8:  exist without this ed, you know, images all have out text for
Speaker 8:  screen readers. So maybe this, the text surrounding the, the VE
Speaker 8:  should be able to describe what it was because it probably
Speaker 8:  will go away one day.
Speaker 2:  Then the sort of the job for us as the verge is to like
Speaker 2:  preserve the stuff that we make in a way that stands the sense of time, rather
Speaker 2:  than sort of worry about trying to like archive the
Speaker 2:  entire internet into our own servers.
Speaker 9:  So many products and especially social products are skewing ephemeral. Not
Speaker 9:  that that's a hip word anymore, but you know, it makes sense that, you know,
Speaker 9:  news is ephemeral too. It just has a bit of a longer shelf life. And thinking
Speaker 9:  of it that way gives me a little bit of peace with the trash embeds that
Speaker 9:  we find on our site sometimes.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And listen, we have stuff on our site from 10 years ago that it's just
Speaker 2:  horribly broken and it, I still enjoy it every time I land on it. So it's,
Speaker 2:  it's all right.
Speaker 9:  I don't know if vine and embed still work, but it would be cool if
Speaker 2:  They did somebody find a VI, me ed, and, and tweeted at us
Speaker 2:  and we'll see if it works. I'm very excited about
Speaker 9:  It. You know, nothing lives forever. And it, it makes sense that you know,
Speaker 9:  every now and then it makes sense to start from scratch and build a new platform
Speaker 9:  in whatever the latest programming languages are. It's like helpful for attracting
Speaker 9:  great engineering talent. Like Matt, it's helpful for making sure that we
Speaker 9:  can reevaluate and cut out features that we're not using anymore. It's a
Speaker 9:  good opportunity to take advantage of site speed or whatever other things
Speaker 9:  can like help us create a more performant website. So it's
Speaker 9:  bittersweet to launch a new stack sometimes because so much work
Speaker 9:  and so many beautiful features went into the old one. But you know, that's
Speaker 9:  ephemeral too, I guess.
Speaker 2:  Well, thank you both for doing this congrats on, you know, the end of not
Speaker 2:  the end, but the end of two years of work in the beginning of I'm sure many
Speaker 2:  more years of work,
Speaker 9:  It's only the beginning.
Speaker 8:  Oh yeah.
Speaker 2:  All right. We're gonna take a quick break. And when we get back, we're gonna
Speaker 2:  get back to Eli and get real big picture and philosophical
Speaker 2:  about the future of Google, the future of search and the relationship
Speaker 2:  with the verge and digital media and the future of everything. We'll
Speaker 10:  People love what's next, the big new thing that everyone has to
Speaker 10:  have, but how do you fight through the idea ending silos, barriers and
Speaker 10:  endless meetings with Smartsheet? Just lay out the perfect process
Speaker 10:  then grab the best people and resources, automate tasks
Speaker 10:  and meet every change with flexibility, everybody together,
Speaker 10:  delivering great work and ready for what's next. Visit
Speaker 10:  smartsheet.com/power. Your process.
Speaker 11:  Hi, I'm Kara Swisher for decades. I've covered Silicon valley, Washington
Speaker 11:  and Hollywood making sense of those worlds by talking directly to the
Speaker 11:  people who shape them. Elon Musk, Barack Obama, Tony Fauci,
Speaker 11:  Kim Kardashian. I've had the pleasure of grilling them all.
Speaker 11:  Now I'm launching a new show called the Joe Rogan experience with Kara
Speaker 11:  Swisher. Just kidding. It's actually called on with Kara
Speaker 11:  Swisher. And let me tell you it is on no holds
Speaker 11:  barred on the tough questions or on my opinions on with Kara
Speaker 11:  Swisher launches September 26th from New York magazine and the Vox media
Speaker 11:  podcast network. Just look for on with Kara Swisher in your podcast
Speaker 11:  app and hit, follow or subscribe.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. And Eli, welcome back. Hey buddy, let's talk about
Speaker 2:  Google, because my sense is that a big part of the future of
Speaker 2:  media thinking that led to this redesign was that basically
Speaker 2:  we wanna be less reliant on Google as a thing. We've talked
Speaker 2:  about platforms we've talked about video, but the honest reality is that
Speaker 2:  Google is the main driving force behind most publishers traffic, I
Speaker 2:  assume, including our, so what is the bet here on the
Speaker 2:  future of Google and the verge?
Speaker 6:  Oh man, that is a spicy question. So lemme just put that whole thing into
Speaker 6:  context. So I think a lot of people are very familiar with
Speaker 6:  Facebook's relationship to the media, right? There was a point I think in
Speaker 6:  early 2013 or 2014, where Facebook just started firing
Speaker 6:  traffic in the media sites like news on Facebook took off, everyone realized
Speaker 6:  it, there was a land grab of like, can we make kitty video
Speaker 6:  webpages for Facebook? Right? And some publishers were massively successful.
Speaker 6:  Then Facebook was like, we're turning that off. And they turned it off. And
Speaker 6:  a lot of publishers collapsed.
Speaker 2:  There's literally like a knob in Menlo park that they were just like, nevermind.
Speaker 2:  Yeah,
Speaker 6:  They were, they were done newsfeed update, you know, number seven. And then
Speaker 6:  that traffic went away for publishers, right? Because it was dicey for Facebook,
Speaker 6:  right? They were promoting some content, not promoting some content, the
Speaker 6:  politics. So that got tortured. That's a long story. I'll just stop it there.
Speaker 6:  Then Facebook was like, video is gonna be the thing. And they published a
Speaker 6:  bunch of inflated inaccurate video numbers. They've since copped to it many
Speaker 6:  times, a bunch of publishers pivoted to video, right? They shut down
Speaker 6:  their newsrooms made everybody make videos. Buzzfeed put rubber bands around
Speaker 6:  a watermelon until they exploded. You might remember. And everyone thought
Speaker 6:  Facebook video was gonna be business. And then Facebook turned it off and
Speaker 6:  their businesses collapsed. And a bunch of people got laid off. That cycle
Speaker 6:  actually repeats outside of Facebook all the time. So our first big traffic
Speaker 6:  fire hose, when we, when launched the verge in 2011 was Yahoo. Yep.
Speaker 6:  Yahoo would just send us floods of traffic. And we would, we would not know
Speaker 6:  why
Speaker 2:  You've told the Phish stories story on the podcast. Right.
Speaker 6:  I don't know if I told about this, but yes, we, we like did the analysis
Speaker 6:  of where the Yahoo traffic came from and we're like, Yahoo loves stories
Speaker 6:  about Phish. So on like very slow Fridays, we would just Google Phish
Speaker 6:  technology. There's a great story. Josh, ER, wrote a story about
Speaker 6:  the whoosh fish cannon that like repopulates salmon by like shooting them
Speaker 6:  off of ramp. It's ridiculous. Yahoo loves the story. That's like
Speaker 6:  the worst incentive. Right? Right. You're like, here's what the algorithm
Speaker 6:  wants. Now. The verge is about fish. Like it makes no sense the audience
Speaker 6:  except for the apparently massive Yahoo fish audience. But you, you just
Speaker 6:  kind of like get buffeted around by other people's algorithms. The reason
Speaker 6:  we don't talk about Google that way is cuz Google for years has basically
Speaker 6:  been stable. Right? And Google's algorithm is essentially the most transparent.
Speaker 6:  It's not actually transparent, but the input in the output is understood.
Speaker 6:  A lot of people are searching for what time the super bowl is. So if you
Speaker 6:  publish a page that says, what time is the super bowl, Google will efficiently
Speaker 6:  match supply and demand.
Speaker 2:  Right? And the difference is just to put a point on that, like this is, I
Speaker 2:  think you actually said this to me a while ago that like the difference is
Speaker 2:  there's at least an input to Google that like the one way to understand the
Speaker 2:  output is, is as a function of the input. Whereas on like Facebook and other
Speaker 2:  stuff, the input is just like magical, unknown, special sauce.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  You just open Facebook and stuff happens to you.
Speaker 2:  Right? You don't tell Facebook. I would like to watch videos about Phish,
Speaker 2:  Facebook just figures out that you would like Phish. So at least Google is
Speaker 2:  like, the line is not perfectly straight, but there is at least a line from
Speaker 2:  the beginning to the end. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  It it's in there somewhere. And so like most publishers have a Google stride.
Speaker 6:  We were very lucky. We, we published a lot of reviews, people search for
Speaker 6:  reviews. You know, we published a lot of explainers about tech, which is,
Speaker 6:  I think a good audience service people search for explainers. So just like
Speaker 6:  everybody, we get a lot of Google traffic. We get a lot of traffic from the
Speaker 6:  Google news box, but our homepage right up there, it's the second source
Speaker 6:  of our own traffic. Right. People come to our home page, they click on something
Speaker 6:  else. So we had this opportunity that most publishers don't have, which is
Speaker 6:  that our own website drives us a lot of traffic. That's where the opportunity
Speaker 6:  comes from. If we had all bailed and tried to start a new site, we, I think
Speaker 6:  this would've failed. We, we don't have that huge asset, which is the verge
Speaker 6:  audience. So we can deliver a better product to like, it's the easiest sale
Speaker 6:  in the game? Like how do you double the revenue of
Speaker 6:  Chick-fil-A you just open it on Sundays? Like you just like,
Speaker 6:  it's like the easiest proposition in business. So like ours is we just take
Speaker 6:  this thing that people already are telling us. They like by clicking all
Speaker 6:  day and just like make it better, more useful. But I just think I look at
Speaker 6:  Google and I look at this dependency that no one talks about cuz it does
Speaker 6:  feel stable. It does feel understandable. Google is generally
Speaker 6:  honest with publishers. That's what the business side of our business tells
Speaker 6:  me. And I said, well Google, what if it goes away? Right? Like
Speaker 6:  everything else in my career in publishing has gone away. I should have some
Speaker 6:  hedge against whether this thing goes away and maybe it won't maybe, you
Speaker 6:  know, people will search forever and Google will send them to us forever.
Speaker 6:  Like that would be great. I'm not saying I, I absolutely 100%
Speaker 6:  think it's gonna go away. But I feel like we should all be hedged against
Speaker 6:  what if the thing goes away because the history of digital media is that
Speaker 6:  the thing goes away. So the one hand it's okay, how do I hedge it? And then
Speaker 6:  it's on the other hand, it's like, how do you become the thing? Right? So
Speaker 6:  Ben Thompson, who we talk about in the show, lot, he became famous for what
Speaker 6:  he calls aggregation theory, which can go read and he's like power on the
Speaker 6:  internet. Doesn't come from having the supply. It doesn't come from having
Speaker 6:  the product. It comes from owning the demand. And so Google owns the demand
Speaker 6:  and they people tell Google what they want. And Google sends you someplace
Speaker 6:  to fulfill your demand. And that puts Google in an enormous position of power.
Speaker 6:  I think our new site can solve some that, right? Like I think we can say
Speaker 6:  to people, come here, if you are interested in what's cool on the internet
Speaker 6:  or what's interesting in tech and we'll send you to those places,
Speaker 6:  are we, are we gonna be the size of Google? We are not, but are we gonna
Speaker 6:  change our relationship to the audience as opposed to just providing
Speaker 6:  things to Google? I hope so. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  And I think, I mean the, the what time does the super bowl start thing is
Speaker 2:  an interesting one, right? Cuz it's like, that is both sort of like all the
Speaker 2:  people who write that it's like naked internet cynicism where it's like,
Speaker 2:  okay, people wanna know this, I'm gonna write something with that exact headline,
Speaker 2:  but it's also audience service. People wanna know when the Superbowl starts,
Speaker 2:  but the thing that Google will do and if it hasn't yet, I'd be honestly
Speaker 2:  surprised that I'm sure that it will is just put up one of those knowledge
Speaker 2:  boxes that says the Superbowl starts at 6:30 PM. And like we
Speaker 2:  we've seen a lot of data recently about like the zero click Google search
Speaker 2:  and how much Google is adding to search results in such a
Speaker 2:  way that a there's a hundred thousand ads before you get to any actual search
Speaker 2:  results. And B Google has more and more incentive to a keep
Speaker 2:  you within Google so that you don't leave and B to send you
Speaker 2:  to its own stuff. So like Google is really happy to send you to
Speaker 2:  YouTube and really happy to just answer your questions rather than
Speaker 2:  sort of be the like neutral arbiter of everything that it once
Speaker 2:  was. And I haven't totally decided how much I buy
Speaker 2:  the, the sort of conspiracy theory around Google's end game there, whether
Speaker 2:  it's to like capture all of that for itself forever or what, but
Speaker 2:  it does seem like the trend there is Google is like closing at
Speaker 2:  least ever so slightly. And a lot of people are gonna have to reckon, I think,
Speaker 2:  with what that means over time.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. If you just step back and you're like, what would make the best search
Speaker 6:  experience? It's like you ask Google a question, it tells you the answer.
Speaker 6:  I don't think that's controversial. Like if you ask it what time something
Speaker 6:  is, just tell you like that's commodity information, the idea that you have
Speaker 6:  to click onto someone else's website and load their like that's, that's like
Speaker 6:  nonsensical, like, you know, like, should Google have a built-in stopwatch
Speaker 6:  or should it send traffic to stopwatch companies? Like, I that's it's like
Speaker 6:  fundamentally at some point it's just ridiculous. Right. But it is true that
Speaker 6:  Google's money is search. Like that's still where they make all the
Speaker 6:  money. They make a money on YouTube and nothing else makes money.
Speaker 6:  And like that's weird, right? Yeah. Like their ads network and they own the
Speaker 6:  entire ad tech stack they're in the first or second position of every layer
Speaker 6:  of the ad tech stack with one of their divisions. So like Google monetizes,
Speaker 6:  the internet, but like really the money is in surgery. Yep. Okay. Well, if
Speaker 6:  you want to make more money, is Google in an uncertain economic
Speaker 6:  time? What lever might you pull? You might keep more search. Like,
Speaker 6:  I don't know. It's not like a, I don't know it for sure. It's not an
Speaker 6:  accusation I'm making. It's just, when I think about the future of our website,
Speaker 6:  how do I build a hedge against the thing that always happens, which is the
Speaker 6:  thing goes away and might I understand a mechanism of this
Speaker 6:  thing going away and like you can see one that exists and then on top of
Speaker 6:  it, like what's the real goal. The verge should be fun is hell to read. So
Speaker 6:  if I can solve like this weird business problem with a cool
Speaker 6:  thing, we should just make the coolest thing.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. If we can make a place, people wanna hang out, that's a pretty easy
Speaker 2:  win that solves a lot of problems.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And hang out at scale, that's the verge, right? It, I always say
Speaker 6:  it's a big thing that feels really small. I, I hope it feels really small
Speaker 6:  to people. And I think actually for Vergecast listeners, the verge feels
Speaker 6:  smallest of all right. It's like this tiny group of people that they hang
Speaker 6:  out with, they tell, well, get emails. It feels like I'm hanging out with
Speaker 6:  you guys. Our home, our whole homepage should feel like that to everybody.
Speaker 2:  If we were starting the verge right now, like the verge is 11 years old.
Speaker 2:  And like you said, we have this, this longstanding homepage
Speaker 2:  first.com. It's very good website that people go to on purpose. If that
Speaker 2:  wasn't the case and we were starting from nothing, would we have done it
Speaker 2:  the same way? Like do you think you can build that
Speaker 2:  direct audience from nothing in 20, 22?
Speaker 2:  Or can we only even try this because of like the
Speaker 2:  history and credibility that we have with people.
Speaker 6:  So I think that's a really good question. I think we have seen a lot of activity
Speaker 6:  around this question in ways that maybe is not expressed in the form of websites.
Speaker 6:  Hmm. So why do people start newsletters instead of websites
Speaker 6:  now? Because they can send the newsletter right. To you and what does our
Speaker 6:  homepage really look like? Right. Like part of it looks like a newsfeed.
Speaker 6:  Part of it looks like Twitter. Part of it looks like we're just live writing
Speaker 6:  a newsletter every day. Like most great newsletters platform are by Casey
Speaker 6:  Hotpod by Ariel. Like if you just abstract them into what they are, it's
Speaker 6:  a, an essay and then a bunch of blurbs about
Speaker 6:  news. Like there's a curation function. That's built into all the best
Speaker 6:  newsletters. Well, that's our homepage now. Right? It's a bunch of cool
Speaker 6:  curation and then a lot of columns and essays and reports and features and
Speaker 6:  whatever else. Yep. There's similarities there to how people are building
Speaker 6:  direct audiences. I just think getting people to come to your
Speaker 6:  website is an ever increasing ask, getting people to
Speaker 6:  sign up for your newsletter is actually way easier. So I think you see people
Speaker 6:  doing that way faster.
Speaker 2:  Okay. Yeah. I mean, it makes sense. And I think the, how do people come to
Speaker 2:  you? Thing is forever interesting, right? Cause it's like if I have a newsletter,
Speaker 2:  I have to open my email app, which I'm already conditioned to do all the
Speaker 2:  time. Like if you're in my YouTube subscriptions, you're just, you're just
Speaker 2:  in places I already am. And like, I think your point that even if
Speaker 2:  I'm already in my browser, that activity of like opening a new tab and typing
Speaker 2:  in the verge.com and hitting enter is like a not small thing
Speaker 2:  to ask of people. And I, I do wonder if that's like a learned behavior that
Speaker 2:  people who have it have it and people who don't are never gonna learn it.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  I'll give you an example of some like homepages I go to, I have the muscle
Speaker 6:  memory of just typing cnn.com three times a day. Sure.
Speaker 6:  There's a reason for that. It's because of CNN, they know they have one of
Speaker 6:  the biggest homepages in all of media and they're just constantly rotating
Speaker 6:  stuff out. Yep. Right? Like, unless something huge is happening, the CNN
Speaker 6:  homepage is always changing. There's a homepage editor. Like they are moving
Speaker 6:  that page to make it valuable for you. Every time you come back to it,
Speaker 6:  most places don't care about their homepage anymore. You I'm sure anybody
Speaker 6:  listening to this who works in media or ads or marketing, whatever has heard
Speaker 6:  this inter conversation with something called side doors, which basically
Speaker 6:  means everybody comes to you on your article page, through a platform instead
Speaker 6:  of ever going to your homepage, which is why article pages are fast
Speaker 6:  tuned with garbage, right? They're everyone tries to make their article page,
Speaker 6:  do the jobs of a homepage and get you to click on one more story or
Speaker 6:  get you to sign up for something else. We all have the same feelings about
Speaker 6:  that. If you can just make the homepage valuable every time people open it,
Speaker 6:  which you can do with a newsfeed, you can, I hope we can build some of that
Speaker 6:  muscle memory where reward people for actually coming to our website.
Speaker 2:  Okay. All right. And then last thing is like, just talk to
Speaker 2:  me about web design. This is like a, a thing we at the verge care deeply
Speaker 2:  about. And I feel like it's an interesting moment again, as you're talking
Speaker 2:  about to like, think how should a website look like the last time we
Speaker 2:  did this, I wasn't here, but I'm assuming having been through like similar
Speaker 2:  things at different places, there's this question of like, back then, it
Speaker 2:  was like, okay, we have a desktop audience and we have a mobile audience.
Speaker 2:  And the, the like responsive web was a thing that everybody talked about.
Speaker 2:  Right. And now it's just like, if you don't start with phones, you're blowing
Speaker 2:  it because that's how most people will experience you at all times. And like
Speaker 2:  the version com looks very different now than it did in the past.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. But I wouldn't say it's like structurally
Speaker 2:  completely overhauled. It's not like, you're like the internet doesn't
Speaker 2:  need headlines and we're gonna put the images at the bottom.
Speaker 6:  We should do that. I don't know like where, where have you been?
Speaker 2:  But like, was there ever a moment where it was like, is there a
Speaker 2:  blow up in how we think about what a news website could look like
Speaker 2:  process? Like how far down that road did we go? Pretty
Speaker 6:  Far. Okay. I think one thing maybe people should take note of
Speaker 6:  here is we've mostly talked about how the site works. Yep. We have
Speaker 6:  not talked about how it looks, but it looks totally different. It's beautiful.
Speaker 6:  We have a new logo. We haven't talked about the new logo for one second,
Speaker 6:  right? Like at the core of this, what we, what we spent all of our
Speaker 6:  time thinking about is how does this site work? What is the software product
Speaker 6:  that we are shipping to millions of people a day? How does it operate? And
Speaker 6:  then how does our team run it? Right. We changed where all the
Speaker 6:  buttons are. Like we have to assign people to push the buttons. So we had
Speaker 6:  to like restructure our team a little bit to support this task that said
Speaker 6:  the site looks way different. Right. And we have thought really long and
Speaker 6:  hard about how it looks on mobile, of course, but also just like, how
Speaker 6:  does a news page work? What should that experience be?
Speaker 6:  I'll give you this really dumb example. So we actually launched the verge
Speaker 6:  without a great mobile site. All of our readers were on desktop in 2011.
Speaker 6:  And if you'll remember, we had like 95 apps. We had like a windows phone
Speaker 6:  app. Oh
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And somewhere along the way, we're like this and what are we doing? So we
Speaker 6:  shut down all these apps. So it cost so much to maintain. And it was really
Speaker 6:  hard to ship the web into apps back then for a variety of reasons.
Speaker 6:  That's a lot easier. Maybe we'll have an app today, not today, tell the CEO
Speaker 6:  I want an app. So then we shut that all down. We added a mobile page to the
Speaker 6:  old design. And then when we redesign the verge, if you just look at that
Speaker 6:  redesign, yep. We had a bunch of new elements, but we just cleaned it up
Speaker 6:  for mobile. Right. That was like the big thrust of that redesign. When you
Speaker 6:  talk about distributed publishing is we've gotta pair this thing down
Speaker 6:  to its most essential elements so that when
Speaker 6:  Facebook instant articles like re constitutes a webpage, it still looks like
Speaker 6:  us. That whole redesign was just about refinement and like
Speaker 6:  minimizing what we needed to convey that we were the verge. And that really
Speaker 6:  is where neon colors came from. These are bright pink.
Speaker 6:  You see it that's us like that. We were like dead on with that.
Speaker 6:  We had all those like laser lines everywhere. Why? Because we wanted people
Speaker 6:  to see the laser line and know that was us. This redesign
Speaker 6:  carries a lot of that through, right. We know people are gonna mostly see
Speaker 6:  us on phones, but a lot of it is the phones are huge. Now.
Speaker 6:  Like the screens are really big so we can do. And the, everybody has a retina
Speaker 6:  screen. Now that wasn't necessarily true when we last redesign the site.
Speaker 6:  So we can go to things, likes fonts. We can have different kinds
Speaker 6:  of images on the page. We can make the images bigger. In some cases we can
Speaker 6:  make the images smaller actually, cuz they're still big. So there's just
Speaker 6:  a lot of that tweaking for like the modern era. And then there's also just
Speaker 6:  the recognition. This is like some real verge stuff. That image
Speaker 6:  aspect ratios are all over the place now. Yep. So the first
Speaker 6:  verge was a 16 by nine website. Like
Speaker 6:  that's what it was. And it was designed to produce 16 by nine images
Speaker 6:  on a landscape desktop display. This is like, we have to be
Speaker 6:  comfortable with portrait images. We have to be comfortable with square images.
Speaker 6:  So there's actually a lot of backend work to just support and deliver
Speaker 6:  the right aspect, ratio of image in the right article at the right time.
Speaker 6:  And it's not, the headlines are at the bottom like level
Speaker 6:  web redesign thinking. It's more like actually a mobile article
Speaker 6:  page has to deliver to a phone with assets or a phone
Speaker 6:  native and maybe the desktop version should look totally different.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I mean that, that to me, like, even as we've been, you know, beta testing,
Speaker 2:  this thing like discovering what a TikTok in embed looks like
Speaker 2:  when you just make it, its own thing is deeply hilarious and trying
Speaker 2:  to figure out how to like pull all of that stuff into one place in a
Speaker 2:  way that they all make sense next to all of the other stuff that we all do
Speaker 2:  turned out to be way harder than I expected. And is the kind of thing that
Speaker 2:  no one has ever really done. Right? Like most news websites are
Speaker 2:  text, right? Like it is, it is overwhelmingly paragraphs of text and
Speaker 2:  images. And we we've been through this a million times when you try to build
Speaker 2:  something else, you have to like build a sort of bespoke thing that can contain
Speaker 2:  it. And then you go to the video apps and they support video. And then even
Speaker 2:  when you get like the landscape video and the vertical video app, it looks
Speaker 2:  bad. And this task of figuring out how to sort of, of be
Speaker 2:  all things to all people with all media is
Speaker 2:  fascinating and it's gonna be like, we definitely have not fully solved that
Speaker 2:  problem. And no one has, and there's a lot left to do. But I think like that's
Speaker 2:  where all of this has to go because this stuff just is so multimedia now.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. You sound like a 1990s, Cedar rom under. I
Speaker 2:  Know I love it.
Speaker 6:  What we've shipped here today is Microsoft and cartel. We hope you like it
Speaker 6:  you'll need at least a four X speed CD rom drive to make it work in a 3 86,
Speaker 2:  It comes on 11 CD,
Speaker 6:  But a beautiful leather binder. You know, it's like, I'll just end on this
Speaker 6:  story. Like we, we have inte all these EDS and you realize like very
Speaker 6:  little thought goes into EDS for anyone but YouTube, YouTube
Speaker 6:  gold standard of EDS. Like the ed is the size of the
Speaker 6:  video. All of the necessary controls and layouts
Speaker 6:  of the ed are contained in the frame. Everyone knows what a YouTube video
Speaker 6:  is. The play button conveys all the branding they need to, they don't send
Speaker 6:  you the comments with it or you can't like, it's like,
Speaker 6:  they're just like, here's our video. Like, we're so confident in ourselves
Speaker 6:  as YouTube that like here's the video. And if people wanna read the comments
Speaker 6:  on YouTube video, they damn well know to like click on the top and go to
Speaker 6:  YouTube and read it. Instagram is like, here's 5,000 vertical
Speaker 6:  pixels.
Speaker 2:  It's so tall.
Speaker 6:  Here is all of Instagram in an ed, right? TikTok
Speaker 6:  is the same way. And Twitter, the embeds are getting bigger and you just
Speaker 6:  see the platform. Companies don't care about the web. Like
Speaker 6:  I will make that accusation like that is not meaningful to them that
Speaker 6:  their content travels outside of their walls. And when it does, they're like
Speaker 6:  we have now colonized you in like the most direct way we can by
Speaker 6:  effectively embedding our whole platform onto your page. Whereas YouTube,
Speaker 6:  I think because it is like infrastructure of the web in some
Speaker 6:  serious way, the embed is like respectful because
Speaker 6:  YouTube knows that everyone will just go back to YouTube in a way that I
Speaker 6:  think Instagram and TikTok and Twitter, like lack of the confidence of
Speaker 6:  knowing that people will go back to
Speaker 2:  Them. When you embed the verge on your website, you just get every story
Speaker 2:  we've ever published. Oh
Speaker 6:  Dude, we're gonna, art posts are gonna get in. Embedable I think that that'll
Speaker 6:  be like one of the fun turns here in the
Speaker 2:  End. I like it. So any, any product stuff to tease for people who are
Speaker 2:  listening what's next? I don't even know the answer to this
Speaker 6:  Question. So we we're gonna ship this version. Our product team keeps
Speaker 6:  falling at verge 2.0 in my head. It's like verge 12, you know, whatever.
Speaker 6:  We're gonna ship a 0.1 pretty soon. We are currently
Speaker 6:  prioritizing what goes on 0.1. I've got one big idea, which
Speaker 6:  I will tease a little bit. I think we now have the tools to do much better
Speaker 6:  event coverage. So that's first on my list is how do we kind of remix
Speaker 6:  what we've built here into a much better experience for an apple event or
Speaker 6:  something like that. And then I really want to focus on some of this community
Speaker 6:  stuff, but I really want the community to tell us what you would like so
Speaker 6:  we can build the right stuff.
Speaker 2:  Awesome. Yeah. Get at us. Call the verge hotline, send us emails. Tell us
Speaker 2:  everything you want from the verge.com. It's a website
Speaker 6:  We're gonna revolutionize the media with podcast.
Speaker 2:  All right. Thanks man. Appreciate it. Thanks. All right. That's it for the
Speaker 2:  Vergecast today. Thank you. As always for listening, you can check out our
Speaker 2:  brand new website, the verge.com right now and forever refresh the
Speaker 2:  page million times. We'll thank you later. We'll be doing a lot of fun stuff
Speaker 2:  there too. So keep it bookmarked and refresh it. Often. This show is produced
Speaker 2:  by Andrew Marino and Liam James Nori. Donovan is our executive producer and
Speaker 2:  Brook mins is our editorial director of audio. The Vergecast is a
Speaker 2:  verge production and part of the V media podcast network. If you have thoughts,
Speaker 2:  feedback, feelings, letters to the editor, thoughts about the website, thoughts
Speaker 2:  about websites in general, you can always email vergecast@theverge.com
Speaker 2:  Alex NELA. Be back on Friday to talk about all the apple reviews which are
Speaker 2:  coming. And I know you'll want to hear about them. We'll see you then rock
Speaker 2:  and roll.