# Transcript
ID: 2d76b8f0-7f2b-11ed-a058-e93b9dfb660f
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Streaming winners & losers of 2022: Netflix, HBO Max, Disney Plus, and more
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-6520673958211620716/3055850122231146254/s93290-US-5023s-1671405809.mp3
Description: The Verge's Alex Cranz, Nilay Patel, and Charles Pulliam-Moore focus on the big streaming services — Netflix, HBO Max, Hulu, Disney Plus, Amazon Prime, Peacock, Paramount Plus — and discuss which are the winners and losers are for this year.
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call the hotline at 866-VERGE11, we'd love to hear from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Disabled
Speaker 2:  You're listening to the Vergecast, the flagship podcast
Speaker 2:  of the Go 90 Scale of Doom Streaming Services. I'm your friend
Speaker 2:  Alex Kranz, and you notice that David's not here because this
Speaker 2:  is the first episode of the Wednesday show that I'm taking over. While David
Speaker 2:  is out caring for that, absolutely adorable baby, he and his wife just had,
Speaker 2:  we're gonna have a really fun time over the next few weeks and we're gonna
Speaker 2:  have a bunch of Verge staff on the show to talk about all kinds of stuff.
Speaker 2:  And I will try not to have an EA segment every week, but
Speaker 2:  I will not promise to not have an EA segment every week. Anyway,
Speaker 2:  this episode is a really fun one because we're gonna be talking about all
Speaker 2:  the big streaming services. I mean Netflix, hbo, max,
Speaker 2:  Hulu, Disney Plus, peacock, paramount plus,
Speaker 2:  Amazon Prime, all of them. And we're gonna think about who are the winners
Speaker 2:  and who are the losers. And to do this, I of course have brought in
Speaker 2:  our Verge editor-in-Chief Eli Patel and our film and TV
Speaker 2:  reporter, Charles Pullam Moore, to go through each and every one of these
Speaker 2:  streaming companies and discuss how they were handled in 2022.
Speaker 2:  Buckle in for this one. I made people talk to me about this for over
Speaker 2:  an hour. It's a lot of fun, but I'm gonna go walk my
Speaker 2:  dog now. So I'll see you guys in a minute.
Speaker 3:  Support for this episode comes from Airbnb. If you've stayed
Speaker 3:  in one of Airbnb's unique homes all around the world, you may be wondering,
Speaker 3:  could my place be an Airbnb and what could I earn? You could be sitting
Speaker 3:  on an Airbnb right now. That might mean your extra guest room or
Speaker 3:  maybe even Airbnb your entire home while you're away on a long trip,
Speaker 3:  whether you could use some extra money to cover some of those surprise expenses
Speaker 3:  or maybe just a little something for yourself, your home might be
Speaker 3:  worth more than you think. Find out how much at
Speaker 3:  airbnb.com/host.
Speaker 4:  This episode is supported by NetApp. NetApp wants our listeners to know
Speaker 4:  that they are in love with the cloud. So in love they'd climb a mountain
Speaker 4:  or cross an ocean just to prove it, but that's not actually necessary.
Speaker 4:  So instead they just made this podcast ad. NetApp makes the cloud work
Speaker 4:  smarter and harder by letting you automate processes, optimize
Speaker 4:  infrastructure access, and securely manage your data. No matter where it
Speaker 4:  is. NetApp, for the love of Cloud Vergecast, listeners can visit
Speaker 4:  netapp.com/verge to see how amazing the cloud can be.
Speaker 2:  All right, and we're back. I got ne Eli here who is the
Speaker 2:  streaming expert at the Verge.
Speaker 5:  Is that true?
Speaker 2:  I mean we can say it is. No one's here to stop us. And I have Charles Pull
Speaker 2:  Moore here who is our other streaming expert at The Verge.
Speaker 5:  I think he should stop us from saying that I'm the expert. I think Charles
Speaker 5:  is the expert.
Speaker 6:  I think we all have a little bit expertise when it comes to the different
Speaker 6:  platforms.
Speaker 5:  Fair enough.
Speaker 2:  And we're gonna talk about the winners and losers of streaming this year.
Speaker 2:  I know. Ha. I have my opinions. I know Charles has his opinions. Some of
Speaker 2:  them are very wrong. Oh wow. Charles, I saw your notes here about Paramount
Speaker 2:  Plus and I had to like had to take a moment. It's fine.
Speaker 6:  I'm very glad that you are watching Paramount Plus and keeping them afloat
Speaker 6:  with your Star Trek love. Well done. Well done. It's
Speaker 5:  All me. Well, there's also the Cowboy people. We got it. Well, we'll get
Speaker 5:  there,
Speaker 2:  We'll get there. We'll get there, we'll get there. Let's not get too far
Speaker 2:  ahead, but, so we're gonna be going through the winners and losers and first
Speaker 2:  up we're gonna talk about the biggest winner, the Biggest Loser. This
Speaker 2:  is the biggest right? Which is Netflix.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. That like, you know, the OG player in this space who taught
Speaker 6:  everybody that streaming was a real business that everyone needed to get
Speaker 6:  very serious about. And you know, I dunno, Netflix has just always been the
Speaker 6:  bellwether that everyone has looked to. And in this year of everyone's sort
Speaker 6:  of realizing that burning cash, you can't just do it
Speaker 6:  indefinitely. Like Netflix sort of being the one who taught everyone that
Speaker 6:  that's how you run this business, had to pump the brakes and be like, you
Speaker 6:  guys since these subscriber rates have sort of flattened and slowed down,
Speaker 6:  perhaps we need to cap our spending. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Cuz they spent a lot of money this year. They
Speaker 6:  Spent, you know, 17 billion, which is both like an
Speaker 6:  ungodly amount of money. But it's also sort of like that is how
Speaker 6:  Netflix is able to be Netflix, right? It's like, let's throw cash at
Speaker 6:  this problem as much as we possibly can. So much so that you can't possibly
Speaker 6:  believe it. And that leads to, you know, the content gets married, subscribers
Speaker 6:  come on. But eventually you do sort of have to look at the bottom
Speaker 6:  line. Netflix in particular has realized like, look, there's a certain
Speaker 6:  degree to which shooting yourself in the foot this way. Can it be beneficial
Speaker 6:  if you're looking sort of down the road? But at some point you do have to
Speaker 6:  talk to yourself and rather realistic terms. Like my
Speaker 6:  foot isn't gonna keep regrowing back, you guys, we gotta sort of staunch
Speaker 6:  the bleeding. And everyone else who has sort of followed on Netflix's footsteps
Speaker 6:  looking at Netflix's example, has recognized like, oh, if we do everything
Speaker 6:  that Netflix does, we will also sort of be in the same position but not necessarily
Speaker 6:  have that same market share. So, you know, since Netflix has
Speaker 6:  sort of put out that call, rather put out that message to its investors,
Speaker 6:  we are capping our spending. All of the other streamers have been like, we
Speaker 6:  are also going to start capping our spending. Well, I'm also gonna
Speaker 6:  start trying to get more value out of, out of our wares
Speaker 6:  by just, you know, squeezing them a little bit tighter.
Speaker 2:  Let's talk about that, like the capping the spending thing there because
Speaker 2:  Netflix capped at spending and I feel like everybody in the
Speaker 2:  industry was kind of like, this is the death of Netflix. Like, like
Speaker 2:  it just went from like zero to everything's ruined really, really
Speaker 2:  quickly.
Speaker 5:  There's like a thing here that we should just for one second
Speaker 5:  highlight, which is this is the first time Netflix
Speaker 5:  has faced real competition. Right? So that
Speaker 5:  crazy curve where they were burning cash or burning money, they were doing
Speaker 5:  anything to get on people's TVs, they were chasing what
Speaker 5:  you might call a monopoly position for streaming and they achieved that
Speaker 5:  position. Yeah. Right? If, if you walked up to a random person and had to
Speaker 5:  guess what they subscribe to, Netflix would be the best bet. Right? Right.
Speaker 5:  In every single case, everyone has a Netflix subscription, right? That is
Speaker 5:  a very difficult thing to achieve. And Netflix more or less achieved it.
Speaker 5:  They're like out of people to get to subscribe to Netflix.
Speaker 6:  Right? And it's like we, it's we, we can joke about it, but like Netflix
Speaker 6:  when it's, it's funny during to-do, to-do whenever,
Speaker 6:  when, when Netflix starts talking about its presence like globally
Speaker 6:  and sort of like all the inroads that it's made in other countries, it's
Speaker 6:  often easy to sort of gloss over. Like Netflix is that girl, like
Speaker 6:  Netflix is the one who is sort of in this space launching international hits
Speaker 6:  like Disney plus Amazon Prime. They don't have like a squid
Speaker 6:  game, right? Yeah. Which is to say they don't have programming
Speaker 6:  that is not explicitly western focused, that still manages to take
Speaker 6:  over everything and sort of be in everyone's minds and sort of own that
Speaker 6:  mindshare. And so while the 17 billion
Speaker 6:  spend is, while it is also paid off for them in a way that is
Speaker 6:  undeniable. That being said, this is the cost that comes with
Speaker 6:  sort of being the trendsetter, sort of laying the blueprint
Speaker 6:  for everyone else. It makes it easier for everyone else to sort of catch
Speaker 6:  up to you, not necessarily get to your same level, but sort of
Speaker 6:  recreate your success to a certain extent enough so that you can become the
Speaker 6:  kind of competition that scares Netflix into not necessarily scares, well
Speaker 6:  gooses them into thinking well we have to think a little bit more strategically
Speaker 6:  about how we're gonna maintain our position and sort of
Speaker 6:  stave the like keep the competition out from being able to really steal our
Speaker 6:  lunch.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Two, thanks. One, I feel as though I have to disclose that I'm the
Speaker 5:  EP of a Netflix show called Key. We should go watch a Netflix. It's great.
Speaker 5:  And also our company makes shows for every one of these streaming platforms.
Speaker 5:  So take, go watch all the Vox media shows on every platform. It's great.
Speaker 5:  Two, I think the really interesting thing about that competition moment is
Speaker 5:  Netflix. Even just last week, Reid Hastings was at the
Speaker 5:  DealBook conference that I was at and he was like, our competition is everything.
Speaker 5:  It's video games, it's the other streamers, it's TikTok, it's YouTube.
Speaker 5:  They think about their opportunity is, you know,
Speaker 5:  the hours and the day that you are watching something. Yeah. That you're
Speaker 5:  looking at a screen. They've kind of solved this problem by just throwing
Speaker 5:  money at it. If you push the button on your remote, Netflix is gonna
Speaker 5:  show you oceans of content. I think when we go talk about the other
Speaker 5:  streamers, they have solved this problem by saying, here's the best thing
Speaker 5:  you should watch. Right. That I think is where the, the real end of Netflix
Speaker 5:  stuff came from. Right? The strategy has shifted and now Netflix is gonna
Speaker 5:  spend less money, which means they're gonna have to make harder decisions
Speaker 5:  about what they spend money on, which just changes the dynamic
Speaker 5:  for everybody. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Like we've all had that experience where you turn on Netflix and it's like,
Speaker 6:  I wanna watch something, what am I going to watch? And you're like, well
Speaker 6:  there's so much, there's so much. And their UI does, none
Speaker 6:  of the UIs are particularly good about like discovery, but nothing about
Speaker 6:  Netflix in particular lends itself to giving you a sense of
Speaker 6:  what you're gonna be in for. And you know, we live in the age of decision
Speaker 6:  paralysis, which I'd be very curious to hear what kind of internal conversations
Speaker 6:  Netflix has had about like, we need to, we need to make it easier for people
Speaker 6:  to sort of wanna try our things out without necessarily thinking that they
Speaker 6:  need to have the, you know, to go watch a show from beginning to end without
Speaker 6:  any kind of interruption. I think it's really telling that we've gotten into
Speaker 6:  a space where all of the streamers like to brag about our watched for something
Speaker 6:  like that sort of become the default metric that they use to tout the success
Speaker 6:  of a particular thing. Right? A metric that means nothing to regular people,
Speaker 6:  right? Like, ooh, like X billion million people watched
Speaker 6:  X hours of show. Like what that means nothing to me
Speaker 6:  as a regular watcher who it tries to stay away
Speaker 6:  from like that super fan investment like rah rah, like let's cheer for the
Speaker 6:  multi-billion dollar company. But I do think that it is
Speaker 6:  reflective of what you were saying earlier, that these companies are starting
Speaker 6:  to be a little bit more transparent about what success looks like to them
Speaker 6:  internally. Right. It isn't necessarily, obviously they all love it when
Speaker 6:  they get nominated for awards, right? Like I'm sure Hulu was overjoyed that
Speaker 6:  the, that the dropout not swept, but really sort of cleaned up. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Cleaned up. But at the end of the day, like what they're really concerned
Speaker 6:  about is, is this a part of your, is this a part of your daily consumption
Speaker 6:  habit? Like are you, do you wake up and just reflexively turn the television
Speaker 6:  on, put something on and then just let it go for the rest of the day? Because
Speaker 6:  that's kind of, sort of what they all want.
Speaker 2:  No, because after three episodes it'll ask if you're still watching, Hmm
Speaker 5:  Hmm Netflix did fine, right? Are they the winner? Are they the loser? Like
Speaker 5:  who knows? But the underlying dynamic that got expressed that Netflix
Speaker 5:  got hit by hardest is you have to make a case
Speaker 5:  for people to spend money on you every month. And if
Speaker 5:  people aren't hitting that button on their remote every day or every couple
Speaker 5:  of days because you're just gonna give them something,
Speaker 5:  then your other option is to make hits. And hits are just
Speaker 5:  way harder. And where Netflix has had hits
Speaker 5:  is in stuff that has generated a lot of controversy, right. The
Speaker 5:  Chappelle specials or stuff that has gone viral on other
Speaker 5:  platforms for reasons no one could predict. Like we are in the middle of
Speaker 5:  the weird goth resurgence around Wednesday, which
Speaker 5:  is a former Skyliner boy, I don't, it's very confusing to me all
Speaker 5:  around, like everyone is just like cosplaying my teens right now. I don't
Speaker 5:  quite understand it, but it's, it's weird, right? Netflix doesn't have that
Speaker 5:  mark getting prowess that the hbos of the world do.
Speaker 5:  They don't create cultural moments cuz they just released everything as a
Speaker 5:  binge. So then Wednesday gets completely deco contextualized
Speaker 5:  into a Lady Gaga remixed video, which is great. Like I'm not,
Speaker 5:  I'm not knocking it at all. It just, that wasn't the plan, right? It
Speaker 5:  just happened to them. That
Speaker 6:  All speaks to how like Netflix has sort of just become terrestrial TV for
Speaker 6:  a lot of people. Yeah. Even though we are paying a premium forward, I think
Speaker 6:  is more kind to terrestrial TV than to
Speaker 6:  basic cable like the basic cable that we grew up with in that it is sort
Speaker 6:  of the expectation that you're going to have a Netflix subscription just
Speaker 6:  so that you can participate in, you know, the discourse about a
Speaker 6:  Wednesday, the discourse, I'm thinking way back to like the early hits of
Speaker 6:  Netflix had like the orange is the New Black. It was just sort of the thing
Speaker 6:  that you talked about. But this is the downside to being the big fish in
Speaker 6:  the pond. Right? Eventually people stop thinking about you as that
Speaker 6:  young upstart that's doing bold, ambitious, I'm thinking again
Speaker 6:  of orange, the new black things things versus this sort
Speaker 6:  of stayed safe bets that draw their success
Speaker 6:  from controversy. Like Chappelle Teran is coming out
Speaker 6:  and being like, we are gonna keep green lighting Chappelle specials
Speaker 6:  until people stop watching them says to me like, oh, like that's not, that's
Speaker 6:  not the position of an executive who's confident in
Speaker 6:  the studio's ability to create, to create up. Its on its own. Exactly.
Speaker 6:  It really that to me does say like, well that's safe. It doesn't
Speaker 6:  telegraph strength to me.
Speaker 2:  We've seen that too with how Netflix has been very eager to
Speaker 2:  like, watch Disney go on this IP binging and just buy
Speaker 2:  up all the different ips and, and Paramount's done it and HBO's
Speaker 2:  done it and Amazon Prime has done it. Everybody's done it and Netflix kind
Speaker 2:  of got left out in the cold. And so they're like, okay, we need, we need
Speaker 2:  IP too. And so like Adams family Wednesday would not be a
Speaker 2:  success probably if it didn't have that Adams family IP attached to it. If
Speaker 2:  it was just about a weird goth girl go into her school with her wear all
Speaker 2:  friends, look,
Speaker 5:  The world needs more original IP about young
Speaker 5:  goth teens and their werewolf friends just in general.
Speaker 5:  And I don't know why we got away from it and I think we should go back,
Speaker 2:  But like you've seen it even happen on Netflix itself. It's done similar
Speaker 2:  shows that just haven't had that same reach. And because there was that,
Speaker 2:  that IP connection, we've seen it with the Witcher, that's like their big
Speaker 2:  IP bend. There are only success in, in creating their own IP
Speaker 2:  has really been Stranger things into an extent Squid game, right?
Speaker 5:  Well, no. So Bridger 10 is huge.
Speaker 6:  People loved Ozark,
Speaker 2:  But Bridger was based on a very successful series of, of romance
Speaker 2:  novels that have been out for years. And I guess the other one you said
Speaker 2:  Ozark, that's a fair, that's a fair one.
Speaker 6:  In in, in the grand scheme of like winners and there just, Netflix is fine,
Speaker 6:  right? Like Netflix, all, all of the calls like, ah, Netflix is doomed. Like
Speaker 6:  everyone, everyone likes that narrative because it's fun, right? In the same
Speaker 6:  way that it's fun that Netflix has a show, two shows, excuse me about Blockbuster.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Everyone gets like a little bit of a thrill out of like, oh, is Netflix
Speaker 6:  finally gonna fall off the throne? Maybe, but like this isn't the year forward.
Speaker 6:  Exactly. Like if and when we do see them really sort of take a tumble,
Speaker 6:  it's not probably going to be like a very dramatic and
Speaker 6:  immediate thing. It is just going to be a slow winnowing of the market share
Speaker 6:  that comes, you know, as a function of the competition just being stronger
Speaker 6:  and smarter.
Speaker 2:  Okay. So if we had to say Netflix was a winner or loser,
Speaker 5:  No, we gotta do this first Castile go 90 scale of Doom Streaming services.
Speaker 5:  Okay? Zero is Alive, okay. And 90 is dead
Speaker 5:  in honor of Go 90, the streaming service from Verizon, which
Speaker 5:  honestly Verizon was like, here's what you want to do. You want a YouTube
Speaker 5:  where you join a gang. That was basically their pitch for it bundled on your
Speaker 5:  mid-range and Android phone. So Zero is alive, 90 is dead.
Speaker 5:  I'm putting Netflix, like Netflix was flatly at zero, right? Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 5:  For a long time. I'll, I'll put 'em at like five.
Speaker 2:  I'm gonna put 'em at three unless they cancel a show I'm really
Speaker 2:  into right now. In which case 90,
Speaker 5:  If Netflix cancels a show that a fan base is into, they're like 90 immediately,
Speaker 5:  immediately. Two saying is out of control. My argument
Speaker 5:  for five is like they've never faced competition like this. And they are
Speaker 5:  reorienting the company, they're rolling out ads, they're doing all this
Speaker 5:  stuff that is unproven. So there's an element of risk
Speaker 5:  to Netflix that has not existed before, which takes 'em to five.
Speaker 2:  All right, I'm at five asterisks. 90 if they cancel
Speaker 2:  Warrior none. Charles, where are you?
Speaker 6:  I think they're at like a two. Okay. I think I, I, I think I'm trying to,
Speaker 6:  I'm trying to weirdly, my mind immediately went to like, at what point
Speaker 6:  in House of the Dragon, right? At what point at like at King
Speaker 6:  VAs is like Decrepitness is Netflix right now
Speaker 6:  and I think it's still like early in the season, right? Like there's just
Speaker 6:  maybe like a little pock mark, just one or two, so Oh, I
Speaker 5:  See. Wow. So in a long enough timeline, every streaming service
Speaker 6:  Oh, in a long enough timeline just face falling off. Right?
Speaker 5:  Fair enough. Yeah. By the way, this thing about the scale is really funny
Speaker 5:  cuz if I had said ten first all of you would've both said five, but I said
Speaker 5:  five. So you're like two and three. Two and three. This is like, this is
Speaker 5:  how you mess with the numbers. I'm just letting you know what you do
Speaker 5:  anchoring. It's like a real thing. All right. But five, that's what we're
Speaker 5:  saying for Netflix. 5, 2, 3. Okay,
Speaker 2:  Let's talk about one that is like probably closer to the 90 side
Speaker 2:  right now. HBO Max,
Speaker 6:  Speaking of Game of Thrones
Speaker 2:  Slash discovery, you have it here. So Charles worked a lot on the
Speaker 2:  rundown for this episode. Charles, you, you have the two kind of bundled
Speaker 2:  together.
Speaker 6:  So like in my mind, H v o Max and Discovery Plus are still two
Speaker 6:  separate entities. Okay. Like we, I I get that internally, Warner Brothers
Speaker 6:  discovery is like, these two things are soon to emerge and be called Max.
Speaker 6:  And if and when, like when I can download death,
Speaker 5:  That, that just stop it. Look, everybody
Speaker 6:  Stop it. When I can download Max the app from the app store
Speaker 6:  onto my, onto my TV and onto my phone, then I will officially be like,
Speaker 6:  all right, the, the merger is done.
Speaker 5:  I'm just saying there are people in this world named Max, including one that
Speaker 5:  I am very responsible for and I think they're all mad.
Speaker 6:  Congratulations on Max new app, that's gonna be great.
Speaker 2:  They had a year, right? Like, like David Zaslav finally they finished
Speaker 2:  the merger of, of the companies not obviously of the apps. They
Speaker 2:  finished the merger, DA David Zaslav came on, he originally did that kind
Speaker 2:  of tour. He went and talked to a lot of execs, a lot of people in the industry
Speaker 2:  and was like, Hey, I'm just a cool guy here to make some cool content
Speaker 6:  Emphasis on content.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And then, and then things got a little messy.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I mean if you call like the raising of villages and the salton of
Speaker 6:  Earth messy Sure. You know, there were
Speaker 6:  just lots of big fires everywhere with H V O
Speaker 6:  this year. I mean I think we all sort of remember the famous like, oh like
Speaker 6:  things are just disappearing from H B O Max left to right. Yeah, yeah. What's,
Speaker 6:  what's going on? Oh, back girl's not gonna come out. It's done. But like
Speaker 6:  we're not gonna release it because it would be prudent for us to just take
Speaker 6:  the tax right off rather than Sully H B o Max's good name by
Speaker 6:  putting out this, you know, this
Speaker 5:  Mediocre,
Speaker 6:  Apparently we'll never know. But I mean like the, when people look back on
Speaker 6:  2022 for H V O Max and Discovery, it will be the year that David
Speaker 6:  Asla came in and started the cleanup house under the auspices of getting
Speaker 6:  the company on track to be more financially solvent. Right.
Speaker 6:  More into the business of putting out movies
Speaker 6:  for theatrical releases that then have pretty sizable theatrical
Speaker 6:  windows before they eventually make the jump to the streaming services months
Speaker 6:  after. And a lot of that was course correction from
Speaker 6:  2021, right. That those Halian days of the pandemic where
Speaker 6:  people could not go Right. When people were not going to movie theaters.
Speaker 6:  Right. And the studios were clumped and unsure what to do
Speaker 6:  and the old guard was like, put it all in max.
Speaker 5:  Well they were not necessarily old guard. Like we can't talk about
Speaker 5:  H B O Max and what is happening to it now. No, without talking about the
Speaker 5:  fact that at and t bought this whole company Okay. Had no
Speaker 5:  idea what to do with it. Their entire theory
Speaker 5:  of buying this company was we're gonna preload
Speaker 5:  Warner Brothers content on at and t phones. Like
Speaker 5:  that's what they wanted to do. Like if you bought an Android phone from
Speaker 5:  at and t, they were gonna preload it with apps that
Speaker 5:  delivered like bite-sized versions of Game of Thrones to you. And that's
Speaker 5:  why you would buy at and t phones over Verizon phones. I cannot even believe
Speaker 5:  that I am saying this like hundreds, thousands
Speaker 5:  of richly paid executives and consultants came up with
Speaker 5:  this plan that just saying out loud to the vergecast audience plainly,
Speaker 5:  I know what people are doing. Yeah. They're crashing their cars and jumping
Speaker 5:  off bridges cuz it's so stupid. But this was their
Speaker 5:  plan was that they would differentiate at and t's network by
Speaker 5:  having Warner Brothers content. Yeah. Which is
Speaker 5:  a plan that has failed every single fucking time. Anyone has ever tried it.
Speaker 5:  Do you know who else tried aol, tried to do that with Warner Brothers content?
Speaker 5:  Does anyone know who owns AOL now? Like no,
Speaker 5:  it's a disaster. And so they spent all this money, they hired Jason
Speaker 5:  Colar to come in and like beat ahead of the studio and he wasn't like,
Speaker 5:  I'm afraid of what's happening with pandemic audiences. He said, I'm pulling
Speaker 5:  the lever on streaming as hard as I can using the
Speaker 5:  opportunity, the pandemic screw you theater, screw you Hollywood,
Speaker 5:  a-list talent that has backend deals to get profit from theater revenue.
Speaker 5:  Right? All that stuff he just said, screw it, the pandemic is an excuse and
Speaker 5:  basically broke the studio. Whatever his as is doing
Speaker 5:  now, it seems like he is being very harsh. I
Speaker 5:  I I don't disagree. I just like what he was handed, what he bought
Speaker 5:  was a disaster of at t's making. And like
Speaker 5:  you, I don't think that there's a way out of that disaster without the perception
Speaker 5:  of harshness.
Speaker 6:  So like, I'm looking at this from the perspective of a consumer, right? Like
Speaker 6:  for a hot second there, H v o Max was sort of the awkward late
Speaker 6:  to the game sibling. Everyone's like, well what is H V O Max supposed to
Speaker 6:  be? Exactly. What is my interest in this outside of
Speaker 6:  watching things that are just gonna be h on hbo o And for a while HBO
Speaker 6:  Max sort of was coming into its own as having, having
Speaker 6:  interesting content, having rather interesting original content in interesting
Speaker 6:  original series as well as like the the established HBO o brands. But then
Speaker 6:  they were getting all of these, you know, blockbuster movies
Speaker 6:  immediately onto the platform. And from the consumer
Speaker 6:  perspective, like that was the dream, right? It was like, look, I will pay
Speaker 6:  a premium. I will pay like a premium premium. Even if, even if we weren't
Speaker 6:  necessarily dealing with the pandemic, if the studios were like, Hey, welcome
Speaker 6:  to our app, pay us anywhere between 30 to $60 to
Speaker 6:  watch the movie that is in the theater right now. Watch it here on the app.
Speaker 6:  People have been wanting something like that for the longest time. And H
Speaker 6:  v o max, you know, through all of these, you know, all,
Speaker 6:  all of the, the situation was able to give people something like that.
Speaker 6:  And because all of these platforms, not as the platforms, but the
Speaker 6:  companies that own them are constantly paying attention to one another for
Speaker 6:  a few months. There was the dream like, is this going to be the direction
Speaker 6:  that they all go in? Are they all gonna start prioritizing streaming in this
Speaker 6:  way because they understand that that's where eyeballs are. Were we going
Speaker 6:  to be on the precipice of a sea change where people just weren't flocking
Speaker 6:  the theaters the way that they used to? Which is why you saw, you know, last
Speaker 6:  year, the year before this really big hmm push for the
Speaker 6:  sentimental appeals to the theater going like, Hey you guys
Speaker 6:  movies are where we fall in love and where we discover ourselves and it's
Speaker 6:  like funny, look, I know you wanna sell this popcorn but you gotta calm down
Speaker 6:  with all that. Cause it's doing a lot. It's doing a lot.
Speaker 6:  But now you know, you know, DESSOLVE comes in and he is
Speaker 6:  a businessman, right? You are right. He's looking at this like, y'all we're
Speaker 6:  not, we're not gonna be solvent if we keep moving like
Speaker 6:  this. And so as plan, as best as we can tell from looking from the outside
Speaker 6:  in has really just been to cut spend to cut spend
Speaker 6:  in the long term. In the short term that looks like, all right, we
Speaker 6:  need to free up space on the platform for cheaper
Speaker 6:  content that we are going to eventually start producing four max
Speaker 6:  in the future. You can have your feelings about whether or not
Speaker 6:  the clearing of house could have been done in a more
Speaker 6:  judicious and quiet and less sort of like bombastic kind of
Speaker 6:  way.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. They were pulling stuff off. A lot of animated shows I know got
Speaker 2:  pulled with the, the creators not even knowing about it and suddenly there's
Speaker 2:  like just zero way to watch their their shows they they worked on.
Speaker 6:  And that's why, not that I'm coming out as a defender
Speaker 6:  of Zaslav, but like when you look at everything that he's done on paper,
Speaker 6:  you, you can see what he is doing. Yeah. He's trying, he's trying, he's trying
Speaker 6:  to save money. The issue and the reason that people have begun to
Speaker 6:  look at Zaslav and W B D in such a dim light is
Speaker 6:  just because of his methodology, right. Just because there does seem to be
Speaker 6:  a lack of care and attention being paid to the fact that, you know,
Speaker 6:  these, the content is the work of artists and creators, some
Speaker 6:  of whom this is their life's work, right? And it is, it is disheartening
Speaker 6:  to see your baby sort of just like thrown off the ship in the name of,
Speaker 6:  you know what I mean, in the bottom line,
Speaker 2:  Buried in the vault, never to be seen unless he has to pay
Speaker 2:  the i r s back.
Speaker 6:  The winnowing of Max also came again, not to bring it back to
Speaker 6:  award season, but it came at a, it came in a year where an H V O had a really
Speaker 6:  strong showing, you know, throughout award season, you know, succession
Speaker 6:  hacks, euphoria, the White Lotus, they were nominated, they were
Speaker 6:  winning these awards and it, you know, did sort of play into this idea like,
Speaker 6:  oh H v o Max, you know, to what you were saying earlier, H v O Max isn't
Speaker 6:  just a streaming platform, it's a streaming platform that's putting out really
Speaker 6:  good content. Things that people like, things that fans like critics. Like
Speaker 6:  it's something that's actually worth the investment of your time and energy.
Speaker 6:  And then to see the platform just having an ax taken to it,
Speaker 6:  it really sort of felt like, ah, why would you do this? Like why would you
Speaker 6:  do it? Especially since you've gotten the platform in such a, a healthy,
Speaker 6:  good, productive space at this point.
Speaker 5:  But there's two parts to that which I think are fascinating. One, if
Speaker 5:  you had to ask me what I would cut down to right now, I would pick HBO O
Speaker 5:  max.
Speaker 2:  Right? Same.
Speaker 5:  What is most consistently winning an hour of my evening? It's HBO O max,
Speaker 5:  right? It just has some of the, the most interesting stuff on it. If I had
Speaker 5:  to pick two, it'd be HBO, O Max and Netflix for sure. But if you had to just
Speaker 5:  ask me like, you get one and probably pick HBO Max just cause I get
Speaker 5:  mine the archive of movies and be happy for a long time, right? But that's
Speaker 5:  hbo I think what, what got the whole platform
Speaker 5:  kind of sideways is they added in all this other stuff, including
Speaker 5:  the Noise of Warner in DC and
Speaker 5:  HBO itself. The thing that makes really good TV shows just
Speaker 5:  had to like carry the weight of the, like they're not cutting a bunch
Speaker 5:  of HBO content. They're cutting a bunch of like Warner Brothers movies and
Speaker 5:  animated series stuff that like makes no sense and now they're gonna like
Speaker 5:  smash it together with Max and add a bunch of reality TV
Speaker 5:  stuff and like TLC stuff.
Speaker 2:  Well they've already started adding it, right? Like, like we saw all, you
Speaker 2:  know, they, they bragged about how Chip and Joanne Gaines's new
Speaker 2:  special about rebuilding a castle in Waco, Texas
Speaker 2:  was one of the, the most watched things on HBO Max this year. Like, like
Speaker 2:  they're already testing it and, and pushing that stuff.
Speaker 5:  One thing that is true about this entire conversation is that
Speaker 5:  there's no accounting for taste. And so like you can say
Speaker 5:  whatever you want and then you look at the most popular list and it's always
Speaker 5:  just the, the craziest garbage is the most pop. Yeah. Like the Big
Speaker 5:  Bang Theory was the most popular show in America for years running.
Speaker 6:  And Zaslav is very transparent. He's like, look, you can have your critical
Speaker 6:  darlings and you can have your little Emmys, but so long as the kids are
Speaker 6:  tuning into Chip and go Joanna Gaines, we're going to be be green lighting
Speaker 6:  more of this. Right? And while we can have our feelings about that like a
Speaker 6:  business perspective, that is a smart kind of move. Now I
Speaker 6:  would also be curious to hear from anyone within
Speaker 6:  H V O or rather from W V D, like how much does the prestige
Speaker 6:  perception matter to the company, right? Like arguably part
Speaker 6:  of HBO Max's success was the fact that it was able to ride the H B O brand
Speaker 6:  and sort of like HBO o as a brand is one of these like intergenerational
Speaker 6:  names that really just sort of consistently means quality to
Speaker 6:  people within like the entertainment space and to see
Speaker 6:  the direction that the company is turning towards with Max. I
Speaker 6:  wonder whether or not, like obviously we've heard rumblings like, oh there
Speaker 6:  will be like an H V O hub within Max where you can go for
Speaker 6:  a four year white lotus, but is the company concerned about people just
Speaker 6:  seeing Max as like the least imagining Lee named of the
Speaker 6:  service
Speaker 5:  Because it was a great name for a little girl. I just wanna put that out
Speaker 5:  there. It's a horrible name for streaming service. Four years ago
Speaker 5:  was a killer name for our daughter.
Speaker 2:  Extremely good name for a kid.
Speaker 5:  So I think one of the things here is like, I don't know that this is true,
Speaker 5:  but I know this is the theory is that allowing HBO to become a
Speaker 5:  tile inside of a Mac, an app called Max allows HBO to
Speaker 5:  maintain its brand the same way that allowing Lucas film or Marvel to be
Speaker 5:  tiles in Disney plus allow them to be somewhat distinct. But
Speaker 5:  the Halo brand there is Disney and here the Halo
Speaker 5:  brand is Max. And I just, and and also like the
Speaker 5:  feelings you get from Marvel are close enough to the
Speaker 5:  feelings you get from Lucas film are close enough to the feelings you
Speaker 5:  get from Pixar. Like Disney makes a thing that is expressed through
Speaker 5:  these gigantic franchises. The feelings you get from
Speaker 5:  the White Lotus should not be the feelings you get from Chip and
Speaker 5:  Joanna Gaines, but like that's the problem, right? There's a,
Speaker 5:  there's an emotional and creative mismatch between the tiles
Speaker 5:  inside of the, the forthcoming Max app.
Speaker 2:  I love to rip on EZ Love because I think a lot of what he's done has not
Speaker 2:  been done delicately enough and he could've, he could've saved people a lot
Speaker 2:  of heartaches with better communication than things. But he is a TV guy,
Speaker 2:  he's like a terrestrial TV guy. Yeah. Like he, he turned discovery from
Speaker 2:  this little tiny like random assortment of the learning
Speaker 2:  channel and these other things into Discovery, which is kind
Speaker 2:  of a behemoth in the cable space now. And, and his plan is to do the same
Speaker 2:  here. He, he, he knows that like brands matter and he
Speaker 2:  knows that he knows how people watch tv I think is the,
Speaker 2:  the most crucial thing here. And his kind of bet is that
Speaker 2:  people are moving from terrestrial tv, they're gonna move to just
Speaker 2:  paying companies directly instead of paying their cable operators
Speaker 2:  instead of watching stuff and sitting through ads. And so
Speaker 2:  his bet is like, I'm gonna build the new terrestrial TV and
Speaker 2:  you're gonna give all of your money to me because I'm gonna have discovery
Speaker 2:  and I'm gonna have HBO and I'm gonna have your little superheroes over
Speaker 2:  here. And I know he talks about them that way. He says they're the
Speaker 2:  little superheroes,
Speaker 5:  Little baby Batmans go 90 scale time. So
Speaker 5:  technically H Rio Max is at 90. This is gone.
Speaker 5:  We already know it's gone. Well
Speaker 2:  It's technically at 89, it's at like 89 until
Speaker 6:  It's gone. Gone, gone, gone, gone. It's not a 90 but
Speaker 6:  it's packing up,
Speaker 5:  It's looking for the door checked out. It has senioritis. Yeah. And so is
Speaker 5:  Discovery. I start every new streaming service out at 45, 50, 50
Speaker 5:  shot. So I would say Max the new service has a 50 50 shot at 45.
Speaker 2:  I'm like a 20. Okay,
Speaker 5:  Really?
Speaker 2:  Again, I dislike Zaslav, but he's a business guy and
Speaker 2:  he knows how to get people's eyeballs on stuff.
Speaker 5:  I've decided to, to be a zla apologist. I know Charles was like
Speaker 5:  dancing around. I'm like full on. Like do it slash and burn. Let's see what
Speaker 5:  happens. Everyone's too polite do some Eon stuff.
Speaker 2:  Like I think if he, I think if he can separate it enough and be like,
Speaker 2:  yeah, I'm gonna have, I'm still gonna have my H B O section over here, so
Speaker 2:  you wanna go do some artsy shit that'll win you some awards. You go hit up
Speaker 2:  my H B O guy, but you wanna make some money? I'm over here with Chip and
Speaker 2:  Joanne,
Speaker 6:  So, okay, we're starting at like a baseline of 45. I put it
Speaker 6:  at like a 60. Oh yeah. I think that we are at a point where there is
Speaker 6:  fatigue amongst consumers for signing up for these things. I do think I,
Speaker 6:  I think realistically there is a degree to which people are kind of tired
Speaker 6:  of being sold on the idea of new subscription platforms and that there
Speaker 6:  is, at least I'm speaking, I'm speaking to my own experience. I'm very comfortable
Speaker 6:  with the subscriptions that I have and the idea of getting logged in into
Speaker 6:  a new thing really does kind of fill me with a, an existential dread that
Speaker 6:  I don't think is unique. But yeah, Zaslav, he's not, if he were
Speaker 6:  canceling successful H B O shows left and right then yeah the future would
Speaker 6:  look pretty bleak. But as it stands now, while our faves
Speaker 6:  may be getting the acts, like the things that people are watching on the
Speaker 6:  platform, they are performing very well and he's made clear as intention
Speaker 6:  to make more of it. So will Max at least be around
Speaker 6:  for five years?
Speaker 5:  Probably. I can't wait for us to spend 15 minutes on Peacock,
Speaker 5:  but we've like in our feelings on Netflix and HBO Max and like
Speaker 5:  we have to get to Peacock still.
Speaker 2:  Okay, we're gonna get back to Peacock and Disney Plus and more, but first
Speaker 2:  we're gonna take a break, we'll be right back.
Speaker 4:  Support for our show comes from click up. One key to managing a productive
Speaker 4:  team is efficiency and also great office snacks, but mostly
Speaker 4:  efficiency. And whether you're leading a group of 10 or 110,
Speaker 4:  it's important to get the most out of every hour in the workday. That's where
Speaker 4:  Click Up can help. Click up is a productivity platform designed to save you
Speaker 4:  a full day every week. That means more time for clients, for meetings,
Speaker 4:  and for eating great office snacks, basically all of the important stuff.
Speaker 4:  Here's how it works. Click up houses, all of your projects, docs, goals,
Speaker 4:  spreadsheets and anything else you need for for work all in one place. Forget
Speaker 4:  wasting Precious times. Switching from app to app or using a multitude
Speaker 4:  of tools to finish a single task. Click up Redefines Productivity by
Speaker 4:  collecting all of your mission critical tools into one fully customizable
Speaker 4:  app. Work the way you work best with Click Up. You can help your team of
Speaker 4:  10 plus be more efficient and productive with Click Up. Use Code
Speaker 4:  Verge to get 15% off click ups, massive unlimited plan for
Speaker 4:  a year, meaning you can start reclaiming your time for under $5 a month.
Speaker 4:  You can sign up today@clickup.com and use Code Verge. Take your
Speaker 4:  productivity to the next level with click up today.
Speaker 3:  Today's episode is sponsored by Airbnb. Airbnb
Speaker 3:  lets you book comfortable stays all around the world so comfortable they
Speaker 3:  might even feel like home, which might lead you to wonder could my place
Speaker 3:  be an Airbnb? And if it was, what could it earn? The exciting
Speaker 3:  answer to that question is that right now you could be sitting on an Airbnb
Speaker 3:  and not even know it. Maybe you have a spare room that's already a haven
Speaker 3:  for visiting friends and family. So why not make it an Airbnb
Speaker 3:  and make some extra cash instead of letting it sit empty. Some people
Speaker 3:  Airbnb their entire homes when they're away for holidays or a big trip.
Speaker 3:  That's a great way to help cover the plane tickets. Whether you could use
Speaker 3:  a little extra money to stash away for a rainy day or you're saving up for
Speaker 3:  something fun, your home might be worth more than you think. Find out
Speaker 3:  how much at airbnb.com/host.
Speaker 2:  Okay, we're back. All right Eli Charles, let's talk about one
Speaker 2:  more big bi myth in the room. Disney plus, hmm Big year
Speaker 2:  this year. Obviously the end of this year has been huge for them. Chap is
Speaker 2:  out i's back and Iger has been pretty
Speaker 2:  vocal about what he wanted to see from the platform, I think especially at
Speaker 2:  Recode earlier this year or at Code conference earlier this year.
Speaker 2:  So what, what's, what's going on there? Like how are we feeling about I Disney
Speaker 2:  plus right now before we get to the ratings, the scores?
Speaker 6:  I mean from a content perspective I think that Disney
Speaker 6:  plus it's the best example of a studio
Speaker 6:  having that vertical system in place. It's like, hey, here's our
Speaker 6:  thing and we filled it with all of our stuff that you love so much, why don't
Speaker 6:  you come pay as a premium forward? Of course you will. You love us And it
Speaker 6:  has proven consistently to just sort of the
Speaker 6:  the dream from that perspective. But obviously it's not necessarily the comp,
Speaker 6:  it's not, it doesn't have the same kind of subscriber rates that it wants.
Speaker 6:  That being said, I in in being sort of like, hey we are the home for
Speaker 6:  Disney things, it in my mind has always sort of been like, yeah it's the
Speaker 6:  Disney one, right? The selection is less diverse
Speaker 6:  in terms of what it is that you can get when you open up the app.
Speaker 6:  And while that is definitely a feature rather than a
Speaker 6:  bug, I think for a lot of people it does just like compare it to the other
Speaker 6:  ones. It just makes it look like, like a less dynamic kind of space. In the
Speaker 6:  grand picture of things we would,
Speaker 2:  Here's my question. If you, you didn't have a small
Speaker 2:  child or you didn't watch a lot of
Speaker 2:  Star Wars and Willow, everybody should watch it, it's great, but you
Speaker 2:  didn't have that kinda like that nerd Gene and you didn't have a child.
Speaker 6:  Do you have a plus subscription?
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Do you have one? And I don't think you do, right?
Speaker 6:  I mean unless you're really, really, really into the Simpsons I guess. But
Speaker 6:  I think you can get that on who,
Speaker 2:  But then you're a nerd. Like if you're that into the Simpsons, you're a nerd,
Speaker 6:  A comedy nerd. But yeah, I, this speaks to
Speaker 6:  Disney's larger plan for things. It's like we need to become a part of like
Speaker 6:  their emotional dna so that yeah everyone has an into
Speaker 6:  Disney like that is sort of the galaxy brain brilliance of Disney,
Speaker 6:  right? It's like we live inside you, you can't get away from
Speaker 6:  right and you are going to pay us to feel good about our existence. Don't
Speaker 6:  question it. And so with that in mind, like Disney plus sort of that
Speaker 6:  is sort of like the, the underlay trick of Disney plus. I think
Speaker 6:  you'd be hard pressed to find people who are completely outside of that,
Speaker 6:  which is sort of what they're banking on. But you're right. Like there isn't
Speaker 6:  a lot, at least here in the US right? There isn't a lot on Disney Plus that
Speaker 6:  would necessarily appeal to Disney adults and you know
Speaker 6:  those a few step from proper Disney adult status.
Speaker 5:  Wait, hold on. This is the generation gap here is real. I encourage
Speaker 5:  you all to live with a small child. Disney Plus is on in our house
Speaker 5:  every single day. Well
Speaker 2:  Yeah cuz you got
Speaker 5:  A kid, right? I'm just saying like between Bluey and Encanto. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Like that's what we pay the money. I do the math almost every day of
Speaker 5:  like, could I buy this archive and just have it versus
Speaker 5:  paying the money a month and Disney because it's like three things
Speaker 5:  and there's a promise there will be more things. The
Speaker 5:  math is, I should just say subscribe to
Speaker 6:  It
Speaker 5:  Because we get, we are just, it's just on constantly
Speaker 5:  everywhere we are. It's like how do we get half an hour of, of
Speaker 5:  peace in our lives? It's just like a little bit more encanto.
Speaker 6:  I can still listen to the Encanto soundtrack and not like reflexively
Speaker 6:  flinch at it because I've heard it so many times. Like Bluey,
Speaker 6:  I am a blue fan, I'll put it on every now and then. It's just like, you know
Speaker 6:  what, what are those Australian kids up to? Let's find out. And it's not,
Speaker 6:  I'm, I'm not bluey poisoned yet and that's kind of what,
Speaker 6:  that's why I wanna I Disney plus like you dip in every now and then get what
Speaker 6:  you need. You dip back out, go on with your life. But no, I totally get from,
Speaker 6:  if you have children in your life, I can totally see like the value add to
Speaker 6:  having Disney plus in your life. Like
Speaker 2:  When you come out of the, you know the baby's born and they give you your
Speaker 2:  baby, do they also just give you a Disney plus?
Speaker 5:  Oh yeah. The hospitals are gonna start, the hospitals do this already with
Speaker 5:  like brands of formula and like they like yeah like having a baby's a fully
Speaker 5:  monetized experience at some point Bob Iger is gonna realize
Speaker 5:  that the three month Disney plus subscription is gonna convert in every hospital
Speaker 5:  for the rest of time.
Speaker 6:  The first way you know you're pregnant is your cvs. Your CVS
Speaker 6:  just prints out a
Speaker 5:  Subscription the data brokers announced and like suddenly you're subscribed
Speaker 5:  to to D plus. That's great. That's the future of all ad based
Speaker 5:  track. What's more interesting to me is those Disney adults, right? Like
Speaker 5:  because people with kids, they all hear about Bluey. Bluey is like a viral
Speaker 5:  phenomenon. Like it's not a marketed show. No. Right? It's just, it's a phenomenon
Speaker 5:  because people are like, I can watch this with my kids and I don't hate myself
Speaker 5:  ka you putting that out there, but it's the Disney
Speaker 5:  adults and I feel like man, Disney just believes that
Speaker 5:  we'll watch like anything like, yeah I watched Moon Night and I
Speaker 5:  was like this is insulting. Like the whole show is like
Speaker 5:  just fully insulting to me that you think this is worth my time.
Speaker 6:  You didn't like the show about the latino slash kind of English
Speaker 6:  man who becomes an avatar of justice wrapped up
Speaker 6:  in Egyptian mythology.
Speaker 5:  That's a show where it's like Disney assumed I would like the concept
Speaker 5:  and the fact that it was a marvel and that there would be an infinite variety
Speaker 5:  of SEO targeted webpages about the backstory,
Speaker 5:  the character and not care at all about
Speaker 5:  the actual show that was on my television, which had a CGI
Speaker 5:  budget of $5, right? And I was like, I'm watching this. I'm like, everything
Speaker 5:  about me is primed to, I love Oscar Isaac. Yeah. Everything about me
Speaker 5:  is primed to love this show. And I, I wanted to go away like
Speaker 5:  I think you should start over was basically my reaction to this. And I think
Speaker 5:  that's, that's just true of a lot of Marvel stuff lately and I think that's
Speaker 5:  actually a bigger problem than Disney wants to admit.
Speaker 6:  I think that we're, what we, krantz and I talk about this a lot cuz you know,
Speaker 6:  we're those people, but I think that what we have sort of part of
Speaker 6:  the ugh is phase four a flop with Marvel. I think that part of what
Speaker 6:  people are picking up on are shifts within the studio, right? Shifts within
Speaker 6:  the budgeting, right? We are seeing, we are all very familiar with what
Speaker 6:  a production that involves volumes looks like these days. And we have our
Speaker 6:  feelings about them. A lot of people, I think the volumes are a big part
Speaker 6:  of Moon Night and that was a big part of what made everything feel so
Speaker 6:  music video, because it's not cheap, it's not that, it's not that they look
Speaker 6:  cheap, they do look very expensive. Expensive isn't the word. They look like
Speaker 6:  the presence of money is involved, right? But,
Speaker 6:  but it's not necessarily leading towards something that feels
Speaker 6:  polished despite it feeling shiny. And I think that yes, from
Speaker 6:  Marble's perspective, there are financial reasons as to why it
Speaker 6:  makes sense to work that way, right? When you are just looking at the
Speaker 6:  list of productions that are going on, you have to keep them under a certain
Speaker 6:  kind of budget. Particularly for these projects that live on Disney Plus.
Speaker 6:  We are at a point right now where when we are seeing a significant part of
Speaker 6:  the franchise existing in episodic format, right? Even though the Netflix
Speaker 6:  shows were sort of a big deal when they first launched Disney slash Marble
Speaker 6:  didn't get really serious, serious about tv, sorry, agents of Sheel
Speaker 6:  until Disney Plus existed, right? Yeah. I mean putting out shows
Speaker 6:  that were directly meant to feed into the movies in a significant kind of
Speaker 6:  way and, but
Speaker 5:  Then they didn't. But even even this, I feel like I did all this homework
Speaker 5:  about the multiverse and then it just didn't matter
Speaker 5:  in that movie.
Speaker 6:  I think that there was a lot of planning that went into it, but I don't think
Speaker 6:  that the execution has been all that great. I think that what we are seeing
Speaker 6:  is one of the biggest corporations in the world trying something out and
Speaker 6:  not entirely sticking the landing despite the fact that their inordinate
Speaker 6:  amount of resources should have made it impossible for them to mess it up
Speaker 6:  quite like this.
Speaker 5:  It literally feels like watching Wanda vision was now homework that I did
Speaker 5:  not need to do. There was like entertaining homework side reading that was
Speaker 5:  not important for any reason.
Speaker 2:  It just feels a lot like comics. Like if you're in the comics
Speaker 2:  space right now, then you're like, oh no, there's a big crossover. I gotta
Speaker 2:  go pick up like Captain Marvel from three years ago,
Speaker 2:  number 12 and read that. So I know what I'm gonna be expecting. And
Speaker 2:  that's a lot of work
Speaker 6:  And in a, it's weird to say, but like the M C U became
Speaker 6:  comic bookie in phase four, which is both a positive and a negative. Do
Speaker 6:  you want ridiculous stories that don't exactly make much sense and sort of
Speaker 6:  don't and don't gel with the character motivations that have
Speaker 6:  clearly been outlined in this recent story by a different creative team?
Speaker 6:  Then here you go. Like that's just comics in a nutshell. And it rubs movie
Speaker 6:  goers the wrong way because we have been, you know, we've been taught to
Speaker 6:  expect not that,
Speaker 5:  And especially by Marvel, right? Which, which successfully shed
Speaker 5:  some of that baggage in translating the comics to the screen. And so
Speaker 5:  the M C U is different and is focused and you understand what Robert
Speaker 5:  Downey Jr is gonna do. He's got a couple of moves, they're great, they're
Speaker 5:  the best moves, honestly. And like we're gonna deliver those moves
Speaker 5:  to you in an escalating series of conflicts until we kill him,
Speaker 5:  right? And like that's great. And now they're just like all over the, and
Speaker 5:  I, the reason I bring this up is to some extent the entire strategy for
Speaker 5:  Disney Plus is you are gonna want more Marvel stuff.
Speaker 5:  You're gonna want more Star Wars stuff. You're just want these franchises
Speaker 5:  to get milked until they're dry and then you gotta make 'em crazy. That's
Speaker 5:  their monopoly strategy beyond your kids are gonna watch Encanto
Speaker 5:  three times a week, but, and that's fine like grades I, but like
Speaker 5:  there's not a lot of rewatch potential inside the
Speaker 5:  Spider-Man movies or whatever, right? Like they're, they're just like missing
Speaker 5:  something now where they're just getting crazier and crazier and it
Speaker 5:  seems like the Marvel audience, the big danger here is the Marvel audience
Speaker 5:  is like, is this one gonna be worth it?
Speaker 6:  Right? And I think that that's kind of, that is the unfortunate reality
Speaker 6:  of where it is right now. Like it's interesting to think of what other alternatives
Speaker 6:  a studio could have gone for. Is it all right? Well now that Thanos has gone,
Speaker 6:  things have to just get bigger and more cosmic and more
Speaker 6:  ridiculous. Is it that, or is just, let's just start over, right? Like let's
Speaker 6:  just start over with a different group of people who exist in this world
Speaker 6:  and the fact that the studio didn't decide to go on that direction or rather
Speaker 6:  has only just started to kind of do it with the thunderbolts
Speaker 6:  and they're sort of like, like let's just sort of, and I'm not sure that
Speaker 6:  raising the stakes was the right move for something that is
Speaker 6:  presumably meant to exist in perpetuity, right? Like
Speaker 6:  comic books are created with the assumption that the stu like the
Speaker 6:  stories are just gonna keep going long enough that it won't matter when stories
Speaker 6:  come back around and you sort of see the cyclical nature of the business.
Speaker 6:  But movies have never worked that way, right? Sequels always have to
Speaker 6:  be bigger and more expensive and better. And unfortunately
Speaker 6:  Disney slash Marvel have not sort of recognized that they
Speaker 6:  are in a position to encourage their audiences not to think that way.
Speaker 6:  They have sort of fed into the expectation that you are always going to get
Speaker 6:  sort of like a more spectacular product. And in doing so, it's kind of work
Speaker 6:  themselves into this weird corner where it's like, well how do we, how
Speaker 6:  do we keep making these things bigger and better? I'm not really sure that
Speaker 6:  you can,
Speaker 2:  Well it's like they, they haven't, they haven't acknowledged that basically
Speaker 2:  they're doing soap operas but with fancier colors and no, they just
Speaker 2:  need to embrace like the whole story mechanism that soap
Speaker 2:  operas figured out in the sixties. But we gotta, we gotta, we gotta vote
Speaker 2:  like Disney plus go 90 scale, where is it right now?
Speaker 5:  Disney Plus or Disney?
Speaker 2:  Disney Plus. We're just talking about Disney Plus, which is where the Marvel
Speaker 2:  lives, which is where Bluey
Speaker 5:  Disney Plus is. Zero. It's a zero ER's back they got
Speaker 5:  Bluey. Yeah, right. Like you know, you don't know what to watch. Avengers
Speaker 5:  end game is right there. It'll burn three hours. Zero.
Speaker 2:  All right, so zero. Unless with an asterisks, if they get rid of Bluey
Speaker 2:  and then it's like a five,
Speaker 5:  If they get rid of Bluey it's a 90, I'm just like, they're dead to me. Get
Speaker 5:  outta here. Hulu I think is like an 85. I think the future
Speaker 5:  of Hulu is, is deeply up for grabs and it, but I will also say this,
Speaker 5:  Hulu has been at 85 since the first day Hulu existed. Yeah, this is
Speaker 5:  an improbable product.
Speaker 6:  The weird Franken service,
Speaker 2:  Charles, where's your Disney plus? Your Disney Plus is at a zero.
Speaker 6:  There's always a little bit of fatalism in me, so like no one is safe, but
Speaker 6:  like I think that they're at like a solid 15. Wait,
Speaker 5:  You gave Netflix a two when you're giving Disney plus a 15?
Speaker 6:  I'm going to stick with what I said because I said it and I'm not gonna
Speaker 6:  backtrack just cuz I was challenged on it, but I do, I do think that
Speaker 6:  there is a, just because Disney Plus is a newer service, I am
Speaker 6:  still waiting to sort of see Disney Plus prove what its thing
Speaker 6:  is aside from, hey, we got the Disney content,
Speaker 2:  We got the babies,
Speaker 6:  We got the babies, and we got the Star Wars nerds. And I get that that's,
Speaker 6:  you know, that is a successful business strategy, but it doesn't light me
Speaker 6:  up. So in my mind I'm like, mm, I don't know. You better watch out. All
Speaker 2:  Right, before we get to Hulu, quick, quick break to talk about
Speaker 2:  Amazon Prime. It's still there. You are still
Speaker 2:  required to have it if you get Amazon Prime
Speaker 2:  for shipping. It is technically, I think larger now than Netflix
Speaker 2:  simply because everybody gets Amazon Prime for shipping.
Speaker 5:  Can I just say that I love that the signature show of Jeff
Speaker 5:  Bezos's streaming network is the boys. It's just, it's like
Speaker 5:  it's perfect.
Speaker 6:  Isn't that wild?
Speaker 5:  It's so good that like when you're like Jeff Bezos, what is your biggest
Speaker 5:  hit in streaming? It's like the boys, the show
Speaker 5:  about billionaires and super, super superheroes who are actually ev like
Speaker 5:  first of all the boys is great and it's amazing that Amazon just lets them
Speaker 5:  run with that show. Like I think it's great. I mean if you haven't seen it,
Speaker 5:  you should go watch it. It is a great show and it's so funny to think about,
Speaker 5:  there are so many scenes of that show where I stop and just start laughing
Speaker 5:  and thinking about Jeff Bezos watching the scene, that scene
Speaker 5:  and being like, all right. And he's like, well this is what I paid for,
Speaker 2:  But this wasn't supposed to be his big series, right? Like this wasn't supposed
Speaker 2:  to be the big landmark series of Amazon Prime. It was supposed to be the
Speaker 2:  one that just came out this year. The Rings of Power, which
Speaker 2:  I finished watching everybody else in my group watch
Speaker 2:  tapped out after like episode five. They couldn't go any further.
Speaker 6:  The rings of power was, it was, it was interesting the three, three
Speaker 6:  episodes that I made it through, but it's kind of like, it is
Speaker 6:  the danger in chasing these kinds of established IP that are
Speaker 6:  very big and very popular, but have been so thoroughly mined already
Speaker 6:  that the question becomes what is not just the point,
Speaker 6:  but sort of like, what is the ad here? What is the ad for me, an
Speaker 6:  average consumer who is not a dye in the wool fan of these things. I think
Speaker 6:  that it's really interesting to look at how the streamers are gunning for
Speaker 6:  fandom and sort of like hoping that they are able to
Speaker 6:  tap into not just a specific fandoms interest in a thing, but a
Speaker 6:  fandoms desire to promote that thing and sort of spread its message
Speaker 6:  to other listeners. And I think that that was definitely a part of the logic
Speaker 6:  behind chasing the Lord of the Rings estate. Yeah. And hounding them
Speaker 6:  down for chunks of the ip but not the great chunks of the IP
Speaker 6:  to Amazon's credit. Like they put the story together, it's solid.
Speaker 6:  The cast is great. Yeah. Love the world building. But it's, it's also
Speaker 6:  just, this was obviously meant to be Amazon Prime's, game of
Speaker 6:  Thrones and that kind of logic just never, I don't think it ever translates
Speaker 6:  well. I think that once you as a consumer can like sniff out that kind of
Speaker 6:  logic from the studio's perspective, you're immediately kind of like, I'm
Speaker 6:  not, I'm not hot on it.
Speaker 5:  Also, everyone knows what happens. I just want to like, you can't
Speaker 5:  be like, this is our Game of Thrones. Also, everyone knows what happens has
Speaker 5:  since they were a teenager and have for 50 years,
Speaker 5:  right? Like there's, there's something broken with that calculus.
Speaker 5:  Whereas Game of Thrones had no one knows what happens,
Speaker 5:  including the guy who has not yet finished the books
Speaker 5:  and then they failed to stick the landing cuz he was like, I know some shit
Speaker 5:  happens. Like here's the, like the outline of it and they were like,
Speaker 5:  we're done with this. Like just get it done.
Speaker 6:  I think we can all agree that in the end, the House of the Dragon did emerge
Speaker 6:  as like the more this the stickier sword and
Speaker 6:  sorcery show that came out this year as opposed to the rings of power. And
Speaker 6:  I think it does sort of speak to not just that Game of Thrones
Speaker 6:  still sort of, despite the fact that a crash in Be the End still sort of
Speaker 6:  has like a, people still have a lot of fondness for it. I think it does just
Speaker 6:  sort of speak to what you're talking about. There is a degree to which this
Speaker 6:  IP has not been so thoroughly mined both with projects and in people's own
Speaker 6:  free time, that there was still like a curiosity there. Whereas with
Speaker 6:  Lord of the Rings, the fandom four Lord of the Rings, the hardcore fans,
Speaker 6:  they've read these books.
Speaker 5:  They were f I said 50 years, 70 years. They were 50 years old when
Speaker 5:  I read them as a teenager.
Speaker 6:  And so it's, it's like, well what could Amazon have done that would've made
Speaker 6:  it a success? I don't know. Right? Like, I'm not exactly sure that there
Speaker 6:  is a way that you take this and turn it into something that's going to be
Speaker 6:  a phenomenon just because it has already existed in the public consciousness
Speaker 6:  like this for so, so long.
Speaker 5:  We should talk about the other part of Amazon. So they've got like the Jack
Speaker 5:  Ryans of the world and they've got their, their little TV franchises. That's
Speaker 5:  not their economic model, right? Their economic model is, we
Speaker 5:  give you this, when you subscribe to Prime, you are much more likely to stand
Speaker 5:  for Prime or we need reasons for you to want this so you become a Prime
Speaker 5:  subscriber and then all the other benefits of Prime make it hard for you
Speaker 5:  to leave. Like, right. Amazon's business model for this service is
Speaker 5:  just wildly different than Netflix or Atrium Max or whatever. And so they're
Speaker 5:  doing things that the other streamers basically won't do or can't do
Speaker 5:  in particular live sports, right? They bought this gigantic
Speaker 5:  NFL package. If you wanna watch football on a Thursday, you have to go to
Speaker 5:  Amazon. How's that working out for you? Nii? It's, it's
Speaker 5:  hilariously fine. Like I, I'll just complain about this cuz this is the Vercast
Speaker 5:  and it's me, but they spent all of the money, they're very proud
Speaker 5:  of having spent all of the money to do 4K football broadcasts
Speaker 5:  and then they are still not doing 4K football. Like there's just something
Speaker 5:  about sports in America where it's like, even when we spend all the money
Speaker 5:  and go and get the trade press around our first in the
Speaker 5:  industry end-to-end 4K broadcast workflow, it's not gonna do it. They're
Speaker 5:  like, we're gonna go with 10 80 this year. Brutal seven
Speaker 5:  20. I, but it's, it's fine. They're able to do it because they're like, look,
Speaker 5:  football fans wanna watch their team. It's a guarantee that they're gonna
Speaker 5:  get irritated into paying for Prime. This is what every football fan has
Speaker 5:  ever said, just let it I, let me watch the game wherever I am, they're gonna
Speaker 5:  pay for it and then they're gonna get Prime and then they're gonna get music
Speaker 5:  and then like their Alexa will work better and then the shipping will be
Speaker 5:  free and whatever bundle of prime things you care about will happen to you
Speaker 5:  and then you'll stay. Right? And so they're able to front investments into
Speaker 5:  things that basically no one else can do. And Charles, I wonder like
Speaker 5:  we've talked a lot about just sort of how the business affects the content
Speaker 5:  and the context of hbo, Netflix. I'm wondering if you see any differences
Speaker 5:  with Amazon there because that's the, I would also put them at a, at like
Speaker 5:  a zero on the go, 90 scale. They're not going anywhere because their business
Speaker 5:  is a subsidy and is subsidized.
Speaker 6:  Right? And it's such a, it's, it's weird to think about it this way, but
Speaker 6:  in my mind, just because I've been covering these things for so long, Amazon
Speaker 6:  Prime rather Amazon's Studios is still a side project for Amazon in
Speaker 6:  my mind, right? Like even though that is an entire, like, that is an entire
Speaker 6:  beat unto itself. And obviously Amazon has proven itself to be a strong
Speaker 6:  contender in this space just by dent of the volume of content they put out.
Speaker 6:  It's not what, you know, it is not the company's sole reason
Speaker 6:  for existence. And in being that sort of like
Speaker 6:  side hustle from Amazon's perspective, it does sort of ensure that
Speaker 6:  it's not always going to exist, but there's no reason for them to get rid
Speaker 6:  of it. Right? It's not, and it's proven itself to be a successful
Speaker 6:  sort of business strategy for them in a way that I am.
Speaker 6:  I think that's part of why you do see, I, I'm thinking in my head right now,
Speaker 6:  like Disney Plus is trying to do like, Hey, do you wanna buy these things
Speaker 6:  from us? And it's such a, it's such an odd sort of pivot for them. Like,
Speaker 6:  Hey, we're opening up a shop to a limited number of our subscribers where
Speaker 6:  you can buy Star Wars paraphernalia. And it's like, that's cute. And I'm
Speaker 6:  sure you know, they'll get a few hundred, few thousand maybe sales out of
Speaker 6:  that. But it does sort of just feel like a pale comparison to the structure
Speaker 6:  of H B O Max, which is just like, hey, while you're watching the boys also
Speaker 6:  get on Amazon and buy the comics, sorry, on
Speaker 6:  Amazon, right? Like buy the comics, buy the Funko pops, buy all of these
Speaker 6:  things, send us more data points to know which characters you like
Speaker 6:  on this show so that we just, you know, like, you know what I mean? It just
Speaker 6:  sort of all seems that the thing that's happening at Disney Plus does sort
Speaker 6:  of feel informed by Amazon's ability to collect all of this information,
Speaker 6:  but it's something that the other studios aren't in a position to really
Speaker 6:  replicate, I don't think. It's not something that any of them can sort of
Speaker 6:  reverse engineer, at least not at this point in a way that would make financial
Speaker 6:  sense for them. And I think that that is definitely something that is
Speaker 6:  always going to keep Amazon on these. Like it's, it's gonna keep
Speaker 6:  Amazon in this space.
Speaker 5:  All right, so I'm at go 90 zero. Are you at zero two?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Yeah, yeah. Nothing like, nothing has heard Amazon in a way that would
Speaker 6:  ever make me think like, oh, Amazon Studios is probably
Speaker 2:  Amazon Prime is going to exist forever. As long
Speaker 2:  as Amazon exists, you're gonna be able to get this,
Speaker 2:  will the content be good? Who can say,
Speaker 5:  Yeah, by the way, we just had Steve Boom who runs Amazon music,
Speaker 5:  actually he just got promoted to run even more things in Amazon, but Steve
Speaker 5:  Boom was just on decoder and he was like, here are the three things people
Speaker 5:  get out of Amazon. Prime shipping, prime video, distant
Speaker 5:  third music. Like it's, they're the two things. It's the, it's the shipping
Speaker 5:  and the video that are the point of Amazon Prime right now. Everything
Speaker 5:  else in the bundle is like Mathed out, but those are the top two and that
Speaker 5:  means I think it's safe forever.
Speaker 2:  That's fair. All right, now we're gonna talk about the really unsafe
Speaker 2:  one, which is Hulu because the big thing here
Speaker 2:  is is Hulu's jointly owned by Disney and
Speaker 2:  Comcast. Right Now
Speaker 5:  We need to disclose that Comcast is minority investor in Vox Media parent
Speaker 5:  company. I assure you if you're listening to this, they don't like us very
Speaker 5:  much, but there's your disclosure.
Speaker 2:  But the, basically this contract is kind of ending next year,
Speaker 2:  right?
Speaker 6:  So this is a holdover from
Speaker 6:  Disney's 2019 acquisition of Fox. Fox
Speaker 6:  owned a third of Hulu along with Comcast and Disney. And rather than
Speaker 6:  buying Fox's portion of Disney because to say, I forget exactly how
Speaker 6:  much Disney bought Fox four, they left those rights to
Speaker 6:  exist with Comcast because bringing them all on at once would've just been
Speaker 6:  too expensive. The deal at the time was, hey look, you can keep this third
Speaker 6:  of Hulu, but in 2024 you're gonna sell it back to us for
Speaker 6:  a price that we agree on now. Like we're gonna set this price, this is just
Speaker 6:  the minimum 2024 comes around, we're gonna renegotiate this.
Speaker 6:  The deadline to follow through on this deal is coming up and it's coming
Speaker 6:  at a time when the streaming landscape is just different, right?
Speaker 6:  Disney is all in on Disney Plus and
Speaker 6:  it wants to sink as much money as it can into just buffing out Disney
Speaker 6:  plus spending the money to buy back those rights from Comcast.
Speaker 6:  It could, it definitely could. It doesn't necessarily want to because it's
Speaker 6:  just a level of spend that all of the streamers universally are sort of like
Speaker 6:  trying to like cut down on if they're going to be spending millions of dollars,
Speaker 6:  it better be on themselves rather than just buying out something else. Also,
Speaker 6:  just in buying Hulu, what Disney gets out of it isn't immediately clear to
Speaker 6:  me. Obviously they would get access to some of the content on
Speaker 6:  Hulu, but then does that get folded into Disney Plus? It's not exactly clear
Speaker 6:  what kind of Well,
Speaker 5:  So, but they're kind of doing it.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I was, I mean probably same thing you were gonna say, but a lot of
Speaker 2:  that content is already folded into Disney Plus in other markets. It's just
Speaker 2:  in the United States where it's split off and when, when Disney Plus was
Speaker 2:  launched, they said, okay, Disney plus is for the kitties and the
Speaker 2:  Star Wars people and the Disney adults, and then
Speaker 2:  Hulu is for normal people and that's gonna be where all
Speaker 2:  of our FX stuff goes and that's where all of our adult stuff is gonna
Speaker 2:  go. And they, they've kind of kept that branding, but we've seen both Capic
Speaker 2:  and Iger be like, eh, do we need those two separate
Speaker 2:  platforms and, and be a lot more hesitant on that. And then we've also had
Speaker 2:  Comcast say, yeah, actually we wanna own this whole platform and, and,
Speaker 2:  and just do that because our business is going to die soon and all
Speaker 2:  we're gonna, we're gonna be in the internet business and that's about it.
Speaker 2:  And we need some sort of TV revenue stream and we're really good, really
Speaker 2:  good at it. I'm using air quotes here so we, we want it so that we
Speaker 2:  can be playing in this space that everybody else is playing in the streaming
Speaker 2:  space. So you've got these like two companies who are both pretty
Speaker 2:  invested and have good reasons to own it, who are gonna have to fight in
Speaker 2:  2023 over it.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And I fundamentally, it's, they both want to use it. They want to kill
Speaker 5:  it to bolster their other products, right? Comcast wants to bolster
Speaker 5:  Peacock and Disney wants to obviously bolster Disney Plus. And
Speaker 5:  it's funny because Hulu itself is a good product that
Speaker 5:  it's customers like its owners have always hated it. And this has
Speaker 5:  been the dynamic since it is Exi, like since the first day that it is,
Speaker 5:  it is successful despite the fact that it's ownership has actively been
Speaker 5:  trying to kill it since its inception. Originally
Speaker 2:  It was like just this little upstart and you're like, oh, you wanna watch
Speaker 2:  TV live? We figured out a way to do it, use Hulu. And then all the TV
Speaker 2:  companies were like, wait, that's our content. We're just gonna buy you
Speaker 2:  all together and own you so that you become our official streamer.
Speaker 2:  Because remember ABC go,
Speaker 5:  Do you remember when every Disney brand was on a the go.com subdomain for
Speaker 5:  some a completely unclear reason.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, absolutely. Brutal. So, so Hulu is, is facing
Speaker 2:  a space, but it's also like it's winning awards. As you noted earlier, the
Speaker 2:  dropout cleaned up pretty reasonably at the Emmy's.
Speaker 2:  Amanda Siegfried run won for the dropout.
Speaker 2:  Elizabeth Holmes lost and is now in jail
Speaker 2:  for 11 years.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I mean look, Hulu is fine. It has some good stuff. It is another one
Speaker 5:  of those sort of default players. It has a good live TV bundle. Yeah. People
Speaker 5:  like it. If you know there, there's a handful of them out in the market.
Speaker 5:  YouTube TV and Hulu seem to be the leaders. It exists. Like
Speaker 5:  there's a conviction to Hulu that is shocking
Speaker 5:  given its ownership. And I think that's just a success. I would say
Speaker 5:  that a year from now when one of these, one of the
Speaker 5:  two owners has eaten it, it's gone. Hmm. And that will actually, it will
Speaker 5:  be in some ways a tragedy.
Speaker 6:  I mean, it is gonna come down to who is willing to either
Speaker 6:  spend slash forego the cash, right? Like that is gonna be the thing that
Speaker 6:  determines Hulu's future. And I genuinely don't feel that anything that's
Speaker 6:  going on at Hulu is going to keep it from being destroyed.
Speaker 6:  Unfortunately, just because everyone who has a financial interest in it does
Speaker 6:  stand to gain something either by its acquisition or destruction.
Speaker 6:  So they won't just leave it to exist.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It's funny cuz we're basically predicting it's going away, but it's
Speaker 5:  the, as I look at the list, well Apple TV plus is on this list in
Speaker 5:  South anymore. But as you look at the list, right, the list here is
Speaker 5:  like, so Netflix, hbo, Disney, Amazon, Hulu, those
Speaker 5:  are the ones where you, you don't feel bad about recommending that anyone
Speaker 5:  pay money for them, right? You're gonna get your money back out of those
Speaker 5:  subscriptions in one way or the other. You're gonna be entertained, the apps
Speaker 5:  aren't gonna crash on you. You know, it it, there's just something
Speaker 5:  solid about these ones we're about to turn the corner into.
Speaker 5:  Ugh, maybe there's one show you want, right? And
Speaker 5:  it's funny that the, the Hulu is the last one to talk about cuz it is the
Speaker 5:  one that is Yep. It's the one you can feel safe recommending.
Speaker 5:  It's also the one that is definitely gonna go away. Right? And this is the,
Speaker 5:  this is the corner that's turning where the business models of these and
Speaker 5:  the ownership structures of these companies are more determinant of
Speaker 5:  their futures than the content or the quality of the content. So, okay,
Speaker 5:  go 90 scale for Hulu. I'm putting it solidly at
Speaker 2:  80
Speaker 5:  80. It's, it's done for
Speaker 2:  Charles.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. 80 feels right, especially because like, because the deadline
Speaker 6:  is coming up and I don't think that it would benefit either side to just
Speaker 6:  not move on it. Like they can't just ignore the deadline and be like, we're
Speaker 6:  just gonna pretend that we never had those conversations. They
Speaker 6:  are gonna, they are, they are gonna move on it and it's probably gonna lead
Speaker 6:  to Hulu's destruction unfortunately. So, hey,
Speaker 2:  I'm putting it at 85 just to be contrarian.
Speaker 2:  I think it's even closer to death cuz Comcast is gonna
Speaker 5:  Buy it at and t buys it.
Speaker 7:  No.
Speaker 2:  Okay, we're gonna take one more break and then we're gonna come back and
Speaker 2:  we'll get into Peacock Paramount Plus and my personal favorite, the Taylor
Speaker 2:  Sheridan Universe
Speaker 3:  Support for this episode comes from another bite. If you're a Shark Tank
Speaker 3:  fan or business junkie, then you'll love another bite. Each week the
Speaker 3:  host breaks down the biggest success stories and most disastrous failures
Speaker 3:  to come out of Shark Tank. From the Squatty Potty to the Waken Bacon,
Speaker 3:  they dive into each company's pitch, analyze the deals that were or
Speaker 3:  weren't made, and answer the million dollar question. Is that company
Speaker 3:  still a company? Basically, they cover all the things you need to know to
Speaker 3:  survive the tank or scale a company on your own. Whether
Speaker 3:  you're an entrepreneur looking for tips or a fan looking to relive the show's
Speaker 3:  most dramatic moments, another bite offers a deep dive into the world of
Speaker 3:  Shark Tank. Just search for another bite and your favorite podcast app,
Speaker 3:  like the one you're using right now.
Speaker 8:  Support for this episode comes from the Hustle Daily Show on the
Speaker 8:  HubSpot Podcast Network. If you're anything like us, sometimes
Speaker 8:  you just want someone to round up the business tech and trends, news stories
Speaker 8:  you actually need to know before you're done with your first cup of coffee.
Speaker 8:  The Hustle Daily Show is that someone this show sifts through some of the
Speaker 8:  most pertinent business media stories of the day to save you from scouring
Speaker 8:  multiple news sources and gives you back that valuable time. Nothing like
Speaker 8:  an irreverent, offbeat, informative take on what's going on in all things
Speaker 8:  business. Join the Hustle Daily Crew every day wherever you listen to
Speaker 8:  podcasts. Head to hubspot.com/podcast network
Speaker 8:  to start listening today.
Speaker 2:  Okay, we're back now. Let's talk about ne Eli's
Speaker 2:  personal favorite. Peacock. Peacock exists.
Speaker 2:  If you wanna watch Yellowstone, you have to subscribe to Peacock.
Speaker 5:  The number of emails I get
Speaker 8:  About Yellowstone,
Speaker 2:  This new show with Carla Gugino, you have to subscribe. That's all I know
Speaker 2:  about Peacock.
Speaker 5:  I've, so we have started watching Yellowstone because everyone has recommended
Speaker 5:  it to us. It's good. It's one of those shows that is, you know, it's like
Speaker 5:  the water, it's everywhere, but no one talks about it except once you,
Speaker 5:  once you tell the algorithms of the internet that you are mildly interested
Speaker 5:  in Yellowstone. Everyone's talking about it. Hmm. First season, the great
Speaker 5:  Second Season's little, it's just, it's one of the, like, they're doing the
Speaker 5:  thing where they keep escalating the stakes and so it's just,
Speaker 5:  it's just getting sillier. But that's fine. It's well acted. It's great.
Speaker 5:  I get why people are into it. It's succession on horses.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. You can't say no
Speaker 2:  Sometimes there's guns.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. The number of characters that are introduced on the show merely
Speaker 5:  so that they can be murdered. Like ever. This,
Speaker 5:  it's, we could do a whole hour on it. It's so funny. Like people talk about
Speaker 5:  how beautifully written it is and there are some banger lines in every
Speaker 5:  episode and then there's just some like, oh, our, our
Speaker 5:  character murders, people need some more people to murder. Here's some people,
Speaker 5:  people that are gonna show up to get murdered. Like it's just like nakedly
Speaker 5:  happening. Like, oh, these people are gonna die. So it, it has its moments
Speaker 5:  in the way that a big swirling soap opera has its moments. Okay. But it's
Speaker 5:  also found an audience for Peacock for Paramount Plus, right? Like
Speaker 5:  Paramount Plus is fully invested in this universe. They're doing
Speaker 5:  prequels after prequels, they're bringing in star talent.
Speaker 2:  1923 is coming,
Speaker 5:  Right? And then they're gonna do 1883. Like they're going back in time
Speaker 5:  in a like a hilarious way. The Stars all want to work with Taylor Sheridan.
Speaker 5:  Like they've built a, a Marvel franchise out of
Speaker 5:  a ranch in Montana and it's sort of like under remarked upon,
Speaker 5:  except now everyone is, they're realizing like, oh, the money is here. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And you might be able to stand up an entire streaming network
Speaker 5:  full of the Paramount Library on the back of this franchise.
Speaker 5:  That's, by the way, Taylor Sheridan like, writes and directs every episode
Speaker 5:  himself. Their bet is that he won't keel over and die. But
Speaker 5:  that's like it, that's, that's what they got. They got that and then like
Speaker 5:  everyone just bought Top Gun Maverick. So like, they didn't even like get
Speaker 5:  the window of Top Gun. There's not a lot else there.
Speaker 5:  And I'm, I'm, and I'm bundling Paramount and Peacock together.
Speaker 2:  You're bundling them together.
Speaker 5:  Well just because the thing that's driving peacock right now is
Speaker 5:  Yellowstone, right.
Speaker 2:  Because Paramount Plus didn't think about it at the time when they were,
Speaker 2:  when they were like, we need to sell the streaming rights and instead of
Speaker 2:  keeping it on Paramount Yeah, right. Peacock, you can have the streaming
Speaker 2:  rights to this, it'll be fine. And they're, they're now like, we have a lot
Speaker 2:  of regret. We asked Peacock if we could have the rights back and Peacock
Speaker 2:  was like,
Speaker 5:  No, no. It's the only reason people subscribe to Peacock. Peacock straight
Speaker 5:  up. So I would say Peacock to me is, is at the most honest
Speaker 5:  80 of them all. Yes. Like it's straight up. It's,
Speaker 5:  it's the Comcast NBC disclosure, Comcast is always, it
Speaker 5:  doesn't have hits. They wanted the hit to be the Olympics trying to figure
Speaker 5:  out that company's approach to streaming the Olympics. Like that was the
Speaker 5:  most honest, how to watch SEO, target bait that we've ever done. You know,
Speaker 5:  like cuz it was hard, it was like legitimate. Like this is a good
Speaker 5:  service to our audience to be like, how do I do this? Because
Speaker 5:  they're so complicated. They haven't gotten the 4K stuff on sports right.
Speaker 5:  At all. Yeah. And then the rest of it is what used to be
Speaker 5:  Netflix's sort of like sleepy time binge watch stuff like The
Speaker 5:  Office, right? Right. And they thought that bringing the office would bring
Speaker 5:  all that audience over and it turns out Netflix would be like, Nope, you
Speaker 5:  want a nap while you watch stuff. We have infinity content for comfort napping
Speaker 5:  to be to happen. So I just think like they've gotta make a huge
Speaker 5:  change to Peacock and maybe it means going away and buying all
Speaker 5:  of Hulu and leaning into Hulu.
Speaker 2:  Peacock's gonna be a channel on Max and Amazon
Speaker 2:  Prime. I think that's what happens.
Speaker 5:  Oh, just like one of those, like you subscribe to it within a larger bundle.
Speaker 5:  Yeah,
Speaker 2:  I think, I think a hundred percent that's what happens to it. But
Speaker 5:  Why wouldn't you just do that with nbc?
Speaker 2:  Because it's called Peacock Neil.
Speaker 5:  This is what I mean. Like, I, I this brand isn't worth anything to anyone.
Speaker 5:  Like Yeah, you buy Hulu and you, you like run it as Hulu and you like merge
Speaker 5:  everything together or you sell NBC or your constituent
Speaker 5:  like famous good brands Yeah. As channels into the bigger services.
Speaker 5:  There's no reason to try to build up a thing called Peacock your
Speaker 5:  desire to have a product like this.
Speaker 2:  Right. Like they just, it was like, I wanna be a part of this as well moment
Speaker 2:  for them. And I think you're right that like it's an 80, it's, it
Speaker 2:  doesn't last much longer. What about you
Speaker 6:  Charles? I'm gonna put it at a 79.
Speaker 6:  Right? For one reason. One reason. And it's not, it's not just
Speaker 6:  the contrarian. I'm legitimately excited to see what poker face is about
Speaker 6:  Ryan Johnson and Natasha Leone's thing that's coming out where she's a non
Speaker 6:  paranormal detective who can somehow always tell when people are lying. Like
Speaker 6:  it's like, it's silly premise. The trail looked great and I'm like, peacock,
Speaker 6:  why? Unfortunately you should have like been leading with stuff like this.
Speaker 6:  You know, the the Gritty Fresh Prince reboot was not exactly going to
Speaker 6:  make me sign up for a new service. And then the show wasn't particularly
Speaker 6:  good. And so I thought to myself, oh, peacock's no one to pay attention to,
Speaker 6:  but then just happened to casually see this and it's like, oh, like that
Speaker 6:  looks interesting. Is it enough to save a
Speaker 6:  streamer? No. Yeah. Could it? Yes it could. It could.
Speaker 6:  It could. And so that's why I'm putting it at a 79 because
Speaker 6:  maybe that will be the thing. Maybe it will be
Speaker 5:  One show.
Speaker 6:  It will be their Game of Thrones and their orange is a new black and
Speaker 6:  they're transparent all rolled into one and everyone
Speaker 2:  Ted lasso everything at once. Yeah, yeah, yeah. All right. Let's talk about
Speaker 2:  Paramount Plus because that's, that's the other kind of weird
Speaker 2:  wonky service started by a terrestrial TV show.
Speaker 5:  I'm telling you. Paramount plus Yellowstone Universe,
Speaker 5:  red America. Yeah, they're, that thing is solid. Like they've got a
Speaker 5:  franchise that they can build on. They've gotta do all the rest of this stuff.
Speaker 2:  They've got multiple franchises. They've got, they've got the, the Avatar
Speaker 2:  franchise from Nickelodeon, they've got all of the Star
Speaker 2:  Trek. A lot of it's just been like nostalgia bait, which is lazy but I'll
Speaker 2:  watch it. People
Speaker 6:  Like lower decks.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, people like lower Decks, people like the one with Anson Mount, it seems
Speaker 2:  to be popular. And then Halo came out. I know a lot
Speaker 2:  of people found it pretty forgettable. I'm still tuning in for season two.
Speaker 5:  Here's what, okay, so here's the argument for it not being under
Speaker 5:  45. Okay? For Right Under 45 is more alive than dead, right? Yeah.
Speaker 5:  The argument for More Dead than Live 45 and over on the
Speaker 5:  go 90 scale of Dune streaming services. The thing that we invented makes
Speaker 5:  no sense, but the argument that it's more dead than Alive is we are in
Speaker 5:  the honeymoon phase of a just launch streaming service that
Speaker 5:  has a couple of hits and the money and the attention and the vibes are good
Speaker 5:  and there's no the the underlying corporate structure,
Speaker 2:  But Paramount Plus is not just launched.
Speaker 5:  Well it kind of did. Right? But it didn't like
Speaker 2:  It. It was a rebranding of CBS All Access, which started
Speaker 2:  almost immediately after Hulu because CBS said we don't wanna be
Speaker 2:  a part of Hulu, we want our own thing.
Speaker 5:  Sure. But CBS All Access was like not a huge hit. What I'm saying is Yeah,
Speaker 5:  paramount Plus is the, the new home of the
Speaker 5:  merged CBS Viacom corporate entity. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Which did not exist before,
Speaker 2:  Which did not. Yeah, that's true.
Speaker 5:  Right. So they rebrand, they took the CBS all access tech platform and they
Speaker 5:  rebranded it Paramount Plus after CBS and Viacom merged, by the way, this,
Speaker 5:  if you want succession, like the actual history of CBS and Viacom and the
Speaker 5:  Redstone, like it's crazy. The Redstone family is nuts, but they now the
Speaker 5:  company, it's one merged company. They've got all the brands and they are
Speaker 5:  in that honeymoon period of new leadership, new company, new
Speaker 5:  product with some big hits. There's nothing aside from that
Speaker 5:  that tells you, oh, these vibes will continue. Right? There's not an
Speaker 5:  enormous business model success underlying it. There's not a
Speaker 5:  history of technology innovation here from
Speaker 5:  this company in particular.
Speaker 2:  I don't think it's history of tech innovation, but I do think like we cannot
Speaker 2:  ignore the fact that CBS for decades has been
Speaker 2:  very, very good at finding what people wanna watch and getting
Speaker 2:  it in front of them. Like CBS dominated,
Speaker 6:  We denigrate like the the ncis. Yeah. You know, of the world.
Speaker 6:  But they are successful franchises that have been on since Time and
Speaker 6:  Morum because people want to watch them. And us talking about the
Speaker 6:  fact that people are still watching Big Bang Theory on h b Om Max. I think
Speaker 6:  that CBS is definitely in a position to leverage its terrestrial
Speaker 6:  audience on two Paramount plus they have not demonstrated
Speaker 6:  any sort of plan or ability to do so. Yet they are
Speaker 6:  still so new into their existence at Yeah,
Speaker 2:  No, no. I'd argue that this Yellowstone thing is their plan, right? Because
Speaker 2:  most of the people who are originally watching Yellowstone are watching it
Speaker 2:  on Paramount tv, a terrestrial, like a cable
Speaker 2:  channel or they're maybe watching it on Peacock to catch up and then
Speaker 2:  they're saying, okay, you watched that, you liked that. Now do you wanna
Speaker 2:  watch this thing where Harrison Ford plays Kevin Costner's, I
Speaker 2:  think great uncle in the 1920s and Helen Miens there
Speaker 2:  in Irish come right. Watch that. And so like that's, that's what they're
Speaker 2:  doing is they're trying, they're trying to do kind of what Netflix originally
Speaker 2:  did, which is say you like these characters, you like this stuff,
Speaker 2:  you are scared of streaming because you live in rural
Speaker 2:  Colorado. I'm thinking of just like one specific friend of mine come
Speaker 2:  spend your $4 you and it's just like watching regular
Speaker 2:  tv. You still get your commercials, spend your $4 and now you get
Speaker 2:  to watch this premium show with Helen, me and and Harrison Ford
Speaker 2:  and like I like, I think we all kind of discount them because it's
Speaker 2:  cbs, it's Paramount. Like it's the people who gave us N C I S and the
Speaker 2:  Chicago series. But at the same time those things are
Speaker 2:  hugely, hugely popular. A lot of people watch it
Speaker 2:  and I think that's gonna continue to be the case for Paramount Plus. I'm
Speaker 2:  really curious to see what their subscription numbers are like.
Speaker 5:  All right, I'm putting them at 45 after this conversation. I'm putting 'em
Speaker 5:  at
Speaker 2:  45. I'm putting 'em at like 32. Okay. It's a fun number.
Speaker 6:  I would still put them at like a 55 because it does it again. Like
Speaker 6:  if they are not able to really sort of get it together and figure out
Speaker 6:  how to convert that old school audience into
Speaker 6:  subscribers, then yeah, paramount Plus is gonna be in a really rough position.
Speaker 6:  But if they are able to make it seem like the easiest and
Speaker 6:  sort of most familiar service for their fans to sort of glom onto,
Speaker 6:  yeah, it will be around.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I think 1923 is gonna be a big deal for them or at least a big
Speaker 2:  change for them one way or the other. All right, now we're gonna talk about
Speaker 2:  Apple TV plus no Ted Lasso this year, but
Speaker 2:  Severance Severance was huge for them. The Major League Soccer
Speaker 2:  finally launching there. Nobody watches it cuz it's Major League
Speaker 2:  Soccer
Speaker 5:  Rael,
Speaker 2:  But it's a sport.
Speaker 5:  David Pierce is so mad at you,
Speaker 2:  He can't be here. Play with your baby David. Enjoy your adorable baby.
Speaker 2:  But you know, they, they they're getting Oscars, they're, they're winning
Speaker 2:  Emmy's. This is kind of the, a lot of people have said this is the new H
Speaker 2:  B O who
Speaker 6:  Has said that? Who?
Speaker 5:  Apples says that Eddie Q is walking around me. Like it's the new
Speaker 5:  Inviro.
Speaker 6:  Let's be specific about who's saying this.
Speaker 5:  No, so they, they have a really high bar. One thing if you open the Apple
Speaker 5:  TV app, there's a lot of stuff in there now. Yeah, right. They just
Speaker 5:  licensed like all the Will Ferrell movies for a while because they've got
Speaker 5:  the new Ryan Reynolds Will Ferrell movie. Like I was like, is this weird?
Speaker 5:  Like I'm watching old school in Apple TV plus right now,
Speaker 5:  like this doesn't make any sense, but they're starting to like
Speaker 5:  fill out the catalog in these like little spurts. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  So you're like, oh, Apple's got all the Will Ferrell movies. That's fun.
Speaker 5:  I'll like watch a bunch of those and then they're gonna go away. They're
Speaker 5:  gonna do it again. So they've got new programming ideas that make the app
Speaker 5:  feel full even though the catalog is nowhere near as big as everyone else.
Speaker 5:  They're making a bunch of stuff. They just, improbably made
Speaker 5:  Three Seasons of Sea, one of the silliest shows ever made.
Speaker 2:  They all wear masks but they can't see why do they wear the
Speaker 5:  Masks? The number of Reddit threads are like, wait, can they see? It's like
Speaker 5:  very funny on that show.
Speaker 6:  I feel like that's Apple School. They just like
Speaker 5:  Confuse a Reddit conversation into existence. They're just making
Speaker 5:  stuff and they're, some people really like the shows, but then they only
Speaker 5:  have had I think the two or three breakout hits.
Speaker 5:  Like they've made three seasons of Mythic Quests, which is a fun show to
Speaker 5:  watch. And also the sort of show that Netflix would've definitely killed
Speaker 5:  after the second season. Right. And Apple's like, yep, we're gonna re-up
Speaker 5:  it cuz some people are watching it.
Speaker 2:  Tons of critical acclaim. Everybody really, really likes Mythic Quests. I
Speaker 2:  think it even got nominated, did it get nominated for Emmy's this
Speaker 5:  Year? Yeah. The best part about Mythic Quests by the way, is how much it
Speaker 5:  relentlessly dunks. It's a show about a game studio. Yeah. And the characters
Speaker 5:  at the game studio relentlessly dunk on the concept of mobile gaming
Speaker 5:  at every turn. It's great. It's the funniest shit you've ever
Speaker 5:  heard. Like Apple made this show
Speaker 2:  A lot of, a lot of like game developers say it's the most realistic
Speaker 2:  version of their world, which horrifying you guys. Yeah. What is
Speaker 2:  happening to your industry. But, but yeah, like outside of Severance
Speaker 2:  and Ted Lasso, there's a lot of shows I really like on it, but I am
Speaker 2:  alone. Like I don't, there's a lot of other people
Speaker 5:  Watching them. We can dispense with this one quickly. Yeah. Apple's at a
Speaker 5:  zero, they're, it's not going anywhere. It's part of their services strategy.
Speaker 5:  It makes their bundle more valuable. It's the same situation as
Speaker 5:  Amazon Prime. Eventually Apple's getting the place where you pay 'em a hundred
Speaker 5:  dollars a month for your phone, your cell service
Speaker 5:  and the bundle of Apple stuff. And then every year or two you get a
Speaker 5:  new phone like they're headed towards just pay us a fee
Speaker 5:  for a phone service and all the stuff that comes on the phone. Right. Every
Speaker 5:  and that's gonna be their, their model for, and they're, that's the regular
Speaker 5:  bird chest that we can talk about that at length. But the TV stuff, they
Speaker 5:  know it's sticky. They love that acclaim. I think Tim Cook likes going
Speaker 5:  to the award shows. Oh yes fine. But the
Speaker 5:  question is they wanted to do more. Right? They wanna do
Speaker 5:  sports streaming. They have done baseball, they're starting to do soccer.
Speaker 5:  There's all the noise about them doing football. They actually have no aptitude
Speaker 5:  at this. Their baseball productions are laughably bad and people hate them.
Speaker 5:  We have not yet quite seen what they're gonna do with soccer. Right. Just
Speaker 5:  getting started and they've told the NFL we want more than the traditional
Speaker 5:  rights cuz we wanna do something innovative and the NFL's like, we make the
Speaker 5:  most money like
Speaker 2:  Buy NFL if you want it.
Speaker 5:  But it's interesting, right, because Apple like Amazon is right, the
Speaker 5:  product is subsidized, but it also creates a subsidy for everything else.
Speaker 5:  They're able to go into other parts of the ecosystem Yeah. That
Speaker 5:  the traditional streamers like Netflix and others won't do. And so I think
Speaker 5:  that to me, the future of Apple TV plus is whether they bring
Speaker 5:  on live sports and live news and take over that part of the cable bundle
Speaker 5:  that a Netflix or a Disney plus just never will.
Speaker 6:  That'd be interesting if they decided to pursue that because I do my
Speaker 6:  reticence about not reticence, I just, for whatever reason, apple shows have
Speaker 6:  not stuck with me. And I don't think it's just because I watch so many of
Speaker 6:  these things. It's just because there's some part of my mind that's like,
Speaker 6:  ah, Apple's doing TV now what do you have to say? Apple? And it all feels
Speaker 6:  like an A student going through the motions of putting out what it thinks
Speaker 6:  of as prestige tv, but it doesn't feel Apples productions never feel
Speaker 6:  like creative endeavors from like a corporate level that they're trying to
Speaker 6:  share with the world. It does very much sort of feel like a
Speaker 6:  transparent business pour, which is fine. Right? I I get it.
Speaker 6:  But it is something that always leaves me a little bit
Speaker 6:  cold to like a amidon. It's like I I
Speaker 6:  I'm not exactly sure what the company could be doing differently to make
Speaker 6:  me feel differently, but the idea of Apple
Speaker 6:  really pushing TV as a bonus utility
Speaker 6:  that sort of comes along with just being a part of the Apple ecosystem does
Speaker 6:  feel like the most prudent way to ensure its success going forward.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And I, I think the question is whether they, you know, apple TV
Speaker 5:  plus as a service is the unique Apple product
Speaker 5:  that is everywhere. Like you can just get it on Roku, you can just
Speaker 5:  get it on Android TVs. Like it's strange in its way.
Speaker 5:  And I think that's part of the underlying dynamic there is does it ever
Speaker 5:  have to be a business or is it always this sort of
Speaker 5:  factor in this long mathematical equation of the lifetime value
Speaker 5:  of an Apple customer that, you know, kind of doesn't have to justify itself
Speaker 5:  all the way because that is really, and Apple's the richest company in the
Speaker 5:  world, it's gonna somebody print money and they're gonna subsidize this thing
Speaker 5:  forever in a day. But the question is whether the service creates
Speaker 5:  an identity by having that sort of existential need to exist in a
Speaker 5:  way that, you know, like Hulu has an identity because at
Speaker 5:  every turn it has had to prove itself as a brand.
Speaker 2:  Well I feel like it's, it's kinda like with Amazon, I feel like when I, when
Speaker 2:  I open up the Amazon Prime app, it's Jeff Bezos going
Speaker 2:  enjoy your content and just flinging it at my face. And then
Speaker 2:  with Apple TV it's like Tim Cook being like, Hey, would you like to sit down
Speaker 2:  and enjoy your content? But they asked me to sit down first and it's really
Speaker 2:  polite. So I'm I'm, I'm down for it. I'm gonna give it a 10
Speaker 2:  rather than a zero. Okay. Just because at some point
Speaker 2:  I wonder if the cost is too much for, for the company.
Speaker 5:  No, you, you have to have an entire CEO transition.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Tim Cook cannot knife his own baby.
Speaker 2:  Tim Cook's not gonna do it, but I'm putting it at a 10 because Tim Cook is
Speaker 2:  gonna retire.
Speaker 5:  You're putting in a 10 because like on a long enough timeline everyone dies.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Like that's your 10. That's
Speaker 2:  My 10. I had a long enough timeline. Everyone dies and so too well Apple
Speaker 2:  TV plus Charles, what about yourself? I
Speaker 6:  Think they're a solid zero. It's Apple to come so late to the streaming game
Speaker 6:  and then to be like, hello everyone, welcome to Apple TV Plus. And then for
Speaker 6:  them to have a couple of flops and we all know it and then to, to sunset
Speaker 6:  the service would be an embarrassment I think that the company does not
Speaker 6:  want to have. So even though I'm saying that it's mostly
Speaker 6:  saving face, they will keep Apple TV plus four.
Speaker 2:  All right, so we're gonna wrap up this episode. I feel like we've learned
Speaker 2:  a lot about TV this year and we've got a bunch of new news coming next year.
Speaker 5:  Send us your submissions for the Go 90 scale of Doom Streaming Services.
Speaker 5:  We want to hear 'em.
Speaker 2:  Let us know if you're Comcast and you're planning to buy Hulu, you can
Speaker 2:  email me at alex dot crans the verge.com.
Speaker 2:  Just let me know. Give me a heads up, I wanna hear all about
Speaker 5:  It. And also, if you're ever around an executive in one of these streaming
Speaker 5:  services, just start casually saying they went 90. Yeah. Get this, get this
Speaker 5:  in the boardrooms of America. That's all I'm asking for.
Speaker 2:  Okay. That's it for the Verge cast today. Thank you guys for listening to
Speaker 2:  all of that rambling and ranting and raving about streaming. I really appreciate
Speaker 2:  it. As always. There's tons more coverage on everything we talk about
Speaker 2:  here@theverge.com. You can also follow all of us on Twitter.
Speaker 2:  Charles is at Charles Pullum. Eli is at
Speaker 2:  Reckless Patel. Or I mean you can talk to him at his real Twitter account,
Speaker 2:  which is at Reckless. And I'm at Alex h Cranz.
Speaker 2:  The show is produced by Andrew Marino and Liam James Nori Donovan is
Speaker 2:  our executive producer and Brooke Mentors is our editorial director of Audio.
Speaker 2:  The Verge Cast is a Verge production and, and part of the Vox Media podcast
Speaker 2:  network. If you have thoughts, feedbacks, feelings or Christmas
Speaker 2:  presents, you can always email vergecast the verge.com. And
Speaker 2:  if you have questions, call the hotline. It's eight sixty six
Speaker 2:  Verge 11, that's 8 66 Verge 11.
Speaker 2:  Send us all your big thoughts and questions about all things tech,
Speaker 2:  especially Ein, but all the other cool stuff too. Neil and I will be
Speaker 2:  back on Friday to chat with more of the Verge crew about whatever's happening
Speaker 2:  this week. Until then, we'll see you later. Rock and roll.