# Transcript
ID: 776113c0-78c3-11ed-a577-df8cefed9bcc
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: The dark, uncertain world of creator funds
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/7086410816898315766/2652014961927136747/s93290-US-1512s-1670701610.mp3
Description: Producer Hadley Robinson reports on the often uncertain world digital creators find themselves in trying to make a living on platforms like TikTok, Instagram, and Facebook. Should platforms pay creators directly? Are creator funds even good? Creators and experts tell us what they have found behind the curtain and what it's like to chase the dream of making a living as a digital creator.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (3 ads detected)
Speaker 1:  Welcome to the Vergecast, the flagship podcast of dynamically viral
Speaker 1:  videos. I'm your friend, David Pierce, and this is the second in
Speaker 1:  our three episode mini-series, all about the Creator
Speaker 1:  economy, emphasis on economy. We wanted to look into all the ways that
Speaker 1:  creators make money and where the money comes from and where it goes, and
Speaker 1:  how it works, and try to make sense of this whole messy
Speaker 1:  world. For this episode, we sent our producer Hadley Robinson to figure
Speaker 1:  out how creator funds work. We've heard this over and over,
Speaker 1:  over the years, Facebook, TikTok, YouTube, everybody comes up with
Speaker 1:  this big pot of money and they say, here are creators have
Speaker 1:  this. Based on how your videos do, it sounds sort of simple, right? But
Speaker 1:  the math of who gets what and where it goes and who that
Speaker 1:  money is actually for and how you earn it is very complicated. So we
Speaker 1:  sent Hadley to figure out how it all works and how creators feel about it.
Speaker 1:  Here's what she came back with.
Speaker 3:  We are now 15 years into the whole idea of a platform paying
Speaker 3:  the video creators who make content on their site.
Speaker 3:  It all started back in 2007 when YouTube launched an ad
Speaker 3:  revenue sharing program to pay their stars for creating content.
Speaker 3:  They agreed to pay creators a majority percentage of the ad revenue made
Speaker 3:  from their videos. The program started with some of the most popular creators
Speaker 3:  of the time. People like Reto, happy Slip, and Lonely Girl,
Speaker 3:  15.
Speaker 4:  We're actually getting ready to do an experiment for you. Mintos, diet Coke,
Speaker 4:  you know that whole thing? Well, we've got a new twist on it.
Speaker 5:  How many times do I have to tell her? It's not Quacker. It's Quaker Oats.
Speaker 5:  Quaker Oats,
Speaker 6:  The Purple Monkey puppet. She doesn't like to know that she's a puppet.
Speaker 7:  Woohoo. We did it. Wow. Wow.
Speaker 3:  That last one was Hank Green.
Speaker 8:  I like it here on the internet. I feel good about it.
Speaker 3:  Hank's been a YouTuber since 2007. He joined the partner program
Speaker 3:  back then and has been making 55% of the ad revenue on his videos ever since.
Speaker 8:  I have an educational media company, it almost entirely makes its money
Speaker 8:  through online video content, and about a third
Speaker 8:  to 40% of our revenue is that money. It's huge.
Speaker 8:  It's a really big deal for us. So that is really important and created a
Speaker 8:  really healthy economic ecosystem around YouTube
Speaker 3:  Content. The partner program built a dynamic where when YouTube as a
Speaker 3:  platform does better and their numbers and ad revenues go up, creators share
Speaker 3:  in that success. YouTube's partner program remains popular all these years
Speaker 3:  later, and the service has largely carried on in a league of its own,
Speaker 3:  but talk's arrival and soaring popularity has threatened
Speaker 3:  YouTube's throne.
Speaker 3:  Recent data shows that people's average watch time is now higher on TikTok
Speaker 3:  than YouTube's. Shortform algorithm driven feed
Speaker 3:  has inspired copycats from Snap, Instagram and YouTube themselves,
Speaker 3:  and they're all competing for top creators.
Speaker 3:  But TikTok and others have yet to master the whole paying creators
Speaker 3:  thing, which could be a problem competitively for them. I talked to
Speaker 3:  Professor Casey Feiser who researches online communities and tech ethics
Speaker 3:  at uc, Boulder.
Speaker 10:  I think that YouTube especially has created an
Speaker 10:  expectation that content creators can make a living
Speaker 10:  from this and that some of that living should
Speaker 10:  probably come from the people who are making money off of
Speaker 10:  their content.
Speaker 3:  She's talking about the platforms who indeed are making boatloads of money.
Speaker 3:  TikTok made an estimated 4 billion in revenue in
Speaker 3:  2021 and is on track to triple that this year. Instagram made
Speaker 3:  over 47 billion last year.
Speaker 10:  I imagine that TikTok considered whether they could have a similar kind
Speaker 10:  of revenue model to YouTube, but it is more of a challenge
Speaker 10:  because on YouTube, advertisements are directly on
Speaker 10:  specific videos. So an ad share makes a lot of sense on TikTok. That's
Speaker 10:  not quite how it works. You
Speaker 3:  Mean these are short videos basically and you can't as easily just
Speaker 3:  slap an ad on it,
Speaker 10:  Right? Well, so if you're scrolling through TikTok, you'll see like
Speaker 10:  video, video, video, video, ad, video, video.
Speaker 10:  So where does the revenue from that ad go?
Speaker 10:  And so I imagine they decided to come up with a different model and the
Speaker 10:  creator fund was what they came up with.
Speaker 3:  TikTok launched its creator fund in July, 2020.
Speaker 11:  TikTok is making a billion dollar investment in the creators making
Speaker 11:  a difference on the platform, launching the TikTok creator fund.
Speaker 11:  The project is starting out with 200 million in the US with
Speaker 11:  plans to reach 1 billion
Speaker 3:  Soon. Other platforms marched out their own similar plans.
Speaker 3:  In Lead 2020, snap launched Spotlight offering 1
Speaker 3:  million a day to creators in 2021. Meta
Speaker 3:  promised 1 billion in bonus programs and YouTube
Speaker 3:  announced a hundred million fund towards creators of shorts. It's answer
Speaker 3:  to TikTok. All of the creator funds work slightly differently and have various
Speaker 3:  requirements to join. For us, US-based TikTok ERs. To get your hands on some
Speaker 3:  of that fund money, you have to be over 18, have over
Speaker 3:  10,000 followers and over a hundred thousand views in the past 30 days. All
Speaker 3:  this money in the Creator Fund seemed like good news to a lot of TikTok
Speaker 3:  creators who rushed to join as soon as they could.
Speaker 12:  So when I hit 10,000 followers at that point, I was at the
Speaker 12:  fashion company that I was working for. I was making 40 k, and I was like,
Speaker 12:  I can use any extra penny that I can get. So I joined the
Speaker 12:  Creator Fund instantly.
Speaker 3:  That's 26 year old Philadelphia based creator Brandon Edelman,
Speaker 12:  Commonly known as Brand Slate. I create like a lot of
Speaker 12:  off the rip chaotic content,
Speaker 12:  mostly videos of me talking to the camera, telling stories,
Speaker 12:  a lot of party content. I tell people that like I'm a lifestyle
Speaker 12:  creator, but my lifestyle is like crazy partying, chaos,
Speaker 12:  kind of like Jersey Shore and the TikTok creator,
Speaker 3:  Brandon started making TikTok videos in January, 2021,
Speaker 3:  mainly just for his friends.
Speaker 12:  And then June, 2021, the vaccine had just come out. So I was like
Speaker 12:  going out all the time, like the world was just like in a fun hobby place.
Speaker 12:  It was summer and I was just doing so many things and I kept posting on
Speaker 12:  TikTok and I started like blowing up a little bit and then I hit like
Speaker 12:  10,000 followers in July of 2021 and
Speaker 12:  now like a year and some change later at Math 330,000
Speaker 3:  When he became eligible for the creator fund, Brandon wanted to see how much
Speaker 3:  he could make, but he says he was a little skeptical because a lot of people
Speaker 3:  he knew reported a drop in views after they joined the creator
Speaker 3:  fund. TikTok denies this happens, but it is something lots of
Speaker 3:  TikTok creators have complained about, but Brandon himself saw no
Speaker 3:  dip in his numbers after joining
Speaker 12:  July and August of 2021, like all my videos were getting like between
Speaker 12:  80 to like 350,000 views. I was making like
Speaker 12:  probably four to $500 a month off the creator fund. So for me that was
Speaker 12:  great, was paying my utilities every month. How
Speaker 3:  Does it work like exactly? Do you, do you know how many views you
Speaker 12:  Need? This is like another thing that's never explicitly confirmed.
Speaker 12:  I think a ratio that's not obviously perfect, but I think it's
Speaker 12:  pretty on the money is you get like 4 cents
Speaker 12:  per a thousand views, but that is your views
Speaker 12:  for the whole day. I have 800 videos on my channel. So
Speaker 12:  like if you post a video today that goes viral and a bunch of people start
Speaker 12:  clicking your profile and they watch other ones, that all counts. If I post
Speaker 12:  a video today and it gets a million views, I'll probably
Speaker 12:  get $20 for that day.
Speaker 3:  See, TikTok hasn't laid out a formula for exactly what it takes to
Speaker 3:  earn money. They don't say, if you get a million views a day, you'll get
Speaker 3:  $20 instead, creators are left doing their own math and
Speaker 3:  some have taken a TikTok to share their earnings.
Speaker 13:  So I joined the TikTok creator Fund on January 28th of this year,
Speaker 13:  and in that time I've only made $17. Not
Speaker 13:  that good at all.
Speaker 14:  I was getting 20, $30 a day. You
Speaker 15:  Can see that I'm making a few dollars each
Speaker 16:  Day. I get paid anywhere from 30 to
Speaker 16:  150 bucks.
Speaker 3:  The numbers are all over the place and so are people's feelings about it.
Speaker 3:  Some people said it felt felt like free money for doing nothing. Others
Speaker 3:  thought they should be earning a lot more considering how much energy they
Speaker 3:  put into producing content. I asked Brandon if he wishes TikTok were
Speaker 3:  more transparent about how to make money from the fund.
Speaker 12:  I do. Yeah. Like I wish it was like a system, but like also I don't really
Speaker 12:  like know how helpful that would be because TikTok is random. When
Speaker 12:  you go on TikTok on every page you have a following and then a for
Speaker 12:  you, TikTok puts your for you page first. So you could follow somebody
Speaker 12:  and never see their videos. They might never come up on your for you page.
Speaker 12:  So even if they said like, oh, if you get 30,000 views a day,
Speaker 12:  you're gonna get $5. I can do my best to make a video that I
Speaker 12:  think we'll get 30,000 views, but it could get 3 million. It could get
Speaker 12:  three. You never know. Like there are videos that sometimes that I post
Speaker 12:  and like, this is so funny, my followers are gonna love this, and they flop.
Speaker 12:  And then there's other videos that like, like the other day I took a five
Speaker 12:  second video of me eating Chick-fil-A in a parking lot with my friend. I
Speaker 12:  was like, oh, if you have a mental breakdown today, eat Chick-fil-A in the
Speaker 12:  parking lot with your friend. I'm like, oh, this is gonna get like 15,000
Speaker 12:  views, 890,000 views. You never know.
Speaker 12:  So would it be helpful, would it be nice if they were transparent?
Speaker 12:  Yes. But I don't really know how that
Speaker 12:  would like help motivate people as a creator because I mean, at the end
Speaker 12:  of the day, it's very random.
Speaker 3:  Brandon's right? He can't really control what the algorithm is gonna do.
Speaker 3:  Despite some creator's best efforts to game the algorithms, they're dealing
Speaker 3:  with two secret black boxes controlled by the platform here. One,
Speaker 3:  how the algorithm works to make their content go viral or not. And two,
Speaker 3:  how the creator fund is calculating payments. They don't know either of these
Speaker 3:  things, and that's a precarious dynamic for content creators who wanna make
Speaker 3:  money.
Speaker 10:  TikTok is almost a hundred percent
Speaker 10:  recommendation. If the recommendation algorithm on
Speaker 10:  TikTok pushes out your content, you make more money.
Speaker 10:  If it does not push out your content, you do not make money. And
Speaker 10:  that is nothing that you have control. Over.
Speaker 3:  The hundreds of videos that Brandon has posted since July, 2021 when he
Speaker 3:  joined the Creator fund has netted him a bit over
Speaker 3:  $8,000. Not enough to live on, but luckily the creator fund is
Speaker 3:  in all Brandon's got, it's just one small revenue stream behind the other
Speaker 3:  ways. He's figured out how to make money on TikTok and Instagram. This past
Speaker 3:  July, Brandon realized he could earn enough as a creator to go at it
Speaker 3:  full-time, mainly through brand deals and ads. So he quit his nine to
Speaker 3:  five job.
Speaker 12:  I think people get confused when they're like, oh, like your full-time job
Speaker 12:  is TikTok. My yearly salary is not $8,000.
Speaker 12:  Like that is passive income. It's literally a third source
Speaker 12:  of income that I can like rely on like just for like, like I said, utilities.
Speaker 12:  It pays my electricity, my water bill, that's it. I've signed brand
Speaker 12:  deals with ad agencies that are $10,000 for one video.
Speaker 12:  So in that sense, it doesn't pay you shit.
Speaker 3:  It sounds like the Creator Fund is not the thing that made you quit your
Speaker 3:  day job.
Speaker 12:  No, definitely not. No. I don't think anyone could solely
Speaker 12:  live off the creator fund except for maybe like
Speaker 12:  celebrities.
Speaker 3:  I talked to Hank Green about what it is that TikTok does give
Speaker 3:  creators.
Speaker 8:  It is very good at giving videos a chance. And so
Speaker 8:  you might end up with a video, an account that has zero followers
Speaker 8:  and has uploaded 20 videos and like their 20th video
Speaker 8:  is actually really good, or it's like something exceptionally funny happened
Speaker 8:  and then that video gets 10 million views.
Speaker 3:  So TikTok is not giving a ton of money, but it does give sort of
Speaker 3:  virality
Speaker 8:  Attention and especially early in a creator's career, that's
Speaker 8:  the most valuable thing. And then you have to figure out how to turn that
Speaker 8:  attention into something that's gonna be sort of a more long-lived fuel in
Speaker 8:  the tank.
Speaker 3:  And Brandon's an example of somebody who's been able to do just that, turn
Speaker 3:  his virality on TikTok into a career.
Speaker 12:  I mean, it definitely is a hustle, but I've, I've never been more busy.
Speaker 12:  I've never worked harder, but I've also never been so successful.
Speaker 12:  So it's, it's all it's you take the good with the
Speaker 3:  Bad's. Creator fund is just one model. When Snap got into the paying
Speaker 3:  creator's game, they handed out big, big checks. We'll have
Speaker 3:  that after the break.
Speaker 3:  Snaps foray into paying their creators for short form. Videos went a
Speaker 3:  different direction than TikTok Snaps program was a lesson in how to
Speaker 3:  make creators rich, drive growth and help bump your stock price
Speaker 3:  at least temporarily.
Speaker 3:  I talked with Mike Metzler, a social and streaming analytics researcher
Speaker 3:  whose side hustle is making Corgi content.
Speaker 3:  Okay, it's not all Corgi content, but that's how we first got going on Snapchat
Speaker 3:  back in 2014.
Speaker 17:  I started on Snapchat because I knew that there was probably money to be
Speaker 17:  made and I've always approached a lot of these
Speaker 17:  platforms with, you know, is this a way to make money in my free time?
Speaker 17:  And it's more possible than ever to do that.
Speaker 3:  Mike made some money early on with Snap through brand partnerships, but he
Speaker 3:  said that had dried up for him when Snap announced Spotlight in November,
Speaker 3:  2020. Spotlight is a feature that looks a lot like TikTok or Instagram reels.
Speaker 3:  Instead of seeing snaps from your friends, there's a general entertainment
Speaker 3:  feed of Snaps selected content and anybody can submit their
Speaker 3:  stories to be featured there. Those who got picked were
Speaker 3:  initially capable of getting a piece of the 1 million
Speaker 3:  per day that Snap was offering to creators back then.
Speaker 17:  So I started posting on Snapchat Spotlight the day it came out. Yeah,
Speaker 17:  I posted for about a month and then I got a notification
Speaker 17:  that was like, Hey, you've made some money, but it didn't tell you how much
Speaker 17:  it was. I got a notification, you know, two or three weeks
Speaker 17:  later that I was getting $25,000. Whoa.
Speaker 17:  And then I posted some more and I got another notification that was like,
Speaker 17:  all right, now you've made $37,000.
Speaker 3:  Do you remember what your video was about? That was the most profitable there.
Speaker 17:  I was trying to make a, here's how to open a
Speaker 17:  pomegranate. And I opened it up and it was
Speaker 17:  completely rotted on the inside. So it was kind of one of those videos
Speaker 17:  where, you know, you, you get hooked in something different happens than
Speaker 17:  what you're expecting. And so it was, it was honestly a good internet type
Speaker 17:  video.
Speaker 3:  Mike wasn't the only one making life changing amounts of cash from Spotlight.
Speaker 3:  There were people, many of them teenagers making over a million dollars
Speaker 3:  in a matter of months. But like's Creator Fund,
Speaker 3:  nobody knew exactly what it took to get featured and paid out on Spotlight.
Speaker 3:  So creators banded together to try and figure it out.
Speaker 17:  I've been in a lot of different creator communities, so we started talking
Speaker 17:  immediately and trying to figure out what's the minimum threshold for what
Speaker 17:  it's gonna take to get a payout. And for Snapchat Spotlight, it was kind
Speaker 17:  of arbitrary. Whenever it started you could probably qualify with like a
Speaker 17:  50,000 views on a video, and now it's between 300 and
Speaker 17:  400,000 to get like a $300 payout.
Speaker 3:  Part of why it got harder to earn money was added competition
Speaker 17:  As soon as the word was out that people were making literally
Speaker 17:  millions of dollars. It became extremely competitive and the,
Speaker 17:  the landscape changed almost overnight.
Speaker 3:  And that's one of the biggest critiques of creator funds. Hank Green points
Speaker 3:  out that when you have a fixed amount of money set aside and more and more
Speaker 3:  people qualify to join, that money is gonna spread around much more
Speaker 3:  and the payouts to an individual creator are going to go down.
Speaker 8:  It's just a, it's a pretty simple math problem. You're dividing the same
Speaker 8:  number by a bigger number in general. As a platform succeeds more,
Speaker 8:  the creators actually make less. And that seems quite wrong
Speaker 3:  For Snap. It wasn't just the added competition of more creators on the platform,
Speaker 3:  it also stopped pouring so much cash into its fund. In
Speaker 3:  2021, the company announced they were shrinking the pot of money from
Speaker 3:  1 million per day to an unspecified millions
Speaker 3:  per month. And then just in October, they announced another reduction
Speaker 3:  to millions per year. Mike said, for all these reasons, he stopped
Speaker 3:  seeing any traction on Spotlight and started focusing on other platforms.
Speaker 17:  I kind of moved towards Facebook reels and Instagram reels, which was
Speaker 17:  more profitable use of my time.
Speaker 3:  Okay, so you moved that way cuz it seemed like that's where the money was
Speaker 3:  going.
Speaker 17:  There was still money to be made on, on Spotlight, but I wasn't willing
Speaker 17:  to put into the effort that it was gonna take for me to do that.
Speaker 17:  Facebook and Instagram reels, I wasn't making nearly as much money
Speaker 17:  as I was making on, on Snapchat Spotlight, but it was easier. And you know,
Speaker 17:  I'm cool with an extra 400, 500 bucks a month, you know, just posting
Speaker 17:  videos on, on social, it's, it's almost passive income. And I think that
Speaker 17:  creators are getting a lot more savvy. You see
Speaker 17:  creators jumping in between these platforms for where they can make
Speaker 17:  the most money, where the best opportunity is. There's obviously a lot of
Speaker 17:  downsides such as, you know, big inconsistencies and the platforms being
Speaker 17:  able to, to change, you know, the rules at any given time,
Speaker 17:  right? For Facebook reels, for example, in August of
Speaker 17:  this year, they were paying two bucks for a thousand views and then they
Speaker 17:  dropped it by more than half, then it was 40 cents for a thousand views,
Speaker 17:  and that just happened overnight. And then you're like, oh, well it suddenly
Speaker 17:  just got much harder.
Speaker 3:  Platforms can use these funds to play Puppet master a little bit by dangling
Speaker 3:  cash. They incentivize people to make a certain type of content on their
Speaker 3:  app in the hopes of keeping the platform competitive. And you see this happen
Speaker 3:  again and again. Meta has been pushing reels on Instagram and Facebook,
Speaker 3:  not just by putting them in users feeds, but also by paying creators to make
Speaker 3:  them.
Speaker 8:  So if you're Instagram, you want people to create reels, you create a fund
Speaker 8:  and you say you can make money if you create reels. I did make a bunch of
Speaker 8:  money, especially during the early stages when they're paying a lot, and
Speaker 8:  then they sort of like cranked it down as they're like, okay, people are
Speaker 8:  coming in. I, I despise that. That's like the ultimate,
Speaker 8:  not treating creators as partners, but instead treating them as like
Speaker 8:  an asset to be manipulated. Like, how do we get this
Speaker 8:  tree to grow in this place so that we can harvest it at the right time?
Speaker 8:  That's what it feels like. No one had a thought about like the, the soul
Speaker 8:  of the tree. They were just trying to get it to like, I feel like a crop
Speaker 8:  that is being fertilized rather than, I don't know, a person with a
Speaker 8:  business, like working with another business, trying to mutually grow
Speaker 8:  our businesses.
Speaker 3:  It may be tough for creators to keep up with the platforms, constant changes,
Speaker 3:  but for platforms, throwing money at the type of content they want can definitely
Speaker 3:  pan out.
Speaker 17:  In, in Snapchat's case, it worked after they really
Speaker 17:  spotlight, everybody flooded to the app, they had record user growth, their
Speaker 17:  stock price hit some new highs. Now everything is going down. And
Speaker 17:  now they announced yesterday that they're, they're cutting that. So it's
Speaker 17:  not working. But for some of these other platforms,
Speaker 17:  it it is retaining users to keep them posting content on
Speaker 17:  there. And maybe that's all you can really hope for is we, we need
Speaker 17:  our best creators to continue to post content if we want people to stay
Speaker 17:  on this app,
Speaker 3:  These funds and these bonuses and stuff, do they drive you to wanna make
Speaker 3:  more videos?
Speaker 17:  Absolutely. It creates, you know, a lot of opportunity for
Speaker 17:  creators, but you really have to put in that grind, which is,
Speaker 17:  for me, I have a full-time job, you know, it's a fun
Speaker 17:  hobby. Or if my full-time income was related to these creator funds, I,
Speaker 17:  I would be stressed all the time.
Speaker 3:  Just two years after the Creator fund trend began, it's showing signs of
Speaker 3:  decline. In addition to Snap announcing a decrease in funding, YouTube
Speaker 3:  said that it's shifting its shorts towards a revenue sharing model, and Meta
Speaker 3:  has introduced a new music revenue sharing model for reals. Revenue sharing
Speaker 3:  might mean less random easy money for those creators who've cashed out on
Speaker 3:  that, but it also means creators could grow more as the platform grows.
Speaker 3:  It's a really different model than creator funds where more growth on the
Speaker 3:  platform can lead to diminishing returns. For creators,
Speaker 8:  It's a gift instead of a partnership with YouTube, our
Speaker 8:  content is the thing you sell the ad-on, like, without my video, you
Speaker 8:  didn't sell that ad. That's the fundamental nature of it. So let's share
Speaker 8:  that revenue. Whereas with TikTok, it's like you created TikTok
Speaker 8:  videos, here's a present from us, it's a hundred bucks. Like
Speaker 8:  it's not shared revenue. It's an amount of money they've allocated to
Speaker 8:  creators.
Speaker 3:  Hank says the platforms are having to navigate the balance between providing
Speaker 3:  a great user experience versus a profitable experience for creators.
Speaker 8:  TikTok really is a very user first experience where it's,
Speaker 8:  it's designed to be the best experience for the person viewing the content
Speaker 8:  and to, to really lower the friction for the people creating the content,
Speaker 8:  like to allow creation to be very easy, but not to be certainly
Speaker 8:  isn't the best experience as a creator. You know, it's, it's very uncertain.
Speaker 8:  People get their accounts banned all the time. You don't make very much money.
Speaker 8:  And YouTube was kind of like this for a while too. It was really user
Speaker 8:  experience focused, and then there were more and more and more
Speaker 8:  ads and that value to the YouTube and the value to YouTube creators got
Speaker 8:  higher and higher, but the value to the user got lower. And somebody who
Speaker 8:  comes in and takes that space, that makes sense to me. And then like TikTok
Speaker 8:  is gonna have to sort of like, make the user experience worse and worse in
Speaker 8:  order to make more and more money because that's your, that's what you're
Speaker 8:  trying to do. And then maybe something else takes that space, or
Speaker 8:  maybe YouTube takes it in the chin and, and meta takes it
Speaker 8:  in the chin to make a product that's gonna cost them a lot of money and not
Speaker 8:  make 'em very much so that they can compete instead of becoming Blockbuster.
Speaker 8:  It's a tricky little world, but ultimately
Speaker 8:  these platforms are optimizing for user
Speaker 8:  experience, which is meaning not optimizing for
Speaker 8:  revenue. You know, and, and I want them to optimize for user experience.
Speaker 8:  I want them to compete. I want them to get eyeballs on my videos, but that
Speaker 8:  really does mean that I'm making like not very much money per view and I
Speaker 8:  ha we like creators have to be really innovative to figure out how to make
Speaker 8:  that money back. Which honestly over the last 10 years, they've been pretty
Speaker 8:  innovative.
Speaker 3:  TikTok for one hasn't yet announced any move away from its creator fund,
Speaker 3:  but it's just a matter of time before the platform will have to figure out
Speaker 3:  better tools to pay creators to keep churning content. After all
Speaker 3:  viral hits don't last and TikTok can only be the hot new thing for
Speaker 3:  so long.
Speaker 3:  This episode was produced by me, Hadley Robinson with Mixing by Andrew
Speaker 3:  Marino. Liam James is our lead producer and Brooke Min is our editorial
Speaker 3:  director. The Vergecast is a Verge production and part of the Vox Media podcast
Speaker 3:  network