# Transcript
ID: 6092f660-4f77-11ed-bedb-2f3f7d86964a
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Kanye wants Parler, smartwatch showdown, and the Vergecast Hotline returns
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-7891340947700814634/-4581841500825424367/s93290-US-4991s-1666160863.mp3
Description: Today on the flagship podcast of slightly inaccurate fitness trackers:
02:15 - David Pierce and Makena Kelly chat about Ye buying Parler, as well as the other new set of apps and app owners entering the space.
Kanye West is buying ‘free speech platform’ Parler
The ugly business logic behind Kanye West’s Parler acquisition
24:44 - Victoria Song and Dan Seifert return to the show for a smartwatch showdown between the Pixel Watch, the Apple Watch Series 8, and the Samsung Galaxy Watch.
Google Pixel Watch review: it’s a smarter Fitbit
Apple Watch Series 7 review: time and time again
Samsung Galaxy Watch 5 review: if it only had a better battery
We could all use a ‘This is Fine’ Focus mode
1:02:07 - Lastly, we return to the Vergecast Hotline to answer your burning tech questions.
Fitbit Sense 2 review: it doesn’t make much sense
1:14:55 - We explain why we still don't have chapters on The Vergecast
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we'd love to hear from you.
We are conducting a short audience survey to help plan for our future and hear from you. To participate, head to vox.com/podsurvey, and thank you!
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (5 ads detected)
Speaker 2:  Welcome to the Verge Cast, the flagship podcast of slightly inaccurate fitness
Speaker 2:  trackers. I'm your friend David Pierce and lemme just tell you about the
Speaker 2:  day I'm having. So on Sunday night we get home from being away for the weekend
Speaker 2:  and we go to bed and then at about 11 or so we get a knock on the door
Speaker 2:  from a police officer. Turns out a tree fell on our car. Now
Speaker 2:  it's three days later, there's still a tree on our car. The road's still
Speaker 2:  closed and I'm standing here staring at it, wondering if I could just pick
Speaker 2:  it up and lift it off my car myself. I'm not supposed to cuz it's
Speaker 2:  technically hung up on a power line but I feel like I could do it, you know.
Speaker 2:  Anyway, enough about me. We have a great show coming up today. McKenna Kelly
Speaker 2:  is gonna come on and explain why. Yay. Formerly known as Kanye West
Speaker 2:  might be buying Parlor. And we're gonna check in on all of
Speaker 2:  the other conservative leaning social apps like Truth, Social and Gutter
Speaker 2:  and Rumble and try to figure out what's going on with them. Then later Dan
Speaker 2:  Seaford and Victoria Song are gonna help me figure out whether the Pixel
Speaker 2:  Watch, Apple Watch or Galaxy Watch is truly the best smart watch out there.
Speaker 2:  And then we've got some great questions on the Verge Cast hotline, so we're
Speaker 2:  gonna answer as many of those as we can as well. All that is coming up. But
Speaker 2:  first I'm gonna go try and lift this tree. Wish me luck and pray that I
Speaker 2:  don't throw out my back or electrocute myself to death. This is the Verge
Speaker 2:  cast. We'll see you in a sec.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. So Monday morning this week brought what I would
Speaker 2:  argue is the single most 2022 news story of
Speaker 2:  all time, maybe even possible. Kanye West, now known as Yay,
Speaker 2:  is apparently buying Parlor, the conservative leaning social media
Speaker 2:  network. So we have yay owning Parlor, Elon Musk owning Twitter, Donald
Speaker 2:  Trump owning Truth Social. There's this whole new set of apps
Speaker 2:  and app owners entering the social space and it feels like it's all getting
Speaker 2:  very weird in real time. Parlor's pitch basically is that it is
Speaker 2:  un cancellable and a fight against censorship. That's also the pitch you'll
Speaker 2:  hear from Truth, Social and Rumble and even the way that Musk
Speaker 2:  increasingly describes Twitter. But as that pitch actually
Speaker 2:  working, it doesn't feel to me like any of these apps
Speaker 2:  obviously except for Twitter have really hit mainstream.
Speaker 2:  But are they headed that way? McKenna Kelly has been tracking the progress
Speaker 2:  of these sites and apps as they try to take on the Twitters and Facebooks
Speaker 2:  and ticks of the world. So let's try to see where they
Speaker 2:  are. Hi McKenna.
Speaker 4:  Hi. It's good to be here.
Speaker 2:  Let's start by talking about Parlor. There's a bunch of like different apps
Speaker 2:  and services I wanna talk about but parlors in the news cuz it's maybe
Speaker 2:  possibly, I would argue probably not gonna be owned by Yay formerly
Speaker 2:  Kanye West at some point. But in reading about this, parlor's been through
Speaker 2:  sort of a weird year. I feel like everybody knows it as like the conservative
Speaker 2:  leaning social media app, but it seems like from your reporting
Speaker 2:  that that's not really what it wants to be anymore.
Speaker 4:  Right. Yesterday I ended up talking to a bunch of sources who told
Speaker 4:  me that Parlor has been trying now Parliament Technologies, they
Speaker 4:  rebranded about a month ago after they acquired at something
Speaker 4:  called Dyna Scale and was were pivoting towards more cloud
Speaker 4:  services, internet infrastructure business rather than social media. But
Speaker 4:  over the last couple of weeks they've been trying to offload Parlor,
Speaker 4:  It is a failing social media network. No one really uses it
Speaker 4:  anymore and they see more of a business need and a market
Speaker 4:  need with un Cancellable cloud services
Speaker 4:  for other online businesses.
Speaker 2:  So, and this has been a thing for a while, right? Because like I think back
Speaker 2:  to even the, there was like the controversy about like the the Chans and
Speaker 2:  like the Daily Storm and this question of like who actually is in charge
Speaker 2:  of moderating this stuff and what should be allowed on you know,
Speaker 2:  AWS versus what should cloud for allow? And we had these like big long conversations
Speaker 2:  and it seems like it doesn't strike me as a totally crazy idea to be the
Speaker 2:  company that will like host and prop up and support these other companies
Speaker 2:  and that like this is the kind of thing that this universe of
Speaker 2:  social apps really needs. Like as business pivots go, this one actually makes
Speaker 2:  a lot of sense to me
Speaker 4:  And it's been happening for a while. So I would take a look at Parlor did
Speaker 4:  this, you know, made this pivot last month but there's also companies like
Speaker 4:  Right Forge that have sprung up to fill this need. And then also Rumble as
Speaker 4:  well has been working on cloud services and even like payment processing
Speaker 4:  and things like that. So even before, you know, this turn
Speaker 4:  this year with Parlor people had been seeing that maybe the social
Speaker 4:  media market for alternative apps is a little saturated.
Speaker 4:  There's too many people we can't compete. So now there's this other
Speaker 4:  adjacent market opening up with cloud services.
Speaker 2:  That's interesting and well I want to come back to that cause I think the,
Speaker 2:  the sort of broader market here is really interesting but in parlor's case,
Speaker 2:  the like joke going around was right that it's like Eon Musk and Twitter
Speaker 2:  and yay and Parlor. But the difference is that yay probably paid
Speaker 2:  like $45 for Parlor because by all
Speaker 2:  accounts it like this thing has not succeeded, right? Like is is this app
Speaker 2:  working in any way?
Speaker 4:  One of the prospective buyers that I spoke to yesterday told me when
Speaker 4:  they were looking at the records and the numbers for Parlor, they had about
Speaker 4:  50,000 daily active users, which is
Speaker 4:  extremely anemic compared to I think Twitter's last quarterly
Speaker 4:  earnings report said it was about like they had about 230 million so compared
Speaker 4:  230 million to 50,000 daily active
Speaker 2:  Users and Twitter is one that is like not a smashing success story. So
Speaker 2:  it's like that's, that's bleak. Okay, why isn't it working? Like what, what
Speaker 2:  is the problem with Parlor?
Speaker 4:  The problem with Parlor I think is a little bit twofold. The platform launched
Speaker 4:  in 2018 as one of the original censorship
Speaker 4:  free, free speech platforms to come out of the Trump administration
Speaker 4:  in this Donald Trump first big tech culture war that brewed
Speaker 4:  during, you know, his presidency, they were fine but it also led
Speaker 4:  to other groups announcing other competing services. You have Gap
Speaker 4:  Getter Rumble, all of these places, alternative ways for them to,
Speaker 4:  you know, find I guess the same service, right? But when it
Speaker 4:  comes to Parlor, Parlor was one of the platforms that was
Speaker 4:  effectively de platform last year entirely after the
Speaker 4:  January 6th riot. So Apple took it down, Google Play Store took it
Speaker 4:  down, AWS took down its website and it wasn't until
Speaker 4:  May that parlor was then reinstated on the app store. And it wasn't even
Speaker 4:  until September, like a few weeks ago that Parlor got back on the
Speaker 4:  Google Play store. Oh wow. Which of course has tremendously more users
Speaker 4:  globally than Apple's App Store, right? So this company
Speaker 4:  really suffered from being de platformed and at the same time when I say
Speaker 4:  this is a twofold thing, the second part is, oh my gosh, all of a sudden
Speaker 4:  there's truth social coming up this year there's more, you know,
Speaker 4:  bigger name competitors in this space than Parlor and Parlor just
Speaker 4:  completely missed out on that wave.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. So it, it seems to me, and you pay a lot more attention to this space
Speaker 2:  than I do, I, I feel like I, I sort of like where I am with these apps which
Speaker 2:  is like blatantly aware that they exist but I don't spend a lot of time on
Speaker 2:  them. But it seems like the one that has like crept into not
Speaker 2:  quite mainstreamness but something much bigger than just like a handful
Speaker 2:  of angry band Twitter users is Rumble like Rumble which
Speaker 2:  is basically like a, a YouTube competitor in sort of this same like free
Speaker 2:  speech un cancellable vein you're talking about. It's the one that seems
Speaker 2:  to be working the best. Is that fair? Is that your experience to
Speaker 4:  I think Rumble is the one to make the easiest case about, for example,
Speaker 4:  like earlier was it just a couple weeks ago Rumble went public like they
Speaker 4:  iPod which is crazy cuz none of these other platforms have
Speaker 4:  done that. When we talk about Rumble, why I think it's probably
Speaker 4:  the most successful and I think Getter arguably is also like the
Speaker 4:  second most successful compared to Rumble. You gotta look at, you know, how
Speaker 4:  they're trying to monetize the service and how they're getting
Speaker 4:  people on. Of course with Rumble you have folks like Russell
Speaker 4:  brand big names that they're getting on to sign exclusive deals for
Speaker 4:  shows that you know, people in this area of the internet,
Speaker 4:  this ecosystem, the internet really admire and listen to, right? I think
Speaker 4:  Russell Brand used to have a YouTube show, I think he might have been de
Speaker 4:  Platform, not entirely sure there And then also with Gutter, Gutter has also
Speaker 4:  been good about getting influencers on the platform and
Speaker 4:  incentivizing them to use it. Gutter as well has a video component Now over
Speaker 4:  the summer it launched its vision service which is technically
Speaker 4:  TikTok but for conservatives I haven't spent too much time
Speaker 4:  with that but they're growing in different ways like that. But you look at
Speaker 4:  Parlor, Parlor just really didn't, I guess give
Speaker 4:  like the right I know deals to get people on the platform. You look at the,
Speaker 4:  some of the exclusives that it has and it's Benny Johnson a contributor to
Speaker 4:  Turning Point USA has like a show called the Left Camp Meme and
Speaker 4:  arguably it's one of the most cringe things I've ever watched in my entire
Speaker 4:  life. And I think the audience for it doesn't really even
Speaker 4:  exist and they're probably over the age of 60 and they aren't even on Parlor.
Speaker 4:  So that's kinda where we are with that. And the other thing is, I, I just
Speaker 4:  wanna go and talk about Truth. Truth has one big user and that's
Speaker 4:  Donald Trump, right? So a lot of these come down to exclusivity with
Speaker 4:  content and who's really winning and attracting the most
Speaker 4:  influential people onto the platforms.
Speaker 2:  Interesting. Cause the next thing I was gonna ask you is like do you think
Speaker 2:  this idea of conservative focused social media
Speaker 2:  is even a thing we're, we're like several years into this
Speaker 2:  pitch for a lot of these companies now, but it almost sounds like what you're
Speaker 2:  saying, like I feel like what you just described is not social networks but
Speaker 2:  like streaming services and we're now in like a Spotify versus
Speaker 2:  Apple Music War, but for like
Speaker 2:  conservative radio hosts as opposed to like there maybe they
Speaker 2:  don't need to try and get Twitter's scale, they're just trying to be like
Speaker 2:  entertainment platforms like Fox News but on the internet, right? Like is
Speaker 2:  that where all this is going?
Speaker 4:  I think it's important to note that a lot of the platforms,
Speaker 4:  these alt ones that are, I guess you can say succeeding
Speaker 4:  in air quotes have a wider user base than
Speaker 4:  just conservatives. So look at Rumble.
Speaker 4:  Rumble recently struck a deal with Andrew Tate, Andrew Tate being
Speaker 4:  that guy who's like a Mane, very sexist,
Speaker 4:  misogynistic content creator who was kicked off of TikTok Instagram, et
Speaker 4:  cetera and found a home on Rumble. Now that is an
Speaker 4:  inherently, you know, conservative political content more as it is like
Speaker 4:  this misogynistic lifestyle content, right? So
Speaker 4:  that's finding a home on Rumble. You look at Gutter, Gutter also has a
Speaker 4:  huge base in Brazil in the uk.
Speaker 4:  They're actively onboarding users in countries all across the
Speaker 4:  world and not just focusing on the US and US users. And I think that's
Speaker 4:  part of the reason why they've been successful. They're kind of growing the
Speaker 4:  space past politics and of course it's taking them a little bit longer
Speaker 4:  to grow maybe and really see the headlines that we see with like
Speaker 4:  Parlor being D platform, all this crazy stuff during the Trump administration.
Speaker 4:  But I do think they are, you know, in the middle of a slow leak
Speaker 4:  globally.
Speaker 2:  Okay, well what's interesting about that though is like Andrew Tate's actually
Speaker 2:  really interesting example, right? Cause it's like guy with a big audience
Speaker 2:  these other platforms decided they didn't want on their platform
Speaker 2:  anymore. And so if I'm one of these networks like it, it
Speaker 2:  makes absolute sense to me that somebody like Rumble right? Who who promotes
Speaker 2:  itself as like a against you know, censorship and cancellation
Speaker 2:  and pro-free speech. It's like that actually strikes me as like a match made
Speaker 2:  in heaven. But in reality there aren't actually that many of those people
Speaker 2:  and there are very few of those people who have like real big audiences.
Speaker 2:  So I guess part of what I'm trying to figure out is like does this idea scale
Speaker 2:  past that sort of small handful of people that everybody cares about, right?
Speaker 2:  Like obviously Trump is sort of the biggest example of like massively famous
Speaker 2:  person in a lot of people care very much about who was kicked off
Speaker 2:  of these other platforms. Like it makes sense that there is a set of people
Speaker 2:  who would go wherever he is. Same goes for Anate, same goes for like this
Speaker 2:  other handful of people but that only gets you so far, right?
Speaker 4:  I don't know, it only does get you so far. But the same time I look at the
Speaker 4:  Elon, I gotta think like Twitter isn't real life, right? This is the, this
Speaker 4:  is the cornerstone of this beat.
Speaker 4:  So you see how folks react to Elon, this is, he has so many
Speaker 4:  fanboy fan girls and that came across, you know, those grew out of
Speaker 4:  I guess just Elon being Elon. But in the early days this you know, kind
Speaker 4:  of progressive virtue of combating climate change with Tesla and all that
Speaker 4:  stuff, right? So he's finding himself in the same boat, maybe not
Speaker 4:  the same life boat off the Titanic but an adjacent one, a
Speaker 4:  separate one coming off of this like kind of cultural moment that we're in.
Speaker 4:  It's Elon Musk people, Kanye West now, you know buying Parlor.
Speaker 4:  This is a somebody who has been in culture for a very long time, one of the
Speaker 4:  most famous rappers, you know, married to Kim Kardashian at one point
Speaker 4:  in time, who is the biggest influencer social media user of all
Speaker 4:  time. I don't want to, I think it's very easy to say
Speaker 4:  as reporters as people in the media that these are
Speaker 4:  failing platforms like Parlor Gutter, et cetera. But at the same
Speaker 4:  time you look at the people who are hawking to this, who feel a
Speaker 4:  lack of control in their own personal narrative online, whether it be Kanye,
Speaker 4:  Elon, whoever who jumped to these things in order to claim
Speaker 4:  that narrative back. And I think now that this is a trend, right? With
Speaker 4:  Trump and truth social Elon Musk with Twitter and now
Speaker 4:  Kanye with Parlor, even though Parlor is anemic and awful and terrible, I
Speaker 4:  think it does set an example and even if we aren't in a place right now
Speaker 4:  where these companies are profitable and successes, I think this is giving
Speaker 4:  them all a sense of, I dunno, legitimacy over the past couple
Speaker 4:  weeks.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, no that makes total sense. And I guess, and this comes back to the
Speaker 2:  cloud services thing too. It's right, it seems like what is increasingly
Speaker 2:  happening is is we're just getting different sort of full stack
Speaker 2:  silos. But then that comes back to this idea that like the unifying
Speaker 2:  thing is these two app stores and it's Google and Apple have
Speaker 2:  just a gigantic amount of control and there's just nothing any of these apps,
Speaker 2:  no matter how you feel about it can do about that fact, right? And it's like
Speaker 2:  as we talk about even TikTok in China, like the companies that have the most
Speaker 2:  influence there, there are the ones who run the app stores because they ultimately
Speaker 2:  get to decide based on whatever they feel like whether these things live
Speaker 2:  or die. And we've seen the effect when they get kicked out what happens next.
Speaker 2:  But then there was this thing recently where like I think Truth Social just
Speaker 2:  recently got back into the Play store and there's been like you said all
Speaker 2:  these issues with Parlor over the course of this year. What's your sense
Speaker 2:  of where all of that is headed? Like can these, can these
Speaker 2:  platforms stay on the right side of the app stores? Do we want them to,
Speaker 2:  are they going to, what's your sense?
Speaker 4:  The way that I view this is mostly that the Trump fight with
Speaker 4:  big tech has created this small, albeit small
Speaker 4:  but mighty group of people Yeah. Who want nothing to do with
Speaker 4:  the mainstream platforms and albeit it's growing into the mainstream economy,
Speaker 4:  right? You see right-leaning folks launching
Speaker 4:  conservative anti woke credit
Speaker 4:  cards. Yeah. Banks now a lot of these things have failed but
Speaker 4:  I think back to, I think it was the Dan Bonino company a couple months ago
Speaker 4:  that tried to copyright the phrase quote parallel
Speaker 4:  economy. Hmm. So there's movement and there's definitely
Speaker 4:  money. I don't know how much money on the right to build
Speaker 4:  out an alternative economy to that with which
Speaker 4:  you know, most people engage in, whether it's Visa, MasterCard, we saw the
Speaker 4:  blow up with PayPal the other week about their misinformation policies
Speaker 4:  and things like that. That's just all getting blown over into this separate
Speaker 4:  bucket of these people who feel
Speaker 4:  disenfranchised by the mainstream media, mainstream economy, et
Speaker 4:  cetera. And so right now is it a competitor? I don't think
Speaker 4:  so. I don't think it's probably gonna make that much money but it's gaining
Speaker 4:  steam and the more that we see folks like yay, Kanye West
Speaker 4:  and all these big name people putting a lot more money, whether it's
Speaker 4:  money or just attention to this, I do think it does have the
Speaker 4:  possibility to grow, especially with the internet the way it is, right? Like
Speaker 4:  people who want this information, who want to know about Kanye West and want
Speaker 4:  to know about these things, they know where to find it. Yeah. And they know
Speaker 4:  that they can find other, you know, adjacent platforms to use
Speaker 4:  to find these things. I don't know, I just at this time it's like these platforms
Speaker 4:  have been around for not so long. Parlor was 2018 and a
Speaker 4:  lot of things cropped up in 20 20, 20 21. But there is a lot of money
Speaker 4:  behind it. Like there's a lot of investment firms and things like that.
Speaker 4:  The IPO that I can't like turn a blind eye, I think it's wrong to turn
Speaker 4:  a blind eye. I think that there is accountability necessary for these things,
Speaker 4:  but at the same time you don't wanna give them too much credence.
Speaker 2:  It's an interesting moment. I agree cuz it's like there is enough going on
Speaker 2:  in this space that it feels like something substantial is happening
Speaker 2:  there. But it's hard to figure out like if, if you asked me to like pick
Speaker 2:  a winner between you know, Gab Parlor and Truth Social
Speaker 2:  and then even like the the Mews of the world, I feel like anyone who would
Speaker 2:  guess the answer would be just lying. We're all just kind of making it
Speaker 2:  up and there's so much like sameness in all of these and what I think it's
Speaker 2:  gonna be fascinating, I was just looking at like Sensor Tower which tracks
Speaker 2:  a lot of the app downloads and Parlor had a big jump after
Speaker 2:  the, the yay thing was announced. Which on the one hand makes sense because
Speaker 2:  it's in the news, people are always gonna download stuff when it's in the
Speaker 2:  news. But also like you're right, he is this like massively
Speaker 2:  famous presence who probably will draw some number of people
Speaker 2:  to him wherever he goes. And that right now is the best thing
Speaker 2:  that these platforms have going for them. And if they're gonna get where
Speaker 2:  they want to go, like 230 million people aren't on Twitter just for
Speaker 2:  Elon Musk, right? Like some of them probably are but like you have to get
Speaker 2:  past that before you can really build something of huge
Speaker 2:  substance. And it's gonna be really interesting to see if anyone can get
Speaker 2:  there at that kind of scale. It's
Speaker 4:  Also important to note that I think Kanye had less than
Speaker 4:  a hundred followers on Parlor. He set up his account last week. Last time
Speaker 4:  I checked early this morning it was less than 16,000. That is
Speaker 4:  so small compared to I think it was like the 30 million he had on Twitter.
Speaker 4:  His reach is so small. And so when it comes like the motivation
Speaker 4:  behind the sale, albeit like who knows how
Speaker 4:  much they sold it to Kanye for or want to sell it to Kanye for or if they
Speaker 4:  even plan on sending it to Kanye cuz no nothing's been signed. Maybe this
Speaker 4:  is just a whole publicity stunt to raise the price of parlor
Speaker 4:  and get it off to someone else who can do it. I mean I was talking to prospective
Speaker 4:  buyers and they just called the number that Parliament was asking as like
Speaker 4:  absurd, it was just too high not even near the price that they would be willing
Speaker 4:  to pay for it, right? And so either Kanye got duped into
Speaker 4:  spending a lot of money for this or he got it for
Speaker 4:  like a $2 bill and a handshake, you know, to make it
Speaker 4:  like look good and hopefully and maybe later he dips out, who knows?
Speaker 2:  Do all these folks see the Elon owned Twitter as like an
Speaker 2:  existential threat to this entire thing? Because if he does some of the stuff
Speaker 2:  that he said he's gonna do reinstate Trump way, reduce the terms of
Speaker 2:  service, make the rules much more lax for people to post on there. That seems
Speaker 2:  like take the thing that those people like about the platforms they already
Speaker 2:  have add 230 million users and suddenly that's
Speaker 2:  gonna be the one that a lot of these folks would pick, right? Like is if
Speaker 2:  Elon does buy Twitter, do a lot of these things just sort of die on the vine
Speaker 2:  as a result?
Speaker 4:  Maybe. But you look at the news this morning that
Speaker 4:  Kanye intends to have dinner with Trump this week.
Speaker 4:  Kanye is going to make a truth social account and he's going to invite Trump
Speaker 4:  on parlor.
Speaker 2:  Okay
Speaker 4:  So what does this mean, right? So what does this mean? It's very clear and
Speaker 4:  I've been hearing this from sources in like the Republican you know
Speaker 4:  right wing online ecosystem for a while that they don't even care
Speaker 4:  about who ends up being the winner. They just want an opportunity
Speaker 4:  to show that they are a powerful force, right? They
Speaker 4:  want to be able to influence the mainstream media and whether that's, you
Speaker 4:  know, combining into one major platform. Sure, maybe, or maybe it's just
Speaker 4:  drawing the attention of all of these, you know, celebrities who do have
Speaker 4:  weight and who do have large audiences to show them that hey actually
Speaker 4:  mainstream culture isn't like Hollywood progressive, it's also us
Speaker 4:  right now. Whether or not you can always ask whether or not it's true. I
Speaker 4:  doubt it's true, it's a very false narrative but it seems like
Speaker 4:  that's kind of the more of the angle that they're pushing and they have so
Speaker 4:  much money. Look at the Republican investors, look at Rebecca Mercer,
Speaker 4:  all these folks, Peter Teal now they have so much money to throw at these
Speaker 4:  things and just a bid for cultural influence and cultural
Speaker 4:  relevancy. And I think that's the major narrative here.
Speaker 4:  You know, if you peel away all of like the little tit for tat company
Speaker 4:  versus company, it really comes down to hoping to influence
Speaker 4:  this like progressive leftist, whatever culture that they see as,
Speaker 4:  you know, encompassing the United States.
Speaker 2:  Totally. Yeah and it's, it's an interesting question whether what you need
Speaker 2:  is sort of one gigantic player or if you can do
Speaker 2:  it with kind of a lot of different slices of the pie. We've
Speaker 2:  never really seen that work in social like it's been very hard to be
Speaker 2:  a small social network over time. So it's, it's gonna be interesting to see
Speaker 2:  if anybody in that space can pull it off. What are you looking at towards
Speaker 2:  the midterms? We're, we're two weeks out from an election, this is all bubbling
Speaker 2:  kind of as political conversation is, is reaching this
Speaker 2:  like crazy fever pitch ahead of the midterms? What are you looking at and
Speaker 2:  looking for as you poke around all these platforms?
Speaker 4:  What I think is most important to bring in this discussion is the stakes.
Speaker 4:  Hmm. There are a lot of stakes here with whoever wins the senate, whoever
Speaker 4:  wins the house, you know, whoever has control of these things because if
Speaker 4:  you know Democrats are able to maintain their majorities
Speaker 4:  or Republicans end up taking the house, which is what it seems like
Speaker 4:  likely this is gonna have a lot of effects on the way that social media
Speaker 4:  is regulated or not regulated under the rest of the Biden
Speaker 4:  administration. So I can imagine, you know, if we
Speaker 4:  have Democrats somehow maintaining their majority
Speaker 4:  in the house, maintaining a majority in the Senate, they would probably pursue,
Speaker 4:  you know, a greater data privacy framework, maybe get that through. That
Speaker 4:  of course is a Biden administration priority. Hopefully they'd be able to
Speaker 4:  get Gigi so confirmed who is the
Speaker 4:  FCC nominee who
Speaker 2:  Has, I'm talking about that for decades it feels like.
Speaker 4:  I know cuz she was nominated almost two years ago and
Speaker 4:  has not gotten the state. So the FCC is like just total lame
Speaker 4:  duck. And now if the Republicans, you know are even able just to take
Speaker 4:  back the house, there's gonna be so many investigations into like the Hunter
Speaker 4:  Biden laptop. There's gonna be investigations
Speaker 4:  into perhaps like taking a more tougher look at TikTok
Speaker 4:  rather than US companies and just kind of putting thet US companies to the
Speaker 4:  side and targeting like TikTok and other foreign-based entities.
Speaker 4:  So there's a lot at stake about like the future over the next two years.
Speaker 4:  And I think it's very critical at a time when we've spent like the last five
Speaker 4:  years since 2016, frankly debating these issues
Speaker 4:  that they're finally yarning enough steam and with bills that are actually
Speaker 4:  moving places. Like a merger filing fee actually got passed like a couple
Speaker 4:  weeks ago. So big tech would have to like pay more of a fee in order to
Speaker 4:  acquire nascent competitors. Like that actually is change. So we're starting
Speaker 4:  to get this momentum and I think depending on who ha who's in charge,
Speaker 4:  somebody's gonna hit the brakes or someone's gonna hit the accelerator and
Speaker 4:  that's mainly what I'm looking
Speaker 2:  For. Fair enough. All right, well we're gonna have more chances over the
Speaker 2:  next few weeks to talk about all of that, but thank you and if you see anything
Speaker 2:  cool on Rumble, you know, let me know.
Speaker 4:  Always searching Rumble.
Speaker 2:  All right, thanks McKenna. All
Speaker 4:  Right, bye.
Speaker 2:  Okay, we need to take a break but then we are gonna come back and try to
Speaker 2:  sort through all of the smart watches that have been launched this year and
Speaker 2:  try to figure out once and for all which one's the best. We'll be right
Speaker 2:  back.
Speaker 4:  Welcome back. It's been a huge year for smart
Speaker 4:  watches. All the phone announcements we got this year were
Speaker 4:  relatively normal and like fine but not that interesting. But there
Speaker 4:  is so much interesting stuff happening in the smart watch world and
Speaker 4:  really there are three at the end of the day that matter the most. There's
Speaker 4:  the Apple Watch series eight, the Pixel Watch and the Galaxy Watch five.
Speaker 2:  Those are the flagship smart watches. The ones that most people are
Speaker 2:  probably choosing between to some extent. Which watch you use is governed
Speaker 2:  by which phone you have. But let's pretend just for the sake of this segment
Speaker 2:  that that's not the case. Which of these smart watches is actually
Speaker 2:  the best I brought in Dan Seifert and Victoria Song, who are the
Speaker 2:  two most smart watchy people I know to help me figure it
Speaker 2:  out.
Speaker 2:  Time to talk watches. Victoria. Hello?
Speaker 5:  Hello
Speaker 2:  Dan. Hello,
Speaker 6:  Hello.
Speaker 2:  We have reviewed many watches,
Speaker 5:  So many watches.
Speaker 2:  You both have all the watches, right? Do we all have all the watches,
Speaker 6:  More watches and wrists?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I don't know what the watch per wrist capita is at my house
Speaker 5:  but it's,
Speaker 2:  It's over one for sure.
Speaker 5:  It's like what? 400 to one or 400 to two? Cause I only have two wrists so
Speaker 5:  yeah,
Speaker 2:  So I didn't tell either of you this but we have a little game to play basically.
Speaker 2:  So I came up with a bunch of categories which I would say are the things
Speaker 2:  that make up a good smart watch and we're gonna go through each of them and
Speaker 2:  decide between the Pixel watch, the Galaxy Watch and the Apple Watch. And
Speaker 2:  if you have like a weird crazy wild card you wanna throw in, knock
Speaker 2:  yourself out and we're just, we're gonna try to lay out what is best at what
Speaker 2:  and then at the end if there is an obvious winner, great.
Speaker 2:  We don't all have to agree, we're just gonna talk about it and see where
Speaker 2:  we land. So first I'm gonna tell you the categories and you can tell me if
Speaker 2:  there's anything really obvious that I'm missing. Here are all the ones I
Speaker 2:  wrote down. You ready?
Speaker 5:  Ready.
Speaker 2:  I have best assistant best for computer things, which I have to be
Speaker 2:  like reminders and smart home and like doing all the little like one touch
Speaker 2:  stuff you wanna do on your phone. Battery life best looking plays
Speaker 2:  best with other devices and you can define that however you'd like to
Speaker 2:  best for regular fitness people, best for Super Fitness people
Speaker 2:  and best overall. Those are my categories. How do we feel?
Speaker 5:  Are we going into specific models within these categories
Speaker 5:  because the answers are different if I have to like consider the Ultra
Speaker 5:  versus the regular series eight versus the se. Same for
Speaker 5:  the Galaxy Watch five Pro versus the standard Galaxy Watch five. So
Speaker 5:  there's
Speaker 6:  Only one Pixel watch.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, there's only one Pixel watch
Speaker 2:  That's actually good. So we're gonna do, for the sake of this
Speaker 2:  discussion, the ones that are most comparable to the Pixel watch. So it's
Speaker 2:  probably the Apple Watch series eight and the regular Galaxy Watch and the
Speaker 2:  Pixel watch. Otherwise everything just gets too crazy and too complicated.
Speaker 2:  Someday we'll like do a Galaxy Watch Pro versus Apple Watch Ultra
Speaker 2:  from like the top of a mountain and it'll be amazing. But for now let's just,
Speaker 2:  yeah we'll do this sort of basic run of the mill. I assume all three of those
Speaker 2:  are gonna be the most popular in their line. So that feels like an okay one
Speaker 2:  for us to
Speaker 6:  Do. I got two proposed questions
Speaker 2:  Hit me
Speaker 6:  Comfort and like band compatibility
Speaker 6:  slash options.
Speaker 2:  Yes.
Speaker 5:  Okay. And then I guess the only category I would suggest is like
Speaker 5:  advanced health features cuz health and wellness tracking versus
Speaker 5:  fitness tracking, they are different things.
Speaker 2:  Ooh, okay, I'm good with that. Let's just dive into this in I would say relatively
Speaker 2:  no particular order best looking of
Speaker 2:  the three of them. I feel like this is, this is gonna be a tricky one
Speaker 5:  Pixel watch for me.
Speaker 6:  Yeah I'm gonna go with Pixel Watch as well even though I think it's too small.
Speaker 6:  Okay,
Speaker 2:  This is not a tricky one. I also agree. I think it's, they just like they
Speaker 2:  did the thing that's like what a watch is supposed to look like.
Speaker 6:  It looks very pretty like I think it's distinct enough that it doesn't look
Speaker 6:  like it's trying to ape an analog watch, which I think the Galaxy
Speaker 6:  watch suffers from a little bit like I don't think the Apple Watch is very
Speaker 6:  pretty at all. I think it's very functional and comfortable or whatever,
Speaker 6:  but the square shape is just, you know a lot of people complain about that.
Speaker 6:  So I think that the Pixel watch nails that and it is like a nice felt
Speaker 6:  size that tapers and the curves make it
Speaker 6:  hide whatever size it has really well. So I don't know, I
Speaker 6:  think I dig the look.
Speaker 5:  Yeah I would agree with that. And it looks modern, you know it's, it's sort
Speaker 5:  of, I don't know, Samsung's watches are really nice looking out of the box.
Speaker 5:  That's true. But it is not what I would call like
Speaker 5:  elegant. Yeah like you, you kind of need to dress it up a bit with
Speaker 5:  straps and it's the same thing for the Apple Watch just out of the box the
Speaker 5:  Apple watch is like hello tiny wrist calculator computer on your wrist. I
Speaker 5:  mean it's nice but you have to buy a really nice strap to kind of dress it
Speaker 5:  up. Whereas I actually think that the Pixel watch is
Speaker 5:  default band. It looks really pretty just it
Speaker 5:  does. And then if you've seen the mesh straps like the metal mesh straps,
Speaker 5:  it is gorgeous. I was, I was in the hands on like oh my god
Speaker 5:  I really want this. And then I saw the price and I was like no okay, it's
Speaker 2:  Fine. Yeah, I was gonna say it's really nice. It's stupid expensive but it's
Speaker 2:  really nice. Yeah. All right, well then I think, yeah I think we're all in
Speaker 2:  agreement. For me it's like it's just the right amount of watchy like you
Speaker 2:  said Dan, it's not trying to do some of the things that like the fossils
Speaker 2:  of the world have done where they try to like sneak technology into a regular
Speaker 2:  watch, like look like a smart watch. That's okay and the Pixel watch does
Speaker 2:  do that, but it also doesn't look like they shrunk
Speaker 2:  an iPhone and put a band on it and put it on your wrist, which is like the
Speaker 2:  Apple watch is a very nice device but it is, you would never mistake it for
Speaker 2:  anything other than what it is. And I feel like the Pixel Watch walks that
Speaker 2:  line very well. Okay, three points for the pixel watch big day. I don't know
Speaker 2:  if we're actually keeping score, but I'm just gonna write all these down.
Speaker 2:  See what happens related to that
Speaker 2:  is Best wearability. So this is the one, Dan, you just brought up this mix
Speaker 2:  of like comfort on your wrist and also the like band
Speaker 2:  and accessory ecosystem. All of the stuff you can put on when you put it
Speaker 2:  on
Speaker 5:  Apple Watch.
Speaker 6:  So I think for comfort they're all the same. They're all pretty
Speaker 6:  comfortable like and and I think what impacts the comfort most
Speaker 6:  is which strap you choose on it and out of the box if you were, we were just
Speaker 6:  go to like the default one you pick up off the shelf, they all come with
Speaker 6:  very similar rubbery sport straps that all
Speaker 6:  feel basically the same. So then it becomes like, well which
Speaker 6:  one can you customize the easiest? And that
Speaker 6:  I think the pixel watch is instantly disqualified because it has the fewest
Speaker 6:  number of strap options and they are using a proprietary mount
Speaker 6:  and it's brand new so there's no third party options or
Speaker 2:  Whatever so, and they're very expensive. Google for some reason made all
Speaker 2:  of these very expensive.
Speaker 6:  Yeah and like I like leather watch straps for my straps and the leather ones
Speaker 6:  are just really not that great. So pixel watch is disqualified,
Speaker 5:  The other ones aren't either. No, it's like I've got this, they sent me
Speaker 5:  the woven one and I really have to stress, so like
Speaker 5:  there's two kind of fabricy ones for the pixel watch and one is like the
Speaker 5:  stretchy one that they were like all gung ho about during the presentation
Speaker 5:  and then there's this woven one which they're like, oh yeah this woven one
Speaker 5:  is here too. And it is stiff. It is light is the stiff as a board
Speaker 5:  like exactly that it's, it's really weird feeling. I like it looks
Speaker 5:  fine but it feels odd. Yeah and like the way you
Speaker 5:  secure the bands onto your wrist itself, they're weird. It's got this button
Speaker 5:  and I don't like it.
Speaker 6:  So then you gotta like compare this, this Samsung and the Apple watch and
Speaker 6:  Samsung has an advantage that they use standard watch pin
Speaker 6:  size that's been around for ages. It's super easy to, you can walk into like
Speaker 6:  almost any watch store or on Amazon super easily find a a strap
Speaker 6:  design that you like that will fit this watch very easily. And then the Apple
Speaker 6:  watch because it's been a market leader for so long, basically has the same
Speaker 6:  scenario because so many third party options exist for it. You can buy I
Speaker 6:  one of Apple's watch straps which are really nice. I think they're really
Speaker 6:  all overpriced and you should just go find a third party option but you do
Speaker 6:  have like a wide variety of options there so it's a little bit
Speaker 6:  of a toss up between the two. I think that because the Samsung
Speaker 6:  is round and uses a standard watch strap, it's a little bit
Speaker 6:  easier to get that watch style look from it compared to
Speaker 6:  the Apple watch
Speaker 2:  The, Tell me why you shook your head when Dan was describing the standard
Speaker 2:  watch sizes cuz that's also I would give it to Samsung for the exact reason
Speaker 2:  he just described that it just works with watch bands, which seems
Speaker 2:  like insane that not others do this.
Speaker 5:  Yeah so I'm gonna go with the fact that it is much easier to slide on
Speaker 5:  an Apple watch strap third party or not because like I
Speaker 5:  really don't think it's hard to get a third party one that makes it look,
Speaker 5:  you know, you can dress it up. There's bracelet types, there's leather types,
Speaker 5:  there's metal types, they're out there. I can't tell you how many manicures
Speaker 5:  I've ruined just trying to change the pins and cuz you know
Speaker 5:  that's part of doing a smart watch review, just how easy is it to swap out
Speaker 5:  the pins and they're so small. I have broken so many nails
Speaker 5:  on it and I do my own manicures so it's just like
Speaker 5:  ah duh, I spend so much time on that. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  I agree that the Apple watch, if you are the type of person that's going
Speaker 6:  to switch their strap any more than once a month, the Apple watch is just
Speaker 6:  so much easier.
Speaker 5:  Yeah and if you're doing fitness stuff, right? I don't know if you've ever
Speaker 5:  seen Alex Krantz is most disgusting leather strap that she wore for a
Speaker 5:  very long time. If you do any sort of fitness and you don't have
Speaker 5:  a leather strap with a silicone underside, you have to switch that thing
Speaker 5:  out for like hygiene reasons.
Speaker 2:  Yeah it gets real nasty.
Speaker 5:  That picture haunts my dreams. It's so disgusting.
Speaker 5:  Anyway,
Speaker 2:  All right. Okay. You've talked me into it. Yeah I think if it was just band
Speaker 2:  ecosystem, I think it's Samsung by a mile even though it
Speaker 2:  is definitely true that there are like a million great Etsy stores that will
Speaker 2:  sell you very good Apple watch bands. That is definitely true. But I think
Speaker 2:  you're right for like day to day wearable ness,
Speaker 2:  it's probably the Apple Watch.
Speaker 5:  Oh and I gotta mention the Pixel Watch's proprietary band
Speaker 5:  mechanism requires a degree in physics to learn how to use.
Speaker 2:  You're saying it's not like twisting on a camera lens, whatever that means.
Speaker 2:  Yeah,
Speaker 5:  I mean you saw me in the office just losing my mind trying to figure out
Speaker 5:  the trick to it. Once you figure out the trick it's like, oh I'm an
Speaker 5:  idiot. This is really easy and satisfying to click into place.
Speaker 5:  But learning it and like it clicking into your hand, into your head
Speaker 5:  rather, there were Google reps at the demo who were like,
Speaker 5:  just give me a second I, I'm gonna figure this out. So it's, it's sort
Speaker 5:  of like Uhuh, it
Speaker 6:  Feels a bit over-engineered.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, that's so weird coming from
Speaker 2:  Google.
Speaker 2:  The next category, I have a feeling this is gonna be the one we get through
Speaker 2:  the quickest and agree on the fastest is best virtual assistant. So
Speaker 2:  we have Bixby, we have Google Assistant and we have Siri. It's just Google
Speaker 2:  assistant, right? We don't even need to talk about this,
Speaker 6:  I disagree. Oh really? It's Bixby. No I'm, I'm it's
Speaker 6:  not. I think and this is like highly
Speaker 6:  contextually specific, I think that Siri on the watch
Speaker 6:  is better than Google assistant on the Android
Speaker 6:  watches and the main reason is it's so much easier to use
Speaker 6:  and for the things that I use Siri on my watch for, it's actually very
Speaker 6:  good at the things that Siri's not good at is like figuring
Speaker 6:  out how tall the Eiffel Tower is or other random facts or
Speaker 6:  whatever. Like it's, it consistently fails at that and like that doesn't
Speaker 6:  change but I don't really ask my watch that very often the things I ask for
Speaker 6:  on my watch are to set timers to turn on and off my lights and to
Speaker 6:  like set an alarm or I ask at the weather maybe or I send
Speaker 6:  a message and all of those things work really well with Siri and I,
Speaker 6:  all I have to do is hold it up to my mouth and start speaking and it
Speaker 6:  instantly transcribes it and does the thing really quickly. Whereas with
Speaker 6:  the Google Assistant or hey g, I have to say hey G,
Speaker 6:  wait for it to like react and know that it's listening, speak what I
Speaker 6:  wanna speak and then have it do it which always has a longer processing time.
Speaker 6:  So for me it's Siri on the watch is actually a better experience.
Speaker 2:  So there's like a theoretical universe that exists in which I completely
Speaker 2:  agree with everything that you just said but my experience with Siri is that
Speaker 2:  Siri just full fails about same 40% of the
Speaker 2:  time. I hope I pull the thing up, like you said, it's great user interface,
Speaker 2:  pull it up to my mouth, say the thing, you know I use it for like reminders
Speaker 2:  a ton just like anything that comes into my brain just like it goes into
Speaker 2:  reminders and truly like two outta five times it
Speaker 2:  doesn't even finish the process. It just goes like one moment
Speaker 2:  still working and then it says I'm sorry please try again. And I'm like I
Speaker 2:  already forgot what I wanted sir. Like
Speaker 6:  I get that on home pods all the time but on my watch it like is way
Speaker 6:  more reliable and what I experience with the Google assistant
Speaker 6:  is it doesn't hear me say hey gee, like I have to say
Speaker 6:  that like three times for it to like grab it and the watch has to be like
Speaker 6:  awake. So I have to do the motion, I have to say the thing, I have to make
Speaker 6:  sure it's heard me say the thing and then I have to say my command. So it's
Speaker 6:  like the whole process of it just like turns me off to it.
Speaker 5:  That's so funny because I use the digital assistant on the watch in a
Speaker 5:  completely different manner. I never use the wake words. I always, you know,
Speaker 5:  do the the hard quoted show shortcut. It's just way more reliable for
Speaker 5:  me. But also the reason why I'm going to give the
Speaker 5:  Google Assistant the win here is that it understands me better and
Speaker 5:  just in general is able to understand ethnic names better,
Speaker 5:  which is relevant to my life when I'm like, hey send emo a
Speaker 5:  text and emo is aunt in Korean and Siri like
Speaker 5:  I don't know who IMO is and it's like okay thank you.
Speaker 5:  Does not like I had a friend who had a Japanese name in in
Speaker 5:  the past and I was like send Seia a text and they
Speaker 5:  would be like there's no one with that name in your actual
Speaker 5:  contacts looks. So I would have to say send CIA
Speaker 5:  a text. Oh
Speaker 2:  No.
Speaker 5:  So like using Google Assistant in that sense is, is
Speaker 5:  a lot easier in my life. The natural language understanding is just better
Speaker 5:  but I just think Siri thinks I've mumble, which is very
Speaker 5:  rude.
Speaker 6:  Well I mean it's two against one, right? So like I mean Google Assistant
Speaker 6:  wins this, right?
Speaker 2:  I guess we're doing it that way. Yeah, Google Assistant technically wins
Speaker 2:  that round. So good. Good job. Google Assistant Dan, congratulations on
Speaker 2:  being like the one person on earth who like Siri gets that feels like it's
Speaker 2:  like a meaningful moment for you. On a
Speaker 2:  related note, and Dan you brought this up a little bit, the next category
Speaker 2:  is the best at computer things. My big theory about Smart Watch is is they're
Speaker 2:  very good at doing all the things that take you three taps on your phone,
Speaker 2:  right? Where it's like changing your lights or setting reminders or
Speaker 2:  quickly like texting a thumbs up emoji to your friend or
Speaker 2:  whatever. I weirdly would've guessed for me that this would
Speaker 2:  be the same answer as assistant, but I made them two separate things because
Speaker 2:  I actually think the Apple Watch is better at those things than the
Speaker 2:  Pixel Watch because mostly because it has more apps. Like there's just
Speaker 2:  more stuff I can do on it.
Speaker 6:  Exactly same reason. I fully agree, I think the voice assistant has a little
Speaker 6:  bit part of it there, but fundamentally I can use the apps that
Speaker 6:  I use on my computer all the time, more likely on my wrist with the
Speaker 6:  Apple Watch than I can with the Google Watch. There's just way more app
Speaker 6:  ecosystem. It supports way more smart home devices. It
Speaker 6:  supports way more like different to-do list apps. So you can basically choose
Speaker 6:  whichever one you prefer. It's gonna have an Apple Watch version and it
Speaker 6:  will have a good complication for it and things like that. So if you wanna
Speaker 6:  see your upcoming to-dos or your upcoming appointments or whatever, the
Speaker 6:  complication systems are way more built out so that the watch
Speaker 6:  face is more customizable to show you the information that you care most
Speaker 6:  about than you can get on either Samsung or Google's
Speaker 5:  Watch. I'm gonna agree with that, especially since I think one of the most
Speaker 5:  underappreciated things you can use an Apple watch for is as a
Speaker 5:  two-factor authentication or just yes. Yep. That kind of device. It has
Speaker 5:  made my life so easy just to pull up like
Speaker 5:  one password just released a like an Apple watch
Speaker 5:  update and it is like wow you mean I can just
Speaker 5:  pull up my Octa password super easily. Amazing. This is great for
Speaker 5:  work but getting apps onto the Apple watch is
Speaker 5:  seamless. You know Google's been fragmented for so long
Speaker 5:  that it's, it's like different watches getting the apps
Speaker 5:  on there, it's not always the same experience and it's
Speaker 5:  same for Samsung and for the Pixel watch. Yeah it's just they're not
Speaker 5:  terrible, it's just Apple does it better.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, Apple also integrates the watch into
Speaker 6:  these iPhone software a lot closer and tighter. So like now with Iowa
Speaker 6:  16 a watch was nine, you can have a different watch face show up for your
Speaker 6:  work focus versus your personal focus. So like you can have a real chill
Speaker 6:  one for the weekends and then one that's like fully dense with your calendar
Speaker 6:  appointments and to-do lists and things like that. And it automatically changes
Speaker 6:  when it comes to work time. Whereas like on the Samsung watch or the Google
Speaker 6:  Watch, I have to like manually switch between them if I want to have that
Speaker 6:  kind of functionality. So it just, it just feels more helpful in that kind
Speaker 6:  of context of having a computer on my
Speaker 5:  Wrist. And that update was like such a game changer in both iOS 16
Speaker 5:  and a watchOS nine. I have so much fun with it. Like I'm just such a
Speaker 5:  nerd with my focus modes and and the the watch I
Speaker 6:  Believe you've written about it, you should go check it out on the verge.com
Speaker 6:  vs written about it.
Speaker 5:  It's my call it, this is fine focus mode.
Speaker 2:  I do love that everyone should have a, this is fine focus mode for when everything
Speaker 2:  is falling apart but I think we, yeah we all agree we're giving that one
Speaker 2:  the Apple watch. So next one is Battery
Speaker 2:  Life. The, you've tested these
Speaker 2:  things probably most aggressively of the three of us. Is there a clear winner
Speaker 2:  here? It's
Speaker 5:  The Apple Watch. Okay, Apple watch, Samsung Pixel. That's, that's how it's
Speaker 5:  gonna go.
Speaker 2:  Wait really? You put pixel below Samsung cause Samsung's battery was
Speaker 2:  pretty bleak.
Speaker 5:  It's pretty bleak but here's the thing, when you wear the Samsung
Speaker 5:  watch for a longer period of time and you know that's one of my blind
Speaker 5:  spots sometimes as a reviewer because I am constantly onto the next,
Speaker 5:  but when you do wear the Samsung watch for a longer period of time, the battery
Speaker 5:  life gets better. So that's shocking. It's not that
Speaker 5:  much better but it gets better.
Speaker 2:  Okay.
Speaker 6:  See Samsung also made forward progress with the Galaxy Watch
Speaker 6:  five versus the Galaxy Watch four. So like even just the newer model this
Speaker 6:  year has has noticeably better battery life and whereas if you've
Speaker 6:  read v's Pixel watch review, it's just
Speaker 6:  making
Speaker 2:  It, it's tough. If
Speaker 6:  You have any variety in your routine, you might not have enough battery
Speaker 6:  life by the end of the
Speaker 5:  Day. Yeah. Just for context, I went on my long run which was about
Speaker 5:  55 minutes. I did not use an offline playlist, I just went on
Speaker 5:  the run with the GPS tracking and always on display just for the run mind
Speaker 5:  you cuz you can do that and it went down like
Speaker 5:  25%. Oof. Normally on other watches it's not gonna go down
Speaker 5:  25%.
Speaker 6:  I feel like we do have to set the context here that we are only comparing
Speaker 6:  against these three watches. Yes. And there are like Fitbits and
Speaker 6:  garments and all this kinda stuff that will have like way longer battery
Speaker 6:  life than the Apple Watch. We're not saying the Apple Watch is like the best
Speaker 6:  watch battery life, but at these three it is the most reliable and consistent
Speaker 6:  and predictable and you will get a longer period of time, especially if
Speaker 6:  you're doing stuff like sleep tracking and wearing it 24 hours a day and
Speaker 6:  stuff like that. You will more reliably experience better, better life on
Speaker 6:  the Apple watch.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, that's a good note. I think this is probably the first category for
Speaker 2:  which like if this is the most important thing to, you don't buy any of these.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, yeah. Well you could get the Ultra
Speaker 6:  You could, You could get the Ultra
Speaker 2:  But even still you could get a Garmin that's gonna last you like days and
Speaker 2:  days you could get a fit that's gonna last you days and days. Like if battery
Speaker 2:  life is like your main thing, this, these are the wrong answer,
Speaker 2:  but
Speaker 6:  They don't do anything like they, they're great for like fitness
Speaker 6:  tracking and like workouts and things like that. But if you wanted any of
Speaker 6:  the stuff we just talk about for like computer assistance stuff, they
Speaker 6:  are terrible. Like, like they're just non-starters for me as as someone who
Speaker 6:  like prefers that stuff. So like it's a completely different concept to me.
Speaker 6:  Yeah,
Speaker 5:  It's your priorities. A Garmin has the most, I think,
Speaker 5:  smart features of any of the, you know, fitness tracker e
Speaker 5:  watches. It's not great Bob. It's just not
Speaker 5:  great.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, there you go. Okay, so we'll give that one to the Apple watch but with
Speaker 2:  like there's like an asterisk next to this one. This is the, the not great
Speaker 2:  Bob Asterisk. Okay. The next category
Speaker 2:  is plays best with other devices. And you can define this
Speaker 2:  however you'd like. Whether it's like tight compatibility or like
Speaker 2:  works with lots of different things. Where do we land?
Speaker 5:  Oh god, they're all bad.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, that was one of the reasons I brought this up. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  They're all pushing an ecosystem agenda. It's hard because I
Speaker 5:  think you could say Apple because it works with like within
Speaker 5:  the Apple ecosystem really well with different devices. You have
Speaker 5:  that third party ecosystem that Dan mentioned very, very good,
Speaker 5:  but it's for iPhone users only, so it's kinda
Speaker 5:  a nonstarter. But then again Samsung and the Pixel Watch right now
Speaker 5:  are for Android users only. So what are you gonna do there?
Speaker 5:  And then of the two between the, the Pixel Watch and the
Speaker 5:  Galaxy watches, it's, I don't know, do you want a choice between BPI
Speaker 5:  and Google Assistant? Is that a choice that you want to have?
Speaker 5:  Do you wanna choose between Samsung Pay and Google Wallet so you
Speaker 5:  have more choice. It's just whether you want those like main
Speaker 5:  functionality choices. So it's like they're all
Speaker 6:  Bad. I will say if you, if we are simplifying this to
Speaker 6:  like works with the most phones because you, you can't use any of these
Speaker 6:  standalone, you have to pair it to a phone. Even if you get the LTE models,
Speaker 6:  you're still relying on a phone works with the most phones is the Pixel
Speaker 6:  watch. Yep. Because it will work the same with any Android phone, whether
Speaker 6:  you have a Pixel or a Samsung phone or what other Android phones
Speaker 6:  are there. Well, a OnePlus, a nothing phone, whatever it might be. It'll
Speaker 6:  work the same in that context. The Samsung watches will work with other Android
Speaker 6:  phones, but they will only have certain features available on
Speaker 6:  Samsung phones. So you have to be in the Samsung ecosystem V correct me
Speaker 6:  if I'm wrong, to get like ECG working on Yes. A Samsung watch.
Speaker 6:  Whereas the Pixel watch will work with any Android phone with that feature.
Speaker 6:  Yep. And then obviously the iPhone or the Apple watch only works with iPhones
Speaker 6:  and it has to be paired to an iPhone. You cannot pair it to an iPad, you
Speaker 6:  cannot use it standalone. You have to use it as with an iPhone.
Speaker 6:  So in that respect I would give it to the Pixel watch, but I think vi's first
Speaker 6:  point about like if you aren't using an Apple watch, it works with
Speaker 6:  more things within that ecosystem, better
Speaker 6:  than the Pixel Watch or the Samsung Watches Zoo. Like you can pair Pixel
Speaker 6:  Buds to a Pixel Watch and Samsung Buds to a Samsung watch
Speaker 6:  and your AirPods to an Apple Watch. But I can connect it
Speaker 6:  to my home kit home and I can connect it to Apple TV
Speaker 6:  and I can, there's, and like Apple Fitness works well across my Apple TV
Speaker 6:  with my iPad and all this. So like if you're bought into that, it works very
Speaker 6:  well. But if you are not into the Apple ecosystem at all,
Speaker 6:  then the Apple Watch is a nonstarter.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I feel like the tie goes to the Pixel watch here just because Android
Speaker 2:  is like a larger ecosystem of more things
Speaker 2:  and you literally have to own one device in order
Speaker 2:  for your Apple watch to work. Yep. And at least Google is giving
Speaker 2:  you some more choices. But I agree the, the, the real answer here is they
Speaker 2:  all suck And it's like, it's ridiculous that like, like I have an Apple Watch
Speaker 2:  and a Mac and they in no way are useful to each other. What
Speaker 6:  Do you mean you don't, you don't unlock your Mac with your Apple watch?
Speaker 2:  No,
Speaker 6:  You don't use the Mac notoriously reliable Bluetooth connection to
Speaker 6:  unlock it with your watch.
Speaker 2:  Oh my God. Kill me.
Speaker 5:  It works fine for me.
Speaker 2:  Touch ID on MacBooks. Wonderful touch Id huge win
Speaker 2:  on MacBooks. I could type a 65 paragraph password in
Speaker 2:  the amount of time it takes my Apple watch to unlock my MacBook most of the
Speaker 2:  time.
Speaker 5:  That's so weird. It works so well for me. That's,
Speaker 6:  I I had to turn it off. It was, it
Speaker 2:  Was too flaky. Must be nice V must be nice. All right, we're getting this
Speaker 2:  one of the Pixel watch. We're gonna move on now we're getting
Speaker 2:  into fitness and health categories. The first one is best for regular
Speaker 2:  fitness people. You're just like, you're a person who wants to like
Speaker 2:  get their steps and make sure they're not dying. Who wins?
Speaker 5:  I'm gonna give it to the Pixel Watch.
Speaker 2:  Really
Speaker 5:  I have reasons for this. It's like so many, so many
Speaker 5:  caveats here cuz we're talking about the average person, right? So when I
Speaker 5:  think about the average person, I'm thinking about someone who is, you know,
Speaker 5:  looking to increase their activity in a way that's holistic and makes sense.
Speaker 5:  And I have a lot of issues with how Apple does this
Speaker 5:  obsessive streak and closing your
Speaker 5:  ring stuff like it's great, don't, don't get me wrong, it's great.
Speaker 2:  It is a bully. Like my, my rings are very passive aggressive. Like
Speaker 2:  I wake up every morning and it's like, it's like hey, hey dip shit you only
Speaker 2:  closed one of your rings yesterday. Maybe, maybe do better today maybe. I
Speaker 2:  don't know. You probably can't but maybe try. That'd be
Speaker 6:  Good. I love getting the alert at seven 30 at night. It's like only a 27
Speaker 6:  minute Bri call and it's like Apple
Speaker 6:  watch, I've been wearing you for seven years, you know I'm not going for
Speaker 6:  that
Speaker 2:  Wall. I've never done this once. Leave me alone.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, so like to get into that, it is a very real thing
Speaker 5:  where Apple will always push you to do more, faster, better. And
Speaker 5:  that's not always the best thing for you. Like at one
Speaker 5:  point I was getting into where, where I was like you need to have 3000 minutes
Speaker 5:  of exercise to get this month's badge. And I was like I will die. I will
Speaker 5:  literally die if you ask me to do that this month and now you're making
Speaker 5:  me break my streak. And it's very bad for your mental health in a certain
Speaker 5:  respect and it requires a lot of discipline to not get pulled into
Speaker 5:  that. Whereas, you know, Fitbit used to be like that. It was
Speaker 5:  really kind of similar in a while. But they have since made moves to
Speaker 5:  be a little more holistic that I think are great if you are just new
Speaker 5:  and easily demotivated. So like they use active
Speaker 5:  zone minutes, which is, you know, it's, it's better than this. Whatever move
Speaker 5:  ring is like I whatever the active zone minutes,
Speaker 5:  you get a certain number of like I'll call them points
Speaker 5:  based on your heart rate activity and it corresponds to the 150
Speaker 5:  minutes of moderate activity you're supposed to get according to the American
Speaker 5:  Heart Association. So it's a lot more forgiving. You don't have
Speaker 5:  to get streaks going, you can just look at your weekly average and go, Oh
Speaker 5:  you know what? I've been really sedentary this week, let me kick it up this
Speaker 5:  last two days. And that's better than nothing. You have
Speaker 5:  a daily readiness score. So that's going to at least get you thinking
Speaker 5:  about recovery, which is also really important. You're not gonna push yourself
Speaker 5:  and demotivate yourself by getting injured. You have stress management that
Speaker 5:  is like not great on the Pixel watch compared to the other Fitbits. This
Speaker 5:  is the whole thing. You can read my Fitbit Sense two review and my Pixel
Speaker 5:  watch review to get the whole picture of it. It's, I'm really mad about it.
Speaker 5:  But at the same time, just overall I, I think Fitbit
Speaker 5:  has a smarter, more experienced approach to how to get people to do
Speaker 5:  health and wellness and Samsung's a nonstarter.
Speaker 6:  I think Samsung's suffers from, it's a poor copy of whatever
Speaker 6:  Apple is doing. And so like Apple's is problematic to begin with
Speaker 6:  and then Samsung tries to clone it basically and then they don't even get
Speaker 6:  as far as Apple gets. And so you know, if you use the Samsung watch for tracking
Speaker 6:  your health, it'll do it. It'll do all the same features. It even the one
Speaker 6:  knock against the Pixel watch is that it doesn't automatically start a workout
Speaker 6:  for you. The Samsung watch and the Apple Watch will do that and things like
Speaker 6:  that. But I think V is right that I have liked the
Speaker 6:  better, more holistic approach that the Fitbit software
Speaker 6:  on the Pixel watch is offering over the other
Speaker 2:  Two. Okay, I love it. I have no qualms. Pixel watch wins this one good
Speaker 2:  for pixel watch. Okay and now best
Speaker 2:  for Super Fitness people which is like you are a person who like
Speaker 2:  whole ass cares about being fit and
Speaker 2:  runs. I don't even know the words to use cause I am not this person but you
Speaker 2:  are a, you are a fitness person Apple Watch, okay, I feel like this isn't
Speaker 2:  even close, right?
Speaker 5:  It's really not. And then again I'm gonna put an asterisk because the Garmin
Speaker 5:  people, this is for people who are kind of intermediate level
Speaker 5:  and still want smart features but still care a lot about fitness.
Speaker 2:  Once every 10 minutes in a smart watch discussion you have to acknowledge
Speaker 2:  that Garmin exists. So consider this the acknowledgement that Garmin exists,
Speaker 5:  The acknowledgement that there are hardcore yes rugged sports
Speaker 5:  watches out there and that none of these, this is not gonna hold a candle.
Speaker 5:  But if we're going between like the smart quote unquote watches,
Speaker 5:  Apple is just gonna win here because the accuracy is
Speaker 5:  better. It actually is more accurate according to this like fascinating
Speaker 5:  YouTube video. You should look it up. It's more accurate with your sleep
Speaker 5:  tracking data even though like the presentation of it isn't great than the
Speaker 5:  Fitbit is. So like wow cool, you want the most accurate data of these
Speaker 5:  three? I'm gonna give it to Apple. Especially with GPS tracking.
Speaker 5:  Like I, you can again look at some of my more recent reviews
Speaker 5:  where you see the GPS tracking the Pixel watch versus the Apple
Speaker 5:  watches and the GPS maps I got were bad. It's a known
Speaker 5:  issue. Fitbit is working to fix it but I went for this
Speaker 5:  run and the Pixel watch map stopped a whole
Speaker 5:  1000 feet ish before the others and I was like so weird.
Speaker 5:  This is crap. I ran that. This is
Speaker 5:  bs. Give me my credit.
Speaker 2:  My favorite is the part where you go on a run and I guess you go like under
Speaker 2:  a bridge or up some stairs or something. Yeah. And and the Apple watch
Speaker 2:  is like, yes V you ran up some stairs and Google
Speaker 2:  is you, you ran 11 miles back and forth randomly for
Speaker 2:  six minutes and we don't know what happened.
Speaker 5:  Yeah it's just, it's you know, just as a caveat, GPS tracking
Speaker 5:  is GPS tracking. If you're a city runner and you're going, so I
Speaker 5:  run up four flights of indoor stairs on my long runs. It's miserable.
Speaker 5:  But the GPS maps are, I love looking at them afterwards cuz
Speaker 5:  they're hilarious. They're like, you're in the East River, you've died, you're
Speaker 5:  like on the park across the street. I'm like not. But
Speaker 5:  yeah, so Fitbit accuracy wise, it's enough
Speaker 5:  to track your, like it's consistent enough, you can track your progress but
Speaker 5:  I wouldn't call it the most accurate. I would actually encourage you
Speaker 5:  to do more so that when you go for a race or whatever,
Speaker 5:  you're not like what is this I trained exactly according to this
Speaker 5:  Fitbit. And then suddenly there's an extra half mile you have to
Speaker 5:  run and you're really angry and dying. Like just tack on extra,
Speaker 5:  a little bit extra, not too much but tack on extra. And then Samsung
Speaker 5:  is the one thing I'll give Samsung is the body composition analysis.
Speaker 5:  That's a thing that the rest don't have, but bioelectric
Speaker 5:  impedance analysis is iffy.
Speaker 6:  The, would you say that the Apple watches stronger third party app ecosystem
Speaker 6:  also plays a part here. Like I feel like I, I'm coming from this as not
Speaker 6:  a advanced athlete or whatever, but I would just assume that like there's
Speaker 6:  more apps for training, there's more apps services and things like that available
Speaker 6:  on the Apple Watch than on either of the Android watches.
Speaker 5:  It's actually pretty like equal ish. Okay. Now for like the major
Speaker 5:  ones like two years ago I would've told you it was Apple but like you know
Speaker 5:  you can get Strava now on both of these. So like Strava's the big
Speaker 5:  one I think for people, well I guess if you're a hiker, you know there are
Speaker 5:  things like commute to like track your routes. So it's kind of
Speaker 5:  equal now.
Speaker 6:  Interesting.
Speaker 2:  Cool. Okay. But yeah, I think, I think we're we're right to give that one
Speaker 2:  to the Apple watch that, that seems fair. Okay. And then
Speaker 2:  the last category before we get to best overall is the best health stuff,
Speaker 2:  which is all the, all the non fitness but health and wellness tracking stuff.
Speaker 2:  And my assumption here would be good first showing from the
Speaker 2:  Pixel watch Galaxy does fine but Apple is clearly in the
Speaker 2:  lead here just in part because they've just been doing this for a while now,
Speaker 2:  right?
Speaker 5:  Apple's in the lead in my opinion. But the gap is closing is how
Speaker 5:  I'll say it. Like actually Samsung and Apple are pretty neck and
Speaker 5:  neck. It's just that once again there's a little extra polish to the
Speaker 5:  way Apple does it versus how Samsung does it. It's just clunkier.
Speaker 5:  I think one really good example I can give from the latest round of products
Speaker 5:  is temperature tracking. So Fitbits have been able to track
Speaker 5:  skin temperature for a while somehow for some reason you cannot do that on
Speaker 5:  the Pixel watch even though ostensibly you could have stuck the the
Speaker 5:  stupid hardware in there. Samsung added temperature tracking to
Speaker 5:  their new watches. But it does absolutely nothing as of right
Speaker 5:  now. So why is it there future proofing? Cool. Apple
Speaker 5:  has also added skin temperature sensing and it at least does
Speaker 5:  something with advanced cycle tracking. So yeah,
Speaker 5:  like that's kind of a really good illustrative
Speaker 5:  example of why it is that way.
Speaker 6:  So the Apple Watch is the only one that has like fall detection?
Speaker 5:  No, Samsung has fall detection as well. Samsung
Speaker 6:  Does. Okay. And
Speaker 2:  Google will in 2023 would really like you to
Speaker 2:  know that's very important that Google tells you
Speaker 2:  that it will happen in 2023.
Speaker 6:  What's interesting to me about the Pixel Watch is that they talk a
Speaker 6:  lot about how it does the per second heart rate tracking all
Speaker 6:  the time and they went really on and on about that. And then they don't have
Speaker 6:  a feature to tell you when you have an elevated heart rate when you probably
Speaker 6:  aren't supposed to. Whereas I know Samsung does that. Apple's been doing
Speaker 6:  that for a long time. It'll tell you about arrhythmia and things like
Speaker 6:  that. Other, other possible concern areas that the, the Pixel watch
Speaker 6:  doesn't do. But it does feel like the fact that the Apple Watch has is
Speaker 6:  we're on the eighth generation of the Apple Watch is, is really
Speaker 6:  helping add out because every year they add one or two more of these things
Speaker 6:  and they just kind of cumulatively stack
Speaker 2:  Up. And for me it's, it's that proactive stuff that you're talking about
Speaker 2:  that I think is a big deal. Like Neil, I was harping on this on the show
Speaker 2:  last week that like the pixel watch can't tell that you're washing your hands
Speaker 2:  and it's like, it's such like a dumb small thing. But Apple is slowly sort
Speaker 2:  of pressing in this direction of like, okay, we understand what's going on
Speaker 2:  inside of your body and we're gonna like tell you about it. And it's only
Speaker 2:  doing it in very small ways and in some ways it's like we can tell you when
Speaker 2:  you were ovulating a month ago and it's like, what is that? Okay?
Speaker 2:  And like, but we all, we all know what the next actual step is there, but
Speaker 2:  Apple just seems to be much further down this road of like not only getting
Speaker 2:  this information but sort of telling you what to do about it. Or at least
Speaker 2:  helping you understand what's going on. It feels like it's, it's several
Speaker 2:  steps ahead on that front. At least in my experience
Speaker 5:  It is. I, I do think the gap is very, very, very slowly
Speaker 5:  starting to close just, just a bit. But it is the things that you mentioned,
Speaker 5:  like well the hand washing timer sometimes thinks you're washing your hands
Speaker 5:  while you're doing the dishes, but it's still gonna start
Speaker 5:  automatically, right? Whereas with Google you have to be like, I'm going
Speaker 5:  to wash my hands before I do that. I'm going to go to the hand washing timer
Speaker 5:  widget and then start it and then do that stuff. So that's just an extra
Speaker 5:  bit of friction there. But the Pixel Watch is also a victim of a
Speaker 5:  very confused lineup. Like as Dan said, there's some
Speaker 5:  weirdness there where it's like, well you guys are basically a Fitbit, a
Speaker 5:  smarter Fitbit, but you're not including things that Fitbit's been able to
Speaker 5:  do on their less advanced trackers for a lot longer. Like it
Speaker 5:  has an SPO two sensor, but you're not going to get nightly SPO two
Speaker 5:  percentages. You're only gonna get this more obscure graph that you
Speaker 5:  have to like dig through a few menus to find called estimated oxygen variation.
Speaker 5:  So it's like what are you doing here? And the answer is, is that they have
Speaker 5:  a sense too in a verse four and they want people to buy it for whatever reason,
Speaker 5:  but they don't know what to do. So things on both watches are
Speaker 5:  unnecessarily nerfed in a way that's infuriating.
Speaker 2:  Yeah and I think that's helpful. A lot of this stuff, it's like stuff
Speaker 2:  that happens on your first generation that like you give Google a couple
Speaker 2:  years and if it's actually serious about pushing on this, they can start
Speaker 2:  to get some of that stuff right? Yep.
Speaker 2:  All right, so we have finished all of our categories and I think the way
Speaker 2:  this nets out is basically the Apple Watch wins but not
Speaker 2:  by like a gigantic margin, like strong, surprisingly strong showing for the
Speaker 2:  Pixel watch.
Speaker 6:  The Pixel watch took some wins there like
Speaker 2:  It did. The Galaxy Watch got nothing. I'm sorry to the Galaxy Watch.
Speaker 5:  It's got second best syndrome. It's, it really does.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, totally.
Speaker 6:  It, it absolutely does. And then there are like, you know, scenarios where
Speaker 6:  it might be the better choice for you, especially if you have a Samsung phone
Speaker 6:  and there's certain things it does better than the Pixel watch. I will say
Speaker 6:  I have a pet peeve with the Pixel watch, it does not have an hourly chime
Speaker 6:  feature. So I'm so used to the Apple Watch and the Samsung watch buzzing
Speaker 6:  on my wrist every hour and it helps me keep track and stay on time and the
Speaker 6:  Pixel watch doesn't have that. So for the entire week I was wearing the pixel
Speaker 6:  watch I like, like was losing track of time all over the place.
Speaker 2:  This is the longest hour
Speaker 5:  Ever. I guess the the hack you can do is if you're okay with it going
Speaker 5:  off at 10 minutes to the hour, you could turn on step reminders and use
Speaker 5:  that
Speaker 6:  As a and just not move.
Speaker 5:  And just not move.
Speaker 2:  Alright. So yeah, I feel like this landed in the right place. I think think
Speaker 2:  it was, I I would've been surprised if we had landed on the Pixel Watch
Speaker 2:  is better at more things but I feel like the Pixel Watch did a good
Speaker 5:  Job. It's a strong showing for a first gen device.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I gave it a six, which I think some people will be like, that's really
Speaker 5:  harsh but tough nos. But it gives it like room to grow,
Speaker 5:  you know like so I, I'm going to, I'm gonna quote
Speaker 5:  like diminishing returns that Apple Watch has diminishing returns, right?
Speaker 5:  It's gotten so far advanced, so long that like
Speaker 5:  the amount that it can really improve by gets smaller and smaller each year.
Speaker 5:  The Pixel watch, the Pixel watch two could be a vast improvement over the
Speaker 5:  Pixel Watch one, the Pixel Watch three could be like exponentially better
Speaker 5:  as well. So like there's greater potential coming from
Speaker 5:  these from the Pixel watch than from I would say the Samsung watch or the
Speaker 5:  Apple Watch. But that's just because it's brand new. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  As long as Google doesn't kill it, it might be great Someday.
Speaker 5:  Someday.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. All right, well we need to take a break but thank you both. This was,
Speaker 2:  this was super helpful and I'm sure we will be back to do this again every
Speaker 2:  year for the rest of our lives.
Speaker 5:  Si
Speaker 2:  Okay, we need to take another break and then we're gonna come back and do
Speaker 2:  some rapid fire answers on the Vercast hotline. Oh and Victoria actually
Speaker 2:  stay on because we have a question we need you to answer first. We'll be
Speaker 2:  right
Speaker 2:  back.
Speaker 8:  Look, robots do a lot of great things. They serve as dim sum like
Speaker 8:  super fast. They do a B minus job vacuuming our homes. They
Speaker 8:  even help our parents remember that all of their passwords are well
Speaker 8:  Password. One thing robots aren't great at though finding your next
Speaker 8:  favorite song. If you're ready to discover music picked by real humans,
Speaker 8:  not algorithms or robots, you're going to love Amp. It's a new
Speaker 8:  live radio app with tons of creators hosting shows on anything and everything.
Speaker 8:  Dive into an endless stream of new tunes, sports talks, shows hitting
Speaker 8:  culture and so much more. There are even shows hosted by iconic
Speaker 8:  creators like Joe Button and Lo Yacht where you can call in and chat with
Speaker 8:  them directly, Tune in, call in or step up to the plate and host your own
Speaker 8:  show from anywhere, right from your phone. Discover your next obsession
Speaker 8:  with Amp download today on the app store. Or just ask Alexa to play
Speaker 8:  amp. Hey, robots are still good for something. Download amp from the
Speaker 8:  app store or head to on amp.com to learn
Speaker 8:  more.
Speaker 9:  Fox Creative.
Speaker 10:  This is advertiser content from Amazon
Speaker 10:  ads. In the past two years, more people are
Speaker 10:  cooking at home gardening for the first time and learning home improvement
Speaker 10:  skills. People are teaching themselves new things and looking to the internet
Speaker 10:  for advice.
Speaker 11:  How often should I water my
Speaker 11:  tomatoes?
Speaker 10:  A well placed ad can be a tool for discovery, allowing consumers to
Speaker 10:  improve their skills or enhance their entertainment.
Speaker 12:  Dreaming of Let Doce Beta, our pasta rollers are
Speaker 12:  the perfect size for any kitchen.
Speaker 10:  Ooh, according to research commissioned by Amazon Ads
Speaker 10:  and Omnicom Media Group, 68% of consumers want ads that
Speaker 10:  are relevant to the content they're embedded in at Amazon ads. We make it
Speaker 10:  easier for brands to connect to audiences with relevant messaging like
Speaker 10:  when they're listening to Amazon music's ad supported tier on an Alexa enabled
Speaker 10:  device. Your customers just need to say, Alexa,
Speaker 5:  Add Pasta roller to my cart.
Speaker 10:  Learn more at vox.com/museum of Modern
Speaker 10:  Ads.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. It's Vergecast hotline time. I love the Vergecast hotline.
Speaker 2:  We've been doing a lot of themed q and as on the hotline recently,
Speaker 2:  but it's been a while since we got to just answer some of the other questions
Speaker 2:  that we're getting, including a few that we get a lot. Please keep calling
Speaker 2:  the hotline by the way, I love these questions. Eight sixty six Verge one
Speaker 2:  one call it nass. Anything on your mind, let's take some time and answer
Speaker 2:  a few of them. Now the first question we got comes from
Speaker 2:  Josh.
Speaker 13:  Hey, my name's Josh and I have a Fitbit Sense
Speaker 13:  with the sense to and the pixel watch coming out. Which one should
Speaker 13:  I get? It seems like Google is very much trying to
Speaker 13:  disincentivize me from getting the sense to Thank you.
Speaker 2:  All right, this is a question that v you and I have been talking about
Speaker 2:  for like weeks now. I feel like there's a very easy answer to this question,
Speaker 2:  but I'm curious what you think.
Speaker 5:  Well, ding ding, ding. Josh has hit the nail on the head, very
Speaker 5:  astute. It's gonna boil down to what your preferences are and what your priorities
Speaker 5:  are. If you really wanna lean into all the health and fitness,
Speaker 5:  you could make an argument for the sense too. But if you
Speaker 5:  care at all about literally anything remotely smart, the
Speaker 5:  Pixel Watch is gonna be better bang for your buck. Like as I mentioned earlier,
Speaker 5:  Google is very confused about what to do with all of these watches that they
Speaker 5:  have now. They've got three technically if you include the Sense Two and
Speaker 5:  the Versa four, which you know, if you asked me they should have merged that
Speaker 5:  together. So what they did was they nerfed the smarter features
Speaker 5:  on the sense too and then they also nerfed some of the
Speaker 5:  more like advanced health features on the Pixel watch. None
Speaker 5:  of this makes sense. The sense too is $300 that
Speaker 5:  makes no sense to price it at that when you are nerfing the fact that it
Speaker 5:  cannot have third party apps on there. So if you enjoy Pandora,
Speaker 5:  these are the random Starbucks app that's on there that's gone now you can't
Speaker 5:  have it. Bye bye. Sorry, that's so stupid on the sense you could have
Speaker 5:  a choice between Alexa and Google Assistant. Well sorry for
Speaker 5:  you on a Google product, you could only have Alexa as your
Speaker 5:  assistant for the sense too. That makes no sense.
Speaker 5:  Pun intended in this case. So what, What
Speaker 5:  you doing? What you doing there Bud? And also you're gonna get Google Maps
Speaker 5:  and Google Wallet much later down the line. It's not available yet on
Speaker 5:  the sense too, it's just, I'm enraged. On the other hand, if
Speaker 5:  you're mostly like okay with having the
Speaker 5:  majority of the health features in a basic sense the Pixel watch is
Speaker 5:  fine, it's only $50 more if you're not getting lte. So
Speaker 5:  it's just like, I really do think you're gonna get a better value for
Speaker 5:  the Pixel Watch. The only reason I would tell you not to is if
Speaker 5:  you are really into the idea of proactive stress
Speaker 5:  alerts and like stress management journaling and you want those
Speaker 5:  proactive alerts like cuz the sense too will be
Speaker 5:  like I detect that you're having a bodily response
Speaker 5:  to something. Would you like to log your mood? So
Speaker 5:  that's like the one thing this watch has and Battery
Speaker 5:  Life.
Speaker 2:  If you wanna say shut up Fitbit, leave me alone 50 times a day,
Speaker 2:  buy a Fitbit. Otherwise,
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I mean I, it's a very thoughtful feature. I think Fitbit does stress
Speaker 5:  management the best and most holistically again a thing. But
Speaker 5:  overall I reviewed the sense too and I was like we're gonna have to
Speaker 5:  pour one out for Fitbit smart watches guys. Cuz this is like, it's,
Speaker 5:  it's just clear that the next time they're gonna
Speaker 5:  unnerve all the fitness things they did for the Pixel watch
Speaker 5:  and then it's just not a competition. I really think they have the sense
Speaker 5:  too and the verse four already like 90% done and they're
Speaker 5:  like, well gotta put them out there. Gotta give
Speaker 5:  incentives. This is artificially our fitness watch and this is
Speaker 5:  artificially our smart one but we're going to half ass instead of whole
Speaker 5:  ass one thing. The Ron Swanson way, it's been
Speaker 5:  frustrating.
Speaker 2:  Yeah and it, it does seem very clearly like the future of Fitbit
Speaker 2:  looks a lot more like the Pixel Watch than it does the versa or the
Speaker 2:  sense Yep. That like if you fast forward a few years from now and you were
Speaker 2:  like, do all three of those things even still exist? Like I would bet no,
Speaker 2:  but the Pixel watch still will it's, it's the one that's gonna come out of
Speaker 2:  all of this.
Speaker 5:  David, you told me one day that like we're one pixel band away from
Speaker 5:  all Fitbits just not existing and I agree with you. Yeah, so I just
Speaker 5:  think it's Google and Fitbit are gonna be the same thing now with
Speaker 5:  one arbitrary data barrier between them because regulators
Speaker 5:  said so like that's it.
Speaker 2:  All right Josh, buy a Pixel watch. That's where we are. Thanks Steve. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Okay, our next question comes from Austin.
Speaker 14:  Hey this is Austin. As somebody who works in my car, one of the things I
Speaker 14:  think about upgrading is my car stereo. I don't know if you guys have looked
Speaker 14:  at upgraded car stereos, but they're just bad
Speaker 14:  pieces of technology. They, they're clunky and they're
Speaker 14:  outdated and even the ones that touchscreens and CarPlay still, you know,
Speaker 14:  just not fun to use. So I was wondering if there's any reason why these
Speaker 14:  just seem like they haven't been improved at all in the last two decades.
Speaker 14:  Thanks.
Speaker 2:  Obviously there is only one person maybe on earth who I would want
Speaker 2:  to answer this question and that is Eli Patel. Hi Eli. What's up? What do
Speaker 2:  you got?
Speaker 15:  So car stereos were amazing in like the nineties and early two thousands
Speaker 15:  because all cars had the same standardized slot in the
Speaker 15:  dashboard to fit a car stereo. It's called the den slot. Some cars had
Speaker 15:  double den slots, which were too high and you could get really crazy car
Speaker 15:  stereos in there. A lot of GM cars had double den slots. But because there
Speaker 15:  was basically a standard hole in your dashboard
Speaker 15:  and all that you needed from a car stereo was to play audio, not all the
Speaker 15:  other stuff in your car. There was like an arms race in cool car stereo
Speaker 15:  stuff cuz the whole market could address the
Speaker 15:  opportunity of we just need to put a stereo in this
Speaker 15:  rectangle in your dashboard that's the same size in every car. What's happened
Speaker 15:  since then is car dashboards have gotten crazy and
Speaker 15:  they're all different shapes, sizes, screens and cars have become all
Speaker 15:  different shapes and sizes. So there's no more standardized spot
Speaker 15:  for a car stereo to go in a car. No modern car really
Speaker 15:  has Aden slot anymore. And the big trend is to actually
Speaker 15:  break the screen away from the computing hardware
Speaker 15:  inside. So for a long time, all the computer stuff
Speaker 15:  behind your car's screen was like right behind the display. And now the
Speaker 15:  big trend is to tuck all that computer stuff elsewhere and make the
Speaker 15:  displays ever thinner and floating space for aesthetic reasons. So
Speaker 15:  there's no market for car stereos anymore, it's, it's gone away. And as
Speaker 15:  cars get newer and older cars go off the road, the actual market for
Speaker 15:  car stereos is shrinking, which is why you see no innovation, there's not
Speaker 15:  a great return on investment to actually invent
Speaker 15:  a new kind of car stereo. There are infinity,
Speaker 15:  bad Android-based car stereos you can buy. So if you get
Speaker 15:  away from the brand names like the pioneers and the Kenwoods or whatever,
Speaker 15:  and you fall down the rabbit hole of weird
Speaker 15:  Chinese companies in other weird companies like Phoenix Automotive,
Speaker 15:  they will sell you an Android tablet that can take over all of the
Speaker 15:  functions of your car. You could replace the entire center stack of a
Speaker 15:  modern Ford with like an Android tablet. It's just a horrible Android
Speaker 15:  tablet and you don't wanna have that experience. And you can watch the YouTube
Speaker 15:  videos of people who do it and they're so excited and then they're like,
Speaker 15:  wait, this is horrible. And they all end up reverting. I've gone
Speaker 15:  down the full loop of like two in the morning, I'm gonna buy one of these
Speaker 15:  Android tablets and then I go and watch a review and then I don't do it
Speaker 15:  and you can just join me on that journey. But the answer basically is
Speaker 15:  new cars don't have the right size holes in them to
Speaker 15:  fit your car stereo. They all have different size holes now, so there's
Speaker 15:  no more innovation.
Speaker 2:  Okay, next up we have a message from Gary in
Speaker 2:  Canada.
Speaker 16:  Hey, it's Gary from New Brunswick, Canada. I have a daughter who's eventually
Speaker 16:  gonna be asking for her own phone. I assume she'll be asking for an iPhone
Speaker 16:  mainly because children can be awful to each other and we know if they get
Speaker 16:  something different from the rest of them, they treat each other poorly.
Speaker 16:  So I assume she'll be one of the sheep and want to get her own iPhone. Our
Speaker 16:  household unfortunately is all Google except for a MacBook Pro. So I would
Speaker 16:  be inclined to just give her an Android phone and be done with it. So my
Speaker 16:  question is, how does one, do parental controls properly on an iPhone when
Speaker 16:  you don't own another iOS device? Can it be done on the single iPhone?
Speaker 16:  Can you manage it with a MacBook Pro? It seems kind of ridiculous that I
Speaker 16:  would've to go buy a cheap iPad or something just to manage it for her.
Speaker 16:  And are there any gaps in features, in functionality with any of
Speaker 16:  the options that you could do to manage that? So thanks, love the
Speaker 16:  podcast.
Speaker 2:  This turned out to be a surprisingly interesting and complicated question
Speaker 2:  and the short version of a longer answer is that Apple actually doesn't handle
Speaker 2:  this very well. But Liam, our producer, did a bunch of looking and
Speaker 2:  researching and found that actually the best way to do this for you,
Speaker 2:  Gary, is gonna be on the device itself. In the screen time settings, you
Speaker 2:  can set up what's called a screen time passcode and basically you would have
Speaker 2:  that passcode but not your kid. And then through that passcode, that's
Speaker 2:  how you'd be able to manage things like content and privacy restrictions
Speaker 2:  and which of the built in apps they're allowed to use. And you can turn off
Speaker 2:  allowing iTunes and app store purchases, all the kind of stuff you would
Speaker 2:  want to do for parental controls, all lives in screen time on the
Speaker 2:  device itself. And if you wanna manage it again, you would need that screen
Speaker 2:  time passcode that does require you to have an Apple id, which could be
Speaker 2:  slightly annoying, but it gives you much more control over what's going on
Speaker 2:  on the kid's device. I would argue this is like a terrible system and should
Speaker 2:  be much easier to manage. But here's where we are. So you're gonna wanna
Speaker 2:  get a screen time passcode in the screen time settings on the iPhone, keep
Speaker 2:  that passcode for you and don't give it to your kid. It does mean that anytime
Speaker 2:  you wanna manage this stuff, you're gonna actually have to have the device
Speaker 2:  itself, which you know, could be testy, whether you conceal your
Speaker 2:  kid's phone away from them in order to change some of this stuff. But that's
Speaker 2:  where it is. So all this stuff lives in screen time and the way you'd manage
Speaker 2:  it for yourself basically is also the way you'll manage it for your kid.
Speaker 2:  You'll just have a separate passcode. It's messy, but it seems to
Speaker 2:  work. Finally, to close out the show, we have an age
Speaker 2:  old question about podcast apps. I love talking about podcast apps,
Speaker 2:  so let's hear it.
Speaker 17:  Hey Vergecast, this is Summer Zika. I'm calling looking for
Speaker 17:  a good podcast app alternative. I have an iPhone
Speaker 17:  and I'm really sick and tired of my podcast app, the
Speaker 17:  Apple Podcast app not syncing up every time Apple releases a new
Speaker 17:  iOS update. What's a good podcast app I can use that's not
Speaker 17:  Spotify and doesn't require a subscription? Thanks.
Speaker 2:  This question prompted a surprising amount of controversy
Speaker 2:  among our little vergecast team over here, so we're just gonna talk about
Speaker 2:  it here. Andrew Marino. Hello?
Speaker 18:  Hi,
Speaker 2:  David, Liam, James. Hello.
Speaker 18:  Hey.
Speaker 2:  Okay, so based on my read of the situation, Liam, you're
Speaker 2:  wrong. So why don't you go first and tell us your bad answer before we tell
Speaker 2:  everybody The good answer,
Speaker 18:  I wouldn't say it's a bad answer, but it is definitely a
Speaker 18:  niche app. It's called Castro for iOS. I don't think they have an
Speaker 18:  Android app. It's for people like me who
Speaker 18:  have tabs on a ton, like over a hundred
Speaker 18:  podcasts, but don't actually listen to them all. So the thing that makes
Speaker 18:  it unique is it's got two buckets. One is the queue,
Speaker 18:  your actual play queue. These are podcasts that that you're always gonna
Speaker 18:  listen to. And the other, and for me, much larger bucket
Speaker 18:  is just podcasts you're keeping tabs on. And so I'll scroll
Speaker 18:  through that list maybe once a week and pick the ones I actually wanna listen
Speaker 18:  to and just wipe all the rest of them. But the whole app is centered around
Speaker 18:  that. So if that's not the way you listen to podcasts, you'll probably hate
Speaker 18:  this app. But I think it is the best one out there. And
Speaker 18:  I'm not wrong.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I give Castro a hard time, but it does for that one specific thing
Speaker 2:  where it's like, I have a bunch of podcasts but I don't wanna listen to all
Speaker 2:  the episodes. I just wanna make myself a queue. Castro's really, really
Speaker 2:  good at that.
Speaker 18:  And I should say, you know, you can basically create that same
Speaker 18:  functionality in other podcast apps, but this is
Speaker 18:  just kind of like an automated, you know, it's like the framework of the
Speaker 18:  app itself. So maybe it's not as important to you. I'm sure you can
Speaker 18:  create this with playlists or something else in another app.
Speaker 2:  Fair enough. It's a, it's a good app but it's not the best app. Andrew, you're
Speaker 2:  correct about the best app, but just to say that you agree with me about
Speaker 2:  what the best app is, tell us what you
Speaker 19:  Think. Yeah, so I use PocketCasts and I started using it
Speaker 19:  because a while back I was using an iPhone
Speaker 19:  and an Android tablet to listen to podcasts. And
Speaker 19:  this was an app that I could sync what podcasts I were listening to
Speaker 19:  on two different devices. So I had been using PocketCasts and
Speaker 19:  also when we put timestamps into the show,
Speaker 19:  pocket casts, when you're listening to the show, you can actually
Speaker 19:  use the timestamps as a hyperlink, which brings you right
Speaker 19:  to that point in the show. And a lot of podcast apps don't offer
Speaker 19:  this.
Speaker 18:  Is that like chapters Andrew?
Speaker 19:  It's like chapters. We get a lot of emails, we
Speaker 19:  get at least one email a week about chapters in the Verge Cast. Where are
Speaker 19:  the chapters? Why won't you support chapters? Everyone does this megaphone.
Speaker 19:  Our publishing platform does not support chapters, so we're not
Speaker 19:  able to do it right now, but we really want to, we're all on board for
Speaker 19:  chapters, but we can't do it yet.
Speaker 2:  We get a lot of emails wondering where chapters are and we also send a lot
Speaker 2:  of emails to different people also wondering where chapters are. So if you
Speaker 2:  want us to have chapters, don't worry. We want it just as badly as you do,
Speaker 2:  right? You're right about PocketCasts and you're also right about the reason
Speaker 2:  for PocketCasts because PocketCasts is everywhere, which is why I think it's
Speaker 2:  great. They have a web app that's very good. There's an Android app that's
Speaker 2:  very good. They're desktop apps that are very good. It is like the
Speaker 2:  most functional cross platform podcast app. It also
Speaker 2:  has a million ways to do stuff. You can filter it, like I have a filter for
Speaker 2:  just like the daily podcast that come out every day and those just dump into
Speaker 2:  one place. I have stuff for like my favorites that I know I'm gonna listen
Speaker 2:  to. So if you wanna like sort the hell outta your podcasts, you totally can.
Speaker 2:  But mostly it's easy and everywhere. And
Speaker 2:  that's good enough for me. For podcast apps, I should say the, the two honorable
Speaker 2:  mentions we should mention are Spotify, which has lots of podcasts
Speaker 2:  and is just a god awful podcast app. Like do not,
Speaker 2:  unless you hate yourself, use Spotify as your podcast player because it,
Speaker 2:  it is awful. And the other one is Overcast, which I think falls into
Speaker 2:  Liam's category of like apps that do less but do it very
Speaker 2:  well. Overcast is really good for like, if you're the type to listen to it
Speaker 2:  fast and you wanna compress silence so you can hear stuff better and get
Speaker 2:  through shows more quickly. It's really good for managing stuff. It's
Speaker 2:  only basically for Mac and iOS users, but it's a really good
Speaker 2:  podcast to have. But for me it's pocket casts and I think it's not particularly
Speaker 2:  close.
Speaker 18:  You know, that begs the question that I really want the answer to Andrew,
Speaker 18:  the man who makes our podcast sound as good as it does. What do you think
Speaker 18:  of these trim silence features? I'm, I'm really curious. There's,
Speaker 18:  you know, a lot of people love and hate listening at 1.5
Speaker 18:  x. I'm very much on the side of listen to it the way it was meant to
Speaker 18:  be listened to, which is one X, But what about trim
Speaker 18:  silence?
Speaker 19:  There's some shows that need the trim silence feature and I think that's
Speaker 19:  okay,
Speaker 2:  But not the Verge
Speaker 19:  Cast, but not the Verge cast. I spend a lot of time cutting
Speaker 19:  silence on my end, so I don't think you need it. And if you do
Speaker 19:  need it then I think you might as well just be using the like
Speaker 19:  two times speed.
Speaker 2:  That's fair. All right, listen to podcast Casts unless you
Speaker 2:  think Liam is right, which he's not. And Castro is also a good app.
Speaker 18:  It's a great app. Support your podcast app
Speaker 18:  developer.
Speaker 2:  Okay. And with that, that is the vergecast for this week. Thank you for listening.
Speaker 2:  As always, there is tons more on everything we talked about@thever.com and
Speaker 2:  you can also follow all of us on Twitter. McKenna is Kelly McKenna.
Speaker 2:  Victoria is Vic m Song. Dan is DC Seifert
Speaker 2:  Eli is Reckless, and I'm Pierce. This show is produced by Angel Marino and
Speaker 2:  Liam James Noria. Donovan is our executive producer and Brooke Miners is
Speaker 2:  our editorial director of audio. The Vergecast is Verge Production and part
Speaker 2:  of the Vox Media podcast network. If you have thoughts, feedback,
Speaker 2:  feelings, ideas about getting trees off my car or cool Halloween
Speaker 2:  costume ideas, you can always email vergecast@theverge.com. Please call the
Speaker 2:  hotline too. Eight six six Verge one one. I'm actually gonna be offline for
Speaker 2:  the Friday show, but NEI and Alex will be joined by senior news editor and
Speaker 2:  much requested Verge cast guest Richard Lawler to talk about the new iPads
Speaker 2:  all day announcements from Adobe Max and much more. See you then. Rock and
Speaker 2:  roll