# Transcript
ID: e8849190-d061-11ec-9ab4-df4b97047a6c
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: 3D printing and trackballs: the future of gadgets?
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-5214852474023028431/5155587356617663277/s93290-None-2376s-1652187891.mp3
Description: In episode two of our Vergecast "creators series," Alex Cranz talks with the creators of Ploopy, the open source trackball that has a dedicated fanbase on Reddit.
Alex also talks with Chris Person, who recently wrote about Ploopy for The Verge, about how 3D printing and online communities are creating opportunities for gadget enthusiasts.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Disabled
Speaker 1:  This episode is brought to you by grain Your
Speaker 1:  life from the shoes you wear to how you make your coffee is
Speaker 1:  fueled by recommendations, maybe from your favorite artists, your
Speaker 1:  sister-in-law or your friend. Who's so cool. It's actually kind of
Speaker 1:  intimidating. Grin is the leading influencer marketing
Speaker 1:  software that allows you to build relationships with creators directly.
Speaker 1:  It's used by top e-commerce brands like Allbirds, skims,
Speaker 1:  Warby Parker, and more find out how grim can help you grow
Speaker 1:  your friend. Watch the demo@grin.co that's.
Speaker 1:  G R I N. Dot C O.
Speaker 3:  Hey Ray, stand out from the rush past on Tuesdays this month, we're doing
Speaker 3:  some extra episodes that are focused on creators or favorite and in
Speaker 3:  true virtuous fashion, it's the nerdiest creators we can find last
Speaker 3:  week, Alex, Cranz talked to people, building a mechanical keyboards. Alex
Speaker 3:  is here. What's up, Alex, Hey,
Speaker 4:  What's up?
Speaker 3:  What nerds did you find me for this week's episode?
Speaker 4:  So this week we're going full nerd. I mean, we've already been going full
Speaker 4:  note, but we're going to be talking track balls, which I think is like niche
Speaker 4:  of niche. Like there are people who really care about gaming wise, but there
Speaker 4:  are even fewer of us who care about track balls. And I went and found some
Speaker 4:  guys and they created their own company to 3d print
Speaker 4:  track balls. It's called poopy. And they've got like a big vibrant
Speaker 4:  community on Reddit where people are like doing all these crazy mods and
Speaker 4:  stuff. And we're going to talk to them about poopy
Speaker 3:  Flippy. I'm not
Speaker 4:  Gonna, I'm not gonna spoil it. You're gonna have to listen. That's great.
Speaker 3:  Alright, let's do it. Take it away, Alex.
Speaker 4:  You know how you maybe have a mouse or game controller and you absolutely
Speaker 4:  love it. You tore the thing, but sometimes you look at it and you
Speaker 4:  wonder if the mouse fit your hand better, where the triggers on the back
Speaker 4:  of the controller are longer. There's just a little tweak you want to
Speaker 4:  make with most gadgets that require some heavy duty modding, some
Speaker 4:  voiding warranties, and a big hunt to find other people trying to do what
Speaker 4:  you're trying to do. The idea behind  a company that makes 3d
Speaker 4:  printed track balls is kind of what if the community and the model was
Speaker 4:  built right in.
Speaker 4:  I first heard about floopy from a fellow track ball nerd, and it was immediately
Speaker 4:  hooked on the concept. Most track balls nowadays, stick to a handful of tried
Speaker 4:  and true designs and are made by companies like logic, tech and Kensington.
Speaker 4:  There hasn't been a lot of innovation in this space and it's felt for years,
Speaker 4:  like all the experimentation with form and design stopped in
Speaker 4:  1997,
Speaker 4:  But poopie actively encourages people to come up with their own designs
Speaker 4:  and mods and weird ideas. And they all share them with each other on a pretty
Speaker 4:  active subreddit. I'm going to talk to someone from that subreddit later,
Speaker 4:  but first I want to talk to brothers Colin and Phil lamb.
Speaker 5:  My name's Colin, and I'm on the call with Phil, my partner and my brother.
Speaker 5:  And I'm one of the co-founders of poopy poopy corporation type. My
Speaker 5:  name is film. I'm also one of the co founders of poopy
Speaker 4:  And yes, they can explain why it's called that. So let's get right into our
Speaker 4:  interview.
Speaker 5:  So originally my brother and I were just spitballing about
Speaker 5:  what kinds of names we wanted to have for the company for
Speaker 5:  this, the companies that the two of us were running ahead, very serious
Speaker 5:  names and very ridiculous offerings.
Speaker 5:  And we thought, you know, maybe like if we switch it up and we have a silly
Speaker 5:  name, it'll help sharpen our focus and, and give us a
Speaker 5:  little bit of direction. And it just so happened that we were kicking
Speaker 5:  around a couple of names one day and the name came up and we loved it
Speaker 5:  so much that we decided to stick with it.
Speaker 4:  Is this the first track ball you guys had worked on together?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Phil was actually the one who came up with the idea originally. I
Speaker 5:  think it's like we grew up in the nineties, right. And I accidentally
Speaker 5:  walked into an office Depot when I was like 14 or 15. And I came out of
Speaker 5:  that store with one of these, with one of the originals, right. Then the
Speaker 5:  Microsoft trackball Explorer. And it turns out there's an entire community
Speaker 5:  of people that just remember this thing very fondly, because honestly, it's,
Speaker 5:  it's a magical piece of equipment. I think when we were talking about something
Speaker 5:  new to do, it was just the project that I had kicking around in my head.
Speaker 5:  I was like, well, I had two of these. I broke both of them. Boy, I wish
Speaker 5:  that I could just have another one. And I bet you, there's lots of people
Speaker 5:  out there that feel the same way.
Speaker 4:  You are a hundred percent, right. I'm one of those people. I like, I had
Speaker 4:  my track balls when, like, I was really big into the, the lodge tech thumb
Speaker 4:  ball. And when they started like reducing the number of track balls they
Speaker 4:  were making in the late two thousands, I like went out and bought a bunch
Speaker 4:  and had like, I was like, I got a stack up, which is like a very weird thing
Speaker 4:  to do. And when my friend hit me up and was like, Hey, have you heard of
Speaker 4:  poopy? I was immediately like, oh my God, this is the best idea ever,
Speaker 4:  like just lost my mind. I was like, you're, you're going to write a story
Speaker 4:  for us about this. Like I, like, I have to know everything I can about poopy.
Speaker 4:  And so it sounds like was that initial poopy kind
Speaker 4:  of modeled after that, that Microsoft?
Speaker 5:  I think the key idea was there's so many companies that are out there.
Speaker 5:  They make something, especially if it's something that you use everyday,
Speaker 5:  like a keyboard or a mouse or a set of headphones or something like that.
Speaker 5:  And then for whatever reason, these companies stopped supporting it. Maybe
Speaker 5:  it's not profitable anymore. Maybe they can't get the parts anymore, but
Speaker 5:  these are gadgets that people get really attached to and they get really
Speaker 5:  used to them. And then all of a sudden they're gone. They're not available
Speaker 5:  anymore. And it really sucks when that happens. I think
Speaker 5:  everybody has experienced something like that. Something that they really
Speaker 5:  enjoy and all of a sudden it's gone. And I think one of the key drivers behind
Speaker 5:  what we were doing, especially with open sourcing, everything was, it doesn't
Speaker 5:  matter if we stop making this thing, this thing's always going to be available.
Speaker 5:  This thing is always going, it's always gonna be possible to make this thing,
Speaker 5:  and it's not going to be hugely expensive. It's not going to require
Speaker 5:  $50,000 to make an injection mold or anything like that. It's always gonna
Speaker 5:  be available. I think that was really the key driver behind why we were going
Speaker 5:  with it in that direction to begin with.
Speaker 4:  I think what's really also kind of cool about this is that you have a lot
Speaker 4:  of different types there. Cause track balls were so unique for such a
Speaker 4:  long period of time. There were so many different form factors and
Speaker 4:  as things kind of like drilled down, suddenly we had like the Logitech thumb
Speaker 4:  ball in the Kensington giant ball, and that was kind of it.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It was funny. The core technology behind all of them
Speaker 5:  is roughly the same. There's some differences in the
Speaker 5:  sensors. Like QMLK huge thing in the keyboard space. It's not
Speaker 5:  a thing in the mouse space or the track ball space or anything like that.
Speaker 5:  And like just a couple of developers from QM, Kay, reached out to us when
Speaker 5:  they figured out what microcontroller we were using and what technology we
Speaker 5:  were using. And that kind of helped make everything more modular,
Speaker 5:  like moving from the classic, which is the original one that we released
Speaker 5:  into the nano, which is only a ball. Like there's no buttons on it at all.
Speaker 5:  It's only a ball moving and porting everything over was really,
Speaker 5:  really straightforward. So it's really easy to create a new form factors
Speaker 5:  and new input types. People were really responding to
Speaker 5:  the sort of philosophy behind, behind the original product. And,
Speaker 5:  and one of the things about running an open source company is that
Speaker 5:  people are really, really eager to give you feedback. And we're also very
Speaker 5:  accessible on Reddit and people are just not afraid to tell you what they
Speaker 5:  think. And you know, just for a while, what we were hearing was this is great,
Speaker 5:  but I wish it was this and this is great, but I wish it was this every
Speaker 5:  once in a while enough people would kind of pile up kind of saying the same
Speaker 5:  thing that we said, all right, well, let's see what happens when we, when
Speaker 5:  we actually do it. Right. And, and that's how we ended up with what we have
Speaker 5:  today, because mostly just people were like, if we want that, we're like,
Speaker 5:  all right, cool. We can make it.
Speaker 4:  So for track balls, it was this one thing you'd always loved. Was there ever
Speaker 4:  the idea that you might do something else besides track balls with poopy?
Speaker 5:  I think so. Yeah. The idea was always to stick with open source. It was always
Speaker 5:  going to be available. There was always going to be options for customization.
Speaker 5:  There was always going to be a community aspect around it, especially, you
Speaker 5:  know, I'm trying to get other people involved, developing new features and
Speaker 5:  just making it accessible. And one of the things that we're working on right
Speaker 5:  now is the headphones projects. And we've just explored like a
Speaker 5:  couple of different ideas in the past. Some not really so successful and
Speaker 5:  some that are really capturing our attention right now. So we always knew
Speaker 5:  we were going to go beyond track balls. I guess we just didn't realize that
Speaker 5:  we would spend, because it's been over two years where we were focused pretty
Speaker 5:  much primarily on track balls and input devices. So
Speaker 4:  I honestly find it fascinating because I think when keyboards really started
Speaker 4:  to develop as this kind of open source project that people were working
Speaker 4:  on, that made sense to me because it's relatively, relatively, I'm not
Speaker 4:  designing my own keyboard anytime soon, simple there's, you know, there's
Speaker 4:  a PCB there's, there's switches. It's, it's all pretty standard. But
Speaker 4:  with, with track balls, you have a lot of additional complexities there.
Speaker 4:  You have to track this ball. You've got these optical sensors. Like
Speaker 4:  that just seems like a lot of extra work for you.
Speaker 5:  The complexity is kind of a blessing and a curse, right? In the sense that
Speaker 5:  it's actually the, one of the most complicated things about the design work
Speaker 5:  is ever making everything fit together. Right? As you say, a keyboard is
Speaker 5:  a linear array of switches, and it's almost, I don't want to say it. I don't
Speaker 5:  want to oversimplify it, but it's, you know, it's a box and you jam some
Speaker 5:  switches inside.
Speaker 4:  I can build a keyboard very easily. I have my plebeian that have not yet
Speaker 4:  built it.
Speaker 5:  And you know, does designing a mouse, all the components are sort of meant
Speaker 5:  to be used in a context where you have control over them over the mechanisms
Speaker 5:  down to the like kind of microphone level, right? People expect injection
Speaker 5:  molded parts to be very accurate. And so in the context of what we're building,
Speaker 5:  something that anybody can kind of spread out on their desk and put together
Speaker 5:  and we can 3d print or they can 3d print for them because all of our designs
Speaker 5:  are designed in such a way that you should be able to just kind of use a,
Speaker 5:  sort of a bog standard 3d printer to produce this stuff. There's the whole
Speaker 5:  idea behind replicating it. Why would we make it special to our like super
Speaker 5:  cool, amazing secret print form. But that means that there's an extended
Speaker 5:  design process to make sure that all these technologies that are normally
Speaker 5:  designed for a sort of a high precision environment fit into this more
Speaker 5:  kind of loose set of manufacturing technologies. I remember
Speaker 5:  kind of early on in the design process, Phil would send me a bunch of
Speaker 5:  stills cause we have, we're not co located. We're located different spaces
Speaker 5:  and he would send me a bunch of stills and he would say, print these, this
Speaker 5:  is the final version of the classic. It's definitely going to work. And before
Speaker 5:  they would even come off the print bed, he would have new still files for
Speaker 5:  me because the design process just required so much iteration
Speaker 5:  to get everything precise and get everything right. So it's challenging.
Speaker 5:  It's challenging work for sure. Just to make sure everything fits together.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Well I know some people, a friend were talking to him
Speaker 4:  for, for the podcast even have done a lot of 3d printing with a really the
Speaker 4:  small one. That's just the ball. But, but these other ones that are, have
Speaker 4:  to need a little bit more precision, have you seen a lot of
Speaker 4:  like iteration from poopy users, like
Speaker 4:  making their own 3d designs for these things with four buttons on
Speaker 4:  them and a scroll wheel?
Speaker 5:  Not so much additional buttons, but the one that stands out to me is
Speaker 5:  there was a designer working out of the UK and he came up with a
Speaker 5:  design that used our, all of our trackball designs use roller
Speaker 5:  bearings. They kind of have some drawbacks they're noisy. They
Speaker 5:  can wiggle around. I think that they work great, especially with the balls
Speaker 5:  that we ship, but this designer was not super, super happy with them. So
Speaker 5:  he put in a new kind of bearing called a ball transfer unit, which
Speaker 5:  has no theoretical resistance in any direction they're
Speaker 5:  supposed to roll forever basically. And he basically
Speaker 5:  redid the design for the entire top shell, right from
Speaker 5:  the ground up, including these ball transfer units. And that's probably
Speaker 5:  the, the biggest amount of rework that I've seen done on it.
Speaker 5:  And it's really very different.
Speaker 4:  Do you think you're going to see more of that? Like more people kind of as,
Speaker 4:  as poopie grows in popularity? Hopefully
Speaker 5:  I hope so as well on the software side, the software side actually is
Speaker 5:  where it really, really took off because for a while there
Speaker 5:  we were the only ones who were involved in, in writing firmware foreign and
Speaker 5:  making sure that it was accessible. And then as soon as the developers from
Speaker 5:  Q and K got involved, it was, it was like watching a monster, transformed
Speaker 5:  a life because I don't think we were involved at all apart from
Speaker 5:  just chipping into, into the code every once in a while or doing,
Speaker 5:  answering a few questions. But that was really amazing to see just how
Speaker 5:  the community took that forward. There's all sorts of weird stuff, right?
Speaker 5:  There's you can, you can scroll with, with a ball and then there was
Speaker 5:  somebody ported it to this there's this thing on QM key called via. Yep.
Speaker 5:  Which allows you to remap buttons without having to reprogram the device.
Speaker 5:  And so somebody went and did that. Now you can remap all the buttons on every
Speaker 5:  plumpy product, I guess the ones that have it, cause the nano it doesn't
Speaker 5:  have any buttons. There's a bunch of other, oh, somebody like did something
Speaker 5:  to the scroll wheel where it made it more  to it. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Because all our scroll wheels they're smooth.
Speaker 4:  And so this gives like the little notches.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, exactly. That one involved the use of a paper clip, a very creative
Speaker 5:  use of a paperclip. I was extremely impressed. That was something. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  The thing we were always hoping for was by making everything as accessible
Speaker 5:  as we possibly could. Then if anyone ever saw a need, they would fix
Speaker 5:  it and they would open source it themselves. I saw someone who
Speaker 5:  wanted to put in, normally the ball that we shipped with is
Speaker 5:  1.7, five inches for the classic. And they wanted to use
Speaker 5:  a track ball, Explorer ball. I don't know why, but they wanted to use one.
Speaker 5:  And it's 1.8, one eight inches. And they redesigned the entire top
Speaker 5:  just to accommodate that ball and open sourced it. And it's available. Like
Speaker 5:  you can, you can print it right now if you want. So really amazing to see
Speaker 4:  That's very, very cool. We talked a little bit about the community. It sounds
Speaker 4:  like poopy. I'm never going to get stopped. Like giggling when I
Speaker 4:  say poopy, I'm so sorry.
Speaker 5:  You know what? It fills my heart with joy. Every time someone laughs at the
Speaker 5:  name, I love it.
Speaker 4:  Where is your community? Is it primarily on Reddit? Is it on discord?
Speaker 5:  It's primarily on Reddit. It's just been a place that's been really welcoming
Speaker 5:  truth. Be told there has been some feedback that has not been helpful, but
Speaker 5:  it's balanced by the unbelievable wealth of knowledge and
Speaker 5:  experience that people bring. And it's definitely pushed everything forward.
Speaker 5:  We'd never would have gotten involved with QM. K if we hadn't been on Reddit
Speaker 5:  and it's just been it's, it's been really incredible
Speaker 4:  Was Reddit and being there and developing that community, always kind of
Speaker 4:  part of the plan.
Speaker 5:  I wouldn't say it was part of the planet kind of happened by accident. And
Speaker 5:  I think Phil was working on the top for the classic. This was
Speaker 5:  maybe two or three months after we decided to team up and he just showed
Speaker 5:  it to me and I thought it looked amazing. And I said, you know what? I'm
Speaker 5:  just going to post this picture on Reddit. I know that there's a track ball,
Speaker 5:  separate. I'm just going to post it there. And there wasn't really any thought
Speaker 5:  or plan behind it. And I did and people were really
Speaker 5:  excited about it and we just kept bringing more news and
Speaker 5:  more developments to Reddit. And the more that that happened, the more excited
Speaker 5:  people got. So yeah, it just kind of happened organically. We do like we
Speaker 5:  do new product design essentially. I don't want to say on Reddit more or
Speaker 5:  less on Reddit, you know, and I think that's, that's something we do that.
Speaker 5:  Not really anyone else. I don't see anyone else doing that. You know, I've
Speaker 5:  got piles of half finished designs, just kind of sitting here and we
Speaker 5:  put them on Reddit. And as Colin said, we get a ton of feedback and it's
Speaker 5:  really helpful because people tell you what they want and they tell you what
Speaker 5:  they do. Not like
Speaker 4:  What's something that they truly do not like.
Speaker 5:  So a lot of the feedback that we're getting more recently is on our
Speaker 5:  headphones. So that's kinda what's top of mind, we frequently post a
Speaker 5:  frequency response. It's as close as you can get to a digitization of how
Speaker 5:  the headphones sound without actually putting them on your head. Right. People
Speaker 5:  are pretty picky about that one. They're like, ah, I don't like, I don't
Speaker 5:  like this part or this part seems not that good and
Speaker 4:  Very strong feelings about frequency, response curves
Speaker 5:  They do. But you know what, it's, it's been helping us focus on the sorts
Speaker 5:  of things to try and push ahead a little bit further. One of the things that
Speaker 5:  sticks out to me from track balls is so some of the things we make, we make
Speaker 5:  a left-handed version. Yes. Not all of them, but some of them, and that
Speaker 5:  vacuum that kind of time before there were left-handed options. People hated
Speaker 5:  that they hated that with a passion, just the sort of like lack
Speaker 5:  of left-handed option was just this thing that people really got stuck
Speaker 5:  on.
Speaker 4:  Do you guys think about these bigger companies and stuff that are still in
Speaker 4:  the track ball space? Like have you heard responses from them? Do you think
Speaker 4:  about like how your products may like make
Speaker 4:  them do things differently?
Speaker 5:  Almost never. We're we're so small compared to
Speaker 5:  the other. I mean, I think we ship in a year, what Logitech ships,
Speaker 5:  every like 25 minutes or something like that. So
Speaker 5:  I think it's less than that. It's like five minutes, maybe 15 minutes. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I would be very flattered if Kensington
Speaker 5:  decided that they needed to alter their business strategy because of what
Speaker 5:  we were doing somehow. I don't think there are any executives losing sleep
Speaker 5:  over there because of what we've done.
Speaker 4:  I mean, I think it is interesting that for the most part, the track ball
Speaker 4:  space, hasn't had a lot of movement. It hasn't had a lot of innovation. So
Speaker 4:  like, you guys are kind of pushing this space forward and that
Speaker 4:  respect and that you're saying, Hey, there's still an audience here. There's
Speaker 4:  still people who care about this and make it cooler, make new
Speaker 4:  things.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I think especially with the way that we've positioned everything, you
Speaker 5:  know, trying to make it open source and, and using licenses that are
Speaker 5:  really friendly for open source. It'd be really awkward, I think
Speaker 5:  for, for a more traditional company to come in and, and
Speaker 4:  Start printing your designs,
Speaker 5:  Especially with the way that they're designed and everything. They're not
Speaker 5:  at all designed for traditional manufacturing, if a larger
Speaker 5:  company were to come in and start doing similar things, I think that it would
Speaker 5:  only be beneficial for people who are using track balls. It would mean that
Speaker 5:  there'd be more offerings on the table. And I'm like you said, you know,
Speaker 5:  there's, there hasn't been much innovation going on in the less than a while.
Speaker 5:  So maybe there's still room for, for new developments to be made.
Speaker 4:  No, it was just, it was nice to see like, oh, somebody is actually willing
Speaker 4:  to like, think about this and think about how maybe the way we
Speaker 4:  interact with our computers could be different. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I think kind of the real leap towards something really new,
Speaker 5:  it was Phil who originally was, he pitched me the idea for the nano and
Speaker 5:  he said, we have to do this. There's just no alternative. We have to do it.
Speaker 5:  I'll be perfectly, I didn't understand how it could possibly be
Speaker 5:  beneficial because it has no buttons. Right. It's just a ball. It's only
Speaker 5:  a ball. And by far it's our most popular kit they're flying off the
Speaker 5:  shelves. So, but that's a fantastic example of kind of being on
Speaker 5:  Reddit and seeing the community develop. Because I don't want to say that
Speaker 5:  you could just kind of look at a post history in a subreddit and just kind
Speaker 5:  of come away with the conclusion that this was a good idea, because I don't
Speaker 5:  think either of us had that feeling, it was more of a experiment, but it's
Speaker 5:  very much like we're close to the people who, who love our products. And
Speaker 5:  sometimes we can kind of get a sense for what they need before they need
Speaker 5:  it. And I don't want to go full Steve jobs on this and be like, we tell users
Speaker 5:  what they like, but there's very much like there's a
Speaker 5:  lot of value in being deeply connected to the people who love your products.
Speaker 5:  And we're really fortunate to have that.
Speaker 4:  I think what Colin and Phil really impressed on me more than anything else
Speaker 4:  is that the community is driving the company. As much as them after the
Speaker 4:  break, I'm going to talk with Chris person, a very active member of that
Speaker 4:  community who has made a trackball based around a pool cue ball
Speaker 4:  and is currently trying to make a track ball with a steel ball bearing instead
Speaker 4:  of a more traditional plastic ball. He's also the guy who introduced
Speaker 4:  me to  to begin with. So stay tuned,
Speaker 1:  Thanks to grin for supporting this episode. So you and your
Speaker 1:  business have finally taken the leap into influencer marketing. It's going
Speaker 1:  great. And you're excited to connect with your audience in a powerful new
Speaker 1:  way, but you've noticed you're spending a lot of time on busy work checking
Speaker 1:  to see if the creator has gotten your product, moving through a tangled web
Speaker 1:  of emails and DMS. And now you're wondering, Hey, did that
Speaker 1:  Instagram post they promised ever even go up influencer marketing
Speaker 1:  can be super effective, but not if it's a drain on your time. That's
Speaker 1:  where green comes in. Green is the number one creator management platform.
Speaker 1:  It helps you find and recruit the perfect ambassadors for your brand and
Speaker 1:  streamlines the communication process. You can collect all creator content
Speaker 1:  in one, easy to find place and track your return on investment and
Speaker 1:  mealtime influencer marketing. Doesn't have to be complicated. Grim
Speaker 1:  makes it simple. So you can treat your creators like your brand revolves
Speaker 1:  around them because in the creator economy, it does
Speaker 1:  influence our marketing is easier with grant. Find out why I
Speaker 1:  glenn.co that's GRI n.co
Speaker 4:  Hey, we're back. I think I mentioned this before on the verge cast, but the
Speaker 4:  reason I went and bought a poopy is because my friend, Chris person slid
Speaker 4:  into my Twitter DMS to talk about his own build. Naturally I had to beg him
Speaker 4:  to write about poopy for the Virgin and he did. And when he isn't in my
Speaker 4:  DMS, Chris runs the YouTube channel highlight reels, which finds and
Speaker 4:  highlights the weirdest clips for video games.
Speaker 6:  This is highlight reel for May 5th, 2022. And we're going to show you some
Speaker 6:  of the best recent clips from around the gaming world.
Speaker 4:  He felt like the right person to talk to because Chris is super active in
Speaker 4:  the pubic community. He understands the appeal, but he's also just been out
Speaker 4:  there building these things and he's collaborating with other community members
Speaker 4:  and he's 3d printing a whole lot of plastic. Let's talk to
Speaker 4:  Chris.
Speaker 4:  I was kind of excited to talk to you about this because the first time I
Speaker 4:  heard about poopy and about building your own track ball
Speaker 4:  was you to sending into my DMS on Twitter and being like, Hey,
Speaker 4:  Kranz, look at this cool thing. I found, look what I'm doing right now.
Speaker 4:  Like, do you remember just like assaulting my DMS
Speaker 4:  with it?
Speaker 6:  Okay. You're like one of four people I do that too, to make you feel less
Speaker 6:  special. But, but no, no. I do remember doing that.
Speaker 6:  I think I thought it was funny at first because I was like called gloopy
Speaker 6:  and it's like, Hey, check it out. Poopy. I'm not attract ball person initially.
Speaker 6:  Like I'm not one of those people. Who's just like really deep into using
Speaker 6:  it as my primary interface. But it's fascinating. Cause like in the nineties,
Speaker 6:  like kind of was pretty prevalent in a way that it simply isn't now.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. You know what I mean? Like you, you could see track balls. Like there
Speaker 6:  were normal people attract balls. It wasn't just this thing that like weirdos
Speaker 6:  had all the time
Speaker 4:  And now it's absolutely the weirdest. Like I say, this is a track
Speaker 4:  ball weirdo. Like I have suffered for years because
Speaker 4:  I love track balls. And I'm one of the few people I know that loves them
Speaker 4:  and I will defend them to the death. And you popped into my DMS and was like,
Speaker 4:  Hey, look at this cool track ball. And I was like, oh no, I have a problem.
Speaker 6:  Well, that's the thing is like to give a little background on what poopies
Speaker 6:  deal is. I think you need a little bit of context on keyboards, not too much,
Speaker 6:  but like the deal on like keyboard stuff recently is that
Speaker 6:  like, you know, okay. Yeah. People love mechanical keyboards. They'll have
Speaker 6:  clicky things of SWAT Cylons you'll have yada yada, yada. But like when you
Speaker 6:  get down to it, what really became the thing was that you could
Speaker 6:  do open source firmware. So you could just remap your keys. You can
Speaker 6:  do macros, you can do layers, which is really, really interesting. And you
Speaker 6:  can, you just need less keys to do the same thing and with less
Speaker 6:  movement. And so as time has gone on the
Speaker 6:  adaptability of not just one from where like QM K, which is the, the
Speaker 6:  kind of the standard, but like other ones like ZM, K like
Speaker 6:  various ones to like, you know, get it to work and Bluetooth and stuff like
Speaker 6:  that. All these open source things that make it. So you can do all this stuff
Speaker 6:  without installing a bunch of dumb crap on your computer. And so that it
Speaker 6:  can work on them on the processor and like not have to like be tethered to
Speaker 6:  a specific device. Right. And so taking that philosophy and then like going
Speaker 6:  into the like pointing space and being like, okay, but what if you did that
Speaker 6:  for appointing device? Poopy makes like a mouse. They make a thumb
Speaker 6:  ball. They make all these different things. And what got me into the
Speaker 6:  idea that I could just make this first. It was like my friend being like,
Speaker 6:  oh, people make modifications to their plebe. That's that was the first
Speaker 6:  thing they said, oh yeah. He's like, I got a 3d printer. We can just print
Speaker 6:  this and you can change. You can add what's called a BT or ball transfer
Speaker 6:  unit,
Speaker 4:  Little balls that support the big track ball and
Speaker 4:  roll across each other.
Speaker 6:  It's a silly name for something. That's basically like a cylinder with a
Speaker 6:  bunch of ball bearings in it, holding up one ball, bearing making it so it
Speaker 6:  can rotate really smoothly. And then you can put the track ball you have
Speaker 6:  on them. So somebody made a model for that. And I was like, oh, that's pretty
Speaker 6:  cool. My friend 3d printed that out to me, we were getting really into
Speaker 6:  it, you know? Oh, you know, you can strip out the lube and put new
Speaker 6:  lubrication in, you know, all this sort of stuff,
Speaker 4:  Customize the crap out of it.
Speaker 6:  Yay. So basically it's like, I got this, this little track ball. Then you
Speaker 6:  go and call the nano, which is the smallest one. And that was the thing that
Speaker 6:  I think was like, oh, okay, God damn, I gotta get this because it is like
Speaker 6:  $40 Canadian, 45. So it's really cheap for what you're getting, you
Speaker 6:  know? And then it fits right into the middle of I'm one of these people with
Speaker 6:  like a split keyboard. So it makes it so that I have this like little tiny
Speaker 6:  pointing device for doing little tiny things. Making sort of have to reach
Speaker 6:  over to my mouse every time. And then from there I got that really liked,
Speaker 6:  it got way more use out of it. Did the modification. And while I was still
Speaker 6:  doing the modification stuff found out about this guy named Jay Fidor,
Speaker 6:  he did this thing where he created his own platform, his own
Speaker 6:  like PCB for something similar and then just prototyped a bunch
Speaker 6:  of them. And at this point I had already gotten into the fact that
Speaker 6:  you can just go to JCL PCB and like all PCB and these like
Speaker 6:  PCB manufacturers
Speaker 4:  And just order a PCB
Speaker 6:  And just order stuff that like people put on GitHub,
Speaker 4:  Like, do you have to solder it yourself when you get it? Or do you just like,
Speaker 4:  it comes you soldered.
Speaker 6:  What you can do is you can upload like the bill of materials and then what's
Speaker 6:  called a component placement file or component placement list rather. And
Speaker 6:  they'll just like, do it for you. It's going to cost you more money. I think
Speaker 6:  I get, do like five of them for 30 bucks and then gave them to a bunch of
Speaker 6:  people I screwed up though, because I didn't recognize, cause I missed a
Speaker 6:  couple of parts and it added a whole extra journey to it. But yeah, no,
Speaker 6:  it's, it's actually pretty easy. As long as you have the files, as long as
Speaker 6:  you kind of know what you're doing, did you get a circuit board printed out
Speaker 6:  as long as it's open source, as long as they have the parts you're you're
Speaker 6:  fine.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I, I don't even know how to like start there cause I'm
Speaker 4:  still, I haven't really sought her. Poopy is going to be my first big
Speaker 4:  project. I got very excited when you, when you sent all of this to me, because
Speaker 4:  while you don't like track balls until this moment, I've always loved them.
Speaker 4:  I was very upset when everybody for a long time kind of Logitech and
Speaker 4:  other kickball makers can sink and kind of shied away from the space
Speaker 4:  and everything they were doing was either really focused on
Speaker 4:  graphic artists and these big professionals and not to people who were just
Speaker 4:  like using it to play video games and fart around on the internet. And they
Speaker 4:  all moved away from that. And I was like, oh no, what am I going to? Like,
Speaker 4:  I, there was one manufacturer it's just logic tech, making a FUM track ball.
Speaker 4:  And I was like, what am I going to do with my life? I went and bought like
Speaker 4:  four of them so that I wouldn't have to worry about them. And now like we're
Speaker 4:  starting to see track balls become a thing again. And poopy is maybe not
Speaker 4:  at the forefront of it because it's, it's, you know, this big open source
Speaker 4:  project, but it's really like providing these cool
Speaker 4:  opportunities and these cool, just like designs that I wouldn't even think
Speaker 4:  of. Like I that's what I, I went and spent so much money on poopy just cause
Speaker 4:  I was like, oh, I've never even thought of using this design. I wonder what
Speaker 4:  this is like, and it's cheap.
Speaker 6:  There's other projects like this that had done it before. Like there's one
Speaker 6:  called the odd ball. That's a 3d printed integrated we track
Speaker 6:  ball. Yeah. Yeah. It's a track ball inside a keyboard. It's a split keyboard.
Speaker 6:  If you look up the oddball keyboard, the person like printed it out, sanded
Speaker 6:  it, cry locks day at primer, all that stuff like that. And then they printed
Speaker 6:  out their own PCB. That's just using like, I think five volt logic or something
Speaker 6:  like that. And it's pretty straight forward. It works with an iterated
Speaker 6:  and see you and stuff like that. But the thing is like, it's a combination
Speaker 6:  of two things. One, it's the idea that technology isn't fun. You know what
Speaker 6:  I mean? Like there's a lot of joy that has been taking it out of using the
Speaker 6:  computer, being on the computer sucks a lot of the time. And so what
Speaker 6:  can I do to make this mine? What can I do to
Speaker 6:  really interact with it in a way that hasn't been since like radio
Speaker 6:  shack days do demystify the process between what's between me and the
Speaker 6:  computer even more, but also realization that stuff is really cheap on Allie
Speaker 6:  express. Like if I wanted to, you know, you could disassemble your mouse,
Speaker 6:  dishonor, the mouse clicks and then put new, better
Speaker 6:  micro switches in there. You know what I mean? And that's not an, a difficult
Speaker 6:  thing. I was talking with somebody on a discord server I'm on who made a
Speaker 6:  board called the chunky, which uses two Cirque track pads,
Speaker 6:  which are the track pads that the steam controller uses. And it's like, okay,
Speaker 6:  yeah. Now you can use like dual touch pads on this and like weird
Speaker 6:  rotary coders. It's just like the ways in which you can just get
Speaker 6:  granular with like, you know exactly how you want to
Speaker 6:  use this. And you know, it's, it's, you're still just talking to a computer,
Speaker 6:  but it's also that and like the fact that I never want to install razor
Speaker 6:  sinaps ever again, if I can avoid it.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I think that's like a really interesting part of this because I got
Speaker 4:  a Mac studio. Listeners will know this, we've talked about it a bunch, but
Speaker 4:  I got this Mac studio. I love it. It restarts itself every
Speaker 4:  day for some unknown reason that I'm hoping will sort itself out.
Speaker 4:  And every single time the logic tech software pops up
Speaker 4:  because that's a track ball I use and it's like, Hey, do you want to go change
Speaker 4:  some preferences and logic tech? And I'm like, no, if I didn't do it the
Speaker 4:  last 12 times, it's restarted this week, why would I do it today?
Speaker 4:  And logic tech, razor, they're all like trying to get
Speaker 4:  in front of your eyeballs all the time. So I guess I think, well, let's put
Speaker 4:  really obnoxious software on people's computers and these keyboard
Speaker 4:  makers and track ball makers are saying, wait, actually that's bad.
Speaker 4:  Let's stop that. Just use the device.
Speaker 6:  I think the first one, one of them that figures out that there's a market
Speaker 6:  for that. If any of them do yeah. Would be smart. Yes. But
Speaker 6:  I don't necessarily know if they are, it's not within their interest to do
Speaker 6:  that. And it's a really minor community of people who would be like, I really
Speaker 6:  want to edit the text file on this firmware to like
Speaker 6:  able to like change the acceleration curve on how this, or give it an
Speaker 6:  acceleration curve. You know, that's a very minor group of people
Speaker 4:  You say it's minor, but you you've talked a lot about these discord groups
Speaker 4:  and these Reddit groups where there's a lot of people doing this
Speaker 4:  and really interested in, you know, the mechanical keyboard Reddit started
Speaker 4:  when I joined it in like 20 12, 20 13 or something. It was a few thousand
Speaker 4:  people and now it's over a million. And I think we all kind of
Speaker 4:  underestimate that market and that interest because there's just not a
Speaker 4:  lot of easily accessible products that feed
Speaker 4:  that. But I do want to kind of poke at you and discord and
Speaker 4:  Reddit. You and I are both on those boards. I am absolutely a lurker. You're
Speaker 4:  much more active in it. How much of Reddit fuels
Speaker 4:  this, this kind of hobby for you?
Speaker 6:  It's a little bit of that. And a little bit of like asking around on discord.
Speaker 6:  I think the discord element is a little cause like I'm in a bunch of them
Speaker 6:  and I think it got everyone in this one, discord I'm in the
Speaker 6:  Absalom, Erica gen one, every Jen's a project that makes it
Speaker 6:  so it's easier to quickly prototype keyboard by storing it
Speaker 6:  all as w YAML code. Okay. So it makes it
Speaker 6:  easy to be like, oh, I want to move that column down. And then it just generates
Speaker 6:  the PCB by changing a few easy to read parameters that
Speaker 6:  anybody can do. I just, just kept talking about track balls and now like
Speaker 6:  a lot of them are more trackable people, but one of them is definitely had
Speaker 6:  already had like five poopies.
Speaker 4:  It's just the two of you and like your own little smaller discord.
Speaker 6:  It's a small place. You know what I mean? It's actually pretty small. I think
Speaker 6:  a lot of there's a lot of lurkers the people at post it's. So it's not that
Speaker 6:  many people after I posted the article, like three different people DM me
Speaker 6:  and they're like, okay, can you please, like, do you have any of those? Do
Speaker 6:  you have any of those PCP? Can you send it to me? Is it okay if I get, you
Speaker 6:  know, and I was just like, man, you can just do it yourself. And I know one
Speaker 6:  thing I will say is also like recently raspberry PI put out the, the P the
Speaker 6:  Pico and the , which is a microprocessor, very, very
Speaker 6:  powerful and very cheap, importantly in the keyboard community is
Speaker 6:  like still trying to wrap their head around it. But you're literally seeing
Speaker 6:  like, people who do this in their spare time, like on these discords like
Speaker 6:  talking about, Hey, if anyone does anyone want to mess around with this and
Speaker 6:  then asking problems? Like, there's a big, long conversation today in one
Speaker 6:  of the words I was in about like kales, pseudo monopoly, over
Speaker 6:  low profile switches and how like, well, maybe what, what about Gator on,
Speaker 6:  you know, and stuff like that. And so people are always like tinkering around
Speaker 6:  and you actually see it pretty iteratively. You see it a little more like
Speaker 6:  the results on Reddit, but in the comments. And then in discourse, you actually
Speaker 6:  see the process a little bit more. And I think it's really interesting cause
Speaker 6:  it's like, yeah, I feel like you just joined one of these,
Speaker 4:  You know, it's really interesting because if lot the times we think about
Speaker 4:  social media and we think primarily like YouTube or Twitter,
Speaker 4:  or even Twitch as these places that are developing
Speaker 4:  fandoms, developing these communities. And we don't think as much about
Speaker 4:  Reddit except for when we were talking about like the Donald, you know, sub,
Speaker 4:  but discord too, it sounds like is really becoming this place where people
Speaker 4:  are gathering and talking about these things and communing in a
Speaker 4:  way that we haven't like seen in a while. Is that right?
Speaker 6:  Telegram,
Speaker 4:  Telegram. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  There's a lot of those guys are Russian or Eastern European and they're just
Speaker 6:  like, love talking about that stuff on there. You know what I mean? It's
Speaker 6:  I don't, I'm not a telegram person nor do I intend to be, but yeah.
Speaker 4:  Film poopy through discourt through a friend on discourt
Speaker 4:  or no,
Speaker 6:  I found  through looking up track balls, I think
Speaker 6:  on Reddit. And then like, I ended up talking to people on
Speaker 6:  discords and stuff like that. And the, the J fitter stuff was like, one of
Speaker 6:  my friends who helped me 3d print out the thing. And that's the other thing
Speaker 6:  is that 3d printing got way easier. I used to look at 3d printing as this
Speaker 6:  thing that like, cause, cause not only did I do the poopy, I did this other
Speaker 6:  second track ball using the Jeff adore ones to, to button one. It has a full,
Speaker 6:  like I got a black cube ball, like an amaranth one
Speaker 6:  to
Speaker 4:  Darkness.
Speaker 6:  It's enormous. It's a really big track. I usually don't use it that much
Speaker 6:  because it's like, it's too big. And cause I haven't found a way to do a
Speaker 6:  BTU model on it, but you know, three, depending not only got cheaper, you
Speaker 6:  can have and just like do it online. Like the other day, somebody uploaded
Speaker 6:  a bunch of like weird sculpted key caps that they printed out in residence.
Speaker 6:  So they look like teeth and they're like, oh yeah, I just got a, a printing
Speaker 6:  service, just print it for me. And I'm like, all right, I'm going to get
Speaker 6:  that printed out in nylon. So I'm getting these key caps that are
Speaker 6:  meant for low-profile keyboards printed out in like, I think what is it like
Speaker 6:  an 11 PLF? And I forget what it's called, but it's this like scratchy
Speaker 6:  weird. Sandpapery nylon, that's a process called
Speaker 6:  MGF printing and you can just get this stuff sent to you. Like you don't
Speaker 6:  need to like buy a Prusa or like one of these 3d
Speaker 6:  printers, you either have to have a friend who has it, or you don't mind
Speaker 6:  like going online to, to like a service that'll do it or
Speaker 6:  cut acrylic for you.
Speaker 4:  I'm kind of curious about that because my assumption with 3d printing, a
Speaker 4:  lot of the times was there was a certain amount of talent and experience
Speaker 4:  to getting it to do go, right, right. Like you have to print it just so,
Speaker 4:  and then you have to like, make sure you remove it. So it doesn't break.
Speaker 4:  Do you find yourself having to go and reprint things that, that you do through
Speaker 4:  a service
Speaker 6:  In this case? I, this is the first time I've used craft cloud, I think is
Speaker 6:  the name of it. I think all, all three PS, the company that owns them and
Speaker 6:  they're like a front end for like several printing services. So it's like
Speaker 6:  a comparison shopper in the case of the, the ones that I had a friend of
Speaker 6:  mine who printed it out and knew what a good print looks like, did it so
Speaker 6:  that there was that element of it. But in this case you just shop around
Speaker 6:  for like, you know, SLA resin printing or whatever, stuff like that. I
Speaker 6:  was pricing out how much it would cost to print something out in titanium.
Speaker 6:  Not as much as you would think. I think a space bar is like 130 bucks, but
Speaker 6:  yeah, I dunno. I guess I guess the, the, the point is what was
Speaker 6:  nice because of the access to the tools is increasingly less
Speaker 6:  so. And I think that the saturation for things like 3d printing
Speaker 6:  and the saturation for things like laser cutters, those
Speaker 6:  things are getting such that like, it's really, really
Speaker 6:  easy to do. And like other people have already done a lot of the work and
Speaker 6:  that's something I'd like to stress. Like I'm working on a board right now.
Speaker 6:  Like all this stuff is stuff that other people made and that I was just
Speaker 6:  like, oh, I could just get that printed out. What if I did that? But I did
Speaker 6:  it in a different color. And that's the thing is people are just like, they
Speaker 6:  don't want the money. I mean, sometimes they want money for it and obviously
Speaker 6:  pay them if they, if they, you know, if they, but if it's open source and
Speaker 6:  they're like go to town, they're pretty nice about it. Cause this is just
Speaker 6:  their hobby. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Well look, the poopy w guys, they just print it out, like in their
Speaker 4:  home or whatever and send it to you. I ordered it. And like I said, these
Speaker 4:  are the colors I want. And one day I just got it all in like just a regular
Speaker 4:  Ziploc bag, nothing fancy, like in a box wrapped in some
Speaker 4:  like Canadian newspaper. And it was great. And I was just like, oh, this
Speaker 4:  is just like some person who really just like digs track balls like I
Speaker 4:  do. And that was a nice feeling.
Speaker 6:  But that's the thing. You see the people who run these shops that you've
Speaker 6:  liked know like in discord, they're like, oh, that's the guy who writes,
Speaker 6:  who runs the MK ultra. It's the name of the low-profile keyboard store. Okay.
Speaker 4:  I mean, that's the way I felt when I saw you drop your truck ball and
Speaker 4:  the sharp Paul subreddit, I was like, oh, Hey, I know that guy. It was nice.
Speaker 4:  This is what I was feeling.
Speaker 6:  It's a series of, Hey, I know that guys. And like, and, and they're really
Speaker 6:  nice. And like, you know, just don't be a Dick.
Speaker 6:  It's pretty straight forward
Speaker 4:  A motto. We should always all live by. Well, thank you, Chris,
Speaker 4:  for chatting with us about poopy and about track balls and 3d
Speaker 4:  printing and subreddits and discord. I mean, we just covered everything
Speaker 4:  today. So that was really awesome.
Speaker 6:  It was nice. Thank you. It was nice talking to you.
Speaker 4:  I want to thank Phil and Collin and Chris again for talking to me on the
Speaker 4:  show. And I want to thank you for listening. I think a lot of the time here
Speaker 4:  at the verge and just in the gadget community in general, we get hung up
Speaker 4:  on what big companies like apple or logic. I mean, heck even Kensington are
Speaker 4:  doing, these are the companies building the devices we interact with daily,
Speaker 4:  but as big as their market share might be in one category. They don't really
Speaker 4:  actually own the whole market. There's a lot of us, including again,
Speaker 4:  most of the verge. And I bet most of the people listening to this
Speaker 4:  podcast right now who want more from a gadget than just the sleek mod
Speaker 4:  free apple experience. I like to build things. And when it comes to gadgets,
Speaker 4:  that's largely left me building a lot of servers, gaming desktops and
Speaker 4:  keyboards. But as Chris noted, 3d printing has started to change things.
Speaker 4:  There's more access to components now than ever before. You can build your
Speaker 4:  own track baller mouse now. And it sounds like you might even be able to
Speaker 4:  build your own headphones too. There are companies like poopy out there,
Speaker 4:  building not the things themselves, but the communities that actually want
Speaker 4:  to build them. I don't know if the poopy subreddit is going to be quite as
Speaker 4:  hopping as the mechanical keyboard separated in eight years, but I don't
Speaker 4:  think this fandom is going to disappear as 3d printing improves as
Speaker 4:  access to other materials improve. I think we're going to see more companies
Speaker 4:  doing what gloopy is doing. The probably without the catchy name.
Speaker 4:  If you have thoughts about this episode, I'm Alex H Kranz on Twitter, or
Speaker 4:  you can email us@vergecastattheverge.com. We really do
Speaker 4:  read all of them and we really appreciate all of them. Our regular
Speaker 4:  Vergecast show will be here on and then next Tuesday
Speaker 4:  I'll return for the final episode of this miniseries around creators. It's
Speaker 4:  going to be all about the community modern game controllers to make them
Speaker 4:  more accessible. So stay tuned have fun. This episode of the
Speaker 4:  Vergecast is produced by me, Alex Cranz lead producer, Liam James
Speaker 4:  in senior audio director, Andrew Marino.
Speaker 1:  This episode has been brought to you by grin. Top creators are
Speaker 1:  already using and loving your product. So why haven't you partnered with
Speaker 1:  them so they can share that love with their audience. Grin helps you bring
Speaker 1:  creators on board is the ultimate champions of your brand. You can
Speaker 1:  recruit ship sample products and track creator content. All in one
Speaker 1:  place. Grin is the number one influencer management platform,
Speaker 1:  helping e-commerce brands connect with their audience through the power of
Speaker 1:  creator partnerships. Find out how grin can help you grow your
Speaker 1:  brand. Watch the demo@grin.co that's, GRI
Speaker 1:  n.co.