# Transcript
ID: 8a66ce40-3581-11ed-af29-990ad6c3e1de
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Reviews of the iPhone 14 Pro, Apple Watch Series 8, and more
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/2515865499387378828/-1358841367591496221/s93290-US-5035s-1663306502.mp3
Description: Nilay Patel, David Pierce, and Alex Cranz discuss The Verge's reviews of the iPhone 14 Pro, iPhone 14, and Apple Watch Series 8.
Speaker 1:  With no fees or minimums banking with capital one is the easiest decision
Speaker 1:  in the history of decisions. Even easier than deciding to listen to another
Speaker 1:  episode of your favorite podcast with no overdraft fees. Is it
Speaker 1:  even a decision that's banking reimagine what's in your wallet term
Speaker 1:  supply. See capital one.com/bank capital one, a member
Speaker 1:  F D I C.
Speaker 3:  Be exuberant. Be electrifying, be iconic
Speaker 3:  in the all electric order. Yours 2023 lyric
Speaker 3:  orders of full go to cadillac.com and complete a pre-order for model year
Speaker 3:  24 to be among the first to order model year 24 when available.
Speaker 2:  Hello
Speaker 4:  And welcome to our chest. The flagship podcast of
Speaker 4:  the dynamic island. First of all, I wanna call it my friend
Speaker 4:  Joanna stern for actually taking a canoe to an island
Speaker 4:  for her review video
Speaker 5:  Was excellent
Speaker 4:  Every now and again. Joanna's like, what if I just do a little
Speaker 4:  bit more than everyone else would possibly do? And the
Speaker 4:  fact that she did her entire video on a small island with a canoe,
Speaker 6:  Did she initially pitch like a bigger island?
Speaker 4:  Well, no. Well, okay. First of all, I'm your friend Eli. That's Alex Kranz.
Speaker 4:  Hi, David Pierce is here.
Speaker 5:  Hi, I live on the dynamic island. It's a, it's a mindset more than a real
Speaker 5:  island, but Joanna found the real island.
Speaker 4:  Her video producer obviously brought a drone. Yeah, I think it's Kenny is
Speaker 4:  her video producer. I'm pretty sure he is one of me this video. And so her
Speaker 4:  point was that the island gets bigger and smaller with the tide. And so they
Speaker 4:  have the video. Wow. The tide making the island bigger and smaller.
Speaker 4:  Just like the dynamic island on the phone.
Speaker 6:  I love this so
Speaker 4:  Much, which is, is just very good. It's a very good joke. It
Speaker 5:  Also straight up would be an apple thing to do to make the dynamic island
Speaker 5:  slightly smaller with the tides, like, like a localized dynamic
Speaker 5:  island that like changes colors as the sunsets and rises.
Speaker 5:  You can
Speaker 6:  Always know the tides. Yeah. Looking at your phone.
Speaker 5:  Whatever happened to that Steven Spielberg show that was only supposed to
Speaker 5:  be available at night on apple TV. Do you guys remember
Speaker 4:  This? No, that was on quibi though. It
Speaker 5:  Was on quibi. Okay. That makes more sense.
Speaker 4:  Okay. And they never built the technology to do it WMP but he was
Speaker 4:  like, I made a horror show. And so you have to watch it at night and it's
Speaker 4:  like, yeah, that's
Speaker 5:  On your phone
Speaker 4:  Constantly turning your phone. And they announced it was such fanfare.
Speaker 4:  Oh
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Yes. Right. It's like the show is only available in the middle and it was
Speaker 4:  very much like that's how a lot of TV worked for quite a
Speaker 4:  long time actually was we only watch on at night
Speaker 4:  for 30 minutes once a week,
Speaker 5:  Put that show in the dynamic island is what I'm saying. That's that's where
Speaker 4:  Quibi goes. Yeah, no. If apple did the tide sensor thing, they, they would
Speaker 4:  be like, we have built a custom array of tide sensing
Speaker 4:  robots,
Speaker 7:  Monitors
Speaker 4:  The coast of California. And that is constantly in
Speaker 4:  a very privacy respecting way. Constantly beaming tight information to your
Speaker 4:  phone
Speaker 4:  all. So a lot time this week, indeed, we
Speaker 4:  reviewed the iPhones 14. We also have, he
Speaker 4:  reviewed the apple watch series eight Iowas 16 is out David
Speaker 4:  reviewed that Sony brought out the place in shin VR, two
Speaker 4:  Google canceled, more stuff. We also, our new website
Speaker 4:  launched, which we did a whole podcast about that came out yesterday, but
Speaker 4:  it's like two days later, three days later told news it's happened on Tuesday.
Speaker 4:  I'm very tired.
Speaker 5:  You've also been talking about the website nonstop for, I mean, as long as
Speaker 5:  I've been at the verge and potentially much longer than that.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Do you want to talk more about the website? How are you on website talk?
Speaker 4:  Here's what I'll say. So the podcast David made with me and the Tara
Speaker 4:  and Matt from our product team, we did that like before it went out.
Speaker 4:  So like, what I will say is now the things out, I think we have a lot of
Speaker 4:  people who make products in our audience. You have no idea how it's gonna
Speaker 4:  go. Right. You just have to, like, I've been looking at this website for
Speaker 4:  six months. I've been reading our site exclusively in these designs for like
Speaker 4:  two months. And you know, the first wave of feedback to everything is
Speaker 4:  like, fuck you change it back. Like, that's just the way life goes. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And so we were expecting it and we certainly got that. And I think those
Speaker 4:  people tend to amplify one another, especially on Twitter, the social
Speaker 4:  network that I'm trying to escape with our new design. So if you're
Speaker 4:  tweeting at me, change it back, I can just get your headlines on Twitter.
Speaker 4:  It's like, yeah. I mean, I'm, that is the dynamic
Speaker 4:  I am fighting against. I'm fighting against the hostility of this platform.
Speaker 4:  We are together as a family on the flip side, you know, a couple days later,
Speaker 4:  we're starting to get way more notes. I'm getting notes in my emails. I'm
Speaker 4:  getting notes on Twitter or we're getting notes across our team. It's starting
Speaker 4:  to click for people. So like you can open us first thing in the morning
Speaker 4:  and see a bunch of cool stuff. And you can check us once at night
Speaker 4:  and see a bunch of cool stuff. Yep. And that's like, yeah,
Speaker 4:  we didn't, we, we didn't get it. Right. We don't think it's perfect. It's
Speaker 4:  not done. We should change some things. And we will like, that's
Speaker 4:  like how it's gonna go. And I, here's what I will say to you, to everyone.
Speaker 4:  Apple made you use iOS seven for one year.
Speaker 4:  They're gonna ship stage manager to a lot of people
Speaker 4:  and it's gonna be like that for one year. Like we're gonna change
Speaker 4:  our site faster than that. So just like breathe,
Speaker 4:  we wanted to try some things. Some of our site is like the
Speaker 4:  most cutting edge web development you can do.
Speaker 4:  And maybe it's a little too cutting edge. Maybe we need to back it down a
Speaker 4:  couple steps. But the main thing, which is did I just publish
Speaker 4:  the tube filter top 50 that I look at once a week
Speaker 4:  to our site in five seconds and point out that the number of
Speaker 4:  channels in the top 50 that are primarily YouTube shorts channels keeps
Speaker 4:  growing every week. And then that was done in four minutes. And I got to
Speaker 4:  share our audience with tube filter, which is a great resource and not
Speaker 4:  have to overdo it and have that be on our, yeah, I got to do that. And like,
Speaker 4:  if we can just do that a little bit more and make it
Speaker 4:  valuable for people to check one more time a day and not have the toxicity
Speaker 4:  of social media, I think we're gonna be fine. And so, yeah, we're gonna tweak
Speaker 4:  the colors and fix the breakers. And if we're gonna do all the things we're
Speaker 4:  gonna keep blurple blurple is deeply important to a lot of people blurple
Speaker 4:  is extremely, you know, but the here's what I think the main thing we have
Speaker 4:  to change is people keep saying there's too many fonts.
Speaker 4:  There's only three fonts. What you are really reacting to is that the
Speaker 4:  display of regular articles and the display of the quick posts
Speaker 4:  are too different. So we actually just need to make them look more the same.
Speaker 4:  And I that's like a pretty easy change, but we have to do it. But like, I
Speaker 4:  think once you make that change and it's just, there's more visual consistency,
Speaker 4:  I think we're gonna be fun.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And I will say the thing that's been the most fun for me the last few
Speaker 5:  days is like way more of our slack
Speaker 5:  is now on our website, which I think is very cool. Like I, I went on vacation
Speaker 5:  in August and I got yelled at for being in slack. And I realized one of the
Speaker 5:  reasons I keep opening slack is because we have this channel called goods
Speaker 5:  tweet because I think there's just to be one called good tweets. That's now
Speaker 5:  dead. So now there's one called goods tweet. And there's just like a
Speaker 5:  long running list of like funny tweets in that channel. And I
Speaker 5:  literally check it on purpose because I like it. And it makes me happy. And
Speaker 5:  it's like, we've just built venues to put that stuff on our website, which
Speaker 5:  was the point it's like, our job is to like see cool stuff on the internet.
Speaker 5:  And we want to give you more of it in public. And people are just having
Speaker 5:  a blast with it. It's just so much fun to do. It's great. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  It's just, it's fun for our staff to be a part of our community and
Speaker 4:  doing it on other people's platforms seems self defeating.
Speaker 4:  So we are gonna try to do it on our own and yes, that's a big change and
Speaker 4:  yes, the whole site, isn't just a list of headlines anymore. But we, we think
Speaker 4:  this is a, like, there are so many ways to get lists of our headlines.
Speaker 4:  Like infinite, you can build custom RSS feeds for days. There's a
Speaker 4:  page on our website. That is one decade old. We'll put a link
Speaker 4:  in the show notes about how to build custom RSS feeds outta the verge. It
Speaker 4:  all still works. Yeah. We've been committed to RSS for one, if you are
Speaker 4:  listening to this show, you know that we've been committed to RSS at a DNA
Speaker 4:  level for like one decade and we're gonna keep doing it. And we're making
Speaker 4:  RSS feed for quick, all the stuff. If you want those views, you can get them.
Speaker 4:  You can just follow us on Twitter. We just tweet all the headlines every
Speaker 4:  day, but we're gonna try something else on our own platform. So like I said,
Speaker 4:  we'll iterate. I'm more pleased. We made everybody talk about a
Speaker 4:  website in 2022. Yeah. That's like the spiritual victory of making
Speaker 4:  everybody talk about a website in 2022 is very high. The
Speaker 4:  reacting to the complaints about people wanting the website to be more like
Speaker 4:  a direct injection RSS feed to the brain. Fine.
Speaker 4:  But like, I'm, I'm happy that people are reconsidering the value of the web
Speaker 4:  in 2022. We've we've accomplished our first.
Speaker 5:  And if you read the verge on a 40 inch ultra wide monitor, and you think
Speaker 5:  that the column of the verge is too small, please just know that we hear
Speaker 5:  you because we all have giant weird, crazy monitors too. And we hear you.
Speaker 5:  Most people use cell phones
Speaker 6:  Like half our staff has like the ultra wides.
Speaker 6:  Sean Hollister has like his, his monitor is as big as his desk.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  What does it look like on the, on the, that crazy Samsung thing? That's
Speaker 5:  11 feet tall. Oh
Speaker 4:  My gosh. It's the vertical curve and the one, it looks great, man. That's
Speaker 4:  just a verge hugging. Yes.
Speaker 6:  Like that's what it's built for. They actually built it for us. That's a
Speaker 4:  Surprise. We started with the, the two use. We start what we St. We
Speaker 4:  shipped a product, right? Like we started with the phone view port, cuz that's
Speaker 4:  most people. And we did like this standard laptop view port, cuz that's almost
Speaker 4:  everybody else we'll get there.
Speaker 6:  Where's my EIN view and my iPad view.
Speaker 6:  That's
Speaker 4:  All I want. I'm just saying I, I, apple needs to use iOS seven for one year.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Just take a breath. We're gonna be fine.
Speaker 4:  All right. Speaking of apple phones, we have phones a
Speaker 5:  Lot. Yeah. You reviewed the pro, which I feel like is like clearly the most
Speaker 5:  interesting of the phones. Like we didn't review the plus. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Allison's review of the iPhone. 14 was very much. It's very funny. You should
Speaker 4:  watch it. It's very good.
Speaker 6:  Her video is extremely good.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I mean it's the same phone. Yeah. Only now
Speaker 4:  you can tell you if you're in a car crash,
Speaker 5:  It's even more the same phone than I realized. Like the, the thing I at
Speaker 5:  least hoped was that in the camera in particular, some of the like little
Speaker 5:  upgrades would add up to something and it kind of sounds like they barely
Speaker 5:  do. It's like very much in the vein of if your
Speaker 5:  phone is dying and you need a new one, this is probably the one to buy.
Speaker 5:  If your phone is not dying and you don't need one, don't buy this one and
Speaker 4:  Keep your phone. I think the iPhone 14 is
Speaker 4:  indicative of the fact that maybe there are no more people
Speaker 4:  without cell phones.
Speaker 6:  Tell me more.
Speaker 5:  Certainly not who might buy iPhones.
Speaker 4:  Right? Like Apple's entire game now. And if you just look at the pricing
Speaker 4:  of these phones, right. It's yeah. The, I know the 14 propri,
Speaker 4:  they start a thousand dollars and the big one is 10 99. Right. But
Speaker 4:  then the carrier subsidies are outta control. It's just, they're totally
Speaker 4:  dependent on the carriers now, cuz the carriers are all in two year upgrade
Speaker 4:  cycles. They really want you to upgrade those phones. Cuz you'll sign another
Speaker 4:  two years of 5g service. For whatever reason you might wanna do such a thing.
Speaker 4:  Like apple has created a world in which
Speaker 4:  most people who are gonna have iPhones have their iPhones and they yep. They
Speaker 4:  need to be competitive and compete with Android and conquest those users.
Speaker 4:  But that huge installed base. If they can just turn them regularly,
Speaker 4:  they're gonna sell a lot of phones.
Speaker 5:  Well, and it's almost like the, the incentive to make it dramatically better
Speaker 5:  every year in for those people is almost going away because now it's
Speaker 5:  like, you're gonna keep your phone until you need to upgrade for one reason
Speaker 5:  or another. And then you're just gonna upgrade to whatever the new one is.
Speaker 5:  So the, the thing where apple has to like ship something
Speaker 5:  spectacularly new every year, because that's the upgrade path for people
Speaker 5:  is just gone.
Speaker 6:  How many people is that upgrade path for though? Like the
Speaker 6:  ones who are doing it year annually. I know a lot of people on our staff
Speaker 6:  do and probably a lot of our listeners are doing the annual, but I feel like
Speaker 6:  a lot of people are, are now just doing like three, four year upgrades. And
Speaker 6:  even then it's the same thing. Like I gotta wait until there's a reason to
Speaker 6:  upgrade. 5g was not a reason for a lot of those people.
Speaker 4:  I mean the carriers will happily lie to you. Tell you,
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Carriers will tell me differently. But
Speaker 5:  Your mom, Alex is on. If I remember correctly like an iPhone 10 R
Speaker 5:  right? Yes, yes. Your mom is gonna buy an iPhone 14 and
Speaker 5:  it's gonna be like magic. Right? Like it is going to,
Speaker 6:  She's not though. Cuz she watched Allison's video. So she's like, I guess
Speaker 6:  I'm gonna get a
Speaker 5:  13. She gonna buy a pro oh she's gonna buy a 13. Even that we'll feel like
Speaker 5:  a huge upgrade. Right? Like the, the summation of these over the course of
Speaker 5:  three or four years is huge. Yeah. But each individual upgrade now
Speaker 5:  is
Speaker 6:  They're so iterative. Pretty
Speaker 5:  Minor. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I mean I held off I'm on an 11 pro my 14
Speaker 6:  pro is currently in Kentucky. I'm so excited for tomorrow. And
Speaker 6:  like I,
Speaker 4:  My understanding of your situation is that you live in New York and your
Speaker 4:  family is in Texas. Is it on its way to you in Kentucky?
Speaker 4:  Or has it
Speaker 6:  Stopped? Yes. Cause I just checked the ups tracking and it's like
Speaker 6:  landed in Kentucky.
Speaker 4:  I didn't know if you had like a burner house in Kentucky
Speaker 5:  Has a PO box in
Speaker 4:  Kentucky's just like I'm working in a elaborate tax scam.
Speaker 5:  It's technically my main residence. Well,
Speaker 6:  Not anymore. Like it's now everybody on the podcast
Speaker 6:  knows. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  The Kentucky state tax authorities are on the case. If you
Speaker 4:  work in, like, if you're a tax O instead of Kentucky, you're listening to
Speaker 4:  our chest. Let me know. I would just what's that like for you, we have
Speaker 5:  A lot of Alex information to tell you
Speaker 6:  Don't call them. Don't call them. It's
Speaker 4:  Fine. You're excited about the upgrade is the point of all this. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I like, I'm fairly excited about it cuz it's actually feels like, like
Speaker 6:  for me, the dynamic island was the moment where I was like, oh yeah, I'm
Speaker 6:  gonna upgrade for that. Oh cool. Which is probably very stupid. My sister
Speaker 6:  was like, who would upgrade for the dynamic island? And I was like, well
Speaker 6:  I did. I just bought a phone. Yeah. For it. I
Speaker 4:  Mean it it's, it's fun.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And it feels like,
Speaker 4:  But I, but I think that the cycle is, has been two years and it is
Speaker 4:  stretching its way to four. Right. And you can kind of see that Apple's
Speaker 4:  slowing the pace of it or of updates. So year to year it's almost nothing.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Right. Four years. It's massive. Yeah. It's and probably your battery
Speaker 4:  is shot. So you're like extremely excited that your phone's
Speaker 6:  Gone. That's the biggest part for me is I'm excited for my phone to last
Speaker 6:  more than four hours. Yeah. Well
Speaker 5:  Yes.
Speaker 6:  Four hours. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  So we've now dispensed with talking about the iPhone 14
Speaker 6:  And that's the iPhone
Speaker 4:  14. We actually talked about it all. Get the 13, the iPhone 14 exists to
Speaker 4:  be upgraded to it. It does not exist for any other like
Speaker 4:  meaningful reason. It just slow iterative updates and it it's there.
Speaker 4:  They cannot advertise the new 48 mango pixel camera. They can't
Speaker 4:  advertise a new chip
Speaker 6:  And 20 minute commercial trying to,
Speaker 4:  Yeah. They can't advertise a new design. They can't advertise the size of
Speaker 4:  the camera bump. What do they got? They got the island. And
Speaker 4:  it's like, oh, that's why they named it. The island. Yeah. Yeah. It it's
Speaker 4:  a great actually I've super come around to the name
Speaker 4:  because if you are me and you are walking the earth and people
Speaker 4:  are like, what do you think of the dynamic island? You're like, let me tell
Speaker 4:  you about notifications and status alerts and smartphone operating systems.
Speaker 4:  And you're like, this is, this is actually how I want to connect with people.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. This is, this is the bond that will bring us together. Is your new
Speaker 4:  found interest in smartphone alerts. And then I look up and they, they have
Speaker 4:  been running for minutes.
Speaker 4:  They've the distance between us has grown so immensely,
Speaker 4:  but their little pixel phone. But that's why I have this community. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  So that's the 14, right? I think it is just a very iterative updated it's
Speaker 4:  designed to capture that group of iPhone 11 owners who are it's time to
Speaker 4:  upgrade. And I think all those people be very happy. Yeah. If you have an
Speaker 4:  iPhone 13, just like stay away. And actually I think the iPhone 13
Speaker 4:  in particularly the iPhone 13 pro you can get it on sale
Speaker 4:  tremend upgrade target. It might be actually a superior upgrade target
Speaker 4:  than either the 14 or the 14 pro. Yeah. Oh, that's interesting. Like if you
Speaker 4:  have an iPhone 11 and you can like get one of those on sale. Whew. That's
Speaker 4:  a good idea. Right. It's like a very complete phone and this is really the
Speaker 4:  point. This was my review of the, the 14 pro the iPhone 13
Speaker 4:  is complete. It is a finished thought. Yep.
Speaker 4:  And Indeed's review of it last year. He was like, there's not a lot here
Speaker 4:  to say. Right. And like, you kind of, yeah, they did the thing. Yeah. And
Speaker 4:  you kind of end up reviewing iOS. Yeah. Right. At like a basic level.
Speaker 4:  And that's like, you know, it's apple, it's hardware and software and services.
Speaker 4:  And that did a, you know, like Tim cook who got speech, but as a product,
Speaker 4:  as a finished product with melds hardware and software, it was just
Speaker 4:  not a lot of rough edges to the iPhone 13 pro yeah. You can
Speaker 4:  criticize the camera in some little way. Like all this stuff, whatever. It
Speaker 4:  didn't have an always on display. It's like all this, they didn't have a
Speaker 4:  bunch of Android features basically. But the 14 pro they've added and always
Speaker 4:  on display, they've added the satellite thing. They've added the island.
Speaker 4:  All those things are like wildly unfinished. The, the 48
Speaker 4:  megapixel camera is new. So you're like, Apple's now in the beginning of
Speaker 4:  this new path. And you're like, oh, I can see all the rough
Speaker 4:  edges. I can see all the things they didn't add. I can see all the, the ideas
Speaker 4:  they didn't complete or what they left off to ship this one. And that's like
Speaker 4:  pretty exciting at the same time. It's also like, boy,
Speaker 4:  there's a lot to criticize you.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Well, and I guess what I wonder with, with the 14 pro and
Speaker 5:  even still wonder kind of after reading your review is like, is there a
Speaker 5:  long road towards something really cool here? Or are we gonna get to the
Speaker 5:  iPhone 15? They're gonna like Polish all those things. And then we're gonna
Speaker 5:  be back to thinking like, okay, they, more or less finished this
Speaker 5:  medium interesting thing they were trying
Speaker 4:  To do. I think I have take it in chunks. Okay. So the
Speaker 4:  island, I think we won't know if it's awesome or if it's
Speaker 4:  3d touch part two until next year, right? Like straight
Speaker 4:  up the live activities, API has to ship, which is turning
Speaker 4:  into a huge deal for apple, right? This like background, task, live activities,
Speaker 4:  API that they put, they're doing Iowa 16, which we
Speaker 4:  saw when we saw it at WWC. I think David and I broke like, oh, that could
Speaker 4:  be a whole thing, but it is the foundation of the dynamic island. So
Speaker 4:  all the thing, all the concepts they showed from flighty and Lyft and all
Speaker 4:  that, like they all need to use it. It's
Speaker 5:  The sand underneath the dynamic.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. What's what are islands made of? It's
Speaker 6:  The volcanic rock. It's
Speaker 4:  Sand
Speaker 5:  Volcanic rock. There you go. It's the dormant volcano underneath.
Speaker 5:  No, but I think, and the interesting thing is I've been talking to a bunch
Speaker 5:  of developers about this, and there's still very much a sense of like
Speaker 5:  uncertainty about the best way to use this stuff.
Speaker 5:  So I think you're gonna see a lot of folks try stuff and
Speaker 5:  roll things out that are live or aren't live that make use of
Speaker 5:  the island. And I, there's a lot of open questions about
Speaker 5:  not like whether this can be cool, but what it looks like when it is
Speaker 5:  cool, that I think is like, to your point, gonna take a while to shake out
Speaker 5:  and especially with the live activities. And I think it's true on the island
Speaker 5:  too. Like it's, it's coming for you. It's not a thing. You get a lot of control
Speaker 5:  over. Like if you're gonna have notifications on, you're also gonna get live
Speaker 5:  activities. So I think figuring out sort of where that pendulum
Speaker 5:  should stop before it's like super annoying and in your face all
Speaker 5:  the time is gonna take a minute.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. So here's one that we couldn't review cuz the live of activities, API
Speaker 4:  hasn't shipped, there are no apps that use it. Like right now in our video,
Speaker 4:  in every video, every demo of the island, what do people do? They start the
Speaker 4:  music player and that flies up to the island. And then they open a timer
Speaker 4:  and the island splits into beautiful. Like the, the classic,
Speaker 5:  The clock app is the most innovative app on the iPhone. Like prove me wrong.
Speaker 5:  It's it's the one.
Speaker 4:  But that makes sense. And there's an internal priority system in iOS
Speaker 4:  that says the music player is more important than the
Speaker 4:  timer. Oh, so the timer's gonna go in this little circle and the music
Speaker 4:  player's gonna be the big one. If you then make a phone call, iOS
Speaker 4:  is like, actually the phone call is the most important thing and we'll kick
Speaker 4:  the music player. We'll stop it. We're gonna stop your music while you're
Speaker 4:  playing a phone call and timers it. So like there's this internal priority
Speaker 4:  system that apple has developed, who knows, right? Like when you
Speaker 4:  add Uber to that mix who wins right. Will Uber
Speaker 4:  respect said priority system? When you add sports
Speaker 4:  scores to that mix, who knows like there are millions of
Speaker 4:  kinds of these live activities. Is
Speaker 6:  Apple handling that or is that gonna be up to the developers? Is it gonna
Speaker 6:  be up to the, the users seems like a terrible idea for it to be up to the
Speaker 6:  developers.
Speaker 4:  So it's not up to the users as far as I know. So apple has this priority
Speaker 4:  system. Yeah. You don't like assign yourself
Speaker 4:  like a five. Yeah. I think they've ranked basically the
Speaker 4:  APIs.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. My app's not very important.
Speaker 4:  I mean, that's what they did on Android. Right. Notifications on Android
Speaker 4:  have priority levels and the developers basically pick their priority levels
Speaker 4:  and everyone picks like the top priority. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  They're like, I'm the most important
Speaker 4:  Surprise. It's true on iOS too time. You need to know what's new on Netflix,
Speaker 4:  right? Yeah. Apple has time sensitive notifications and like half of my
Speaker 4:  notifications are marked time sensitive because developers like, of course
Speaker 4:  this is time sensitive.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. It seems like a terrible idea to give the developers any control over
Speaker 6:  that because they, well,
Speaker 4:  This is where I think Apple's control of the app store for better or worse
Speaker 4:  comes into play. Like they're gonna pay a lot of attention to how this thing
Speaker 4:  is being used. So, you know, here's a question are, what if developers just
Speaker 4:  start putting ads in the dynamic island? It's a thing you could reasonably
Speaker 4:  do. Right. Like
Speaker 6:  I throw my phone out the window,
Speaker 4:  You're near a McDonald's and McDonald's is like, boo, boo, like
Speaker 4:  stop in for some French fry. Like you can see it coming. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Right. And like, I think Apple's ability to police its platform. And
Speaker 4:  I think perhaps more importantly, it's absolute willingness to police its
Speaker 4:  platform is gonna come through here. So there's just this part of it.
Speaker 4:  I can't review yet. Yeah. Right. Cause that huge ecosystem of experiments
Speaker 4:  has not actually begun. Then the part you're you can review is like, you're
Speaker 4:  just like using your phone and it's like, oh, I'm not supposed to use this.
Speaker 4:  Like it's just background stuff. Like
Speaker 4:  I'm what I'm supposed to do. My iPhone is use apps. Yeah. Like there's not
Speaker 4:  really a world in which you're
Speaker 4:  like using the maps app to navigate
Speaker 6:  Via the island and
Speaker 4:  You open another app.
Speaker 4:  Right? Like how often does this happen to you?
Speaker 4:  It's very rare. There's a world in which you have the map app up and the
Speaker 4:  phone call comes in and like that little thing is fine, but just like sort
Speaker 4:  of the opening round is like, oh yeah, it's the music. It's phone calls.
Speaker 4:  It's the timer. That's what I really want there. And kind of everything else
Speaker 4:  is just like a, a demo.
Speaker 6:  You kind of compared it to 3d touch earlier. But I feel like it's more
Speaker 6:  adjacent to, I'm sorry to everyone besides me who loved it,
Speaker 6:  the touch bar
Speaker 4:  That's
Speaker 6:  Rude. Like I feel like it's that same. And, and, and I, I wonder if like
Speaker 6:  the touch bar part of its failure was that like apple and
Speaker 6:  developers had very little interest in it. Like developers didn't do a lot
Speaker 6:  with it. Apple did like three things and it was like, yep, there it is. And
Speaker 6:  there was no, nothing more happened with it. Is this
Speaker 6:  different? Like, is this gonna be different?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I think it's, I think it's different. I hope so. The, the,
Speaker 4:  the problem with the touch bar is like apple replaced a set of
Speaker 4:  good and useful buttons. Right. That had been on computers for
Speaker 4:  1000 years. Yep. With like, so you don't need this idea. And it was like
Speaker 4:  not useful. And I was like hard to use and whatever this is like, all right.
Speaker 4:  There was a notch, which you basically didn't see. I know some people
Speaker 4:  claim to be able to see it. And now there's this thing that you definitely
Speaker 4:  see because it is always moving, like stuff is happening up there all the
Speaker 4:  time. And it's like, you gotta pay for that. Right. You gotta make that so
Speaker 4:  useful. It's worth it to be there in your face all the time. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I always think about things in terms of cost. Right? So like the first apple
Speaker 4:  watch to me was not worth it because the cost of having to care for its little
Speaker 4:  battery was like too high. Yeah. Like you was always charging it. And like,
Speaker 4:  like didn't do a lot. And it was pretty slow and it was like, oh, I'm putting
Speaker 4:  more into this than getting out of it. The notch was like a great
Speaker 4:  value proposition. It took away a little bit of screen, but it added face
Speaker 4:  ID. And like after a day you're like, I'm not even looking at this thing
Speaker 4:  anymore. Yeah. Now I face ID. This is like, they've made it more prominent.
Speaker 4:  It's in your face. You're looking at it. You kind of want to use it.
Speaker 4:  And it doesn't do a lot yet. Like it is legitimately cool
Speaker 4:  that the airdrop indicator is in there. It's cool. Like that's just
Speaker 4:  neat. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I do think you might be underrating the widget
Speaker 5:  access from other apps that like, I, to
Speaker 5:  me, it's like the closest thing we've ever had to like persistent
Speaker 5:  playback controls on an iPhone, which I would argue if done
Speaker 5:  really well is like hugely useful. Yeah. There was a tweet
Speaker 5:  somebody did the other day. That was basically like, after looking at the
Speaker 5:  dynamic island, they never noticed that your phone doesn't tell you what
Speaker 5:  you're listening to as you're using it. It just has, there's just audio playing.
Speaker 5:  There's no sort of latent information about it unless you go looking for
Speaker 5:  it in one way or another. And I've spent a bunch of time thinking like, is
Speaker 5:  it, is that actually a thing I want, if I'm like listening to music, do I
Speaker 5:  need it? Like ticker scrolling the song I have on at all times? Like probably
Speaker 5:  not. But do I want access to playback without having to
Speaker 5:  do three or four other things? Like, yes, that strikes me as really useful.
Speaker 4:  But you did you just swipe down, you get like the widgets on the
Speaker 4:  notification center. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  But the like,
Speaker 4:  Or it's in a control center,
Speaker 5:  The control center thing sucks. I will, I will control center is
Speaker 5:  useless and I will not stand for anyone telling me control center is good.
Speaker 4:  Okay. But so then here's, but here's my push back to you. You have to tap
Speaker 4:  and hold. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  You want it to just be the one tap to get there.
Speaker 4:  You just tap it and open it. Since we published that take, like, I've heard
Speaker 4:  arguments, like some apps won't have it, you know, like they won't have a
Speaker 4:  widget. You'll just like, go back there anyway. Like, okay, fine. What, like,
Speaker 4:  what is the appropriate widget for like, I don't know the stocks app. It's
Speaker 4:  just like take you to the stocks app makes a dynamic island widget. Like
Speaker 4:  we're all doomed. Like we financialize too much of our lives.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I, the, the widget part of it is really cool.
Speaker 4:  Like that's actually the coolest part of it is because they, to your point,
Speaker 4:  it's like always on playback controls. They have made it look like a screen
Speaker 4:  that gets bigger with this sub pixel anti aliasing.
Speaker 4:  Right. It's very crisp. And it like opens very cool. And all the
Speaker 4:  animations are cool. Like that's the way to think about it. Like, you've
Speaker 4:  got a secondary display on your iPhone. Now that lives way, way
Speaker 4:  over the top of the system.
Speaker 6:  Like a touch bar, like
Speaker 4:  A touch bar. And it just,
Speaker 6:  It is a bar that you touch. Sure.
Speaker 4:  I just, it doesn't, they didn't take away the escape key on the
Speaker 4:  keyboard, like right. It's the cost. Isn't that high. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  They added like, it would've been like if the touch bar had been above the
Speaker 6:  function key bar and instead,
Speaker 5:  No, it would've been like if apple had replaced the dock on your Mac with
Speaker 5:  a touch bar, like that's functionally, what's going on here. It's like a,
Speaker 5:  it's a space you kind of use that is still a software space that they're
Speaker 5:  turning into something different.
Speaker 6:  I'm just thinking about that. And like trying to swipe across the bottom
Speaker 6:  of my monitor. That's gross, but
Speaker 4:  Look on face right now. Incredible.
Speaker 6:  Ugh. No, thank you. Absolutely not.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. So look, we'll like, that's my big, this is what I mean. So the first
Speaker 4:  bucket is like a year from now. We'll be able to confidently
Speaker 4:  evaluate the dynamic island. Yeah. Right now what I can, I'm just telling
Speaker 4:  you, the trade off is a little bit upside down. Like it's more in your face.
Speaker 4:  If you, I run my phone in light mode, it covers up the content. You can
Speaker 4:  see it's just a black pill on top of your display all the time in a way that
Speaker 4:  the notch, because there was no bright contrast at the top of the
Speaker 4:  notch. It was easy to ignore. But now there's screen at the top
Speaker 4:  too. So you can just like, see it glowing and it moves. So you're like, look
Speaker 4:  at it all time. It's worth it. Is it cool? Do people wanna talk to me about
Speaker 4:  status indicators on the phone? They do. I love
Speaker 5:  It. Alex, do you use dark mode or light mode?
Speaker 6:  I am a dark mode, like avid religious believer.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It's like full, crazy to me that you use your phone on light mode,
Speaker 5:  Eli like that is it it's it's do you just turn on your phone
Speaker 5:  at night and it blinds you to
Speaker 4:  Death? Well, based on tweets about our redesign, I am not the only one.
Speaker 6:  I mean, we have some, some light mode lovers
Speaker 6:  also@theverge.com.
Speaker 5:  I mean, I too love to be blinded by my phone. Every time I turn it on.
Speaker 5:  It's great.
Speaker 6:  It's like, it's upsetting to me. I have like a white screen on me right now
Speaker 6:  and it's giving me great lighting on one side of my face. And that's the
Speaker 6:  only reason for light mode.
Speaker 4:  Okay. So that was the first bucket a year from now. The second bucket is
Speaker 4:  like, who knows?
Speaker 4:  Well, the other thing I put in the year from now bucket would be the camera.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Really? Why,
Speaker 6:  Why would you put that in the year from now bucket? Cause it feels a little
Speaker 6:  like apart from the sharpness issues you had, it felt pretty
Speaker 6:  complete in your review.
Speaker 5:  And this is like an old idea. Apple did not like invent a new
Speaker 5:  theory about photography here. It just pixel bins.
Speaker 4:  Right. And then like, so what you get out of it is that the sensor is much
Speaker 4:  bigger. So you get a little bit better blur like Boca and the photos,
Speaker 4:  which is nice. Not so much that like you have
Speaker 4:  to like, go look for it and then it's there. And it's a very, it is very
Speaker 4:  nice, but it's not so much more than 13. Yeah. And you get a little bit better
Speaker 4:  lowlight performance, you do get better find detail, but that find detail
Speaker 4:  comes with a bunch of sharpening. You're just not getting this a
Speaker 4:  year from now. I think apple will be more confident in how to use this sensor.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Right. I think right now they played it pretty safe and they're, they're
Speaker 4:  not pushing it. And I'm just telling whoever
Speaker 4:  from apple is listening to this. Like the photo processing is getting
Speaker 4:  too aggressive, like the combo platter of noise reduction and
Speaker 4:  sharpening that is occurring on the iPhone right now is like just getting
Speaker 4:  weird, like too much, like back it off.
Speaker 5:  It is the side by sides of particularly the
Speaker 5:  14 pro and the pixel six were pretty
Speaker 5:  wild. Just that it's like, and you even say this in the review, it's like,
Speaker 5:  these are two photos of ostensibly the same thing that just
Speaker 5:  have wildly different opinions about what a good photo is
Speaker 5:  supposed to be. And you can look at them both. And they're both pretty good
Speaker 5:  photos. It's like, this is in incredibly bad lighting. And it's,
Speaker 5:  it's a relatively like sharp, nice looking photo, but it is
Speaker 5:  stylistically like miles apart from each other. And it's,
Speaker 5:  it's wild. Like I've, it's, it's gotten so much more pronounced over
Speaker 5:  time. Samsung has this like very warm tone
Speaker 5:  idea about the world where everything is like colorful and
Speaker 5:  smooth and beautiful Samsung
Speaker 4:  Phones are on a different planet. I don't know what else to say about this.
Speaker 4:  Like they're in a different dimension where everything is different color.
Speaker 4:  I
Speaker 5:  Kind of like the world, it lives in, it's a very like optimistic
Speaker 5:  universe that Samsung's phones live in, where everything is like beautiful.
Speaker 5:  And the sun is always setting.
Speaker 4:  So I, the last time I did an iPhone pro I didn't do last year, two years
Speaker 4:  ago, I did a 12 pros. And my takeaway that year was all these
Speaker 4:  phones are the same. They all look the same, like no differences exist.
Speaker 4:  And then this year they're as wildly different as they've ever been. I mean
Speaker 4:  like, and bright light when you like shoot a person on a city street. Like
Speaker 4:  that look exactly the same, but it's on the edges when they have to make
Speaker 4:  decisions. It's like, it's hard to even describe
Speaker 4:  like they're making artistic decisions that are wildly different from
Speaker 5:  Each other. Yeah. And the pixel is very sort of like neat and tidy. And then
Speaker 5:  apple is just like, let light range, see what happens.
Speaker 6:  It's like the dynamic range. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It's
Speaker 6:  Nuts on the 14 pro versus the six, the, the pixel six
Speaker 6:  pro is, is incredible. Like you're looking, oh, I can like look into these
Speaker 6:  buildings on the pixel six pro. And I
Speaker 6:  simply know that there are buildings there with the iPhone.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And they're very bright.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Very brightly that up. You know, it's like other stuff like
Speaker 4:  apple, it does not appear. Apple spent a lot of time on portrait mode,
Speaker 4:  you know? And like Samsung is just a, even a baby S 22, not the S 22
Speaker 4:  ultra does better portrait mode segmentation of like, hair's the
Speaker 4:  bummer than the iPhone does now. Just like, there it is. And we actually
Speaker 4:  did that demo with the S 22, just cuz it's interesting to see that the
Speaker 4:  not pro Samsung phone is outperforming the, the iPhone 14 pro
Speaker 4:  I think that, you know, the pixel is contrasty and moody. It always has been
Speaker 4:  apple is what what'd you say? Alex? It's like festival of lights. Like it's
Speaker 4:  very Thomas Kincaid. Like it's, everything is very bright.
Speaker 4:  There's almost no shadow. Like, can you switch it? Can you switch it to rich
Speaker 4:  contrast mode or like mess with a yes, you can do all these things. But it
Speaker 4:  just, I think apple has gotten, they've like backed themselves
Speaker 4:  into a corner with the processing a little bit. And they,
Speaker 4:  this is, I think now with a new sensor, they can collect more light. They
Speaker 4:  can get out of it and go to a different look that does not require them to
Speaker 4:  do the amount of noise. Cause when you shoot 48 megapixel raw,
Speaker 5:  I was just about to ask.
Speaker 4:  It's not like the world's noisiest photo. Like it's a fine photo. They're
Speaker 4:  huge. It takes the shutter. Like when you push the shutter, the capture time
Speaker 4:  is really long.
Speaker 6:  Oh, interesting.
Speaker 4:  Like I would not run around shooting a 48 pro 48 mega per hour. Like
Speaker 4:  you'll just get annoyed and the files are 80 Meg. I can't even destroy this
Speaker 4:  phone in one afternoon, but you can see there's a lot for apple to work
Speaker 4:  with there, but I just, I think they're a year away from that thing. And
Speaker 4:  then God only knows like, they've, you know, they've rebranded this
Speaker 4:  whole thing as the photonic engine. And they've really the main move there
Speaker 4:  is, they've moved deep fusion, the mid light and low light
Speaker 4:  pixel by pixel. Now they're running it early in the process on uncompressed
Speaker 4:  data. And it's still just like, what does sweater mode do?
Speaker 4:  Like, did this do anything like, who knows? But like, you
Speaker 4:  know, they're, they're getting more comfortable sort of talking about their
Speaker 4:  processing pipeline as something other than magic, you know?
Speaker 4:  And like, I think that's good. And I just, I think they can start making
Speaker 4:  different decisions. So that's what, it's a year away from being like, oh,
Speaker 4:  there's a 48 megapixel sensor in this camera. They can do stuff
Speaker 4:  that the 13 pro definitely cannot do. And right now they're just like, we're
Speaker 4:  right on top of each other.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So is that, is the next turn there then to basically open up
Speaker 5:  like a new set of camera modes to people because it feels like what you're
Speaker 5:  describing is like apple has this like incredible amount of raw power now.
Speaker 5:  And the solution is to give that back to users, like to just
Speaker 5:  let you do more stuff with your camera feels like the next
Speaker 5:  turn from like, we just collect an incredible amount of light and have an
Speaker 5:  incredible amount of processing power, like find clever ways to put that
Speaker 5:  back into the camera app seems like where this goes. And I feel like,
Speaker 5:  I just think about like the, what's the thing called in Mac OS now where
Speaker 5:  you can use your phone as the webcam. And it'll also look at your desk,
Speaker 4:  Continuity camera
Speaker 5:  Continuity camera. Thank you. Continuity camera feels like a version of that
Speaker 5:  thing. Right. Where they're just like, okay, now we have lots of pixels to
Speaker 5:  use and lots of processing power with which to use them. Like what wacky
Speaker 5:  new stuff can we open up? And it feels like that's what I would hope apple
Speaker 5:  would spend the next year working on.
Speaker 6:  Are they gonna focus on the camera though? Cause I feel like the camera for
Speaker 6:  the longest time has been the differentiator year to year for, for most phones.
Speaker 6:  Right? Like most phones, the big upgrades camera related,
Speaker 6:  but it also feels like the majority of people have gotten bored with that.
Speaker 6:  Don't care as much about the camera upgrades, like present company
Speaker 6:  excluded.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. The 12 pro camera was fine. Yeah. The 13 pro camera was great.
Speaker 4:  Like what are you gonna do?
Speaker 5:  But like action mode, I think is an example of something that is like a,
Speaker 5:  and I've said this on their show before, like is a meaningful change. It
Speaker 5:  doesn't sound like it's great yet. But like that kind of thing is the kind
Speaker 5:  of stuff where it's like, everybody's just running around, making tos all
Speaker 5:  day right now. If you can make them more stable, like you, you have accomplished
Speaker 5:  something real for people.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Yeah. So action mode is like really interesting, you know, cuz you
Speaker 4:  know, what they're doing is across all the sensors, they're just like cropping
Speaker 4:  down, you know? There's like the TikTok filter, which just like holds under
Speaker 4:  your face. That is what it is doing. Yeah. Like it just, it just,
Speaker 4:  but without the little line it's cropping the sensor down and then as you
Speaker 4:  move around, it's just moving around the sensor. Yeah. Which is a,
Speaker 4:  you know, that's neat. But as far as I know, when you do it on the
Speaker 4:  48 megapixel sensor on the main wide, it doesn't use the
Speaker 4:  additional space. So you, you don't get like more stabilization
Speaker 4:  off the 48 megale sensor than you do off the other 12 megapixel sensors.
Speaker 4:  Like that's just like one of those like things you could just figure out
Speaker 4:  how to do, you know, like the a 16 bionic processor is like
Speaker 4:  a, is what I, from what I'm told by apple, the performance is off
Speaker 4:  the unlabeled charts.
Speaker 8:  So,
Speaker 6:  So we all just need to be 50 times better. Really excited about
Speaker 6:  iOS 17.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I don't think the camera is the thing they don't update. You're right.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It's like, and that's weird. I just think that's weird. I think they
Speaker 4:  should start doing camera updates and versions of iOS. Like you have the
Speaker 4:  hardware particularly like the iPhone 13 pro to the iPhone 14,
Speaker 4:  same processor, same camera. As far as
Speaker 4:  we can tell. Right. 12 lens are same lens. Why does the 14 have the
Speaker 4:  photonic engine with deep fusion and the 13 pro doesn't get it. That's just
Speaker 4:  weird. It's a software camera. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Cause you need to pay for
Speaker 4:  It. Like I don't, that's like at some point when apple does this
Speaker 4:  segmentation and they're, they're, they're just playing games that I think
Speaker 4:  are, are dumb for software to play. Yeah. But I dunno, we'll see like
Speaker 4:  that, but I'd put the camera like action mode is great. If you have a ton
Speaker 4:  of light and it's still not that great, but like it's a baby step forward
Speaker 4:  to a really important thing. And so like a year from now, will it be like
Speaker 4:  a meaningful change? Like maybe? And that's like, that's I put the camera
Speaker 4:  and the island in that like one year from now, I
Speaker 4:  would put always on display in one year from now, because I think a
Speaker 4:  lot of people are gonna discover that they want their always on display to
Speaker 4:  be slightly more off than this display.
Speaker 5:  Take us through that. Cuz that was the thing. I am like the single feature
Speaker 5:  about the 14 pro I'm most excited about is the always on display. And I left
Speaker 5:  your review. Not kind of thinking like maybe I'm gonna buy this phone and
Speaker 5:  then turn in the, always out display off.
Speaker 4:  I'm definitely turning always on display off.
Speaker 5:  Why is it not good?
Speaker 4:  Bluntly, apples behind Android phones have had this for a, a long time.
Speaker 4:  Yep. And they've had to compete on making that thing. Good. Right. So like
Speaker 4:  across the Android landscape, always on displays, like you can customize
Speaker 4:  them, you can put widgets on them. You can, you can make, 'em look like just
Speaker 4:  a clock you can make 'em look like all kinds of things. They look wildly
Speaker 4:  different than the home screen. Apple's like, what if we just dim the lock
Speaker 4:  screen? Yeah. This is what is occurring. And they don't, you know, and it's
Speaker 4:  still very colorful. So like Becca and I were sitting extra show. We both
Speaker 4:  thought our phones were on all the time.
Speaker 5:  So we say it functionally, not that different from just having your phone
Speaker 5:  on, but the brightness turned like all, almost all the way down. Is that
Speaker 5:  like basically what it feels
Speaker 4:  Like? Well, and the screen is only refreshing it. One hurts. Like imagine
Speaker 4:  you had a way shittier version of your
Speaker 8:  Phone.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. So it's like, you know the screen isn't updating, but notifications
Speaker 4:  are flying. Yeah. Like it looks too on. Yeah. And like, I would
Speaker 4:  prefer like that pixel style, fade it or Samsung style, fade it all the
Speaker 4:  way to black and white, you know, and like show o'clock show o'clock in like
Speaker 4:  my next calendar appointment. Yep. Call it a day. Right. And the other,
Speaker 4:  I noticed this in, I think mark noticed this too. It feels like
Speaker 4:  it's running the battery down faster. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Which is like the main thing apple says it doesn't
Speaker 4:  Do. It's just like, it's the wrong set of trades.
Speaker 6:  Like I think we don't want to, to happen. Yeah. It
Speaker 6:  has to because you're still you're, you're still firing those pixels. Like
Speaker 6:  everybody else did it, black and white because you could turn all the black
Speaker 6:  as just the pixels are. Yeah. You could
Speaker 4:  Turn almost to
Speaker 6:  The screen and they're like, what if we left the entire screen
Speaker 6:  on? Yeah. But at 20% brightness, right.
Speaker 4:  A better way of thinking about the always on display at most Android phones
Speaker 4:  is that it is the mostly off display. Yeah. And
Speaker 4:  Apple's like, yo, this thing's on. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  It's
Speaker 4:  Just on. So, and I think, you know, like, as we've seen from I 16 tons
Speaker 4:  and tons of customization is in I yeah. So it's like just like
Speaker 4:  another year of refinement away from being great. Yeah. These are all the
Speaker 4:  reasons it got an eight. Like we reset our scores cuz we had score inflation,
Speaker 4:  but I'm just like, well always UN display, like not a thing like cameras
Speaker 4:  like pretty much the same. Like I wouldn't say it's necessarily
Speaker 4:  better than the, the pixel or S 22 ultra in fact, in some ways
Speaker 4:  it's definitely worse in some ways it's much better, but yeah. It's like,
Speaker 4:  it's a tie to just behind like that's how I put the camera on video. I think
Speaker 4:  it's way ahead of everybody as always. And then the island is like, who knows?
Speaker 6:  It's crisp
Speaker 4:  Question mark city. Yeah. It's very crisp. And the rest of the stuff is like
Speaker 4:  satellite connectivity. It's like, it's not even out yet. And I can't review
Speaker 4:  it. I can just tell you it's there car crash detection. Like I don't know.
Speaker 6:  Did you, you didn't crash a car.
Speaker 4:  We did not crash a car. I have heard tell that there are some plans
Speaker 4:  to crash some cars.
Speaker 6:  I have also probably heard that.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. We're gonna Alex. After the show, we have to figure out our insurance
Speaker 4:  force for the car crashing.
Speaker 6:  It's gonna be great guys. Stay tuned.
Speaker 5:  This feels like the sort of thing I'm gonna be made to do against my will.
Speaker 5:  And I just want everyone to know that I don't want do it. I'm saying it on
Speaker 5:  this
Speaker 4:  Podcast, David, we have a meeting tomorrow for your
Speaker 6:  Calendar. Bring your fluffies sweater. Maybe a really fluffy hat,
Speaker 6:  like just
Speaker 4:  A fluffy hat,
Speaker 5:  Fluffy hat,
Speaker 6:  Bulky
Speaker 4:  Style. That that is the most Texas car crash instruction. Like you don't
Speaker 4:  need to help me. You just get yourself a bulky hat bill. You're gonna be,
Speaker 4:  you're gonna be great. You just go
Speaker 6:  Like this. You just hunch and fly. Great.
Speaker 4:  We, we gotta take a break. Yes. We were talking about the iPhone so much.
Speaker 4:  Come on now so much. We're gonna take a break and we're come back and talk
Speaker 4:  about this watch. Yeah. I'll tell you what wear your fluffy hats. We'll be
Speaker 4:  right back.
Speaker 9:  When was the last time you were alone? When you truly didn't know
Speaker 9:  where to turn, was it your first day at a new school or having to take
Speaker 9:  the bus alone or maybe it was your first time in a new city point? Is
Speaker 9:  that the feeling of being alone? Just doesn't always sit well with us. You
Speaker 9:  need to find your own crew. Those who like the things that you do and with
Speaker 9:  LinkedIn, not only can you find that crew, they can help your professional
Speaker 9:  career as well. LinkedIn has a community of over
Speaker 9:  850 million people who care about the same things you do,
Speaker 9:  whether it's healthcare, sports, finances, or anything in between.
Speaker 9:  LinkedIn allows you to connect with like-minded individuals who help your
Speaker 9:  career path. It doesn't matter if it's a new job, a speaking engagement
Speaker 9:  contract work or more followers. The people who see your work on LinkedIn
Speaker 9:  are the ones who can generate business outcomes. That's why when you share
Speaker 9:  what you know on LinkedIn, you're not just connecting with other people.
Speaker 9:  You're connecting with opportunities, visit linkedin.com today to
Speaker 9:  join the conversation and get the tools you need to reach your audience.
Speaker 9:  That's linkedin.com.
Speaker 10:  You listen to this show week in and week out because well, we'd like
Speaker 10:  to think we offer sharp unfiltered insights into the biggest stories in
Speaker 10:  tech, business and politics. We also understand that your time is
Speaker 10:  valuable and we want you to apply the lessons that you hear on this podcast.
Speaker 10:  So what if you could get bite size snippets of the best content we have
Speaker 10:  to offer every week, while you are in luck? What a thrill,
Speaker 10:  because pivot and Salesforce are teaming up
Speaker 10:  to give you just that Salesforce has a new streaming service called Salesforce
Speaker 10:  plus, and they're helping to bring pivot on camera. That's right.
Speaker 10:  Salesforce plus will now be the exclusive home for visual highlights of
Speaker 10:  pivot showing four video segments each and every week. But it's not
Speaker 10:  just pivot Salesforce. Plus users can stream live experiences,
Speaker 10:  original series, virtual learning and other programming to help your business
Speaker 10:  grow. The award-winning shows on the platform, illuminate the future of
Speaker 10:  technology in the digital first work, anywhere world and
Speaker 10:  Salesforce plus will inspire business leaders, including you to
Speaker 10:  learn new skills, pursue new career opportunities and drive change in
Speaker 10:  the world. Sign up today to watch pivot and more
Speaker 10:  exclusive content salesforce.com/plus
Speaker 10:  that's salesforce.com/pl
Speaker 10:  us
Speaker 4:  We're back. I think we can dispense with the apple watch series eight very
Speaker 4:  quickly.
Speaker 5:  I think that's right. Unfortunately that seems to be
Speaker 6:  Right. It also does car crashes.
Speaker 4:  It does that's car crash
Speaker 6:  Put on your fluffy gloves.
Speaker 4:  So car crash plans in the future aside the
Speaker 4:  video team tried to trigger crash detection with the series
Speaker 4:  eight, by buying an RC truck, mounting a GoPro to it,
Speaker 4:  and then having the watch on the truck just like crash into stuff. And
Speaker 4:  that's, I mean, why do we, why did we, why did we start the verge?
Speaker 6:  I, I, I learned about that because I just heard the wine of the
Speaker 6:  motor through the office and I was like, what is that noise?
Speaker 6:  And then I saw it whip around the corner and just crash sadly into a
Speaker 6:  desk.
Speaker 4:  Yesterday was one of the busiest days in our office. In the past two years,
Speaker 4:  there was like apparently some sales conference. And obviously we had the
Speaker 4:  relaunch and there's a bunch of product people. And it's like, how does the
Speaker 4:  verge team show up? Well, we've attached a watch to an RC truck and we're
Speaker 4:  just crashing it into walls. This is what we do here.
Speaker 4:  Welcome
Speaker 6:  We're professional adults.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, that's great. It did not work. We did not generate sufficient G forces
Speaker 4:  to trigger or the watch was like silly
Speaker 4:  children. Yeah, this won't do it. The
Speaker 5:  Only answer is to get slightly bigger vehicles until
Speaker 5:  it actually triggers.
Speaker 4:  I think it might also know that it wasn't on a person. So I think we have
Speaker 4:  to get like a Luke warm sausage and like, you know,
Speaker 4:  just be like trying to trick it in the face tense detection.
Speaker 5:  No, we have to put, we have to put David in a power wheels and then see what
Speaker 5:  happens. I'll do it.
Speaker 4:  I think you're just getting in the car with the fluffy helmet dog. That's
Speaker 6:  What you're doing. It's in the mail. Get ready.
Speaker 4:  So the, the series eight, largely the same as the series seven and I think
Speaker 4:  V's point was if you have like a series three, you should upgrade and you'll
Speaker 4:  have the time of your life and everyone else will be fine because the new
Speaker 4:  watch OS will bring you almost all of these features.
Speaker 6:  Right?
Speaker 5:  It's kind of the same story as the iPhone 14, right? It's like if yours
Speaker 5:  is, if like you're you use the one you have, and it is
Speaker 5:  obviously nearing the end of its life, upgrade to this one, you'll be psyched.
Speaker 5:  If you already have one that you like quite a bit, don't worry about it.
Speaker 5:  Nothing is going to change. The ultra seems to be a very different story,
Speaker 5:  but we haven't reviewed that yet. So we'll see. But the, yeah, the series
Speaker 5:  eight is like, for me, it's like I haven't had a watch in a few years. I
Speaker 5:  was like all in on the watch for a little while and then kind of like tapped
Speaker 5:  out on having too many notifications on my wrist. So I just like stopped
Speaker 5:  being an apple watch guy for a few years. And I think I'm gonna get back
Speaker 5:  in. And now the question is like, if I had bought a series
Speaker 5:  seven, I would not feel the need to upgrade. Now I can't buy a series seven,
Speaker 5:  so I'm gonna buy a series eight because it's just the one to buy. Yeah. But
Speaker 5:  there doesn't seem to be anything. If you've bought a watch in the last
Speaker 5:  say three years, it's very unlikely that anything here is gonna blow your
Speaker 5:  mind. It's we it's wild to me that apple got to this point of these like
Speaker 5:  teeny tiny annual upgrades this quickly with the watch. But
Speaker 5:  this just seems to be kind of where we are. I mean,
Speaker 6:  They could fix the battery life. Like there's stuff they could actually be
Speaker 6:  doing that they're not, or that they haven't,
Speaker 5:  I'm not sure that's even true though. Like it's a small thing.
Speaker 4:  They did fix the battery life with the ultra. They made it gigantic. And
Speaker 5:  My shadow
Speaker 4:  In there,
Speaker 6:  They shove a couple more batteries
Speaker 4:  In there. They solved your problem. Yeah. I think it, you know, it's interesting
Speaker 4:  cuz the reason we're saying the iPhone 14 is that the sitter of stage is
Speaker 4:  like they're out of iPhone customers. And so now they just have to
Speaker 4:  be there and then squeeze you for apple TV money. It's like as hard
Speaker 4:  as they can, the watch is not there. Right?
Speaker 4:  The, the total market for apple watches is the installed base of the
Speaker 4:  iPhone. And as far as I know, they have not yet arrived at one to one
Speaker 4:  apple watch to iPhone
Speaker 5:  Sales. If they are apple is lying on it. Earnings. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Well, I mean that's, that's part of why they did the, the thermometers right.
Speaker 6:  Temperature readers. What are those called
Speaker 5:  Temperature sensors
Speaker 6:  There? We go
Speaker 4:  Your belief is that the, the thermometer, the,
Speaker 4:  that there are people around the world with iPhones being like, if
Speaker 4:  only I knew what temperature was.
Speaker 6:  No, cuz I think this is part of, there's been this weird kind
Speaker 6:  divide.
Speaker 4:  Oh, I see what you mean
Speaker 6:  In right. There's been this gender divide in wearables. Oftentimes people
Speaker 6:  who identify as women have been put pointed towards like get the aura ring,
Speaker 6:  get a Fitbit. Like you don't need a whole lot. Oh you're you identify as
Speaker 6:  a man, you need the biggest smartest watch you can buy. And,
Speaker 6:  and this like apple kind of perpetuated that by being like, look at this
Speaker 6:  manly, manly, enormous ultra, and then look at this
Speaker 6:  smaller one that can track your period or help you anticipate
Speaker 6:  your ovulation through temperature readings.
Speaker 4:  No, you can. It cannot help you do that.
Speaker 6:  It can't, it can help you. It
Speaker 5:  Can tell you after the fact
Speaker 6:  It'll tell you afterwards, and then you can use that to be like, Hmm,
Speaker 6:  maybe I'll have a better idea for next time.
Speaker 4:  Right. And then apple is not on the hook for their off
Speaker 4:  book, unlicensed, FDA. Right? That's
Speaker 4:  just you guessing
Speaker 6:  That's you guessing, right? You just wanna, you wanna get that sensor and
Speaker 6:  go for that. But it's, it's very like fundamentally appealing to these women
Speaker 6:  and saying, Hey, if you don't wanna go get one of these other devices out
Speaker 6:  there, if you wanna be part of the apple ecosystem, we've got you
Speaker 6:  now. And I don't know if that's gonna be successful, especially because like
Speaker 6:  they really half-assed it by being like, we will not get any sort of approval
Speaker 6:  whatsoever. We're just gonna put this out here so you can anticipate and
Speaker 6:  use it on your own time. And that's like not great, but
Speaker 6:  yeah.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. But I, you know, I think these review had it, right. There's a couple
Speaker 4:  apps that on different platforms are that do have the
Speaker 4:  certification to do it
Speaker 6:  And you can use those.
Speaker 4:  You can see how apple would, you can see how they would show up on the watch
Speaker 4:  and maybe get the certification. You can see how apple would go after the
Speaker 4:  certification. Yeah. So yeah. I, I, I buy that like, okay, they're
Speaker 4:  expanding the capabilities of this thing such that they might be able to
Speaker 4:  get more people.
Speaker 6:  Right? Yeah. And I think that's exactly what it is. It's just like, we know
Speaker 6:  there's this huge market of people who historically, haven't been buying
Speaker 6:  these as often they've been on these other platforms and
Speaker 6:  now we can convince them to get this really big watch that continues to be
Speaker 6:  grow larger every year. Not every year, every other year. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  I'm upset about it.
Speaker 5:  I have a theory about this that I'm just developing right this second. And
Speaker 5:  I'm curious what you guys think. It seems like one of the things that apple
Speaker 5:  pulled off with the iPhone was to basically open up the app
Speaker 5:  store and make everybody else make the case for the iPhone for them. Right?
Speaker 5:  Like the, the, the apple designed very few of the best things about the
Speaker 5:  iPhone, ultimately that is not true on the apple watch in like
Speaker 5:  any meaningful way apple designs, all of the things about the apple watch
Speaker 5:  at this point. And the, the, like, there are apps on it obviously, but I
Speaker 5:  I've seen very few apple watch apps that appear to be like apple watch first
Speaker 5:  apps there there're like companions to other things or sort of
Speaker 5:  barely thought of things. And I,
Speaker 4:  Yeah, but there's one now there's exactly one flow.
Speaker 4:  No, it's oceanic. Plus by, by Huish on the apple watch
Speaker 4:  ultra fair. This is the one they built the entire watch.
Speaker 4:  They partnered with another company, which is a big move for apple.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And that app is supposed to sell the apple
Speaker 4:  watch ultra to scuba divers. And I don't think that it is meant to be used
Speaker 4:  as an extension of an iPhone app, because if you're using your
Speaker 4:  iPhone in the open ocean, you have problems. So like they've got
Speaker 4:  one. Yeah. And maybe that's the beginning of something else. But I think,
Speaker 4:  think that's just mostly related to how often do
Speaker 4:  you have your apple watch without your phone? And they still sell lots of
Speaker 4:  I'm. I would bet most of apple watches that get sold don't even have the
Speaker 4:  cellular capability. And even the ones I'd send the last year and a half
Speaker 4:  with an cellular capable apple watch that I never hooked up. Yeah. Cause
Speaker 4:  it's been a pandemic. I was like, what am I gonna do? Make a call from this
Speaker 4:  downstairs. I'll just go upstairs and get my phone.
Speaker 6:  Is there ever a case where like, cuz I never feel comfortable going
Speaker 6:  with just my watch and not my phone. Right. Like if I get a phone call, then
Speaker 6:  I'm gonna have to figure out the AirPod situation. I can't play music on
Speaker 6:  it as well. Like I don't trust the apple
Speaker 6:  pay and stuff on it. I should. But I don't like,
Speaker 4:  Yeah, you should definitely trust that. That's fine. But
Speaker 6:  There, there, I think there I'm not the only one. I think there is a lot
Speaker 6:  of people who, who do have this like slight phobia of just going with the
Speaker 6:  watch and leaving the phone at home. Like
Speaker 4:  You should do it. When I, when we lived in the city and I would go on walks
Speaker 4:  with max, I would only take the watch. And it was great cuz I didn't have
Speaker 4:  my phone. And so like I could get texts. I could make the one phone. Like
Speaker 4:  I could make the emergency phone call if I needed it. Yeah. I could pay for
Speaker 4:  stuff. I still have my wallet, but it was great. Cuz I couldn't like check
Speaker 4:  Twitter and see what people were mad about.
Speaker 6:  But besides those walks, how often are you without
Speaker 6:  your phone?
Speaker 4:  Well, now I live in a house that's full of computers. Yeah. It's a real problem.
Speaker 4:  I gotta buy another house. It's no computers shack in the woods.
Speaker 4:  Okay. I'm just saying like give it a shot. Like yeah. But I,
Speaker 4:  that, like we said, we were gonna dispense with the series a quickly, like
Speaker 4:  now we are just generically talking about the apple watch.
Speaker 5:  Yes.
Speaker 4:  Right. The series eight is an instantiation of the apple watch is very
Speaker 4:  iterative. Very nice. And they've added capabilities that might appeal to
Speaker 4:  a few more people, maybe many more people
Speaker 6:  And focus modes too in
Speaker 4:  Focus. But
Speaker 6:  No, that one's cool because I'm gonna be able to have like when I'm not at
Speaker 6:  work, have one that doesn't have my calendar on it. That's good. Not having
Speaker 6:  to look at my calendar while I'm off work. That sounds great.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. We'll talk about the ultra more next week. I think that's the
Speaker 4:  interesting one. So very nice. If you have a three upgrade you, anything
Speaker 4:  else? You know, upgrade, watch west. You're gonna be very happy. David. You
Speaker 4:  wanna talk about iOS 16 real quick? Sure.
Speaker 5:  I mean you've used it actually in a funny way, in a more advanced
Speaker 5:  way than I have. Like one of the funny things, I mean it comes back to what
Speaker 5:  we were talking about before, right? Like one of the most interesting things
Speaker 5:  about iOS 16 is gonna be live activities in the, and the dynamic island
Speaker 5:  cuz the whole like thesis of iOS 16. If I was to like
Speaker 5:  have a big heady thought about iOS 16 is that it is trying to make
Speaker 5:  your phone do more things without you having to do them. And we've talked
Speaker 5:  about this already on the show, but it's like the always on screen is about
Speaker 5:  this. Like how do you get information without having to open up your phone?
Speaker 5:  Which I think is like an absolutely correct path for apple to be on based
Speaker 5:  on your review. It doesn't sound like it's handling it perfectly, but like
Speaker 5:  lock screen widgets are amazing. Like huge win.
Speaker 5:  I wish I could have more of them. I wish they were more interactive, but
Speaker 5:  like I can tap on my phone and I can see what is next on my calendar. And
Speaker 5:  I can press one button to take a note on my phone.
Speaker 6:  You went widgets instead of the cutout.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. None of my pictures are cool enough to need a cut out. Although I do
Speaker 5:  now my, my calendar widget is over top of my wife's face and
Speaker 5:  she is not thrilled with that. I would
Speaker 4:  Say
Speaker 5:  There was some consternation, but I think it's great. And like using, having
Speaker 5:  a bunch of different lock screens that like I was talking about or hooked
Speaker 5:  to focus modes is great. There's like these little ideas, especially about
Speaker 5:  the lock screen that I think apple got like really right. And then everything
Speaker 5:  else about iOS 16 is just like common sense stuff that it would've been
Speaker 5:  great to have had several years ago, but it's here now and pretty happy about
Speaker 5:  it. And that's like, that's basically been the story of iOS for a while is
Speaker 5:  they're just like, oh here's a future you want, we made it for you.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It's interesting. Cuz all the stuff you're describing that you want
Speaker 4:  on the lock screen is stuff that I have in my apple watch.
Speaker 5:  That's interesting.
Speaker 4:  Right. Like I never do any of this customization cuz like what I put, I just,
Speaker 4:  I use the modular face in the watch, right? Yeah. So like all there's the
Speaker 4:  calendar. I just look at it. Like there's not much else. I guess
Speaker 4:  it's that's a weird dynamic. Yeah. Right? Like you can overload your lock
Speaker 4:  screen with ambient information or you can just like overload your wa
Speaker 5:  Right? Yeah. No I think that's right.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I did the cutout cuz I don't need the widgets. Like those are all on
Speaker 6:  my watch. Yeah. But I do, I do have one quibble with iOS 16.
Speaker 6:  I was talking with will Joel, our creative director. And we were mainly talking
Speaker 6:  about the verge website and I was grilling him on the colors and
Speaker 6:  everything cuz I wanted to understand it cuz I just think it's neat to talk
Speaker 6:  about color choices. Is
Speaker 5:  It the clock fonts? It
Speaker 6:  Moves the clock fonts. Like we immediately started talking about the clock
Speaker 6:  fonts. So like I was, I was like, look at these fonts, I'm talking about
Speaker 6:  the verge site. And I'm like, these fonts are great. Unlike these fonts.
Speaker 6:  And he had a really, really interesting point that I thought was great
Speaker 6:  was just that like the, the watch fonts they've given us so much
Speaker 6:  choice. It's almost anti apple cuz they've given us these really
Speaker 6:  ugly watch fonts. Right? Like they're all kind of
Speaker 6:  unattractive and they didn't think what they, it didn't have that like
Speaker 6:  apple touch cuz apple usually is so good at design.
Speaker 6:  And if it's gonna give you choices, it's always gonna give you choices that
Speaker 6:  it thinks are aesthetically pleasing. And I refuse to believe that it thinks
Speaker 6:  these fonts are aesthetically pleasing, especially because they don't like
Speaker 6:  thes fonts. You can choose don't work with the widget sands
Speaker 6:  fonts. Yes. They, they clash and you're like, this is ugly. Yep.
Speaker 6:  And so an apple and it was just really,
Speaker 6:  I
Speaker 4:  Hate it, but that's what they want. It's my space time for gen Z. And it's
Speaker 4:  gonna happen on their lock screens. Ugh.
Speaker 5:  That's real. I mean the fact that that widget Smith app is so
Speaker 5:  massively popular is like, there are definitely people at
Speaker 5:  apple park who took notice of that, that like people wanna make
Speaker 5:  their phones uglier in this service of making it look more like
Speaker 5:  them. And that's actually the correct thing for apple to do. I also Alex,
Speaker 5:  to your point, I think it's not apple. I think what you just described is
Speaker 5:  Johnny. I like like the, the thing where
Speaker 5:  it's just like, this is the right answer. And if you don't like it, you're
Speaker 5:  wrong and can just go screw yourself. Yeah. That's Johnny.
Speaker 5:  That was all Johnny I've. And I think like when he's gone you can draw a
Speaker 5:  pretty straight line to this.
Speaker 6:  He was like, he was that apple design. And I think if, if, if this was, if
Speaker 6:  that was Johnny and this is like obviously an operating system made without
Speaker 6:  his influence for the most part, as far as we know. Mm. Less than less
Speaker 6:  than previous years at the very
Speaker 5:  Least less influence. Certainly. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Then what does that mean for apple in its its own
Speaker 6:  philosophy about design? Because that's a pretty radical shift to say, like
Speaker 6:  to go from being like, we, we know it looks good and we'll guide you
Speaker 6:  to here's some fonts, here's some colors you do. You,
Speaker 4:  It's not, it's some, that's what, it's some fonts and some
Speaker 4:  colors. If apple was like any font and
Speaker 6:  It's
Speaker 4:  What I want iOS users for like comic sand let's do
Speaker 6:  Wing.
Speaker 4:  They're not doing that. They they've, pre-selected some
Speaker 4:  aesthetics for you,
Speaker 6:  But they're bad aesthetics. And
Speaker 4:  You may engage in them,
Speaker 6:  But they're like,
Speaker 5:  But like some of them are very ugly. I agree. But I think like the, even
Speaker 5:  when you go to pick a lock screen, it actually does this in a very interesting
Speaker 5:  way. Cuz it gives you, it basically like stack ranks, what it thinks are
Speaker 5:  good ideas. And it'll even pick a bunch of your photos that it's like, what
Speaker 5:  if you use this photo as your lock screen, that might look nice. But then
Speaker 5:  if you like,
Speaker 6:  It picked a photo of my friend, Sam at his wedding,
Speaker 6:  crushed it. And it was like, don't you want a picture of your friend, Sam
Speaker 6:  at his wedding to look at every day for the rest of your life. When you turn
Speaker 6:  on your phone. And I was like, no, apple, what?
Speaker 5:  What's wrong with your friend, Sam? What do you have against Sam?
Speaker 6:  Like, I mean, he's fine, but we're not friends enough for him to be on
Speaker 6:  my phone like that.
Speaker 5:  All my lock screens are are of you guys. I don't know what you're talking
Speaker 5:  about.
Speaker 4:  There's already a TikTok meme of like people changing lock screen for their
Speaker 4:  side, their side pieces. It's pretty good. It's
Speaker 6:  Like pretty good focus modes.
Speaker 4:  That's
Speaker 5:  A good use of focus mode. That
Speaker 6:  Is my cheat and focus mode as you did, it's all you
Speaker 4:  All right. We should take another break. I can't wait for these live activities.
Speaker 4:  It's the point of I 16 is like live activities. Yeah. Yeah. It's gonna be
Speaker 4:  cool. It's gonna be great. Like it's a big deal and it's just like not here
Speaker 4:  yet. All right. We gotta take another break. We'll go through a little lightning
Speaker 4:  around when we come back. We right back.
Speaker 11:  Any job at Amazon can turn into a high paying career for
Speaker 11:  employees looking for security today, Amazon offers good pay and healthcare
Speaker 11:  on day one, new parents also get up to 20 weeks of fully paid leave.
Speaker 11:  So they have the flexibility to spend time with family while making a living
Speaker 11:  for opportunity. Tomorrow, Amazon is investing 1.2 billion
Speaker 11:  into free technical training. That's available to over 750,000
Speaker 11:  associates across the country. With these programs, hourly
Speaker 11:  employees have the opportunity to move into higher paying highly skilled
Speaker 11:  jobs in fields like software engineering and robotics. Learn
Speaker 11:  more@aboutamazon.com.
Speaker 12:  Facebook is taking action to keep its platform safe. In the last
Speaker 12:  six years, Facebook spent over 16 billion enough
Speaker 12:  to build seven pro stadiums all to help create safer connections.
Speaker 12:  Learn more about the work ahead at
Speaker 12:  facebook.com/action.
Speaker 4:  Okay, we're back. Do we want to talk about the pixel book?
Speaker 5:  I do, but before we do, can I give one more iOS 16 thing? Yes.
Speaker 5:  I got the greatest comment that I've ever gotten from a story that I wrote
Speaker 5:  on the verge.com and it, it has emboldened me to share the thing that I
Speaker 5:  discovered on this podcast. So I wrote in the I 16 interview
Speaker 5:  that it was stupid that you couldn't sort in messages just to see
Speaker 5:  your unread messages because that's stupid and you've never been
Speaker 5:  able to do that. And that's stupid that that can't happen. You can unsend
Speaker 5:  messages. That's great. You can edit messages. That's great. You couldn't
Speaker 5:  just sort to see the unread ones. And we all have that one message from like
Speaker 5:  two and a half years ago. That's the reason you still have the badge and
Speaker 5:  your messages app. Anyway, I got a bunch of people on Twitter. Thank you
Speaker 5:  to all of you who said, actually you can do this. There's a, there's a thing
Speaker 5:  at the top left that says filters. And if you go to filters, you can now
Speaker 5:  filter down to unread messages, but you can
Speaker 5:  only do this. If you've turned on a feature in settings, you go to settings
Speaker 5:  messages, scroll all the way down and turn on filter. Unknown sends. It's
Speaker 5:  not on by default. Oh, but if you turn it on, then you go to the
Speaker 5:  messages app and you'll have a filters button at the top. And you can filter
Speaker 5:  just to see your unread messages. What? This is the greatest thing ever.
Speaker 5:  I wrote about it on the verge. And it was like this hidden feature lets you
Speaker 5:  filter. And I just, for everyone listening, I just blew both of their minds
Speaker 5:  right now. This is the greatest thing.
Speaker 4:  And then there's a red button. Yeah. This
Speaker 6:  Is incredible.
Speaker 4:  You can select all mark red.
Speaker 5:  It's magic.
Speaker 4:  Well, I can't do that cuz I need to get back to some people. But,
Speaker 5:  But I wrote about this and somebody commented saying usually when I read
Speaker 5:  the 10 hidden tricks, it's all stuff I know, but I didn't know this one.
Speaker 5:  So thank you. Aww. And I was like, yes. So turn on filter.
Speaker 5:  Unknown sends filter, unread, life changing. You're welcome.
Speaker 4:  The other thing, the reason that I had filter unknown sends on already is
Speaker 4:  cuz I have an app called robo color, which is amazing. It, it
Speaker 4:  not only blocks spam calls. Sometimes it just takes them and plays
Speaker 4:  script at them. Yes. And that script that's be bonkers. And then it
Speaker 4:  records that. And then sometimes you can just listen to that interaction.
Speaker 5:  That's a podcast. I would
Speaker 4:  Listen. That's funniest thing that you can do on your phone. It's like
Speaker 4:  just an old man going hello? Hello for five minutes.
Speaker 4:  And I'm desperate spammer trying to get through that wall.
Speaker 6:  That's
Speaker 5:  I want that's
Speaker 4:  Awesome. It's it's a very good, highly recommended. It's like four bucks
Speaker 4:  a month and every now I just listen to 'em but that's why I filter on and
Speaker 4:  send on. They need to do it with text when people replied to spam texts.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Yes. So now if you delete, I, I found this out cause I got a spam text yesterday.
Speaker 6:  I'm on 16 and I deleted it and I said, do you wanna report this as junk?
Speaker 6:  Ooh. And I was like, what? Love that game changer.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And then I did deleted another text and I didn't wanna report that
Speaker 6:  one as junk. I was like, no, that's just my mom.
Speaker 5:  That's just my friend, Sam. Who's
Speaker 4:  Not is why she buy your mom. An iPhone messages. App is industry leading
Speaker 4:  the worst. Okay. Let's start, let's start with the pixel book. So
Speaker 4:  this is, is rewind. Rich minor comes back to
Speaker 4:  Google to start a tablet division. Oh wow. To make hard work. Okay. All right.
Speaker 4:  And then they're like, yep. It happened. Yep. We're excited about Android
Speaker 4:  tablets again. Then there's a recession
Speaker 4:  in quotes.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Depending on who you talk to on what day? Right. Ish. And
Speaker 4:  Google's like clamping down sun doors telling people like tighten up, be
Speaker 4:  20% more productive. Remember how Google you could like spend 20% of your
Speaker 4:  time inventing Gmail we're done with that do stuff that we
Speaker 4:  want you to do instead. So Google's clamping down. They just shut down area
Speaker 4:  one 20, which is their like inventions factory. We've covered a bunch of
Speaker 4:  inventions. They're spinning off project balloon tech into some other
Speaker 4:  that's the internet balloons. Remember when every tech company was like,
Speaker 4:  what if internet from the sky? Google's like balloons and Facebook was like
Speaker 4:  planes and they, I don't know. So Google's clamping down and it seems
Speaker 4:  like one of the things that got clamped was the next pixel book.
Speaker 4:  Yes. And they're just winding it down.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So according to our reporting, they had, they, they knew what this
Speaker 5:  thing was going to be. It had been prototyped. It was scheduled to launch
Speaker 5:  next year. And not only is that not going to happen, the team that
Speaker 5:  was building it is no longer.
Speaker 6:  They were all told to find jobs elsewhere in Google. Right.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Which is also just a funny thing that you can be like, Hey,
Speaker 6:  you still work here, but find a job,
Speaker 4:  Find something to do with don't you. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Well do be more productive. Yeah. And I think, look, it it's one of those
Speaker 5:  things that like if, if a hundred million people had bought a pixel book,
Speaker 5:  they would still be making pixel books. So it's, this is the kind of thing
Speaker 5:  that there's like a small set of tech nerds who really loved the pixel book.
Speaker 5:  The pixel book was perfect. Laptop hardware. I will, I will go to my
Speaker 5:  grave believing this a hundred percent perfect. It needed like the second
Speaker 5:  version of it. Would've had slightly smaller bezels and it would've been
Speaker 5:  fine, but it was, it was unbelievably great. It's still my favorite laptop
Speaker 5:  hardware I've ever used.
Speaker 4:  No, the Chromebook pixels, my favorite laptop hardware, the
Speaker 5:  Chromebook pixel was awesome.
Speaker 4:  Actually. That's not true. My 16 inch MacBook pro with M one pro is the best
Speaker 4:  laptop hardware used.
Speaker 5:  That's
Speaker 6:  Fair's all about that pixel book.
Speaker 5:  But the Chromebook still came out nine years ago
Speaker 4:  And like it, yeah. My mom still uses the one that I got her and it is
Speaker 4:  lovely. Cuz I bought her one with core I seven to run Chrome.
Speaker 4:  It kicks Chrome. It's great. It was overkill at the time,
Speaker 4:  but it's great. It's still, it's still rocking cuz it just runs Chrome. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Yeah. I mean, and I think the, the story really here
Speaker 5:  as, as Alex and I were working on this story, Alex in the editing,
Speaker 5:  Alex I yeah, sorry. Alex Kranz had nothing to do with it and deserves
Speaker 6:  Nothing at all. I was like, Ooh, a surprise.
Speaker 5:  But Dan cer sent this link to a, a
Speaker 5:  study saying basically that like the PC market had this huge run up in
Speaker 5:  the course of the pandemic and has like crashed back down to earth and Chromos
Speaker 5:  has crashed even harder back down to earth. And basically what we've learned
Speaker 5:  is that Chromos massively successful in schools and education
Speaker 5:  really has not made any inroads in any interesting way anywhere else.
Speaker 5:  And you know, who doesn't wanna buy lots of thousand dollar
Speaker 5:  Chromebooks schools. Yeah. And so there was just, there was
Speaker 5:  no way for the pixel book to continue to exist, which makes me very sad.
Speaker 5:  But I also sort of understand.
Speaker 4:  I really think that for a lot of people, a Chromebook is
Speaker 4:  the best choice for a laptop.
Speaker 5:  I agree. But the market does not agree with that. Believe it. I disagree
Speaker 5:  to my bones. That
Speaker 6:  That is true. I disagree. We already have people who Monica did that great
Speaker 6:  story last year about people who were raised up on phones and pixel
Speaker 6:  books. So they don't understand file hierarchies. And like, that's why
Speaker 6:  I'm like, no Chromebooks are bad for your fulltime for computer.
Speaker 4:  Like what Alex is like, what I need you to do is understand the concept of
Speaker 4:  a file. Yes, yes. You're home. That's the first we're here for you.
Speaker 4:  But I honestly, you know, the holidays are coming by
Speaker 4:  your parents a Chromebook. It will make your life better. I will never get
Speaker 4:  over. I mean, obviously some of you have parents who are very good at computers.
Speaker 4:  They're fine. If you're like me and every time your parents call,
Speaker 4:  it's like a knives out mystery to figure out how they broke the
Speaker 4:  computer. Just get 'em a Chromebook. Yeah. Cause like, all
Speaker 4:  they're doing is going to websites. Like that's all they really want to do.
Speaker 4:  And the thing is really good at it. And then they have a phone for all the
Speaker 4:  other stuff and they like use the phone to like do FaceTime calls. Like you
Speaker 4:  don't, you don't need an app model on that device for that
Speaker 4:  for like look at websites. Good. You
Speaker 6:  Know? Yeah. I mean the Chromebook probably might make sense for a lot of
Speaker 6:  older customers who, who maybe don't need a whole lot. They're retired. They're
Speaker 6:  not doing like their taxes on the thing or anything like that. They have
Speaker 6:  an accountant, but that, that those that younger the generation Z
Speaker 6:  or whatever we wanna call it, those kids don't necessarily
Speaker 6:  need or want just a little window to the internet. They've already got that.
Speaker 6:  They've got their phone. They want something that can do a little bit, a
Speaker 6:  lot more. Yeah. Not even a little bit, but a lot more stuff. So I
Speaker 6:  think it makes sense that Chrome is not reaching out to those kids, especially
Speaker 6:  because they also care more about their privacy. And
Speaker 6:  you're just buying a window to Google when you buy a Chromebook,
Speaker 6:  you're just saying, here's my data, Google.
Speaker 4:  These are people who are buying windows, laptops, and then running Chrome.
Speaker 6:  No they aren't though. They like, I cannot tell you how often I see the teens
Speaker 6:  being like don't use Chrome. It's terrible. You have to go get Firefox.
Speaker 6:  Save Firefox. No.
Speaker 5:  Nope. There's like
Speaker 6:  On TikTok and
Speaker 5:  Stuff. I tell you confidently. That is not a real thing. That is happen.
Speaker 5:  I
Speaker 4:  Don't know what teens you're hanging. Swear.
Speaker 6:  The teens, the teens love it. My
Speaker 4:  About teenagers
Speaker 5:  Go use Firefox.
Speaker 6:  It cracks me up
Speaker 4:  Every time here's a digression for you. I can't believe this.
Speaker 4:  Hasn't come up on this show yet. Ford announced a new Mustang yesterday.
Speaker 4:  Yes. It looks exactly the same as the old Mustang.
Speaker 4:  They've added a crease to the back. Whatever on the inside looks totally
Speaker 4:  different. They've added huge screens everywhere. Everywhere. Just it runs
Speaker 4:  unreal engine. I think it doesn't run Android yet. They've really dicey,
Speaker 6:  But it runs unreal engine.
Speaker 4:  But yeah, they've got all these animations to, you know, cars now are video
Speaker 4:  games and actually the PR is full of references to video games. They're like
Speaker 4:  we made the dashboard look more like a video game. No, and it's like, it's
Speaker 4:  weird. Don't do that. But there's this line in it. They've taken
Speaker 4:  out the buttons and the knobs for the climate control and the
Speaker 4:  radio. There's maybe a volume button. So, or a volume knob still. And
Speaker 4:  the line is like we asked gen Z
Speaker 4:  millennials and traditional Mustang owners and they all prefer
Speaker 4:  having screens. And it's like, those are your three generations.
Speaker 4:  There's gen Z. There's one animals
Speaker 5:  Mustang.
Speaker 4:  And then the generation that forever be known as traditional
Speaker 4:  Mustang owners.
Speaker 4:  It's like, alright, that's, you know, I've always been kind of on the border
Speaker 4:  of gen X and I'm gonna a traditional Mustang
Speaker 4:  owner from this point on.
Speaker 5:  I actually feel like that describes you personally better than any other,
Speaker 5:  other labels.
Speaker 4:  It's like you wanna do Oregon trail? No, no, no. Traditional Mustang
Speaker 4:  owner. That's that's always been me. I'm an old
Speaker 4:  soul.
Speaker 5:  Also Ford. You interviewed the wrong people a hundred percent. No, they
Speaker 5:  no,
Speaker 4:  Just
Speaker 5:  Hard disagree.
Speaker 4:  It's very funny. It's it's just such a confidently stated line in this
Speaker 4:  press release too.
Speaker 5:  But wait back to, to Alex's browser point, that's actually a really good
Speaker 5:  segue into another thing we should talk about, which is Adobe buying Figma
Speaker 5:  for 20 billion. Yes.
Speaker 4:  Terrible.
Speaker 5:  Because there are lots of reasons it's terrible. But one big thing.
Speaker 5:  This is, is like a fundamental bet on web browsers. Like Fig's thing
Speaker 5:  for a long time has been that like the web is a place for
Speaker 5:  massively powerful apps and it has like built one of those things inside
Speaker 5:  of web technology. And Adobe has been saying for a long time that it wants
Speaker 5:  to build more of its tools into the web and has
Speaker 5:  struggled pretty hard to do so. But like Scott Beski at Adobe has been talking
Speaker 5:  about this forever. And this is like, this is going to be a push
Speaker 5:  for them to do more stuff on the web. And I think my like theory slash
Speaker 4:  If it doesn't get blocked
Speaker 5:  Well, yeah, again, there are lots of reasons this might not happen, but might
Speaker 5:  not. It might not be a bad idea, but like a window to websites is a much
Speaker 5:  more powerful thing going forward then I think it has been
Speaker 4:  Recently. Yes I, so I, there lots of big company, Microsoft, Spotify, whatever,
Speaker 4:  where they're actually provisioning their designers, Chromebooks to run
Speaker 4:  Figma. Oh wow. It's like a real thing that occurs. Oh, well I don't think
Speaker 4:  Microsoft is provisioning. Chromebooks fair maybe, but Microsoft is getting,
Speaker 4:  there's a great CNBC story that I think Tom link to today in his piece,
Speaker 4:  just from a week ago, that Figma is like taking root inside of
Speaker 4:  Microsoft and Microsoft, Adobe have been very cozy and like it's actually
Speaker 4:  straining the relationship. Who knows? I do think that if you're in a world
Speaker 4:  where Lena Kahn wants to block meta from buying supernatural
Speaker 4:  an app that only runs on the quest because she's like,
Speaker 4:  there's not enough competition. And everyone seems to want to stop
Speaker 4:  Microsoft from buying Activision based on call of duty alone.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. That Adobe, which has Adobe XD buying its
Speaker 4:  only real competitor in Figma probably needs to get stopped. It
Speaker 4:  maybe, maybe it's too wonky. You know, maybe, maybe the FTC doesn't know,
Speaker 4:  know what Figma is, but in this world it's like a big,
Speaker 4:  big deal. And so I don't we'll see. I, I would just imagine they're gonna
Speaker 4:  charge head first into antitrust time.
Speaker 6:  I just can't like, I, I feel the O Adobe has been
Speaker 6:  this company. We always kind of dance around when it comes to antitrust because
Speaker 6:  they, they have effective monopolies in a number of places, including like
Speaker 6:  that, that image, you know, Photoshop, like it's Photoshop, you go
Speaker 6:  somewhere and they say, can you do Photoshop? That's like, that's it.
Speaker 6:  And I wonder why it's taken this long
Speaker 6:  for the antitrust eye to even glance.
Speaker 4:  Well, it hasn't glanced. They're like, we're gonna buy Figma. I mean,
Speaker 6:  I feel like probably glancing right now for, I feel like Lena Conns on the
Speaker 6:  verge right now. She's seen it. Yeah. She knows she's G
Speaker 4:  Glanced, whatever. When Microsoft set out to my activation, there was like,
Speaker 4:  there was a run up of like Microsoft
Speaker 4:  executives saying how open they were gonna be like, you know, they accept
Speaker 4:  the stage, you know? Like we love openness. We are gonna do
Speaker 4:  our UB. Not we're good. Yeah. Right. And then when they announced it,
Speaker 4:  they announced all these principles. They've been trying to say that
Speaker 4:  call of duty. I think Tom has reported this. Like they sent a letter to
Speaker 4:  Sony by just doing some math based on what they're saying. Yeah. It's
Speaker 4:  seven years of a commitment. They haven't said seven years. Exactly.
Speaker 4:  But they said a few more years in the existing deal. It's like, you just
Speaker 4:  like, you have to like know like you can add it up. And it's like seven years.
Speaker 4:  Like Microsoft did a lot of like pre-work around
Speaker 4:  regulators to like butter them up into improving. Adobe's still not gonna
Speaker 4:  succeed maybe. Right. Like it's still getting all this scrutiny.
Speaker 4:  Adobe's like, I we're just mind Figma.
Speaker 6:  So why somebody it's wild. Because I feel like I see
Speaker 6:  more complaints about the monopoly at, at Adobe than I do
Speaker 6:  even Google and Microsoft and Facebook and everybody else that we
Speaker 6:  talk about be, excuse me, meta being these big antitrust nightmares.
Speaker 4:  I think one of the reasons, well, one Photoshop is Photoshop. Yeah. There
Speaker 4:  are a lot of competitors to Photoshop in the world. Yeah. Right. And the
Speaker 4:  switching cost is actually like zero right apart from
Speaker 4:  Photoshop files in the cloud or
Speaker 6:  Whatever. But they're not like it's still, most people expect Photoshop to
Speaker 6:  be the thing you use.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. But that's just like, the market has picked a thing that you use, like
Speaker 4:  Adobe is not out there locking you into Photoshop. Like the
Speaker 4:  world of ad agencies is like, we use Photoshop, right? Like here's the skill
Speaker 4:  you need to have to work at this. Company's fine. And then with XD
Speaker 4:  the design program, like Figma was winning. Right? So like
Speaker 4:  the, you know, like the people complain a lot about how much creative cloud
Speaker 4:  costs and to become a young creative in the world. You gotta pay all
Speaker 4:  this money a month just to show up at work. Yeah. I it's an expensive
Speaker 4:  proposition and maybe they should be cheaper, but like one to one for those
Speaker 4:  apps, like final cut exists. It is meaningful
Speaker 4:  competition to premiere, I guess like
Speaker 4:  there are lots of image editors that are not Photoshop. The fact that the
Speaker 4:  industry is set a standard for its professional software, I think is
Speaker 4:  like, fine. It's here where there's like a people are
Speaker 4:  not using the Adobe app. They're using this app from a startup and Adobe's
Speaker 4:  like, whatever, we're just buying it to foreclose competition that you, you
Speaker 4:  get this scrutiny. Yeah. We'll see. I don't,
Speaker 5:  That's what it seems to smell like to a lot of people. Right. Which is like,
Speaker 5:  everybody has Facebook buying Instagram because Instagram was cool
Speaker 5:  on their mind right now. And that is like, that looks an awful lot. Like
Speaker 5:  what Adobe is doing here, they're saying, oh, they've figured out something.
Speaker 5:  We can't. They're cool. We have to, we have to eat them before
Speaker 5:  they eat us. And like, that is just, that is a dynamic, people
Speaker 5:  are primed to see in a way that I think they have not been in a long time.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I don't know whether it's actually the case here. It certainly looks
Speaker 5:  like it on its face, but it's gonna be interesting. But I would be willing
Speaker 5:  to bet that the FTC has never once had a meeting about Adobe with the possible
Speaker 5:  exception of like today or tomorrow. Like
Speaker 6:  Do it,
Speaker 4:  Do it, Adobe runs a gigantic ad business. Yeah. I think Adobe
Speaker 4:  is fundamentally one of the most undercover companies in tech. I think
Speaker 4:  it is absolutely fascinating and like totally agree. We have a new reporter
Speaker 4:  in the UK trust weathered. She is creative. She's part of the creative community.
Speaker 4:  Like she's, she's gonna write a story about the Figma community and the reaction
Speaker 4:  to Adobe. And I'm excited to point her more directly to Adobe overall.
Speaker 4:  Okay. Alex, I just want you to explain one more thing before we go. Okay.
Speaker 6:  What's that?
Speaker 4:  I'm just gonna read this headline that you wrote.
Speaker 5:  Oh, I know what it is already. Hell yeah.
Speaker 6:  It's a great
Speaker 4:  Headline. I've I've read it so many times and I didn't read this story just
Speaker 4:  because I was like, I'm gonna try to make Alex explain this to me. Disney's
Speaker 4:  CEO teases, a quote, hard bundle of Disney
Speaker 4:  plus and Hulu. And the sub-headline is the current
Speaker 4:  soft bundle is so confusing. They have an ad campaign to explain
Speaker 4:  it. And it turns out that I have no idea what any of this means.
Speaker 4:  Alex,
Speaker 5:  Could you tell us first all of your rejected headline ideas,
Speaker 6:  They're not safe for the podcast community to
Speaker 6:  hear,
Speaker 6:  but yeah, I didn't know what a hard or a soft bundle
Speaker 6:  was until this week. When, when
Speaker 6:  Disney's CEO teased his stuff. Bob chap, where did he tease
Speaker 6:  this?
Speaker 4:  Bob two. Bob
Speaker 6:  Two. I actually don't remember where he teased this. I wrote this whole blog
Speaker 6:  and I forgot everything. Okay. So yeah, Bob chap spoke to
Speaker 6:  the Los Angeles times this past weekend. They, he was at D
Speaker 6:  23, which is Disney's big fan event. They announced a whole bunch of
Speaker 6:  movies, Marvel news, star wars stuff, tons of trailers,
Speaker 6:  new trailer for Willow, which only me and four other people are excited about.
Speaker 6:  But boy are we excited? And he kept talking
Speaker 6:  about hard and soft bundles. Like this was just part of the conversation
Speaker 6:  they were having. And a soft bundle is, is when you take
Speaker 6:  a whole bunch,
Speaker 5:  It's imagining somebody going up to Bob in the middle and being like Bob,
Speaker 5:  you know, people can hear you. Don't talk about this. Wait,
Speaker 4:  What? Okay, what is a soft bundle?
Speaker 6:  So a soft bundle is what, what we have have now, which is
Speaker 6:  Hulu plus plus plus or whatever. They're calling it at the moment.
Speaker 6:  So it's Hulu, it's the live TV. It's ESPN plus it's
Speaker 6:  Disney plus that's a soft bundle. Most companies are doing this.
Speaker 6:  HBO. Max is doing a soft bundle now with it and
Speaker 6:  discovery go a hard bundle is just an
Speaker 6:  app where all of the stuff is in one place. But instead of calling
Speaker 6:  it an app, they called it a hard bundle.
Speaker 4:  Okay. So a hard bundle is when they just make Hulu and Disney
Speaker 4:  plus the same app.
Speaker 6:  So, but Hulu Disney plus and ESPN, and it was really weird
Speaker 6:  how he phrased it because he
Speaker 6:  was talking about, it would be all of the experiences in one place.
Speaker 6:  But somehow saying that was different than an app that was just Hulu
Speaker 6:  and Disney plus merged together.
Speaker 4:  Right. Cause, well, you don't wanna make, you don't wanna mix the Hulu shows
Speaker 4:  with the Disney. So it's like an app with three tabs and that's a, yeah,
Speaker 6:  I think it'll be like you click into it and you'd be like ESPN, like an app
Speaker 6:  with sub apps.
Speaker 4:  What would that app be called? Would it be called the Disney hard bundle?
Speaker 6:  I hope so.
Speaker 5:  Be called Bob's hard bundle. That's that's what
Speaker 4:  We be called. That's it? That's the very chest. Everybody. We got
Speaker 4:  to the inevitable conclusion of this conversation. We tried
Speaker 4:  to avoid it for as long as we could. It took one minute and 18 seconds.
Speaker 4:  Thank you, David. We're very sorry. Liam will be
Speaker 4:  marking this episode as explicit. So kids guys tell your mom what happened
Speaker 4:  here and you can have a conversation about that with your parents.
Speaker 4:  I'm very sorry. That makes okay. It makes sense to me that they would like
Speaker 4:  make everything one app. Yeah. Right. But doesn't ESPN have
Speaker 4:  its own ESPN should be over there.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And I think that's what they're trying to figure out. And also are
Speaker 6:  they even gonna be able to buy Hulu because Comcast CEO this
Speaker 6:  week also was like, Hey, I know that we're, everybody's expecting us to sell
Speaker 6:  our 33% share to Disney, but maybe we want Hulu
Speaker 6:  and it would make sense. Well
Speaker 5:  That, and also the other thing Comcast said that I loved very much was
Speaker 5:  basically intimate. That what if Hulu is actually worth
Speaker 5:  1 trillion, they're like, we'll, we'll sell it to you.
Speaker 5:  But it is the most expensive thing in the history of
Speaker 5:  the universe. Disney. Do you still want it? But I will say to me the,
Speaker 5:  the, like there's a, there's a lesser version of this, I think,
Speaker 5:  which is basically just that they stay three separate things, but you have
Speaker 5:  to get all of them. And I think that would not totally shock me if Disney
Speaker 5:  is just like cable, this is the price. You get everything. It's
Speaker 5:  cable again. And it's like, oh, you don't watch sports, but you wanna watch
Speaker 5:  Disney movies. Like what's up everybody. It's 1992. Again,
Speaker 5:  you're gonna pay for it. Yeah. And if Disney wants to fund all the stuff
Speaker 5:  it wants to do, especially with ESPN, it's basically gonna have to force
Speaker 5:  a lot of people who don't wanna watch sports to pay for sports. So I would
Speaker 5:  not be at all shocked if that's where this lands,
Speaker 4:  I'm required to say that Comcast is an investor in Fox
Speaker 4:  media, parent company.
Speaker 5:  We also made a Netflix show, which people should know. It's a good show.
Speaker 5:  You should watch it. If you
Speaker 4:  Haven't poly made a quibi show. That's a real thing that happened. It's
Speaker 5:  I also really liked the bear on. Who's clear by now. I dunno if that's a
Speaker 5:  disclosure, I should think it's very good.
Speaker 4:  That's true. Yeah. I watch NFL prime time on ESPN plus every
Speaker 4:  week. It's it's another disclosure. It's great show. Really great
Speaker 4:  music. The end.
Speaker 4:  Alright. We should wrap this up. We've gone way over, by the way. Speaking
Speaker 4:  of Comcast, they're rolling out two gig speeds to millions people. I, you
Speaker 4:  know, I usually have nothing but unre reserved scorn for this company,
Speaker 4:  but you know, I don't believe so actually faster access is pretty good. That's
Speaker 4:  true. But they're saying to millions. So if you've gotten two gig
Speaker 4:  internet access from Comcast late, let me know. I'm I'm very
Speaker 5:  Curious. And, and we'll all come over to your house. Hang
Speaker 4:  Out. Oh, shouts Chris Welch. He's he totally scooped the center sub mini,
Speaker 4:  which was announced it's 4 29. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  That was great.
Speaker 4:  Very good. Got that totally. Right. All right. Next
Speaker 4:  Wednesday, David, you're doing the hotline, right?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. We are gonna take all of people's burning apple questions. So
Speaker 5:  if you, anything you wanna know that we didn't cover or stuff that you have
Speaker 5:  feelings about, about apple 8 66 verge one, one, or
Speaker 5:  I should say, if you don't want call or can't, for some reason you
Speaker 5:  can record a voice memo and email it to vergecast@theverge.com. That
Speaker 5:  works great too. All your apple questions send 'em along.
Speaker 4:  And then on Monday we have a little mini series starting. Yeah. About the
Speaker 4:  future of music on this show, which I think would be very good. Alex, do
Speaker 4:  you have the first episode of that?
Speaker 6:  Yes, I will be on the first episode of that. And I am talking with Charlie
Speaker 6:  Harding, who is a music journalist and I believe
Speaker 6:  also on the V media network with his podcast. Switched on pop.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Switched on pop. Right. It's great. Charlie has been on the
Speaker 4:  other show that I'm not allowed to say in this show. That was a good episode.
Speaker 4:  We talked about.
Speaker 6:  You're not allowed to talk about it here. We only talk about the verge cast
Speaker 6:  and switched on pop and it's a really, really good conversation.
Speaker 6:  We revealed far too much about our musical taste. It was great.
Speaker 4:  That's great. Speaking of the other show onco next week is Ryan Peterson.
Speaker 4:  The CEO of Flexport he's spicy. So like sports
Speaker 4:  is like a logistics company. We had a little supply chain conversation. Very
Speaker 4:  good. It's good. I'm excited. Might have gotten himself into some
Speaker 4:  trouble at the end. We'll see how it goes for it is good. Just wanna talk
Speaker 4:  to him. You can tweet at us. I'm at reckless. David's at Pierce
Speaker 4:  Alex's Alex H Crans redesign is up. It's running.
Speaker 4:  We are not going to revert it to the other way. I it's like such a weird
Speaker 4:  question, but we're, we're just gonna keep improving what we got, but I
Speaker 4:  promise you're gonna improve it. Thank you for visiting us in particular.
Speaker 4:  I want to hear from broadcast listeners about it, cuz the whole point of
Speaker 4:  the side is a community and this podcast is the heart of our community.
Speaker 4:  So by all means, reach out to us with feedback. We are eager to hear it.
Speaker 4:  That's it. Let's show chef rock roll.
Speaker 1:  And that's a wrap for Vergecast this week. Thanks for listening. If you enjoy
Speaker 1:  the show, subscribe in the podcast app of your choice or tell a friend, you
Speaker 1:  can send us feedback at vergecast@theverge.com. This show is produced by
Speaker 1:  me, Liam, James and our senior audio director. Andrew Marino. This
Speaker 1:  episode was edited and mixed by Amanda Rose Smith. Our editorial
Speaker 1:  director is Brooke mentors and our executive producer is Eleanor Donovan.
Speaker 1:  The verge cast is a production of the verge and box media podcast network.
Speaker 1:  And that's it. We'll see you next week
Speaker 13:  Support for this episode comes from Salesforce. Did you know that pivot
Speaker 13:  is now on Salesforce plus it's Salesforce's new streaming service
Speaker 13:  where you can now stream award-winning original series live experiences
Speaker 13:  and virtual learning with Salesforce. Plus business leaders can
Speaker 13:  tap into the latest engaging inspirational stories and get thought
Speaker 13:  leadership and expert advice on demand. Join for free and watch new
Speaker 13:  business series like pivot on demand@salesforce.com slash.