# Transcript
ID: 27f4b850-cd06-11ec-880c-edc9be0ded90
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: "After Steve" author Tripp Mickle / Fortnite’s back on iOS / Sonos’s voice assistant
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-1743408713013973014/-3318446657850937190/s93290-US-4801s-1651818548.mp3
Description: Nilay Patel and David Pierce chat with Tripp Mickle, a New York Times reporter and the author of a new book titled After Steve: How Apple Became a Trillion-Dollar Company and Lost its Soul. They talk about the rise of Jony Ive and Tim Cook, the power struggle between the two, and how Apple is grappling with everything from building a car to managing its relationship with the Chinese government.
After that, Verge managing editor Alex Cranz joins the show to talk about Starlink’s new Portability mode, HP’s super high-end new Chromebook, Fortnite coming back to iOS courtesy of Xbox Cloud Gaming, Sonos’s upcoming soundbar and voice assistant, and why Siri can’t seem to successfully close Nilay’s garage.
Speaker 1:  This week on the verge cast author trip Mikkel joins the show to tell us
Speaker 1:  about his new book. After Steve is Johnny ive, his real
Speaker 1:  source. Then Alex cran comes on to tell us all about this
Speaker 1:  week in gadget scores. That's coming up right after
Speaker 1:  this.
Speaker 3:  Hello and welcome to the verge cast the flagship podcast, the form
Speaker 3:  over function. It looks good, David. What's up, man?
Speaker 5:  Hi, I'm David Pearson. I'm your friend who will always loan you a billion
Speaker 5:  dollars when you want to buy it Twitter.
Speaker 3:  There you go. Oh, by the way, I'm Nila. I'm also your friend. I will not
Speaker 3:  give you any money for any reason. We've got a great show for you today,
Speaker 3:  David, I'm going to talk to Tripp Mikel, who just wrote a book called after
Speaker 3:  Steve. We talked about in the show last week. It's all about apple. And
Speaker 3:  the 10 years after Steve jobs died, very much focused on Tim cook and
Speaker 3:  Johnny Ives. And then a little later, Alex Cranz is going to join us with
Speaker 3:  toxin gadgets. David, you worked with Tripp.
Speaker 5:  I did. So we overlapped when we were both at the wall street journal a
Speaker 5:  few years ago and I got to see him sort of spin up on the apple beet
Speaker 5:  and apple, as we have found many times is an
Speaker 5:  absolutely impossible company to get inside. Like it is its culture
Speaker 5:  of secrecy goes way back. And it is like
Speaker 5:  based on this being this tiny insular thing where like even the people who
Speaker 5:  work there don't know what the other people who work there are working on.
Speaker 5:  So I got to watch him sort of piece by piece, like get inside the company
Speaker 5:  and start to understand how it works. And I think he said, he's been working
Speaker 5:  on this book for like five years, which would track back to kind of when
Speaker 5:  I started working with him and he did a great job. Like most
Speaker 5:  books I've read about apple are about a product
Speaker 5:  and there they have this sort one very specific thread. Right? And you talk
Speaker 5:  to you talk to suppliers and you talk to people kind of around this thing
Speaker 5:  to understand like how a product came to be. But he got into like
Speaker 5:  how the company works and talked about org structures
Speaker 5:  and relationships between people and the kind of thing you just don't get.
Speaker 5:  A lot of, I really enjoyed the book and I know you did too.
Speaker 3:  I did. I think you'll hear it when we talk to, to trip. But you
Speaker 3:  know, the book is structured around two big characters, Tim cook and Johnny
Speaker 3:  eyes, and you can read it in a couple of different ways. All of those
Speaker 3:  ways will make people mad. You can read it is Johnny. I was the
Speaker 3:  sole of Apple's design and he left. And now apple is this like
Speaker 3:  services, drug or not financial company. I think a lot of people
Speaker 3:  think that about apple and that some of that there's evidence for that in
Speaker 3:  the book, but that's not the whole book. You can read it as Johnny. I've
Speaker 3:  got disengaged and Apple's design went sideways with iOS
Speaker 3:  seven and the first generation watch, which was pretty messy. And then he
Speaker 3:  left and everything got better. You can read it as Tim cook grew into the
Speaker 3:  role and became very confident after taking over for Steve jobs. Like there's
Speaker 3:  all these ways to read this book. And like I said, I think all of them make
Speaker 3:  everybody mad, but I think that's like the sign that
Speaker 3:  it's, it has the reporting to back up all of those claims.
Speaker 5:  Totally. And I think th the other only one I would add to that is that there
Speaker 5:  is just like, there's an unbearable hugeness of apple now
Speaker 5:  that like the company just got so big and had so much
Speaker 5:  money. And like, there's a, there's a bit in the book about when Warren buffet
Speaker 5:  invested in the company and there's this feeling of like, oh my God, this
Speaker 5:  means like regular people's money. Now it depends on the stuff that apple
Speaker 5:  does. And just like what that did to the culture of the company and the
Speaker 5:  fighting internally and all the people who wanted to be in charge of things.
Speaker 5:  And everybody's making hilarious amounts of money along the way. And it's,
Speaker 5:  it's just wild, but yeah, you can kind of take anything away from it you
Speaker 5:  want, and you're probably right.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. And it's, again, I think it's cause trip to the great shot reporting.
Speaker 3:  It that's enough of us. We should actually just talk to trip. Here we go.
Speaker 3:  Trip Mikel trip, Mikel. You are the author of
Speaker 3:  after Steve a book, which on this very show I
Speaker 3:  described as making everyone mad, welcome to the virtuous.
Speaker 6:  Thanks so much for having me. I like, I like getting people riled up. That's
Speaker 6:  why I'm here.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. The book is absolutely fascinating. It is about effectively the
Speaker 3:  relationship between Tim cook and Johnny ive, famous apple. If you're listening
Speaker 3:  to virtuous, you know who these people are like, you just, I dunno what you're
Speaker 3:  doing here, but it's about Tim cook and Johnny ive and how they grew into
Speaker 3:  their roles and out of their roles after the death of Steve jobs, why did
Speaker 3:  you start chasing this book? Then?
Speaker 6:  It's interesting. When I landed at the journal in 17, after coming
Speaker 6:  off what we call the sin, beat alcohol and tobacco, I had a cup of coffee
Speaker 6:  with John Markoff and he was like, you know, one thing you should really
Speaker 6:  look into is Johnny ive and the battery. And that's, that's about all
Speaker 6:  John John said, and I started asking questions and learn
Speaker 6:  pretty quickly that Johnny was growing disillusioned with, with
Speaker 6:  apple. And I just thought that was so interesting. How could you, how could
Speaker 6:  you help build this great company and then begin to kind of
Speaker 6:  fall out of love with it? So to speak, it just made me wonder what was, what
Speaker 6:  was behind the line. So I just kept asking more and more questions and eventually
Speaker 6:  he left in 2019.
Speaker 5:  Did this start out to be kind of a Johnny and Tim
Speaker 5:  story? Because part of what was so interesting to me about this as like the,
Speaker 5:  the initial frame is like, it's the sort of the story of Apple's decade,
Speaker 5:  right? And then almost immediately it's the Johnny and Tim story,
Speaker 5:  which to some extent makes sense, right? Like they're the two most important
Speaker 5:  people, the company, but like, was it obvious at the jump that, like, those
Speaker 5:  were the two main characters of this story,
Speaker 6:  The privilege that you're granted, when you get to do a book, as you, you're
Speaker 6:  given time to, to think and let the story kind of unfold,
Speaker 6:  as you think through structure and your, and, and what's your focus
Speaker 6:  on, and from the outset, I was planning to do the decade at
Speaker 6:  apple after Steve jobs. That was really the intention. But the
Speaker 6:  more I looked at that, the more, I felt like the best way to tell that
Speaker 6:  story was by chronicling the history of,
Speaker 6:  of Johnny and Tim. And so for a lot of readers who come to this, they're
Speaker 6:  going to say, well, why am I getting the history of apple all over
Speaker 6:  again? I I've, I've learned this from Isaacson's book, et cetera, but
Speaker 6:  you're going to get a different window into that because you're going to
Speaker 6:  be looking at Apple's history, history through Johnny Ives work,
Speaker 6:  and then through Tim Cook's work. And it just, it just lent itself to tell
Speaker 6:  the entire apple story through these two characters and
Speaker 6:  figures that are, that are so prominent at the company and really were, were
Speaker 6:  who jobs set up to lead the company toward it? It kind of naturally evolved
Speaker 6:  that way, honestly.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. So one of the central dynamics in the book and at apple
Speaker 3:  is before Steve jobs dies, he anoints
Speaker 3:  Johnny is that absolutely have designed and says, I set up the company said
Speaker 3:  no one can get in his way. And then no one got in his way. And some of the
Speaker 3:  problems that's true. And some of the products went completely sideways.
Speaker 3:  Meantime, Tim cook is casting about for Apple's
Speaker 3:  next big thing. And I don't know if anybody remembers that first year, 20
Speaker 3:  11, 20 12, Tim cook was like going on TV and saying, we're going to do it.
Speaker 3:  We're going to do TV stuff. Because jobs had ended the book by saying he'd
Speaker 3:  finally cracked TV, which seems like just a masterful troll at this
Speaker 3:  point. It is very unclear what he meant when he said to Walter
Speaker 3:  Isaacson, I've cracked it. And so apple, I chases after effort for a year
Speaker 3:  and they chase that for a car and they do all this other stuff. And it seems
Speaker 3:  like Tim cook is looking over there and he's given I've control over
Speaker 3:  the product portfolio, which I mean, apple is like the most successful company
Speaker 3:  in the world, but some of the products went completely sideways during this
Speaker 3:  period, right? The butterfly keyboard, the phones got thinner.
Speaker 3:  Like it just, there's a really weird moment for apple design in there.
Speaker 3:  That's my perspective from the outside. But reading the book, it seems like
Speaker 3:  there's actually more tension between the two than one's ever revealed,
Speaker 6:  Sir. I mean, there's, it's, it's an unspoken power struggle kind of over
Speaker 6:  what will be core to the company's future. You know,
Speaker 6:  Tim needs a new product category essentially after
Speaker 6:  Steve jobs stuff, because that's what the outside world is demanding and
Speaker 6:  pressuring apple to deliver. There was a lot of expectation for that.
Speaker 6:  And Johnny ive was the natural person to, to bring that forward. And the
Speaker 6:  watch was that answer. Ultimately, that's what they went with.
Speaker 6:  And then at the same time wall, Street's never satisfied. So Tim
Speaker 6:  cook has to almost think about, well, what's the next thing beyond that?
Speaker 6:  And the answer winds up being the services business that apple
Speaker 6:  unveiled really officially in, in 2019, but was
Speaker 6:  gradually building through the course of the beets
Speaker 6:  acquisition and some of the other product introductions along the
Speaker 6:  way.
Speaker 5:  I think power struggle is a really interesting way to put it because there's
Speaker 5:  a weird dynamic between the two of them where they never seemed to
Speaker 5:  fight. Like I kept waiting for like the meeting where Johnny and Tim like
Speaker 5:  had it out and it never really happened. They just sort of
Speaker 5:  increasingly like diverge paths. And Johnny did his thing while Tim did his
Speaker 5:  thing. And because Tim is CEO and because they were making a hell of a lot
Speaker 5:  of money Tim's way kept winning and Johnny just sort of fell further
Speaker 5:  and further apart from everything that apple was doing and then started to
Speaker 5:  distance himself and everything went away. But it was, it was just so interesting
Speaker 5:  to me to watch just like Tim, just sort of like subsume
Speaker 5:  everything, at least as far as I could tell, without any particular
Speaker 5:  like angry power grab over the design team.
Speaker 6:  Well, that's just a reflection of Tim's own inscrutability right. I mean,
Speaker 6:  there's, there's this, there's a certain degree of unknowability about him,
Speaker 6:  his relationships with people aren't as strong
Speaker 6:  as say, jobs, individual relationships with a lot of people were. And so
Speaker 6:  it's an, it's a natural outgrowth of that. And then also Tim's
Speaker 6:  decision to be deferential to the creative people.
Speaker 6:  He, the way apple was structured when jobs was alive
Speaker 6:  was jobs was at the, at the center of it. And the creative people were in
Speaker 6:  the, in the ring right around him. And that's what he was kind of
Speaker 6:  migrating around. I mean, from meetings with design
Speaker 6:  team, to meetings, with the software, people, to meetings with the advertising
Speaker 6:  people to come up with the next creative ads and everything else. And
Speaker 6:  then beyond that in the ring outside of that
Speaker 6:  was operations and finance
Speaker 6:  and legal and some of the other aspects of the company
Speaker 6:  and what happened when jobs died and Tim cook became CEO is all
Speaker 6:  of a sudden the operations people came to the interior of the company.
Speaker 6:  It's almost like throwing a rock into a pond and they were just ripples that
Speaker 6:  kind of float across everything. And everyone tried to
Speaker 6:  reassess how they fit into this new world. And Tim's
Speaker 6:  choice in that new world was not to try to replace Steve, not to get involved
Speaker 6:  in product because he didn't feel comfortable doing so
Speaker 3:  How do you see that playing out with things like beets, right? Where
Speaker 3:  he actually brought in some very powerful creatives, like the
Speaker 3:  idea that Trent Reznor was ever an apple employee is like, to me very funny,
Speaker 3:  right? Like it's just a track, but you're right. He buys his
Speaker 3:  company because he wants to get into services and he sees that they've already
Speaker 3:  built something they want, he's got a headphone company to deal with as well.
Speaker 3:  That's a big integration. It's like still one of Apple's biggest deals
Speaker 3:  ever, but he brought in these huge creatives from my
Speaker 3:  perspective on the outside. Never really did anything. But in, in your
Speaker 3:  book there, they're like in the background of a lot of things in
Speaker 3:  complicated ways, like how did that dynamic play out
Speaker 6:  There's pressure at that point in time, right? To satisfy wall street, deliver
Speaker 6:  more growth. And one of the easiest ways to deliver growth is to acquire
Speaker 6:  it. The fascinating thing to me in reporting this and, and the
Speaker 6:  fascinating thing to a lot of the beets staff who were
Speaker 6:  acquired was once they got inside apple, they realized that apple had
Speaker 6:  been at work already on building out a subscription music
Speaker 6:  business. But there was some for whatever reason, there were some
Speaker 6:  disfat satisfaction internally with what that looked like and
Speaker 6:  are in a field that they needed some help from the beats creative team.
Speaker 6:  So that's why they went out and they brought him beat. They refashioned beats,
Speaker 6:  they released apple music. It's a course flawed. And
Speaker 6:  then, you know, lo and behold, not that long afterwards, all of the beats
Speaker 6:  staff kind of peel away eventually because this is a
Speaker 6:  giant company with very well-defined rules. And it's not
Speaker 6:  kind of the, I don't know, the, the kind of
Speaker 6:  rambunctious rebellious place that Jimmy Ivan had
Speaker 6:  fashioned beats music.
Speaker 3:  But that to me is like, right, as apple becomes this bigger content company.
Speaker 3:  And now they've got these big Hollywood ambitions, the interplay between
Speaker 3:  the inscrutability of Tim cook, the nature of
Speaker 3:  Apple's brand, and then the reality of making good
Speaker 3:  art, whether that's music or movies or whatever those things are
Speaker 3:  like in conflict. And that seems like one of the hardest challenges
Speaker 3:  that Tim very personally has been dealing with outside
Speaker 3:  of Johnny Ives, making iOS seven look insane. Right? Like it
Speaker 3:  seems like that was more of a distraction than the products, which is really
Speaker 3:  fascinating to me.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, absolutely. Yeah. It's an, it's an interesting point, I think. Well,
Speaker 6:  is that the journal we had, we had fun with a piece about Hollywood
Speaker 6:  adjusting to Apple's arrival and its expectations for what
Speaker 6:  content should look like and include. And there
Speaker 6:  was some real trepidation inside apple early on about
Speaker 6:  showing anything with too much vulgarity,
Speaker 6:  nudity, et cetera. They really wanted kind of a clean cut
Speaker 6:  image. And they've since abandoned some of those
Speaker 6:  inclinations and they've adopted a bit more of an HBO style
Speaker 6:  approach. There's obviously some, I don't know, some
Speaker 6:  interesting content like within the morning show and everything else
Speaker 6:  that suggests that they've made peace with being more dynamic, but I found
Speaker 6:  it fascinating to see that they won a best picture for Coda, which
Speaker 6:  for all intents and purposes, like Disney could have made that movie. Right.
Speaker 6:  I mean, it's a, it is a really feel good film.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It's the exact kind of thing that I'm sure Tim cook was like thrilled
Speaker 5:  to win for. Whereas like I've been watching the show, shining girls on TV
Speaker 5:  plus, which is basically just all about women dying and being
Speaker 5:  murdered and going back and like thinking about that piece, you did where
Speaker 5:  Tim cook is like mad that there's cursing in some of the shows it's like,
Speaker 5:  boy, things have changed.
Speaker 6:  And part of that speaks to, to this, this kind of like
Speaker 6:  persistence and cautiousness that they approach things
Speaker 6:  with. Now, I think for a lot of people, that's, that's been the jarring thing
Speaker 6:  about watching apple lately is they remember the, the
Speaker 6:  two thousands and, and kind of all the perfect products that they
Speaker 6:  felt like they, they just arrived. Perfect. Some people forget that it
Speaker 6:  took a little while for the iPod to be as great as it was, but they have
Speaker 6:  this recollection of it being a perfect product. And they were watching and
Speaker 6:  struggling with like, well, why are they only having like 10 shows on this
Speaker 6:  new product that they've launched? You know, why is it taking so long to
Speaker 6:  build this? Why is, why is major league baseball? Why are there three people
Speaker 6:  in the booth? And then why are they, you know, why are they
Speaker 6:  struggling to explain what's going on in the game? There are these like moments
Speaker 6:  of imprecision that people are unaccustomed to, but I think that's
Speaker 6:  emblematic of this giant company trying to get things right
Speaker 6:  and having the leeway to do so because it's got so much
Speaker 6:  great reach with how many people who have an iPhone and everything else.
Speaker 3:  So the reason I wanted to start with like TV and content and just lay that
Speaker 3:  foundation, because right now it's very clear that Tim cook cares about Hollywood
Speaker 3:  and he wants celebrities on his streaming platforms. I think that's all just
Speaker 3:  a cover for the real services revenue, which is in that purchases and games.
Speaker 3:  And he has to talk about re Reese Witherspoon said, but right. It's very
Speaker 3:  clear that he's engaged that part of the industry like Hollywood
Speaker 3:  and apple are very close now, but a huge part of the book
Speaker 3:  is Johnny Ives saying we're a fashion company now and bringing in a bunch
Speaker 3:  of fashion people, especially around the watch and
Speaker 3:  losing focus on products. Like he's like, there's a line. I actually
Speaker 3:  sent a screen, a, I took a picture of the book and sent it to Walt
Speaker 3:  Mossberg. Or Johnny's like, our future is in the hands of like Anna
Speaker 3:  Wintour, not Walmart's bird. And while it was like, well, it turned
Speaker 3:  out, we were still pretty important, but that dynamic, right. You
Speaker 3:  see, I'm just curious how you see that evolution, that they, they went really
Speaker 3:  hard at fashion with a watch. It distracted them from making the products
Speaker 3:  really great, the watch in particular. But now they're back to
Speaker 3:  Hollywood. Like they're back in that same cultural sphere.
Speaker 3:  They tried really hard with Johnny, but Tim has sort of like diligently got
Speaker 3:  himself back into.
Speaker 6:  It's interesting that you raise that and you bring up the fashion thing.
Speaker 6:  I really wrestled with that and came into reporting on that with the
Speaker 6:  same mindset that a lot of people look back on that
Speaker 6:  period with this day in age, where they say like, why the
Speaker 6:  heck did they do that? And I was curious about that as I, as I went into
Speaker 6:  it and I left through my reporting somewhat persuaded that that actually
Speaker 6:  was not a misguided focus. There's a scene that a lot of people point
Speaker 6:  to who worked on the watch from the devil wears Prada,
Speaker 6:  where the woman who's kind of playing the character of Anna Wintour.
Speaker 6:  Upbraids the Anne Hathaway character over having on this
Speaker 6:  surillian blue sweater and not realizing that it was
Speaker 6:  introduced in fashion two years earlier. And the entire reason
Speaker 6:  that gap is selling it is because that it was on a runway
Speaker 6:  two years before and internally inside apple, for those
Speaker 6:  who kind of were on the fashion leaning side of this thing, that
Speaker 6:  was, that was important because they were introducing a watch that was going
Speaker 6:  to look identical. And if you, if you think back to your early reviews of
Speaker 6:  it, that was one of the things I think you struggled with was, well, this,
Speaker 6:  this looks the same from, from on everybody's wrist and that's
Speaker 6:  not the way watches typically were. So they needed the endorsement
Speaker 6:  of society's tastemakers in order to get that thing off the ground.
Speaker 6:  The problem was that maybe they lean too far into that. And they had to
Speaker 6:  course correct relatively quickly and get into the fitness aspect of it
Speaker 6:  so that people could use it. But really the, ultimately the problem was it
Speaker 6:  just didn't have any battery life. Like if you look back, you know, it just,
Speaker 6:  it, you know, it was dead half the time it was on your wrist. Like that's,
Speaker 6:  that's not the most useful product.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. The thing that really jumped out to me was that like, there's a lot
Speaker 5:  of the apple marketing team in this book, which I think is appropriate. And
Speaker 5:  like I've had, I still remember a bunch of years ago, an apple exec who was
Speaker 5:  like leaving the company. He was talking to me and they were like, yeah,
Speaker 5:  the only smart people who work at apple are all in the marketing team. And
Speaker 5:  they're, they're kind of all over this book. And the thing that struck me
Speaker 5:  about the watch thing was that like the fashion piece of it was smart marketing,
Speaker 5:  I think you're right. And they were like, they were talking about it as like
Speaker 5:  the most personal device. And they had all these different bands and like
Speaker 5:  there's a world in which that could have worked. It's just that the product
Speaker 5:  wasn't that good. And there's so much of it in this book where it's like
Speaker 5:  Johnny really wanted to build a watch. He didn't really know why the health
Speaker 5:  stuff didn't really work. The fitness stuff. Wasn't ready. The battery
Speaker 5:  wasn't very good. It's just like, they, they didn't have the thing to
Speaker 5:  sell in the same way that they did with the iPhone. So if they had like had
Speaker 5:  a very good product and then sold it as fashion, it would have worked. But
Speaker 5:  that was the only thing it had going for it in those earliest days. And the
Speaker 5:  only thing they were selling about it. And it felt like that to me, was where
Speaker 5:  it was like, okay, this is just the part that they missed.
Speaker 6:  And that's, that's some of the shakeout that you see kind of post Steve.
Speaker 6:  There was a, there's a great moment at the end of one chapter, as they're
Speaker 6:  about to launch the watch where you have the lead engineer, pull
Speaker 6:  aside Jeff Williams and say, Jeff, I'm going to ask you a question. If you
Speaker 6:  came to work today and you forgot your iPhone, what would you do? And Jeff
Speaker 6:  said something to the effect about I'd go home and get, get my iPhone. Like
Speaker 6:  I need my iPhone to make it through a day. And the engineer looks at him,
Speaker 6:  says, well, if you forgot your watch, what would you do? I guess I get it
Speaker 6:  when I got home. And the engineer's point was, that's the reason we can't
Speaker 6:  launch this product. It's not ready. It's not something people need to
Speaker 6:  have. I think they've gotten there over time, but it's taken quite
Speaker 6:  some time to get there.
Speaker 3:  So two things, one, I love the devil wears Prada. I watch it whenever it's
Speaker 3:  on TV, it's a good
Speaker 5:  Scene too.
Speaker 3:  It's a good scene. And I think that I'm Anne Hathaway and my wife has always
Speaker 3:  reminded me that I'm not assuming It's a real problem.
Speaker 3:  Explains a lot about how the verge works. But in that, I just want to put
Speaker 3:  our focus on the watches, a gadget, right? My pushback, when I wrote through
Speaker 3:  a view of the first watch was like, this thing is a mess, right? It's actually
Speaker 3:  not a very good gadget. And maybe you can talk all this game about
Speaker 3:  fashion and you can tell me that the digital crown is a
Speaker 3:  revolutionary input device on par with the mouse and the
Speaker 3:  touch, which is what they said, right. But the underlying work
Speaker 3:  to make this thing a great gadget isn't there. And it's when they
Speaker 3:  made it a great gadget that it became this huge success and they didn't actually
Speaker 3:  need all the fashion focus. If they had just made a great gadget
Speaker 3:  from the jump, the fashion stuff would have just come along for the ride.
Speaker 3:  That feels like to me, where apple got lost, when they started taking for
Speaker 3:  granted that they would make great gadgets and the industry would follow
Speaker 3:  them. And what they really were, what was like a lifestyle
Speaker 3:  company. Right? And that's where you get, at least from my
Speaker 3:  perspective is just someone who like, thinks about the products
Speaker 3:  themselves. That's where you get, well, we're going to take all the ports
Speaker 3:  off the computer. And you're just going to Johnny is going to
Speaker 3:  change the industry because he wants fewer reports on the
Speaker 3:  computer or the phone's going to be a little too thin and maybe it'll bend
Speaker 3:  a little bit, eat more easily than it should. Or the battery life will be
Speaker 3:  really low. And then he leaves and like apple
Speaker 3:  corrects that stuff really fast, right? They go back to making really great
Speaker 3:  gadgets. Is that all Johnny in that moment, that's like pushing it
Speaker 3:  towards more aesthetic features or is it a push and pull?
Speaker 6:  It's certainly a consequence of his philosophy
Speaker 6:  and a push gradually towards thinness. And a lot of
Speaker 6:  people will come at this book and be like, well, why didn't you write about
Speaker 6:  the butterfly keyboard and the fiasco there. And you, anytime
Speaker 6:  you're, you're a writer, you guys can appreciate this. You do this all the
Speaker 6:  time. You got to pick and choose. You gotta, you gotta make choices. And
Speaker 6:  especially with something like a book, it's got to connect across like a
Speaker 6:  long period of time. That was something that I chose not to
Speaker 6:  focus on because in my reporting and you all's reporting may differ from
Speaker 6:  this. I kept hearing that that was more of an
Speaker 6:  engineering shortcoming than anything else.
Speaker 6:  And that engineers had allowed that to
Speaker 6:  happen rather than the designers now, philosophically, what were the
Speaker 6:  engineers trying to do? Fulfill the expectations of designers who wanted
Speaker 6:  things to be thinner, that, that those were kind of the marching orders
Speaker 6:  and is partly an outgrowth of this culture that
Speaker 6:  was directly descended from jobs, empowering design
Speaker 6:  so much and turning these guys into kind of the
Speaker 6:  jetties who can do no wrong inside of apple. Right. That worked when
Speaker 6:  jobs was there as an editor, but it, it got out of whack
Speaker 6:  when they were, I guess, less left to their own devices.
Speaker 5:  Well, and wasn't it job. So has used to say like, design is how it works,
Speaker 5:  right? Like it, it feels like that's the part that seemed like it just sort
Speaker 5:  of fell apart over time to Neil's point that like, and I think you even kind
Speaker 5:  of say it at the end of the book, that, that it became like a form over function
Speaker 5:  company. And then Johnny is off, like spent helping build an office
Speaker 5:  where people keep running into the glass walls and which is just like, what
Speaker 5:  a perfect metaphor for the whole thing right there. And he's spending his
Speaker 5:  time on this, like one Leica camera and worrying about
Speaker 5:  the soap dispensers on his plane. And it, it just, you, you could just sort
Speaker 5:  of feel it fall away into like, fashion, right? It's
Speaker 5:  like, it's not about how the thing works
Speaker 3:  Well. So let me ask the hard question to follow up on David's point. I think
Speaker 3:  everybody should read this book. It will make everybody mad in different
Speaker 3:  directions. It's a good time. I would say the most, the experts that have
Speaker 3:  been published in the times and elsewhere, the thing that is like most
Speaker 3:  focused, that sort of anger is the sense that the book is about Tim
Speaker 3:  cook, letting Johnny ive getaway, right. And that Johnny ive drifting
Speaker 3:  off and not feeling engaged is somehow an error in apple has lost
Speaker 3:  its magic because of that, I would argue that actually he should have
Speaker 3:  clipped Johnny earlier and let him go when he was on his way out the
Speaker 3:  first time. Yep. In spare the company, that weird middle period where his
Speaker 3:  focus was split.
Speaker 5:  That's my read
Speaker 3:  Too. But I think a lot of people are mad about that idea too. So like where,
Speaker 3:  where do you come down having written this whole thing?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. That's a fair point. You can pick apart flaws and what
Speaker 6:  both men did. And then you also have to ground those flaws. And
Speaker 6:  the fact that both men were grieving. And, and that's something that I think
Speaker 6:  is just fundamental, that gets misplaced. When, whenever you talk
Speaker 6:  about this company, like for those who worked with jobs, you know, his
Speaker 6:  death and the fallout from that, and having to come back to work and
Speaker 6:  facing criticism and expectations externally, that's
Speaker 6:  really hard. That's really hard to deal with. And in the wake of that, they,
Speaker 6:  they galvanize themselves around the watch. And one of Johnny's
Speaker 6:  errors and doing that is he takes on a bunch of other
Speaker 6:  different projects concurrently with it. He takes
Speaker 6:  on the watch. He does the, like a camera at the same
Speaker 6:  time he's working on apple park.
Speaker 6:  And in addition to that, you know, forestall is fired
Speaker 6:  and he assumed responsibility for an influence over the
Speaker 6:  software design and the, and the user interface. And all of a sudden
Speaker 6:  has dozens of more employees that he's responsible for. I mean,
Speaker 6:  jobs have kept his, his responsibilities pretty
Speaker 6:  narrow. And in terms of like bureaucratic responsibilities of like
Speaker 6:  HR and managing staff and so on, so forth, because he wanted him to
Speaker 6:  focus on design and, and dreaming up products, Tim cook
Speaker 6:  allowed those things to happen. And also if you talk to people at
Speaker 6:  apple on the creative side, one of their frustrations is that
Speaker 6:  he didn't turn to people who had had a sense of how to
Speaker 6:  work with creatives and either listened to their advice. When they said
Speaker 6:  like, Hey, go buy, like, see Johnny and the design
Speaker 6:  studio work with your talent and recognize that
Speaker 6:  talent has different needs than some of the people you work with in
Speaker 6:  an, an operations. And so they were working inside the
Speaker 6:  same company, but really just speaking a totally different language. And
Speaker 6:  that's, and that's where the breakdown is. I, I think there's shared share
Speaker 6:  shortcomings in that. And you're probably right in 2015, if Johnny ive,
Speaker 6:  if you had, if you were the Monday morning quarterback and Johnny ive came
Speaker 6:  to you and said like, look, I'm burned out. I'm tired. I want to leave. The
Speaker 6:  better thing to do is probably just let him go. You're right. But Tim cook
Speaker 6:  was so afraid after taking over the reins of
Speaker 6:  CEO, that the core leadership group that jobs had left
Speaker 6:  behind would abandoned him. That, that, that was something that
Speaker 6:  he was, he just couldn't stomach the idea of Johnny ongoing at the time,
Speaker 6:  people said that he didn't want to be remembered as the CEO who let Johnny
Speaker 6:  ive walk out the door.
Speaker 3:  So the interesting juxtaposition of your book coming out is it's coming out
Speaker 3:  right next to Tony. Fidel's book about building things. If it all was obviously
Speaker 3:  an apple, he was just on decoder last week. And I, I asked
Speaker 3:  him, you know, Steve jobs manage this team of
Speaker 3:  gigantic personalities, right? It's Scott
Speaker 3:  forestall and Tony Fidel, and Johnny. And just down the line, these are huge
Speaker 3:  forceful characters. And you look at Tim Cook's apple,
Speaker 3:  and it's not there anymore. That just feels like the best U2
Speaker 3:  fan club that has ever existed. And they all drive their Aston Martin saran
Speaker 3:  together like that. And that's obviously a very cultivated image. Fidel's
Speaker 3:  point to me was, look, you just don't know about the, the absolute bloodsport
Speaker 3:  politics inside of a big company, unless you see it. But that is the image
Speaker 3:  that Cooke wanted. He did let go of forestall, who
Speaker 3:  was the biggest personality in that team had the most forceful vision for
Speaker 3:  how the software should work. And he has sanded off the rough edges
Speaker 3:  of the company. Do you think that's w I mean, obviously apple is like very
Speaker 3:  successful. So by one metric it's worked, but do you think it's worked?
Speaker 6:  That's what you lost when you lost job jobs, you lost an Uber
Speaker 6:  ego who really enjoyed managing other egos
Speaker 6:  and could do it because, because his word was final and everyone
Speaker 6:  respected him, he was able to kind of balance those things. And
Speaker 6:  what Tim cook saw to create was a more egalitarian
Speaker 6:  world where everybody had a voice and came to some
Speaker 6:  consensus before charting a path forward. And for
Speaker 6:  Johnny Ives, that was incredibly disorienting, right? He, he had
Speaker 6:  historically been sheltered from those kinds of conversations. And all of
Speaker 6:  a sudden, somebody with artistic sensibilities and an aversion to
Speaker 6:  conflict was thrust into a world where he had to build
Speaker 6:  consensus to achieve what he wanted to do. It just stood in such
Speaker 6:  contrast to what they were accustomed to. The forced, all of that to me is
Speaker 6:  still fascinating. I don't know what the answer is to this, but, you know,
Speaker 6:  not only had he jostled as Tony Fidel put, it
Speaker 6:  had some sense of bloodsport political bloodsport behind the scenes
Speaker 6:  before job's death. But he was also understood by his peers to be the only
Speaker 6:  one who considered himself to be
Speaker 6:  capable of being the CEO of the company. So Tim cook takes over and who's
Speaker 6:  the first person out the door. It's the only other person who really considered
Speaker 6:  himself potential successor as CEO. I don't know. I mean, I just
Speaker 6:  think that's, that's a really interesting choice.
Speaker 3:  We got to take a break, but when we come back, when I talked to trip about
Speaker 3:  how Tim cook became adept at working over politicians, we were at
Speaker 3:  back,
Speaker 6:  We're back with Tripp Mikel. A big piece of the book is Tim
Speaker 6:  cook having to become a politician. So I would write, he's got to manage
Speaker 6:  all these egos. He's got all this apple stuff, he's handling the internal
Speaker 6:  politics of apple, but then the there's this, the rising pressure for Tim
Speaker 6:  cook to handle actual politics and to be Donald
Speaker 6:  Trump's best friend.
Speaker 5:  Great moment in the book, by the way, when it just like you just like turn
Speaker 5:  the page and all of a sudden it's, it's just like, oh, and then Donald Trump
Speaker 5:  happened.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Donald Trump happens. There's a trade war in China. There's a
Speaker 3:  moment which is not in the book, but I think is a signature
Speaker 3:  moment of that cook era where that he allows Trump
Speaker 3:  to announce a factory that already exists. And it's just a
Speaker 3:  deadline. Like he's the factor is there before making the same product
Speaker 3:  before and Trump got to re announce it, and this is just him learning to
Speaker 3:  play a game that maybe he didn't want to play, but now he has become
Speaker 3:  quite expert at how much of that is you were reporting out, came to the
Speaker 3:  fore that this actually became existential for apple and
Speaker 3:  became more important than butterfly keyboards.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it's, it's, it's there for two reasons because it is existential
Speaker 6:  for apple. And in, in many ways it is more important than the butterfly keyboards
Speaker 6:  it's representative of what Apple's become, which is a two and a half trillion
Speaker 6:  dollar empire onto its own. It's really a geopolitical force in the
Speaker 6:  world, not unlike the U S government or the
Speaker 6:  Chinese government, both are, are dependent on them on
Speaker 6:  apple, the U S government, because it's such a central part of our
Speaker 6:  economy and China, because it employs so many
Speaker 6:  people in China who were working on the iPhones and
Speaker 6:  everything else, my hope and people reading that as they have a deeper
Speaker 6:  appreciation for what apple is today, versus what
Speaker 6:  it was in 2011, when Tim cook first took over, these are, these are
Speaker 6:  the type of concerns that are really taking up his day.
Speaker 5:  There's a certain extent to that. That just seems like it was, it was coming
Speaker 5:  anyway. Like it's, it's a really interesting sort of what have to imagine,
Speaker 5:  like how Steve jobs would have dealt with those same things, because
Speaker 3:  You can't say trip, he just shook his head very
Speaker 3:  strongly
Speaker 5:  Because to some, some of them were coming anyway, right? Like I think
Speaker 5:  there's a lot of apple that has sort of led this to happen, like the way
Speaker 5:  that apple decided to work in China and the way that it decided to think
Speaker 5:  about privacy and stuff like that. But like Donald Trump was going to get
Speaker 5:  elected president no matter who was the CEO of apple. Right. And so I think
Speaker 5:  it just is an interesting sort of sliding doors moment to see, like how
Speaker 5:  would that have gone under a different CEO and would they have had to sort
Speaker 5:  of learn how to play the same game? Yeah.
Speaker 6:  There are a lot of people who who've worked closely with Tim and just
Speaker 6:  have complete admiration for the job he's done. And they just think that
Speaker 6:  if, if jobs were in charge of the company probably would be much less valuable.
Speaker 6:  And that, that everything that would've happened in the Trump years would
Speaker 6:  have just been a total fiasco and disaster. So full credit to
Speaker 6:  Tim for being able to, to not only increase the company's
Speaker 6:  value financially, but also navigate those
Speaker 6:  political, this choppy political waters that, that he did in that period.
Speaker 6:  And honestly, like that's probably more urgent for the company going
Speaker 6:  forward, you know what they're gonna, what they face and relation to
Speaker 6:  China, then whether or not they're going to make a car. I know that's disappointing
Speaker 6:  for listeners of the Vergecast, but that's, I think that
Speaker 6:  speaks to Apple's role in society today
Speaker 6:  and in a way that you would have never imagined it would in the
Speaker 6:  2000 to 2010 Camelot era of apple and all these amazing
Speaker 6:  products.
Speaker 3:  I'm just curious for your read on this. I would say that Cook's ability to
Speaker 3:  manage Trump and China and the trade war and the increasing
Speaker 3:  political scrutiny and regulatory scrutiny of apple on the one hand, his
Speaker 3:  greatest success, right? He's done a masterful job at that. His, his, I
Speaker 3:  think you call it his inherent inscrutability I think is an amazing asset.
Speaker 3:  Do you know what Elon Musk thinks? Do you know what Tim cook thinks you do
Speaker 3:  not? Right. And I think that's an asset for him. On the flip side, there
Speaker 3:  are some values that he's a very clear about, right? He very obviously
Speaker 3:  believes in human rights. He very obviously believes in equality. He came
Speaker 3:  out of the closet publicly to inspire a young
Speaker 3:  people. And then you're like, but you do all this business in China and you
Speaker 3:  just brush the stuff under the rug and that it might have been as great as
Speaker 3:  success, but you could also love you as the greatest criticism of
Speaker 3:  cook that he has made this deal. And he will bend to
Speaker 3:  the Chinese government because that's the only path forward. And I,
Speaker 3:  because he's so inscrutable, you don't like, I don't know how he feels about
Speaker 3:  that, but does he like walk the streets at night, like showing
Speaker 3:  contend with this deal that he's made? Or does he just like go to bed on
Speaker 3:  a, on a bed of money?
Speaker 6:  It's, it's impossible to answer without asking Tim directly, you know,
Speaker 6:  about, about how he feels about that. It's not something I was able to get
Speaker 6:  into from people around him. And I think it's
Speaker 6:  become something that's become more pronounced as I've, as I've finished
Speaker 6:  the book, because I think we have a deeper appreciation for the, for the
Speaker 6:  plight of the weaker community in China and the human rights violations that
Speaker 6:  have taken place. That's become more pronounced over the past year, year
Speaker 6:  and a half, not to mention, like we're seeing all these like
Speaker 6:  severe lockdowns in Shanghai and some of the trauma that that's
Speaker 6:  created as well. When it, when it comes to that disconnect
Speaker 6:  between what he says here at home
Speaker 6:  and what, you know, their, their presence and dependency
Speaker 6:  on China, that's going to be the one thing that they're going to really have
Speaker 6:  their feet held to the fire over. Especially if, if there's a change in congressional
Speaker 6:  leadership in the coming in the coming months. And next year, we're already
Speaker 6:  seeing some of that from the FCC and Brendan Carr who's who
Speaker 6:  wrote a pretty critical letter about apple and how it has this position on
Speaker 6:  privacy and how there's a disconnect between that position on privacy
Speaker 6:  and it not allowing voice of America in
Speaker 6:  China because the Chinese government don't want it to be available there.
Speaker 3:  That to me is like very complicated, right? There's a long section in the
Speaker 3:  book about the FBI and encryption, and then the out in that
Speaker 3:  conversation all the time as well. But in China, you just let iCloud be hosted
Speaker 3:  by the Chinese government. Why wouldn't you just let us do that? Why wouldn't
Speaker 3:  you provide us that kind of access? And their answer is always well,
Speaker 3:  because in America we like really respect privacy and we would never let
Speaker 3:  you do this, but in order to do business there, we have to accept the laws
Speaker 3:  of the country rent. Right. But you never see Tim cook, like put those
Speaker 3:  ideas together himself. Right? You don't see him say that in the congressional
Speaker 3:  hearing, you don't hear him grapple with the contradiction that
Speaker 3:  I'm just wondering if you think that that, like having done all this
Speaker 3:  reporting when that moment comes, which it might, if
Speaker 3:  Congress flips or there's a new president a few years or anything, Brennan
Speaker 3:  Carr continues, treading angry letters. I know Brendan, that's fine. Well,
Speaker 3:  how do you see the company contending with that? And keeping focus on the
Speaker 3:  stuff that makes wall street happy
Speaker 6:  And it makes water continuing to make the products they need to make, right?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I mean, you, you're seeing them kind of wrestle with how to deal with
Speaker 6:  that as they try to spin up manufacturing in India and
Speaker 6:  Vietnam and elsewhere, and really struggling with
Speaker 6:  trying to find a way to move on from China
Speaker 6:  and diversify their supply chain beyond China. And that's really the only
Speaker 6:  answer. I mean, there, because up to this point, there hasn't been a plan
Speaker 6:  B, but they've got to reduce that dependency.
Speaker 6:  Otherwise, otherwise they're going to continue to run into the type of headaches
Speaker 6:  that they announced in their most recent quarter where they're saying, we're
Speaker 6:  going to have four to $8 billion, less than sales, because
Speaker 6:  there's a COVID outbreak and people can't get into the Shanghai
Speaker 6:  factories. You're looking for something more pointed. Like when is Tim
Speaker 6:  cook going to comment on this? Yeah. I mean, Tim cook is
Speaker 6:  fond of this, this turn of phrase. Often, particularly during the Trump
Speaker 6:  years, you saw it, you know, around immigration where you would, he would
Speaker 6:  say something to the line, to the extent of, I wish Trump would
Speaker 6:  put more heart into this. There's there's a great scene in the book, right?
Speaker 6:  Where he goes in to meet with, with Trump as part of this
Speaker 6:  giant CEO meeting, or right before that meeting Axios has a teaser
Speaker 6:  story that says, Tim, Cook's going to confront Trump on
Speaker 6:  immigration. And so everybody from the Trump administration comes in
Speaker 6:  there and is like, wide-eyed for this moment when
Speaker 6:  Tim cook is going to challenge Donald Trump about his immigration
Speaker 6:  policy and totally afraid of what Donald Trump's going to say back to
Speaker 6:  him. And they go through the whole meeting, it never comes up.
Speaker 6:  And then as Tim cook is, is leaving, he kind of
Speaker 6:  quietly says to Trump on his way out the door, I wish you put more heart
Speaker 6:  into your immigration strategy. And the next thing everybody
Speaker 6:  knew that wound up in Axios. And that was what was kind of
Speaker 6:  broadcast back to the work, you know, back to apple workers,
Speaker 6:  apple customers was Tim cook confronted Donald Trump.
Speaker 6:  But for everybody who witnessed this, this was a far more subtle
Speaker 6:  interaction in subtle episodes than some big squeeze.
Speaker 6:  And that's, that's just his style, right? We're not going to see him come
Speaker 6:  out and say disease, young pain. Like I really wish you would shut
Speaker 6:  down all those weaker camps that you have spun
Speaker 6:  up. And gene Jane, you know, so that we can continue to
Speaker 6:  manufacture stuff. They're such a confrontation. We we'd
Speaker 6:  be naive to think that's ever going to happen.
Speaker 3:  How do you think about the next CEO of apple in that context then?
Speaker 3:  Because, you know, he said to Kara Swisher, I think
Speaker 3:  a few months ago, I won't be here in 10 more years. Right? He's already
Speaker 3:  started talking about it. Like there's obviously a succession plan inside
Speaker 3:  of apple. It's what is the most fun game you can play in a podcast? It's
Speaker 3:  talk about who might take over a company, right? It's right. It's right there
Speaker 3:  with casting a movie who would play Johnny. But when you think about the
Speaker 3:  qualifications for the next CEO of apple right now, it is just a
Speaker 3:  company they're not, you're not necessarily in the shadow of Steve jobs.
Speaker 3:  In that way. It is very successful. The products were really successful.
Speaker 3:  The services businesses built out. I think a lot of people look and
Speaker 3:  they think, oh, this is it's a product person should run this company. But
Speaker 3:  the argument you're making is actually you need a politician, you need an
Speaker 3:  operator and a politician to run a company of this size because it is effectively
Speaker 3:  a state unto itself.
Speaker 6:  Yes. And, and that's, what's interesting because the person who's most likely
Speaker 6:  to step into that role, hasn't demonstrated up to this
Speaker 6:  point, the type of statesmanship that we've seen from Tim cook,
Speaker 6:  he'd have to develop that that's Jeff Williams, right? I mean, he, he seems
Speaker 6:  to be the successor in waiting. He and Tim cook have worked together since
Speaker 6:  their IBM days. Granted they're, they're, you know, similar
Speaker 6:  in age. So there's, there's that to contend with,
Speaker 6:  but he he's still the most likely successor. The one thing that he
Speaker 6:  has that Tim couldn't didn't have, if he were to fill that
Speaker 6:  role is more product experience because he led the watch
Speaker 6:  product and he's been deeply involved in their healthcare efforts.
Speaker 6:  And he also, before that was, was fairly
Speaker 6:  involved in the iPhone. And when Tony Fidel was, was fired from the company,
Speaker 6:  he, he filled Tony Fidel's seat in terms of making some product related
Speaker 6:  decisions on the iPhone. And a lot of people were quite impressed with
Speaker 6:  the degree of savviness that he brought to
Speaker 6:  kind of understanding both the engineering issues that they confronted, but
Speaker 6:  then also some of the design, sensibilities and
Speaker 6:  aesthetic decisions that they were trying to make as well
Speaker 5:  In the realm of thinking about like where apple goes next, the car comes
Speaker 5:  up a bunch in the book, the, the like mythical apple car that either will
Speaker 5:  or won't exist.
Speaker 3:  They just hired a new person. They just hired another Ford executive to run
Speaker 3:  the car. It's a real pipeline from Ford to apple, back to Ford. That's
Speaker 3:  what you do
Speaker 5:  And Tesla to. Yeah, it's good. It's great. But so th the car factors in
Speaker 5:  pretty prominently, and then there's this like, great, what if moment
Speaker 5:  where it was going to be the watcher, it was going to be to the TV and it
Speaker 5:  turned out to be the watch. And it's like, it is now my favorite alternate
Speaker 5:  history. Like what if, instead of getting super obsessed with watches, Johnny,
Speaker 5:  I've gotten super obsessed with TVs, but like, as, as we're looking out towards
Speaker 5:  sort of what's coming next, like my first question is, is the car ever going
Speaker 5:  to happen? Like if you were a betting, man, is there ever going to be an
Speaker 5:  apple car?
Speaker 6:  Yes. Okay. And, and the reason I think it'll happen is I
Speaker 6:  think they've got to move into a category that big, they just
Speaker 6:  do. I mean, you know, the growth, the growth expectations of wall
Speaker 6:  street will demand that they enter something that new and that ambitious.
Speaker 6:  And we haven't, we've seen them kind of dabbling in healthcare for a long
Speaker 6:  time, but we haven't seen them show the ability to, to
Speaker 6:  turn healthcare into a real financial opportunity for the company. Yet I
Speaker 6:  would argue beyond the watch. I mean, that's still the primary income
Speaker 6:  stream for healthcare,
Speaker 5:  And Apple's tried pretty loudly with the healthcare stuff like it.
Speaker 3:  Tim cook has said our biggest contribution to the world will be in health,
Speaker 5:  But that doesn't seem to be like, I think you're right. That that is whatever
Speaker 5:  that's going to be. It's not that yet.
Speaker 3:  I would say the COVID tracking initiative did not stop COVID
Speaker 6:  No, no. I mean, I, how many notifications did you get about your, you
Speaker 6:  know, your close, close brushes with Lyft candidate through that? The one
Speaker 6:  thing that the reason I'm, I'm more, I left reporting the book more
Speaker 6:  optimistic about the possibility and potential of a car was
Speaker 6:  weirdly because of what they did with apple park and what they pulled
Speaker 6:  off there. I know this is going to sound like a bizarre leap. Why are we
Speaker 6:  going from, from, from cars to, to
Speaker 6:  construction? But the big feat with
Speaker 6:  apple park is that they took this
Speaker 6:  incredibly ambitious design to make this curve glass that had
Speaker 6:  never been made before in the world. They persuaded a
Speaker 6:  German manufacturer to build a giant warehouse, to make this
Speaker 6:  precisely curved glass. And then in doing so,
Speaker 6:  they not only built this unique building for themselves,
Speaker 6:  but they unlock the possibility that architects and people in
Speaker 6:  construction could start designing things with
Speaker 6:  similar curvature. It's kind of radical to think about the idea that a
Speaker 6:  company that makes electronics change the
Speaker 6:  construction and architecture industry in a fundamental way. And so when
Speaker 6:  you think about that and you think about like, auto know, could they jump
Speaker 6:  into the auto industry and change the way that's been done for some time?
Speaker 6:  I mean, that's what, that's what makes me optimistic. It's weirdly,
Speaker 6:  it's weirdly the design sensibilities and the design history, which is
Speaker 6:  now, you know, Johnny hives departed. So TBD how that,
Speaker 6:  that manifests itself going forward. But it's the
Speaker 6:  operational sophistication and engineering
Speaker 6:  talent of that company to pull off a feat like they did with a building
Speaker 6:  that makes you, you makes you look at the car thing and be like they could,
Speaker 6:  they came into this, they could do something that nobody else has thought
Speaker 6:  of or done,
Speaker 3:  But why are there been so many restarts along the way? Cause this is like,
Speaker 3:  it's their white whale. I agree with you. It's, it's the next biggest market
Speaker 3:  that they can enter, but they can't seem to figure out how or why or what
Speaker 3:  they should do.
Speaker 6:  It speaks to some of the political bloodsport that Tony Fidelis
Speaker 6:  alluding to the book, the book hits on this, but basically at the outside,
Speaker 6:  you had these two competing ideas for what,
Speaker 6:  what the car can be. One of those ideas was there. We just
Speaker 6:  jump in super efficiently and we displaced Tesla with an
Speaker 6:  electric vehicle. And the other idea was, well, if we're going to come
Speaker 6:  in, we need to go full autonomy. And Johnny hive was really the one
Speaker 6:  who, who was pushing for that, that idea that we go full
Speaker 6:  autonomy. And this was in the, the kind of
Speaker 6:  go-go years where we were all going to be riding around and, and autonomous
Speaker 6:  vehicles. And that's just, I mean, I don't know. You talked to anybody who
Speaker 6:  really believed that around 2015, they've given up an
Speaker 6:  abandoned hope that that'll ever be a reality until there's a major breakthrough
Speaker 6:  in AI, but they were all buying into though the promise and the
Speaker 6:  illusion of that in 2015. So that that's been the
Speaker 6:  biggest holdup. That was a major problem.
Speaker 3:  It feels like there's a third notion there, which was, we'll just make an
Speaker 3:  electric car. Like Tesla will do this. There's a great scene in the book
Speaker 3:  where Johnny ive does like a fake Siri demo for, for Tim cook with an
Speaker 3:  actress, pretending to be Siri in the car. And that's just nuts.
Speaker 3:  Like everyone should buy the book just to read that scene and be like,
Speaker 3:  imagine that actually happening, because that is just nuts to
Speaker 3:  me. But then there's like the third option, which is, we'll just make software
Speaker 3:  for everyone else's cars, right? And we'll, we'll just colonize all the other
Speaker 3:  cars and apple services will be in them. And they seem to have vacillated
Speaker 3:  between all three of these things. Where do you think they are now?
Speaker 6:  Right now, literally what they're doing is, you know, they have cars rolling
Speaker 6:  around on the streets with these, these mattress pads. I don't know if you
Speaker 6:  guys have seen those locally, but there are these mattress pads that are
Speaker 6:  on top of the car and they look like giant I-phones in
Speaker 6:  terms of, in terms of what what's driving around. So they're still
Speaker 6:  looking to refine the autonomous capability of it. And then I guess,
Speaker 6:  combine that with some of the battery pack, sophistication that they've developed
Speaker 6:  over the years.
Speaker 3:  So you think they're going full autonomous car. So how long do you think
Speaker 3:  that? Do you think it will be God and no one wants to make this bet. This
Speaker 3:  is how you get fired from leading the apple.
Speaker 6:  Thank God. Yeah. We should call the guy at lifts, right? When, when are we
Speaker 6:  gonna all be riding around with cars that
Speaker 3:  I interview a lot of autonomous cars, CEOs on decoder. And they're like,
Speaker 3:  I'm not, I'm not making a prediction, not at this time, but you think they're
Speaker 3:  going to do it. You think they're just going to keep piling money into it
Speaker 3:  and wall, Street's going to let them keep piling money into it.
Speaker 6:  There's no shortage of cash over there. I don't know if you'd noticed that,
Speaker 6:  but I think, I think, I think they can afford
Speaker 6:  to continue to bet on it. I think the bigger question is, and if you
Speaker 6:  look back at the tension, it's like, who's going to step into that void
Speaker 6:  and, and provide some direction. That to me was a more
Speaker 6:  interesting thing. When you looked at the car project was, you know, during
Speaker 6:  the jobs era, jobs could come in and, and chart a path forward, and
Speaker 6:  everybody could rally behind that in his absence, in this, in this
Speaker 6:  age of consensus, you increasingly have conflict without
Speaker 6:  resolution. And that's what I think has been the hangup.
Speaker 3:  All right. Well, we are running out of time with you. Thank you for giving
Speaker 3:  us so much time. I just to wrap this up, you've now spent a lot of time paying
Speaker 3:  attention to these two figures inside of apple and how the company has
Speaker 3:  worked. What do you think it's biggest? What do you think Apple's biggest
Speaker 3:  challenge right now is
Speaker 6:  I think its biggest challenge in this in particular for Tim
Speaker 6:  cook is finding his next pair. And then
Speaker 6:  when I look back at the history of apple, it's really stunning when you,
Speaker 6:  when you analyze it. But jobs built apple with was jobs
Speaker 6:  return and kind of saved apple with eyes. That was his key
Speaker 6:  partner. And then Ivan cook had been key to this
Speaker 6:  past decade and the success that they've had, both in the development of
Speaker 6:  services and the development of, of the watch and AirPods
Speaker 6:  category. So who's cooking a team up with now. I mean, if they're pressing
Speaker 6:  issues or China and figuring out how to
Speaker 6:  reduce their dependency on that, that's certainly something that Tim and
Speaker 6:  Jeff can work on. Is it, is it Johnny Shruti is, is
Speaker 6:  Tim Cook's Johnny really Johnny Srujith. And it's going to be about
Speaker 6:  ships that you can predict how much power is going to improve on
Speaker 6:  machines on a given year. And you're going to be more focused on what goes
Speaker 6:  inside the machine and how the exterior of a product
Speaker 6:  looks. I mean, that, that seems to be the direction they're heading, but
Speaker 6:  identifying that person and, and unleashing their talent is
Speaker 6:  going to be key to the, their ability to get there.
Speaker 3:  There's not a lot of chip talk in the book, right? There's not a lot of PA
Speaker 3:  semi or Johnny surgery, but this is actually the, the engine of
Speaker 3:  apple success over the last two years in particular, is that their chips
Speaker 3:  design, power, performance, power
Speaker 3:  consumption, far outpaces the entire industry, their strategy
Speaker 3:  to let TSMC build the chips while they design them, set the model for
Speaker 3:  everybody else. And you know, the Macans having a Renaissance
Speaker 3:  because they've moved to their own chips and they brought them in house.
Speaker 3:  If I had to point to one, like here's a criticism, this book is going to
Speaker 3:  get it's you it's not in there, right? Why is that? Not in there.
Speaker 6:  This is gets back to the choices that you have to make, right? You know,
Speaker 6:  if you want to, if you want to bring the reader along and keep the focus
Speaker 6:  relatively tight, the company that I found myself falling and the
Speaker 6:  issues that Tim cook was most concerned with were
Speaker 6:  developing services, right? And then also
Speaker 6:  dealing with these extraneous issues of the empire that he
Speaker 6:  had built it's Trump and China. They were less about, about the product and
Speaker 6:  where the product was going. And by that point, Johnny was gone. I mean,
Speaker 6:  the book does end in 2019. So when you say like the
Speaker 6:  last two years, well, the book literally the last page is Johnny
Speaker 6:  ive walking out of the door and that was summer of 2019.
Speaker 6:  So you're, you're highlighting a period that the book doesn't cover and these
Speaker 6:  are choices you have to make.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. And there's like one line that you cut out at the end, it was like,
Speaker 3:  and then Johnny Srujith peeked over the Bush,
Speaker 3:  Johnny,
Speaker 6:  The SQL is called new Johnny
Speaker 3:  Trip. This has been amazing. The book is really good. We could obviously
Speaker 3:  talk for another hour. Like I said, it's going to make everyone mad, which
Speaker 3:  I think is the sign of success for a book like this. Everyone's mad in different
Speaker 3:  directions. I have to ask this last question. You're not going to like
Speaker 3:  it. You're not going to answer it. But I have to ask this, Johnny, I have
Speaker 3:  the source for the scenes where Johnny ive is standing alone in rooms, contemplating
Speaker 3:  his own future.
Speaker 6:  I can't get into the sourcing, but you guys
Speaker 6:  know full and well. And it's been hilarious to watch Jonathan Martin and,
Speaker 6:  and, and the guys who just came out with a book on Trump, Theo of these questions,
Speaker 6:  like who gave you the McCarthy audio? It's never who you
Speaker 6:  think it is, right? It just never is. I mean, it's not the obvious
Speaker 6:  person. And that's why people are having a hard time with the SCOTUS thing
Speaker 6:  as well. Who leaked this? Like, nobody's got a clue. It's just
Speaker 6:  not,
Speaker 3:  That was a really good deflection. I got lots of well-practiced
Speaker 3:  trip. It's great. I recommend everybody. If you're listening to this show,
Speaker 3:  you're going to love this book. You should go read it. Congratulation trip.
Speaker 3:  It's great. We'll have to have you back on soon.
Speaker 6:  Thanks so much. I appreciate you having me.
Speaker 3:  We gotta take a break, but when we come back, Alex, Cranz join us. Right?
Speaker 3:  Gadget lighting
Speaker 3:  around.
Speaker 3:  We're back. Alex Kranz is here. Yeah.
Speaker 9:  Hey, I have no new news about sexy Clippy.
Speaker 9:  Sorry.
Speaker 3:  All right. There's some gadgets talk about
Speaker 9:  There's a lot. Yeah. There's a lot of gadget news this week.
Speaker 3:  There is, there's a bunch of gadgets, like exciting leaky gadget news. Well,
Speaker 3:  let's start with my favorite Starlink. Yeah. So I got an
Speaker 3:  email and a lot of people got the email. If you're a Starling customer, they
Speaker 3:  will now let you move the dish around wherever you want and use it wherever
Speaker 3:  you want, which is a big step
Speaker 9:  Each step.
Speaker 3:  Because before you kind of like, they start like divides the world into like
Speaker 3:  little hexagon shapes and you were hexagon is where you could be.
Speaker 3:  And if you left it, you got in trouble tonight. You can go to any hexagon
Speaker 3:  you want
Speaker 5:  As someone who has never used Starlink define trouble, like what, what would
Speaker 5:  happen if you previously tried to move,
Speaker 3:  They would shut you down. Oh, okay. Like first it wouldn't work. And then
Speaker 3:  if you try to move it on the website too many times, they would like catch
Speaker 3:  you and you, so you weren't allowed to like, change your location on the
Speaker 3:  website too many times because they were just protecting the network. None
Speaker 3:  of this is nefarious. They're just like, right. But they've launched a bunch
Speaker 3:  of new satellites. I think they have the capacity now. So they're enabling
Speaker 3:  portability, which means you can take it anywhere. Here's the, here's the
Speaker 3:  rub $25 a month.
Speaker 9:  Oh, are they they're waiving that fee? I assume in
Speaker 9:  Ukraine,
Speaker 3:  I don't know it, starlets pricing is like, they've raised the fees for everyone
Speaker 3:  else. So they went from 90 to 110 for the base service. And
Speaker 3:  now if you want to move around with Starlink you're at a year at another
Speaker 3:  25, so $135 for your portable startling
Speaker 3:  experience, you still can't like put it on a car, which I think a lot of
Speaker 3:  people want to do, but anywhere you are in a service area, if you pay the
Speaker 3:  extra fee, you can set the thing down on the point itself to the sky and
Speaker 3:  go,
Speaker 5:  And am I right in thinking that Starlink has said, it's working on the, like,
Speaker 5:  you can use it in motion thing. Cause that seems like that's pretty clearly
Speaker 5:  like the thing it ought to be is that it just works.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Again, the technical limitation of Starlink every
Speaker 3:  time is that even a single utility pole
Speaker 3:  will degrade your service, but one tree
Speaker 3:  will do great. So yeah, you're driving around. But like if you drive next
Speaker 3:  to a tall car, you drive next to a satellite truck,
Speaker 9:  Like any 18 Wheeler,
Speaker 3:  Like you're hooped. So I think there's, there's a little bit of that for
Speaker 3:  them to, to yet figure out. I'm pretty sure the answer is like all things
Speaker 3:  Starling is more satellites. Like Tony stark style, like a suit of
Speaker 3:  armor around the world.
Speaker 9:  The just going to follow you. The satellites will just like, be like drones.
Speaker 9:  I think we just need to put satellites on drones. That's the next star link.
Speaker 3:  They're launching more satellites. They're opening more service and they've,
Speaker 3:  this is a big step for them because this is the thing you were not allowed
Speaker 3:  to do before. And when we reviewed it, I actually tried to give it to Monica
Speaker 3:  where she had bad internet service at her parents' house. And Starlink was
Speaker 3:  like, what are you? The police are coming stop. And actually part of the
Speaker 3:  thing that people got mad at me, and they were used like, I, you know, my
Speaker 3:  house, I've got big trees. So to test it in a place where the
Speaker 3:  installation worked, drove down the street to where there were no trees.
Speaker 3:  And so then the criticism is, well, you were out of your service area. And
Speaker 3:  I was like, I was just down the street, but now for $25 a month, I can make
Speaker 3:  that criticism go away. So watch out Starling fanboys, I'm
Speaker 3:  paying the money and come and free
Speaker 9:  Riverview.
Speaker 5:  I find this super exciting, like as someone who does not have any need
Speaker 5:  whatsoever in my life for Starlink, because I have, I mean, I was going to
Speaker 5:  say fast internet, but as Liam, our producer can attest. It's not fast, but
Speaker 5:  it's internet at home. And it works fine. Like the, the appeal of Starlink
Speaker 5:  has never actually hit me as a person. But like now startling, it goes from
Speaker 5:  like thing you get, if it's your only way to get internet, because you're
Speaker 5:  somewhere far with bad connectivity or no connectivity to
Speaker 5:  like it now does things that my Comcast internet
Speaker 5:  connection, won't like, I can take it with me on vacation, which is like
Speaker 5:  a meaningful, real thing that I think is kind of cool.
Speaker 9:  Does it, your phone also do that though.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. But if 5g was real, this would be X 5g would be cool and
Speaker 5:  exciting,
Speaker 3:  Right? It certainly doesn't have data caps yet. They're not doing like, they
Speaker 3:  are a better, they're still an ISP and they, in their terms of service have
Speaker 3:  reserved the right to do all the bad things. Right. You do too much
Speaker 3:  torrenting. Starlink is looking at your path or your packets and they will
Speaker 3:  shut you down for copyright infringement, just like anybody else. But right
Speaker 3:  now I'm not doing any of it. I think the question is, does the network have
Speaker 3:  capacity? And also traveling with Starlink is
Speaker 3:  like, it's an unwieldy and complicated thing. Like there's a dish.
Speaker 3:  There is a power injector box. There's its own custom router. That's all
Speaker 3:  a lot, you know? So like you're trying to take
Speaker 3:  Starling through the TSA. Like let me know. Cause I want to be there on that
Speaker 3:  day. Like if you have an RV or you're like doing van life, I
Speaker 3:  think this is like ideal.
Speaker 9:  I was like, those chick talks of people building their vans so they can live
Speaker 9:  off the grid. So excited for the Starlink episodes. Now,
Speaker 3:  Notable verge, ex-pat Evan Rogers, building a van and his Instagram right
Speaker 3:  now. It's pretty
Speaker 9:  Good. Will he put Starlink in it?
Speaker 5:  Probably knowing Evan, like that's coming,
Speaker 3:  We'll get it. We'll get them to review startling on the road. Next lightning
Speaker 3:  round item. This is actually really cool. So you can now play
Speaker 3:  fortnight on iPhone or Android in the browser, through
Speaker 3:  Xbox cloud gaming, which is like the browsers, the out for all of these
Speaker 3:  services and all this in app purchase stuff. It's pretty cool that you can
Speaker 3:  do it.
Speaker 9:  And this was like, after epic, pretty notoriously didn't want to work with
Speaker 9:  Microsoft for a long time because their competitors and they were like, we
Speaker 9:  don't want you to, like, we compete with you. We don't want our stuff on
Speaker 9:  your services. And then they're like, oh, in this
Speaker 9:  particular instance, this is a win for both of us. And Microsoft gets still
Speaker 9:  a very magnanimous.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It was like an enemy of my enemy is my friend moved this one pretty
Speaker 5:  clearly. Like they both have a lot to gain from
Speaker 5:  screwing up this whole app store thing apple has going on.
Speaker 5:  And this is like a pretty, it's a pretty good way to
Speaker 5:  do it. Actually. They're like it's in the browser. It works. It's fortnight
Speaker 5:  magic.
Speaker 9:  One of my favorite things is how Microsoft has just been egging everybody
Speaker 9:  on in this whole like saga and the, you know, they
Speaker 9:  have, they have their stake. Like they want an Xbox cloud gaming app. They've
Speaker 9:  tried repeatedly to do it. They can't, they're doing the browser. And so
Speaker 9:  instead they're like just being friends with everybody else and being like,
Speaker 9:  you know, that's right. That would be cool. We should be able to have our
Speaker 9:  apps.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. And they're putting out an open letter as being like we're the most
Speaker 3:  open company except for the Xbox. Yeah.
Speaker 9:  Is wondering like I just, I love X-Box. It's just like, don't, don't, don't
Speaker 9:  pay attention to that side of things.
Speaker 3:  So, but you wonder, right. Epic versus Google is
Speaker 3:  marching right along. You have to think, Google's going to be like, well,
Speaker 3:  why is this a problem? You can just play it in the browser. I'm Microsoft
Speaker 3:  platform. Look at how competitive this is. If you're a Google's
Speaker 3:  lawyers and you just had that thought just now, I don't know what you're
Speaker 3:  like. You should come on
Speaker 3:  already. That should be first on your list when you seniors like this. But
Speaker 3:  I imagine we're going to hear this argument. So there's a little bit of like
Speaker 3:  games has been shipped inside an announcement. Like
Speaker 9:  It's a counter to that. I like, I know the counter in this room would be,
Speaker 9:  well, have you played things on the browser versus an app? Like
Speaker 9:  what's the legal counter besides being like, judge, judge, please play
Speaker 9:  fortnight on an app right now while we watch.
Speaker 3:  So for apple, the counter to all the browser stuff was apple nurse, the
Speaker 3:  browser, which is not really an argument you can make about
Speaker 3:  Google, right? Because there's other rousers available. You can, you don't
Speaker 3:  need to use the Chrome engine on Android phones. You can download other browsers
Speaker 3:  with other browser engines. So there's a lot. I think that case is going
Speaker 3:  to be the much more interesting one compared to apple. Apple is interesting.
Speaker 3:  Cause you got, you know, Tim cook on the stand and the judge was yelling
Speaker 3:  at him and like the goo Hayes is like, that's all deals,
Speaker 3:  right? Licenses, Android, the deals have the
Speaker 3:  control embedded in the language of them. So like, I think there's more to
Speaker 3:  come from that case. I don't think the safari team is like
Speaker 3:  writing a contract with the Astro team. Like that's
Speaker 3:  how Android works. Like they have a contract with Samsung and with the carriers
Speaker 3:  and like all this stuff. So we shall see Chris Welch
Speaker 3:  continues to just ruthlessly scoop the Sonos team about this new
Speaker 3:  thing, the Sonos, right.
Speaker 9:  Nothing left for the actual announcement. They'll just refer to the verge.
Speaker 3:  I hope they don't go crazy. I think actual an answer. And they're like, it's
Speaker 3:  actually a TV. And like Patrick Spence like pulls up. He's
Speaker 3:  like,
Speaker 5:  It's a projector screen that pulls up out of the soundbar.
Speaker 3:  Exactly.
Speaker 5:  It's actually a good idea. I'm just going to say like a screen that pulls
Speaker 5:  up out of your soundbar. It's a pretty good idea.
Speaker 3:  It's a tiny little screen,
Speaker 5:  But like short throw projector in my soundbar throws up on the, on the pull
Speaker 5:  up screen, like the used to have in middle school. This is a good idea. I
Speaker 5:  just, I just invented something.
Speaker 9:  The name Sonos Ray. It could be a short throw projector,
Speaker 9:  just like Ray is, is kind of a silly name. Paul used to everyone named
Speaker 9:  Ray, listening to this Ray for the name of a soundbar is a silly
Speaker 9:  name. Add like maybe it's beaming rays of
Speaker 9:  light onto a short throw projector screen. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Well it's 250 bucks and supposed to go on sale in a matter of weeks. But
Speaker 3:  the more interesting piece that also Chris Welch league, they're going to
Speaker 3:  introduce their own voice assistant, which is fascinating.
Speaker 3:  So as you know, Sonos and Google are tied up in patent
Speaker 3:  litigation all started when Sonos wanted
Speaker 3:  Alexa and Google assistant to operate simultaneously. Amazon
Speaker 3:  doesn't care because they're the winner. But Google
Speaker 3:  apparently said no, like very vociferously
Speaker 3:  that led to patent litigation Patrick's fence and the chief legal office
Speaker 3:  of Sonos or on decoder talking about it. But you can see they're like, we'll
Speaker 3:  just do our own to do the things we want to do. So in order to extend your
Speaker 3:  platforms, there are building this home theater or us there's job listings
Speaker 3:  for it. But here's a really funny thing about this. So Sonos voice will
Speaker 3:  be on all S two Sonos devices that have
Speaker 3:  microphones. So it will support apple music, Amazon music,
Speaker 3:  Pandora, Deezer, obviously these are hockey teaser. And
Speaker 3:  then Sonya says on this radio that Spotify and YouTube music are
Speaker 3:  not on board. And it's like, well, yeah, obviously YouTube music is
Speaker 3:  not
Speaker 5:  So close.
Speaker 3:  Spotify is a big one.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. It was like maybe YouTube, like get it. People will survive
Speaker 9:  as Spotify. That's a, that's a really big one to not have on there.
Speaker 5:  Spotify is an interesting one in that range actually, because Spotify has
Speaker 5:  its own voice search thing that it obviously has
Speaker 5:  incentives to get people to use. But also Spotify has been pretty open
Speaker 5:  in working inside of this space. Like Spotify connect is very
Speaker 5:  good. It's everywhere my guests would be. And I have
Speaker 5:  absolutely no inside knowledge on this, but my guess would be that, that
Speaker 5:  is a like a timing thing rather than a philosophical
Speaker 5:  difference because it, unless there's something we don't know about this
Speaker 5:  voice assistant, it seems very surprising to me that Spotify would not be
Speaker 5:  interested in being part
Speaker 3:  Of it. Or Spotify wants its voice assistant on there too, maybe. Right. Cause
Speaker 3:  like, you know, Sonos is like, we'll have Siri on there. If Hafele would
Speaker 3:  let us Netflix like no, no, no, no you
Speaker 3:  don't.
Speaker 9:  You don't want Siri on your speaker
Speaker 5:  Already exists to be launched by accident on my computer while I'm downstairs.
Speaker 5:  That's a serious here.
Speaker 3:  My current serum moment is I've I've installed a smart garage door
Speaker 3:  opener. It's very fancy. So I leave the house and I say, close the garage
Speaker 3:  in Siri on my watch. It's just like I'm working on
Speaker 3:  it. And it actually says that
Speaker 9:  It's the worst thing in the world.
Speaker 3:  This is, this is the dumbest thing that you can do as a computer. You close
Speaker 3:  a relay. It's all doing like the box is
Speaker 3:  very, it actually patches into the switch itself and
Speaker 3:  just closes the wire. Like it's not a complicated,
Speaker 5:  I'm just imagining serious, like a very tiny person hanging from your garage
Speaker 5:  door being like, come on,
Speaker 3:  I'm working on it. I'm going to just like, like, like a dark
Speaker 3:  brown.
Speaker 3:  And then about 50% of that's private sales.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. That's it.
Speaker 9:  Whenever they, whenever she says I'm working on it, you're like, oh, I'm
Speaker 9:  just going to have to say this in 20 minutes. Once you finish working on
Speaker 9:  it and failing.
Speaker 3:  But it's funny. Cause it, Siri, it suggests all these like very
Speaker 3:  optimistic automation routines. Like when we detect that
Speaker 3:  you've come home and we're paired to the car, we'll open the
Speaker 3:  garage for you. And I'm like, you can't, you don't, you can't open the garage.
Speaker 3:  Like I don't, What do you think you're to that's like me saying,
Speaker 3:  I'm gonna run a marathon. Like I'm definitely not going to do that.
Speaker 9:  I had her set up so where she was supposed to, whenever the camera
Speaker 9:  detected motion and I wasn't home, it would turn all the lights
Speaker 9:  red and sing that song. I'll be watching you to really creep,
Speaker 9:  freak out. Whoever had snuck into my home. It only
Speaker 9:  activated when I would get
Speaker 9:  home. It wouldn't like the trigger that
Speaker 9:  I was home would come later. So it'd be like, I'm watching you. And I'm like,
Speaker 9:  no, I, I know something's wrong. Know?
Speaker 3:  Oh no, she don't know this way. I have to write. I'm obligated to remind
Speaker 3:  you that Siri on our show, isn't it. We do not gender robots on the
Speaker 3:  Vergecast
Speaker 9:  Sorry. I apologize.
Speaker 3:  It only comes up because Amazon is so insistent on gendering Alexa.
Speaker 3:  It's like
Speaker 9:  They don't have their robots.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. And not very smart ones.
Speaker 9:  They're very stupid.
Speaker 5:  I have a question at this sunup. Thanks. So I think w like leaving
Speaker 5:  aside, whether Sonos can do this in a way that is good, which I
Speaker 5:  would say given Sonos is software experience is just an absolute
Speaker 5:  coin flip who knows. Sometimes soreness does cool stuff. Sometimes it's a
Speaker 5:  total disaster coin flip. We'll see. I think this is a
Speaker 5:  very good idea. Both for like strategic reasons, because Sonos is
Speaker 5:  just going to like middle finger, Google and apple and Amazon
Speaker 5:  and everybody else who doesn't work with them. But also because my, my like
Speaker 5:  longstanding thesis about voice assistants is that
Speaker 5:  actually we should have lots of them. And not just one,
Speaker 5:  like I want to, I want to talk to my TV by talking to my TV, not
Speaker 5:  by talking to Alexa about my TV. And I think like Roku has worked
Speaker 5:  on this in the past. And to be honest has changed his plan so many times
Speaker 5:  that I have no idea what Roku is doing with voice assistants anymore. But
Speaker 5:  I think this idea that Sonos is like, okay, you want music? Talk to Sonos,
Speaker 5:  don't talk to Alexa about Sonos. Talk to Sonos. I actually think is a
Speaker 5:  really good idea for a bunch of reasons. Especially as they want to get people
Speaker 5:  like used to the idea of using its products in lots of different places.
Speaker 5:  So they can pull this off. I actually think it's going to be really smart
Speaker 5:  and music assistance work. They're good. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. And I also think they have a great pie. So I know they've told us,
Speaker 3:  they've told everybody they make products that microphones because oh, a
Speaker 3:  huge segment of customers do not want microphones and everything. Right.
Speaker 3:  Because privacy implications. So if you're Sonos and you're like this
Speaker 3:  isn't Amazon, this isn't, whatever else this is us. And what it does is it
Speaker 3:  plays music, which is the thing you want to do. They throw in multiple timers,
Speaker 3:  like, Ooh, watch out
Speaker 9:  Giving you the weather, like
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Bezos, your empire will crumble. Yeah. But maybe not even the weather,
Speaker 3:  like maybe it's just that the things that people do is just set
Speaker 3:  timers and play music. And they're like, this is what we do. And it's
Speaker 3:  private. And you know, we're not going to sell you ads or we're not going
Speaker 3:  to pop up and say like, have you heard about the games? Like, we're just
Speaker 3:  going to do the two things. Very smart question is, are they gonna make you
Speaker 3:  pay for it?
Speaker 5:  Oh, that's interesting question.
Speaker 9:  I hate that question.
Speaker 3:  Like, is this like a premium Sono subscription situation?
Speaker 9:  I mean, that makes a lot of sense for them looking for like additional revenue
Speaker 9:  streams. Like everybody wants that consistent $5 a
Speaker 9:  month. These customers all have money to pay like
Speaker 3:  Right. Who doesn't love recurring revenue.
Speaker 5:  Well, and especially as they're going to start to, like, if they're going
Speaker 5:  to make headphones and they have these Bluetooth speakers, like being the
Speaker 5:  thing that stitches everything together is Sonus this whole thing. And
Speaker 5:  then add on to that, like this amazing control system. I could absolutely
Speaker 5:  see them charging for that.
Speaker 9:  I feel like there's two things that will make this kind of dead on
Speaker 9:  arrival, not having Spotify. Yeah. Like that's a huge
Speaker 9:  one. And also the fact that if you already have other smart assistants
Speaker 9:  in your home, you're now having competing smart assistants and you have to
Speaker 9:  remember their names and remember to activate the right one at the right
Speaker 9:  time. Maybe that's just a me dead in the water thing, but I will
Speaker 9:  forget the names immediately. I will absolutely call Siri what I mean to
Speaker 9:  call sodas and the other way around. Cause I do it with my dog and my brother
Speaker 9:  now, like when one of them isn't even as
Speaker 9:  like a human being, I will mess it up constantly.
Speaker 3:  I think I'm with David. I think that's just timing just given historically
Speaker 3:  or Spotify or Spotify demanding that they get their weird voice thing on
Speaker 3:  there too. We'll see. This Chromebook seems
Speaker 3:  amazing.
Speaker 9:  It's amazingly expensive,
Speaker 3:  But I'm like down with the thousand dollar Chromebook.
Speaker 5:  So I added this one to the rundown and that's the exact conversation I
Speaker 5:  want to have because this has been tried a bunch of times. And as far as
Speaker 5:  I can tell this, this new Chromebook, which is it's called the HP
Speaker 5:  dragon fly the
Speaker 9:  HP elite dragon fly you're
Speaker 5:  Right. I apologize. As the elite dragon
Speaker 5:  fly, it has high-end chips. It has Intel's V pro platform. It
Speaker 5:  gets super bright. It has an HTMI port. It's like, it's a, it's a whole ass
Speaker 5:  computer and it starts at $1,149. And I think the
Speaker 5:  question I have been wondering for years is like,
Speaker 5:  will anyone want to pay this much money? Even for the
Speaker 5:  best imaginable Chromebook? And I'm actually really excited for, at the
Speaker 5:  idea that we're going to find out
Speaker 9:  They didn't do it with the pixel book. Why would they do it? What's the difference
Speaker 9:  between this and the pixel book?
Speaker 3:  Well, the principal principle was a little shaky. It was like a little too
Speaker 3:  much. Right. But I will say this, I bought my
Speaker 3:  mom a Chromebook pixel. It was a thousand dollars and
Speaker 3:  it is the single best technology purchase I've ever made because you do not
Speaker 3:  have to support that thing. Yeah. It sounds web browser. And there's all
Speaker 3:  the other stuff that Chromebooks can do now. Like they have, you can run
Speaker 3:  Android apps for some godforsaken reason that hopefully Dieter will figure
Speaker 3:  out, Hey buddy. But like, it's just a web browser and you
Speaker 3:  like hand somebody, a beautiful laptop that isn't like, have
Speaker 3:  you heard about services, revenue we've opened the, the apple TV
Speaker 3:  app is on your laptop for summer. Like none of that. No,
Speaker 3:  no windows guard. It's just like, here's a web browser, but it's
Speaker 3:  beautiful. Like it did still. My mom's like primary
Speaker 3:  computer year and this is years now. Like maybe five years, she's still using
Speaker 3:  this thing. Am I call it? It's timed upgrading. Like, here we go. You're
Speaker 3:  an elite dragon fly. Now mom, you're a real game.
Speaker 5:  Oh God, if only it wasn't called the elite dragon fly.
Speaker 9:  I do love that this is the first one that's kind of like had a
Speaker 9:  really good display or sounds like it has a really good display. We haven't
Speaker 9:  seen it in person, but a thousand nits.
Speaker 9:  Like that's, that's nice.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. The Pixelbook had those bezels. I wasn't even about to put those bezels
Speaker 3:  near my mother. I respect her. She's a brilliant and accomplished woman.
Speaker 9:  I tried to say that I liked the bezels and as I get older, I'm like, why
Speaker 9:  didn't I say that? I was like, it's good for my fingers when I'm interested
Speaker 5:  Too liked the bezels.
Speaker 9:  When I was in tablet mode, it was really nice. I played a lot of fallout
Speaker 9:  shelter on the pixel book and it was great for that.
Speaker 9:  And that's it. That's
Speaker 5:  A wild take.
Speaker 9:  And then I tried to put fuchsia audit and broke it. So
Speaker 3:  Yeah, I'm definitely going to buy this. I can see it coming.
Speaker 5:  And this is like a thing. There's a, there's a, these are starting to trickle
Speaker 5:  out these computers that are like very good computers that ordinarily like
Speaker 5:  could have run windows one day and now are running chromo. S and I
Speaker 5:  feel like if I'm Microsoft, that's real bad news, but as a person who loves
Speaker 5:  Chromebooks, I think that's super exciting.
Speaker 3:  It's just an .
Speaker 9:  Oh yeah. That's it's,
Speaker 5:  It's a Chromebook.
Speaker 9:  I mean, it doesn't need a lot, but also, yeah, it's an
Speaker 9:  . I think it even has less, it has not a lot of
Speaker 9:  storage. Eight gigabytes of Ram, 128
Speaker 9:  gigabytes of storage. So for the same price, you can
Speaker 9:  get a Mac book.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. With the Mac book, we'll like the Mac book. We'll just like, find ways
Speaker 3:  for Tim cook to ask you for money. And like the slightest provocation
Speaker 9:  Mac book. I mean, I got my one over Christmas and the
Speaker 9:  calls about that. I get, I feel I'd still do it
Speaker 9:  with the Chromebook, but that's just because my mom's annoying, but like
Speaker 5:  The iCloud troubleshooting for me, I control the shooting.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. Well she doesn't, she doesn't want anything. And she's like, I don't
Speaker 9:  want anything in the cloud.
Speaker 3:  No one has ever cared about anything in my life. As persistently, as my Mac
Speaker 3:  book has cared about turning on wifi calling, It's just like, I
Speaker 3:  don't, I do not wish to ever receive phone calls on this.
Speaker 3:  It's like, we stopped So
Speaker 9:  Persistent.
Speaker 3:  All right. Last one. This is like leaks week.
Speaker 5:  It was,
Speaker 3:  And this leak actually blew up. So the Sony's got new
Speaker 3:  headphones. Yeah. I always get the name wrong.
Speaker 9:  The w H dash
Speaker 3:  1000 X MH five.
Speaker 9:  No, it just X, M I think
Speaker 5:  The age fives are the earbuds.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I always get this mixed up. Anyway. I have the XM twos
Speaker 3:  and they're great, but the battery's starting to go and every year I'm like,
Speaker 3:  should I get the XM three? Should I get the XM four in like, no, cause they're
Speaker 3:  the same headphones, but these are appreciably different. We'll just call
Speaker 3:  them editors.
Speaker 9:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  So these are still, these were my go-to airplane headphones and I stopped
Speaker 3:  wearing, or my X, M twos were my go-to
Speaker 3:  airplane headphones. And then I stopped flying airplanes, but now I'm on
Speaker 3:  airplanes again. And I'm like, oh, the noise canceling. Like noise-canceling
Speaker 3:  technology has improved dramatically. Yeah. So I'm in it. But
Speaker 3:  Sony saw as a problem like everybody else does. If you have an iPhone, you're
Speaker 3:  stuck with whatever apple that you do. So you can't do high quality audio.
Speaker 3:  You can't do on press. Like you're just kind of stuck at apple sound quality
Speaker 3:  situation, which I am sure the next versions of the
Speaker 3:  AirPods will overcome in some proprietary way. And like, you just have to,
Speaker 3:  you just have to look into your heart and be okay with that.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And truthfully, I think for most people, the, like the thing that Sony's
Speaker 5:  have going for them, which is stupendously long battery life. If,
Speaker 5:  especially if this leak is true and it's 40 hours, like that's, that's a
Speaker 5:  crazy number, really good noise cancellation. They're super comfortable.
Speaker 5:  Like, that's the thing about the Sonys that always gets me is just the
Speaker 9:  They're like little clouds.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I can just wear them for like a eight hour journey and it
Speaker 5:  doesn't feel bad, which I love. And I also think their, their
Speaker 5:  microphone is really good, which is a thing that it's possible. I am the
Speaker 5:  only person on earth who cares about, but matters to me a lot. Yeah. I'm
Speaker 5:  very excited about these zones, especially if they have, like, the new design
Speaker 5:  is a little sleeker, it has kind of a little sort of candy cane
Speaker 5:  looking thing, attaching the bands to the cups instead of just being like
Speaker 5:  all band and yeah. I, these Sonys, I think have
Speaker 5:  consistently been the best noise canceling headphones
Speaker 5:  for a bunch of years now. And the, the XM five
Speaker 9:  Since the . Yeah, right. Like I got the
Speaker 9:   I love them. I wore 'em to Taiwan and
Speaker 9:  back, like with my glasses on, which is normally like a recipe
Speaker 9:  for pain. Totally comfortable. It was great. I mean, 14 hour flight
Speaker 9:  wasn't but the rest was really great. Like, yeah. They,
Speaker 9:  they just, and the noise canceling, like the way Sony does noise
Speaker 9:  canceling and their approach to it where they don't kind of, the sound
Speaker 9:  profile is still, they still maintain quality of the sound profile. Whereas
Speaker 9:  Bose goes really flat. Apple goes really just expensive. Nobody
Speaker 9:  wants to buy the apple ones. Cause they're, I don't even know how they sound
Speaker 9:  because they're
Speaker 3:  Still heavy and weird.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. And like, these
Speaker 3:  Are like, yeah,
Speaker 9:  These are clouds. These are clouds that shut off the airplane
Speaker 9:  for you, but still gets you where you need to go.
Speaker 3:  I haven't tried new Bose ones. I have quiet comfort twos and they're so bad
Speaker 3:  at low end symbol. To me,
Speaker 5:  I have the, the QC 40 fives, which are not like the highest end one, but
Speaker 5:  are pretty recent ones. And it's exactly the same thing. Like I, I love the
Speaker 5:  way they sound. I love the way they feel. And if it is like, if it's been,
Speaker 5:  if it has been breezy in the last five days, my headphones will
Speaker 5:  sound like trash. And it sounds like I am blowing away in a
Speaker 5:  storm.
Speaker 1:  It's awful.
Speaker 5:  Otherwise, they're great though. But no, I think that like, yeah, these Sonys
Speaker 5:  are very exciting and I'm absolutely convinced that if they had a better,
Speaker 5:  more memorable name, they would have absolutely already eaten the headphone
Speaker 5:  market alive. But because no one can go Google them and find them.
Speaker 5:  We still have to tell people they exist. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I do this for a living. I still can't say the product name correctly.
Speaker 3:  All right. We want, we talked, we spent a long time talking about trip medical.
Speaker 3:  So we are officially over on the verge cast. Once again, Alex, thank
Speaker 3:  you. Yes. Some stuff supply, you should listen to Dakota this week, we
Speaker 3:  had Tony Fidel. It was a real, a real ride. And then obviously
Speaker 3:  the Fidel conversation and the mythical conversation got started, like play
Speaker 3:  off each other, Fidel, by the way, there's some people who are like
Speaker 3:  actively and aggressively. Fact-checking his conversation with me on Twitter
Speaker 3:  right now, like X drop cam employees. So that's pretty
Speaker 3:  good. Alice has got her mini series. What's going on with creators this week,
Speaker 3:  Alex.
Speaker 9:  So this week we talked to Jacob Alexander, who is one of
Speaker 9:  the first guys who started selling keyboards online. Like people were selling
Speaker 9:  keyboards online, but he was selling them on Kickstarter, making his own
Speaker 9:  keyboards. And we kind of talked about where the spaces and how we got
Speaker 9:  there and where it's going to go next and how it's like small creators like
Speaker 9:  him who are doing it. It was very fun. It's
Speaker 5:  A great episode.
Speaker 9:  And next week, we're going to talk to the guys from floopy.
Speaker 3:  No, no followups.
Speaker 9:  You're going to have to listen to find out why it's called . It
Speaker 9:  was the first thing I asked. It was great.
Speaker 3:   come. And everybody you can tweet at us. Alex is
Speaker 3:  Alex H Kranz. David is at Pierce. I'm at reckless. We'd love to
Speaker 3:  hear from you. That's it. That's the word cast.
Speaker 3:  Rock'n'roll
Speaker 1:  Thanks for listening to this week show and Hey, we'd love to hear from you.
Speaker 1:  Shoot us an email at Birch cast, the verge.com. And if you'd liked the
Speaker 1:  show, share it with a friend Vergecast is a production of the verge. And
Speaker 1:  part of the Vox media podcast network today's episode was produced by
Speaker 1:  me, Liam, James, and our senior audio director, Andrew Moreno.
Speaker 1:  Our executive producer is Eleanor Donovan. That's it. We'll see
Speaker 1:  you next week.