# Transcript
ID: fd69d470-2ab2-11ed-953c-a1152fe1b899
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Snap laying off 20 percent of employees, Twitter starts testing edit button, and Logitech’s cloud gaming handheld leaks
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-3000060864341176981/733958011131962422/s93290-US-5379s-1662118261.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, David Pierce, and Alex Cranz discuss this week's gadget news.
Casey Newton joins the show to discuss Twitter finally adding the edit button for tweets.
Speaker 1:  Support for this show comes from Klaviyo. Klaviyo is the email marketing
Speaker 1:  platform that brings all your customer data into one place. With hundreds
Speaker 1:  of e-commerce integrations, Klaviyo helps you send relevant email and SMS
Speaker 1:  messages to the right people at just the right time. So you can build genuine
Speaker 1:  customer relationships and grow revenue. As brands face a more volatile
Speaker 1:  economic climate and a challenging digital landscape. Clearview is
Speaker 1:  powerful marketing automations and customer. First data are critical to
Speaker 1:  retaining brand loyalists and increasing ROI. It's time to talk to your customers
Speaker 1:  like you know them because you do with Klayvio learn
Speaker 1:  more@klaviyo.com. That's K L a V I Y
Speaker 1:  o.com.
Speaker 1:  This might have to be your last appearance on the verge cast. Like I don't
Speaker 1:  know how we in good faith, bring you back after this.
Speaker 5:  Hello and welcome to our chest flagship podcast of reacting. Well
Speaker 5:  to change, that's the theme of this episode. I'm your friend Nila. David Pierce
Speaker 5:  is here.
Speaker 1:  Hi, unlike you I'm at home. Where are you? You lie. What is happening here?
Speaker 5:  So I'm at my parent's house. I'm in their office. They're both doctors
Speaker 5:  literally got on a call yesterday and someone said, are you in a doctor's
Speaker 5:  office? Because my mom had the shelving unit put in by the people who did
Speaker 5:  her actual doctor's office. So it very much looks like a
Speaker 5:  doctor. There's a model of a heart behind me,
Speaker 6:  Point out the heart
Speaker 5:  That listeners can't see this, but I will just say, here's their mass pad.
Speaker 5:  It's an emergency helicopter MassPAT pad
Speaker 1:  With an 800 number to
Speaker 5:  Call in case you need a flight for life. That's kind of swag. My parents
Speaker 5:  get it's got it's. I was in I'm interesting because I moderated a
Speaker 5:  panel on Foxconn last night for a group of concerned citizens. It was great.
Speaker 5:  It was very fun. I told as many jokes about being from Racine as I could
Speaker 5:  to try to diffuse the room. And then at the end they had questions. I
Speaker 5:  submitted all the questions on pieces of paper and just a huge stack of
Speaker 5:  questions was about the project manager of the Fox. His name is
Speaker 5:  Claude wise and literally the questions are, why do we keep paying this guy?
Speaker 5:  There was just like a stack, like a quarter inch thick stack of paper
Speaker 5:  that all just said, why are we paying this guy? It was good, but it's going
Speaker 5:  to be back in our scene. It's very good. I will say that I'm using a bunch
Speaker 5:  of podcasts here that I just rustled up at best buy. Yeah. Like every
Speaker 5:  best buy is the same, but like your teenage best buy is special. I got to
Speaker 5:  go back to my teenage best buy and I just bought podcast gear and
Speaker 5:  much to everyone's dismay. I think, including my own,
Speaker 6:  Not my dismay. This is the best
Speaker 5:  Moment it has a built-in soundboard came with preloaded sound
Speaker 5:  effects. So like at any time I can just
Speaker 5:  ruin the show.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. That's all over now. I really like imagining you going back to your
Speaker 1:  teenage best, by the way that like superstar high school athletes go back
Speaker 1:  to their gymnasium. You open the door and everyone is like, oh
Speaker 1:  my God,
Speaker 5:  It's him. And starts cheering.
Speaker 1:  There's like a statue of you in the corner. Somewhere like Nila bought the
Speaker 1:  whole best buy. One time.
Speaker 5:  It's stand in the middle of the TV island. Do you know who I am? I'm trying
Speaker 5:  to resetting the settings on every one of these demo televisions, sir, by
Speaker 5:  the way, forgot to introduce Alex, Alex. Cranz this year.
Speaker 6:  I'm also here. Yeah, that's true. But play me some, thank you. I was going
Speaker 6:  to be like, I need some intro music. Give me some intro
Speaker 5:  Music. I got that. I had that button too.
Speaker 6:  It's so
Speaker 6:  Alex is here.
Speaker 5:  All right. I promise not to overdo it. This is why they haven't given me
Speaker 5:  a soundboard.
Speaker 5:  Okay. I want to start by just two things at the top
Speaker 5:  one. I'm only going to hear for the first second of the show. The code conference
Speaker 5:  is next week and I have infinity meetings to go to
Speaker 5:  because the code conference, which by the way, it's happening at the same
Speaker 5:  time as the apple event. So the next week of my life is next week of all
Speaker 5:  of our lives. The verge is bonkers. So sadly, I'm just going to hear it for
Speaker 5:  the first segment, but I think Casey is joining you all talk about snap and
Speaker 5:  editable tweets.
Speaker 1:  That'd be great. We're excited about it will be fun.
Speaker 5:  Finally replaced by Casey, a longstanding dream of flying
Speaker 6:  Soundboard set
Speaker 5:  Because of the soundboard. Second, I just want everyone to take a moment
Speaker 5:  and think kind thoughts about Liam, our producer, like stop what you're
Speaker 5:  doing, pull over the car and just think about Liam in a positive way.
Speaker 5:  Because last week I also had a meeting and we had to cut the show short
Speaker 5:  and we actually got out the explanation because it was just
Speaker 5:  in the middle of a long nonsensical ramble. We cut out a lot of long non
Speaker 5:  sensible rambles on the show. And we were making jokes with a clock because
Speaker 5:  Liam had me on a timer. So I could go to my meeting
Speaker 5:  with rod to explain it to all of you. And it was fine. And you know, we always
Speaker 5:  go over our show's supposed to be an hour long. We historically have gone
Speaker 5:  over for five years, which is fine. But
Speaker 5:  the notes were at first, very positive and heartwarming. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  I think it got weird. Y'all like to the point where I was reading articles
Speaker 5:  about what Harry styles does, when one direction fans get out of control,
Speaker 5:  you know, I was like, all right, we have like, I don't know what's going
Speaker 5:  on here. So I appreciate our fandom such as it is a
Speaker 5:  bunch of people resetting the settings in best buy you're my people. I love
Speaker 5:  you. We love you. But it was me that made the show short
Speaker 5:  last week. And Liam was just keeping me on task, which is no easy
Speaker 5:  feat. This man is heroic. So just, just think kind thoughts
Speaker 5:  about Liam will do a better job explaining when my schedule makes the
Speaker 5:  show not 90 minutes, it's still going to be, you know,
Speaker 5:  60 solid,
Speaker 1:  I think in general, you should assume that if something is wrong with the
Speaker 1:  Vergecast it's Neil I's fault. Like that feels like generally the right
Speaker 1:  answer. It's like if something bad happened
Speaker 6:  A hundred percent,
Speaker 1:  Yes. Case in point,
Speaker 5:  I
Speaker 6:  Just want to say, I feel
Speaker 7:  Really uncomfortable right now. Also dear listener, I had
Speaker 7:  nothing to do with this sound board. It was not approved by me.
Speaker 7:  I will do my best.
Speaker 5:  And you get rid of
Speaker 5:  that one. Still Andrew pushed the wrong button.
Speaker 7:  No, we're leaving that in. I need people to know what you would do
Speaker 5:  To not push these four buttons. Do you
Speaker 6:  Have a wall?
Speaker 5:  I sure do. It's buried in the settings of this thing,
Speaker 5:  which I will not go through at this time, but maybe later, maybe we'll just
Speaker 5:  have a 90 minute Vergecast or I play with the settings of my zoom pod
Speaker 5:  track.  and we can just do it. That's our take talk strategy,
Speaker 5:  but people sent weird notes to Liam. I think that's out of bounds. Don't
Speaker 5:  do that. If you're a problem to show, talk to us, Liam is a part of our show.
Speaker 5:  He, he makes the show good along with Andrew, our, our engineer. So be cool
Speaker 5:  to them. Blame it on me. That's fine. Okay. Let's talk about some news this
Speaker 5:  week. We got apple event next week and a bunch of gadget news. This week.
Speaker 5:  Twitter is doing editable tweets. Casey's going to have to talk about that.
Speaker 5:  Let's start with apple. We've got a big sort of state of apple special
Speaker 5:  episode coming next week that David made us do quite honestly, he gave us
Speaker 5:  homework. We had to do homework for
Speaker 6:  Us. It was good. I did. All of mine
Speaker 5:  Was a lot of homework. So we'll talk about the broader state of apple next
Speaker 5:  week, but let's talk about the event cause it's common. It's called far out,
Speaker 5:  by the way, a number of people wrote to us after we said, does anyone
Speaker 5:  want to write about the invites? A lot
Speaker 6:  Of people do.
Speaker 5:  And I think Jake is actually has assigned that story based
Speaker 5:  on. So it's good. So the event's called far out. You don't know what that
Speaker 5:  means. There's a lot of noise about satellite connectivity and phone's slightly
Speaker 5:  what's going on there
Speaker 6:  Far out, man,
Speaker 1:  A far out, you know, hints at satellite
Speaker 1:  is one version of this. And there have been rumors flying around. I think
Speaker 1:  mostly thanks to mark Gruner at Bloomberg, who is usually right about this
Speaker 1:  stuff. That satellite connectivity is a thing that apple has been working
Speaker 1:  on. It may depend on some complicated deals with
Speaker 1:  wireless carriers, how that would work, but satellite
Speaker 1:  connection is potentially a thing that you are going to get on future apple
Speaker 1:  devices. And the thing that I think is most interesting. And you
Speaker 1:  said this new line, I think I thought you were wrong and it turns out, I
Speaker 1:  think you were right, is that the apple watch seems to
Speaker 1:  be like maybe the most interesting thing coming at this
Speaker 1:  event, especially if the new apple watch pro, which is rumored to be bigger
Speaker 1:  and more rugged and industrial. And like for people who use big garments,
Speaker 1:  more watches, if that thing gets satellite connectivity, which is one of
Speaker 1:  the things that's now being talked about would be a huge deal. And there
Speaker 1:  seems to be a lot of excitement about that idea
Speaker 6:  Because its competitors already have satellite connectivity, but like in
Speaker 6:  a different way, right? Like, like the competitors are doing it to kind of
Speaker 6:  like be a backup to GPS, I think, whereas the rumors
Speaker 1:  Like an emergency system for a lot of these.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And the rumors for the apple one is that this would help you like
Speaker 6:  stay connected online and be really good emergency
Speaker 6:  services, but maybe not this year, but
Speaker 5:  There's a few cuts at this. Right? So T-Mobile and Starlink just
Speaker 5:  announced a big deal. T-Mobile phones were able to connect to
Speaker 5:  Starlink, which is cool. Like just legitimately cool. But you know,
Speaker 5:  you obviously need to have line of sight to Starlink, which is a
Speaker 5:  startling.
Speaker 1:  It's one of those things that like sounds really cool in the abstract and
Speaker 1:  will not affect any real person in life. Very often. It's
Speaker 1:  like as a T-Mobile subscriber in New York city, like this will affect my
Speaker 1:  life in no way whatsoever.
Speaker 5:  I mean the game is coverage gaps in time. Like you're going to make the apple
Speaker 5:  watch bigger. You're gonna add a big battery. And then you're going to add
Speaker 5:  the radio that will kill that battery as fast as possible. Like that's part
Speaker 5:  of the game that's being played here. But so the startling thing is like
Speaker 5:  Starlink is on its own bands as its own communication system.
Speaker 5:  It does its thing
Speaker 6:  It's on bands for now,
Speaker 5:  Until there are ongoing fight with dish network continues to
Speaker 5:  rage, then there are a bunch of other companies, there's a company called
Speaker 5:  link with a Y that we've written about. We just reached out back to them,
Speaker 5:  Mitchell Clark owner, a great story about these other satellite companies
Speaker 5:  that are doing satellite connectivity. They're actually all pretty excited
Speaker 5:  about the Starling thing in the way that companies are always excited. When
Speaker 5:  the famous company starts to do the thing they're doing, they're like a rising
Speaker 5:  tide. Everyone will know about us. We'll see how that goes. But link
Speaker 5:  actually is basically doing cell towers in space, right? So you've
Speaker 5:  got basically a cell base station on a satellite sending
Speaker 5:  standard LTE signals, 5g signals to
Speaker 5:  phones. And so we've covered this before. Loren Grush wrote
Speaker 5:  about it. Mitchell just wrote about it. This is okay. You're in a place with
Speaker 5:  no service. And your phone just connects using a standard radio
Speaker 5:  to a satellite, which is different than Starling, right? It's it's still
Speaker 5:  using it's LTE radio. It's unclear. And there's a
Speaker 5:  third thing that apple has been rumored to be doing, which is a totally
Speaker 5:  different satellite system. So it's unclear which of these things will come
Speaker 5:  to the watch. I'd very much doubt at Starling. The question is whether
Speaker 5:  you know, it, most people, most days with their apple watch are sitting
Speaker 5:  inside of an LTE or 5g coverage area, right? Like that's,
Speaker 5:  that's the point of the cell network is to mostly cover everything. It's
Speaker 5:  when you are up on the mountain or in the middle of the ocean or wherever
Speaker 5:  the, you don't have a cell network that you'll hit, hit, hit the satellite,
Speaker 6:  The entire great Plains. You just won't have internet
Speaker 6:  connection half the time. It's really bad. Right.
Speaker 5:  I think the question is like, okay, you're in a rural area. You're here in
Speaker 5:  Wisconsin and you drive off the highway for 45 minutes where there's no
Speaker 5:  service is your phone slash watch, gonna flip over to satellite.
Speaker 6:  And that's cool.
Speaker 5:  Open question. Yeah. And I think that, that would be really cool if they
Speaker 5:  pull it off. I think the question is like, which satellite system are they
Speaker 5:  going to use? Right. Because there are these competing variations of it Starling
Speaker 5:  being one Lincoln, the other one's being another, like which system is apple
Speaker 5:  going to use if, if they use any of them and how will they type of battery
Speaker 5:  life.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. But I do think, I mean, this is why I think it, like there had been
Speaker 1:  rumors about this coming to the iPhone and stuff too. And I think all of
Speaker 1:  that makes some sense, but I think, especially for people who are like the
Speaker 1:  watch pro potential buyers, assuming the watch pro is, you know, what it's
Speaker 1:  called and what we think it is. Those are the people who like seek out the
Speaker 1:  kinds of places you're describing. Right. Yeah. And, and are going to be
Speaker 1:  willing to make the kind of trade-off where it's like, okay, this, this might
Speaker 1:  be a thing I like have to turn on on purpose, but it means I don't have to
Speaker 1:  carry a gigantic satellite phone or one of those
Speaker 1:  big Garmin in reach things like it's just as an
Speaker 1:  added extra thing, it strikes me as like very niche, but
Speaker 1:  massively meaningful for those kinds of people. Even if it's like a
Speaker 1:  somewhat clunky system, I have to say, I would not rule out Starlink, just
Speaker 1:  because I think it would be like deeply hilarious Elon Musk thing to be like,
Speaker 1:  he, he just like, he's putting it all the weird places you can think of.
Speaker 1:  And they're Lakewood watch Starlink. We don't know what it's for cost
Speaker 1:  $9,000 a month, but it exists.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I mean he just announced Starling kind of cruise ships, Starlink perfect
Speaker 5:  for cruise ships, no trees in the ocean. I'm told
Speaker 5:  I, you know, I just think like the, the T-Mobile deal is like, it's
Speaker 5:  interesting. T-Mobile is aggressive in that way of it. They need to expand
Speaker 5:  their coverage map. Right. They've got a really good network and the places
Speaker 5:  they are, but they're not everywhere. That deal makes sense for them. And
Speaker 5:  they get some hype. But I think for apple and the iPhone, a feature
Speaker 5:  like this cannot be tied to one carrier is
Speaker 5:  availability, right? It's it's gotta be taught. It's got to work on all the
Speaker 5:  carriers. It's everywhere. They sell however many iPhones a minute. It's
Speaker 5:  got to work in all the places. Apple sells all those phones around the world.
Speaker 5:  And so I think they need something more robust than just us Starling deal.
Speaker 5:  So we'll see. I think the fundamental question is like, what partner are
Speaker 5:  they going to choose? Is it multiple partners? What systems are they going
Speaker 5:  to use? And fundamentally like, if you are the person that's seeking out
Speaker 5:  the remote area and you're relying on the satellite connectivity, how much
Speaker 5:  battery are you going to get? Because this is the thing that might save your
Speaker 5:  life. Right. Are you going to carry a battery pack with inductive charge?
Speaker 5:  Like those big honkin, Garmin things with they're also big
Speaker 5:  batteries. Like,
Speaker 6:  Well, I think the idea there is that like, it doesn't activate unless you
Speaker 6:  need it to like, oh, I'm stuck on a mountain. I'm like,
Speaker 6:  got way off the trail. I need help. Now I hit the
Speaker 6:  button. Now it activates the satellite. Now it connects me to
Speaker 6:  emergency services so they can come find me,
Speaker 5:  But that's one riff at it.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And that's like a step above what you're seeing, like Garmin and some
Speaker 6:  of these other companies do now, which is like just souped up
Speaker 6:  GPS, essentially. Like it's just using a number of
Speaker 6:  extra satellites and bands to like,
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So we'll see. The question is like, what system are they going to use?
Speaker 5:  Does it provide like, think about Starlink sewing provides
Speaker 5:  broadband data. It doesn't have ancillary services. It's a broadband
Speaker 5:  data connection. The Garmin thing provides a location and like a
Speaker 5:  beacon. There's a whole universe of things in between those two extremes.
Speaker 5:  Where is apple going to land? I think it's a good question.
Speaker 6:  The star lake thing, I just keep going back to, like, I've got a lot of friends
Speaker 6:  who live in rural areas and are driving all the time, just crisscrossing
Speaker 6:  across like New Mexico and Texas. And I'm like, that whole industry of people
Speaker 6:  is just going to go get T-Mobile phones if it works out that well.
Speaker 6:  Right. Like if you can guarantee all those dead
Speaker 5:  Spots above their car as they drive away.
Speaker 6:  Exactly. And I'd be like, finally, I got a service it's wild. You'll be like,
Speaker 6:  just driving down a fairly large highway in like west Texas
Speaker 6:  and like, okay, I just don't have internet now. I guess I just hope this
Speaker 6:  is the right road to get me where I'm going. Goodbye GPS. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  So,
Speaker 5:  Yeah, that's also
Speaker 1:  What I'm hearing is Apple's going to launch a Sabbath, like an actual satellite
Speaker 1:  dish that you buy and just carry with you.
Speaker 5:  I will say. I agree. Like the watch is getting more and more interesting
Speaker 5:  as we learn more and more about it. We have a bunch of stories on the watch,
Speaker 5:  the phone, not much more easily tied about the phone next week.
Speaker 6:  My new phone.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. It seems like we have a pretty good idea of what the, the non notch
Speaker 1:  notch is going to look like. And that's kind of all there.
Speaker 1:  So
Speaker 5:  We wrote a story about it. This today, the lightening cable just turned
Speaker 5:  10. So if Apple's going to switch to USBC, this is actually
Speaker 5:  regardless of, you know, European regulators walking around the Capitol
Speaker 5:  cities of Europe, being angry at apple, regardless of what happens there
Speaker 5:  with USB-C, this would be the moment to switch over to the next generation.
Speaker 5:  Right. They rarely make it more than 10 years with,
Speaker 6:  Do you think we're really going to get a USB-C iPhone this year? I feel like
Speaker 6:  20% chance
Speaker 5:  Sort of thing. Like if it was going to happen, it would have already, wheat
Speaker 5:  is my feeling
Speaker 6:  That would be the, that would be the news.
Speaker 5:  The accessory makers would know case makers would know, like it would,
Speaker 5:  it would be huge news, but we'll see it's it is possible that
Speaker 5:  this is the last lightening iPhone. It's also, I would say to a
Speaker 5:  vanishingly smaller percentage possible that this is the USBC FN.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. That, that I, I agree that that's unlikely. Cause it seems like, like
Speaker 1:  your point about accessories is the right one that they tend to be the ones
Speaker 1:  who write this stuff ahead of time, just because you start to see
Speaker 1:  stuff, go through the FCC and everybody's making the models. And it's always
Speaker 1:  hard to know because some of that is just them guessing as based on the same
Speaker 1:  news reports that everybody sees. But there there's like, there's no smoke
Speaker 1:  around that at all right now. And you would think there would at least be
Speaker 1:  a little bit, even if it was going to be like just the pro max is now the
Speaker 1:  USBC model. I feel like there would be, there would be more
Speaker 1:  about that out there right now. Cause that would be a gigantic,
Speaker 5:  You could see them phasing it in that way. That's what they've done with
Speaker 5:  the iPads. So we'll see, it's just it's 10. And that
Speaker 5:  means, regardless of what is happening with regulators and antitrust,
Speaker 5:  like 10 years for any connector is a long time. And this is
Speaker 5:  historically when apple flu,
Speaker 6:  She did it last longer than that original iPod connector. It did. Right?
Speaker 5:  The iPod catcher was made it like eight
Speaker 6:  Years. Good job lightning,
Speaker 5:  2001 to 2008 because they flipped to lightening with a
Speaker 5:  four. No they didn't. So the hold on, let me say it
Speaker 5:  all over again. The iPod connector made it nine or 10 years
Speaker 5:  because they launched the lightning. No, that's still not right. I'm gonna
Speaker 5:  get this right. I'm not going to look. No,
Speaker 7:  You're you're right. It, they started phasing in and out at around nine
Speaker 7:  years, but it lasted for 10 years, the
Speaker 7:  iPod connector, the 30 pin.
Speaker 5:  Right. But th the first iPod had FireWire
Speaker 5:  rip FireWire the greatest connector ever
Speaker 6:  Made best connector.
Speaker 7:  Absolutely. It was Mac only and all that. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And then they switched to
Speaker 6:  Plug it into your iMac. Bondi blue.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. They switched to 30 pin when they were going, when they started doing
Speaker 5:  windows and then it lasted through the iPhone four and the iPhone
Speaker 5:  five had lightning and that was kind of it. So it was around for about
Speaker 5:  10 years. Okay. Liam is correct. C thank you, Liam.
Speaker 5:  But anyway, this is about the time, regardless of the regulatory thing. So
Speaker 5:  we'll see, because the apple doing another proprietary connector for the
Speaker 5:  phone seems bonkers and Meg safe
Speaker 5:  is like most weird apple proprietary connectors,
Speaker 5:  not an ecosystem of value. I'm still on the hunt for a
Speaker 5:  MagSafe car charger. That is good. Like there aren't any,
Speaker 1:  My guess would be apple is going to have a USB-C port
Speaker 1:  and also try really hard to sell you. MagSafe accessories is there, they're
Speaker 1:  going to like bury the fact that there's a USB-C port at the bottom of
Speaker 1:  every release and webpage and be like, but would you like to charge with
Speaker 1:  mag safe? And so they're going to like, try to convince you to use it, but
Speaker 1:  then actually everyone's just going to use USB-C and apple will happily sell
Speaker 1:  you a $50 USBC because yeah.
Speaker 5:  They'll ever take the portfolio off the phone to me, strike like apple
Speaker 5:  will destroy its own service ability. If there's not a wired
Speaker 5:  connection to the phone to do resets and all that stuff and diagnostics.
Speaker 5:  Okay.
Speaker 6:  I think I would buy one. If it didn't have some sort of like port that was
Speaker 6:  easily.
Speaker 5:  So this is your line and it stamps Bluetooth ports, sir, I leave
Speaker 6:  At least one port because wires are good. I won't, I won't
Speaker 6:  stand for it.
Speaker 5:  And during theme of the verge, why, why are things are better than Y
Speaker 5:  so that's apple. I mean, we're expecting two phones, a watch. I think
Speaker 5:  my interest in the watch just continues to rise. I'm ready for new one. Do
Speaker 5:  you think it'll be still be a square or anything? They're going to be a circle
Speaker 6:  And you don't have like the big shock ring that like all of the, the
Speaker 6:  garments and stuff have, you know, set to protect it. Like, is it going to
Speaker 6:  be like a chunky monster? Like most of them, or is it going to be
Speaker 6:  like apple?
Speaker 5:  I hope so. I hope so. I mean, I think they have to sell the
Speaker 5:  idea of durability here, which is not a thing apple traditionally sells.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I hope they go full sports Walkman and it's bright
Speaker 5:  yellow and it like has a foldy cover that flips for no reason.
Speaker 5:  Let's do it
Speaker 6:  Just a little bit off.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Yeah. If you haven't seen a Sony sports Walkman from the early
Speaker 5:  nineties, there's a design language that needs to come back into our lives.
Speaker 6:  That was like the satisfaction of closing that versus a regular
Speaker 6:  Walkman. Like if they just
Speaker 5:  Click in the hinge,
Speaker 6:  It was, I can just feel it. It was good. Go by one, everyone,
Speaker 5:  All the rest of the show. Also every one of those sunny products had the
Speaker 5:  word sports written on it in giant
Speaker 6:  Letters, for some reason to sport,
Speaker 5:  Just in case the bright yellow wasn't enough of a tip off
Speaker 5:  what it was. It's like, this is where sports you guys. It's a
Speaker 5:  boombox for sports. All right. There's a bunch of other gash and here's,
Speaker 5:  what's this Logitech thing.
Speaker 6:  I am most excited about this.
Speaker 1:  I'm very excited about this. So we've, we've known for a while, or at least
Speaker 1:  there have been, there have been rumors and leaks for awhile. That logic
Speaker 1:  tech was going to make something along the lines of the
Speaker 1:  Nintendo switch and the steam deck, like where in that spectrum, it would
Speaker 1:  be, nobody knew. But like, as we've talked about on the show, it's basically
Speaker 1:  just a screen with some buttons, logic Tech's really good at making buttons
Speaker 1:  makes a lot of sense that this is a thing logic tech would do. And then the
Speaker 1:  leaks came out and it basically, Alex had kind of like, it's like a,
Speaker 1:  it's like a Nintendo switch light, but it runs
Speaker 1:  actual Android.
Speaker 6:  It's basically a bunch of companies have already been doing this. I think
Speaker 6:  IO is how you pronounce it is one of the big ones besides like steam deck
Speaker 6:  and Nintendo. And this is like logic text version where it's not about
Speaker 6:  creating a whole game ecosystem. It's just like, Hey, you want cloud gaming?
Speaker 6:  You also, I guess, want to play, play store game. Sometimes you can do all
Speaker 6:  of that with this. And it'll probably be really cheap compared to
Speaker 6:  a steam deck or a Nintendo switch. I would hope it looks cheap, like
Speaker 6:  in a good way though.
Speaker 1:  It does achieve well. And I think the, there have been a bunch of rumors
Speaker 1:  out there about like what the specs are going to be. And it sounds like it's
Speaker 1:  going to be much more like phone specs than
Speaker 1:  like,
Speaker 6:  Well, we just, all
Speaker 1:  You need named X specs in that it's not designed to like, right.
Speaker 1:  And they're going to go all in on game streaming. They're doing this with
Speaker 1:  Logitech is working with Tencent to do this, like this idea that like, I
Speaker 1:  need just enough power to basically run like streaming video apps. And then
Speaker 1:  I'll stream games that are harder than that from the cloud
Speaker 1:  strikes me as like the perfect medium of this. I like, I'm very excited.
Speaker 6:  My favorite bit about this image is like the top image shows you a
Speaker 6:  sensibly. A lot of the things you'll be able to play out of the box, Google
Speaker 6:  play X-Box G-Force invidious
Speaker 6:  cloud service. It's great. X-Box
Speaker 1:  Xbox logo for some reason,
Speaker 6:  Theme Chrome and YouTube. So no
Speaker 6:  Luna and no stadia. And somebody pointed out that
Speaker 6:  they probably had stadia in there and realized it was like too many Google
Speaker 6:  things on the page. So instead they just replaced it with an Xbox
Speaker 5:  Xbox.
Speaker 6:  That's what? That was the theory in my Twitter
Speaker 1:  List. No one cares.
Speaker 6:  People care. All four of them have been in my DMS this
Speaker 6:  week being like, how did you, could you make fun of stadia? And I was like,
Speaker 6:  it's just, I just noticed it's not there, but it's so easy
Speaker 6:  to exist. And people are like, I want to kick you. I don't know why
Speaker 5:  That's not the right instinct for anything
Speaker 6:  Cloud gaming services. It is.
Speaker 5:  I want to kick it. It's just like you should, in general, you're like
Speaker 5:  matching up the right fair. I want to kick the
Speaker 5:  air violently in the direction of stadia the Alex grand story. It's
Speaker 5:  true. Here's my concern about this whole thing. Cause you said it looks cheap
Speaker 5:  and cheap in a good way. It looks inexpensive.
Speaker 6:  Yes. That's a better way to
Speaker 5:  Put it. And we think it's going to have this Qualcomm G three
Speaker 5:  X platform chip in it reasonably good
Speaker 5:  GPU. Here's my worry about cloud gaming is
Speaker 5:  the most latency dependent thing you can do on a computer,
Speaker 5:  right? Like you push the button, it's got to go to the cloud service.
Speaker 5:  Something's got to happen. It's got to render the next frame of the video
Speaker 5:  in response to your button and send it back to you. Right. That's hard. Like
Speaker 5:  it's just a hard thing. It's, it's hard on Xboxes,
Speaker 5:  which have lots of processing power. Mine is plugged directly into the wall,
Speaker 5:  not the wall. I mean, it is plugged directly in the wall that is accurate.
Speaker 5:  Mine's plugged directly into the router. Like it has a wired connection to
Speaker 5:  my actual internet service. And it's still like, Ugh, you know,
Speaker 5:  inexpensive wifi gadget, having a good cloud gaming
Speaker 5:  experience,
Speaker 6:  Enough cloud gaming like on the steam deck and on like a pixel three, a and
Speaker 6:  stuff that I think for most games, especially like adventure games,
Speaker 6:  you'll be fine. I wouldn't want to go playing like street
Speaker 6:  fighter on this or call of duty. Those really like Twitch
Speaker 6:  intensive games. I would not want to play that in the cloud ever. And
Speaker 6:  certainly not on this, but if you're like, you know what I want to just like
Speaker 6:  bang out some star wars, fallen, Jedi order,
Speaker 6:  whatever it is called, it has a terrible name. But if you want to play that
Speaker 6:  game or an assassin creed, you can
Speaker 5:  Do,
Speaker 9:  It was a twitchy game. You got to step right at the right time.
Speaker 5:  The whole game is stabbing. The whole game is time to stamps.
Speaker 6:  It's not as bad as like having to block someone in street fighter.
Speaker 9:  No people are trying to stab you in that. Have you played Assassin's creed?
Speaker 9:  Yes,
Speaker 6:  But I don't. I would never watch it. People
Speaker 5:  Try to stab you enough to be able to,
Speaker 6:  But I feel like the timing on that's easier to like anticipate versus street
Speaker 6:  fighter.
Speaker 5:  All right. The Assassin's creed, people are going to come for you. And
Speaker 6:  Unfortunately
Speaker 5:  They are assassins.
Speaker 5:  Therefore the leaves are roots.
Speaker 6:  We've established a kick. I got chicken. I'm going to
Speaker 6:  kick in the air and their direction. This has gotten very violent. I'm
Speaker 6:  so sorry.
Speaker 5:  I say, I, I, I it's, I think it's, this stuff works on
Speaker 5:  hilariously. It works on PCs. It works on steam deck, which is a little
Speaker 5:  PC. It works on consoles to some extent I'm
Speaker 5:  just like inexpensive wifi gadget. The most important spec for
Speaker 5:  this Ondracek thing is the wifi chip
Speaker 6:  A hundred percent. Yes. And that's the thing we don't know yet. Right? Like
Speaker 6:  we don't know any of the guts of this thing. So it could still be hot, garbage,
Speaker 6:  and also like the price on it. Like just looking at it, thinking about the
Speaker 6:  processor and stuff, the phone that you would need to play cloud gaming is
Speaker 6:  going to be, you know, 400, $500. Are they going to drop that price
Speaker 6:  down here? And how are they going to cut costs to get down to that price
Speaker 6:  for one of these things? Like, is it going to just have the crummiest display
Speaker 6:  of all time? Are the buttons going to be junkie? Like
Speaker 5:  The first place he cut the cost? They're like, you know what? They're going
Speaker 5:  to be a big cheap screen. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  You see every pixel.
Speaker 1:  Yep.
Speaker 6:   it's gonna be great. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  What's interesting is this is going to come up against, you know, presumably
Speaker 5:  a rebooted switch at some point. Yep. And I, it doesn't seem like
Speaker 5:  Nintendo is going to let X-Box game streaming happened on their platform.
Speaker 6:  Never.
Speaker 5:  So I just think there's going to be an odd set of choices here, where you,
Speaker 5:  instead of having cartridges, you just have a lineup of weird little handhelds.
Speaker 6:  That's what I have now. And he
Speaker 5:  Was like, pull it out to play a game.
Speaker 6:  Like which one will I do today? Like steam deck switch.
Speaker 1:  That is definitely where we're
Speaker 6:  Headed the little play date, which is really hard.
Speaker 5:  I'm play date.
Speaker 6:  I have a play date. I'm terrible at it. Like there's a game where you surf
Speaker 6:  and you have to, you have to do the crank and time with it. And I do not
Speaker 6:  know how people accomplish it. Like there's no instructions. You're just
Speaker 6:  supposed to,
Speaker 5:  I think what I'm learning from this conversation is that you are not good
Speaker 5:  at games with timing. And in fact, you discount them. So you discount timing
Speaker 5:  so much. There's no timing and assassins.
Speaker 6:  I was really good at soul caliber to soul
Speaker 6:  caliber too. I was an incredible, that's got timing.
Speaker 5:  That's a logic thing. There's like all kinds of ND screen news going on right
Speaker 5:  now.
Speaker 1:  The screens, I love them. Everybody just looks at screens and goes like,
Speaker 1:  what if this was insane? Why would you spend thousands of dollars on that?
Speaker 5:  You can tell like the me, like order
Speaker 5:  sheet went out and the prices were low enough.
Speaker 6:  Everybody said yes. Like
Speaker 5:  Everyone got the facts. It's like bendy screens now available. And they were
Speaker 5:  like, oh, these are cheap now. Sure. Bendable theater, TV
Speaker 5:  stand.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, we've got, we've got LG has its first bendable OLED,
Speaker 6:  which is not quite true because they had the one that rolled. And technically
Speaker 6:  if it's rolling, it's bending, but we'll, we'll allow it.
Speaker 6:  Cause this is like an actual
Speaker 1:  Outside of this one is it lets you choose. I think this is like actually
Speaker 1:  kind of great. Like the more I read about this thing, the more I like it,
Speaker 1:  it, it basically lets you switch between flat and
Speaker 1:  curved modes. And so as we've talked about before, the only
Speaker 1:  use I've ever found for curved screens is to make it feel like you are
Speaker 1:  inside of your zoom call and you just like wrap everyone around you. And
Speaker 1:  that is very cool. And so you can use that and then just push it back when
Speaker 1:  you want to like actually watch TV, like a regular person and not feel like
Speaker 1:  an idiot for buying a curved screen. That makes total sense. To me, I'm very
Speaker 1:  into that. I don't know that I would spend what this thing will cost, but
Speaker 1:  I'm very into that as an idea.
Speaker 6:  I think it's also interesting because for LG in particular, like they're
Speaker 6:  calling it a TV, they're branding it as a TV, but it's at
Speaker 6:  42 and which is lower than, which is smaller than that 48 inch. And that
Speaker 6:  48 inch is really where like a lot of people started adopting TVs
Speaker 6:  as monitors and saying actually like the pixel density
Speaker 6:  is good enough. Now that I can just use the setup as a monitor. And this
Speaker 6:  feels like part of LG kind of continuing to dip its toe into
Speaker 6:  like TV's as gaming monitors, LG already
Speaker 6:  has a huge like gaming monitor business. But this is a whole new
Speaker 6:  category of all ads that they're selling as TVs. But really our
Speaker 6:  monitors, like this thing is just a monitor. All the pictures of it are
Speaker 6:  as a monitor. Like it's big tower is very monitor based.
Speaker 5:  Oh yeah. The stand of this TV hill is ridiculous.
Speaker 5:  Like if you actually use this as a TV, like everyone would be like, what's
Speaker 5:  going on with your TV? Cause it, it has a gigantic and he should, the gift
Speaker 5:  that we have in this story is just incredible. And pull over in your car
Speaker 5:  and read the story about the old, the LGO and flux TV at Eva that we have
Speaker 5:  on the site because a gift is beautiful.
Speaker 1:  It looks like it's about a rapids self around you and like strangle you to
Speaker 1:  death.
Speaker 6:  It's going to be at Eva and, and John Porter is,
Speaker 6:  is there. And he's going to, he's going to go look at this thing
Speaker 5:  And it's going to hug him and hug him until he does.
Speaker 6:  It's just going to embrace him. And it's liquid electric diodes.
Speaker 5:  So Samsung also has a big old gaming monitor. The G eight it
Speaker 5:  guess what supports chief horse out and stadia in game pass right
Speaker 5:  in the display. Great.
Speaker 1:  I have come around on this thing that Samsung is doing, which is basically
Speaker 1:  like building smart TVs into its monitors. It took me a while to sort
Speaker 1:  of understand why that's useful. Cause I'm like, well, if I just want to
Speaker 1:  watch Hulu, I'll just go to hulu.com on my computer and it accomplishes at
Speaker 1:  the same thing. But something like this where it's like, okay, you can just
Speaker 1:  like, you can not attach anything and sort of use it as a TV,
Speaker 1:  but then like plugging your laptop when you come home. It's like, that kinda
Speaker 1:  makes sense.
Speaker 5:  It's not useless when your laptop is somewhere else or doing something else.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, exactly. Yeah. I, I like it. It also looks great at 34
Speaker 1:  inches.
Speaker 6:  This is your home set up. Look like with this thing. Like these big ones
Speaker 6:  totally makes sense. In a dorm room. I can immediately see the big Lebowski
Speaker 6:  poster behind it as soon as you put it in. But, but what's
Speaker 6:  like in a home usually have your, for most people,
Speaker 6:  those of us not in New York, like you usually have an office and a
Speaker 6:  TV room and this puts the two together.
Speaker 1:  I'm sorry. Do you imagine that everyone who doesn't live in New York lives
Speaker 1:  in a gigantic mansion?
Speaker 6:  I assume you all have so many reports on your home. I have
Speaker 6:  three that's it?
Speaker 5:  I'm in a doctor's office
Speaker 1:  Is real. That's fair.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I mean, I think they're set up with this kind of looks like you, maybe
Speaker 5:  like somebody works from home and you've repurposed a room as an
Speaker 5:  office. And like, then you realize like for many hours a day I can use this
Speaker 5:  room for something else. Or you just want to have another TV in your
Speaker 5:  house and you're going to use this as that TV, but
Speaker 5:  then you can also use it in an office set up.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. This is for all the people whose home office is also in a corner of
Speaker 1:  their bedroom, which I think is a lot of people. And now it's also your bedrooms
Speaker 5:  Having a, like a 34 inch ultra wide bedroom TV is
Speaker 5:  a particular kind of flex.
Speaker 6:  I was like, I have a 60 inch bedroom TV. It's important to have
Speaker 6:  a nice TV. Your bedrooms.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Big guy, other gadget news. So Monica
Speaker 5:  reviewed the Zen book, which folds the new one, the 17 fold.
Speaker 5:  And she was like, this is really close, but it's a six and dumped by it.
Speaker 5:  And then she wrote up the new ThinkPad X one fold the second gen. And she
Speaker 5:  was like, this could be it, but it might be a sex in them by it.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. It's like
Speaker 5:  The,
Speaker 1:  The, the, the main thing is like, can we build a laptop with a screen
Speaker 1:  that folds? And the answer is like, starting to be yes. But
Speaker 1:  then in both cases, it's like, oh no, you forgot to build a good lab.
Speaker 6:  I kind of love it because all of this was happening. Like these things have
Speaker 6:  been in development for years. We've all seen these prototypes
Speaker 6:  slate. When you go to a briefing, somebody say, Hey, come here, come here.
Speaker 6:  I got something cool for you in the, pull it out of a bag. And it's always
Speaker 6:  one of these devices. Yeah. And for years now, right.
Speaker 6:  And then we all thought it was because windows, Microsoft was going to do
Speaker 6:  their big, what was it? The Neo, they were going to do Neo. And it was going
Speaker 6:  to be like their big folding laptop thing. And then they just have banded
Speaker 6:  it. And all of that,
Speaker 5:  It wasn't folding. It was dual screen. Microsoft has like, the future of
Speaker 5:  everything is two screens.
Speaker 6:  And these are effectively kind of dual screen. Cause they fold. And then
Speaker 6:  you can use both screens in that weird folding way that you would never
Speaker 6:  use your Samsung galaxy folders. So I just, I think it's interesting
Speaker 6:  that they're still doing it despite not really as much support from
Speaker 6:  Microsoft because Microsoft was like, yeah, do this. And he's like telling
Speaker 6:  everybody, yeah, I do this. We all should have these. And then everybody
Speaker 6:  made them in Microsoft. Like, oh yeah, you think that's
Speaker 5:  The interesting thing about both of these, right? When you think about, okay,
Speaker 5:  it's a folding screen laptop, you think that you would open it like a regular
Speaker 5:  laptop and the bottom would be like a touch screen keyboard on top of you
Speaker 5:  the screen. And they could open it all the way and get the big display. And
Speaker 5:  here both companies are like, also we shoved a Bluetooth keyboard in the
Speaker 5:  middle of the sandwich because actually typing on a touch screen is no good.
Speaker 5:  So there's like both of them have like a little like a keyboard
Speaker 5:  Frisbee that you like sticking to it. And you can use it in the big tattle
Speaker 5:  mode with the keyboard in front.
Speaker 6:  Well, it's also to protect the display because these things are so big that
Speaker 6:  you can't fold them flat. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I just don't think we've hit the form factor of this if you still need
Speaker 5:  physical keys.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Right. It's like undercuts. The whole purpose of it is which is like, is
Speaker 1:  it even possible to do like a touch screen, haptic keyboard? That feels
Speaker 1:  good. I'm not positive that it is, but I think, yeah. It's
Speaker 1:  like, can we make a screen that folds, that doesn't look like trash? Like
Speaker 1:  the, these companies are starting to say like, yes we can. And then it's
Speaker 1:  like, how do we make this like an enjoyable device for you to use in all
Speaker 1:  of the ways that aren't just basically a big
Speaker 1:  tablet with a crappy Bluetooth keyboard. And we have not yet
Speaker 5:  In many ways, what they have made is like a super surface,
Speaker 5:  right? If you just had a big surface, like a Microsoft surface
Speaker 5:  tablet and it was just bigger. Yeah. Like they've accomplished that
Speaker 5:  goal, which is an interesting goal,
Speaker 1:  Which is something. But
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I think the form factor of folding phones, I think has settled into
Speaker 5:  two camps. Right? There's big foam that gets smaller and big firm
Speaker 5:  that gets bigger. And I think with laptops, it's like weird laptop that gets
Speaker 5:  weirder
Speaker 5:  set. So he wanted,
Speaker 5:  I think there's a couple more rounds here of like figuring out what all this
Speaker 5:  screen is for and how you like, where he, the thing that had one is hilarious.
Speaker 5:  Cause it still has the ThinkPad nub.
Speaker 6:  That's the best part,
Speaker 5:  The track point. So it's like, there are so many ways to move the mouse on
Speaker 5:  this.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. It, just, to me, it feels like, like, you know, you see the people
Speaker 1:  at the coffee shop who like set up their laptop and then reach back into
Speaker 1:  their bag and pull out the keyboard and then reach back into their bag and
Speaker 1:  pull out the mouse. And it's like, okay, this to me is what failure looks
Speaker 1:  like. Like somebody needed the way bad product and convinced you to buy it.
Speaker 1:  If this is how you're having to use it. And to me, it's like, that's how
Speaker 1:  I feel about the foldables too. It's like, I will believe in these things
Speaker 1:  when I start to see people sitting at Starbucks, hammering away on the
Speaker 1:  screen without any other attachment, like if I need another piece,
Speaker 6:  Do you think it's more likely to be seen in a Starbucks in the next year?
Speaker 6:  People with these are people bringing like a full tower and monitor
Speaker 5:  Full tower? Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  They're not going to steal that
Speaker 5:  Away. I've definitely seen somebody. I
Speaker 6:  Was just wondering like maybe, maybe it becomes popular.
Speaker 5:  I've definitely seen somebody bring a full iMac back to a coffee shop.
Speaker 6:  It's incredible. You just watch them. You're like they're coming in. It's
Speaker 6:  very clear what they're going to do. All right.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It's not subtle. What's about to happen here. The man has a
Speaker 5:  27 inch iMac and a determined look on his face.
Speaker 6:  He needs to buy so much coffee.
Speaker 5:  All right. Last one, ring Intercom. And that's also
Speaker 5:   going on. That's why there's so much gadget news. It's a big
Speaker 5:  gadget show in Europe.
Speaker 6:  So excited about this Intercom.
Speaker 5:  I don't quite understand this Intercom.
Speaker 6:  So I personally am excited because I have an Intercom in
Speaker 6:  my home and it's got three buttons on it. And one is to
Speaker 6:  yell at people. One is to hear people yell at me and
Speaker 6:  one is to open the door so they can come up and yell at me. It's very angry
Speaker 6:  in my neighborhood
Speaker 5:  Because they're kicking everybody all the time.
Speaker 6:  But this is meant to like work with those kinds of systems. It's
Speaker 6:  primarily focused in Europe right now because there's a lot more apartments.
Speaker 6:  They're all with intercoms. And so it's kind of like to give
Speaker 6:  you the ability that some of you guys have maybe where you can
Speaker 6:  just check on your phone. If somebody buzzes, I have to get up and like go
Speaker 6:  and find someone, and this will let you do it from your phone. Or like I
Speaker 6:  could do it from the office. If somebody was buzzing my house right now,
Speaker 6:  it could be like, yeah, you go drop the package off or no, I don't want your
Speaker 6:  urine. Take it to the place next door happens. So often
Speaker 1:  I actually, I think this is great. I don't want a
Speaker 1:  camera. And my wife is pretty religious about like, we just
Speaker 1:  don't have, we don't have cameras in or outside of the house. And I've like,
Speaker 1:  basically agreed with that rule. But having a thing that is still a
Speaker 1:  way to communicate with someone at the door is very useful. And also, I just
Speaker 1:  liked the idea that it's like, okay, lots of houses have doorbells. Lots
Speaker 1:  of houses have intercoms. All of them are always broken. It's just like,
Speaker 1:  it's just true. Like I have an Intercom in my house. My house
Speaker 1:  was built in like the sixties. It doesn't work. It probably never worked.
Speaker 1:  It just sits there. And I do nothing with it and bring, just shows up and
Speaker 1:  they're like, just stick this thing on top of it and pretend it works. Essentially.
Speaker 5:  I'm in kind of the most interesting trend in smart home stuff right now
Speaker 5:  is just retrofit hacks. So ring actually
Speaker 5:  started this trend a little bit. You can buy the retrofit kit. If you have
Speaker 5:  like an old school ADT alarm system, you can just buy a new brain and
Speaker 5:  wire, all the existing sensors into it and make it a, a ring system,
Speaker 5:  which is like complicated and weird. But I know some people who've done it.
Speaker 5:  They love it. You have to spend hours being like, I guess this is the motion
Speaker 5:  detector and like labeling stuff. But if you're a gadget nerd,
Speaker 6:  I was like, that sounds like that's my weekend.
Speaker 5:  Then there's like the touch spot stuff
Speaker 5:  where Jen just read about it. It's like a smart door lock, but it just like
Speaker 5:  bolts over the top of your existing door lock. And it just turns the handle.
Speaker 5:  Right. And then there's a bunch of stuff where there's just like a little
Speaker 5:  arm comes out and switches the light switch for you. And it's a bunch,
Speaker 5:  a bunch of that switch spot that's what's called
Speaker 6:  Tato. Is it? I think it's Tato is like the thermostat company that's
Speaker 6:  explicitly for like apartment heating systems,
Speaker 6:  radiators and stuff. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Right. And it's just kind of like bolts onto the physical control.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. You put it on like the radiator and it like does the radiator thing
Speaker 6:  controls?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I mean, I, I, it's just funny that we kind of started with what if
Speaker 5:  we replace all the things with new things that are smart, we're going to
Speaker 5:  tear it all year olds. And now it's like, what if we just did little robots
Speaker 5:  to push the existing buttons? Cause that's all we really need to do here.
Speaker 5:  And so I just think it's like a really interesting trend that the industry
Speaker 5:  has given up on. We'll replace the inner calm in your house with,
Speaker 5:  or the door locks in your house with here's a little tiny motor. It's going
Speaker 5:  to push the button for you.
Speaker 1:  I just, I think everybody's spent a decade like vastly under
Speaker 1:  estimating how hard it is to convince
Speaker 1:  people, to like get out of screwdriver and do stuff. And it's just like,
Speaker 1:  like if this, this basically this ring Intercom huge, literally
Speaker 1:  it looks like just shove it over top of the existing thing like you're talking
Speaker 1:  about. And it's like, so many of these are just like, oh, your thermostat
Speaker 1:  is basically just like three wires and four screws in the wall. Just pull
Speaker 1:  it out, put in a nest, easy peasy, no problem. And I think most people look
Speaker 1:  at that knowing air,
Speaker 6:  Well, this one, I mean, this one you do have to do. It's similar to the nest
Speaker 6:  and that you do, you're going to have to do some wiring
Speaker 1:  Through, if you want to be able to open your door, you do
Speaker 6:  That. Like you're still going to have to go in and do
Speaker 6:  wires, but it's also same thing. It's like two to three wires. And I think
Speaker 6:  the big thing here, and that's something that, that Jen talked about in her
Speaker 6:  piece is that this is for renters. There's a lot of people who,
Speaker 6:  who can't install cool doorbells because their
Speaker 6:  landlord will be like, what are you doing? They can install
Speaker 6:  a lot of this stuff. And so the, these smaller things, they are like just
Speaker 6:  robots you stick on on the stuff that already exists is really, really useful.
Speaker 6:  Like it's what almost 40%. I think it's like 36% of Americans,
Speaker 6:  American households are renters. That's a big chunk of people that
Speaker 6:  don't have access to a whole lot of this like smart home, the smart home
Speaker 6:  trends. And this gives them, me access to that
Speaker 6:  eventually. Cause it's starting in the UK, it won't come to the U S until
Speaker 6:  next year. And it also, currently doesn't work with the inner
Speaker 6:  calm that I have in like 80% of new
Speaker 6:  Yorkers have that was like, put it in the sixties and is absolute garbage.
Speaker 6:  That's like do that one guy. So, so
Speaker 5:  You need three switch spots.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  So that when your door buzzes, you like push the button. And it's like,
Speaker 6:  I was like looking into a project of like, can I get a raspberry pie and
Speaker 6:  like wired into this Intercom and do all of this stuff.
Speaker 6:  Yes. It would be incredible to anybody who rings. The
Speaker 6:  doorbell would be great.
Speaker 5:  All right, this segment has gone over. See I'm doing it. I'm trying to try
Speaker 5:  to ease the tension. The segment's gone over. I have to get to a meeting.
Speaker 5:  Y'all gonna take a break. And I believe you come back to Casey.
Speaker 10:  Yep.
Speaker 5:  That's it. We'll grab that.
Speaker 1:  If you run an e-commerce business, you might be laser focused on acquiring
Speaker 1:  new customers, which makes sense at face value until you realize that this
Speaker 1:  isn't necessarily the best business model. According to a Harvard study,
Speaker 1:  acquiring new customers can be anywhere from five to 25
Speaker 1:  times more expensive than retaining existing ones. That same study
Speaker 1:  also found that increasing customer retention rates by 5%
Speaker 1:  increases profits by up to 95%, keeping your customer base
Speaker 1:  engaged and happy is a good way to grow, which is what the Cleevio platform
Speaker 1:  can help you achieve. Klaviyo's email and SMS marketing platform brings all
Speaker 1:  your customer data into one place. Over a hundred thousand e-commerce
Speaker 1:  brands grow their businesses and drive revenue with real-time data
Speaker 1:  segmentation and automations that the Klayvio platform offers. So you
Speaker 1:  can now know what your customers want and when they want it. Plus
Speaker 1:  Klayvio allows you to drive successful marketing campaigns with pre-built
Speaker 1:  behavior triggered automations. So you can develop longterm customer
Speaker 1:  relationships. It's time to talk to your customers like you know them because
Speaker 1:  you do with Klaviyo, learn more@klaviyo.com. That's K
Speaker 1:  L a V I Y o.com.
Speaker 10:  Today's episode is sponsored by DraftKings. This season draft Kings wants
Speaker 10:  you to get in on the action with the first ever NFT fantasy game rainmakers
Speaker 10:  football. You can collect player cards and then use your deck to compete
Speaker 10:  in weekly fantasy football contest, craft lineups of your favorite players
Speaker 10:  and earn points for touchdowns, receptions, and more just like daily fantasy
Speaker 10:  football. If you do well, you can climb the leaderboard and compete for
Speaker 10:  prizes every week of football season. And right now, everyone can get their
Speaker 10:  first full roster starter pack for free build your entity franchise and
Speaker 10:  enter free Rainmaker's football contest all season long. Download the
Speaker 10:  draft Kings daily fantasy app. Now sign up with the promo code Vergecast
Speaker 10:  and click the Rainmaker's tile to opt in. Get ready for the latest drop
Speaker 10:  and get your first full roster starter pack for free plus play for
Speaker 10:  millions and prizes all football season. While you build the ultimate NFT
Speaker 10:  fantasy franchise with Rainmaker's football that's promo code Vergecast
Speaker 10:  build play when only a draft gangs entries,
Speaker 10:  depending on type of number of NFTs held void where prohibited or restricted
Speaker 10:  see draft kings.com for eligibility restrictions and details.
Speaker 1:  Welcome back. Neil has gone. Casey Newton's here. Hi Casey.
Speaker 11:  Casey. David.
Speaker 1:  Oh, there we go. Hi Casey. I feel like this is like a tremendous upgrade.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Casey, what are your feelings on like soundboards?
Speaker 6:  Like just buttons you can press and make drum
Speaker 1:  Roll products today.
Speaker 11:  I, yeah, I brought a number of drops just based on
Speaker 11:  funny verge quotes over the years and my favorite
Speaker 11:  internet memes. So we should integrate those.
Speaker 1:  Perfect. So we've brought you here because I assume today is
Speaker 1:  the greatest day of your life. Is that fair to say like, is this, is this
Speaker 1:  the best you've ever felt in your whole life? Tell us what happened today
Speaker 1:  with Twitter? What happened?
Speaker 11:  Oh, well, I mean, yes, I was popping champagne at, at 8:00 AM
Speaker 11:  and they announced it at like five 40 this morning, but yes. And by the
Speaker 11:  way, the verge readers already know this, but Twitter after
Speaker 11:  18 years, ish has finally unveiled a way to
Speaker 11:  let you edit a tweet for up to 30 minutes
Speaker 11:  after it was posted in the face of enormous
Speaker 11:  opposition from some extremely annoying
Speaker 11:  people. This has been shipped and I am now dancing on the graves of my
Speaker 11:  hitters.
Speaker 6:  I'm so happy for you. I don't want it though. I don't want the
Speaker 6:  edit. I want everything to live in horror for all to see.
Speaker 6:  I want like just a Testament to my crimes on the internet.
Speaker 11:  I am happy to re-litigate all of the stupid arguments against the edit button.
Speaker 11:  I'm just here to tell everyone that you continue to be wrong and that every
Speaker 11:  other platform that creates a text box enables you to edit it
Speaker 11:  and democracy ain't dead yet, baby. So look,
Speaker 11:  will it create new problems? I'm sure, but we have
Speaker 11:  cases all the time where, you know, a half a percent of users abuse
Speaker 11:  the feature and we still let people, you know, that we still at the 99 and
Speaker 11:  a half percent of people enjoy the feature and 99 and a half percent of
Speaker 11:  people are going to really enjoy being able to fix a stupid typo.
Speaker 1:  Yes. Okay. So let, let me just, let me just lay out the like details of how
Speaker 1:  this works, because, because the most annoying thing about this announcement
Speaker 1:  to me was I have been staunchly against the edit button this whole time.
Speaker 1:  I have always thought it was a terrible idea. Hate it. Think it's the worst
Speaker 1:  bad idea. And then I read it today. And so basically the way that it works,
Speaker 1:  I'll just read from Twitter's blog posts. It says tweets will be able to
Speaker 1:  be edited a few times in the 30 minutes. Following publication edited
Speaker 1:  tweets will appear with an yeah, I don't know what a few means. We'll come
Speaker 1:  back to that in a second edited tweets will appear with an icon timestamp
Speaker 1:  and label. So it's clear to readers that the original tweet has been modified.
Speaker 1:  The edit label will have a complete edit history
Speaker 1:  and you'll be able to click into it and see all the past versions of the
Speaker 1:  edited tweet.
Speaker 6:  I love this. This sounds great now. Nevermind. Cause I just wanted, like,
Speaker 6:  I want all of my horror to be available. Like every typo I want you
Speaker 6:  all to know that I'm bad at typing. And so like, okay, the history is
Speaker 6:  there. I'm fine. Roll it out. Let's do it. Let's go.
Speaker 1:  So Alex, I would point out you're not required to edit your tweets. You don't
Speaker 1:  have to change.
Speaker 6:  I probably won't be real because it costs money too. Right? Like
Speaker 11:  Alex, you're an editor at the verge. You're an editor at the verge and you're
Speaker 11:  not going to edit your tweets. What kind of message does that send to your
Speaker 11:  employees?
Speaker 6:  Really good work-life balance. When I'm on Twitter, I'm at, I'm
Speaker 6:  at home. I'm having a great time. There are 40 typos in the
Speaker 6:  first sentence. It is illegible. That's the way it should
Speaker 1:  Know work-life balance like a lot of tweets, as far as a
Speaker 6:  Lot of illegible tweets at 2:00 AM that's work-life
Speaker 6:  balance, right there.
Speaker 11:  There's something that happened to me the other day. Yes. Can I share
Speaker 11:  something that speaks to the need for this? So this week
Speaker 11:  with my colleague, Zoe Schiffer at the verge, I, we wrote this
Speaker 11:  story that was very serious about Twitter, and it's a problem with
Speaker 11:  child sexual abuse material. And I wrote a follow-up to it yesterday
Speaker 11:  for my newsletter platformer about, about the
Speaker 11:  fact that apple, you know, might have something to say, if Twitter went,
Speaker 11:  went ahead with its plans to build an only fans competitor, which is something
Speaker 11:  that Twitter has been considering. So I tweeted out my newsletter and
Speaker 11:  w what I hear, I'm going to read it to you. What I tweeted out, I read about
Speaker 11:  another reason left out of the red team's report that Twitter might've hit
Speaker 11:  the brakes on its only fans, competitor fears. It would risk a crackdown
Speaker 11:  from apple over existing, poor on the platform.
Speaker 11:  He O O R. And so, no, you
Speaker 6:  Do not delete
Speaker 11:  Within three minutes. A bunch of people are tweeting. What do you mean poor
Speaker 11:  P what poor, you know? And I'm just like, what's happened. And then I see
Speaker 11:  I've made the typo, but of course, by now, the tweet has already started
Speaker 11:  travel. And so I just replied to the tweet with the single all
Speaker 11:  caps word porn, because obviously I meant porn. And then
Speaker 11:  that, you know, then people started quote, tweeting that, and just be like,
Speaker 11:  oh, look at what this tech journalist, you know, is tweeting about this
Speaker 11:  whole cycle of in this world. This problem is
Speaker 11:  now solved. I just go in and I change poor to porn
Speaker 11:  and my life is better. And that is how technology should work. It should
Speaker 11:  be in service of me. I should not be in service of Twitter. Twitter should
Speaker 11:  be in service of me.
Speaker 6:  I like is that I would still be able to go back, look at your edit
Speaker 6:  history screenshot that you originally wrote poor and be like, look at
Speaker 6:  this, look at this typo he first did. And that's important to me.
Speaker 6:  Like, I think we get the best of both worlds. You get to, you get to correct
Speaker 6:  it and I can be like, never forget.
Speaker 6:  It's perfect. I love it.
Speaker 11:  And that's fine. I am totally happy with that. Trade-off I'm totally happy
Speaker 11:  with that. Trade-off we need that audit trail, right? Because yes, you could,
Speaker 11:  you can imagine ways that this feature could be abused. I'm sure some people
Speaker 11:  will try to abuse it. I just think that the number of times that that
Speaker 11:  happens is going to be smaller than the haters say. And I think the consequences
Speaker 11:  of it happening are going to be much less than, than people say.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Okay. So let's, let's just play out the worst case scenario of this
Speaker 1:  for a minute. Cause I think this is the thing I've, I'm thinking about a
Speaker 1:  lot because I think
Speaker 6:  What goes wrong.
Speaker 1:  There is this instinct that I have also had many times that this
Speaker 1:  is like an inherently bad idea. Right? And it's like, somebody who's going
Speaker 1:  to embed a tweet on a website and then you can change it. No, no, everything's
Speaker 1:  awful. But like, you've talked to a lot of people who like work at Twitter
Speaker 1:  and think about this stuff about this stuff, right? Like what is literally
Speaker 1:  the worst that could happen here is your sense.
Speaker 11:  Donald Trump could become president again in 2024
Speaker 6:  And they give him his Twitter back or just, just these precedent, which is
Speaker 6:  worse.
Speaker 11:  No, that's just like, just like any, any bad platform
Speaker 11:  decision to me, like the worst case scenario is Donald Trump becomes president.
Speaker 11:  Now. I don't think that will probably happen in this case,
Speaker 11:  but you know, here, I mean, here's what people, you know, people talk a
Speaker 11:  lot about like, well, could you use this to change the market
Speaker 11:  somehow? Like if you said, oh, you
Speaker 11:  know, the, the CEO of a, of a tech giant just
Speaker 11:  died to like crash the market and then it goes viral. But then you
Speaker 11:  change the tweet to like a crypto scam or something. Like, I
Speaker 11:  don't know exactly what, what people think is going to happen. I think it's
Speaker 11:  important to note that they only have 30 minutes to change it, which means
Speaker 11:  that your tweet can only get so viral in 30 minutes. And yes, tweets do
Speaker 11:  go viral in 30 minutes, but like a manageable number. Right? So if
Speaker 11:  Twitter sees some tweet going crazy bananas numbers and like the first
Speaker 11:  five minutes, they can probably get a set of eyeballs on it and just be
Speaker 11:  like, okay, is this, is this a verified actor? Is this an account that has
Speaker 11:  been taken over? So there, there will have to be an enforcement layer, but
Speaker 11:  like, these are the kinds of things.
Speaker 6:  No, I'm just thinking about the crypto scheme, like really viral tweet. And
Speaker 6:  you're like, all right, switch it out. Now I'm going to rake in the dough.
Speaker 6:  Right. I assume that's how those screams work. Yeah.
Speaker 11:  Th this is my issue is like, oh, you know, well, now that there's this edit
Speaker 11:  feature, it's like, what do people try to do bad things on Twitter? What
Speaker 11:  do they try to promote crypto scams? You know, or what if they try to like
Speaker 11:  PR promote hate speech and say it's already happening, you know? And that's
Speaker 11:  not to say that we should necessarily do things to make it worse. It's just
Speaker 11:  that Twitter has policies and enforcement teams in place
Speaker 11:  to manage the bad actors. So look, if your argument against us
Speaker 11:  is you think it's a great idea and the feature seems technologically well-designed,
Speaker 11:  but Twitter is a battered shell of its former self. And there's no way it
Speaker 11:  can enforce like some new set of features like
Speaker 11:  this. I don't think that's actually that bad of an argument to me, that's
Speaker 11:  probably the best argument, but is it worth a, try to the like
Speaker 11:  500 people who pay for Twitter Ballou? Like I think, yes. Why don't we
Speaker 11:  just roll it out to 500 people and see how they use it
Speaker 1:  Yet? So I will say do by the logic of making it a Twitter blue
Speaker 1:  thing, actually, because I think it's like, it's a relatively self-selecting
Speaker 1:  group of people who are probably more likely than average to like,
Speaker 1:  not try to abuse the system. And it's also a group of people who are like,
Speaker 1:  by definition, going to be paid more attention to by Twitter as a
Speaker 1:  platform. So like all the random, you know,
Speaker 1:  I'm going to laugh when like a million Russian bots I'll start getting Twitter
Speaker 1:  blue. It's going to be like incredible for Twitter's revenue. It's like,
Speaker 1:  incredible
Speaker 6:  Is Elon Musk on Twitter blue? Like, does he pay $5 a month for the edit,
Speaker 6:  but
Speaker 11:  Not to my knowledge,
Speaker 1:  $10 a month. And you get the fire hose is, is what happens.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. You will be paying 44 billion soon, but
Speaker 6:  he's got to start paying now. No, I think my initial
Speaker 6:  concern about this was always that, that, that tumbler thing where tumbler
Speaker 6:  were like, yeah, you can edit all of your tumblers, which was a delight because
Speaker 6:  people were just like, I'm going to put hardcore porn in. I'm just going
Speaker 6:  to replace this viral tumbler post with hardcore porn. And it was hysterical
Speaker 6:  also, like, don't look at Tableau at work. So, but,
Speaker 6:  but this sounds like it really solves a lot of those problems because there
Speaker 6:  is like that, that time period there is that like
Speaker 6:  kind of watching it happen, like somebody is monitoring this
Speaker 6:  to some extent.
Speaker 11:  Yeah. And Twitter doesn't have to invent the whole wheel here. Right?
Speaker 11:  It's like, you can edit a Facebook post. You can edit a slack post, you
Speaker 11:  can edit a discord post. Like this is not a brand new technology
Speaker 11:  that has like been invented in the deepest recesses of
Speaker 11:  Frankenstein's lab. Like we know how to build editing features. And
Speaker 11:  frankly, I think the reaction against it has, has legitimately been
Speaker 11:  hysterical. Like, I feel like I'm like listening to a bunch of like people
Speaker 11:  in like 1901 reacting against the, the creation of the telephone.
Speaker 1:  But I will say the thing that's different about that is like one thing that
Speaker 1:  is different about Twitter than all the other things you just named is that
Speaker 1:  like a lot of people experienced Twitter, not on Twitter. Right. There's
Speaker 1:  like, there's, there's the there's embeds, which is how a lot of people experience
Speaker 1:  Twitter. There's like third-party apps. Twitter is like theoretically back
Speaker 1:  to, you know, giving a crap about third-party developers for the
Speaker 1:  11th time. And I'm sure it'll change its mind again. Yeah. But
Speaker 1:  like, it's the kind of thing that I think is like much easier to do
Speaker 1:  when people are, are coming to your place to do this stuff. But if you are
Speaker 1:  this kind of distributed machine, which is what Twitter is, it's, it's
Speaker 1:  not impossible. It's just a harder thing to propagate in a way
Speaker 1:  that like makes sense. I think,
Speaker 6:  Well, I think this doesn't like solve some of those key problems with like,
Speaker 6:  people love to trade those screenshots. Right? That's that's like a really
Speaker 6:  popular way to like interact with Twitter is take a
Speaker 6:  screenshot and post it. And this isn't going to necessarily solve that. Like,
Speaker 6:  I will absolutely be able to screenshot Casey's poor tweet
Speaker 6:  and like distributed to the wide world. But
Speaker 6:  like, I think that they found, it sounds like they found kind of a nice middle
Speaker 6:  ground. I'm learning all about this on the verge cast as we speak,
Speaker 6:  this is, this is great news for me personally. Thank you, Casey.
Speaker 11:  I mean, this, I come here to educate, this is what got me excited
Speaker 11:  about podcasts in the first place. So happy to be here,
Speaker 11:  but yeah, let's, let's give it a shot. People let's be open to the idea
Speaker 11:  that maybe somethings can work sometimes. How about back
Speaker 6:  In a work with DMS?
Speaker 1:  No. Twitter, Twitter has never, for five consecutive minutes, Twitter has
Speaker 1:  never cared about DMS. I refuse to believe that Twitter even knows DMS exists
Speaker 1:  on this platform. Like it's not, I
Speaker 11:  Don't think to start. It is going to work with DMS. I
Speaker 6:  Use them so much.
Speaker 1:  Dams are great. It's the worst messaging app on planet earth, but everyone's
Speaker 1:  there. So it's fine. It does the job. But I have to say the thing that is
Speaker 1:  the most annoying about this to me is that it actually seems like Twitter,
Speaker 1:  like really thought this all the way through which to be honest is like a
Speaker 1:  real bummer because Twitter, nobody does product more
Speaker 1:  chaotically than Twitter. They're just like, here's a bunch of stuff. We're
Speaker 1:  going to test it with 12 people, but we're going to tell everyone about it
Speaker 1:  for some reason. And we're going to leak all of it accidentally to Jane Wong.
Speaker 1:  Everything's going to be insane. Here's some stuff is like the Twitter way.
Speaker 1:  And this one is like, I read through the blog posts and it's like, oh, you
Speaker 1:  like really like, did your homework and thought this through. And I wonder
Speaker 1:  if 30 minutes turns out to be the right answer. And like we were saying before,
Speaker 1:  I wonder what a few times is like who, and that's, that's a, that's
Speaker 1:  not a number.
Speaker 11:  Well, just real quick. I just want to say, I've been talking to them about
Speaker 11:  this in 2018. I mean like ever since Kayvon baker became the
Speaker 11:  product manager, I was like lobbying him in person to think about this.
Speaker 11:  And it was very much on his mind already. This is the number one.
Speaker 11:  This is the number one request from the Twitter user. Oh, it's such a niche
Speaker 11:  thing. It is literally the number one thing that people ask Twitter
Speaker 11:  to build. Okay. So a lot of the haters are asking Twitter to ignore
Speaker 11:  the number one request from its user base. Right. But there, they were thinking
Speaker 11:  about it for four years. So if it, if it feels thoughtful and Polish it's
Speaker 11:  because of this has been like a four year project.
Speaker 6:  So like that was one of the things I did want to ask you is one of the
Speaker 6:  running jokes in the world is that anytime Twitter needs like a get out of
Speaker 6:  jail free card and completely change the conversation about the company,
Speaker 6:  it can just be a finally like edit button here and conversation
Speaker 6:  real bad about Twitter this weekend. Last partially, thanks
Speaker 6:  to great reporting from you and Zoe, is this timing
Speaker 6:  coincidental or maybe a little more intentional,
Speaker 11:  You know, in, in my experience, most timing
Speaker 11:  related to product is coincidental because it's just too hard to like line
Speaker 11:  up the tracks to like get the thing ready out, to be out the door
Speaker 11:  in time, to align with a news cycle that said, I think they
Speaker 11:  are under pressure to show that they can build things. And morale internally
Speaker 11:  is so bad that I think they probably did say, can we get this
Speaker 11:  out the door? Because this would be a win and we can, we can sort of give
Speaker 11:  the team a moment to feel like, look, we're doing some good, we're giving
Speaker 11:  our customers what they want. We, we still have some life
Speaker 11:  in us yet. So if anything, I imagine this is something they
Speaker 11:  prioritize to sort of rally the troops internally.
Speaker 6:  Oh, that's,
Speaker 1:  That's a really interesting point because I think, I mean, what the last
Speaker 1:  four months now have just been like a,
Speaker 1:  I dunno, shit show seems like under selling, what's going on inside of Twitter.
Speaker 1:  And there's been all this stuff about like, you know, getting rid of longterm
Speaker 1:  product stuff and they fired a bunch of product people, including Kayvon,
Speaker 1:  like you were talking about, like it, I can imagine somewhere
Speaker 1:  that there has been like a big, big edit button billboard that now
Speaker 1:  somebody gets to like, you know, throw out a windows in a celebratory
Speaker 1:  manner. And this is like the wind that they've been waiting for for a long
Speaker 1:  time. I can absolutely see that being the case.
Speaker 11:  Have you seen the end of stranger things season four, like the most
Speaker 11:  recent season, and I guess this will be a spoiler. So if you don't want
Speaker 11:  to know how it ends, maybe skip forward 30 seconds. You know how the final
Speaker 11:  shot of the season is like all of the good guys are like
Speaker 11:  looking out on the horizon and the like a tear has opened in space and time.
Speaker 11:  And the upside down is started to invade and take over Hawkins. Like
Speaker 11:  that is, that is what the Twitter people have felt like for the last four
Speaker 11:  months. It's like a giant rip in space sometime time called Elon
Speaker 11:  Musk appeared over the horizon and is now just swallowing up
Speaker 11:  the entire reality.
Speaker 1:  And the edit button is like the peanut butter sandwich that you get to eat
Speaker 1:  during the day. It's like, we can't make this all better, but like, here's
Speaker 1:  a peanut butter
Speaker 6:  Peanut butter sandwich. It was made by Ooma Thurman's daughter. It's
Speaker 6:  great.
Speaker 6:  Spoilers. Sorry, keep fast-forwarding guys. You're fine.
Speaker 1:  Okay. So before we take a break and get into some of other stuff going on,
Speaker 1:  what, what do you know internally about what took so long here? Like this
Speaker 1:  is a four year long project, to your point. It is the most
Speaker 1:  requested thing, which I actually think says a lot about how it's going to
Speaker 1:  be used. Like to your point about there will be people who abuse it. Like
Speaker 1:  most people are not in this to like ruin democracy. Most people are
Speaker 1:  in this to fix their dumb tweets. And so in that sense, like, I am willing
Speaker 1:  to give this an actual chance to help regular people fix their regular
Speaker 1:  tweets. Why did this take four years? Then this is actually not that complicated
Speaker 1:  a thing. What the hell is going on here?
Speaker 11:  Well, you know, Twitter was just never built to do this, right. I mean,
Speaker 11:  the original tweets were sent over SMS. You can't edit SMS. Right. So
Speaker 11:  it was just bill on a system that never anticipated that anything would
Speaker 11:  ever be edited. Yes. And you would be amazed at how
Speaker 11:  many systems at Twitter are 18 years old,
Speaker 11:  but yeah. So they had to sort of, you know, build the, the, the basic
Speaker 11:  editing features. They had to build like an audit trail, right. There was
Speaker 11:  visual design. They had to really think through what is the
Speaker 11:  timer we're going to set on this thing. And then they had to think about,
Speaker 11:  well, how are we going to roll it out as, as something that we do with a
Speaker 11:  test group. And then, you know, they decided to do Twitter, blue, Twitter,
Speaker 11:  blue didn't even exist until last year. Right. We're sort of gave them a
Speaker 11:  sort of audience, you know, that, that maybe they could test this out
Speaker 11:  with and in a productive way. So there are a lot of things to line up. Now,
Speaker 11:  all that said, do I think this feature should have been available in 2010?
Speaker 11:  Yes, I absolutely do. But that's why it took as long as it did.
Speaker 1:  Fair enough. Well, I look forward to all of us abusing it. Horrifically,
Speaker 1:  Alex, you have said on the podcast that you're not ever going to change any
Speaker 1:  of your tweets, so you are not allowed to do.
Speaker 6:  I am not allowed to use it, but I will be screenshotting all of your edit
Speaker 6:  histories. Just be ready. I don't want, I also
Speaker 6:  it's $5 a month. Like,
Speaker 1:  Yeah. It's more expensive now. They're like, oh, you want to edit tweets?
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Give us some money.
Speaker 6:  No, I mean, unless I do some really egregious ones, my
Speaker 6:  typos are normally legible enough. You can, you can like
Speaker 6:  interpret them. It'll be fine.
Speaker 11:  What can I, can I tell you guys my idea for a, what they should rebrand
Speaker 11:  Twitter blew as
Speaker 1:  Yes. Go.
Speaker 11:  I think they should just call it the Twitter legal defense fund. And I think
Speaker 11:  they would make 10 times as much money.
Speaker 6:  It would.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. The, the Elon Musk blocking situation,
Speaker 6:  I really am excited for the moment he edits a tweet because he's gonna
Speaker 6:  do it. He is gonna subscribe and he's gonna edit. And then we're all
Speaker 6:  going to be like, why are you giving them money? You won't give them money,
Speaker 6:  but you'll give them $5 a month. Yvonne, what the hell
Speaker 1:  Through power move would be to like specifically gate
Speaker 1:  out Elon Musk from this test so that he is like the last person on
Speaker 1:  Twitter to get access to this. It just, it would just be like, he
Speaker 1:  would, you know, he would complain like every single day about now. And they'd
Speaker 1:  be like, sorry, it's just a test. And he'd be like, what do you mean? 300 million
Speaker 1:  people have this Twitter doesn't even have that many users. How are you doing
Speaker 1:  this? I'm the only one were like
Speaker 6:  Super random that you were the last person chosen.
Speaker 1:  What are the odds?
Speaker 6:  So rad.
Speaker 6:  Some mathematician could like make that work. If
Speaker 6:  you're that mathematician, please email Nila.
Speaker 6:  He'll be really excited to learn more about this conversation.
Speaker 1:  There you go. All right, we should take a break. There's a bunch of more
Speaker 1:  social stuff stuck to you. So Casey, stick her out. We we'll be right back.
Speaker 7:  Big wireless companies have used confusing contracts to hide fees and
Speaker 7:  fine print and charge more money for way too long. We've all seen it
Speaker 7:  happen. You sign up for a plan at the advertised price. And then when you
Speaker 7:  get the bill, it's completely different. This is one of the reasons I signed
Speaker 7:  up for mint mobile. It offers premium wireless starting at just 15 bucks
Speaker 7:  a month. And I figured there would be some hidden fees, but I read the contract
Speaker 7:  twice and there aren't any. And here's why mint mobile cut out. The one
Speaker 7:  middleman big wireless still relies on in-person retail.
Speaker 7:  Every plan gets you high-speed data delivered on the nation's largest 5g
Speaker 7:  network. Plus unlimited talk and text. Keep your phone, keep your
Speaker 7:  number, just change your provider to mint mobile, to get your new wireless
Speaker 7:  plan for just 15 bucks a month and get the plan shipped to your door for
Speaker 7:  free. Go to mint, mobile.com/verge that's mint,
Speaker 7:  mobile.com/verge. Cut your wireless bill to 15
Speaker 7:  bucks a month@mintmobile.com slash verge.
Speaker 12:  This is the advertiser content from knob Creek.
Speaker 12:  My name is Fred. No, my family has been making whiskey since
Speaker 12:  1795. Well, when I enjoy a glass of
Speaker 12:  knob Creek, the first thing I do, you know, I put my nose into it, looking
Speaker 12:  at it. And to me, the vanilla notes
Speaker 12:  kind of jump out of the glass. When why don't barrels are used
Speaker 12:  to age whiskey, you're going to get vanillin, which is
Speaker 12:  in white Oak. And that makes the vanilla
Speaker 12:  flavor and smell that you pick up, come out of the
Speaker 12:  wood. It's in the wood, very distinctive and knob Creek. I
Speaker 12:  think it's the marrying of all of these flavors,
Speaker 12:  the sweetness and the oakiness that makes knob
Speaker 12:  Creek. One of my favorites to sip and savor
Speaker 13:  Must be 21 years or older drink, responsibly knob Creek, Kentucky, straight
Speaker 13:  bourbon whiskey, 50% alcohol by volume, copyright 2022 James
Speaker 13:  beam, distilling company, Clermont, Kentucky.
Speaker 1:  Welcome back. Like I said, there's a bunch of more social news. The
Speaker 1:  biggest there's a lot more. Yeah. There's like a surprising amount of social
Speaker 1:  stuff going on. It's just like the week before labor day, everybody's supposed
Speaker 1:  to be on vacation. I don't understand why this turned out to be like a shockingly
Speaker 1:  newsy week. But anyway, snap is probably the next one. We should talk about
Speaker 1:  Alex, what's going on with snap.
Speaker 6:  So snap Alex, Heath reported to this. He broke the news for us,
Speaker 6:  but unfortunately they're going to be laying off 20% of their employees
Speaker 6:  particularly hit hard is their hardware team, which like just had that little
Speaker 6:  cute drone that they immediately canceled. What, four months later, was it
Speaker 6:  four months?
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I'm very sad about that. Yeah. It, it, it launched
Speaker 1:  effectively like yesterday and is now gone and
Speaker 1:  yeah, so snap has 6,400 employees. It's laying off 20% of them, which
Speaker 1:  is like an enormous number of people that
Speaker 6:  Is a lot of people.
Speaker 1:  And it's not just hardware. We should say like a lot of it is hardware with
Speaker 1:  snap is also canceling a bunch of its original discover shows. It's
Speaker 1:  killing. I think the minis project, which I always thought was
Speaker 1:  mifty and then a bunch of other projects. And it's basically saying like,
Speaker 1:  if it's not directly contributing to how we make money right now, or
Speaker 1:  augmented reality, which is hilarious, we're not interested in it.
Speaker 1:  Casey, what do you, what do you make of all this what's going on at snap?
Speaker 11:  I think it's really sad. You know, I feel like yesterday when all this was
Speaker 11:  announced, basically three quarters of the things that the company had ever
Speaker 11:  briefed me about just went away. The only thing in there that
Speaker 11:  felt like slightly like a vindication was that
Speaker 11:  they got rid of their original shows, which, which I, I, you know, I'm not
Speaker 11:  saying, cause I wanted them to go away. It's just that the company had always
Speaker 11:  touted how many views they had, oh, you know, 10 million people watched
Speaker 11:  this. And I was just like, if, if literally tens of millions of people are
Speaker 11:  watching these shows, they would have some cultural footprint whatsoever.
Speaker 11:  And it's like, none of these have ever been mentioned anywhere. Right.
Speaker 11:  And so I sort of felt like reality finally caught up with the snap originals,
Speaker 11:  but like I thought that drone was fricking cool. I love the
Speaker 11:  zenlea app. And then of course, you know, just always sucks
Speaker 11:  when a bunch of people lose their jobs. So, you know, the, the reason I
Speaker 11:  value snap as a company is that it is very creative compared to its peers.
Speaker 11:  And it tries stuff that, that other companies don't. And so to see
Speaker 11:  them losing some of those creative planks of the company, I just think was
Speaker 11:  really sad. And I hope they've figured out a way to bounce back.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Wait, you mentioned zenlea, which is an app that if I'm being
Speaker 1:  completely honest, I only discovered on the day that snap announced it was
Speaker 1:  shutting down and then there's another one voicey spelled with like an
Speaker 1:  S, which I thought, which is also getting shit. What are these apps? Like?
Speaker 1:  I had no idea. Snap had other apps that it was running.
Speaker 11:  Zen only is an app that you,
Speaker 11:  it was kind of like, like, imagine it find your friends on iOS
Speaker 11:  was created by a bunch of like cools
Speaker 11:  zoomers like that. That was only, it was really slick. Really.
Speaker 11:  Well-designed really fun. You could see where your friends were. You'd like,
Speaker 11:  get an alert if they left the country or when they came back into the country,
Speaker 11:  you know, it would sort of show you where your friends were and like what
Speaker 11:  the battery life of their phone was and like how long they had been wearing
Speaker 11:  it. So it's like very sort of intimate, invasive stuff that like a company
Speaker 11:  like Facebook could never get away with building, but snap, because it's
Speaker 11:  sort of limited to your real friends has a lot more trust with its users.
Speaker 11:  They could build something like that. And this was apparently really popular
Speaker 11:  in Europe. Like apparently 3 million people downloaded the loaded it last
Speaker 11:  month alone. So the things still had some legs. Voicey was like a, like
Speaker 11:  a music making app that I don't really understand very well myself. And
Speaker 11:  it doesn't seem like it was nearly as popular, but like zenlea was something
Speaker 11:  that people legitimately liked a lot.
Speaker 6:  Is this good? I was gonna say, is this the right move for snap?
Speaker 6:  Like, to me, it almost feels kind of silly that they're saying, okay,
Speaker 6:  we were branching out into all these other places because we only have like
Speaker 6:  so much road ahead of us with, with our core product. And instead they're
Speaker 6:  like, now we're going to just invest in our core product and kill all these
Speaker 6:  potentially successful things. Blake, oftentimes before they even had a chance
Speaker 6:  to really like even try it, it feels a little goofy to me. But
Speaker 11:  Yeah, I mean, so the thing about zenlea in particular
Speaker 11:  is that snap does have the snap map. If you open up Snapchat, there is
Speaker 11:  a map that shows you where your friends are. And so I think if you're
Speaker 11:  Evan Spiegel and you have, you know, rapidly shrinking revenue and an
Speaker 11:  uncertain outlook for the future, and you have two teams building a
Speaker 11:  map, it's probably easy call to say, we should build one map.
Speaker 11:  So I get it in that, in that sense. And I hope that they do import a
Speaker 11:  lot of that Zen lead DNA into the snap map because zenlea feels like it's,
Speaker 11:  you know, 10 years ahead of where the snap map is right now. So I think
Speaker 11:  that's why they made that decision in particular. But again, it
Speaker 11:  would have been nice if they had figured out something else to do with it.
Speaker 1:  I feel like more broadly, this feels like, and
Speaker 1:  I say all of this, knowing that like the economy is complicated right
Speaker 1:  now, everybody's nervous about what the next couple of years are gonna look
Speaker 1:  like. And this is a lot easier said than done. But if I were running snap,
Speaker 1:  I would be looking for every excuse right now to like
Speaker 1:  try to Zig or dig where others are zagging
Speaker 1:  and to be the one to really push into stuff right now. Right? Like
Speaker 1:  Snap's whole thing for a decade has been that it is just
Speaker 1:  fast followed by every other company and they all just eat it alive
Speaker 1:  because they have the scale and the ad business. And now all of those
Speaker 1:  other companies Metta in particular is like retrenching because
Speaker 1:  it cares only about the metaverse and reels. And so
Speaker 1:  if I'm snap, it's like, this is the moment to sort of push ahead with
Speaker 1:  everything you can think of to try and differentiate. When you have some
Speaker 1:  real runway to differentiate where there's not just a team of 10,000 Instagram
Speaker 1:  engineers ready to build everything you ship, the minute that you ship it.
Speaker 1:  It just seems like, I don't know. I mean, a 20% is an
Speaker 1:  enormous number of people to lay off at your company. Like at a
Speaker 1:  company that big 20% is a huge number of people, which makes me think they
Speaker 1:  are really nervous about what the next few years are going to look like.
Speaker 1:  But it also seems like if ever there was going to be a moment for snap to
Speaker 1:  really try to play offense when everybody else is playing defense, this
Speaker 1:  should have been it. And it's just a bummer that that is not how it's going
Speaker 1:  to shake out.
Speaker 11:  Yeah. So I think they are playing offense when it comes to
Speaker 11:  augmented reality, but that's so expensive because it's this
Speaker 11:  like frontier technology where you're trying to solve problems of physics.
Speaker 11:  And so it was just enormously expensive and snap isn't that
Speaker 11:  big. And so they can only afford to play offense in like
Speaker 11:  one or two places right now. And, and they've sort of made
Speaker 11:  their bet. So it's, it's, you know, it really interesting to think about
Speaker 11:  like sort of mark Zuckerberg and Evan Spiegel, obviously Facebook in a much
Speaker 11:  better financial position, but both of them are betting their companies
Speaker 11:  on this AR stuff in a way that really is risking the
Speaker 11:  future of the company. I mean, these are very, these are very bold bets
Speaker 11:  that have significant downside if they don't pay off. And so like
Speaker 11:  Zuckerberg and Spiegel are, are really in, in pretty serious
Speaker 11:  competition right now.
Speaker 6:  Oh, was like, I keep just thinking about this, right. Silicon valley has
Speaker 6:  been obsessed with AR VR for 10, 15 years. Now
Speaker 6:  this has been like this big thing everybody's chasing it. They want to make
Speaker 6:  it huge. These two companies have bet enormously on it, but the
Speaker 6:  technology is still not actually there for the big gross adoption that they
Speaker 6:  want. They're still like 10 years out. And Facebook can
Speaker 6:  definitely like at least limp along. Even if things go bad, they
Speaker 6:  can limp along to get there. Snap doesn't have that kind of
Speaker 6:  runway like snaps in a much more precarious position. And so I'm
Speaker 6:  like, that's it that's, that's your bet. Just like going in on
Speaker 6:  snap, which is losing users as far as we know, and also
Speaker 6:  AR which you've got at least minimum five
Speaker 6:  years before there's any real like longterm success.
Speaker 1:  Well here, here's just one way to think about the difference in scale there.
Speaker 1:  Like we, we've done a bunch of reporting on what's going on inside of Metta
Speaker 1:  and Facebook on this front too. And Mehta announced this big hiring
Speaker 1:  slowdown and they had plans to hire 10,000
Speaker 1:  developers this year. And we're pulling that back to six
Speaker 1:  or 7,000 and that was framed. So the company is like a huge, huge, huge
Speaker 1:  slowdown. But essentially what that means is Metta is going to hire
Speaker 1:  a snap in the period of time. Snap is going to be
Speaker 1:  lowering its staff by more than a thousand people. And both of those
Speaker 1:  companies see that as like a gigantic slowdown in business and what's going
Speaker 1:  on, like, it's, these two companies are playing like sort of the
Speaker 1:  same game, but it's like, it's like one is like in the NFL. And the other
Speaker 1:  is like my nephew's JV football team. Like
Speaker 1:  it's, it's just wild to see how different these two things are. And,
Speaker 1:  and now we're sort of at a point where like, until snap gets to this
Speaker 1:  augmented reality future where it has, you know, this, this
Speaker 1:  magical AR camera that it can sell to everybody. It's just a
Speaker 1:  messaging app now. Like it, it is systematically getting rid of everything
Speaker 1:  else that looks like money to snap it's except for the messaging app.
Speaker 1:  And so it it's it's, it almost feels like snap is,
Speaker 1:  is like lowering the odds of it. Being able to get where it's
Speaker 1:  going, as things go here. And obviously these are like external
Speaker 1:  forces that are forcing snap to do this. This is not like Evan Spiegel. Didn't
Speaker 1:  wake up one morning and be like, you're all fired. But it's
Speaker 1:  like, I mean, you never know LA is a weird place to live, but
Speaker 1:  it's like, it just seems like it, it just, it hurts
Speaker 1:  much worse at snap what's happening right now than it seems to even at
Speaker 1:  Metta.
Speaker 11:  Yeah. I mean, I think, I think there's a lot of pain at, at both
Speaker 11:  companies. You know, I think if there's a silver lining for Snapchat and
Speaker 11:  all this it's that people still really like Snapchat, like particularly
Speaker 11:  young people really like Snapchat and that counts for
Speaker 11:  something, right? It's like people under 30 don't care about Facebook, they
Speaker 11:  don't care what, you know, whether it Facebook's around or not. And you
Speaker 11:  know, Facebook's bad reputation may actually prevent it from having
Speaker 11:  success in this market. Even if they are able to, you know, figure out some
Speaker 11:  of the hardware problems that they have to figure out. So there's still
Speaker 11:  a path.
Speaker 6:  The snap still like mainly teens. Cause the only people I know, like the
Speaker 6:  teens I know are all on Tik TOK and the only people I know are 40 somethings
Speaker 6:  in rural Texas that you Snapchat.
Speaker 1:  Oh no. You're you're missing out. The teens are very much on Snapchat.
Speaker 6:  It's them and his 40 year old farmers in rural Texas.
Speaker 6:  That's all, one of them.
Speaker 1:  My favorite things to do is go on long car trips with my two nephews
Speaker 1:  who are 16 and 15 and just basically see what
Speaker 1:  push notifications they get. And it's like sitting there with, with one of
Speaker 1:  them in the passenger seat, it was like a Tik TOK notification, every eight
Speaker 1:  seconds and a Snapchat notification, every eight seconds. I mean, it was
Speaker 1:  unbelievable. I like made him show me his screen time and he picks up his
Speaker 1:  phone to open a Snapchat notification like 300 times
Speaker 1:  a day. Like it's, it's wild and cases. Exactly. Right? Like there's no
Speaker 1:  money in my 15 year old nephew for Snapchat.
Speaker 1:  But like people love snap in a way that they don't love anything that
Speaker 1:  meetup makes with the possible exception of WhatsApp. But like,
Speaker 6:  Could you show him all of your sweet slack notifications where you're like,
Speaker 6:  I get notifications. I check the time too.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I was like, oh, I was like, oh, you want to, you want to send me an
Speaker 1:  email? And he's like, what is that? Like, no, you're a hundred thousand years
Speaker 1:  old
Speaker 6:  When I tried to
Speaker 1:  Text him and he was like, why are we texting? Like just take a picture and
Speaker 1:  send it on Snapchat. Like, it's fine. I'm very old,
Speaker 6:  Very old. We all are.
Speaker 1:  All right. We should also talk about truth socials. Speaking of companies
Speaker 1:  that seem to be falling apart,
Speaker 6:  Alex, does it count as a company?
Speaker 1:  I mean, yeah. I mean, that's fair. I guess if, if snap is like
Speaker 1:  the JV football team truth, social seems like, like one
Speaker 1:  guy in jeans, throwing a football in a park. It's like, is that
Speaker 1:  anything?
Speaker 6:  I think it's like, I, I am convinced true. Social is
Speaker 6:  run off of like somebody's network attached
Speaker 6:  storage. Like they bought at best buy and they plugged it in and
Speaker 6:  they like, they, they, they booted up like their bootleg Twitter and they're
Speaker 6:  like done. This is, this is our whole application we're here. And it's just
Speaker 6:  like one guy, every time they have an outage it's because like Comcast is
Speaker 6:  just having an outage in that one dude's area. And he's like, oh, I'm sorry,
Speaker 6:  man. I keep I'm on the phone with him.
Speaker 11:  I ever tell you guys about the time I got ratioed on. True. So now
Speaker 1:  Are there enough people to ratio you?
Speaker 11:  I, I post it. Oh yeah. Yeah. President Trump has a lot of
Speaker 11:  fans famously. Yeah. I just posted
Speaker 11:  vaccines are safe and effective. And I just got roasted to hell.
Speaker 6:  Well, you know, the company is supposed to be doing, it was supposed to do
Speaker 6:  a spec, right? It was, it was supposed to be acquired by another
Speaker 6:  company. And that has been delayed because everybody is realized that
Speaker 6:  SPACs are actually probably a terrible way to go public. And if you
Speaker 6:  go public this way, you will lose lots of money and lose your investors.
Speaker 6:  Lots of money. Don't do it. I mean, do it, you live your life. It's your
Speaker 6:  money. It's not mine unless it's in my 401k, which please don't
Speaker 6:  add any smacks to my 401k. But so they, they still had to do their
Speaker 6:  sec filings. And that's where we saw that they've lost a lot
Speaker 6:  of money this year, like six they've they've lost over
Speaker 6:  $6 million and they've generated absolutely no
Speaker 6:  revenue. This company has made no money.
Speaker 1:  There's one way to read that where this is actually like a
Speaker 1:  relatively fiscally responsible startup, like, oh, they've only lost
Speaker 1:  $6 million this year. And they're, pre-revenue like, that's pretty
Speaker 1:  good. That's like, that's how you get interest and Horowitz to like write
Speaker 1:  you a check for $650 million most of the time.
Speaker 1:  But it also seems like the, like every piece of what's going on at true
Speaker 1:  social is just like collapsing. Like do they owe their
Speaker 1:  hosting company over a million dollars? Apparently.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. They, they stopped paying right forge, which is a conservative
Speaker 6:  internet infrastructure company. They stopped paying them. And the guy
Speaker 6:  who's like right forward CEO, Martin availa is like, well, we're gonna, we're
Speaker 6:  going to keep servicing it. We're going to keep providing service even though
Speaker 6:  Mr. Trump's, company's not paying us any money, which is not a new thing
Speaker 6:  for a Trump owned company. They are actually notorious for
Speaker 6:  never paying their bills. So these people should not be shocked
Speaker 6:  in any way, shape or form, but yeah, it's, it's, it's, it's not
Speaker 6:  going well. And I think it was earlier last month where
Speaker 6:  where's it based it's based in Sarasota, right? Like your social is based
Speaker 6:  in Sarasota and the newspaper and Sarasota like went to the offices and was
Speaker 6:  like, oh, nobody's been there in months. It's just like a ghost town office.
Speaker 6:  It's incredible. It's just this huge house of
Speaker 6:  cards. And you walk in and it doesn't collapse because they're
Speaker 6:  very nice cards. And there's just that, that network attached storage at
Speaker 6:  Synology somebody's unread just sitting in the middle of an office.
Speaker 6:  I don't know if that's true, but that's what I
Speaker 1:  Assume flex
Speaker 6:  Server runs Plex.
Speaker 1:  And also, I just want to say, first of all, that the fact that you just said
Speaker 1:  the phrase, conservative internet infrastructure company, and we were all
Speaker 1:  just like, that makes sense is like bananas. Like how is this the
Speaker 1:  world that we live in? And yet
Speaker 6:  That's a thing. There's a conservative phone company in
Speaker 6:  Texas right now. That is like, we're a conservative phone company
Speaker 6:  and we support America and one like, oh, okay.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I definitely care what my GPU's have to
Speaker 1:  say about American politics.
Speaker 6:  They're like funding a bunch of the big library races in Texas,
Speaker 6:  where people are trying to pull books from the library. But, but yeah, there's
Speaker 6:  a lot of these like little spin-off companies who are like, oh,
Speaker 6:  you've made your, your political like
Speaker 6:  choices, your identity. And you want to only ascribe to things that also
Speaker 6:  associated with that identity. We will take your money. Will the service
Speaker 6:  be good? Probably not.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I just, yeah, my GPU's voting for president is the
Speaker 1:  thing. I really have a lot of thoughts about, but, but the other thing that's
Speaker 1:  happening in the social is it, it keeps getting kicked off of app stores,
Speaker 1:  right? Like, yes, he hasn't this become like, like content moderation is,
Speaker 1:  is now like hilariously true social's biggest problem.
Speaker 11:  Well, yeah, cause they, they can't even get their app on the Google play
Speaker 11:  store, which is like, this might be one of the only cases I know about where,
Speaker 11:  where apple is letting something onto the app store that Google is
Speaker 11:  not letting on to its app store over reasons of content moderation.
Speaker 11:  So Google has apparently said to them, your content moderation is a good
Speaker 11:  enough. And true social came back and said, yes, it is. But so far
Speaker 11:  that w we are where we are. I can of course still access to
Speaker 11:  social on my iOS device. But our Android friends are out
Speaker 11:  of luck. And that's that,
Speaker 1:  What does true social do here? Like the content moderation thing. And true
Speaker 1:  social has been a weird thing to follow over time, because like,
Speaker 1:  in part, it launched based on the idea that everybody was moderating content
Speaker 1:  and that that's a huge problem, but then they've started to moderate content
Speaker 1:  because it turns out if you don't, your platform becomes a nightmare, hellscape
Speaker 1:  that nobody actually wants to hang out on you're you're our true
Speaker 1:  social influencer on the, on the podcast. What, what is true
Speaker 1:  social doing? Have they landed somewhere? Do they have policies?
Speaker 11:  They say that they do. And you know, for what it's worth, these discussions
Speaker 11:  are not really held out in the open. So I don't know what Google found
Speaker 11:  or, or did not see in terms of moderation that made it feel like
Speaker 11:  it didn't belong in the app store, but I'll say like usually has to be pretty
Speaker 11:  serious, right? Like, cause these companies don't do not want to be in these
Speaker 11:  fights. They don't like drawing attention to how much power they have over
Speaker 11:  the entire internet economy. So my guess is that, that, that there is
Speaker 11:  something happening there that, that really freaked out the Google people.
Speaker 1:  I just, yeah, all of this is like, yeah, of course this is going on. I do
Speaker 1:  wonder if there was a gating event like you're talking about, but it seems
Speaker 1:  like this is the kind of thing that either of these platforms could
Speaker 1:  have just picked any moment they felt like to just be like and know,
Speaker 1:  and yeah, it just feels like truth. Social is at this moment of you
Speaker 1:  now discover truth social. When you see somebody take a screenshot of a Trump
Speaker 1:  post and post it on Twitter, like that is the entirety of my interaction
Speaker 1:  with true social is Trump's screenshots tweeted by other
Speaker 1:  people, which is like, I'm not sure what we're accomplishing here, but it
Speaker 1:  it's, it, it doesn't feel great.
Speaker 6:  I mean, it was like I do again, I know a lot of folks
Speaker 6:  who are fairly conservative and in rural areas in truth, social was like
Speaker 6:  a big deal for a second. There, like there was a really serious
Speaker 6:  migration of these folks who were getting their news almost exclusively
Speaker 6:  from like conservative memes on Facebook, which is
Speaker 6:  unfortunately more people than it should be. They really think they
Speaker 6:  believe in this thing. They think it's real. They think that like they're
Speaker 6:  helping the country by being on truth, social, and they're
Speaker 6:  helping their president. And there's, there's
Speaker 6:  definitely some like, it's weird, man. It's just like a weird app to
Speaker 6:  me. And it's weird that it tried to be a SPAC and it's
Speaker 6:  weird that the SPAC is collapsing and it's weird that like the primary
Speaker 6:  company is not making money and is losing money and is maybe not
Speaker 6:  going to be able to buy it, which was all just kind of a big money laundering.
Speaker 6:  Legal, let me be clear. SPACs are illegal money laundering
Speaker 6:  scheme. Like this is all just extremely wild to me.
Speaker 11:  I mean, it's certainly an eventful story and
Speaker 11:  it's an eventful story. And yet, if you had asked me two years ago to predict
Speaker 11:  some likely events in the history of true social, getting
Speaker 11:  kicked off of an app store and going bankrupt would have probably been two
Speaker 11:  of the main things that I predicted.
Speaker 6:  It's not it's, you know, it's not close to being bankrupt yet. They've they've,
Speaker 6:  they've declared no bankruptcy, right? Like that hasn't happened,
Speaker 6:  but it certainly seems like it could, if somebody kicks over
Speaker 6:  the, the little Synology server in their empty office,
Speaker 6:  anything could happen. Don't do that.
Speaker 1:  All right. If we've learned one thing today though, it's that if, if they
Speaker 1:  just roll out editing truths, then it's all over.
Speaker 1:  Everything's going to be fine.
Speaker 6:  Be
Speaker 11:  Great. I'm all in.
Speaker 1:  There you go. All right. We have gone way over. Even without the light here.
Speaker 1:  It's not on the Ally's fault, but it's mostly in the lies fault, but we should
Speaker 1:  go a bunch of really good stuff on the verge of this week. Casey, you and
Speaker 1:  Zoe had a really great piece, big scoop about Twitter. You want to give us
Speaker 1:  like the super quick rundown on that? Cause you're here.
Speaker 11:  Yeah. So the story is that was planning to
Speaker 11:  release an only fans competitor. They were going to let the adult creators
Speaker 11:  on the platform, begin selling subscriptions to
Speaker 11:  photos and videos that included sexually explicit content.
Speaker 11:  But before they launched it, they conducted what they call a red team exercise,
Speaker 11:  where they convened a bunch of people to try to poke holes in the plan and
Speaker 11:  say, where could this go wrong? And the number one thing that came up was
Speaker 11:  that Twitter does not currently have the tools in place necessary to
Speaker 11:  adequately police, the amount of child sexual abuse material on the
Speaker 11:  platform and the amount of nonconsensual nudity on the platform. So they
Speaker 11:  identified some really serious problems. And then we paired that with another
Speaker 11:  document that we obtained from last year, where researchers sounded the
Speaker 11:  alarm about this and said, this is a real issue. We do not have the tools
Speaker 11:  we need and leadership needs to invest. And our understanding is that for
Speaker 11:  the most part, leadership has not invested.
Speaker 1:  It's a really good story. You guys should read it. And I believe we have
Speaker 1:  at least one other Twitter scoop coming that is probably going to be
Speaker 1:  live by the time you hear this podcast, the first.com take a look. It's good
Speaker 1:  stuff. Our Homeland series keeps running. We had a great story this week
Speaker 1:  on the humiliating history of the TSA and Nicole Weitzman wrote a
Speaker 1:  great thing about disaster consultants. It's wild and
Speaker 1:  terrifying decoder, which is the other podcast that we never talk about.
Speaker 1:  I would never, ever promote Dakota.
Speaker 6:  You're talking about
Speaker 13:  Here.
Speaker 1:  No, but there's the, I would never do it. You know, this except that this
Speaker 1:  week's episode is Alex Heath talking to Tom Alison, the head of Facebook
Speaker 1:  about how implants compete with Tik TOK. So Neil, I gets no credit for
Speaker 1:  that. So I will, I will happily, I will happily send people to Alex Heath,
Speaker 1:  because it's a good episode. You should go listen to it next week for us.
Speaker 1:  It's going to be all apple stuff, big iPhone event. Next Wednesday, lots
Speaker 1:  of talk about, follow us on Twitter. Nila is reckless, but don't fall on
Speaker 1:  him cause he's not here. Casey's Casey Newton. Alex is out safe Kranz.
Speaker 1:  I'm at Pierce. That's the Vergecast Rockville.
Speaker 7:  And that's a wrap for Birch cast this week. Thanks for listening. If you
Speaker 7:  enjoy the show, subscribe in the podcast app of your choice or tell a friend,
Speaker 7:  you can send us feedback@vergecastattheburj.com. This show is
Speaker 7:  produced by me, Liam, James, and our senior audio director. Andrew Marino.
Speaker 7:  This episode was edited and mixed by Amanda Rose Smith. Our editorial
Speaker 7:  director is Brooke mentors and our executive producer is Eleanor dominance.
Speaker 7:  The verge cast is a production of the verge and box media podcast network.
Speaker 7:  And that's it. We'll see you next week
Speaker 13:  Looking for a great hands-on gift for the curious kids in your life. That
Speaker 13:  tinker who can't stop exploring building and
Speaker 13:  taking things apart. Kiwi COEs delivers super cool
Speaker 13:  science technology and art projects for kids of all ages
Speaker 13:  straight to your door every month, choose from nine different subscription
Speaker 13:  lines focused on subjects like engineering, art, and design
Speaker 13:  science of cooking and more. Every crate delivered has everything you
Speaker 13:  need to complete the project in their fun.
Speaker 13:  Get 50% off your first month on any subscription line at
Speaker 13:  QE code.com/vox 50 that's
Speaker 13:  QE code.com/v O X five zero
Speaker 7:  With no fees or minimums banking with capital. One is the easiest decision
Speaker 7:  in the history of decisions. Even easier than deciding to listen to another
Speaker 7:  episode of your favorite podcast with no overdraft fees. Is it
Speaker 7:  even a decision that's banking? Re-imagined what's in your wallet
Speaker 7:  terms, supply, see capital one.com/bank capital one and a
Speaker 7:  member FTSE.