# Transcript
ID: a6b2fcc0-446f-11ed-84ff-bf351227b135
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Amazon’s Kindle Scribe, printer problems, and earbuds on a bike
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/8217259444051795558/7360609291510553439/s93290-US-3512s-1664948108.mp3
Description: Today on the flagship podcast of hardcopy peripherals:
02:27 - David Pierce and Alex Cranz chat with Dave Limp, SVP of devices and services at Amazon.
Amazon’s Kindle Scribe is an E Ink tablet for reading and writing
24:04 - David also tries to answer a listener question about why it feels like printers haven't improved in years.
Best Printer Buying Guide (Consumer Reports)
39:55 - Lastly, Becca Farsace tests out which earbuds sound the best when calling from a bike ride.
Bose QuietComfort Earbuds II review: noise cancellation domination
Apple AirPods Pro (second-gen) review: same look, better everything else
Google Pixel Buds Pro review: the sweet sound of redemption
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we'd love to hear from you.
We are conducting a short audience survey to help plan for our future and hear from you. To participate, head to vox.com/podsurvey, and thank you!
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (7 ads detected)
Speaker 2:  Welcome to the Vergecast, the flagship podcast of Hard Copy peripherals.
Speaker 2:  I'm your friend David Pierce, and while I'm not doing anything interesting
Speaker 2:  today because it's been raining for like a week and there's nowhere to go,
Speaker 2:  and so all I do now is sit here and try to get my hands on an
Speaker 2:  iPhone 14 Pro Max. The phrase not available today
Speaker 2:  at 12 nearest stores is starting to drive me truly, truly
Speaker 2:  insane. Every day. I check every day, it's not available. Anyway,
Speaker 2:  fun show. Coming up today we're gonna talk a bunch more about the Kindle
Speaker 2:  Scribe, including with the executive in charge of it at Amazon, and we're
Speaker 2:  gonna try to see where it fits into the broader EIN tablet
Speaker 2:  market. We're also gonna dig into the printer industry and try to figure
Speaker 2:  out why it feels like printers haven't changed or improved
Speaker 2:  in decades. And then we're gonna put Apple's new AirPods Pro and
Speaker 2:  some other new models up to our brutal earbuds microphone test.
Speaker 2:  All that's coming in just a second, but first I'm gonna see if I can get
Speaker 2:  a phone in like Indiana. Wish me luck. This is the Vergecast.
Speaker 2:  See you in a
Speaker 2:  second.
Speaker 1:  Welcome
Speaker 2:  Back Today, the first thing I wanna do is dive back into Amazon's
Speaker 2:  event last week, specifically the Kindle scribe, the new
Speaker 2:  10.2 inch EIN tablet that's meant for both reading and writing.
Speaker 4:  Scribe does this with the world's first 10.2 inch, 300
Speaker 4:  PPI adjustable front light display.
Speaker 2:  I think this thing is kind of sneakily fascinating. It's called a
Speaker 2:  Kindle. Yes, but even to hear Amazon describe it, this is
Speaker 2:  definitely more than just a raving device. It's about way more than just
Speaker 2:  selling you more books. Alex Kranz, as I'm sure you know, is my comrade in
Speaker 2:  All Things Inc. Right after the event last week, she and I spent some time
Speaker 2:  with Dave Limp, who's the senior vice president of devices and services at
Speaker 2:  Amazon, which basically means he's the guy in charge of all of Amazon's gadgets
Speaker 2:  and we asked him to give us some of the big picture plans for the
Speaker 2:  Kindle going forward. First I wanna play you a bit of that conversation and
Speaker 2:  then Alex and I are gonna talk a bit about where we think the Kindle Scribe
Speaker 2:  fits into the market. So let's just get into it. Here's
Speaker 2:  Dave Limp. When we asked him why make this device now and
Speaker 2:  more importantly in a world where lots of startups and companies are
Speaker 2:  making EIN tablets like this one, what took so long?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, it's the Kindle I think the team wanted to build for a long time too,
Speaker 4:  but sometimes you know, you have to wait for the technology to catch up to
Speaker 4:  the vision. And so I think there's two
Speaker 4:  things that converged to make this
Speaker 4:  possible. The first is the display technology and our ability
Speaker 4:  to build a display stack up. That made sense cuz you know,
Speaker 4:  we could have built a writing only device years ago, but you can't put Kindle
Speaker 4:  on that. Like it has to be world class reading experience so you don't get
Speaker 4:  to use the name Kindle, it would had to be some new name. So there's some
Speaker 4:  things that we have to have in a paper white display and these days if you're
Speaker 4:  not 300 ppi, it's, it's a non-starter. If you can't
Speaker 4:  do a front light that is really uniform and beautiful, people have
Speaker 4:  just come to expect that from Kindle now. And so that display stack
Speaker 4:  up took a little bit longer than we would've thought. Secondarily, then you
Speaker 4:  have to build a writing experience. I would call it a
Speaker 4:  whole experience that is up to what people expect from writing and you
Speaker 4:  know, the state of the art of writing on things has moved forward
Speaker 4:  a long way. And so you have to have the latency and you have to have it very,
Speaker 4:  it has to feel like writing and so you get to play with various wave forms
Speaker 4:  on the ink display and once those converge then we felt like we could
Speaker 4:  build something we loved. And so here it is.
Speaker 5:  You talked about like the display technology being kind of up to
Speaker 5:  snuff. We've had these 300 kind of PPI displays in
Speaker 5:  smaller forms. Was it really you needed a 310
Speaker 5:  plus inches?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, there's probably a dimension in there. I think you could probably,
Speaker 4:  you know, anywhere from 9.7 inches up to
Speaker 4:  probably 1111, you could have built a form factor but you want it big. Like
Speaker 4:  what you find with writing is writing on something small. Those we have in
Speaker 4:  the lab too is it's just doesn't, it's not comfortable. You end up
Speaker 4:  feeling cramped how you're writing and it, it doesn't really make sense.
Speaker 4:  I even find that writing on small tablets, you know, it doesn't work as well.
Speaker 4:  You kind of wanna put your palm down, you wanna rest it. So there was kind
Speaker 4:  of a sweet spot for the display. I think the side effect of
Speaker 4:  that was, and again we'll know more once more customers see it, but at
Speaker 4:  least from our beta participants, and I can speak for myself, is
Speaker 4:  that the reading experiences surprisingly better. I mentioned this somebody
Speaker 4:  yesterday, I, we used to have a 9.7 inch Kindle product was called
Speaker 4:  Kindle DX a long time ago, right when I got to Amazon and there's not a lot
Speaker 4:  of those left active I I, I should get the actual count but I,
Speaker 4:  it's probably thousands of them left. But they're the most
Speaker 4:  passionate vocal minority I've ever met. I probably get an email on the
Speaker 4:  Kindle DX alias once a week from somebody plant saying please make
Speaker 4:  another dx. And so we didn't call it that this time, but hopefully those
Speaker 4:  customers will find a path to upgrade to this. So
Speaker 5:  Some of the competitors in this space, like in the United States, we don't
Speaker 5:  see a lot of EIN stuff. I think Amazon, you guys are the biggest seller
Speaker 5:  of EIN products, but in China we're seeing a ton of
Speaker 5:  these eReaders and these ere products from like big me and books and stuff
Speaker 5:  like that. But they're funky. I would not have my,
Speaker 5:  my siblings or my mom used one. I've tried and
Speaker 5:  it's ends and failure and sadness. But is it because
Speaker 5:  that ecosystem for E Inc is just not developed enough to go to like
Speaker 5:  say Android and and do full Android or kind of the full
Speaker 5:  Kindle tablet experience in an e ink form?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I think there's two reasons we haven't gone that direction. I mean
Speaker 4:  yeah you can buy an infinite number of probably, you know,
Speaker 4:  reflective display kinds of things out of China. Firstly, and I'm just kind
Speaker 4:  of back to what I've said in the beginning, which is you know, we wanted
Speaker 4:  it to be a great reading experience and writing. If you were designing a
Speaker 4:  writing only product, you would do many different things differently, right
Speaker 4:  in the form factor in how you would lay out the board everything. But I
Speaker 4:  think secondarily when you look at this
Speaker 4:  product can describe in this case we really worked
Speaker 4:  at getting something that when we did add writing it felt
Speaker 4:  like a natural extension of it. Sometimes when you think about how some of
Speaker 4:  those other products they feel like they're tacked on to a
Speaker 4:  tablet os yeah and you know, I don't think customers care what operating
Speaker 4:  system is running inside of a Kindle. They care that the reading's great
Speaker 4:  and now the writing's great and the other thing that comes along with
Speaker 4:  those I mentioned in the launch event, but is one of the things I
Speaker 4:  love about Kindle is it is distraction free.
Speaker 4:  It's very subtle but when I'm reading I really don't want to get
Speaker 4:  the notifications. You know, I have a couple VIP contexts and they pop through
Speaker 4:  almost everything on my phone. One being my wife, the other being my boss.
Speaker 4:  And so I, but I don't want that when I'm deep into a book and I love
Speaker 4:  it. So I think that having a more bespoke solution
Speaker 4:  gives you some of those side benefits without having to block them or or
Speaker 4:  hack the os or do other things.
Speaker 2:  What do you make of this sort of state of this market? Obviously it's
Speaker 2:  a lot more people own these things in countries like China than do in the
Speaker 2:  States, but there's also a couple of companies out there like Remarkable
Speaker 2:  who have been making these things for a little while. Like where are we in
Speaker 2:  the, in the evolution of like this particular space?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I don't, I haven't tracked too closely the
Speaker 4:  writing only market segment, you know, of people that are just after
Speaker 4:  a writing for all I know they're doing well. I don't know, I can't really
Speaker 4:  opine upon that. I do think that the pandemic, you know, you was
Speaker 4:  an awful experience in any, by any dimension.
Speaker 4:  One silver lining of it was that people did rediscover
Speaker 4:  reading, you know, and I think reading leads to better literacy and I, I
Speaker 4:  just think people are more educated if they read more. And so I think that
Speaker 4:  was a, a side benefit. And so the
Speaker 4:  Kindle, call it readers in general but I can speak for the
Speaker 4:  Kindle, it started growing pretty substantially during
Speaker 4:  the pandemic and lots of categories this year are not growing in
Speaker 4:  consumer electronics cuz there was a lot of pent up demand that got pulled
Speaker 4:  forward into the pandemic. Were also in a different economy than we were
Speaker 4:  last year at this time. But Kindle continues to grow. It's a category that's
Speaker 4:  been around for 15 years. I wouldn't say it's one of these things where it's
Speaker 4:  you know, hyper growth again. But I do find that people are kind
Speaker 4:  of circling back to the classics in some way. In the case of
Speaker 4:  Kindle reading, there's a whole generation of people growing up now that
Speaker 4:  are kind of also loving physical books again, you know, we see that on Amazon.
Speaker 4:  So there's some interesting trends happening and I think by bringing
Speaker 4:  writing and and merging it together, you know, I think we'll find Kindle
Speaker 4:  lovers that will also love this. But I think we might find a whole new audience
Speaker 4:  that might adopt this. I don't know how big that is but you know, we always
Speaker 4:  kind of start with the products we want and we write that working backwards
Speaker 4:  sometimes we are the customer that's in mind and you know, this is definitely
Speaker 4:  the Kindle that I want.
Speaker 2:  I did have that thought in the briefing ahead of this that like if any
Speaker 2:  company was ever gonna create this, it would be the one that is famous for
Speaker 2:  having six page documents that everybody reads at the beginning of a meeting.
Speaker 2:  It's like, yeah of course, of course. The executives that Amazon would like
Speaker 2:  a device like this to work
Speaker 4:  With. Here's my morning right here, whole pile of six page documents. There
Speaker 4:  you go. So if you want, if you want to know what next year's products will
Speaker 4:  look like that it's sitting right next to me. So
Speaker 5:  Just like flip that around to the camera. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  Just hold it up. You don't have to say anything
Speaker 4:  Purposely held it from backwards forward and says so you didn't, didn't get
Speaker 4:  a glimpse of
Speaker 4:  the
Speaker 4:  future.
Speaker 2:  We're done with Dave Limp back in the studio, me and Alex. Hi Alex.
Speaker 5:  Hi. This is a good time. He's
Speaker 2:  A good hang. I like Dave Limp. He talks about technology and doesn't
Speaker 2:  sound always like a person who runs a technology company, which I, I
Speaker 2:  appreciate, appreciate
Speaker 5:  It. It's
Speaker 2:  Nice. I want to talk more about like this market the Kindle scribe is coming
Speaker 2:  into. Yeah. Because I think the EIN writing
Speaker 2:  tablet feels like an idea that is overdue and has
Speaker 2:  kind of happened already and feels like it's maybe happening more than
Speaker 2:  people realize. But if I'm not mistaken, and correct me if I'm
Speaker 2:  wrong, this kind of seems like if you and I could have sat here and
Speaker 2:  tried to force Amazon to build the relatively
Speaker 2:  reasonable Kindle we wanted, it would've been a lot like this,
Speaker 2:  right?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I would've preferred some some page turning buttons and
Speaker 5:  I would've preferred the ability like actual Android but Kindle
Speaker 5:  was, Amazon is never gonna be like, yes we're gonna put Android on your device
Speaker 5:  so you can get all of our competitors and use their book readers. Like of
Speaker 5:  course they're not gonna do that.
Speaker 2:  That is true. I actually hadn't even thought about that. But it is like totally
Speaker 2:  anathema to the whole business model of Kindle because their whole thing
Speaker 2:  is they don't make money on the hardware, they make money when you buy the
Speaker 2:  books. And if he's gonna let us get cheaper things to read elsewhere, what
Speaker 2:  is the point of Kindle for Amazon? I hadn't even thought about that.
Speaker 5:  I get why they elected not to put Android on it. Do I want
Speaker 5:  Android on it? Yes. Do I understand why Amazon is almost never gonna
Speaker 5:  do that? Yes.
Speaker 2:  Take me through the competition here a little bit because I know I'm in a
Speaker 2:  position where like I am hopelessly devoted to Amazon at this point. I've
Speaker 2:  just spent so long buying Kindle books that I'm just gonna keep reading on
Speaker 2:  Kindles because that's just what I have. But you are not in that boat, which
Speaker 2:  means you have a much freer reign of what's out there. So what is out there?
Speaker 5:  I mean there is a lot out there. There are some people who are making just
Speaker 5:  note taking devices and reading's kind of an afterthought and I think
Speaker 5:  Remarkable is obviously the most well known of those guys. People
Speaker 2:  Like the new remarkable right? They're remarkable too.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, they're remarkable too. They like it because it really is just about
Speaker 5:  writing, you know, Remarkable went out of their way to say how can we
Speaker 5:  replicate that, that pin and paper experience in EIN and they do it
Speaker 5:  better than anybody else, like hands down just better than anybody else.
Speaker 5:  Everybody else, there's little like sacrifices you have to make and it's
Speaker 5:  cheaper too than the describe right? But also you are not
Speaker 5:  getting Amazon, you are not getting e-books. You can put eBooks on
Speaker 5:  a remarkable, you can put PDFs on a remarkable, you can do a lot with remarkable,
Speaker 5:  but it's, it's fussy. Okay. It's not like a super
Speaker 5:  smooth experience, especially for ere because most people
Speaker 5:  are buying their books from Amazon and then they have to convert them and
Speaker 5:  then put them on the remarkable, nobody wants to do that. Right? And then
Speaker 5:  there's also like the SuperNote, which is really similar like to
Speaker 5:  the remarkable, very focused on the writing experience, very focused on being
Speaker 5:  on replicating that kind of like a four paper experience, which is
Speaker 5:  why it's called like the A five and the A six. Thank you to listeners. Somebody
Speaker 5:  said Alex, why do you never mention the super note? And it's because I always
Speaker 5:  forget the super note exists. So here I am for you guys reminding people
Speaker 5:  that the super note does exist and people like it. Like it's, it's got a
Speaker 5:  very small, very passionate fandom and then once you kind of start to
Speaker 5:  move away from that, you start to see it's primarily like these Android
Speaker 5:  EIN tablets that we've talked about before. And for me the the
Speaker 5:  absolute standout there is the books. I've been using 'em for two or three
Speaker 5:  years now and I really love the products. I think they
Speaker 5:  are on the right track, but it's also, I'm never gonna buy
Speaker 5:  my mom a books. I tried to get her to use one last
Speaker 5:  Christmas did not go well. Just like the worst thing I've
Speaker 5:  ever done, worse than the time I tried to set up a password manager for her.
Speaker 2:  Oh wow. Awful. But it seems like the books thing, I have never actually used
Speaker 2:  one of these devices I should say. And it seems to me that what
Speaker 2:  they're basically trying to be is just a full on Android tablet
Speaker 2:  but instead of like an L E D or LCD screen, it has an E
Speaker 2:  Ink screen. But it like other than that it's trying to make as few changes
Speaker 2:  as possible. Is that right? Right.
Speaker 5:  I don't think that's necessarily the purpose. Like it really wants to be
Speaker 5:  an e-reader. It really wants to be a note taking device. Okay. It just says,
Speaker 5:  oh you want the Play store? Yeah we can give you the Play store. Is it gonna
Speaker 5:  be a good experience? No because the play store is not designed for eating
Speaker 5:  and everything's gonna be slowed okay and obnoxious. But if you wanna use
Speaker 5:  your Nook reading app, if you wanna use Libby, if you wanna use the Cobo
Speaker 5:  app, you can use all of those. That's what I do. That's why I, that was why
Speaker 5:  I initially went that route, right? Was because I wanted to get away from
Speaker 5:  Amazon, I wanted to try and have that experience without being locked
Speaker 5:  into Amazon and that seemed like the best choice.
Speaker 2:  So why doesn't that work? That sounds like the dream.
Speaker 5:  I think that is the dream. I think right now it's not user friendly. My like
Speaker 5:  for me the the kind of mark is my mom loves to read, can I give my
Speaker 5:  mom this e-reader and she just go and read
Speaker 5:  and no one does that well except for Amazon. And Amazon only does it well
Speaker 5:  with Amazon products. Cobos out there saying, well would we do it too? And
Speaker 5:  also you can go to the library through us and that's not true because I
Speaker 5:  got my mom a Cobo reader and you guys can all do the next time
Speaker 5:  she calls to try to figure out how to get check out a book on the Cobra
Speaker 5:  reader, we'll just have it do on the vergecast. We'll just spend an hour
Speaker 5:  and a half on the Vergecast teaching my mom how to do it. Her and the librarians
Speaker 5:  at her local library. So most of the experiences just aren't user
Speaker 5:  friendly and that's because nobody in the United States really cares about
Speaker 5:  that, right? Like in the United States the market is
Speaker 5:  Amazon, that's the market and Cobos out there like picking up the pieces
Speaker 5:  at Walmart,
Speaker 2:  Right? There's Amazon and then there's the people who do not want Amazon
Speaker 2:  products. That's the only reason you don't buy an Amazon product.
Speaker 5:  A hundred percent. And so everything else in this market right now is
Speaker 5:  very niche in the United States. It's different story in
Speaker 5:  China, e-readers are a lot more common there. They don't care
Speaker 5:  about Amazon. Nobody over there really uses Amazon devices but everybody
Speaker 5:  wants to read. That's why you're seeing all of this like proliferation in
Speaker 5:  China of all these different e-readers is because there's actually a market
Speaker 5:  for it there. And China can also, a lot of those companies
Speaker 5:  can afford to do smaller runs and really kind of figure things
Speaker 5:  out. Whereas we just don't see that in the United States. Nobody wants to
Speaker 5:  experiment at that scale in the US with hardware.
Speaker 2:  I feel like Amazon over time has tried to push in
Speaker 2:  some new like ways of thinking about books. Like they did the
Speaker 2:  Kindle singles thing and there was like a serials thing that they were doing
Speaker 2:  and none of that seems to have taken off. And I think part of me wonders,
Speaker 2:  will devices like this as they get bigger start to change some of the
Speaker 2:  content that people want? Or are we just stuck in a thing where it's like
Speaker 2:  I want books or I want like the internet and if I want the internet I'm gonna
Speaker 2:  go to a different thing. Like they're, they're that middle grounder talking
Speaker 2:  about like the web books and that kind of content just doesn't seem to exist
Speaker 2:  here. And I wonder if it ever will.
Speaker 5:  I think it does exist and and I think people have really found ways
Speaker 5:  around Amazon's World Garden. If you look at the the biggest kind
Speaker 5:  of American web book spaces, they're primarily fan fiction, right? They're,
Speaker 5:  they're primarily WPA and a oh three and both of those have figured
Speaker 5:  out how to put stuff on an Amazon device pretty quickly. And a lot of
Speaker 5:  those readers also are younger and they're just like, I've got a phone, I
Speaker 5:  don't, don't need this. Whereas I wanna be able to read and not worry about
Speaker 5:  my notifications popping up. So I want an e-reader where my notifications
Speaker 5:  are gonna pop up and that's what I give with the books. I can just go and
Speaker 5:  I have no idea if any of you text me if like you hadn't called me, I
Speaker 5:  wouldn't know that I needed to be here for this call today. That's not true.
Speaker 5:  I was working very hard. Like that's what you see a lot of
Speaker 5:  people say No I just want something to focus on writing and reading and doing
Speaker 5:  that. And that's what this crop of products in China is doing. They're just
Speaker 5:  saying we're gonna give the Android experience but a little limited. You're
Speaker 5:  not gonna be answering your emails on this unless you really want to and
Speaker 5:  also wanna cry Fair instead. You wanna read, you wanna take notes. We got
Speaker 5:  you.
Speaker 2:  Okay. So to that point actually the reviews to come on the Kindle
Speaker 2:  scribe, it's supposed to come out before the end of the year. I don't know
Speaker 2:  when, I didn't wanna wait but let's assume this is everything
Speaker 2:  that Amazon claims that it is, which like Kindles have been very good for
Speaker 2:  a very long time. I don't think it's insane to believe Amazon when they say
Speaker 2:  this thing is gonna work pretty well, is this thing gonna light the world
Speaker 2:  on fire? Like does this appeal to Kindle people or is there gonna be like
Speaker 2:  a watershed moment where all of a sudden everybody wants one of these devices?
Speaker 2:  I
Speaker 5:  Think we're closer to that watershed moment with this device because it's
Speaker 5:  got two things going forward. One, it's got a bigger display and people,
Speaker 5:  as much as I hate it, people do love bigger displays. They want, they want
Speaker 5:  a big screen and lip talked about the really loyal
Speaker 5:  DX fans. They're still out there and there's a lot of them and there's a
Speaker 5:  lot of people who are getting older and they wanna blow up the text as big
Speaker 5:  as possible. And I've seen it when they blow up the text as big as possible
Speaker 5:  on that six inch e-reader, it's like four words per page. I
Speaker 2:  Know it's crazy. And
Speaker 5:  So they need at least seven. Yeah and this will give them those seven words.
Speaker 5:  So I think you're gonna see a lot of people embracing it for that reason.
Speaker 5:  And I think the writing is gonna be useful but like
Speaker 5:  I think Amazon has kind of programmed everybody in the United
Speaker 5:  States to think that the Waled Garden is the only way to go and
Speaker 5:  so it's gonna be really hard for people to understand that there are other
Speaker 5:  ways to do this. It's not just the Amazon way of living in this Waled
Speaker 5:  garden only having access to Kindle books only having access to your word
Speaker 5:  docs and PDFs in doing annotations on them with this
Speaker 5:  device.
Speaker 2:  No it, I think that's totally right and I think the idea of like a
Speaker 2:  digital handwriting notebook seems like the kind of thing that when we get
Speaker 2:  it right is gonna be massively successful to lots of people and it's gonna
Speaker 2:  be super interesting to see if, if this is the one Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Like if they can figure out the ui, if they can make the UI really interesting
Speaker 5:  and feel snappy because that's one of the problems with the E ink is E Ink
Speaker 5:  that refresh is just slow, slow, slow. Yeah. And even at
Speaker 5:  its fastest, it's still glacial compared to everything else we do.
Speaker 5:  And that's just a huge limitation and they're fixing it, they're improving
Speaker 5:  on it. We're seeing year after year E Ink is getting a lot better at that
Speaker 5:  refresh rate and that's the thing they're very focused on cuz they know that
Speaker 5:  like until the refresh rate gets up to stuff, nobody's gonna adopt this at
Speaker 5:  other things. As long as you see that gross ghosting and the flash as
Speaker 5:  it refreshes the entire page, people are gonna be like, ew, icky. So I think
Speaker 5:  if they can figure out like ways around that refresh problem and we've
Speaker 5:  seen like books has gotten decent at it, remarkable has gotten decent at
Speaker 5:  it, you don't feel that sluggishness necessarily with those products.
Speaker 5:  If Amazon can figure that out, I think it starts to get people excited
Speaker 5:  about it. We'll see what the scribe, I would probably say Hazard like the
Speaker 5:  scribe too. We'll be the big watershed moment rather than the scribe
Speaker 5:  one as much as I want that moment.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, no I I would guess that you're right, but we're gonna, we're gonna
Speaker 2:  come back on here whenever they do ship as one to try out and we'll, we'll
Speaker 2:  talk about
Speaker 5:  It. I'm so excited for that day. Whoever gets to review it, it's gonna be
Speaker 5:  me. I'm gonna fight everybody at the Verge. I can't wait to fight you David.
Speaker 5:  We'll save it for the podcast.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I I like this plan. All right, we need to take a break and then we're
Speaker 2:  gonna come back and talk about a gadget category. We don't talk about much
Speaker 2:  on this show, just printers, you don't think about them. You probably think
Speaker 2:  your sucks and I tried to figure out why we'll be
Speaker 2:  right
Speaker 2:  back. If you run an e-commerce business, you might be laser focused
Speaker 2:  on acquiring new customers, which makes sense at face value until you realize
Speaker 2:  that this isn't necessarily the best business model. According to a Harvard
Speaker 2:  study, acquiring new customers can be anywhere from five to
Speaker 2:  25 times more expensive than retaining existing ones.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. So a couple of months ago we asked you to call the Vergecast
Speaker 2:  hotline and ask us all your Burning Tech questions. You should still do that
Speaker 2:  by the way. The number is 8 6 6 Verge one one and we want to
Speaker 2:  hear everything. We've gotten a lot of really great questions, but there's
Speaker 2:  one in particular that I just have not been able to stop
Speaker 2:  thinking about. Here's the message.
Speaker 6:  Hi, this is Jacob. I've got a question that I think a lot of people
Speaker 6:  will resonate with. I have a printer in home that
Speaker 6:  doesn't work and I want to know why don't any
Speaker 6:  printers work and why hasn't a company disrupted the
Speaker 6:  printer market? Thanks, bye.
Speaker 2:  This message just hit me right in the face. Why isn't
Speaker 2:  there any innovation in printers? So for the last few weeks I've been trying
Speaker 2:  to figure that out. The first thing you should know is that
Speaker 2:  the printer market is humongous. If you include everything
Speaker 2:  that is theoretically printing businesses, governments, advertising,
Speaker 2:  3D printing, basically the idea of taking a digital thing and
Speaker 2:  using a device to make it a physical thing. This market is hundreds of billions
Speaker 2:  of dollars a year, But let's narrow it down
Speaker 2:  a bunch and just talk about the printers you might buy or that a small business
Speaker 2:  might use. You know the boxes you buy at Staples and stick in a cupboard
Speaker 2:  and use to print concert tickets and Amazon return labels. Four companies
Speaker 2:  make up about 85% of that market according to the research
Speaker 2:  firm idc, HP is the leader, then Epson, then Cannon, then brother.
Speaker 2:  The printing market had a big boom during the pandemic with so many people
Speaker 2:  at home dealing with work and school. They just needed to print more stuff.
Speaker 2:  Things have slowed down a bit since then, but the market is
Speaker 2:  still huge. A 2019 estimate said that 62%
Speaker 2:  of US households owned a printer and that number has definitely gone up
Speaker 2:  since then. The other thing you should know is that just the basic
Speaker 2:  job of printing is actually really, really hard. Paper
Speaker 2:  is an organic material and no two pages are exactly alike.
Speaker 2:  Feeding that through a fast moving machine, which everybody always wants
Speaker 2:  to be smaller and cheaper and as a result everything gets really hot
Speaker 2:  and really complicated is really hard. I bet your printer still
Speaker 2:  jams. Mine certainly does, but there is plenty of evidence that things
Speaker 2:  are getting better. Still though printers are
Speaker 2:  printers, right? They're super annoying to set up and they throw these
Speaker 2:  unintelligible error messages whenever anything goes wrong. The printing
Speaker 2:  market is the same few companies making the same kinds of devices that they've
Speaker 2:  made for forever. This is what our buddy Jacob really wants to know about.
Speaker 2:  Why is it still like this? So I called up two people with radically different
Speaker 2:  views on the printing industry. Diana Soroka, the global head of HP's
Speaker 2:  consumer Printing services, and Cory Doctoral, an author and blogger and
Speaker 2:  a fellow at the Electronic Frontier Foundation. Let's start with Diana who
Speaker 2:  I called with a simple question, is there any innovation happening in the
Speaker 2:  printer industry? What cool stuff is going on that we don't know about? She
Speaker 2:  said yes, which of course she would say, and she pointed me not to
Speaker 2:  a specific printer but to an app. It's called HP Smart and
Speaker 2:  it's designed to be the main and much better way that you interact
Speaker 2:  with your printer.
Speaker 7:  There were times in the past where it could take people up to an hour to
Speaker 7:  get their printer up and running and I would say if you look at current technology
Speaker 7:  today, no one has the patience for that. And with our HP
Speaker 7:  Smart app, absolutely new printers today, certainly within 10 minutes you're
Speaker 7:  up and running. So I think some of it is an article, the past experience
Speaker 7:  and if you've taken that long to set up a printer and all you wanna do is
Speaker 7:  see that first page come out with whatever content you wanted on it and you're
Speaker 7:  waiting and and going through different issues with your wifi connection
Speaker 7:  or whatever else, it's so much simpler. Now
Speaker 2:  The smart app is how you set up your printer, but you can also use it to
Speaker 2:  print photos from your phone or see how much ink you have left and
Speaker 2:  even like print a piece of lined paper or a blank Sudoku board you
Speaker 2:  can fill out. I think it makes sense to abstract a lot of this stuff over
Speaker 2:  to your phone. And I do think the idea of printers being
Speaker 2:  more generative is really interesting. Instead of having to find
Speaker 2:  a template online or download an image just to print it,
Speaker 2:  it'd be cool to just say, Print me a lined eight and a half by 11 piece
Speaker 2:  of paper, or I need 10 sheets of paper with blank spaces for
Speaker 2:  answers. Numbered one through 10, Amazon has a service called print with
Speaker 2:  Alexa that is thinking about similar stuff. You can just say, print my shopping
Speaker 2:  list right before you leave to go to the grocery store or print today's Sudoku
Speaker 2:  right when you sit down to do it. It's a good idea and it makes things easier,
Speaker 2:  but I don't know that that counts as like earth shaking innovation. And
Speaker 2:  this is one thing I heard from folks across the printing industry. It's not
Speaker 2:  so much that people want their printer to do fancy crazy new
Speaker 2:  stuff or want a router in their printer or a speaker in their printer. It's
Speaker 2:  that they just want their printer to be easier to use.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, printers doing printer jobs and we wanna make sure, like I said, that
Speaker 7:  that's as easy as possible.
Speaker 2:  One way HP has tried to do this is through a program called Instant Ink,
Speaker 2:  which is a subscription service for ink. You pay a monthly fee depending
Speaker 2:  on how much you print and HP automatically sends you the ink you're gonna
Speaker 2:  need to get it done. Diana said, it's been a huge
Speaker 7:  Hit, we've enough to think about and no one wants to worry about how much
Speaker 7:  ink is left in that cartridge when they all of a sudden realize they have
Speaker 7:  to print. I don't know, their child's book report, which is suddenly 20 pages
Speaker 7:  long and they weren't planning on that and it's 10 o'clock at night and they're
Speaker 7:  like, Oh geez. Now what? I'm gonna run to the store and figure out how to
Speaker 7:  deal with this.
Speaker 2:  This is the moment I knew I needed to call Cory. Doctor Corey is
Speaker 2:  a long, long, long time critic of the printing industry and
Speaker 2:  his argument for why there's no exciting innovation in printers is
Speaker 2:  that basically there's no incentive for printing companies to
Speaker 2:  do anything innovative.
Speaker 8:  I think one of the things that makes people so angry about printers is that
Speaker 8:  we seem to have passed the threshold where buying a good printer
Speaker 8:  means that you have a good printer. Like if you
Speaker 8:  have $16,000 to spend on a ticket from Los Angeles to London, you will get
Speaker 8:  a really comfortable chair and someone who will like actually care about
Speaker 8:  your comfort and they'll serve you a really good meal. And then another really
Speaker 8:  good one, when you get up in the morning and so on, you could spend $16,000
Speaker 8:  on a printer and it would still be garbage.
Speaker 2:  Ultimately though, I would say Corey's not mad that printers jam. I mean
Speaker 2:  he is, but he's especially mad that the industry works the way that
Speaker 2:  it does. And he's particularly mad about the fact that if you
Speaker 2:  wanna buy ink for your printer, it's a lot harder than it
Speaker 2:  should be.
Speaker 8:  We actually do have something new in printers, which is third party ink.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, the printers aren't very durable and they do these things where it's
Speaker 8:  like, Oh, you know, you've printed X thousand pages, therefore we're gonna
Speaker 8:  brick ourselves or whatever. But all of that stuff, including
Speaker 8:  that bricking, all of that stuff can be solved by altering the firmware,
Speaker 8:  the printer so that it accepts third party inks so that it resets its page
Speaker 8:  count to zero and so on. What
Speaker 2:  He's describing is the way a lot of markets work, right? Somebody comes in,
Speaker 2:  builds an accessory or a replacement for a small part of a successful
Speaker 2:  thing and sort of eats them from the inside. Cory gave me the example of
Speaker 2:  Apple, which built keynote and pages in order to copy what
Speaker 2:  was great about PowerPoint and Word and then tried to compete with Windows
Speaker 2:  that way. But in the printer industry like some others, Corey says the law
Speaker 2:  has made that all but impossible. And it starts with the
Speaker 2:  Digital Millennium Copyright Act of 1998.
Speaker 8:  It's a law that says that if there's an access control
Speaker 8:  that restricts access to a copyrighted work like the firmware of
Speaker 8:  a printer, then removing that access control, selling someone a tool to
Speaker 8:  remove that access control as a felony, it's punishable by a five year prison
Speaker 8:  sentence and a $500,000 fine.
Speaker 2:  Basically Corey argues printer companies have spent the time that they might
Speaker 2:  spend innovating and building new products on figuring out how to prevent
Speaker 2:  any other company or developer from doing so. And then once they
Speaker 2:  had all of your printing life all to themselves, they focused on just
Speaker 2:  getting all the possible money out of you. And he argues that
Speaker 2:  things like Instant Inc are nothing more than just a naked money grab.
Speaker 8:  You can see why the street would love it, right? You can see why Wall Street
Speaker 8:  would love it. They've gotten out of the product business except incidentally,
Speaker 8:  in fact, you could even imagine HP exclusively
Speaker 8:  licensing the ability to make HP printers to third
Speaker 8:  parties and Ink and HP would just be in the
Speaker 8:  extracting rent for Ink business.
Speaker 2:  I asked Diana about this criticism by the way, and she said basically that's
Speaker 2:  just not how she sees it. Well
Speaker 7:  The first thing is the business model as it exists today in the market is
Speaker 7:  you buy your own printer. Okay? So you own the printer, you purchased it
Speaker 7:  from wherever your favorite retailer is, and it's yours to print whatever
Speaker 7:  you want. You can enroll an Instant Inc at the time you set it up. You can
Speaker 7:  enroll a month later, two years later whenever you find interest or you find
Speaker 7:  that subscription service of value to you. And while you're on the service,
Speaker 7:  we shift you what we call subscription cartridges. And that's part
Speaker 7:  of the service. It's part of being able to leverage the firmware and the
Speaker 7:  technology and the printer to be able to run the service for you. If at any
Speaker 7:  point in time you cancel, we let you know that at the end of that particular
Speaker 7:  billing cycle that you'll have to return to purchasing what we call
Speaker 7:  traditional cartridges. So it's not about holding your printer cartridge,
Speaker 7:  it's just saying when when you're on the service, you pay for pages
Speaker 7:  and we monitor that and when you're not, you're back to printing in the
Speaker 7:  traditional way. So no, no hostage printers out there.
Speaker 2:  In fact, what she said is that not only do people like this world in which
Speaker 2:  they don't buy or think about their own ink, they feel the same way about
Speaker 2:  printers and paper too. Pretty soon actually, you might start
Speaker 2:  to see subscription printers becoming a thing for a lot of
Speaker 2:  users.
Speaker 7:  We actually called it instant platinum, just as a simple branding for
Speaker 7:  the purposes of our test, we pick three printers and we put them out in
Speaker 7:  the market. And basically it's a very simple enrollment flow. You pick your
Speaker 7:  printer, your page plan, you the option to add paper and
Speaker 7:  you get amazing printing taken care of forever. What
Speaker 7:  that means is 24 by seven support your printer breaks. We get you on
Speaker 7:  the next day for one low monthly price. You truly set it, forget
Speaker 7:  it. So now you're not even worried about the printer itself, the printer
Speaker 7:  hardware, anything that could go wrong. And of course you can upgrade that
Speaker 7:  printer along the way. We'll always be messaging you if there's a better
Speaker 7:  printer for you.
Speaker 2:  This debate turns philosophical really quickly and is actually a story about
Speaker 2:  much more than just printers. It's about the fight between openness and
Speaker 2:  innovation on one side, Corey's side and simplicity and convenience. On
Speaker 2:  the other Diana's side, there aren't many times you get to have
Speaker 2:  both and printers definitely don't seem to be one of them. So what do you
Speaker 2:  want A printer that just works that you don't have to think about or the
Speaker 2:  best printer ever made, at least one better than anything you've seen before.
Speaker 2:  I'm increasingly not sure you get to have it both ways, but Corey at least
Speaker 2:  thinks we can.
Speaker 8:  You know, when the DVD players were like five or 10 years old,
Speaker 8:  people just forgot that we used to be able to record tv or if they remembered
Speaker 8:  it, they were like, there must be something intrinsic to the DVD player that
Speaker 8:  makes it hard. It was just a design choice, right? Like people have forgotten
Speaker 8:  that you can have federated social media or interoperable app
Speaker 8:  stores or any of these other things. They just like, they just don't remember
Speaker 8:  that it's a possibility and you have to make people know what's missing.
Speaker 8:  You have to remind them what they're missing before you can get the political
Speaker 8:  will to get people to have it. And you know, I think the printer companies
Speaker 8:  would like us to just forget that printers ever worked and that weren't
Speaker 8:  a
Speaker 8:  rip off.
Speaker 2:  Oh, before we go, here's another voicemail we got about
Speaker 2:  printers.
Speaker 10:  Hey Vergecast, my name is Nick, I'm from Colorado. I'm calling to ask
Speaker 10:  a question about wireless printers. My wife and I have
Speaker 10:  a HP NV 5,000 series that's on the fritz and I need to
Speaker 10:  replace it with something that's maybe a little bit more efficient on
Speaker 10:  ink. Just figured wireless printer can be a fun niche topic
Speaker 10:  to talk about. Thanks for your help.
Speaker 2:  I don't have a perfect answer for this one except that I have a brother laser
Speaker 2:  printer and it serves me pretty well and I hardly ever have to think about
Speaker 2:  it and that's basically the goal. But in the course of researching this episode,
Speaker 2:  I spent a lot of time asking around and researching to figure out
Speaker 2:  what you should look for in an everyday printer. And I did find some
Speaker 2:  pretty straightforward tips for getting it right. Here's
Speaker 2:  three, One, buy a laser jet printer. Especially if all you need to do is
Speaker 2:  print simple things like return labels and word documents. They're often
Speaker 2:  a little more expensive upfront but much cheaper and easier to maintain over
Speaker 2:  time. And if you only print every now and then like I do, the toner in a
Speaker 2:  laser jet printer lasts much longer than the ink in an ink jet buying
Speaker 2:  device. Number two, go black and white if you can since that'll be even cheaper
Speaker 2:  to maintain. Here's what Consumer Reports said in a really great buying guide
Speaker 2:  that I'll link to in the show notes. It says, Our research shows that people
Speaker 2:  print lots and lots of texts in black and white, rarely print graphics and
Speaker 2:  almost never print photos. And that's where monochrome laser printers excel.
Speaker 2:  They print crisp text and they print it fast. And economically, our survey
Speaker 2:  data says they're generally more reliable than inkjets in the long term,
Speaker 2:  which is why many of the survey respondents who bought laser printers really
Speaker 2:  love them. It's good advice, I totally agree with it. Buying advice
Speaker 2:  number three, if you print photos but only a few times a year, don't buy
Speaker 2:  a fancy printer just like save the address for the nearest
Speaker 2:  Michaels or Kinkos and spend a few bucks when you need to instead of a lot
Speaker 2:  of money for a thing you'll rarely use. If you do print a lot though,
Speaker 2:  there are some great photo printers out there and you should shop based on
Speaker 2:  the cost per page as much as the actual cost of the printer. That number,
Speaker 2:  the cost per page will be what really determines how much you spend
Speaker 2:  on printing. And quick bonus buying advice. Number four, the all
Speaker 2:  in ones are actually really good now, not that long ago, I remember someone
Speaker 2:  telling me that the best printers were always the dedicated ones and that
Speaker 2:  adding more features made the printing worse. By all accounts, that's not
Speaker 2:  the case anymore. You can get a scanner printer, even a fax
Speaker 2:  machine if that's how you roll. And it can do all of those things pretty
Speaker 2:  well. Printers maybe kind of suck still, but they're
Speaker 2:  also
Speaker 2:  pretty good. Okay, we need to take a break and then we're gonna come back
Speaker 2:  and we're gonna test some new earbuds, including the latest AirPods Pro.
Speaker 2:  We'll
Speaker 2:  be
Speaker 2:  right back.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. It's time for, if I'm honest, my favorite segment on
Speaker 2:  the Vergecast, our earbud voice call tests. I know there's like a few of
Speaker 2:  you out there who absolutely hate this segment and for those of you, please
Speaker 2:  know this is probably the last one of these we'll do for a little while,
Speaker 2:  but also I love it. So I'm just sorry. In past episodes of this show,
Speaker 2:  we've had Verge reviewer Chris Welch take wireless earbuds on wild
Speaker 2:  stress tests so we can hear how well their microphones work because
Speaker 2:  microphones matter, they matter for voice calls and zoom obviously.
Speaker 2:  But increasingly also for Siri and voice dictation and more and more
Speaker 2:  of our day to day phone interactions. We took Chris to a busy
Speaker 2:  coffee shop and we put him on a ferry and we stress tested the heck out
Speaker 2:  of everything we could find. So far the two sets of earbuds to make it out
Speaker 2:  of our tests and into our future tests have been
Speaker 2:  Apple's AirPods Pro and Google's Pixel Buds Pro. But now it's tech review
Speaker 2:  season and more new earbuds have hit the market. Most recently we have the
Speaker 2:  Bose quiet Comfort earbuds too and a new second generation update
Speaker 2:  to the AirPods Pro. So we had to put those to the test. Chris Welch wasn't
Speaker 2:  able to join us this time because again, it's tech review season. So this
Speaker 2:  time we had senior video producer Becca Versace take the new
Speaker 2:  earbuds and our pass winners on a bike ride in Brooklyn. The question was,
Speaker 2:  are wireless earbuds good enough to take some calls from your bicycle commute?
Speaker 2:  We were testing wind, we were testing park noises, we were testing all kinds
Speaker 2:  of stuff. And Becca, who has spent a lot of time with these earbuds for her
Speaker 2:  video reviews is gonna help us find out Becca.
Speaker 2:  Hello. Hi, where are you? What is happening here? Yes,
Speaker 14:  I am in Prospect Park, better known as Brooklyn's Backyard. We're
Speaker 14:  gonna be doing some
Speaker 2:  Loops. We are. So the shtick here is we always try to put these in like deeply
Speaker 2:  unpleasant places that are horrible for everyone to listen to, which is precisely
Speaker 2:  the point. So we're gonna try to fix this, but let's just set everybody up
Speaker 2:  here. You have a helmet on which is good, good and safe of course. And if,
Speaker 2:  if I'm looking at this correctly, we're on video right now so I can see your
Speaker 2:  face and it looks like I'm inside of your bag. Is that, is that correct?
Speaker 2:  I just wanna give people the vibe of what's happening here. Close.
Speaker 14:  So I have a very cheap phone mount that I use
Speaker 14:  on my bike. So you are inside the phone mount.
Speaker 2:  And what headphones are we listening to right now? Just to, just to start
Speaker 2:  things off.
Speaker 14:  So these are like $20 wired Apple
Speaker 14:  headphones, except they are so old that they have the eighth inch jack
Speaker 14:  on them and I'm using them with my S 10, which still has a headphones jack
Speaker 14:  and is so hard to let go of because of that
Speaker 2:  I support this. But in theory, this is the best sounding thing we're
Speaker 2:  gonna hear, right? It's all downhill from here. You're not moving yet, you're
Speaker 2:  on wired earbuds like this should be the best we get, right?
Speaker 14:  That's correct, yes. And now there's someone backing up so that should maybe
Speaker 14:  not help so much, but correct.
Speaker 2:  Hey, this is the world, this is what we're here for.
Speaker 14:  All right, we're getting outta here. We're on the road.
Speaker 14:  Okay. Oh, excuse me.
Speaker 2:  All right, well then stop when it's safe and you're not gonna die. Switch
Speaker 2:  headphones. Let's do, we have four to test today. So let's start with the
Speaker 2:  one that won our last test. Let's do the Pixel Buds Pro from Google.
Speaker 2:  Let's try those first. You
Speaker 14:  Got it. All right, David, these are the pixel buds pro.
Speaker 14:  I love them because Pixel Buds, the o O G with
Speaker 14:  the cords had swipe up and down volume controls and
Speaker 14:  these also have that and I just love that legacy.
Speaker 2:  It is a nice thing.
Speaker 14:  These headphones are $200. They have pretty solid anc. If you have
Speaker 14:  an Android phone, you know you have that quick pairing option, which is
Speaker 14:  great. Pretty much standard at this point. And they sound pretty good. All
Speaker 14:  right,
Speaker 2:  Well let's go for a ride. Let's hear how we do.
Speaker 14:  All right, here we go. We're gonna chase this N
Speaker 14:  YP D car. All right, so we're taking
Speaker 14:  out some good here. The N car is
Speaker 14:  on three wheels. The, it's a beautiful day in
Speaker 14:  Brooklyn. What do you got from me David?
Speaker 2:  You sound like you're riding a bike in pretty heavy wind. I can
Speaker 2:  hear you, but it's pretty quiet. Like it's, it's very clear Google is like
Speaker 2:  working really, really, really, really hard to kick the noise outta your
Speaker 2:  headphones. I'm not getting much background noise at all, but I'm also not
Speaker 2:  getting much of you.
Speaker 14:  Okay. There isn't much background noise except for the wind. But even
Speaker 14:  I can hear all the wind at these buds are taken up.
Speaker 2:  Try slowing down a little. Just give me like a, like a nice gentle coast
Speaker 2:  and see if it like, I want to kind of know where the wind
Speaker 2:  goes from manageable to, not really manageable cause this is pretty rough.
Speaker 2:  Okay,
Speaker 14:  So this is at like a nice Sunday cruising speed. Okay. You know,
Speaker 14:  I'm just too along. There's a horse, there's
Speaker 14:  two horses, there's all these children screaming. Can you hear
Speaker 14:  them at all?
Speaker 2:  Hardly at all. Actually, this is actually pretty manageable. You're still,
Speaker 2:  it's clearly like compressing your voice just right down to the middle. So
Speaker 2:  I'm not getting like much of anything interesting around you. But I, I
Speaker 2:  can at least like hear you pretty clearly as you ride like that.
Speaker 14:  Oh hell yeah. I would say this breeze is like a very light breeze
Speaker 14:  on a summer day. Yeah, you're not in a windstorm, but it's also
Speaker 14:  not no breeze. And I hear it a lot less. I got a car
Speaker 14:  coming up on my right right now and I
Speaker 14:  see parks. Oh, you could grab the back of that bed and coast.
Speaker 2:  Okay, so a thing I just noticed that you, you just confirmed a theory that
Speaker 2:  I had, which is that what it sounds like is happening is when these buds
Speaker 2:  only have to cancel the wind. They do a pretty good job because when it was
Speaker 2:  in that quiet phase, I could hear you really well, but then it's like as
Speaker 2:  soon as another thing comes up and it has to do two things at once, it starts
Speaker 2:  to kind of fall apart. Like you got way worse when the car showed up, even
Speaker 2:  though I couldn't hear the car. And then it got better as soon as it was
Speaker 2:  gone.
Speaker 14:  So what's worse? Like canceling out the noise and also making
Speaker 14:  my voice funny or just letting the noise be because I
Speaker 14:  am outside and those sounds happen.
Speaker 2:  This is such a good question. I feel like the the right answer is somewhere
Speaker 2:  in the middle, but to me it's like I would rather
Speaker 2:  hear nothing than hear everything. Just personal opinion, like listening
Speaker 2:  to someone who appears to like be inside of a
Speaker 2:  concert, talking to you on a phone is just a nightmare. And so I'd rather
Speaker 2:  just be like, I can't hear anything. Call me later than just be like overcome
Speaker 2:  by all the insane noise of your life.
Speaker 14:  Wow, okay. Interesting. Cause I have the opposite opinion. Often I'm on
Speaker 14:  the phone with my parents and they're like, You do sound bad. What? What's
Speaker 14:  going on? You know, it's like that sort of like level of concern and I just
Speaker 14:  have to be like, no, it's just a, a car going by. And if they could
Speaker 14:  hear that then they wouldn't worry that I'm, you know,
Speaker 14:  dying
Speaker 2:  Fair. But then the flip side of that is every time a car goes by it's gonna
Speaker 2:  sound like the your, your building exploded.
Speaker 14:  This is true.
Speaker 2:  All right, I think we're good on this one. Go ahead and pull over and let's
Speaker 2:  switch to the next one. Let's do the Bose headphones next.
Speaker 14:  Oh, you got it. Ready to connect. These are the
Speaker 14:  Bose quiet comfort earbuds too. And I often refer to them as
Speaker 14:  the QC twos.
Speaker 2:  Okay. So the thing with these before we test the real thing is the noise
Speaker 2:  cancellation on these, according to Chris Wild who reviewed them is like
Speaker 2:  unbelievable. Has that been your experience too? Is it
Speaker 2:  incredible, David?
Speaker 14:  Unbelievable. You want main character energy in your life. Get a pair
Speaker 14:  of these, put on some, I don't know, song from
Speaker 14:  your teens and walk down fifth Avenue in Manhattan.
Speaker 14:  You are the main character. A hundred percent.
Speaker 2:  That is all I've ever wanted. It's the dream. Let's go for a bike
Speaker 2:  ride.
Speaker 14:  All right, we are on the road. It's a bit breezy over on the side of the
Speaker 14:  park right now. Oh, interesting. So the bows are, I'm
Speaker 14:  hearing the breeze and as soon as I start to hear it, the bows are canceling
Speaker 14:  it out for me. We've seen this feature from a few buds, but I didn't know
Speaker 14:  that these ones had that, so that's cool.
Speaker 2:  I'm getting some interesting stuff from you here. Like on the one hand, it's
Speaker 2:  basically doing the thing where it is, it just compressed your voice to like
Speaker 2:  one teeny tiny frequency. So you sound like you're coming through a phone
Speaker 2:  call basically, which is fine. I can hear you fine. It just, it's just super,
Speaker 2:  super, super compressed. But I'm getting more
Speaker 2:  wind noise and I guess it's wind noise than I expected. It sounds like
Speaker 2:  someone is sucking something through a straw is the only
Speaker 2:  way I can describe it. And it's very odd.
Speaker 14:  Is there a lot of water in the cup or is there no water in the cup? Are
Speaker 14:  we like
Speaker 2:  Slurping? No, it's like right at the end of the cup when there's like a little
Speaker 2:  bit of water, but mostly you're getting, it's like the last bit of
Speaker 2:  the milkshake straw bit. It's not great. I don't love it. I would
Speaker 2:  say you sound worse, but I can hear you better. And you're going
Speaker 2:  pretty fast.
Speaker 14:  I am going faster than I was at the end of the pixel buds. And I will
Speaker 14:  say these buds stick out the most from the sides of my ears. Like
Speaker 14:  they're pretty chunky on the outside, which I used to dock
Speaker 14:  buds for, but I don't know if you have that great of anc. I can
Speaker 14:  have some chalkiness.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, that's understandable.
Speaker 14:  All right. Should I pull over and switch?
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I think so. Let's do the first Gen AirPods real quick. We'll just
Speaker 2:  do those quickly and then switch to the new ones. Okay,
Speaker 14:  You got it. These are the first
Speaker 14:  Gen AirPod pros, so they should have a pretty good mic
Speaker 14:  quality.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, the thing I've liked about the AirPods in our past tests is that it's
Speaker 2:  a pretty good middle ground of like, it does pretty good noise
Speaker 2:  cancellation and pretty good mic. It's not the best at either one, but it's
Speaker 2:  like good enough at both that it tends to work for most people. And the thing
Speaker 2:  is, for me at least, the transparency is the reason the AirPods are great.
Speaker 2:  Yes. It's like leaps and bounds better than anybody else's.
Speaker 14:  Yeah, it really does feel like there's nothing in your ears at all, which
Speaker 14:  is what I love about the Sony Link buds as well, cuz they're, you know,
Speaker 14:  quite literally have holes in them. But you know, the danger is, I have
Speaker 14:  a feeling in 10 years, like your doctors are just
Speaker 14:  gonna be banking. Like if you're looking for a career right now,
Speaker 14:  go learn about the ears because we're all gonna have gunked up,
Speaker 14:  funked up ears.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. We're all just gonna be deaf in a decade too. Like all right,
Speaker 2:  let's, let's go for a ride. I'm already hearing more background noise than
Speaker 2:  either of the other two, which is interesting.
Speaker 14:  All right, so you're on the road. It's a bit breezy. We got that cross
Speaker 14:  breeze again. I'm not going too fast yet, but there's pretty
Speaker 14:  good headwind coming along.
Speaker 2:  Okay. You sound pretty good so far. Okay. I mean one of the things I'm realizing
Speaker 2:  here is that like the main thing a lot of these companies are doing
Speaker 2:  is trying to cancel wind noise. So it's not super shocking that they're all
Speaker 2:  pretty good at canceling wind noise, but the fact that they're able to do
Speaker 2:  a lot of wind noise and some other stuff, that's where it kind of seems
Speaker 2:  to vary, which is interesting.
Speaker 14:  I'm going down a bit of a hill here, so we're gonna take on a little bit
Speaker 14:  more wind to good baseball fields. I'm crossing where
Speaker 14:  the Nighthawk Cinema is the exit for that and the city bike
Speaker 14:  rack that never has city bikes because it's at the top of the
Speaker 14:  hill and well, you take the bike down, not a,
Speaker 14:  that's for sure. Yeah. How's that?
Speaker 2:  It's gotten substantially worse. Okay, I can still hear you.
Speaker 2:  Okay, but we're, we're sort of veering towards the pixel buds thing where
Speaker 2:  its answer is just to make you very compressed and very quiet.
Speaker 14:  Ah ooh. Yikes. Yeah, turn off that volume.
Speaker 2:  The good news is none of these are like, like absolutely failing the tests
Speaker 2:  so far, which is nice. Unlike the, the Samsung Galaxy Buds Pro from the last
Speaker 2:  time, which absolutely failed our test. This is all like varying degrees
Speaker 2:  of like, it kind of works so far.
Speaker 14:  All right, so I'm about to hit a big, Oh there's a guy playing a saxophone.
Speaker 14:  Can you hear the guy playing the saxophone? He's playing one single note.
Speaker 2:  All I hear I was gonna say, all I hear is one single note, it just
Speaker 2:  sounded like just one two of the saxophone.
Speaker 14:  It was one he must be, you know, just warming up that read. Is that
Speaker 14:  what, So we're about to hit a big hill. We're about also about to cut
Speaker 14:  some horses. Do you want me to bomb down the hill or do you want me to change?
Speaker 2:  Let's switch before you do the big hill. Cause I think we're gonna, we're
Speaker 2:  gonna put the AirPods Pro two through the hardest test of
Speaker 2:  them all, so let's see how it does.
Speaker 14:  All right, cool. These are the AirPods
Speaker 14:  Pro second gen.
Speaker 2:  So these are the new ones which are ostensibly basically like slightly better
Speaker 2:  at everything without being like a gigantic earth shattering new
Speaker 2:  thing, right? That's
Speaker 14:  Correct. A lot of folks seem to think they are earth shattering and I think
Speaker 14:  that's because if you've had a pair of AirPod pros and you use them regularly
Speaker 14:  for more than like a year and a half, they start to like dump
Speaker 14:  in every way possible. And so when you do get a new pair, you're gonna be
Speaker 14:  like, Oh my God, this is the greatest thing ever. But if you are
Speaker 14:  looking at them in terms of like the full market of earbuds and
Speaker 14:  outside of ecosystem, they're good. Okay. If you shout out to the video,
Speaker 14:  go watch it. We did like a cool ANC test and Owen Grove
Speaker 14:  and Jasmine Lewis, my two directors with me, like we just put our heart
Speaker 14:  and soul into that one. So go check it out if you
Speaker 2:  Haven't, it's a good one. Yeah, we'll put that link in the show notes. It's,
Speaker 2:  it's a good video. Thanks bud. All right, so we have a big, big downhill
Speaker 2:  to do here. So we're gonna put these two the probably the
Speaker 2:  hardest test of anything we've tried so far. Let's see how we do.
Speaker 14:  Yeah, if you ever see me in Proso car going down this hill, even when I'm
Speaker 14:  not testing my quality, I'm screaming. So this is nothing new.
Speaker 14:  First we're starting out next to some horses and here we
Speaker 14:  go. Yep. Hello. Good friends. Have a great walk.
Speaker 2:  Oh, I heard a lot of horses that time. More horses than usual on that one.
Speaker 14:  I got a little close, I was a little excited you talking to
Speaker 14:  me. I love, I love a good,
Speaker 14:  you
Speaker 14:  know, we,
Speaker 2:  This is what I was hoping for. We successfully broke the
Speaker 2:  test.
Speaker 14:  Okay. Could you hear any of that on towards the bottom
Speaker 2:  There? Barely. It's one of those things like, you know when you can hear
Speaker 2:  through the wall that somebody is talking but you can't hear any of the stuff
Speaker 2:  that they're saying. That's essentially what I'm getting you right, right
Speaker 2:  now I can like, I can tell you're talking, I just don't know what
Speaker 2:  you're talking about.
Speaker 14:  Give us through the wall blue. Okay. We are at the bottom of
Speaker 14:  the hill. It's still relatively windy. I will slow down now though and
Speaker 14:  we'll, we'll do a little bit less headwind.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, give, get us back to the, the Sunday stroll pace and we'll see how
Speaker 2:  we do.
Speaker 14:  Yeah, so we we're strolling. I have to imagine this sounds pretty good.
Speaker 14:  There's like a small breeze again, it's like a fall day breeze. There's
Speaker 14:  not too much outside noise. There's some traffic, but it's not moving quickly.
Speaker 2:  The thing that is amazing me about this is how similar all four
Speaker 2:  of these have been performance wise. Yeah. Like the distinct vibe that I'm
Speaker 2:  getting here is basically like avoid going very
Speaker 2:  fast if you can while talking to people, but like it works in
Speaker 2:  a pinch. This is the kind of thing like I think if you, if you are like riding
Speaker 2:  your bike and need to ask Syria a question, like
Speaker 2:  it would probably work,
Speaker 14:  You know, what I do find though is like a total disaster is
Speaker 14:  speech to text. I think it's usually not great, but whenever there's
Speaker 14:  the least bit of outside noise Wow. Does it tank?
Speaker 2:  Yeah, that is fair. Almost any pair of headphones, even in good conditions,
Speaker 2:  speech to text seems to get like substantially worse for me. And I've never
Speaker 2:  totally understood why that is.
Speaker 14:  I mean all of these earbuds, right, they're all using Bluetooth of, of
Speaker 14:  some sort. Yep. And so there is a point where it's like it can only get
Speaker 14:  so good on that standard, which is why, you know, we had those rumors about
Speaker 14:  Apple like creating their own standard, which I was about to be so mad if
Speaker 14:  that was true. So it's not true yet, but maybe in
Speaker 14:  three years when they put out another generation of the haircut pros.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, it's even Apple has basically said like, we have maxed out the limits
Speaker 2:  of Bluetooth. If you want it to get better, we're gonna have to figure out
Speaker 2:  something else. So it's gonna be interesting to see. All right, Becca, thank
Speaker 2:  you for bringing us on your bike ride today. We've, we've been through a
Speaker 2:  lot together, so I'm gonna let you go. This test was super helpful. I learned
Speaker 2:  a lot, I'm surprised I heard you as much as I did and we will definitely
Speaker 2:  be sure to check in with you next time. Another earbuds are released it to
Speaker 2:  the world.
Speaker 14:  Super. I'll talk to you all soon.
Speaker 2:  One overall takeaway here, which I know we say every time is that actually
Speaker 2:  most of these are pretty good. Now, as long as you're in a good spot, if
Speaker 2:  you're at home or in a Quietish office, you'll probably have good luck
Speaker 2:  with all of these high end models. But as you heard, things get messy
Speaker 2:  when the world gets louder. I think I probably wouldn't recommend long phone
Speaker 2:  calls from the middle of a bike race on any of these headphones, but you
Speaker 2:  gotta do what you gotta do sometimes. Just talk loud, I
Speaker 2:  guess. Oh, and here's a really crucial piece of info Becca's bike
Speaker 2:  ride ended up at the Prospect Park Zoo. So we got one last very
Speaker 2:  important test in here's how the AirPods Pro two would handle a phone call
Speaker 2:  if you were hanging out with a bunch of sea lions.
Speaker 14:  I hope this podcast,
Speaker 2:  Whoa, whoa, was that,
Speaker 14:  Wouldn't you like the low? Hold on,
Speaker 14:  they'll be
Speaker 14:  back.
Speaker 2:  Wow. Okay, so if, if we've learned one thing so far, it's that
Speaker 2:  nobody prepared for sea lions.
Speaker 14:  Nobody has prepared for this. This is the, oh my
Speaker 14:  God.
Speaker 2:  And with that, that's it for the Vergecast this week. Thank you so much for
Speaker 2:  listening. As always, there's tons more coverage on everything we talked
Speaker 2:  about at our still very newly redesigned website verge.com. There's new stuff
Speaker 2:  coming there all the time. Keep checking it out. You can also follow all
Speaker 2:  of us on Twitter. Alex is Alex h Cranz. Becca is Becca
Speaker 2:  Versace, and I'm Pierce. This show is produced by Andrew Marino and Liam
Speaker 2:  James. Nora Donovan is our executive producer and Brook Winters is our editorial
Speaker 2:  director of Audio. The Vergecast is a verge production and part of the Fox
Speaker 2:  Media podcast network. If you have thoughts, feedback, feelings, or still
Speaker 2:  use a Kindle DX and really wanna talk about it, you can always
Speaker 2:  email vergecast@verge.com. And I know I mentioned this already, but we're
Speaker 2:  still working on an episode all about cybersecurity and we're gonna do a
Speaker 2:  full on call in show answering our questions. We've got some great ones already,
Speaker 2:  but if you have a cybersecurity thing you can't figure out or
Speaker 2:  a crazy mystery, you don't know what's going on and there might be
Speaker 2:  something nefarious happening, call us eight six six Verge 11
Speaker 2:  or send us a voice memo to vergecast@verge.com and we'll get back to you
Speaker 2:  if we think we can help. Alex, Neil and I will be back on Friday to talk
Speaker 2:  about the Google event. We're gonna get pixel phones, pixel watches, all
Speaker 2:  kinds of other stuff, and all the other tech news of the week. We'll see
Speaker 2:  then.
Speaker 2:  Rock
Speaker 2:  and roll
Speaker ?:  Ransomware can ruin the trust between businesses and the tech they rely on.
Speaker ?:  And while these attacks might seem unstoppable, one company is here to
Speaker ?:  help you fight back at Bay. Combines insurance with security
Speaker ?:  to reduce ransomware events by five times the industry
Speaker ?:  average. Renew confidence in your business' digital world with at bay. To
Speaker ?:  learn
Speaker ?:  more, visit@bay.com.