# Transcript
ID: 4b89dd00-6f26-11ed-9ee2-2538705d6798
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: The creator of the future is smart, attractive... and animated
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-7386924605804331894/-4754743803979134890/s93290-US-2001s-1669644535.mp3
Description: As we spend more time in digital spaces, our avatars are becoming part of our personality. And digital creators and influencers are becoming part of our culture. Producer Gina Pollack join's The Verge's David Pierce with stories about why advertisers love digital creators, why a dancing hot dog will never leave your brain, and what the creator industry is learning from mascots. Next time you’re scrolling through your Instagram feed, keep your eyes peeled — not everyone’s as human as they look.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (4 ads detected)
Speaker 1:  Welcome to the Verge Cast, the flagship podcast of the Uncanny Valley.
Speaker 1:  I'm your friend, David Pierce. And for the next three weeks in this feed,
Speaker 1:  we're gonna be doing a mini series that we made all about the creator
Speaker 1:  economy, emphasis on economy. We're gonna look into how all
Speaker 1:  kinds of influencers, the brands they represent, and the people who manage
Speaker 1:  them make and spend their money. Today we're starting with
Speaker 1:  a story from producer Gina Pollock about a topic I know
Speaker 1:  nothing about and am super excited to get into, which is virtual
Speaker 1:  influencers. Maybe you've seen them out there, they look just like the other
Speaker 1:  models and cool kids posing and promoting brands on Instagram or TikTok
Speaker 1:  or wherever else, but there's something different about
Speaker 1:  them. And then you look a little closer and you realize they're not human
Speaker 1:  at all. They're actually these hyper realistic 3D
Speaker 1:  illustrations designed to look like humans ish,
Speaker 1:  but not exactly. Managers, artists and tech companies are making big,
Speaker 1:  big money with these digital characters and they could become an even bigger
Speaker 1:  deal as virtual reality is like the metaverse become more mainstream. And
Speaker 1:  this phenomenon brings up all kinds of questions. Could digital
Speaker 1:  influencers change the future of the creator economy or replace
Speaker 1:  human influencers entirely? Or is this just a passing
Speaker 1:  trend? So Gina, I don't even,
Speaker 1:  let's, let's just get into this here. Welcome to the show.
Speaker 3:  Thank you. I'm very excited to talk about this.
Speaker 1:  So at the very beginning, this story was about humans and you came back and
Speaker 1:  said, actually humans, that's old hat passe. Tell me how you found
Speaker 1:  out about this phenomenon.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, so a couple years ago I was doing another story
Speaker 3:  about Instagram influencers and I talked to this agent named
Speaker 3:  Jennifer Powell. She was showing me like her roster of
Speaker 3:  clients and one of them looked a little different to
Speaker 3:  me. And her name is Shoe Do. Okay.
Speaker 3:  And I want you to open and look at her page
Speaker 3:  because I feel like you have to see it.
Speaker 1:  Okay. You sent me her Instagram link. She's 237,000
Speaker 1:  followers. Good for her.
Speaker 3:  And I would say to describe her, she's very tall, she has very
Speaker 3:  short hair, she has really dark, perfect
Speaker 3:  skin emphasis on Perfect. And I think the celebrity
Speaker 3:  that she reminds me of most is Looped and Jango.
Speaker 1:  That's exactly who I was about to say a hundred percent.
Speaker 3:  She's like Lupita Jango, but somehow even more
Speaker 3:  symmetrical, which is shocking because Lupita is perfect
Speaker 3:  looking.
Speaker 1:  Yeah,
Speaker 3:  Already
Speaker 1:  That's a high water. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. So when I was first working on that story, I was
Speaker 3:  surprised that she wasn't a real person and also
Speaker 3:  confused like who is making her. And I ended up
Speaker 3:  talking to Cameron James Wilson, who is her
Speaker 3:  creator, and he was a fashion photographer for
Speaker 3:  a long time. He was going through a difficult time in his personal life and
Speaker 3:  was kind of stuck at home. This was way before the pandemic. And he started
Speaker 3:  playing around with virtual imaging and creating
Speaker 3:  these 3D models. And he said he just
Speaker 3:  wanted to create the perfect woman. And that's how
Speaker 3:  he landed on sh Do
Speaker 4:  I think sh Do Represents what I see as Beautiful. And
Speaker 4:  eventually she kind of became almost her own personality, her own
Speaker 4:  individual self and became the world's first
Speaker 4:  digital supermodel, which
Speaker 1:  Yikes, like interesting and yikes simultaneously.
Speaker 1:  Is that, is that a fair response to that?
Speaker 3:  Yeah, it's weird because it was this white man who
Speaker 3:  wanted to create this perfect, beautiful
Speaker 3:  black woman. So that created some
Speaker 3:  controversy. Of course,
Speaker 1:  All of that aside, I'm kind of like, if you had just shown me
Speaker 1:  this Instagram and not given me any other information ahead of
Speaker 1:  it, I would've a hundred percent just believed this was a real person and
Speaker 1:  moved on. And even I'm like poking through the comments on her page now and
Speaker 1:  people are responding like she's a real person. This is kind of
Speaker 1:  blowing my mind.
Speaker 3:  So when he actually first created her, it didn't say in the profile
Speaker 3:  that she wasn't a real person. And he made
Speaker 3:  this image where there was this orange background and she's wearing
Speaker 3:  this orange lipstick and he matched the shade of the lipstick to a
Speaker 3:  Fenty Beauty lipstick. And Fenty
Speaker 3:  repost it on their Instagram and it went super viral. People were like,
Speaker 3:  who is this model? Oh wow, this is amazing. She's
Speaker 3:  beautiful. And then people started commenting, wait a second,
Speaker 3:  this is not a real per, is this a real person? This is not a real person.
Speaker 3:  And then Fenty Beauty actually took it down
Speaker 3:  because they didn't know it wasn't a real person.
Speaker 1:  Oh wow. Clearly real or not, this thing is
Speaker 1:  working right. She has tons of followers, lots of comments,
Speaker 1:  there's a lot of engagement on it. Everybody like treats her like they would
Speaker 1:  be fans of any other supermodel, like real or digital. Sheu seems to be working
Speaker 1:  on Instagram, which is kind of nuts.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. And Sheu has worked with huge brands and fashion
Speaker 3:  magazines.
Speaker 4:  She was, was actually paid to model
Speaker 4:  for Vogue Australia with Al Harper's Vogue,
Speaker 4:  cosmopolitan.
Speaker 3:  She's worked with all these major luxury brands,
Speaker 4:  Luton, Bama, Lexus, Tiffany,
Speaker 4:  Todds, Faragamo, the list goes
Speaker 4:  on.
Speaker 3:  So if she was a real model, she would be considered very successful.
Speaker 1:  Wow. So how much is this a totally new
Speaker 1:  thing?
Speaker 3:  I talked to actually a guy named Christopher Tra, and he runs a
Speaker 3:  website called Virtual Humans, which is kind of like an encyclopedia of digital
Speaker 3:  influencers. And he was talking about how he was actually
Speaker 3:  inspired by the early internet, like the late nineties
Speaker 5:  When I was a kid. There was no social network that was focused on
Speaker 5:  being yourself. It was all using handles and pseudonyms. So for a good 10
Speaker 5:  years I was playing video games, browsing forums, and engaging in chat
Speaker 5:  through pseudonyms.
Speaker 3:  He was just really into this idea of inhabiting another
Speaker 3:  body. So you're pulling the strings, but the body isn't yours and the
Speaker 3:  personality isn't necessarily the same as your personality.
Speaker 1:  Totally.
Speaker 3:  But the next wave of social media was really more
Speaker 3:  encouraging us to be ourselves. Like Facebook and Instagram,
Speaker 3:  I'm creating an image of myself and then I'm supposed to, you know, like
Speaker 3:  update my friends on what I'm really doing. And Christopher says, this whole
Speaker 3:  trend of digital models is kind of like a rewind back to the beginning
Speaker 3:  of the internet where we could all be different people.
Speaker 5:  Now the internet is coming full circle to this idea because
Speaker 5:  avatars are taking form and they're competing with humans now
Speaker 5:  in what was supposedly this human media feed,
Speaker 5:  right? People are now leveraging the same technology that is used
Speaker 5:  to create video games and characters in video games to now create characters
Speaker 5:  outside of video games for all sorts of purposes. That could be
Speaker 5:  modeling, that could be influencing, that could be live streaming. So
Speaker 5:  the form could be a digital model, but if you take this digital
Speaker 5:  model and you post it redundantly on social media, that starts to look like
Speaker 5:  a virtual influencer.
Speaker 1:  That transition actually makes complete sense to me in that sense. Now you're
Speaker 1:  making me wonder like, do I go on Instagram every day and half the things
Speaker 1:  I see are digital characters that I don't even realize are digital
Speaker 1:  characters? Like how big is this space right now?
Speaker 3:  I wouldn't say it's at that level yet. There are definitely
Speaker 3:  a lot of these, but you kind of have to look for them. And I didn't happen
Speaker 3:  to be following any of them. I just, once you kind of look
Speaker 3:  into it, then you find more and more and more and they're all over the world.
Speaker 3:  So the first one that I saw was a character called Lil
Speaker 3:  Makayla. And her creators basically looked
Speaker 3:  at what influencers were doing. They took Lil Makayla and mimicked
Speaker 3:  that entire lifestyle and that entire ethos of being an
Speaker 3:  influencer. Oh wow. And that made her go super, super viral. Like,
Speaker 3:  oh, they're hanging out with their friends, they're shopping, they're at
Speaker 3:  the pink wall taking a picture. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Whoa. She has almost 3 million followers on Instagram.
Speaker 3:  She's kind of like the most Gen Z optimized
Speaker 3:  cool girl that could possibly exist. Like
Speaker 3:  she is ethnically ambiguous. Apparently
Speaker 3:  she's 19, 19 years old and she has these two buns that she wears
Speaker 3:  on top of her head. And you're kind of like, Ooh, I wanna hang out with her.
Speaker 3:  I wanna be her friend.
Speaker 1:  And Mikayla's been around for a while, right? Yeah. Like I'm impressed
Speaker 1:  how she remains as popular as she has been for
Speaker 1:  what it looks like a long time. I mean, she's posted 1,250 times on Instagram.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Which is not a small amount of work.
Speaker 3:  She was created in 2016 by an LA company called
Speaker 3:  br. It's B R U D. It might be brewed, we'll never know because they
Speaker 3:  don't respond to emails from journalists. So
Speaker 3:  unclear. But I think they kind of created this persona
Speaker 3:  for her where she talks about being a 19 year old robot living in
Speaker 3:  la
Speaker 6:  If you're late to the party, Hey, I'm McKayla, I'm a 19 year
Speaker 6:  old robot living in LA making music and
Speaker 6:  well, I guess just keep watching and catch up.
Speaker 1:  It's gotta be tough. It's hard out there for a 19 year old robot.
Speaker 3:  It's hard out there. But she's actually not a robot because she's not
Speaker 3:  artificially intelligent. She is just voiced by an actor.
Speaker 3:  She has a YouTube page where she does the kind of confessional
Speaker 3:  videos that you'd see on the YouTube page.
Speaker 6:  Wait, I'm dead at the fact that my mind just made me the person being broken
Speaker 6:  up with. Does that mean I'm the toxic front? No. To self discuss the next
Speaker 6:  Tuesday's therapy session.
Speaker 3:  And she even has a music
Speaker 3:  video.
Speaker 1:  Oh my gosh.
Speaker 3:  She's a very complete being as far as a not
Speaker 3:  real person.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. She's a real like multihyphenate over here.
Speaker 3:  She became really famous because the media loved her because she was
Speaker 3:  the first digital in influencer. She was the first one
Speaker 3:  to be doing exactly what human beings were doing. And she followed that playbook.
Speaker 3:  Exactly. And by she, I mean her creators, but again, it's like
Speaker 3:  hard to not personify them. Right? Because it's easier for me to
Speaker 3:  say she than to say it.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I'm struggling with this too, cuz it's like McKayla is obviously not
Speaker 1:  a person and so saying she feels wrong, but also I'm looking at her Instagram
Speaker 1:  and it is the Instagram of a 19 year old girl
Speaker 1:  in la.
Speaker 6:  Okay, we're done here. Send me your questions for next time. And what? That's
Speaker 6:  right. Don't forget to recharge your hearts.
Speaker 1:  Okay. So let, let's get back to the economics of all of this because
Speaker 1:  I'm assuming like shoot, you and Lo Makayla don't
Speaker 1:  have bank accounts and there's no them to pay for their
Speaker 1:  services. So how, how do these virtual
Speaker 1:  humans actually make money, right?
Speaker 3:  For example, Jennifer represents shoe do, but
Speaker 3:  really she's representing Cameron, so that's a little different from another
Speaker 3:  influencer that she represents. Name sincerely Jules. Sincerely Jules is
Speaker 3:  her client, but here you have her client creating another client and
Speaker 3:  the first one is not appearing as themselves. Aside from that,
Speaker 3:  it's very similar as Christopher explained.
Speaker 5:  When you think about virtual influencers, how does it work that they can
Speaker 5:  also do brand deals? Well the Playbook, playbook was written
Speaker 5:  exhaustively by human influencers and by brands who are willing
Speaker 5:  to pay. Honestly, human influencers to a lot of brands are just
Speaker 5:  mannequins. And so I've met brands who say they really care about working
Speaker 5:  with, you know, the right influencers and all of this. What they really mean
Speaker 5:  is, I care about reaching your fandom in the right way and I will pay you
Speaker 5:  to do it for me. So when you think about how a human
Speaker 5:  influencer set the playbook and built the pipeline
Speaker 5:  for brand dollars to flow through to them. Now when you
Speaker 5:  simulate a human influencer, the infrastructure is already in place
Speaker 5:  and brands can now flow their dollars in through virtual
Speaker 5:  influencers and achieve the same end.
Speaker 3:  Brands know how to work with them, they pay them a certain
Speaker 3:  amount of money for a post. They have marketing tools that tell
Speaker 3:  them what the return on investment was. Jennifer says the way it's generally
Speaker 3:  calculated
Speaker 8:  Is there's no great way to quantify, but if I was
Speaker 8:  going to, it'd be like a thousand for every hundred thousand
Speaker 8:  followers perhaps. I mean that's kind of a rule of
Speaker 8:  thumb ish. But then people can ask for whatever they
Speaker 8:  want
Speaker 3:  For sincerely, Jules who I was talking about, she has 7 million followers.
Speaker 3:  So the minimum that a brand would pay for a post from her would be $70,000.
Speaker 3:  But it varies because they might be like, oh, we want five posts, or we want
Speaker 3:  one post and an Instagram story, or we want a tweet and we want you to appear
Speaker 3:  at the store. But that's kind of the baseline that Jennifer told me.
Speaker 8:  I really did put the same sort of like price tags on shoe
Speaker 8:  do as a human talent. But the
Speaker 8:  difference is, is the production costs. And so I have to
Speaker 8:  factor that in and that's almost like how I figured out a day rate. And then
Speaker 8:  I figure out a usage. And it's the same
Speaker 8:  like a human model. When you thought of them shooting a fragrance, then
Speaker 8:  you have to talk about exclusivity and you have to talk about a term
Speaker 8:  that they're going to be associated with the brand and such. And we do the
Speaker 8:  same thing with Sudu. We don't wanna create conflicts or anything for Sudu
Speaker 8:  because she is intellectual property. She is,
Speaker 8:  her image is very much like an actual human.
Speaker 1:  But you were saying Cameron has like a whole, this is like an
Speaker 1:  agency thing
Speaker 3:  Now, right? Like so just like bred the company that made Lil McKayla
Speaker 3:  created Bermuda to be her like Arch Ral friend. That's
Speaker 3:  kind of also what Cameron did. And
Speaker 3:  we just have to listen to him explain it for himself because
Speaker 3:  he's the best at doing
Speaker 4:  It. Danny is a Caucasian model with red
Speaker 4:  hair and freckles. Kofi is a
Speaker 4:  gorgeous tool, muscular black model. He's
Speaker 4:  very athletic into body building. I imagined
Speaker 4:  when I created him that him and Chu would be kind of like
Speaker 4:  the Adam and Eve of the digital world, the new Barbie in
Speaker 4:  can, an alien model called
Speaker 4:  Gaia. And she's really tall with blue Skin
Speaker 4:  Voice is non-binary and is a virtual
Speaker 4:  drag queen. Another character that we created is
Speaker 4:  Bran. She's a a mixed race plus size
Speaker 4:  model with stretch marks. And then Jay
Speaker 4:  Young, who is a Korean male model. And we are
Speaker 4:  currently developing him even further.
Speaker 1:  There's just a lot going on there that I need to spend a lot
Speaker 1:  of time sorting through. But he really sees them as people
Speaker 1:  with personalities and imperfections and you know, he talks about
Speaker 1:  stretch marks and the different features that different versions of them
Speaker 1:  have. It's like, it's really interesting that the goal here is to
Speaker 1:  go sort of extremely human rather than
Speaker 1:  like kind of science fiction futuristic robot, which I
Speaker 1:  would think would be one way a lot of people would go with this.
Speaker 3:  The trend now in marketing for female clothes
Speaker 3:  and female products has gone from, okay, everybody has to be really
Speaker 3:  skinny and look like a six foot tall, 100 pound woman.
Speaker 3:  To now, like, we wanna see real women brands like Dove or like
Speaker 3:  Airy for example, have different sized models and models again
Speaker 3:  with stretch marks and they're not Photoshopping. And so he can then create
Speaker 3:  a character, this character brand that he's talking about, who, who's perfect
Speaker 3:  for those brands. And then he can create a non-binary virtual
Speaker 3:  drag queen. So it's like whatever the trend is in
Speaker 3:  the larger culture, he can kind of roll with that
Speaker 3:  and create the perfect person in air
Speaker 3:  quotes to represent that trend.
Speaker 1:  And I guess it's true that if the audience is gonna respond to
Speaker 1:  these characters in roughly the same way that they would respond to
Speaker 1:  actual human influencers, you've basically like replaced central
Speaker 1:  casting with a bunch of animators in a way that like, it's a little bit
Speaker 1:  cynical in a way. Yeah, but it's, it, it almost makes total sense to
Speaker 3:  Me. It's like you're cutting out the middle man and the middle man is the
Speaker 3:  human. The
Speaker 1:  Literal man. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  The literal man in the middle. You're like, we, we just don't need
Speaker 3:  you.
Speaker 1:  It's so much safer in so many
Speaker 1:  ways. Like your, your virtual influencer is never gonna have a rebellious
Speaker 1:  phase. That's not like a thing,
Speaker 3:  A real model. You have to fly her from Milan to New York.
Speaker 3:  I mean, that's time consuming. You have to coordinate all of that and
Speaker 3:  pay for those expenses. And you can't have somebody doing two photo
Speaker 3:  shoots at once. But obviously with these digital models, you
Speaker 3:  can,
Speaker 5:  Brands can now work with this character over a lifetime because that
Speaker 5:  character's never going to age out. It's never going to die for all these
Speaker 5:  various benefits from a technological standpoint, all the way down to the
Speaker 5:  fact that you can better control what a virtual influencer says
Speaker 5:  over a human influencer.
Speaker 1:  Your model will never die. Is is honestly, it's a really good sales
Speaker 1:  page. All right, we're gonna take a quick break and we
Speaker 1:  will be back with more on digital
Speaker 1:  influencers.
Speaker 1:  All right, we're back. Now you've got me wondering how this actually
Speaker 1:  goes down. Like I'm, I'm thinking about if I wanna take a picture of Charlie
Speaker 1:  DME with a Dunkin Donuts, that's pretty
Speaker 1:  straightforward. How do you do one of these virtual
Speaker 1:  photo shoots?
Speaker 3:  It's definitely a production. Cameron told me all about this and it's
Speaker 3:  like when you think about a regular photo
Speaker 3:  shoot,
Speaker 4:  You would probably have hair stylist, a makeup
Speaker 4:  artist, a clothing stylist, a photographer,
Speaker 4:  a photography assistant. You'd have the model, you'd have to hire
Speaker 4:  the studio.
Speaker 3:  It's a physical shoot that's happening, especially when you're talking about
Speaker 3:  modeling doing that digitally. It's this whole other
Speaker 3:  process and it's kind of hard to conceptualize because it's not an actual
Speaker 3:  shoot.
Speaker 4:  The problem with virtual shoots is time. You know, it might take two
Speaker 4:  weeks or more to kind of work on a 3D editorial
Speaker 4:  in the studio. Will, we might have to buy certain digital
Speaker 4:  assets.
Speaker 3:  The one where shoe do is wearing Louis Vuitton and
Speaker 3:  standing in New York on Broadway. That background was a panel
Speaker 3:  created by an illustrator that was given to
Speaker 3:  Cameron, who then takes shoe do and puts her
Speaker 3:  on that background. And he uses a real
Speaker 3:  model to pose in the same pose that Shooter's
Speaker 3:  doing.
Speaker 4:  If you imagine an influencer receives a product and they can
Speaker 4:  just pop that product on and take a photo with it. When it
Speaker 4:  comes to us, you know, we have to get a model
Speaker 4:  involved. We have to put that product on, we have to do a whole photo
Speaker 4:  shoot, then we have to replace the model with shoot and,
Speaker 4:  and kind of match her in in 3D to the real
Speaker 4:  one. In some circumstances we have to recreate
Speaker 4:  all of the clothes virtually. There
Speaker 3:  Are these companies that create digital
Speaker 3:  clothing based on photographs. So I thought maybe Louis Vuitton is
Speaker 3:  gonna send their jacket to this company and they're gonna
Speaker 3:  just digitize it. But it's actually just a photo of the jacket. You're taking
Speaker 3:  the jacket, you're taking a picture of it, and then the company is
Speaker 3:  recreating that jacket digitally and then it becomes a digital
Speaker 3:  product that then can be put onto Shoe do
Speaker 3:  by Cameron. Wow. In his digital software. And
Speaker 3:  that was really surprising to me cause I was like, I can't believe there's
Speaker 3:  not only one company that does that, but multiple companies do that.
Speaker 3:  Cameron also works with a stylist named Tom.
Speaker 4:  His specialty is a digital fashion. He's actually a
Speaker 4:  virtual stylist. I've coined that kind of term
Speaker 4:  a couple of years ago when he was working
Speaker 4:  constantly on these kind of photo shoots, styling them in 3d that
Speaker 4:  is very specific to working with digital fashion
Speaker 3:  Instead of a regular stylist where he's working with the brands and finding
Speaker 3:  the right clothes that match the right jewelry.
Speaker 3:  Tom is getting those assets from the
Speaker 3:  digital fashion companies.
Speaker 1:  This is the dumbest thing to have just thought of. But there's the moment
Speaker 1:  in Clueless where she's standing there looking at her closet.
Speaker 10:  I mean, I get up, I brush my teeth and
Speaker 3:  I pick out my skull clothes
Speaker 1:  And she basically scrolls through all of the
Speaker 1:  available different clothes, find something that's gonna match, and then
Speaker 1:  basically hits a button and her closet spins until it finds the right stuff.
Speaker 1:  She pulls it off and puts it on. And I feel like you're describing that exact
Speaker 1:  process, but it all happens digitally. Yeah. For a virtual influencer.
Speaker 3:  And then someone in the metaverse could buy that
Speaker 3:  digital clothing item using cryptocurrency
Speaker 3:  and put it on their avatar. Oh wow. Or they could just buy it
Speaker 3:  to have it like an nft,
Speaker 8:  A person could buy a digital dress that
Speaker 8:  they can put on their avatar and they can also buy the
Speaker 8:  same physical dress so they can put, you know,
Speaker 8:  on their human self.
Speaker 3:  It just keeps going, you
Speaker 1:  Know? Yeah. Well and it kind of comes back to that same point, right? Where
Speaker 1:  if we are in a time where we treat these digital
Speaker 1:  things and these real world things the same. And if I'm being
Speaker 1:  totally honest, I, I am like deeply suspicious of the idea that people are
Speaker 1:  gonna gonna like care about their Metaverse Louis Vuitton jacket, the way
Speaker 1:  that they care about their real world Louis Vuitton jacket. But it does seem
Speaker 1:  like we're headed in some version of that direction. And if, if
Speaker 1:  the metaverse is gonna be a thing, if buying, you know, clothes in Fortnite
Speaker 1:  is gonna be a thing, like that's, that's where a lot of this is gonna head
Speaker 1:  in some way, shape or form.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. And Jennifer mentioned that too cuz she was like, my kids play Fortnite
Speaker 3:  all the time and they're always buying these skins. I think the skins are
Speaker 3:  like different costumes.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, they're, they're basically costumes.
Speaker 8:  Not everybody is gonna buy into it and that's okay. But there are people
Speaker 8:  that are gonna be engaged in the Metaverses no matter what they are. I
Speaker 8:  mean, my kids live on Fortnite and that really is in fact,
Speaker 8:  metaverse and the kids that this generation that's coming up, that's what
Speaker 8:  they know they can buy things with in Metaverse and they get sold
Speaker 8:  to in Fortnight all the time. So I think it's just
Speaker 8:  gonna continue happening.
Speaker 3:  And that's like actual cold money coming out of Jennifer's bank accounts.
Speaker 3:  So she's like, it is real. They are buying these things.
Speaker 1:  Yep.
Speaker 3:  Again, like you're right, who's gonna buy a $3,000
Speaker 3:  Louis Vuitton bag that's digital. I'm not really sure,
Speaker 3:  but it's not as crazy an idea as maybe it
Speaker 3:  sounds.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, I I think that's exactly right. And speaking of the expense of this
Speaker 1:  all, one of the things you're making me think of with this process is this
Speaker 1:  feels like it's such new behavior that it might be both
Speaker 1:  like more efficient and way less efficient. Like what does this cost? Do
Speaker 1:  you have a sense, if I wanted to do a virtual photo shoot or a real life
Speaker 1:  photo shoot, is it the same price? Is it more one way or the other?
Speaker 3:  I think it definitely depends on the digital character you're using. Like
Speaker 3:  she do, for example, is so intricate that she would be more
Speaker 3:  expensive than a human because then, you know, you're
Speaker 3:  working with a digital stylist and it takes all these different teams of
Speaker 3:  people to make that happen. So there are all kinds of ways
Speaker 3:  that you can make this even more expensive if you want
Speaker 3:  to.
Speaker 1:  And is it the same on the other end too? Like I, I feel like the, the big
Speaker 1:  sort of unasked question through all of this is like, does this stuff
Speaker 1:  work? Does it work more than having human models? Does it work less than
Speaker 1:  having human models but it's worth it for the other stuff? Like what, what
Speaker 1:  do you hear from these folks?
Speaker 3:  The difference is actually in the shock
Speaker 3:  value. It really is more about the novelty. It's about the
Speaker 3:  click factor. What Christopher and Jennifer both
Speaker 3:  explained is that if you want to
Speaker 3:  have a simple like person posing with
Speaker 3:  a product and you wanna generate foot traffic to that store or you wanna
Speaker 3:  sell that product, you're probably gonna go with a human
Speaker 3:  influencer.
Speaker 5:  If it's about those purposes, they're gonna filter that money down
Speaker 5:  into agencies who are capable of delivering foot traffic
Speaker 5:  and delivering app installs in a very scientific
Speaker 5:  way. You know, a tracked way, a very return on investment
Speaker 5:  mindset. However, often with virtual influencers, the
Speaker 5:  real spend they activate is on pr, on the backend.
Speaker 3:  Now journalists are gonna say, wow, did you know
Speaker 3:  she's not real? That's still so many years
Speaker 3:  later a huge story. Totally. It's just like a different kind of
Speaker 3:  advertising. It's still surprising. I don't know how long
Speaker 3:  that novelty can last. It's possible that it could wear
Speaker 3:  off, but it definitely right now seems to still
Speaker 3:  generate enough PR for it to be worth it for these brands to do
Speaker 3:  it because they are doing it. And like as we get into more animation
Speaker 3:  and more metaverses and video games kind
Speaker 3:  of merging with those spaces, it's possible that this will
Speaker 3:  become even more lucrative. And whether or not that's gonna happen
Speaker 3:  remains to be seen. Like a lot of the metaverse we don't really
Speaker 3:  know yet.
Speaker 1:  It also leads towards the kind of other questions of what
Speaker 1:  other kinds of digital influencers are there gonna be, right? Cause I feel
Speaker 1:  like we're at a moment now where everything, at least some of those you've
Speaker 1:  been talking about are very like human looking and it makes sense that that
Speaker 1:  would be a place we would start. But then I think about like the, remember
Speaker 1:  the dancing hotdog that Snapchat released a bunch of years ago that everybody
Speaker 1:  got really excited about? Like that's just a digital influencer that's like
Speaker 1:  one Instagram page away from making millions of dollars.
Speaker 3:  And when you say dancing hotdog, it's funny because I was going to bring
Speaker 3:  up an example of probably my favorite non-human virtual
Speaker 3:  influencer. Nobody sausage.
Speaker 1:  Oh my God. Is there another dancing hot dog?
Speaker 3:  Yes, there's another dancing hot dog.
Speaker 1:  This is the best news.
Speaker 3:  Maybe technically a sausage, not a hot dog. He doesn't have a bun. He's
Speaker 3:  just a hot dog by himself.
Speaker 1:  Oh yeah. I'm getting his TikTok page where he has 18.2 million
Speaker 1:  followers. Yes. I'm getting a lot of like claymation
Speaker 1:  kind of vibes here. He comes in many colors.
Speaker 3:  He kinda reminds me of Gumby a little bit, who is really good at
Speaker 3:  dancing and also does comedy sort of
Speaker 3:  videos where he's like falling on the ground. It's very
Speaker 3:  entertaining and people seem to love it.
Speaker 1:  That is really something. This now gets into a, a weird
Speaker 1:  mix of things where it's like, we used to have Tony the Tiger with Frost
Speaker 1:  Flakes. There was like Snap, crackle and Pop for the Rice Krispies are
Speaker 1:  virtual influencers, just the new brand mascots.
Speaker 1:  Can you sort of draw a straight line from one to the other?
Speaker 3:  So all of those characters are just mascots. But if
Speaker 3:  you put those characters on Instagram and then give
Speaker 3:  them a personality and a backstory, that's when they become
Speaker 3:  digital influencers. So for example, the Geico
Speaker 3:  Gecko actually does have an Instagram account. Of course
Speaker 3:  he talk and another one is
Speaker 3:  Barbie actually. So you know, we all know Barbie as the toy, but
Speaker 3:  kids would know Barbie as a 3D
Speaker 3:  character who has a personality and talks to them.
Speaker 3:  And Barbie on Instagram has 2 million followers.
Speaker 1:  Amazing. What does the like next five years of this look like, do you
Speaker 3:  Think? I think in terms of saying if this has staying power, a lot of
Speaker 3:  these companies are actually becoming very
Speaker 3:  profitable. So the Fabricant, which is one of the companies
Speaker 3:  that makes virtual fashion designs just raised 14 million in
Speaker 3:  investments to build the wardrobe of the
Speaker 3:  Metaverse and then sell those closes NFTs. Okay. And
Speaker 3:  bred the company that created little McKayla was recently
Speaker 3:  acquired by Dapper Loves, which is an NFT startup, and they
Speaker 3:  value bread at 125 million. Wow. So
Speaker 3:  these companies are actually making money
Speaker 3:  and have created a little mini
Speaker 3:  ecosystem that Cameron says, it's just gonna keep getting bigger.
Speaker 4:  I think this industry is growing exponentially and
Speaker 4:  every year it matures. It's kind of proving itself, it's sticking
Speaker 4:  around, it's, it's not just a fad anymore. It, I think we're gonna see
Speaker 4:  lots and lots more businesses being created in this
Speaker 4:  space. Lots of different job opportunities. I think we're gonna see a lot
Speaker 4:  more digital fashion houses, digital modeling agencies,
Speaker 4:  different characters, different avatars. So you really
Speaker 4:  have this growth coming from all directions. And I've seen
Speaker 4:  so, so many people becoming instantly successful and
Speaker 4:  and busy because these skills are so in demand.
Speaker 3:  They definitely believe that this is where the
Speaker 3:  world is going. Like in the next five years, 10 years,
Speaker 3:  the near future, we will be living more
Speaker 3:  in digital spaces. We will be living more in digital worlds. And the
Speaker 3:  line between real life and digital life is
Speaker 3:  going to be blurrier. We'll be able to interact with these characters
Speaker 3:  in the Metaverses and we're all gonna have our own avatars,
Speaker 3:  and that's where they feel the future is going. So I think
Speaker 3:  the creators of them are very aware of that. They're like, whatever
Speaker 3:  technology comes out, that's where we have to be. If the
Speaker 3:  metaverse is the thing that's cool, we gotta be in the metaverse. If people
Speaker 3:  wanna talk to us, we better animate. Like they have to keep
Speaker 3:  evolving to stay relevant and to stay desirable if they wanna keep
Speaker 3:  making money.
Speaker 1:  Another extremely human desire stay relevant
Speaker 1:  or the modeling industry forgets about you, I think is something a lot of
Speaker 1:  real humans can identify with. Eventually. This is coming
Speaker 1:  for us too. You and I are gonna be replaced by AI
Speaker 1:  versions of us who make podcasts together. Yeah, I'm actually okay with that,
Speaker 1:  even as I say it out loud. That sounds great. I'll just, I'll be around.
Speaker 1:  It's no problem. All right, Gina, thank you for exploring this deeply bizarre
Speaker 1:  world with us. This, this is incredibly fun.
Speaker 3:  Thank you so
Speaker 3:  much.