# Transcript
ID: 3f9a2c00-6726-11ed-b546-5d076f40ee00
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Meta Quest Pro review, Taylor Swift crashed Ticketmaster, and more
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-1268590563179435658/5633915829349884787/s93290-US-6276s-1668764825.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, David Piece, Alex Cranz, and Adi Robertson discuss the Meta Quest Pro review.
Later, the crew discuss Ticketmaster crashing after Taylor Swift fans try to buy concert tickets. Also: Elon Musk's Twitter saga continues and some weekly gadget news.
Speaker 2:  Today on the Vergecast MedQuest Pro, Ticketmaster, Elon
Speaker 2:  Musk. Mistakes were made. We'll get into all of it. That's all coming up
Speaker 2:  right after this.
Speaker 3:  Hello
Speaker 4:  And welcome to First Cast, the flagship podcast of the Ticketmaster
Speaker 4:  monopoly, which will crush your fucking spirit until you're
Speaker 4:  dead. Sorry, teenage girls. You're dead now.
Speaker 5:  And also Eli,
Speaker 4:  I got through man. Okay. I won. We're I, I assure you, we will talk about
Speaker 4:  Ticketmaster on this episode of the Verge Cast. There's it's software,
Speaker 4:  it's monopolies, there's a lack of competition and there's Tay
Speaker 4:  to the, it's the most verge cast keywords.
Speaker 6:  This is the most verge cast you can
Speaker 4:  Be. You can, yeah. You add 'em all up. That's the Verge cast.
Speaker 6:  Nothing more verge cast than Taylor
Speaker 4:  Swift. Competition issues and software on the major cultural figure. That's
Speaker 4:  our whole show. It's the whole show. All she needs is Bluetooth.
Speaker 6:  It's there. That's how you get the tickets.
Speaker 4:  What kind
Speaker 5:  Blue? What headphones do you think Taylor Swift listens to her own music
Speaker 5:  on?
Speaker 4:  Oh, that's a good
Speaker 6:  Question. She
Speaker 6:  doesn't,
Speaker 6:  she like, and if she does, she has a very nice audio system. She
Speaker 6:  has other people like play.
Speaker 5:  No, see I go straight to like Wired EarPods. Just like buy, buy a
Speaker 5:  fancy coffee and walk down the street with your wired EarPods listening to
Speaker 5:  your new album. Like that's, that's,
Speaker 6:  Well that's what she would wear like in the Diet Coke commercial. Remember
Speaker 6:  that one? That would always play in the movies. Yes, exactly. She got singing
Speaker 6:  to herself. Yeah. Always wear the wired ones. That's right. Yeah, that's
Speaker 4:  True. Okay, well two things. I forgot. Thoughts, two
Speaker 4:  things. One, there was the phenomenon of Ah, girl
Speaker 4:  wired EarPods. Yeah. Took place over last summer. That was the whole thing.
Speaker 4:  I could see her fitting into that. Yeah. Second unrelated, my favorite Bruno
Speaker 4:  Mar's fact in the entire world is that he masters all
Speaker 4:  of his records in an old Cadillac Escalade that he leaves parked in
Speaker 4:  his driveway. Yes. Just cuz he says that's where his music sounds the most
Speaker 4:  amazing, incredible. And I, it is a great, it's a rolling stone profile.
Speaker 4:  Bruno March from ages ago. He just has it. He doesn't go anywhere. He's
Speaker 4:  like, this slate is where the magic happens. You
Speaker 6:  Spent 10,000 on your speaker. Stupid.
Speaker 4:  Like if it doesn't sound good in the slate, it doesn't sound good. I have
Speaker 4:  to imagine Taylor has a similar superstitious
Speaker 4:  audio situation
Speaker 6:  And it's the EarPods.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, she's got like a pair
Speaker 6:  Wired, sorry, EarPods like
Speaker 4:  Wired EarPods. She's got a pair that was like old cost headphones with like
Speaker 4:  the, you know, the foam is getting all rotted out. Like those are her special
Speaker 4:  ones that everything sounds good on. Yeah. Yeah. Like she's bringing that
Speaker 4:  to the national guy Studio being like, I need to plug these in. They're porta
Speaker 4:  pros. Like I feel it. That's just my theory. If you know,
Speaker 4:  I would, I'm dying to know. Cuz it can't just be airplanes.
Speaker 6:  What if she burns it to a CD and plays it on her old
Speaker 6:  Discman?
Speaker 4:  Oh that's like her thing. Her thing. If it doesn't,
Speaker 6:  Cause she's from that era, so she's like, okay, I gotta put it on my Discman
Speaker 6:  that I've had since 2000. See how I sound?
Speaker 6:  I sound great. Ship it. We're done here.
Speaker 4:  How do we always end up talking about burning optical media with you? It
Speaker 4:  has I on the show. It's
Speaker 6:  So often.
Speaker 4:  All right. Hi, it's the Verest. I'm your friend Eli. That's Alex Kranz.
Speaker 6:  Hi. I'm your friend that's really sorry. Reckless Patel has been quiet this
Speaker 6:  week. He's trying to get those T Swift tickets.
Speaker 4:  I if only my clone. I can't wait to talk about this experience. David Pierce
Speaker 4:  is here.
Speaker 5:  Hi. I have no interest in Taylor Swift tickets. I'm
Speaker 4:  Over Robertson joining us. Hi. You okay David? When
Speaker 4:  I first, when I knew you as a young man, you cared about Taylor Swift tickets
Speaker 4:  more than any other young man
Speaker 5:  That I, oh, I still do. There was, there was a day at the Verge office where
Speaker 5:  I had fully half of the
Speaker 5:  staff online just to
Speaker 5:  buy me Taylor Swift tickets, which is how I know I was early to Taylor
Speaker 5:  Swift because this was before everyone else was online buying Taylor Swift
Speaker 5:  tickets. No, if I wasn't about to have a child and thus never
Speaker 5:  going out to do anything fun ever again for the rest of my life, as far as
Speaker 5:  I can tell, I would've been in the Ticketmaster offices yelling at them about
Speaker 5:  Taylor Swift this week. Like that Just bring
Speaker 6:  The baby.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, the shows are on like June.
Speaker 5:  It'll like be in college by then.
Speaker 4:  You leave the kid home alone by June. It'll
Speaker 6:  Be fine.
Speaker 4:  All right. There is a lot to talk about. We will return to the subject of
Speaker 4:  Taylor Swift. I assure you, Ticketmaster just put out an explainer blog post.
Speaker 4:  It starts with we knew people would wanna buy these tickets, which
Speaker 4:  is, I feel like if you are trying to explain your behavior, starting
Speaker 4:  with, we were aware of the problem that we made.
Speaker 4:  You're already on your back foot. But we have been teasing
Speaker 4:  our Meta Quest Pro review for weeks on the show. In many
Speaker 4:  ways the written review is up on the website. You should read it. Abby
Speaker 4:  did a great job writing that review the video review, I think
Speaker 4:  next week, early next week. It's, it's like coming. It's
Speaker 4:  a hard edit is what I would say. Yeah. Because it takes place not
Speaker 4:  only in reality but also the metaverse
Speaker 7:  Virtual reality.
Speaker 4:  Virtual reality, which is not a
Speaker 4:  predictable, stable or even an easy to
Speaker 4:  enter environment in any way, shape or form. Right.
Speaker 4:  Like just logging into the metaverse. Very challenging at a,
Speaker 4:  I mean this is like the crux of your review is like this software is
Speaker 4:  horrible.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. It's the thing that really disappoints me is that meta is
Speaker 7:  typically really, really good at software because it takes software in
Speaker 7:  earlier generations to mean games and it's really good at buying
Speaker 7:  games. And then yeah, you come out with this thing, this thing is all about
Speaker 7:  Horizon. It's metaverse platform and it's, it's miserable.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. So let's start, let's actually start with the Quest two cuz you
Speaker 4:  mentioned games. The Quest two is basically a games console. It
Speaker 4:  is an, I think Meta itself has referred to it as an Nintendo Switch
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 7:  For your face.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, it's, it's a, it's a midrange Android phone for your face and it is
Speaker 4:  very much geared around, it's an appliance, it's a game console. You put
Speaker 4:  it on, you pick a game, you play the game, you're done.
Speaker 7:  Right. There are people who don't use it that way, but if you get it then
Speaker 7:  they have this thing just ready for you to go. Which is like, Hey, do you
Speaker 7:  wanna play Beat Saver?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And and they have bought up most of the popular games and
Speaker 4:  apps on the Quest two. Like all of them, all of them they are under
Speaker 4:  FTC review for buying within the company Makes Supernatural. Right? Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And by the way, meam put out their answer to that lawsuit this
Speaker 4:  week. I mean I dunno if you listen to Phil Spencer onco this week, but
Speaker 4:  like any company that is in the middle of a competitor review starts just
Speaker 4:  self-flagellating itself with how much they suck. So Phil Spencer's onco,
Speaker 4:  he is like, we suck at video games. Sure. We're in certain place.
Speaker 4:  Okay, we're horrible at, no one likes us in mobile crap
Speaker 4:  garbage. I'm a bad like the whole thing cuz they wanna buy activation
Speaker 4:  Meta is in this FTC review, put out their answer to the
Speaker 4:  FTCs complaint and they're like, we've never made a successful VR software
Speaker 4:  product ever. We've had to buy them all. I mean
Speaker 7:  Not, it's not wrong. Very true. Yeah. That's both self
Speaker 7:  mean. You probably cut VR out of that and it was still most
Speaker 7:  transformative.
Speaker 4:  It's just a very funny legal document. They're like, we should be allowed
Speaker 4:  to buy this company because we actually can't do it on our own.
Speaker 4:  So this would be cool if we could buy the successful company. But
Speaker 4:  the question to a, I think you share this opinion with me is a great
Speaker 4:  product. It's self-contained. It was until
Speaker 4:  recently relatively inexpensive. It over
Speaker 4:  delivers on the core promise, which is you will experience virtual
Speaker 4:  reality in a convenient self-contained way
Speaker 4:  and you'll mostly have a good time.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. I think it, it compensates that there are things that VR
Speaker 7:  headsets still just, they're always gonna be kind of heavy. They're always
Speaker 7:  gonna be kind of bulky. There are still just things that we haven't figured
Speaker 7:  out with them, but they do a very good job of trying to streamline those
Speaker 7:  things and emphasizing the positives
Speaker 4:  Of it. Yeah. So I just wanna start there. That's the foundation
Speaker 4:  for this conversation is the Quest two me's second
Speaker 4:  mainstream VR headset. Right. Is a good product that like
Speaker 4:  over delivers.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. But also one, one thing Addie just said that like is is a, I think
Speaker 5:  a useful construct for me. Even like I just went back and reread your review
Speaker 5:  and now what you just said makes a lot of this make a ton of sense to me.
Speaker 5:  Which is like the quest is a thing you like put on use for a few minutes
Speaker 5:  and then take off and it's like even the games are very short. Like all the
Speaker 5:  bad reviews of the games in the Quest store are people being like, this is
Speaker 5:  super fun and it costs me $19 and it ended after 25 minutes.
Speaker 5:  And like that's perfectly fair criticism. But it's also like this is not
Speaker 5:  a thing you're meant to wear for hours at a time. It's like put it on, do
Speaker 5:  your 30 minute workout, take it off, go do something else. Like it is, it's
Speaker 5:  a, it's an episodic thing.
Speaker 7:  Although ironically I've spent way more time in single sessions with the
Speaker 7:  Quest two than I have been able to in the Quest Pro, which is one of my problems.
Speaker 5:  Fair. Yeah. Okay, let's get into that.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, so I just want to start there. It's not that I, I don't think any of
Speaker 4:  us think virtual reality is a hopelessly broken concept. I don't think that
Speaker 4:  this is like dumb to chase after. Yeah. There's an example from meta of
Speaker 4:  a successful product that over delivers, especially for its previous
Speaker 4:  price, right? The Quest Pro is supposed to do far,
Speaker 4:  far more than that quest to, right? Like the entire premise
Speaker 4:  is you're gonna wear it all day at work.
Speaker 7:  I mean I hesitate to say what the entire premise is because I am still
Speaker 7:  convinced that Meta doesn't know what the premise is and they just had to
Speaker 7:  come up with a pitch and the pitch they came up with Yes. Is that you're
Speaker 7:  gonna have meetings in this thing, you're gonna wear it for all for
Speaker 7:  using, I don't know, Microsoft Office. Yes. Yeah. It's
Speaker 7:  supposed to be the professional, the computer that you use. It's like a
Speaker 7:  laptop
Speaker 4:  Especially cuz it's, it's priced like a laptop at 1499
Speaker 4:  before you even add the full white blocker, which
Speaker 4:  I think is absolutely needed on this. So the first thing I would say by the
Speaker 4:  Quest two is the hardware when you pull outta the box is physically
Speaker 4:  far superior to the Quest two. Yeah. Right. It it is just
Speaker 4:  a nicer thing until you try to use it and then it is
Speaker 4:  immediately revealed to be a much worse thing.
Speaker 7:  Oh I think it sneaks up on you. Yeah, I think those first, my first half
Speaker 7:  hour when I wear it I'm like, oh this is nice. It's so much more convenient
Speaker 7:  to put on like it doesn't have this overhead strap that's really like
Speaker 7:  bad. It's really nice that I can see outside because it has, you know,
Speaker 7:  less light blocking and then like it just, it
Speaker 7:  devolves. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Yeah
Speaker 6:  Because that was your complaint, right? Both of you is is that it doesn't
Speaker 6:  block the light on the sides and so you're seeing a lot more of the world.
Speaker 6:  So your, your brain is basically like, what is reality
Speaker 6:  vomit?
Speaker 4:  Well so it, it depends. Okay. And I, this is where
Speaker 4:  this I to agree with Addie, they didn't decide what it was
Speaker 4:  for. So it's trying to be several things. Okay. So if
Speaker 4:  you wanna use it as a VR headset
Speaker 4:  out of the box, this thing will make you vomit because of the light
Speaker 4:  issue. Right. Because the wings it comes with to block the light aren't on
Speaker 4:  by default. So you'd put it on and like do VR stuff in that without the wings.
Speaker 4:  Cause
Speaker 6:  The wings are additional they cost
Speaker 4:  No, no the wings come in the box but they're like magnetic. Magnetic.
Speaker 7:  No, the wings are included. There is a separate thing that you can buy that's
Speaker 7:  $50 that blocks out even more light. Okay.
Speaker 5:  Can you just explain to me how this feels on your face? Because I, I have
Speaker 5:  now read your review a bunch of times and talked to you both about it and
Speaker 5:  I still cannot get a mental image of why on earth you would put this thing
Speaker 5:  on and they're like, look, it's a headset but you can also
Speaker 5:  have peripheral vision. Like is this like leaky light? Is it like
Speaker 5:  you can
Speaker 4:  See No, so this is, it's there's a big gap. Look at pictures of it.
Speaker 4:  Like pictures of ADDIE in it or picture their own marketing materials. There
Speaker 4:  are two rubber wings that can magnetically attached to the side
Speaker 4:  that will block out your peripheral vision. Okay. They are not always on.
Speaker 4:  You are meant to take them off. You can take them off and many of the marketing
Speaker 4:  materials, they're not there. That's for I think when you're trying to do
Speaker 4:  the mixed reality stuff. Right, right. When you're, when you're doing
Speaker 4:  augmented reality and you're looking through a video
Speaker 4:  feed in the headset and you're looking at the world around you and like basically
Speaker 4:  the only demo that works is now you're a DJ and it's like man
Speaker 4:  I did this in my twenties. Oh look it's just me
Speaker 4:  DJing to no one just like my twenties. Right. Like
Speaker 4:  that's like the mixed reality. Yeah. So you want the light cuz you're
Speaker 4:  in your environment. Okay. So you want your peripheral vision a little bit
Speaker 4:  cuz you're in the mixed reality world. You're in the room
Speaker 4:  that you're in. Right. Which
Speaker 5:  Is where the pass through video also comes in. So you're like okay I get
Speaker 4:  It. Right. And then you can put the wings on. I'm not sure what
Speaker 4:  for
Speaker 7:  This is like a real, the wings are actually completely adequate. I think
Speaker 7:  the wings. The wings stop me from having motion sickness. They're perfect.
Speaker 4:  Okay. So that, so maybe that's for some people it's fine for me. You put
Speaker 4:  the wings on, you try to do VR stuff and I just like got sick and I think
Speaker 4:  that the pancake lenses which make the thing thinner
Speaker 4:  are harder to look through than the Fresno lenses on the Quest two.
Speaker 7:  Do you have to like relax your eyes as like magic eye?
Speaker 4:  It's not like magic. There's just something weird about just unsettling.
Speaker 4:  It's just unsettling. Like I, I just, I, it's less comfortable.
Speaker 7:  I've heard from people who, who actually say the opposite who say like
Speaker 7:  this thing is so much better. I like the way that it has this sort of depth
Speaker 7:  of field but that kind of makes me ultimately think it is subjective.
Speaker 7:  That it is not like this is this necessarily incredible leap
Speaker 7:  forward for everyone. And I think that still just resolution. It's not, you
Speaker 7:  know, metas fault here. Resolution is hard but it is not a huge leap in
Speaker 7:  resolution.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And I, again, I'm someone who like works
Speaker 4:  out in supernatural consistently. So I, I spend a lot of time
Speaker 4:  in E Quest two. So I put this thing on, I was expecting a leap. Yeah. And
Speaker 4:  instead it was just like inherently more uncomfortable and you can put the
Speaker 4:  full face blocker on and then adding, I both had this experience
Speaker 4:  where it wants to all this eye tracking and has a camera for your
Speaker 4:  face. It wants to help you adjust it to look good and there's
Speaker 4:  a little dial on the top. Oh no, that's like move the
Speaker 4:  spacing of the lenses to match your eyes. And the Quest two, it's just fixed
Speaker 7:  To be clear not the problem. And then no it also it move adjusts the distance
Speaker 7:  for your eyes. You, you wanna adjust the spacing you have to reach inside
Speaker 7:  it and press them together physically. Which is not,
Speaker 6:  Which is your thing. Ary
Speaker 4:  Your pd, your pary distance. So in the Quest two there's like three to tens,
Speaker 4:  you get three choices. The Quest pros like 500 choices. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  There's lots of little stops and you have to reach up up through your nose
Speaker 4:  and like bonk it around and it the whole time it's like farther, closer,
Speaker 4:  farther and it's like I hate you. Then you can adjust the,
Speaker 7:  It does it every time I launch an app. It's just, I understand you were trying
Speaker 7:  to give me the optimal experience. I am never going to get that experience.
Speaker 4:  And then there's the depth of the lenses from your eyes, which is the wheel,
Speaker 4:  which is the wheel on top and it just doesn't believe
Speaker 4:  that you have reached the farthest point of the wheel. It's like keep going,
Speaker 4:  keep going to the left. And both Addie and I had the same reaction which
Speaker 4:  was like shut up mark. It's all the way to the left. Like it's, it's
Speaker 4:  so annoying.
Speaker 6:  Well you guys have 2020 vision, like no absolutely not.
Speaker 6:  No add Right? So you guys are like wearing contacts. I'm wearing
Speaker 7:  Contacts. Yeah. No I just, I have one eye that works at the house. Good
Speaker 7:  vision and one eye that's like 20, 40, 20 60 and I compensate.
Speaker 4:  I'm a cyborg.
Speaker 7:  No I just live with it.
Speaker 6:  I do wonder if that's part of it because you know they were saying if you
Speaker 6:  wear glasses you're gonna have to go get special lenses for it to see through
Speaker 6:  it or you're gonna have to go for context. And I think there's a lot of stuff
Speaker 6:  here oriented towards perfect vision. Perfect.
Speaker 4:  There's a lot of stuff here that's oriented towards I think
Speaker 4:  describe the Quest two as compensating. Yeah. The Quest two is an
Speaker 4:  average experience. Yes. Everyone has the same level of average
Speaker 4:  experience. Right? Like you put the thing on you cv, there's dinosaur
Speaker 4:  great grandma screamed, everyone got their views on YouTube today we're moving
Speaker 4:  on. Right. This thing is trying to make you have a great experience. So
Speaker 4:  it actually has all these more fine adjustments for you in your eyes. And
Speaker 4:  it is measuring things and and all of that is,
Speaker 7:  Although it's most of its adjustments are doing things that other headsets
Speaker 7:  have done. It's value add is that it will like it will
Speaker 7:  detect where things are and it will tell you how to adjust it. Which I'm
Speaker 7:  convinced that the reason it has all these annoying things is because it's
Speaker 7:  gonna do that automatically in the next generation. That they've filed patents
Speaker 7:  that do automatic like inter pupillary distance adjustments. So I think this
Speaker 7:  is a midpoint but it's an annoying midpoint.
Speaker 6:  Is it like clippy? Like is that the level of annoyance? No.
Speaker 4:  At least Clippy had your best interest trying. Yeah this is very much like
Speaker 4:  I need you to stop talking Mark. It's as far to the left as it can
Speaker 4:  go. Stop it, stop it right now
Speaker 5:  The the middle point thing seems right to me cuz like this seems like
Speaker 5:  directionally clearly the right thing for meta to be trying to do because
Speaker 5:  the whole, you're never gonna get to a point where it just one idea
Speaker 5:  works for everybody And I think the, you can either do the sort of lowest
Speaker 5:  denominator thing, which is gonna make some large portion of people
Speaker 5:  physically ill because VR is cool and fun like that. Or you can
Speaker 5:  eventually build towards this thing where it, there is a magical solution
Speaker 5:  for everybody and I'm super suspicious of the idea that a lot of dials
Speaker 5:  and knobs is the right answer. But maybe someday in the future if it
Speaker 5:  does work automatically that
Speaker 4:  Feels, feels like a good answer. I'm just saying we've paid $1,500 and we
Speaker 4:  we're 15 minutes into this conversation. We haven't even finished putting
Speaker 4:  it on. Right. Like it is just,
Speaker 4:  we're already deeply annoyed at the thing that costs $1,500.
Speaker 4:  This is supposed to be the future of all computing and human experience And
Speaker 4:  I'm like I can't turn this dial anymore to the left than it is.
Speaker 7:  I would also just like to add it puts all my weight on my forehead on like
Speaker 7:  a one inch strip and look again, GR headset
Speaker 7:  straps often they kind of suck. This is just, it's bad in a
Speaker 7:  really specific way that makes it really hard for me to wear.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And it's supposed to be more balanced. Well
Speaker 6:  It's bad in that it's $1,500. Cause I did see some like complaints
Speaker 6:  being like well you could just go get another strap and it's like for
Speaker 6:  $1,500 I should not have to buy additional things to make this
Speaker 6:  thing usable. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Just so just like out the gate that pro, that's the problem that
Speaker 4:  sneaks up on you. I've worn this thing for a while. I'm a little bit more
Speaker 4:  nauseous than I was in the other one and my forehead hurts.
Speaker 4:  Great. Like this is the future of work
Speaker 6:  Supernatural.
Speaker 4:  Right? Like that's all bad. Then I think Addie has mentioned the
Speaker 4:  display resolution several times. I was just not impressed by it. It
Speaker 4:  has a wider, a wider field of view but it actually,
Speaker 7:  I don't actually even think it has a significantly wider field of view. Looking
Speaker 7:  up the numbers. The numbers are relatively similar.
Speaker 6:  You see, you still see pixels, right? Like you still see
Speaker 4:  Everyone and not to call anyone out but Meta did a lot of
Speaker 4:  influencer stuff where they did the ar, everyone has three screens on a
Speaker 4:  monitor looking through the lens. That's great. That's what influencer marketing
Speaker 4:  is for. And then you actually try it and you're like, oh these three screens
Speaker 4:  are six 40 by 40. Like there's not enough pixels here to play the game.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Because
Speaker 6:  You have to go like way, way, way, way, way, way, way higher than
Speaker 6:  you actually think you do because you're not just being like resolution,
Speaker 6:  you have to be like resolution under little magnifying
Speaker 6:  glasses because that's what makes this vr. Yeah that's just, yeah I
Speaker 6:  was, I was always kind of,
Speaker 4:  It's all grainy and there's a little
Speaker 7:  Text is just, it's hard. Like I guess I maybe dark mode
Speaker 7:  would help but I still just don't even think it really does. And I also should
Speaker 7:  not have to activate dark mode to like read things on
Speaker 7:  Google.
Speaker 4:  Right. Like you bring up a browser window and what you're gonna see is that
Speaker 4:  the border of the window is gonna have, you know that like old school anti
Speaker 4:  Alia thing? Yeah. It's marching shimmer. Ooh.
Speaker 4:  It's all over the place. Gross. And then the text and the browser window
Speaker 4:  is like not very high resolution And
Speaker 6:  Do all your spreadsheets in this.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. So like just from the jump like this basic thing, I'm gonna
Speaker 4:  put this on and I'm gonna have three screens for my laptop, which is what
Speaker 4:  they marketed. I have no, no, absolutely not. I can't think
Speaker 4:  of a reason. I wanted
Speaker 7:  To, if you were already, if you have to use VR for your job and you
Speaker 7:  have like a workflow then this is not materially worse. But it's
Speaker 7:  also if you do not use VR for your job, you should not do this. Do not do
Speaker 7:  this. It is not a good experience.
Speaker 4:  Okay. So that's just putting it on and using it like they want you to.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. None of that's good. And I think the Quest two is superior. Okay. Then
Speaker 4:  there's Horizon which also runs in Quest two, which is just
Speaker 4:  an unmitigated disaster. And the worst part,
Speaker 7:  Let's be specific about which Horizon we're talking about. It is a cornucopia
Speaker 7:  of bad,
Speaker 4:  There's Horizon Work Rooms which is the like
Speaker 4:  conferencing solution. Yeah. And there's Horizon Worlds, which is
Speaker 4:  like the hangout and play games and be cool with your friends one. Right.
Speaker 7:  Sure. Be cool. It's basically roadblocks by
Speaker 7:  Facebook.
Speaker 4:  What I can,
Speaker 7:  And this is probably being flipping, this is the best way to describe it
Speaker 7:  from what I can tell, I was like that seems to explain everything in
Speaker 4:  My No Minds around the corner to buy Roblox by Facebook.
Speaker 4:  No one could for tell. So we tried work rooms and the big
Speaker 4:  feature here is it does the face tracking so you can see expressions. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  This was basically a disaster from the jump. Like even just trying to
Speaker 4:  get into work
Speaker 7:  Groups is bad. Like
Speaker 4:  I don't know how to, it's we couldn't make it, first of
Speaker 4:  all we just like couldn't make it work. Like why is this video delayed
Speaker 4:  for so long? It's just days of frustration
Speaker 4:  like transpire. I'm
Speaker 7:  Just at ease review. It's
Speaker 4:  Bad. I mean this is some of the worst software that I've ever used.
Speaker 5:  This part is so surprising to me cuz like Horizon Worlds is like a very hard
Speaker 5:  thing to get right. It's like a, a persistent space that you have to get
Speaker 5:  a lot of people in and find fun interesting things to do with them.
Speaker 5:  Horizon work rooms is is conference rooms for your
Speaker 5:  avatars where no one has legs. This is like not hard
Speaker 7:  Software.
Speaker 4:  This is like,
Speaker 5:  Like the idea of how to make this work is so, so,
Speaker 5:  so straightforward And it's kind of amazing to me that they seem to
Speaker 5:  have botched it as badly as it seems like they did.
Speaker 7:  It's just that they spread this thing out across desktop and
Speaker 7:  VR in the most confusing way possible while
Speaker 7:  not taking advantage of, you know, the social networking thing that they
Speaker 7:  have been pushing into VR headsets for like three years.
Speaker 7:  Like you, so you, The entire thing is virtual
Speaker 7:  rooms that you go and meet in. You can't create a meeting in vr.
Speaker 7:  What? Like unless you hook up a separate computer and then
Speaker 7:  go into a browser and then log through this login system. I still don't know
Speaker 7:  what it attaches to what account I put in email address. It seems to work.
Speaker 7:  And then you invite people through email and then maybe they
Speaker 7:  get an invite if you hook it up to a calendar and then they click a link
Speaker 7:  and then ideally they get into the meeting
Speaker 7:  unless they don't get into the meeting.
Speaker 4:  I just wanna point out that the way you're supposed to do this, it's true
Speaker 4:  you're supposed to do all this in computer. You are supposed to install
Speaker 4:  screen mirroring software on your laptop. Oh
Speaker 7:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  It sends your screen into the headset and then the cameras and
Speaker 4:  the headset are supposed to detect your laptop and put a
Speaker 4:  VR keyboard where your keyboard would be.
Speaker 7:  Did that happen?
Speaker 4:  No, because they have not, they don't yet support
Speaker 4:  this 16 inch.
Speaker 6:  So did you like take the wing off and just kinda like look out the side of
Speaker 6:  your eye to type?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. You kind of look under your nose, you know,
Speaker 7:  Finally all my mava speak and paid off. I can touch time.
Speaker 5:  This means at some point there was a meeting where somebody was like, we
Speaker 5:  made a prototype where you're in a workroom and you can just hit a button
Speaker 5:  that says invite people and then you can invite them by their phone numbers
Speaker 5:  or their meta accounts or just have a link that you can share with people.
Speaker 5:  And somebody presumably Mark Zuckerberg goes no they have to install
Speaker 5:  companion software on their
Speaker 5:  laptop
Speaker 7:  And like the companion software, the idea is a lot of it is you have this
Speaker 7:  private workroom and you can do your three screens thing, which we obviously
Speaker 7:  have our own problems with. But it is bizarre to me that you cannot
Speaker 7:  just like log into a meeting and like go
Speaker 7:  into the metaverse on your headset. There's just not any reason to have to
Speaker 7:  use a desktop for that.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. So like say Addie, you start the
Speaker 6:  meeting, you want Eli to come to the meeting and he's in there
Speaker 6:  doing supernatural. He's having a great time. No,
Speaker 4:  No that's a different app.
Speaker 6:  But But you, so you won't get like a notification being like add wants
Speaker 6:  meeting time.
Speaker 4:  There is that stuff at the base layer of the Quest headset.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. You can see if your, it's a game console. You can see if your friends
Speaker 4:  are online. It is not And this is like a very verest thing to say.
Speaker 4:  It is not a
Speaker 6:  Computer. Yeah. But like right now, if I put on the supernatural,
Speaker 6:  I have it paired. So like if I get a slack in the middle
Speaker 6:  of my workout, I can be like, oh I should pause this and go do that. You're
Speaker 5:  A monster. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  What like whatever, whatever. What?
Speaker 6:  But I can do
Speaker 4:  That is monstrous. Just
Speaker 6:  Focus.
Speaker 7:  If you're getting email, be in the zone. In theory it's
Speaker 4:  Free. You know what I mean?
Speaker 6:  Gotta get in that zone five.
Speaker 7:  It's just, just like this is not how you imagine a thing works. Like this
Speaker 7:  is not how you imagine a service from a company that is entirely known for
Speaker 7:  connecting people.
Speaker 4:  Right. Let just describe our first attempt to meet in her husband.
Speaker 4:  Okay. I was at home at was at her house. He I believe
Speaker 4:  was at his house. Yeah. He may have been in our office.
Speaker 6:  He was actually in the Twitter bathroom waiting for the next
Speaker 4:  Office. I'm like, I'm getting in this meeting. I sent add a link. No one
Speaker 4:  got in the meeting. That's just what happened. And so we were just
Speaker 4:  like talking like no one nothing's working.
Speaker 7:  Technically I got into the meeting several times, just not very far.
Speaker 7:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Addie entered a meeting at one point and her avatar was just stuck in a
Speaker 4:  wall. Just stuck in a wall. I got into a different meeting
Speaker 4:  stuck into a different wall. That's it. That was our first
Speaker 4:  five hours of screwing with Horizon work rooms just stuck in
Speaker 7:  The corner. We had to get Alex Heath into a meeting
Speaker 4:  Together. It's true. So then we try again. Alex is like, I'm gonna join the
Speaker 4:  meeting. He's just like, I'm not in this meeting. The frustration level coming
Speaker 4:  through Slack, which has been screen mirrored into VR for me
Speaker 4:  is like I'm not in the meeting. Did you guys start without me? I want to
Speaker 4:  be in this meeting.
Speaker 6:  Where is
Speaker 4:  Everybody? Patty and I are just like sitting at a table Vera and our video
Speaker 4:  director is like on Zoom and not on Zoom like on a video conference and we're
Speaker 4:  just like waving our arms at each other.
Speaker 6:  So he's a real person. The jealousy looking down at your
Speaker 7:  Cartoons.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Cuz you can, people can video conference in the jealousy. I felt looking
Speaker 4:  at Veen who was a fully rendered human being, he's got
Speaker 4:  legs in control of his emotions and what his face looked
Speaker 4:  like was off the charts because adding and I are just like, are you winking?
Speaker 4:  Cuz it looks like you're winking the cameras. It
Speaker 7:  Seems to think my eyes are half closed all the time. I can't
Speaker 6:  Figure it out.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I'm like outta your asleep, you're, you just look asleep every time
Speaker 4:  I look at you, you look mad or asleep or you're winking at me. Why?
Speaker 4:  And I was like, I don't trust what her face looks like so there's no way
Speaker 4:  I can trust what my face looks like. I am now just talking like my grandpa
Speaker 4:  just waving the hands around just, and then
Speaker 4:  I'm waving 'em so fast the headset loses track of them. At one point I
Speaker 4:  knocked into one of the controllers of my real desk and it was like, you're
Speaker 4:  holding controllers now. So then I had like weird outstretched broken
Speaker 4:  hands and I'm just like wave my hands and easy to find
Speaker 4:  my
Speaker 7:  Once that hand tracking has gotten quite good. I don't think that the hand
Speaker 7:  tracking, I did not have materially better results. But like in general just
Speaker 7:  meta's hand tracking has gotten quite good.
Speaker 6:  Better than less.
Speaker 4:  I mean it just didn't like me so I was like, okay so we have our little meeting.
Speaker 4:  You can see part of it in the video. It's not the idea that we're all
Speaker 4:  gonna meet together in that space and have more empathy for each other.
Speaker 6:  Well Veen lords over you. Perfectly ready.
Speaker 4:  Jealous. The only thing I felt that Ven was a real boy and not a cartoon
Speaker 4:  was so mess
Speaker 6:  He had arms.
Speaker 7:  And let me tell you, it is hard to make people jealous of video conferencing.
Speaker 7:  Yes.
Speaker 5:  But that's the thing. Like I just can't get past this idea that like if you
Speaker 5:  want to have a video conference with someone in a meta product, there are
Speaker 5:  100,000 ways inside of meta products to
Speaker 5:  talk to someone on video. And they just decided that this one, which is
Speaker 5:  the one that they essentially care the most about and are making you buy
Speaker 5:  specialized hardware for is just a, the heaping pile of garbage. It's like
Speaker 5:  great
Speaker 4:  Job. I mean it's so bad.
Speaker 7:  And all I can figure is that they need this to work with, I don't know, a
Speaker 7:  bunch of enterprise software and it's gonna, eventually it's gonna hook into
Speaker 7:  teams and Zoom. But A, that's not like I, that's not there yet. And
Speaker 7:  B I just don't see how it gets better when you hook it into even
Speaker 7:  more software.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And I promise the Zoom integration that just doesn't exist.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It's just like you're like how do I integrate? And it's like nothing.
Speaker 4:  There's press releases. Sure.
Speaker 5:  This is all really validating my like overarching thesis about the Quest
Speaker 5:  Pro, which is that Meta absolutely did not make it to be an enterprise device
Speaker 5:  and then made it and it sucked. And they were like, okay, no actual person
Speaker 5:  is gonna buy this. Can we get it? People to buy it so that their companies
Speaker 5:  think they're cool maybe. And then it became an enterprise device,
Speaker 7:  Which is what makes me kind of mad because if they had actually been
Speaker 7:  honest enough to just say this is not for most people to like use as
Speaker 7:  a computer. This is for businesses that want to do business things and then
Speaker 7:  they scrapped all of the meta e stuff. Like you don't have to create a dumb
Speaker 7:  meta account to use it. You can just use it like you can use an HTC headset,
Speaker 7:  it's a piece of hardware. If they sold it as hardware, I would be much more
Speaker 7:  positive on it. They're just trying to create this like
Speaker 7:  suite and trying to sell it to people who do not have a
Speaker 7:  preexisting need for a VR headset. And it's really frustrating, right?
Speaker 5:  It's like the, the thing Google did with Google Glass is like, I think exactly
Speaker 5:  what you're talking about. Where they were just like, here's like a small
Speaker 5:  handful of things that this thing does. It's great if you like wanna see
Speaker 5:  an instruction manual while you're working on a thing. It's like there are
Speaker 5:  a small number of things that enterprise VR is like good and real and useful
Speaker 5:  for. And if you just lean into that, that's fine. But
Speaker 5:  meta instead was like, this is the future of everything. This is
Speaker 5:  a glimpse at the Metaverse that we're betting billions of dollars on. And
Speaker 5:  also none of it works
Speaker 6:  When you spend billions of dollars.
Speaker 4:  10, 10 billion,
Speaker 6:  10 billion,
Speaker 4:  10 billion
Speaker 6:  And you know that you're not actually gonna make money for at least 10
Speaker 6:  years. You gotta, you gotta do something.
Speaker 4:  He's not getting fired. I wanna, I wanna wrap, I wanna come to that at the
Speaker 4:  end of this. Okay. Cause we are not yet through the experience, oh sorry.
Speaker 4:  I agree with Addie that if they were just like, here's our interim
Speaker 4:  point of a high-end headset, it's more of a developer kit situation.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. But they, I think Zuckerberg had needed to show
Speaker 4:  something for the name change for the massive amount of dollars.
Speaker 4:  Right? Like this is the thing, he's betting his entire
Speaker 4:  reputation on the Metaverse and he can't be like another year of the
Speaker 4:  Quest two. They're
Speaker 7:  Also just, they're obsessed with locking people into an ecosystem that
Speaker 7:  they're, they want to own the next iOS. And so they can't just offer
Speaker 7:  this as enterprise hardware the way that Google did with glass or the way
Speaker 7:  that hey HTC does. Yeah. With its headsets. Like they have to
Speaker 7:  own this whole software ecosystem and they're bad at software like this.
Speaker 7:  You
Speaker 4:  Know how Meta has never successfully made a VR app by itself? Well they actually,
Speaker 4:  or aware of this meta. It's helpful. Tell the court Can I just,
Speaker 4:  we this is like we're concluding, right? These are the wrap up thoughts but
Speaker 4:  no, no point out. We have not yet talked about Horizon
Speaker 4:  worlds at all. Which is just
Speaker 4:  another kind of disaster. Like another
Speaker 4:  creeping body horror disaster that can befall
Speaker 4:  you.
Speaker 7:  So mind experience was delightfully surreal.
Speaker 7:  I hear it wasn't actually that, but I don't know. Cause that wasn't my experience
Speaker 7:  cuz I have no idea how this system
Speaker 4:  Works. All right. So he can't get in any of our meetings by
Speaker 4:  the way, the idea that you would, I host entire broadcast about decisions.
Speaker 4:  If your CEO is like, I made this decision in a VR
Speaker 4:  workspace, you're run from that company, don't work there. Just get out.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Just be like, you know what Elon, I'm not, I'm not coming to the office
Speaker 4:  somehow I'm not hardcore enough for this joint. Like, get outta there so
Speaker 4:  he can't get into this meeting. So like, all right, let's go in Horizon Worlds.
Speaker 4:  Maybe the corporate network block Horizon Worlds, by the way, our corporate
Speaker 4:  network not blocking the consumer playtime
Speaker 4:  vr but blocking the conferencing solution is a
Speaker 4:  perfect encapsulation of corporate networking seems scammy. So we click the
Speaker 4:  button, we drop into Horizon worlds. We're we're trying to like go to Addie's
Speaker 4:  house.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. I have a house in this scenario.
Speaker 4:  She, she has a house in the Metaverse. It's very nice. It's full of shapes.
Speaker 7:  It's full of shapes.
Speaker 4:  Just endless shapes. There's a dark board and then there's for some reason
Speaker 4:  there's a shooting gallery on the
Speaker 4:  balcony.
Speaker 7:  On the balcony.
Speaker 4:  It's a very confusing, it's, you know, daddy that
Speaker 4:  was like, what do I want in my house shooting range? Of
Speaker 4:  course
Speaker 7:  Not incorrect.
Speaker 4:  Confusing. Anyway, so that is Mark Zuckerberg's entire bet. I'm the future
Speaker 4:  of his company and his reputation. Look, I, there's a great piece in the
Speaker 4:  New York Times by Cashmere Hill who's a great reporter about the people who
Speaker 4:  spend all kinds of days of their lives in horizon worlds and they
Speaker 4:  love it and they sleep with the headsets on plugged into the wall.
Speaker 4:  It's, it's very much the matrix. They're just brains and vats. But they love
Speaker 4:  it. And you know what? It's America. Do you wanna be a brain in a va?
Speaker 4:  God speed. I hope your crypto investments panel,
Speaker 7:  This is where we get to like, the problem is meta. Like there are
Speaker 7:  services that do this similar, a thing like this and people love it.
Speaker 7:  There is VR chat, there is Roblox, there is, I mean Fortnite, depending on
Speaker 7:  how you define it, it's that meta is in a lot of ways just uniquely bad
Speaker 7:  at trying to get people to the places where they would have fun.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I I just like you started out by saying this, they don't know
Speaker 4:  what this thing is for. So it's not designed to make you have
Speaker 4:  one good experience. It was designed to prove the point that Meta has
Speaker 4:  spent a lot of money making a headset
Speaker 7:  Just here it is. And
Speaker 5:  I think if we had come out of this and it was like, okay, the software
Speaker 5:  sucks. The, the, the thing sucks, but like some of the new
Speaker 5:  tech that meta put into here, like face tracking and the improved
Speaker 5:  pass through and it's like if, if we, if there was some semblance of progress
Speaker 5:  here that it was like we're not even close to there yet, which I don't think
Speaker 5:  any of us thought we would be, but at least were in a useful or interesting
Speaker 5:  direction. I would at least feel like, okay this is like a deeply
Speaker 5:  hilarious failure, but at least is like some small step in the right direction.
Speaker 5:  But it, it even seems like all of the tech that they built that in
Speaker 5:  in theory should have at least been like a good demo isn't like the fact
Speaker 5:  that the face tracking doesn't really seem to work at all in any sort of
Speaker 5:  meaningful useful way to me is way more damning than like any of the rest
Speaker 5:  of this for the Quest Pro.
Speaker 4:  Oh. But we should mention the video pass through is very grainy. Like
Speaker 4:  it's not usable all
Speaker 5:  The time. Yeah. If you can't read texts, you have nothing. Like
Speaker 4:  I'm, when you turn on the cameras and you're passing through reality so
Speaker 4:  you're doing like fake augmented reality. Yeah. It's is it like, it's like
Speaker 4:  unusually grainy.
Speaker 7:  Is it the same as the Quest two? Cause the Quest two is like super grainy
Speaker 4:  And the Quest two is black and white. So this is basically that color.
Speaker 5:  Oh cool. That's not better. It's like,
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I mean it's just like there's a part of me and I can't, you know, there's
Speaker 4:  two ways to look at this. One, if this is the absolute state of the art,
Speaker 4:  then Apple is not releasing a product for five years. Yeah. Right? Like
Speaker 4:  if this is the absolute state of the art, there's no way that Apple releases
Speaker 4:  a product like this. It is just not ready. Even if the software is great,
Speaker 4:  the thing the hardware can do where they're passing through the video pasture
Speaker 4:  part of it, they're five years away or Apple is way better and they've
Speaker 4:  been hinting that they're gonna do it just to troll Facebook into releasing
Speaker 4:  this thing. Right? Like I, I can't tell. But
Speaker 4:  if this is the state of the art, there's no way that app, the Apple that
Speaker 4:  we know is anywhere close to releasing a product. Cuz there's, it's not good
Speaker 4:  enough to be a consumer product, especially at this price point. And I I
Speaker 4:  think you're right. Like the, the Quest two is a superior product to this.
Speaker 4:  If you wanna like play around in vr, even if you wanna do like the thing
Speaker 4:  where you have two or three screens off your laptop. Yeah. Quest two is better
Speaker 4:  because you'll get close enough to the same experience
Speaker 6:  For a fraction of the price for
Speaker 4:  A fraction. And the Quest three they already said is command next year. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  So it'll probably be cheap too.
Speaker 5:  That is super damning cuz that means meta is not making
Speaker 5:  quick, real, meaningful progress towards this thing that it's
Speaker 5:  claims is right around the corner. Like that's if, if things have not gotten
Speaker 5:  better since the Quest two, that is scary news for Meta and the whole idea
Speaker 5:  of the metaverse.
Speaker 6:  Well I think there's like a lot of technological challenges
Speaker 6:  that are just holding this back. There's the displays, there's
Speaker 6:  the cameras that can do all the spatial stuff while also being able to be
Speaker 6:  good at pass through. There's just a lot of stuff where it's like where,
Speaker 6:  you know, has anybody actually solved this problem even in like
Speaker 6:  a lab somewhere? Are there actually really good ones cameras out there
Speaker 6:  that can do the spatial audio and do the good pass through? Well
Speaker 4:  You use most of the products in the market. You've seen Facebook's next
Speaker 4:  generation tech for control. I mean is anyone ready
Speaker 4:  Control
Speaker 7:  Labs? Yeah, I, the thing that I'm mainly curious about how third party
Speaker 7:  developers are going to use this because I think that the tracking cameras,
Speaker 7:  it is possible a lot of like the face tracking, it's possible. A lot of the
Speaker 7:  shortcomings there are software related, right? That there are things
Speaker 7:  where, you know, six months down the line they release an update and
Speaker 7:  suddenly it gets way better and they release, they have a like API
Speaker 7:  that's accessible enough that this gets into VR chat, which is in a lot of
Speaker 7:  ways much more sophisticated than Horizon worlds that you have all of these
Speaker 7:  potential breakthroughs that I really, the thing I'm still
Speaker 7:  really, I think that the pass through is not viable
Speaker 7:  as a good product, but the face tracking I think has a lot of potential and
Speaker 7:  could be really interesting. And I'm very disappointed that they did not
Speaker 7:  find a good showcase for it. And I think it speaks badly of them that they
Speaker 7:  did not like communicate with developers in a way that would have something
Speaker 7:  ready.
Speaker 4:  Even the, the main thing that should
Speaker 4:  be helpful to everyone, which is Foviated
Speaker 4:  rendering where they dere the parts of the display
Speaker 4:  that you're not looking at and put all of the GPU power into the part of
Speaker 4:  the display where you are looking. Yeah. Which is a very cool idea, right?
Speaker 4:  Like next generation sci-fi level idea. Like how do we
Speaker 4:  get the most out of GPU in a super
Speaker 4:  constrained mobile package? Yeah. We figure out where your eyes are and we
Speaker 4:  put more polygons there basically. That's just a cool idea. Doesn't seem
Speaker 4:  to be doing anything. There's, I think, but one game that uses it. Addie,
Speaker 7:  I haven't gotten an official confirmation from Meta on it, but there we know
Speaker 7:  there is a game.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 7:  So yeah,
Speaker 4:  It's like a game. Even like the core promise of the thing is like
Speaker 4:  not happening. Yeah. Right. That you're gonna get higher. Well
Speaker 7:  Cause this isn't for games that they're like, they're just not trying to
Speaker 7:  get developers, game developers onto this.
Speaker 5:  I mean it's, it's for nothing is where it lands basically, right? Like this
Speaker 5:  is, this is for nothing.
Speaker 7:  I think that there are probably cases where this works really well for people
Speaker 7:  with extremely specific needs in the enterprise VR space. Like if
Speaker 7:  you have a thing and you really want to do a particular kind of fo rendering
Speaker 7:  or you really wanna do a certain kind of mixed reality or you just really
Speaker 7:  need a, I don't know, a high resolution
Speaker 7:  ish headset that you can wear that's pretty mobile. Like I
Speaker 7:  don't necessarily think that this is a bad choice, but I am also not convinced
Speaker 7:  that it has any really amazing use cases that make
Speaker 7:  it a must buy over the competition there.
Speaker 4:  And again, the competition is their own headset.
Speaker 7:  The competition is also things like the HTC five focus three.
Speaker 7:  Like there's vaio this company that does actually have just incredible
Speaker 7:  resolution in the primary eye area. Like there are other enterprise
Speaker 7:  headsets. And I mean I am have no doubt that there are
Speaker 7:  areas where this is definitely the best choice. It does not seem obvious
Speaker 7:  to me that it's the best choice. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Well it's on sale. We'll see how people do. My,
Speaker 4:  my i I keep thinking like a 1920s
Speaker 4:  newspaper whenever we think about summing this up and I'm like, it's Zuckerberg's
Speaker 4:  Foley. Like, like he staked his reputation
Speaker 4:  on this idea and this is as far as he's gotten.
Speaker 4:  Yes. And I, if I were meta, I would've kept
Speaker 4:  this one in the lab. Like fundamentally I would've been like, we're working
Speaker 4:  on some stuff. We've read some great demos, quest three's coming, we're gonna
Speaker 4:  have the, you know, they they, some of the stuff they did right, they had
Speaker 4:  influencers and reporters come in and put on the headset and be on rails
Speaker 4:  for 10 minutes. And you don't quite realize like you can't turn the knob
Speaker 4:  all the way, like in a very controlled environment, this thing feels great
Speaker 4:  and then the second it encounters reality, it just falls apart.
Speaker 4:  And like I think they had to show it. I think they had to release something
Speaker 4:  to prove that all this investment was worth something. Especially as they're
Speaker 4:  laying off 11,000 people and the cuts are not
Speaker 4:  focused on reality labs. They're everywhere. I think they had to have,
Speaker 7:  Although they have apparently canceled their smartwatches, which is really
Speaker 7:  disappointing to me.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. They canceled the portal devices and the smart watches that hadn't
Speaker 4:  come out. So what they got left is this headset and I like,
Speaker 4:  ooh. I dunno. It's, it's something. It's
Speaker 4:  something else. The video comes out next week. All right, we gotta take a
Speaker 4:  break. Addie, thank you so much. Yeah. When we come back, we gotta talk about
Speaker 4:  Elon. We gotta talk about Taylor Swift, Chris Gadgets. There's much more
Speaker 4:  chance coming. We'll
Speaker 4:  grab
Speaker 4:  Okay, we're back now to talk about the two biggest celebrities on the
Speaker 4:  planet. Elon Musk and Taylor Swift. Who I think vibe wise, my God,
Speaker 5:  That's, wait, hold on.
Speaker 6:  I don't like that.
Speaker 5:  That's true. Isn't it? Like at this moment in our world, that
Speaker 5:  is literally true.
Speaker 6:  I hate it. That
Speaker 5:  Sucks.
Speaker 4:  Well, 50% sucks. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  50% of what
Speaker 6:  I'm fine with. Like Jillian Anderson's just out there and y'all are just
Speaker 6:  calling her trash. This is terrible.
Speaker 4:  I'm sorry. There's not a world in which Jill Anderson, it's a bigger celebrity
Speaker 4:  than I
Speaker 6:  Somebody called her the lady from X five. So upsetting where
Speaker 4:  That curve goes up and down.
Speaker 6:  Oh yeah, no, she was definitely 1990, like eight. It
Speaker 6:  was Jillian Anderson. Taylor Swift was in like seventh
Speaker 6:  grade. She wasn't famous.
Speaker 4:  The Y axis on that scale is deeply, I want, you
Speaker 5:  Know, that's, that's an Apple chart right
Speaker 4:  There, right? We're gonna start with Elon or Taylor.
Speaker 6:  Let's talk about Taylor. I wanna talk about T Swift. Let's
Speaker 5:  Do Taylor. Okay,
Speaker 4:  So Taylor Swift, American recording artist, famous. Have you heard of
Speaker 4:  Scooter bro?
Speaker 6:  She will destroy him.
Speaker 4:  Scooter bro, by the way, invited himself on Koder and then uninvited himself
Speaker 4:  from
Speaker 6:  Well he saw, he was like, whoa, whoa, whoa. How much does he, how much does
Speaker 6:  he Swift? Does he listen to? No, nevermind. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  It was not gonna happen. Anyway, Taylor is on tour, the ERAS tour.
Speaker 4:  She hasn't been on tour in three years. Lots of people want to go to
Speaker 4:  this
Speaker 6:  Show. She's gotta bang her new album out. Yeah. People wanna see you sing.
Speaker 4:  People excited. I have a niece and nephew who are seniors in high school.
Speaker 4:  The show in Chicago is the day before they graduate. One of the shows the
Speaker 4:  day before high school graduates my sister. And I'm like, all right, this
Speaker 4:  is a graduation. We're gonna do this. It's gonna be fun. I bought the, I
Speaker 4:  bought midnights on vinyl is I want to do, oh my god, physical
Speaker 4:  media.
Speaker 6:  It's great.
Speaker 4:  I want it. I have it. Burn it. My niece
Speaker 4:  bought it on vinyl two, she bought all the, I mean she's like hardcore fan.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, she did not get the verified fan.
Speaker 6:  That's
Speaker 4:  The only way. And she's like on a class trip, she's not even home. So my
Speaker 4:  sister and my brother-in-law were like designated to buy the tickets. Okay.
Speaker 4:  But they got wait listed. I got in. So like everyone's already
Speaker 4:  kind of mad. So
Speaker 6:  Wait, wait. But you had to be verified, right?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, but I bought the, I mean I purchased from Ticketmaster before and then
Speaker 4:  I signed, I was instructed to sign up for the pre-sale. So
Speaker 6:  You were verified Taylor Swift fan.
Speaker 4:  And I had purchased the record. Yeah. So I got the Boost. I was
Speaker 4:  verified. You're ready? I was like in it. Yeah. They were on the wait
Speaker 4:  list.
Speaker 6:  Sucks.
Speaker 4:  I was in it. Everyone like already everyone's like sort of irritated at me,
Speaker 4:  right? Like all of our hopes and dreams are on me and I'm like, do do like
Speaker 4:  right
Speaker 6:  With your bad internet.
Speaker 4:  Well I'm bad internet in the woods. I'm looking at my calendar and I got
Speaker 4:  you. You gotta show up on the website a half an hour on
Speaker 4:  ticketmaster.com at half an hour to enter a waiting room and the waiting
Speaker 4:  room will dump you into the queue and all this stuff. And I'm thinking like
Speaker 4:  everyone in the world, well this will just be an ordinary software
Speaker 4:  experience that I have. Yeah. Or I push a button and something happens and
Speaker 4:  something happens and I push another button and it takes my credit card and
Speaker 4:  I've accomplished my task for the day. Yeah. And I'm looking at my calendar,
Speaker 4:  I'm like, oh this is gonna be weird cuz I'll be on the radio talking about
Speaker 4:  Elon Musk while all of this clicking is occurring. Oh no. And the other
Speaker 4:  guest on NPR at that time is Senator Ed
Speaker 4:  Markey. So it's me, the senator Taylor Swift
Speaker 4:  and Ticketmaster we're all just gonna do this at the same time. And I was
Speaker 4:  like, you know what, whatever it's npr. My mouth can
Speaker 4:  run about Elon and Autopilot. He's a politician. He won't shut up. Like
Speaker 4:  I'll be able to handle this. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  There was also like a 60% chance that Ed Mark was buying Taylor Swift Taylor.
Speaker 5:  Right? Like if you think about that moment, like he for sure had another
Speaker 6:  NPR host also do it.
Speaker 4:  So like everyone, no question. You know, go to buy the tickets.
Speaker 4:  We're all excited cuz I got waitlisted for the right day. There's like
Speaker 4:  a real chance cuz you had to tell 'em what shows you wanted. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Do you know how many layers deep into like weird, insane filters you are
Speaker 5:  right now. Like again, to go back to the Quest thing, we haven't even talked
Speaker 5:  about the buying tickets. This is all like the runup to the buying thing.
Speaker 4:  Like I'm like worried I'm gonna end up getting tickets for their actual
Speaker 4:  graduation. Yeah. And my family is gonna have to make a very important
Speaker 4:  decision.
Speaker 5:  You skip graduation, that's easy. Hundred
Speaker 4:  Percent. We're gonna skip graduate. We we got the right day, the day before
Speaker 4:  graduation. It's all good. So I'm like in line on the phone. I'm like First
Speaker 4:  amendment da stuff,
Speaker 6:  The knee stuff.
Speaker 4:  What you got listed to. I think I did a good job. I don't think you would
Speaker 4:  know that. I was like in a dead flop sweat looking at like Chrome. All this
Speaker 4:  was happening. The thing is just immediately a disaster crashing all over
Speaker 4:  the place, it drops you in the queue. The Q says 2000 plus queue in Chicago
Speaker 4:  does not move for hours. Oh. Meanwhile, all their queues are moving. Other
Speaker 4:  people are getting booted. People are just lying all over the internet. Like,
Speaker 4:  I got in the queue. There's no tickets left. All of you should drop out.
Speaker 4:  Like
Speaker 6:  I would do that.
Speaker 4:  And like various big tech engineers are making chrome extensions to
Speaker 4:  show you your actual place in the queue
Speaker 6:  In like live. Live. That's incredible
Speaker 4:  Because in the, in the page source, there's actually the number of people
Speaker 4:  in front of you. Oh. So like I'm watching ticks of
Speaker 4:  like teenage Taylor Swift fans. It's like, here's what you do. You
Speaker 6:  Ed Mark is just,
Speaker 4:  You hit view source, you scroll down to line two 20 of the source code
Speaker 4:  and then it will show you the key of how many people are in front of you.
Speaker 4:  It's using to render the thing. And I'm like doing all this
Speaker 6:  Radio Ed's just over there being like, yeah. Government.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. So the queue's not moving. AOCs tweeting, Ticketmaster of
Speaker 4:  Monopoly. This is all bad. Six and a half hours
Speaker 4:  later. The Chicago queue moves.
Speaker 6:  You were on the radio for so long. Long.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I was only radio for now. I canceled like all of my meetings. Like
Speaker 4:  many of my meetings. I have most of my meetings on a Tuesday.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Can't today.
Speaker 4:  And I was just like openly telling people like I'm trying to buy Taylor Swift
Speaker 6:  Tickets and people Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Box media, the company that it is the team that we have. Everyone's like,
Speaker 4:  I understand that's a high priority,
Speaker 5:  But also this was like a, a cultural moment in that way. That it was like
Speaker 5:  everyone could have used that excuse on Tuesday. Right. It's like no matter
Speaker 5:  what you were doing or what your responsibilities were, if you were just
Speaker 5:  like, ah, Taylor Swift tickets, everything would've been like, I understand.
Speaker 5:  Please let me know if I can assist you in any way. Yeah. It's like we were
Speaker 5:  all united in fighting Ticketmaster that day. I
Speaker 6:  Was in more than one meeting where somebody was like, I'm here. I'm paying
Speaker 6:  attention, but I'm also trying to buy Taylor Swift
Speaker 4:  Tickets. Yeah. I was in those
Speaker 5:  All. Yeah. Which means I'm not here and I'm not paying attention.
Speaker 4:  I wasn't at my regular computer. I was at the, cause I was on the radio.
Speaker 4:  I was my podcasting setup. So
Speaker 6:  Like for like 2015,
Speaker 4:  It's just like everything was, I was on my 2015
Speaker 4:  iac. The whole thing is ridiculous
Speaker 4:  to finally come through. It's six o'clock at night, it lets me through and
Speaker 4:  it immediately crashes and puts me back with queue. This happens three times.
Speaker 4:  I would, so now it's 6 45.
Speaker 5:  So it gives you the page that it's like you have tickets, do you wanna buy
Speaker 5:  them? And you say yes. And it says, just kidding. Back in
Speaker 4:  Dumps you. So then you finally get it. Oh my God. And it's, it's Ticketmaster.
Speaker 4:  So you're looking at it like a picture of Soldier Field and it's
Speaker 4:  like, and then here's the part that again, I got through, I managed my tickets.
Speaker 4:  I feel very lucky. I'm gonna complain about the process of winning.
Speaker 4:  Just like, bear with me.
Speaker 6:  It's fine.
Speaker 4:  This is the worst fucking video game I have ever played in my entire
Speaker 4:  life. Cuz they're just lighting up seats on
Speaker 4:  a giant picture of Soldier Field and then they're fading out
Speaker 6:  And you have to decide.
Speaker 4:  So you have to, it's like, I need six tickets. I need them all together.
Speaker 4:  There's like clumps of two, two and four everywhere. There's packages. All
Speaker 4:  the tickets are being like bought by the 17,000 other people that are
Speaker 4:  trying to buy tickets. Yeah. And you're like, okay, I'm gonna hit refresh.
Speaker 4:  The sections around where I wanna sit are lit up. I'm gonna double click
Speaker 4:  on those and it's gonna zoom very slowly. And while the
Speaker 4:  zooming is happening, sold out, I'm gonna wash the seats
Speaker 4:  that have been available. Disappear. Mm. So then it was,
Speaker 4:  I'm gonna refresh. Okay. I'm only gonna zoom halfway. Yeah. I have one
Speaker 4:  of those Logitech mice where you can undo the wheel tens and you can smooth
Speaker 4:  scroll. So I, I'm gonna figure out how to roll it exactly
Speaker 4:  halfway. And so I get click targets. They're not huge,
Speaker 4:  they're just some click targets. Yeah. And then I'm gonna try to
Speaker 4:  click six times as fast as I can. When I say it's the worst
Speaker 4:  video game ever made, like I did this for a
Speaker 4:  half an hour. Oh my God. The whole time I was like, this is so stupid. You
Speaker 4:  know, I want six tickets, like dinner's ready. You know how much I'm willing
Speaker 4:  to pay. Just like it's a computer.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  They just,
Speaker 5:  Instead you're playing like scroll wheel arbitrage.
Speaker 4:  Just like find six tickets near each other that with
Speaker 4:  this total number. Yeah. And then be like, these are your tickets. And I'd
Speaker 4:  be like, thank you sir. No. And instead it's like, here's what you're gonna
Speaker 4:  do. You're gonna refresh a picture of a stadium. Some parts of the stadium
Speaker 4:  will be blue. You're gonna try to scroll in on the zoom on the blue parts
Speaker 4:  to find little orange circles with stars in them. Then click on six of
Speaker 4:  those. If you don't click on all six at once, someone can take them from
Speaker 4:  you. Then you have to start over half an hour. Get all the way
Speaker 6:  Through. You're not good at
Speaker 5:  This game. This sounds like a Mario Party mini game that I would've like
Speaker 5:  hated on the nten season.
Speaker 4:  It was the worst video game I've ever played. I called my sister in the middle
Speaker 4:  of this and I was like, I'm gonna cry. And she's like, are you in? I'm like,
Speaker 4:  I'm in. But it's worrisome. This isn't even over yet. There's actually,
Speaker 4:  there's one more layer of software chaos. Okay. I get in, I get the six tickets,
Speaker 4:  they're in the cart, they're not all together. I got four and two. Feel great.
Speaker 4:  Hit the button, save payment information. Put in the three
Speaker 4:  digit CVV on the card. Yeah. Doesn't go
Speaker 4:  through. What the fuck? Try it again. Doesn't go through what the
Speaker 4:  fuck. Enter the card over again. Start from scratch, put the card in.
Speaker 4:  Doesn't go through. You've tried to pay with this card too many times. Dumps
Speaker 4:  me back out. This is real thing happened right as it dumps me back out. I
Speaker 4:  get a text message for my credit card fraud alert. Were you trying to hold
Speaker 4:  tickets from ticket? I was like, yes. I literally wrote,
Speaker 4:  yes. Fuck you back. And it was
Speaker 4:  like, go ahead and try again. I was like, no I can't. Did it all again. Play
Speaker 4:  the video game for another four or five minutes. Got the tickets in the end,
Speaker 4:  played the video. I was good at the video game the second time around. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  You know how you're like playing old school Mario and you like, you kinda
Speaker 6:  Suck and then you get
Speaker 4:  Into it, you kind of suck and like, I dunno if this is ever happened to you,
Speaker 4:  it was happening when I was a kid. Like there would be like a power blip
Speaker 4:  or the game would crash right at the end and you're like, I've gotta do it
Speaker 4:  again. And then the second time you'd be really good at it. Yeah. Is that
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Perfect. All intended. Actually, Ticketmaster,
Speaker 4:  That's like finally at seven 30, I played the video games paid with a different
Speaker 4:  credit card. Okay. Sent my sister a Victoria screenshot and she, she called
Speaker 4:  me and she was like, how do you feel? And I was like, I hate you. Like this
Speaker 4:  has been one of the worst days of my
Speaker 5:  Life. That was literally your day. Like that
Speaker 4:  Was what I did that day.
Speaker 5:  Oh my God.
Speaker 4:  Now the parts of this, right? And I've seen other ticket
Speaker 4:  vendors, like there are ways to do this better,
Speaker 4:  but it does not create the cultural moments that all the artists
Speaker 4:  want. Right? You want Ticketmaster to crash. That is a sign of
Speaker 4:  success. You want there to be more demand than you have sales for.
Speaker 6:  You want all your customers furious,
Speaker 4:  Right? You want, you want, in some cases you want the secondary market cuz
Speaker 4:  Ticketmaster owns the secondary market and they get a cut of all those. I
Speaker 6:  Mean that was like the whole thing with the PS five in the Xbox Series X.
Speaker 6:  Where it's like, okay, you want to be in the grind. I don't actually,
Speaker 6:  I hate the grind.
Speaker 5:  I mostly agree with that premise, but I think it turns on you
Speaker 5:  eventually. Right? And it's like it has clearly turned on Ticketmaster in
Speaker 5:  this moment, which we should talk about. But I think one of the interesting
Speaker 5:  things to me is when people do, and don't get mad
Speaker 5:  at the artists involved because there have been times where like this just
Speaker 5:  recently happened with Blink 180 2 where everybody got really mad at Blink
Speaker 5:  180 2 for charging like many hundreds of dollars for
Speaker 5:  basically every ticket to everyone of its concerts. And then that
Speaker 5:  became this whole story about actually how Ticketmaster dynamic pricing works,
Speaker 5:  which is more like airlines where it's, it's an all about supply and demand
Speaker 5:  and they essentially surge prices. So know everything is really expensive
Speaker 5:  so that they get the secondary market out of it. And it's like this whole
Speaker 5:  system sucks and is opaque and who we decide to be
Speaker 5:  mad at seems to vary kind of based on the day. And of course Taylor Swift
Speaker 5:  has never done anything wrong in her life. So we can't be mad Taylor Swift.
Speaker 4:  So it's starting to come for her, right? People are like, why you, you said
Speaker 4:  anything? Why mean you apologize? Why? Why are you excusing this
Speaker 4:  starting to come? But a lot of the early angers pointed Ticketmaster. Ticketmaster
Speaker 4:  did put out their explainer blog post today. By the way, they canceled the
Speaker 4:  actual public sale. So they said they sold that. Which is not, I mean
Speaker 5:  Literally Ticketmaster's whole excuse has been like, did you guys know that
Speaker 5:  Taylor Swift is this popular? And we're all like, yes, it's Taylor's like,
Speaker 5:  yeah, it's everything Ticketmaster has said is basically like, we
Speaker 5:  are bad at our jobs.
Speaker 4:  So the thing that's really just on the tech
Speaker 4:  level. So their whole thing was they were overwhelmed by demand. As they
Speaker 4:  was saying, they're expecting 1.5 million verified presale
Speaker 4:  people. They 14 million people show up and they got three and a half billion
Speaker 4:  requests. Okay. I believe you that that is
Speaker 4:  a crazy numbers more than you thought.
Speaker 5:  But that's also, even that itself is, is a technological failure on Ticketmaster's
Speaker 5:  part. Right? The fact that 14 million people needed to generate three and
Speaker 5:  a half billion requests to their servers to buy tickets is already a failure
Speaker 5:  of Ticketmaster's technology.
Speaker 4:  And there's like some bots there, but it's like, you know how many
Speaker 4:  people, because of how this all this whole system worked
Speaker 4:  where you have to be a verified fan and some people were on a wait list and
Speaker 4:  some people weren't. You know, the total number of people who are
Speaker 4:  eligible to buy tickets, those people should go into
Speaker 4:  a system that can manage that demand. And then
Speaker 4:  the other 12 and a half million people in
Speaker 4:  bots can go to a YouTube video or like whatever.
Speaker 4:  You can just send them somewhere else. That's the thing that does not
Speaker 4:  add up in this explanation, in this blog post and all these other things
Speaker 4:  they've said is somehow, even though we
Speaker 4:  were in control of gating this demand, we let through these other
Speaker 4:  12 and a half million people in bots who generated three and a half million
Speaker 4:  requests and then we sold out of tickets
Speaker 6:  And the other 2 million verified fans including your
Speaker 6:  sister on a wait list. On a wait list. So they didn't even like, so there's
Speaker 6:  like 14 million people being like, I'm gonna get in your sister's. Like I
Speaker 6:  can't.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. There's just a procedural step here that doesn't add up.
Speaker 4:  That's like you are not in control of your software and then you can zoom
Speaker 4:  that out. Right. So Ticketmasters owned by Live Nation actually the
Speaker 4:  chain of corporate ownership here is great Ticketmasters owned by Live Nation.
Speaker 4:  Okay. Which is Live Nation is the big concert promoter. They own a lot of
Speaker 4:  venues. They bought Ticketmaster in a deal that many people including AOC
Speaker 4:  and your friendly local podcast. So think should not have gone through because
Speaker 4:  of clear vertical merger. Now the now if
Speaker 4:  you want to play, if you're an artist, you wanna play in a city, you have
Speaker 4:  to like go deal with the mob. Yeah. Like they own the venues, they own the
Speaker 4:  ticketing. You're paying some money to this corporation. Totally
Speaker 6:  Vertically
Speaker 5:  Clear. They also Live Nation also manages a lot of artists like
Speaker 4:  Directly. Yeah. So we have 360, it's even
Speaker 5:  More like literally from from the building down to the person
Speaker 5:  working the building. They own every single part of the whole
Speaker 4:  Stack. 30% of Live Nation is owned by Liberty Media, which also owns
Speaker 4:  f1, which is great. Cool. I mean Liberty,
Speaker 4:  Liberty is a huge investor in Warner Brothers Discovery. It's just like,
Speaker 4:  it's just a big consolidated situation. Yeah. That's not to say that
Speaker 4:  Liberty CEO John alone is not kind of like a straight shoot and genius. He's
Speaker 4:  like, here's what I do. I buy everything and then I make money. I appreciate
Speaker 4:  that about him. But it's just this big stack of consolidation. Yeah. Taylor
Speaker 4:  Swift, not Live Nation artist Taylor Swift's tour is run
Speaker 4:  by aeg, which is the only, the other big monopoly they put on Coachella and
Speaker 4:  all this other stuff. And so Ticketmasters defenses, you all think we're
Speaker 4:  Monopoly, but even AEG chose Ticketmaster. Cause
Speaker 6:  You're all that
Speaker 4:  Exist can do it. And it's like Yeah, because anyone else who tries
Speaker 4:  is crushed by your monopoly. Yeah. Like that's the actual problem
Speaker 4:  here. No other ticket vendor can reach scale because they can't go
Speaker 4:  to Live Nation venues and they can't service Live Nation
Speaker 4:  artists. So everyone else is small. So when an artist at the scale of
Speaker 4:  Taylor Swift has to go buy this service, her
Speaker 4:  options on the market are risk it with companies that cannot operate at the
Speaker 4:  scale. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Or you Bob's ticket sales.
Speaker 4:  Right? It's like if your choice was AWS or your Plex
Speaker 4:  server, like those are Taylor's choices.
Speaker 6:  Come on Taylor, it's gonna be
Speaker 4:  Great. And like that's like the fundamental thing that people are talking
Speaker 4:  about here is because Live Nation owns Ticketmaster, no other ticketing service
Speaker 4:  can address those venues and achieve the appropriate scale. And Ticketmaster
Speaker 4:  is monopoly and they can concoct these like
Speaker 4:  ultimately unsatisfying explanations and that's all you
Speaker 4:  can do.
Speaker 6:  Well I think it's more than that too. It's also they don't have
Speaker 6:  to do a good job. They never have to do a good job
Speaker 6:  and they never have done a good job. Name. A time where Ticketmaster like
Speaker 6:  using Ticketmaster was a pleasant experience.
Speaker 4:  Okay. 1987. Were you high when I bought the
Speaker 4:  tickets from the back room of the Kohl's department store, which
Speaker 4:  had the Ticketmaster
Speaker 6:  Computer. That was, that was
Speaker 4:  It. That was it.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And then that
Speaker 4:  Was like a real thing. That was their, by the way that was innovation was
Speaker 4:  they put computers in like department stores around the country on
Speaker 4:  a
Speaker 6:  Proprie to
Speaker 4:  Master network.
Speaker 6:  You had to go to the stadium where it, it's being sold. And my sister
Speaker 6:  would do this like stand outside and wait a day or two in
Speaker 6:  advance and go through and do it. Kinda like when you go to buy a ps Yes.
Speaker 6:  Three.
Speaker 4:  Alex, are you just explaining how buying tickets
Speaker 6:  Works? You know what that's happening right now? We have young audience.
Speaker 6:  I appreciate that. We had like they're young verge vergecast people who are
Speaker 6:  like, what was it like before Papa?
Speaker 4:  Let's just zoom back. So the movie days are confused like a huge
Speaker 4:  plot. Like the plot of this movie is the next day they're gonna go buy tickets.
Speaker 6:  Yeah,
Speaker 4:  That is true. Yeah. It's, you don't think that that's the plot of the movie.
Speaker 4:  That's the plot of the movie, which is, is that they have to make it through
Speaker 4:  the night and not be so stoned they can't go buy tickets.
Speaker 6:  Which would be more fun getting really stone and
Speaker 6:  barely making it in time to buy your tickets by lining up or what You
Speaker 6:  did
Speaker 4:  The worst video game in American history. I'm gonna go with the other thing.
Speaker 4:  The movies seem bad, but, so there's like this middle ground. Yeah. This
Speaker 4:  is what I'm saying. There's a middle ground of you have to physically go
Speaker 4:  and buy tickets in the seventies with your friends. Yeah. Great. You
Speaker 4:  can
Speaker 6:  Do the computer and Kohl's,
Speaker 4:  Matthew McConaughey is there, right? Yeah. Then there's the eighties in
Speaker 4:  early nineties where Ticketmaster is like, here's what we're gonna do.
Speaker 4:  Sears is gonna sign up for a phone line. We're gonna give them a
Speaker 4:  20 BOD modem and a weird mainframe and train someone
Speaker 4:  to use it. And we're gonna consolidate ticketing on our, our client
Speaker 4:  server system. Yeah. This is legitimately the
Speaker 4:  Ticketmaster innovation. Right? They like built a weird
Speaker 4:  network on the phone lines, which by the way, the government broke up at
Speaker 4:  and t and required the phone companies to allow things to connect to their
Speaker 4:  phone lines. Just a side note, Carter phone decision, we think about it a
Speaker 4:  lot here at the Vercast enabled Ticketmaster to exist. Then they moved
Speaker 4:  that onto the internet, got rid of the, the checkout staff at Kohl's department
Speaker 4:  store
Speaker 6:  Don't need
Speaker 4:  'em. And they're like, you're gonna do it
Speaker 6:  Yourself Self checkout. Yes.
Speaker 4:  So the the thing they're doing is still this network, it just, you're doing
Speaker 4:  self checkout
Speaker 6:  And it
Speaker 4:  Sucks and it sucks. But they own, they still own the network. They still
Speaker 4:  control the venues and now they control the artists. And you would think
Speaker 4:  that any big company, the number of tweets I saw, our friend Mark has
Speaker 4:  tweeted Taylor should just start her own ticketing company. It's like,
Speaker 4:  yeah, now you're all the way at the point where it's like, oh, I could just
Speaker 4:  set up a server and
Speaker 6:  Run tickets. Oh, you get your PL server. Yeah. You also does tickets. Now
Speaker 4:  Here's, I don't know if you know this, an Invidia Shield, a single Invidia
Speaker 4:  shield can run all of Ticketmaster. It's true. Right? But what you
Speaker 4:  don't have is the, the four decades of venue contracts that you
Speaker 4:  need and four decades of being mobbed up in the music industry and then being
Speaker 4:  owned by Live Nation and then being owned by like on and on and on. So at
Speaker 4:  the end of the day, it's not, the technology has been commodified out, even
Speaker 4:  though that was a thing that enabled the business in the eighties. Now it's
Speaker 4:  just a bunch of contracts that you can't break through. Right.
Speaker 5:  We've talked, there are plenty of other ticketing platforms on the internet.
Speaker 5:  Like if, if you just wanna sell, like Taylor Swift could have gone to Event
Speaker 5:  Bright and been like, Hey, I'm gonna sell all my tickets through Event Bright.
Speaker 5:  Right. Like there's a million of these out there. It's just that none of
Speaker 5:  them can sell interesting tickets because of this actual monopoly that
Speaker 5:  exists. Right. It's like the only way to take down Ticketmaster is to build
Speaker 5:  a bunch of concert venues. Yeah. Like that's literally what
Speaker 4:  It's, and to sign Jays into a 360 deal. Right,
Speaker 5:  Exactly. And easy. Yeah. And so it's like you just, you can't,
Speaker 5:  you can't beat Ticketmaster without essentially taking on the entire live
Speaker 5:  music industry, which no one is able to do because
Speaker 5:  it's impossible at this moment in time.
Speaker 4:  We have a grand ideas for how to make a combination YouTube video deco
Speaker 4:  episode about this. So I'm gonna put a pin in this. We'll go back to it.
Speaker 4:  There's a great John Oliver segment about this. Also, you could just go back
Speaker 4:  to the nineties and watch Pearl Jam testify to Congress about the Ticketmaster
Speaker 4:  monopoly. That's a real thing you can do with your time while you're waiting
Speaker 4:  for your dealership tickets to No,
Speaker 5:  They're sold out. That's the video that Ticketmaster should have sent the
Speaker 5:  other 12 and a half million people to. That would've been a cool move.
Speaker 4:  All right. Let's quickly talk about Elon then. We'll take a break and we'll
Speaker 4:  we'll do a gadget. Sounds good. We'll do a gadget lightning round. Elon David,
Speaker 4:  what's going on?
Speaker 5:  So we're kind of out of the like brief,
Speaker 5:  bonkers, chaotic product phase and into the,
Speaker 5:  like Elon Musk blows up the org chart phase I would say. So I
Speaker 5:  think right around now as we're recording, this is the
Speaker 5:  set deadline for all Twitter employees to literally fill out a
Speaker 5:  form on the internet as far as I can tell that says either I am
Speaker 5:  committed to being, what was the, what was the quote? Extremely
Speaker 5:  hardcore in building the next phase of Twitter.
Speaker 5:  Or if you check yes, welcome to you know, hardcore Twitter if
Speaker 5:  you check. No, that is, you have resigned from the company. This
Speaker 5:  cannot possibly be legal. I am not a lawyer. I don't know anything this,
Speaker 5:  there's just no way that this is how any of this actually works. But, so
Speaker 5:  that's happening. He's like, he's very clearly trying to weed a lot of people
Speaker 5:  out of the company as fast as he possibly could, right? Yes. He's been firing
Speaker 5:  anyone who criticized him on Twitter. He's been firing people who criticized
Speaker 5:  him in Slack. He is out there saying he doesn't wanna be the CEO of
Speaker 5:  Twitter or any company, which is something he said before. I think he said
Speaker 5:  that during a deposition about Tesla. And so he's just now at this place
Speaker 5:  where he's like, okay Twitter blue. We rolled it out, it went horribly.
Speaker 5:  We're we're rolling it back. That's now set to come out November 29th.
Speaker 5:  And it's, it's very clear that he is in full like
Speaker 5:  burn Twitter the company to the ground and build it back up
Speaker 5:  face. And whether that's gonna be possible I think is the next thing to see.
Speaker 5:  But like that's the distinct vibe I get is that he's really, really hoping
Speaker 5:  a lot of people check no on that box tonight. Right.
Speaker 4:  Except too many people check. No already. Here's a problem. This, this is
Speaker 4:  happening while we've been recording. Oh wow. So the deadline is arriving.
Speaker 4:  There's a newsletter called the Pragmatic Engineer that's been reporting
Speaker 4:  on this that authorized Twitter account and he's been putting a lot of stuff
Speaker 4:  there. Basically like teams of 50 40 people are like,
Speaker 4:  I'll quit. So Elon is now holding
Speaker 4:  meetings where he is like it gets severance cause he
Speaker 4:  gets severance. Although the terms of the severance agreement are not,
Speaker 4:  they haven't been released. So you have to basically say I leave agree to
Speaker 4:  a contract that I haven't read, which is
Speaker 6:  I wouldn't
Speaker 4:  Do that, I wouldn't do that. They're already being sued over that. It's like
Speaker 4:  the lawsuit got filed while we were talking,
Speaker 5:  When he fired half the company two weeks ago, he promised severance that
Speaker 5:  at least as far as we've heard so far, has not yet materialized. So I think
Speaker 5:  there's a lot of reason to believe this is not up enough.
Speaker 4:  Right. So he is, he's already in labor lawsuit number one. But then too many
Speaker 4:  people are leaving. So he is asking to come back. He's already relaxed his
Speaker 4:  work from home rules. So initially he said you can either
Speaker 4:  work in this office or it's resignation accepted,
Speaker 6:  Got a lawsuit for that one,
Speaker 4:  Got a lawsuit for that one. Cause you have to have an office that's
Speaker 4:  inclusive and you have to make accessible
Speaker 6:  Accommodations for people who need it. And he's not,
Speaker 4:  Alex is a person who handles all this stuff on the ver
Speaker 4:  Can you tell the managing editor is a good manager?
Speaker 6:  Sorry,
Speaker 4:  There was a time when I knew this stuff, but now you don't have to
Speaker 4:  everybody it's great. Highly committed. He
Speaker 4:  hasn't made reasonable accommodations for people. He's relaxed the work from
Speaker 4:  home rules into this sort of ran
Speaker 4:  situation. Yeah. Where if your
Speaker 4:  manager vouches for you that you, you're
Speaker 4:  extraordinary, then you can work from home. He's cool man. And if they're
Speaker 4:  wrong, they're fired. And it's like, I would not
Speaker 4:  do that.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  It's just another bet I wouldn't make. Cuz who knows what the criteria
Speaker 4:  are and whether they will change.
Speaker 6:  What is the definition of cool man?
Speaker 4:  It's like also you've already fired half of
Speaker 4:  everyone. Why would I be like they're great. I'm putting my job
Speaker 4:  on the line for it when no one knows how you make decisions. Yeah. That's
Speaker 4:  another lawsuit that's waiting to come. And so he is having an all hands,
Speaker 4:  I believe right now the reason Alex Heath is not with us on this episode
Speaker 4:  is because there's an all hands happening while we record. Where he is basically
Speaker 4:  saying, please stay at Twitter. Even though I have asked most of you to leave
Speaker 4:  if you're not hardcore enough. Is that about the summary of
Speaker 5:  It? Yeah, that's about right. And this is, this is perfectly in keeping with
Speaker 5:  what the last several weeks have been like. Right? It's just like all the
Speaker 5:  Elon Musk era of Twitter has been, is just whipsawing back and forth between
Speaker 5:  these like grand proclamations and really quick shipping of something. Oh
Speaker 5:  God, that didn't work. We have to undo that. And then like 15 minutes
Speaker 5:  later some crazy grand proclamation slash new feature in a different direction.
Speaker 5:  Like this is what Blue was, this is what verification was. Remember the official
Speaker 5:  badge that was there and gone and there and gone and there and now I think
Speaker 5:  it's gone again.
Speaker 4:  The verge keeps getting the official badge and it keeps going away.
Speaker 5:  Like over and over. This keeps happening. It's like it, it honestly, honestly
Speaker 5:  is like the, the company is just absolutely spinning out of
Speaker 5:  control in all directions at all times now. And there has
Speaker 5:  been a lot of people saying essentially that this is on purpose.
Speaker 5:  That this is how you do a cultural reset and that he's trying to blow up
Speaker 5:  the company. And you've gotta figure that there's gonna come a time where
Speaker 5:  he looks around and goes, oh God, I need some employees. I keep thinking
Speaker 5:  about the thing he says about WhatsApp, right? Where he's like, WhatsApp
Speaker 5:  got to 2 billion users with 50 engineers. Like does he just want 50 people
Speaker 5:  to work at Twitter? Cause like he's well on the way to that,
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I think that's, that's the entire thing. You know, a lot of people
Speaker 6:  have been saying, oh he's gonna blow it up because he wants to blow up Twitter
Speaker 6:  because he's mad because he had to pay 54 or 20 a share for that. I
Speaker 5:  Don't believe in that for that. And I don't think that at all. I think the
Speaker 5:  idea that he's gonna destroy it out of spite I think is wrong. I
Speaker 6:  Just don't know that. Yeah. I think he is aggressively saying like, think
Speaker 6:  about it, his companies, he maybe didn't create those
Speaker 6:  companies. SpaceX and, and Tesla, even though he is
Speaker 6:  technically a founder, he didn't create those companies, but he created the
Speaker 6:  culture there and he created a culture that is very like, we work hard.
Speaker 6:  That's it. We just work hard. We go as hard as we can. Sometimes
Speaker 6:  sexual harassment happens and that is the price we pay for doing really cool
Speaker 6:  rocket ships and stuff. And Twitter is from a very different culture
Speaker 6:  of like, we care about our employees. We believe in work life balance. We
Speaker 6:  believe that like people shouldn't die just to make a weird app on the internet.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And, and so he has to reset that culture and he can either
Speaker 6:  do that like the slow and gentle long term way, which would take years. Or
Speaker 6:  he can be like, everybody get out and I'm gonna take the wreckage. I'm gonna
Speaker 6:  save a bunch of money because I'm not having to pay all of these people.
Speaker 6:  And if I can weather the storm of the shit show that I've created,
Speaker 6:  then on the other side of this, I'm gonna be fine. And it seems very clear
Speaker 6:  that that's the decision he's made, even though it's a bad
Speaker 6:  one. Gross.
Speaker 5:  I agree a hundred percent. And I think the thing that he's doing is
Speaker 5:  thinking that that, that Twitter is the same as Tesla and SpaceX. Right?
Speaker 5:  And this has been sort of talked about to death that like, you know, oh he
Speaker 5:  runs Tesla and SpaceX, he must know how to run Twitter. Why are all of you
Speaker 5:  people on Twitter mad at this? And I think like what, what seems
Speaker 5:  to be true is that working at Tesla and SpaceX like largely sucks.
Speaker 5:  But there are a lot of people who work there believing that it is in service
Speaker 5:  of something really good, right? Like we are, we are either going to space
Speaker 5:  or we are like saving the planet. Like,
Speaker 6:  Or we really like Elon Musk, like the entire point of a Tesla AI day
Speaker 6:  is to like inoculate people get there. Or not inoculate, but I
Speaker 6:  wish, but like, like bring them in.
Speaker 4:  It's like everyone gears a here's a guy in a
Speaker 4:  suit, everyone's got an mr a shot.
Speaker 6:  But it is about like making, like finding these people who
Speaker 6:  will put up with all of his, his bullshit, who will see a dude in a suit
Speaker 6:  dressed as a robot and be like, that's the future. I indoct
Speaker 6:  indoctrinate. There's a word. That's the one I meant to say. But so
Speaker 6:  he, he really is out. Like Tesla AI day is there to indoctrinate these
Speaker 6:  people and Totally. And he's gotta do that at Twitter now.
Speaker 6:  And that's like, that's kind of his plan. He's like, I'm gonna get out everybody
Speaker 6:  who doesn't wanna be a part of my vision. Who
Speaker 4:  Doesn't? Well so here the problem is that his vision does not
Speaker 4:  make any sense and is actually not really well articulated.
Speaker 6:  Well cuz his vision is what Elon wants. Elon gets.
Speaker 6:  That's the vision. He's really out there saying, do you wanna be a part of
Speaker 6:  an Elon Musk enterprise? If not, get out.
Speaker 4:  No, I'll be more charitable. And I've been very rude to Elon on Twitter because
Speaker 4:  I know that he's reading all the tweets and that he reads the virtual every
Speaker 4:  day. It's great when you know that you have that feedback loop in your life.
Speaker 4:  Yes. With SpaceX and with Tesla, the vision
Speaker 4:  is crystal clear. The steps to the vision are
Speaker 4:  obvious and the challenges are crystalline. Right?
Speaker 4:  SpaceX is, we want humanity to be an interplanetary species. I
Speaker 4:  need to put people on Mars to get there. We have to launch rockets and land
Speaker 4:  them because the first problem is cutting the cost of a launch down. Right?
Speaker 4:  And they went and they solved the first engineering problem, which is launch
Speaker 4:  the rockets, land them, make the rockets reusable. Very impressive. Very
Speaker 4:  impressive. But like, there's a big goal, right? There's all the goals
Speaker 4:  underneath it and then there's the first goal, which is land the rocket stage
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And reuse it to lower the cost of getting to orbit. And they went and
Speaker 4:  accomplished that and that and then that one in the market as it should
Speaker 4:  have. Yeah. Now our rocket launches are cheaper than everyone else's, where
Speaker 4:  the market leader, let's go, we win. Right? Okay. Then we are then, then
Speaker 4:  his goals are like hilarious. Like space suits look cool. So
Speaker 4:  kids want to go to space. Like this is a thing he said, I thought it was
Speaker 4:  like one of the rast things he's ever said. Yeah. Right. They, it should
Speaker 4:  look cool. It should be inspiring and awesome. Okay. We're gonna totally
Speaker 4:  computerize the capsule so that when we send astronauts to iss, they're not
Speaker 4:  really doing anything. They're just looking at screens. Cause computers are
Speaker 4:  better at this. They did it. Yeah. Okay. So like you see like they're solving
Speaker 4:  these really hard engineering challenges that are all baby steps
Speaker 4:  to the big goal. Yes. Tesla I think is the same way, right? We want to reduce
Speaker 4:  the amount of emissions on the planet. Everybody who works on
Speaker 4:  autonomous driving knows that computers are better drivers than people. You
Speaker 4:  want to decrease the rate of fatalities. You can argue about whether that
Speaker 4:  will ever come true. You know, but it's a noble, it's
Speaker 4:  more challenging AI problem in almost anything. We're, I would say we're
Speaker 4:  not much farther along the autonomous driving curve than we were five years
Speaker 4:  ago.
Speaker 5:  Well, and that's actually a, a good like counterexample of what you're talking
Speaker 5:  about, right? Where like, I would actually argue that Tesla's vision for
Speaker 5:  self-driving is incredibly like murky and unclear
Speaker 5:  and in the way that it's vision for like, you know,
Speaker 5:  curving emissions and electrifying the entire vehicle industry is
Speaker 5:  like crystal clear. And to your point, it's like it has steps towards it
Speaker 5:  and we kind of know what the end game looks like. Self-driving is just this
Speaker 5:  like messy thing that nobody kind of knows what it's gonna be at the end.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It's proving so much harder to do. And so even Elon's vision,
Speaker 4:  some of his pronouncements have assumed that he will solve
Speaker 4:  this hardest of all engineering problems. Yeah. We'll have robo, we'll
Speaker 4:  have a million robo taxis in a year is a thing that he has said on
Speaker 4:  the assumption that they will solve self-driving. Right. And so they just
Speaker 4:  have to keep doing it. But like he assumes he will solve the engineering
Speaker 4:  problems and he won't do a thing. The problem with Twitter is even the big
Speaker 4:  pronouncements, the pronouncements at the level of we will go to Mars or
Speaker 4:  we will have a million robo taxis in a year or whatever it is. His big pronouncements
Speaker 4:  are like shit the Online News Association was talking about in
Speaker 4:  2007. Yep. Bloggers will compete with
Speaker 4:  journalists, citizens will make the news. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  He was treating a lot about
Speaker 4:  That. We will, we will crowdsource truth. And it's like you guys, like I
Speaker 4:  live through this, it was boring the first time. Like do you
Speaker 4:  wanna, can I just like do a search about bloggers versus journalists and
Speaker 4:  show you some crap from 2001? Like we did this
Speaker 4:  already and we know what it looks like. And it is true that social
Speaker 4:  media has like changed the dynamics of the news and like,
Speaker 4:  my God man, like we cannot do like the
Speaker 4:  best journalists, the most relevant journalists you can think of all came
Speaker 4:  up as hardcore bloggers and social media personnel. Like down the line,
Speaker 4:  you pick a field in journalism and you're like, who's at the top? And it's
Speaker 4:  like that person had a blog spot Yeah. And they blogged their face
Speaker 4:  off. That's where we all came. Like it's just true. Like
Speaker 4:  the thing that he is describing is happening on Twitter already happened.
Speaker 4:  Yep. It happened at scale. It reorganized the shape
Speaker 4:  of the world.
Speaker 6:  It's happening as we speak sometimes
Speaker 4:  It's happening on TikTok right now. So you just, you, you can't get to this
Speaker 4:  vision without a engaging with the fact that the
Speaker 4:  conversation's already like been had at massive scale with,
Speaker 4:  in a way that reorganized the shape of the culture.
Speaker 4:  Like black Twitter exists. Do you guys remember we spent like a several years
Speaker 4:  of our life just talking about the words on Freak. Yes. And who should get
Speaker 4:  paid for the words on that's Twitter, that's black Twitter creating
Speaker 4:  culture Yep. And having it cycled out into the mainstream.
Speaker 4:  And there was, I mean to this day I think there's a reasonable discussion
Speaker 4:  and debate over where the money should flow that
Speaker 4:  cycled into TikTok dance. It's like, we've just done this a thousand
Speaker 4:  times. Ferguson is a, Casey new
Speaker 4:  and I both have t-shirts that Jack Dorsey Andreessen gave
Speaker 4:  us after Ferguson after black Twitter, like
Speaker 4:  used Ferguson to create awareness of police
Speaker 4:  brutality. They handed us t-shirts at a conference that said stay woke with
Speaker 4:  a Twitter bird on them. I can't find mine. I know Casey. Like we did
Speaker 4:  this already. Yeah. And you cannot destroy a company
Speaker 4:  and say, my vision is what this company was already doing.
Speaker 4:  Right. You have to engage the very squishy
Speaker 4:  problem of what do you mean by a town square? A digital town square?
Speaker 4:  You have
Speaker 6:  To engage with reality.
Speaker 4:  Right. It's it, and I just think like, yeah, maybe he's got a vision for
Speaker 4:  Tesla that you can understand. And I think that's a great vision. And I
Speaker 4:  honestly think SpaceX is the more impressive company because the challenge
Speaker 4:  was harder. And the the idea that you could actually
Speaker 4:  reinvent a government run business in a
Speaker 4:  market driven, like that's
Speaker 6:  So cool. And notably he, he doesn't run that the day to
Speaker 4:  Day there. Gwen Shotwell runs that company. Yeah. Although SpaceX got sued
Speaker 4:  today by a number, by nine employees. We, this is
Speaker 4:  following on a great piece that Lauren GREs for us. They wrote several employees
Speaker 4:  at SpaceX wrote a letter saying this company basically tolerates sexual harassment.
Speaker 4:  Yep. They all got fired. They were dragged into a meeting where they were
Speaker 4:  told this is Elon's company. Either you're with Elon or against him Yep.
Speaker 4:  To file a lawsuit. So even SpaceX, someone insulated from the chaos
Speaker 4:  because of the person of Gwen Shotwell, maybe not so insulated. Yeah. I just
Speaker 4:  think there's no vision for Twitter, so you cannot blow up the
Speaker 4:  company. Right. And say, I've got a vision and it's these
Speaker 4:  platitudes that are like 2001,
Speaker 4:  2003 level. What does it mean for journalists to use
Speaker 4:  the internet platitudes? Because obviously we're all just gonna
Speaker 4:  dunk in you all day at night.
Speaker 5:  But that's the thing. It's like, it, it would be one thing if he was basically
Speaker 5:  trying to recreate Twitter from the ground up, which would be like a very
Speaker 5:  funny outcome because he is, he's tweeting all the things. Like I'm just
Speaker 5:  looking at his Twitter now. His most recent tweet says Twitter is like open
Speaker 5:  sourcing the news. Which like, I guarantee Jack Dorsey has tweeted at some
Speaker 5:  point in the mid two thousands. I guarantee it. Dude,
Speaker 4:  Do you remember when Reddit tried to figure out who the Boston Marathon bombers
Speaker 4:  were and then got it wrong? That's what happened when Open source the
Speaker 4:  news.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So and, and then, but he says that on the one hand and then
Speaker 5:  he talks about, you know, making the x the everything app, which
Speaker 5:  nobody knows what the hell that means, but it has something to do with payments.
Speaker 5:  And apparently Casey and, and the platform crew, they got a thing that
Speaker 5:  says he's bringing long tweets back. So he wants to invent blogging.
Speaker 5:  It's like Twitter has always been this like weird sort of amorphous
Speaker 5:  thing. Apparently Vine might come back. Like there is no plan.
Speaker 4:  I just wanna read you a headline. Here's a headline that we wrote
Speaker 4:  in 2013, Reddit apologizes for online
Speaker 4:  witch hunts Go Cas community to be sensitive of its own power.
Speaker 4:  This is after they open source the news and they try to figure out
Speaker 4:  who the Boston Marathon bombers were until they found the wrong person and
Speaker 4:  an online mob descendant upon them. We have been through the cycle
Speaker 4:  before. So these platitudes that are ignorant
Speaker 4:  of all of the history of these ideas are not gonna motivate
Speaker 4:  anyone at Twitter who is deeply aware of, like, again, I
Speaker 4:  need to say this every single time criticism of Musk running Twitter is not
Speaker 4:  praise for Twitter under previous administrations
Speaker 4:  poorly
Speaker 6:  Run
Speaker 4:  Company, a badly run company. But one of the reasons it's run so
Speaker 4:  badly is because it has always been
Speaker 4:  paralyzed by its own. Like its own overwhelming
Speaker 4:  power. Right. Twitter's influence is disproportional to its size
Speaker 4:  and its revenue. And because they have always been so aware of it, they're
Speaker 4:  paralyzed into not doing anything. Whereas Facebook, hilariously how they
Speaker 4:  do it, influence is directly proportional to its size and revenue. And they're
Speaker 4:  like, screw it, let's do a genocide. Right? Like, like Mark Zuckerberg is
Speaker 4:  like, screw it. We're so important. I need to set up a Supreme Court that
Speaker 4:  will issue four decisions a year. Yeah. Twitter's like, what if we are just
Speaker 4:  paralyzed? And I, I just think like, I'm looking at all this must stuff.
Speaker 4:  And again, he, he told his staff, Twitter is at heart a software and
Speaker 4:  servers company. And it's like, no, it's not. Dude. You are a social sciences
Speaker 5:  Company. You're a content moderation
Speaker 4:  Company. You run a small country and you're the king of that
Speaker 4:  country. And the most important thing about that country is
Speaker 4:  if the citizens of that country can pull your pants down, they
Speaker 4:  will. That's Twitter. You're the king of the,
Speaker 4:  of a country whose sole purpose is to pants you good luck. Like
Speaker 4:  it's not software and servers,
Speaker 6:  But he thinks it's like, I I genuinely think a lot of his
Speaker 6:  stuff about making it the town square doing all of this is platitudes to
Speaker 6:  explain the fact that like what he really wants, he wants to do the big X
Speaker 6:  everything app. That's, that's like his endgame. He said it repeatedly. And
Speaker 6:  I think everything in between that is just how do I get people
Speaker 6:  to abide by the cult personality? This Elon
Speaker 6:  Musk,
Speaker 4:  I, if you wanna do the, so the X David, you've written about these apps before,
Speaker 4:  right? In China and other countries. WeChat is like a dominant
Speaker 4:  social fabric app. Yeah. Everything happens on the, and
Speaker 6:  He wants to do that, like he said repeatedly, I wanna do that here. And
Speaker 6:  with his current team, he's not gonna do that because that's not what Twitter
Speaker 6:  is. But
Speaker 5:  You just, you need more than 50 engineers. It
Speaker 4:  Turns you need more than 15 engineers. You need more than 229 million users.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Yep. You need a
Speaker 4:  Lot. Like one of the reasons WeChat works is there's like one and a half
Speaker 4:  billion people in China and they all use it.
Speaker 5:  Well, and the, I mean this like WeChat had a
Speaker 5:  hook, right? Like WeChat had, WeChat was first a like massively
Speaker 5:  successful messaging app and that that was the thing it had going for it.
Speaker 5:  And then once you have that, you have this big captive audience you can bake
Speaker 5:  all kinds of stuff into. And for a million cultural reasons, this is impossible
Speaker 5:  to do in the United States. Like I, I would bet anything you asked me to
Speaker 5:  bet that no one, including Elon Musk will ever
Speaker 5:  pull this off in the United States because it is just not how our ecosystem
Speaker 5:  works and how we do life in technology.
Speaker 5:  But it all requires more than 50 engineers and it
Speaker 5:  requires a thing people want to use, which is being systematically
Speaker 5:  destroyed on both ends every single day by Elon Musk right now.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. All right. So we've wrapped up Elon, we'll see how this goes. Every
Speaker 4:  day is cast, I will tell you, once a week, the Virgin editorial team gathers
Speaker 4:  and I say, are we over covering Elon? And we all kinda look at each other
Speaker 4:  and we say, not yet. So we have received a request for
Speaker 4:  a button on our homepage that will turn Elon stories off. We've taken
Speaker 5:  That's a good idea.
Speaker 4:  It's just a straight Elon filter. There's other stuff happening. The
Speaker 4:  tech industry is in turmoil. There's new gadgets, which we should talk about.
Speaker 4:  But this thing that is happening at Twitter, I feel like is the biggest story
Speaker 4:  in the world because for, I mean, what was my thesis? And welcome to how
Speaker 4:  Twitter will destroy your reputation and potentially cause grievous damage
Speaker 4:  to other companies. It is happening so much faster than I expected. Yep.
Speaker 4:  So we'll see how this goes. If he has to sell more Tesla stock, whew.
Speaker 4:  That's not great. Okay, we're gonna take a break. We're come back.
Speaker 4:  We're gonna talk about gadgets on this. The Vercast, I love a gadget
Speaker 4:  only took us an hour and 40 minutes to get there. We're in an hour 40. All
Speaker 4:  right. This is be a lightning round of all lightning rounds. We'll be right
Speaker 4:  back.
Speaker 4:  Okay, we're back. We are just way over, just ridiculously
Speaker 4:  over
Speaker 6:  45 more minutes of Elon. Let's go. Let's
Speaker 4:  Go. That has to be fun, right? We're gonna talk about gadgets. Alex run the
Speaker 4:  lightning round.
Speaker 6:  It's barely on here, but what I really wanna talk about is that Qualcomm
Speaker 6:  announced a whole new brand for Windows
Speaker 6:  CPUs because this time, this time Qualcomm is
Speaker 6:  serious about Windows CPUs.
Speaker 4:  Okay? I cannot, for the life of me remember this word. I looked at it a
Speaker 4:  lot last night and I was like, oxymoron. ORs. Like what
Speaker 4:  is
Speaker 6:  Or Orion?
Speaker 4:  Orion or,
Speaker 6:  Oh, it's a Y or
Speaker 6:  why No,
Speaker 4:  Or I
Speaker 6:  Or I.
Speaker 4:  Oh, Ryan.
Speaker 6:  No, Ryan. It's poorly spelled o r
Speaker 6:  y o n. I'm gonna call it Oron.
Speaker 4:  Oron.
Speaker 5:  It's oron. Or I will hear no other answer. It's oron forever.
Speaker 5:  Qualcomm did this to themselves. It's definitely O, but it is oron.
Speaker 4:  So there are no details about the cpu.
Speaker 6:  No details. It'll be released in 2023. What is interesting is
Speaker 6:  that this is using part of a company called Nuvia that Qualcomm acquired
Speaker 6:  a couple years ago that's made up a bunch of engineers who worked on
Speaker 6:  Apple's chips. Yes. Back in the day. And those eventually became the M
Speaker 6:  one, which is a very, very good cpu. So theoretically the same could happen
Speaker 6:  for Qualcomm. But given that Qualcomm's been trained to do this for how
Speaker 6:  many years, I'm not super optimistic.
Speaker 5:  Qualcomm chips to me are like, are like the LG
Speaker 5:  display screens that you see every once in a while where they're
Speaker 5:  just like, here's a neat thing we made. And then you never see it again.
Speaker 5:  Like the number of times Qualcomm has been like, oh, there's a problem that
Speaker 5:  you have with your headphones slash car slash tablets slash television
Speaker 5:  slash wearables slash pc. We'll fix it. And then
Speaker 5:  they put out a chip and you're like, is this, is this the one that you said
Speaker 5:  was gonna fix it? And they're like, yeah, it's slow, but next generation,
Speaker 5:  we're gonna fix it. It's gonna be great. And this is just what we do. It's
Speaker 5:  like we are kicking the football and Qualcomm is, is Lucy just
Speaker 5:  jerking away it's chip every time we try get it
Speaker 4:  Be crazy. So I want
Speaker 4:  two things. One, Qualcomm announced us that they're yearly junked in
Speaker 4:  Hawaii
Speaker 6:  We did not attend. Which
Speaker 4:  We won't take, we won't let companies pay for
Speaker 6:  Junkets. And I don't wanna send anybody to Hawaii and listen
Speaker 4:  Me, we're, we're just not paying the money to Hawaii.
Speaker 6:  Like, and I go to Hawaii to
Speaker 4:  Watch them be like, here's a spelling of the word Orion that you've not seen
Speaker 4:  before. No further details. Perfect. So this happens, like this happened
Speaker 4:  late at night Hawaii time. And we're just like, what is this? No details.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. But know that there is a very fancy Qualcomm junket going on in the
Speaker 4:  background. There are, by the way, entire industries that are basically junk.
Speaker 4:  It driven, like I love cars, I love to cover cars
Speaker 4:  more. We have to overcome the ethical barrier of the drunken driven
Speaker 4:  car media, which I, we cannot do.
Speaker 6:  Like 90% of entertainment media is like, do you wanna just go hang out
Speaker 6:  with Chris Evans? You can for 30 minutes come
Speaker 6:  to Budapest.
Speaker 5:  I do, I do. I will. Thank you for asking. It's
Speaker 4:  Yes. I know that the disclosures are a joke for us across the board, but
Speaker 4:  it's like, oh man, I can't do that many disclosures.
Speaker 6:  It's too many. That's just the, that's the Verge cast
Speaker 6:  folks.
Speaker 4:  We took a trip to Hawaii, we went to Budapest. Christ was there.
Speaker 4:  Then I drove a Cadillac across the mountains that was also like, it's all
Speaker 4:  like that. Whatever. It's fine, fine. We do our best. We pay for when at
Speaker 4:  support. But there's this big Qualcomm event going on. So there's a bunch
Speaker 4:  of news, other Qualcomm event. Second thing, Nuvia is really fascinating,
Speaker 4:  right? Yeah. So a bunch of ex Apple engineers, they got sued by Apple, Qualcomm
Speaker 4:  by Nuvia. So Arm has sued Qualcomm. So you can't make these trips.
Speaker 4:  Apple's mad at Nuvia. So you took some stuff from us and Qualcomm
Speaker 4:  is out there being like, Orion, we're doing it. It doesn't
Speaker 4:  matter. So it's just like these chips, this name,
Speaker 4:  lot of baggage underneath this collection of letters.
Speaker 6:  And what if it just sucks on top of all of that? It finally comes out and
Speaker 6:  you're like, it's
Speaker 5:  Going to
Speaker 6:  I three,
Speaker 5:  It's going to
Speaker 6:  I three level.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It, it's just, I don't know. Are we, are we at a point now where
Speaker 5:  Qualcomm like made one really good thing 20 years ago and we just forgot
Speaker 5:  that they never made nes?
Speaker 4:  Wait, I need to, I need to, I need to be, I need to make
Speaker 4:  clear. Hold on. Apple did not file a lawsuit against Nuvia. Oh.
Speaker 4:  They filed the lawsuit against Gerard Williams ii,
Speaker 4:  who is the chief architect. He was the chief
Speaker 4:  architect of the M series. And then he left to start Nuvia. So they filed
Speaker 4:  it against him, not Nuvia itself. This is important, but not important because
Speaker 4:  presumably he's architecting the chips Nuvia.
Speaker 4:  But anyway, Apple's got a lawsuit against some of the things that happen
Speaker 4:  in Nuvia Arm has a lawsuit against Qualcomm. And you're right David, they've
Speaker 4:  gotta actually make the chips. They've gotta be good. But theoretically they
Speaker 4:  bought this company to get ahead of the curve
Speaker 6:  Lawsuits. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Oh, Ryan
Speaker 6:  Orion.
Speaker 4:  All right. What's next on the line you're
Speaker 6:  In Right next up is, I mean this one's for me. I'm very excited about it.
Speaker 6:  The I Gatos new stream deck. It's the stream deck plus and it's got
Speaker 6:  knobs. That's it.
Speaker 4:  That's, I will say this is one of our best headlines ever. And Alice
Speaker 4:  wrote it. Oh God. New stream deck joins the knob. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  definitely. Hiphop crew. It's very pretty. I won't want, I have no idea
Speaker 4:  what I would use it for.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, same. That like, it's perfect. I just, I don't know what I'll do with
Speaker 6:  it, but I'm gonna have a great time. It's got a bunch of knobs. We're, we've
Speaker 6:  seeing that a lot in like the keyboard space. Everybody's like, you know
Speaker 6:  what your keyboard needs big old knob and it's nice. That stream deck was
Speaker 6:  like, you know what? Yes. Yeah, let's do it. This
Speaker 5:  Just makes me happy. Like the Verge believes in buttons. This is like a thing.
Speaker 5:  I feel very strongly like the Verge, we we, the verge, we believe in buttons
Speaker 5:  and this has a lot of buttons. Yeah. And it has a little tiny touch bar thing,
Speaker 5:  but you don't have to touch that cuz you can just control it with the knobs.
Speaker 5:  And the knobs look nice. They have a little like reflective thing on them
Speaker 5:  for when the light shines. It's lovely. It makes me happy.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Everything about this
Speaker 5:  Put them all to my volume so that I can spend all of them at the same time
Speaker 5:  just to make the volume go up really fast. It's gonna be,
Speaker 6:  It's gonna be really, really cool.
Speaker 4:  Every button is an emotional adventure that you can take. It's
Speaker 4:  true. Any button you see in your life, someone put it there and someone pushes
Speaker 4:  it. And those are all decisions. A lot of feelings got get tied up in all
Speaker 4:  those decisions.
Speaker 5:  I
Speaker 6:  Love it. And then Sona said their earnings call this week and they confirmed
Speaker 6:  that they plan to enter four new product categories starting next
Speaker 6:  year. One of those is lightly gonna be some Sonos headphones,
Speaker 6:  which I don't personally think makes sense, but I feel like David has,
Speaker 6:  has contested this before on the Verge cast with me. So
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I I just feel like if you're Sonos you have to make headphones at some
Speaker 5:  point. Like it's just, it's it's taken them too long. Like just make
Speaker 5:  headphones like we're why we get it. Your Sonos. I kind
Speaker 5:  of thought them getting into the whole portable speaker thing was a weird
Speaker 5:  idea that it's like if you wanna invest in the home, invest in the home,
Speaker 5:  but they need to do other stuff. So just, just buy all the way in. Make your
Speaker 5:  AirPods Max competitor, make your AirPods competitor and just
Speaker 5:  try to be the real full audio company
Speaker 5:  that runs your whole life. Yeah. Like for all I know, they're gonna start
Speaker 5:  making like third party speakers to put into your car.
Speaker 5:  Like NE's gonna swap out the CarPlay thing in his Jeep for a
Speaker 5:  Sonos thing in his Jeep. And that's where this is gonna be.
Speaker 6:  It could happen. It could happen. But like, I think what was really interesting
Speaker 6:  is they said new categories. Yeah. So we know that a bunch of Chris Welch
Speaker 6:  has done a lot of reporting and, and shown that we're getting a new like
Speaker 6:  sub, I think we're getting a new kind of replacement for the Sonos play.
Speaker 6:  Five.
Speaker 4:  The opto the
Speaker 6:  Optimal. It's good, it's great. But these are new categories. One of
Speaker 6:  'em may be a home theater box or your dream.
Speaker 4:  They've gotta make a receiver. I'm telling you the thing they should make,
Speaker 4:  Patrick, if you're listening to this and I know you are, make a receiver
Speaker 4:  and make the lights really big on the front. Yeah, right.
Speaker 4:  Just a big atmos light. Big Doby vision light. One light for every speaker
Speaker 4:  channel. Boom. Just big lights.
Speaker 6:  Just look at a glance.
Speaker 4:  That's all I want in the world.
Speaker 6:  Just see everything.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. The home theater thing seems like it's definitely gonna happen like
Speaker 5:  that. That's another one where it's just like Sonos, just finish the job.
Speaker 5:  Right? Like you, they've, they've been sort of trending towards this for
Speaker 5:  a while. It's like either make a TV or make a set top box.
Speaker 5:  Just do it. I'm bored of dealing with your nonsense. Just make
Speaker 5:  the damn
Speaker 4:  Box. But gigantic. L e d indicators for atmos provision
Speaker 4:  for every channel of speakers. That's all I
Speaker 5:  Really like. I imagine now that if, if, if I were to like walk into your
Speaker 5:  house, there would just be like a glowing neon Dolby atmo sign
Speaker 5:  above your television.
Speaker 4:  It's just like, you know, we actually don't watch movies. We just watched
Speaker 4:  that one Atmos cliff, we're hearing a forest and it's raining. I'm like,
Speaker 4:  come, let's go watch a movie. I'm like, is you're in this forest
Speaker 4:  again. Right? What else you
Speaker 6:  Got? And then Chris, this is also from Chris. He really,
Speaker 6:  really, really liked Amazon Alexa Voice
Speaker 6:  Remote Pro.
Speaker 4:  Is that the one with the big buttons? They
Speaker 6:  Got the big buttons. It's got backlight so you can like see
Speaker 6:  the big buttons. It's, it's still got buttons that are like Netflix,
Speaker 6:  Hulu, but their buttons, you'd actually use no Blockbuster Insight. So Netflix,
Speaker 6:  prime Video, Disney Plus and Hulu paid to this.
Speaker 4:  They paid the money.
Speaker 6:  They paid and like, okay, I'm glad you took their money and not What's
Speaker 6:  Walmart's thing called?
Speaker 5:  Voodoo?
Speaker 6:  Voodoo. I don't want Voodoo ever. It's never gonna happen.
Speaker 4:  I used Voodoo for a while cuz it had higher bit rate than anyone else. And
Speaker 4:  then Walmart bought it and that's,
Speaker 6:  And now, I dunno, it's garbage. Don't use it.
Speaker 4:  No. There's like one Voodoo fan here. You're like a Plex person.
Speaker 6:  I love Plex Plex, but I don't love Voodoo. I do like that it,
Speaker 4:  They all railhead. Were deep on Voodoo for a while.
Speaker 6:  It was fun. I didn't have good internet then.
Speaker 4:  That's why
Speaker 6:  Literally
Speaker 4:  Hate it off the rails. It's a remote, not off the rails. Welch gave it an
Speaker 4:  eight. It's got good buttons.
Speaker 6:  He really, really liked it. It was great. We're starting to see a lot of
Speaker 6:  stuff coming from Matter. So Jen Tuy was, was in
Speaker 6:  Amsterdam for the big matter announcement two weeks ago.
Speaker 6:  And so we're starting to see some of that stuff start to come out. TP
Speaker 6:  Link has got a huge router that's gonna have matter in it, but
Speaker 6:  also is doing wifi seven. You cannot currently I think buy anything
Speaker 6:  that uses wifi seven. So that's some real future proofing.
Speaker 4:  But it also is, it looks like a, a cross
Speaker 4:  between a gaming PC and a ups.
Speaker 6:  You can, like the lights on it are customizable so you can make like a little
Speaker 6:  smiley face or a little sat like
Speaker 4:  Little face. What I want my router to do, it's wink at me with like
Speaker 6:  Only when like when you're like, is the internet being slow because my computer
Speaker 6:  or the router and you look at it and the router winks, that would be like
Speaker 6:  choice. And then Wise is getting into the mesh
Speaker 6:  router business. I don't know if I would use a router
Speaker 6:  from Wise, but it's happening. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  I mean it's like matter time and then there's like the one plug that you
Speaker 4:  can buy. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  So lot of news. A lot of it's really great. It's on the site. You should
Speaker 6:  all go read it. A lot of really great stuff.
Speaker 5:  The one other cool thing that was announced this week, which is actually
Speaker 5:  the, the like one of the early 2023 stories I am most curious about is
Speaker 5:  that Apple announced that the major league soccer streaming service that's
Speaker 5:  been working on is launching I think February 1st. And
Speaker 5:  it's gonna be a hundred bucks for the whole major league soccer season. I'm
Speaker 5:  not even really a, an MLS fan, but like
Speaker 6:  No blackouts
Speaker 5:  What looks like when Apple builds a streaming service from scratch
Speaker 5:  for sports, I think it's gonna be fascinating. Yeah. They've said no blackouts,
Speaker 5:  you get all the live games for a hundred bucks a season, they're gonna do
Speaker 5:  a like red zone style whip around show. Apple
Speaker 5:  has, I would not say done like a super great job of
Speaker 5:  broadcasting sports so far. Like it, it, it felt like, it like hired a bunch
Speaker 5:  of people who had never watched baseball to do its baseball show. But it's
Speaker 5:  gonna be really interesting to see like these two like really tied together
Speaker 5:  and were like from the ground up we're gonna build a new thing and I think
Speaker 5:  it's gonna be fascinating. Can
Speaker 4:  Can you do a whip around show for soccer?
Speaker 4:  What's
Speaker 6:  A whip around
Speaker 4:  Show? So like NFL Red Zone is like a whip around show where it jumps from
Speaker 4:  game to game to game. Okay. But
Speaker 5:  Like as interesting stuff happens,
Speaker 4:  No but like it has a very, like football is a very
Speaker 4:  organized
Speaker 6:  Sport.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Right? They're like, it's called Red zone because if you're inside
Speaker 4:  the 20 yard line, you're in the red zone. Yeah. So whenever any team is in
Speaker 4:  the Red Zone, red zone cuts to that team and they're like, they're gonna
Speaker 4:  score a touchdown or a field goal or not. This is the exciting part of the
Speaker 4:  game we're gonna show to you. Yeah. And all the games happen at the same
Speaker 4:  time. Mostly. Right.
Speaker 5:  That's the key. There's so much going on simultaneously that it's really
Speaker 5:  easy to do that where if you're cutting between three basketball games in
Speaker 5:  a night, like it's just, it doesn't work the same
Speaker 4:  Way and and then it's not as structured cuz you're like Right. The soccer
Speaker 4:  ball is near the goal and it's like usually nothing happens.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  When that like
Speaker 6:  I feel like soccer does not lend itself.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Like soccer is to
Speaker 6:  The red zone.
Speaker 4:  The beauty and elegance of these kicks and runs
Speaker 6:  The beauty and elegance of dudes falling and pretending
Speaker 4:  Their heart once again,
Speaker 5:  There is gonna be a lot of the whip around show that says look at this awesome
Speaker 5:  pass that accidentally went out bounds. Like there's gonna be a lot of that.
Speaker 5:  I was just saying and I'm ready for it.
Speaker 4:  Maybe there is somewhere internationally there's like a football with and
Speaker 4:  I'm just not aware of it. Please let me know if you've heard, because I'm
Speaker 4:  just thinking structurally how would you produce it? And it's like, I mean
Speaker 4:  it's,
Speaker 5:  It's, it's literally, it's gonna be a lot of like beautiful runs and beautiful
Speaker 5:  passes and almost goals. Like that's what highlights are now. Right. Like
Speaker 5:  I watch, I'm a big Arsenal fan and so I watch the like 16 minute
Speaker 5:  long highlights of an Arsenal game if I miss it. And
Speaker 5:  it's like a one nothing game that they get 16 minutes of highlights on.
Speaker 4:  So it's like
Speaker 5:  They're gonna do it, it'll it'll be there. It'll just be like, look at this
Speaker 5:  great kick that no one got to on the other end of it. And you have to appreciate
Speaker 5:  that it's the beautiful
Speaker 4:  Game. I did. That's what I was saying. Like look at the power and elegance
Speaker 4:  of this long pass that it's no
Speaker 4:  mill. Yeah, that's fine. I'm,
Speaker 4:  I'm very excited for Apple. Lets try this out. I just like, this is the
Speaker 4:  lead up to Apple trying to get Sunday ticket, which is like the big product.
Speaker 4:  Yes.
Speaker 6:  To get a sport that people actually
Speaker 4:  Watch
Speaker 5:  And that's why like this just as a product. That's why I'm fascinated by
Speaker 5:  this for that exact reason cuz there are bigger prizes out there that this
Speaker 5:  is gonna be what they try to get.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And Eddie Q has very publicly been like, we're not gonna just take
Speaker 4:  rights and rebroadcast things. We wanna do it our own way and this is their
Speaker 4:  own way. And it's like alright this is their attempt to make
Speaker 4:  something that looks like Red zone. Cuz if you take it you gotta make Red
Speaker 4:  Zone. I
Speaker 6:  Mean it sounds way better than everything. My brother tries to watch football
Speaker 6:  games and then I have to deal with the phone calls cause he can't watch the
Speaker 6:  football games. So this already, I wish he was into this kind of football
Speaker 6:  because this seems like it's gonna save me a lot of phone calls
Speaker 4:  Because you're gonna buy the one thing from Apple. Yeah. And you're still
Speaker 4:  gonna get the phone calls.
Speaker 6:  I hate it.
Speaker 4:  Alright, we gotta wrap this show up. There's some more stuff. I think it's
Speaker 4:  very funny that Cannon is trying to charge people $50 a year
Speaker 4:  to, for their webcam software.
Speaker 6:  Don't do it.
Speaker 4:  Please show, just buy a capture card please for
Speaker 4:  $50.
Speaker 6:  Go buy another webcam. Just don't, don't give them your money.
Speaker 4:  It's very good. Which
Speaker 6:  Is terrible.
Speaker 4:  But some good news Razor is upgrading the USC ports on the
Speaker 4:  2020 twos late 14 to USB four. Which is cool. That's
Speaker 6:  And they're doing it through
Speaker 4:  Software. Through software. That's awesome. Good job. Razor. Good job. Okay.
Speaker 4:  Some stuff on the site you should read. Zao had a great piece
Speaker 4:  about Buzzfeed, which Buzzfeed is a public company now. They just had some
Speaker 4:  earnings. Not great. Buzzfeed pretty weird. The It's like a
Speaker 4:  bittersweet, it's like a bitter, it's like a poignant Yeah it's a good like
Speaker 4:  at the end of the day with a cup of tea wistful or like early in the
Speaker 4:  morning, you know like when the dawn breaks and you can just feel like the
Speaker 4:  beginning of the day you, if you want like a sad Sunday, read the
Speaker 4:  story. Some people want a sad Sunday.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Soccer
Speaker 5:  Fans.
Speaker 4:  Look, if you, if you wanna like, you know be like, if you wanna be like,
Speaker 4:  I was young once, like read this story. Oh wistful, we got
Speaker 4:  a great piece from a man in Chicago Lewis about the Department of Homeland
Speaker 4:  Security. It's 20 years. This is a big package for the year called Homeland.
Speaker 4:  Quite frankly it's awards bait. If you're a Pulitzer voter and you're listening
Speaker 4:  to this, first of all, what are you doing? Second of all give this appealer
Speaker 4:  be vote for us. We like to do that. I dunno if that's in the rules.
Speaker 6:  It's probably fine.
Speaker 4:  It's probably fine. It's probably fine department Homeland security is a
Speaker 4:  boondoggle, like a pure boondoggle. Nobody wanted to create it. They bunched
Speaker 4:  all this stuff together. Corporate structure. You know how I, how I feel
Speaker 4:  about corporate Tructure. Yeah. It's just a mess. Read the story everyone
Speaker 4:  quoted in the story is like, this thing's a mess and it sucks. You gotta
Speaker 4:  read. Perfect. It's great. And then lastly, James Enson has a great piece
Speaker 4:  about AI copyright, which no one knows what's gonna happen
Speaker 4:  with this generative AI copyright stuff. Very complicated, very verge. Love
Speaker 4:  the story. Two more things. One, by the time you listen to
Speaker 4:  this, we'll have our first set of tweaks redesign coming out.
Speaker 4:  So you got a new hero. The new top of the page will be, we're gonna have
Speaker 4:  a top five stories and a story showing move down. We think people are gonna
Speaker 4:  like it. We've got some big ideas for that on mobile, which the thing that
Speaker 4:  happens, you watch new web design, everyone clicks on everything. Yeah. So
Speaker 4:  your ability to measure and see what's working and not it's like
Speaker 4:  just goes to hell. Yeah. So yes, we waited, we waited for the
Speaker 4:  clicks to calm down. We figured out what people wanted. We think this is
Speaker 4:  gonna be great. You're, it's gonna be fun. We're gonna switch the river eventually
Speaker 4:  to light mode. Cause people have asked for that. And we're gonna add a toggles,
Speaker 4:  you can switch back and forth. That's please. And we're adding comments to
Speaker 4:  quick post that's coming later. That's
Speaker 6:  The thing I'm most excited
Speaker 4:  About. Yeah, it's be good. But it's be great with all that's happening by
Speaker 4:  the time. Listen this new hero, go check it out. Let us know what you think.
Speaker 4:  That's gonna be very cool. And these fools you back on
Speaker 4:  Wednesday. David, Alex Russell Brando. Jen
Speaker 4:  Tuey doing some cool, we
Speaker 5:  Have some fun. We have some fun friends giving you stuff we're gonna do.
Speaker 5:  I think we're, we're gonna, we're basically gonna try to get Jen
Speaker 5:  to blow up her house with smart kitchen gadgets. So assuming we all
Speaker 5:  survive, it's gonna be really
Speaker 4:  Fun. That's great. All right. That's it. We way
Speaker 4:  over. We'll see you in the Metaverse. That's the ver chest rock. Wait
Speaker 4:  on, you can tweet at us for however long that lasts. David's at
Speaker 4:  Pierce. Alex is Alex Aran. Addie is at the
Speaker 4:  Dexy on that reckless. We'll see you inverse. That's it. Rock and
Speaker 4:  roll.
Speaker 2:  And that's a wrap for Vergecast this week. Thanks for listening. If you enjoy
Speaker 2:  the show, subscribe in the podcast app of your choice or tell a friend, you
Speaker 2:  can send us feedback at vergecast@theverge.com. This show is produced
Speaker 2:  by me, Liam James, and our senior audio director, Andrew Marino.
Speaker 2:  This episode was edited and mixed by Amanda Rose Smith. Our
Speaker 2:  editorial director is Brooke Miners and our executive producer is Eleanor
Speaker 2:  Donovan. The Verge Cast is a production of the Verge and Box Media
Speaker 2:  podcast network. And that's it. We'll see you next week,
Speaker 2:  week.