# Transcript
ID: cb4527f0-d162-11ec-804d-cbb3ad29c274
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: How Google is trying to make ambient computing work
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/9187540364411120719/-6930299993357724039/s93290-None-1486s-1652298248.mp3
Description: Google has big visions for the future of computing. It’s working on building what it calls an ambient computer: a virtual helper that can accomplish anything, anywhere, any way you want. But that vision won’t come easy. Ahead of Google’s I/O developer conference, The Verge sat down with some of Google’s most important executives to talk about the company’s vision, its new hardware and software, and how the company is changing to build the future it imagines.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Disabled
Speaker 1:  One to thrive in the new world of work, meet lattice, the leading people's
Speaker 1:  success software platform that helps companies develop enviable cultures
Speaker 1:  that engage employees, serving thousands of customers of all sizes
Speaker 1:  globally. Lattice is unified solution helps employees in all industries
Speaker 1:  succeed. And when employees succeed your business succeeds,
Speaker 1:  learn why companies like slack, sauna, Solera, health, and article choose
Speaker 1:  lattice. Visit lattice.com today. That's L a
Speaker 1:  T T I C e.com.
Speaker 2:  Dakota is a show about how big ideas really work and where they might go
Speaker 2:  wrong. Hosted by me, Neil Patel editor in chief of the verge. I interview
Speaker 2:  CEOs, policymakers, tech, experts, and creators about how they make decisions
Speaker 2:  and how those decisions affect our shared future for better
Speaker 2:  or worse past episodes have covered everything from self-driving cars to
Speaker 2:  crypto, to social media moderation. It's a thoughtful, critical
Speaker 2:  conversation about business and technology that you will not hear anywhere
Speaker 2:  else. Follow Dakota, wherever you find your podcasts, new episodes come
Speaker 2:  out every Tuesday.
Speaker 4:  Welcome to the Vergecast. The flagship podcast of tablet apps that are
Speaker 4:  really just blown up smartphone apps. I'm David Pierce.
Speaker 4:  So it's Google IO this week, which is Google's developer conference. And
Speaker 4:  also the company's biggest launch event of the year. There's a ton of
Speaker 4:  product news coming out of IO this week. And we're going to get into a lot
Speaker 4:  more of that from the software to the hardware, to the services, to all the
Speaker 4:  weird stuff Google is working on on Friday show. But today I want to look
Speaker 4:  at the bigger picture. Google likes to call IO it's state of the union, which
Speaker 4:  is actually a pretty good way of thinking about it. Google is this huge
Speaker 4:  sprawling decentralized company where teams build lots of
Speaker 4:  things. Often. It seems like nobody seems to know what anybody else is working
Speaker 4:  on. And then once a year, the company tries to pull everything together
Speaker 4:  and figure out what's Google the whole thing, the entire company,
Speaker 4:  all of these hundreds of thousands of people actually up to, I
Speaker 4:  spent a good chunk of the last week talking to Google executives about that
Speaker 4:  exact question. And it's funny to do that, honestly, because you start to
Speaker 4:  hear the same things over and over and over again. For starters,
Speaker 4:  everybody really likes to talk about Google's mission, which is to organize
Speaker 4:  the world's information and make it accessible and useful. I know this by
Speaker 4:  heart now because Google people won't stop talking about it.
Speaker 5:  You know, our mission and Android is to bring computing to everyone in the
Speaker 5:  world.
Speaker 6:  I give Larry and Sergei a lot of credit for coming up with this mission.
Speaker 6:  All those years ago,
Speaker 7:  We've extended it recently to basically being about being helpful for
Speaker 7:  users,
Speaker 4:  But every year at Google IO, there's the story Google is trying to tell about
Speaker 4:  itself. And then there's the story it's really telling. And this year, the
Speaker 4:  story it's trying to tell is about how powerful its computing tech is.
Speaker 4:  Google talks a lot about the tensor chip and the pixel phones and how it
Speaker 4:  lets Google do all kinds of powerful AI stuff. It also talks about
Speaker 4:  large language models, which are AI systems that can develop a radically
Speaker 4:  better understanding of text images and even videos and how
Speaker 4:  all of that helps Google organize information computing and AI
Speaker 4:  over and over computing and AI computing and AI. And that's all
Speaker 4:  true. But underneath all that, as I talked to folks at Google, I heard a
Speaker 4:  different story what's going on with Google right now is that
Speaker 4:  Google has become this huge sprawling decentralized company where
Speaker 4:  teams build lots of things. And nobody seems to know what anybody's working
Speaker 4:  on. And as a result, Google feels kind of incoherent for so
Speaker 4:  long. You could think of Google as a search company and mostly be right now.
Speaker 4:  It's I don't even know how to describe it. It does all the things. And
Speaker 4:  honestly, even in search, it's confusing, there's Google search, but
Speaker 4:  there's also Google lens, which is kind of like Google search, but in a different
Speaker 4:  way. And there's Google assistant, which you can use for search, but it's
Speaker 4:  really a whole different thing. Google is still more or less on the organize
Speaker 4:  the world's information and make it accessible and useful grind. But as the
Speaker 4:  company has gotten bigger, it's pieces have stopped sort of making
Speaker 4:  sense together. It makes phones and computers that can barely talk to each
Speaker 4:  other. I mean, dear God, have you ever tried to just send a file from your
Speaker 4:  Android phone to your Chromebook? The whole of Google sometimes feels like
Speaker 4:  less than the sum of its parts. That is what Google is working on. Now
Speaker 4:  it's trying to take the many parts of Google, the countless features and
Speaker 4:  products and initiatives and experiments and prototypes and make them
Speaker 4:  make sense together. I think Lee's read a VP of engineering at
Speaker 4:  Google who works on search actually explained this better than anyone else.
Speaker 4:  I talked to
Speaker 6:  A lot of these newer use cases, there's a style or a taste
Speaker 6:  component. There's a way to process information. Some people really find
Speaker 6:  it easy to process video and other people will find it distracting. On the
Speaker 6:  other hand, some people's literacy is not as good. And so along
Speaker 6:  webpage that you have to read through not only takes time, but they're going
Speaker 6:  to get lost. And a video that's spoken in their language is really intuitive.
Speaker 6:  I think we need to assume that there is no best answer for
Speaker 6:  many of these things. I mean, if there's a height of the Eiffel tower, okay,
Speaker 6:  there's an answer to that. But if it's like, I'm finding a wedding dress,
Speaker 6:  there is no right answer. People have very different styles. They have different
Speaker 6:  price capabilities as well. So how do we really let you find the
Speaker 6:  dress you want versus your next door neighbor, find
Speaker 4:  Multi search, which Liz and her team have been working on is one of the things
Speaker 4:  Google is talking a lot about at IO. And it's a pretty good microcosm
Speaker 4:  of what it looks like for Google to start to put the pieces together. The
Speaker 4:  idea behind multi-serve is that you can't always express your entire question
Speaker 4:  in one way, right? Google likes to give the example of a dress. You like,
Speaker 4:  you see the dress, you want that dress, but you want it in green so far.
Speaker 4:  There is literally no way for you to ask Google to find that for you, but
Speaker 4:  with multi search, you can take a picture of the dress and then type in green
Speaker 4:  and Google understands and processes the search that way.
Speaker 4:  One way Google is making all this stuff work is by making it conversational.
Speaker 4:  I heard this also over and over from Google exact. So over the last week,
Speaker 4:  they're absolutely convinced that rather than you just barking an order at
Speaker 4:  your phone or speaker, that you should have something that more closely
Speaker 4:  approximates, an actual back and forth conversation. And what that means
Speaker 4:  is that in the process, Google can ask you questions. It can refine your
Speaker 4:  search results. It can figure things out better than just doing it. One exchange
Speaker 4:  at a time. I am skeptical of
Speaker 4:  this. First of all, have you tried having a conversation with a voice assistant
Speaker 4:  it's either infuriating or it breaks, or actually no, those are the only
Speaker 4:  two options, but Google thinks it can work and feel natural and not be
Speaker 4:  the worst. And the reason it does is because of those large language models
Speaker 4:  I was talking about, rather than me try to explain, I'm going to let Zubin
Speaker 4:  governor Mani, a distinguished researcher at Google do it. This is kind of
Speaker 4:  a long one, but it's worth it. I promise.
Speaker 9:  So about 10 or 15 years ago, the field of language
Speaker 9:  technologies really was revolutionized by deep learning. And
Speaker 9:  of course at Google, we've been using deep learning very extensively from
Speaker 9:  at least 10 years ago in language and other domains. And then in
Speaker 9:  the last five years. So back in
Speaker 9:  2017, we actually develop a form of language
Speaker 9:  model called the transformer. And the transformer is in some
Speaker 9:  ways kind of like the grandmother of a lot of the modern language
Speaker 9:  models. So the T in Bert, in
Speaker 9:  in open AI GPT three and metas opt,
Speaker 9:  it all stands for transformer. So this has been an incredible
Speaker 9:  breakthrough that has enabled a lot of these other
Speaker 9:  interesting language models to flourish over the last five years.
Speaker 4:  Okay. Let's skip ahead. A little, here's a little bit on how transformers
Speaker 4:  and new language models have changed the way translation works, which is
Speaker 4:  both a big deal and a pretty good explanation of what it means for the whole
Speaker 4:  system.
Speaker 9:  You know, the traditional way you think about doing translation is you need
Speaker 9:  a line text like text in French and English. Let's say to
Speaker 9:  be able to translate from French to English and vice versa, right? That's
Speaker 9:  the way translation traditionally was thought to require. But actually
Speaker 9:  it turns out with some of these large models, you can just
Speaker 9:  learn to translate in some of these languages using only
Speaker 9:  monolingual text. So the model is exposed to many different languages, but
Speaker 9:  it doesn't need that aligned translation. It just needs
Speaker 9:  some monolingual texts without any translation pairs of
Speaker 9:  sentences. And that's the kind of breakthrough that again, is
Speaker 9:  surprising to me is a researcher who's been in the field for 30 years. Of
Speaker 9:  course, when you dig into it, it makes sense because
Speaker 9:  there are patterns in the data that help it extract the common
Speaker 9:  representations between different languages that are needed to do that
Speaker 9:  translation. But it's still a breakthrough that really helps us. For
Speaker 9:  example, deploy translate across many more languages that
Speaker 9:  are useful to lots of other people.
Speaker 4:  Basically Google is turning practically everything from text to audio,
Speaker 4:  to video, to images, into language, and then using these language models
Speaker 4:  to help understand it all. So you can change the way Google understands an
Speaker 4:  image by adding a bit of text or ask it a paragraph long question
Speaker 4:  and have it understand you. Here's Nino Tasco. Who's a director of product
Speaker 4:  management on Google speech team who had a pretty good idea about where this
Speaker 4:  all goes.
Speaker 10:  You can imagine like a 45 minute YouTube video of do
Speaker 10:  it yourself, steps one through nine and a large
Speaker 10:  language model can actually understand that video. And so now I can ask
Speaker 10:  it to play and be like, oh no, no, skip to step four. Cause I already know
Speaker 10:  one through three and the model understands that video. And if you go back,
Speaker 10:  that's like how I would talk to you is how I want to talk to my assistant.
Speaker 10:  So it comes back to the beginning of, okay, well what's the natural
Speaker 10:  conversation look like when it's this back and forth media not just play
Speaker 10:  a video and I'm going to sit and be silent while the video plays, I might
Speaker 10:  play the video and then I might want to interact and talk to my assistant.
Speaker 10:  I might want to jump to a command and I want to pause, go to the next command,
Speaker 10:  but having this full understanding of the video or, you know,
Speaker 10:  Linda can theoretically understand the whole internet, right? And so you
Speaker 10:  can ask questions, cross-referencing documents that you just can't today.
Speaker 10:  And when you think about that kind of knowledge, that can come into play.
Speaker 10:  This need to have more of a conversational interface, just becomes
Speaker 10:  more apparent
Speaker 4:  Like me. And I've said most of this isn't possible yet, but this is very
Speaker 4:  much where Google is headed. Step one is making Google easier to talk with,
Speaker 4:  which is starting to show up in little ways. The big Google assistant news
Speaker 4:  this week is that you can talk to the Google nest hub max, just by looking
Speaker 4:  at it and then speak to it. No hot word necessary because it's using on
Speaker 4:  device gaze recognition. To notice you looking on the same device, you can
Speaker 4:  also just say set a timer for 10 minutes or turn off the kitchen
Speaker 4:  lights and Google understands the commands without meeting an okay Google
Speaker 4:  ahead of time. And in general, since so much of this stuff is happening
Speaker 4:  on device, it's both more reliable and lower latency and generally just
Speaker 4:  much more usable.
Speaker 4:  So that's the big picture stuff. We're going to take a quick break and come
Speaker 4:  back with more on the future of Google.
Speaker 12:  When you were a kid, did your parents get on you about watching too much
Speaker 12:  TV? Did they tell you that watching TV was bad for your brain or that
Speaker 12:  you were too young to be watching it all day? That if you told them you
Speaker 12:  were watching Salesforce, plus they wouldn't have that same energy is when
Speaker 12:  you were a kid, because these are shows you can totally watch it work.
Speaker 12:  Salesforce plus is a streaming service that provides live experiences,
Speaker 12:  original series podcasts, and other programming to help your business
Speaker 12:  grow with Salesforce. Plus you can stream the latest,
Speaker 12:  inspirational stories and access expert advice on demand
Speaker 12:  and it's free series on the platform. Aluminate the future of
Speaker 12:  technology and the digital first work anywhere world. And these
Speaker 12:  shows and experiences will inspire you to learn new skills, pursue new
Speaker 12:  career opportunities and drive change in the world. Salesforce
Speaker 12:  plus is available right now. Join for free and watch new business series
Speaker 12:  like pivot on demand at salesforce.com/plus,
Speaker 13:  Hey folks, it's Preet Bharara, the former us attorney for the Southern
Speaker 13:  district of New York. I led that office for over seven years until I
Speaker 13:  was fired by former president Trump five years ago. Now I host
Speaker 13:  a podcast called stay tuned with Preet, from cafe and the Vox
Speaker 13:  media podcast network. Every Thursday, I have long form
Speaker 13:  conversations with the Newsmakers shaping our current moment and the
Speaker 13:  thinkers who help make sense of it. Politicians, journalists,
Speaker 13:  academics, and activists, people like Adam Schiff, Anita
Speaker 13:  hill Masha Gessen and Daniel economy. As a former
Speaker 13:  prosecutor, I focus on questions of justice. That means I dive
Speaker 13:  deep into the war in Ukraine, the threat of climate change, the future of
Speaker 13:  technology. And of course the legal and political battles that are
Speaker 13:  defining our time, like the investigations into former president Trump
Speaker 13:  and the fights for voting and reproductive rights. I hope you'll consider
Speaker 13:  listening and subscribing just search, stay tuned with Preet,
Speaker 13:  wherever you get your podcasts.
Speaker 4:  Welcome back. So the reason I wanted to start by talking about search
Speaker 4:  is that, well, Google's a search company, but one thing that really stuck
Speaker 4:  out to me over the last week is that Google is also increasingly a hardware
Speaker 4:  company. It built the tensor chip to be able to do more of its AI, work
Speaker 4:  on devices and has clearly begun to bet big on the pixel lineup in
Speaker 4:  general. And for now Google execs all over the company acknowledged that
Speaker 4:  practically everything Google wants to do has to start with their smartphone.
Speaker 4:  But when Google talks about the smartphone, it actually has a vision that's
Speaker 4:  much bigger than just the smartphone. Here's Rick Costello, Google's SVP
Speaker 4:  of devices and services,
Speaker 7:  Our vision of where the future is that it's totally different. That, you
Speaker 7:  know, people will interact with devices in a way that's almost like it's
Speaker 7:  one computer. You know, they interact seamlessly across
Speaker 7:  different modalities, different form factors, different use case scenarios.
Speaker 7:  Contexts. They'll be able to interact with computers in various different
Speaker 7:  ways, voice tapping and in the future, a lot of things will be done
Speaker 7:  proactively for you. So you don't even really it's like an agent is doing
Speaker 7:  things for you. And we call this vision, ambient computing. We want to bring
Speaker 7:  all of Google's latest innovations and hardware, software, and AI put it
Speaker 7:  together for user to offer the maximum possible help. We can be
Speaker 7:  as helpful as we can for users. That vision is one that's very hard to
Speaker 7:  build. Like it means you have to have expertise across a lot of different
Speaker 7:  arenas, both in devices, but also in a number of
Speaker 7:  different technologies and AI and software. And now Silicon
Speaker 7:  certainly for the foreseeable future, we feel like the most crucial part
Speaker 7:  of that is the pocketable computer, the mobile phone that
Speaker 7:  continues to be the center of most people's computing focus. And
Speaker 7:  certainly today, the most important element of a computing future
Speaker 4:  Google in general is making this big push away from being a search
Speaker 4:  box, you type into and more of an always on experience,
Speaker 4:  a thing, helping you and working with you. And sometimes literally talking
Speaker 4:  with you like the movie her all day, and that means Google better make
Speaker 4:  damn sure it's powering the phone in your pocket. The only way this works
Speaker 4:  is if Google is everything and everywhere, Rick showed me
Speaker 4:  the new pixel seven and pixel seven pro the new flagship phones. The company
Speaker 4:  is teasing this week, but fully launching in the fall. And also the new pixel
Speaker 4:  six, a the $449 phone launching now. And Rick
Speaker 4:  said that the key to the pixel six a is bringing all that AI, all of
Speaker 4:  that Googling us to as many people as possible without changing the
Speaker 4:  experience.
Speaker 7:  Well, I think this is really important is that it takes a lot of the capabilities
Speaker 7:  we've offered for the first time with tents are on pixel six and six pro
Speaker 7:  and brings it to a different price point. It brings it to a lower price point
Speaker 7:  at 4 49 beautiful device. You know, it's, it has Google
Speaker 7:  tensor. There's a good spec on the rest of the device. I think people are
Speaker 7:  going to see it for a great value for money, but the big punchline is that
Speaker 7:  you get all of the AI power that comes with tensor on a
Speaker 7:  much more accessible price point.
Speaker 4:  Google is also finally launching its own smartwatch. It's called the pixel
Speaker 4:  watch, and it's a nice looking round smartwatch running. Google's where oh,
Speaker 4:  S it'll do normal smartwatch things like tell the time and get notifications
Speaker 4:  and work with Google assistant. But it's primarily being sold as a fitness
Speaker 4:  device with Fitbit. Built-in,
Speaker 7:  You'll be able to sync with a Fitbit account. You'll be able to get all
Speaker 7:  like Fitbit's latest algorithms for health and fitness. Be able to track
Speaker 7:  against your personal goals. Everything will sync back to the Fitbit
Speaker 7:  service. So you can see it on the web, on your app. And it's
Speaker 7:  deeply integrated throughout, you know, the watch face and throughout the
Speaker 7:  device.
Speaker 4:  In addition to all that, Google's also making a pair of high-end earbuds
Speaker 4:  called the pixel buds pro, which are basically as far as I can tell
Speaker 4:  exactly the same as the AirPods pro, but for Android devices. And
Speaker 4:  Google is even going to make an Android tablet after it spent so many years,
Speaker 4:  basically not giving a crap about Android tablets.
Speaker 4:  So what's going on here? Why is Google suddenly going big and
Speaker 4:  wide on all these devices? It had a brief run with smartwatches in the middle
Speaker 4:  of last decade before essentially appearing to give up on the idea. Now
Speaker 4:  it's saying, no, just kidding. We're back. We love smartwatches, where are
Speaker 4:  forever and same with tablets. Every Android fan has fond memories of the
Speaker 4:  nexus seven tablet, but that was nine years ago. And Google not only
Speaker 4:  stopped making tablets, but stopped seeming to care about Android for tablets
Speaker 4:  at all. Now both the hardware teams and the Android teams told me they're
Speaker 4:  all in on both counts. So what gives here Samir
Speaker 4:  Sammat a VP of product management on the Android team gave me what I think
Speaker 4:  is pretty much the correct explanation.
Speaker 5:  We were early pioneers in watches. For example, we were actually very early
Speaker 5:  in multi size form factors for tablets. There's been a number of
Speaker 5:  different form factors that we've worked on, but I think consumer expectations
Speaker 5:  have changed as well over time. So, you know, the phone is certainly super
Speaker 5:  important, but it's also becoming very clear that there are other device
Speaker 5:  form factors, which are complimentary and also
Speaker 5:  critical to a consumer deciding which ecosystem to
Speaker 5:  buy into and which ecosystem to live in
Speaker 4:  That last thing. He said, that thing about the ecosystem. That's the whole
Speaker 4:  thing here. What Google wants is to not be a search engine,
Speaker 4:  but to be a sort of AI companion that understands and adapts to you
Speaker 4:  at all times, it's a cool vision, frankly, and it makes a lot of sense for
Speaker 4:  Google to be following. It also requires Google to be essentially all
Speaker 4:  things to all people at all times. It has to know everyone's taste, work
Speaker 4:  on everyone's devices, speak everyone's language, understand everyone's
Speaker 4:  workflows and be perfectly personalized to every single person
Speaker 4:  on planet earth. That's a really high bar, even for Google. And if
Speaker 4:  you're buying an iPhone because you love your apple watch, that makes life
Speaker 4:  even harder for Google. Apple has long understood that an ecosystem is
Speaker 4:  powerful, that you can sell devices and services through your other devices
Speaker 4:  and services. Google at long. Last is finally figuring that out.
Speaker 4:  That idea has forced Google to change a lot about how it works, even at
Speaker 4:  a company level. Here's just one good example. For years,
Speaker 4:  Google treated its Android and hardware teams like two totally separate
Speaker 4:  things. And actually used to talk about how Android treated pixel,
Speaker 4:  just like any other Android manufacturer. Now Rick told me the two
Speaker 4:  sides are getting much closer together
Speaker 7:  In our very earliest days, it was like we're making platform software.
Speaker 7:  And then we would make devices on that software. It's very different now
Speaker 7:  and that we really sort of co-design where things are headed. And
Speaker 7:  I think that's just sort of the nature of how computers have changed, like
Speaker 7:  in computing models have changed. So like, you know, the better together
Speaker 7:  initiative is like a key part of Amie computing. The reason we're doing
Speaker 7:  both of these things is that this is our vision for how the model of computing
Speaker 7:  changes in the future. And we're working on it together. We're making sure
Speaker 7:  that our hardware compliments the software that's being built and vice
Speaker 7:  versa.
Speaker 4:  That's one way this push towards ambient computing is changing Google, but
Speaker 4:  it's not the only one Google knows it's set up in this
Speaker 4:  crazy decentralized way. And it knows that to get to this
Speaker 4:  ambient computing, everything connected future, the company
Speaker 4:  itself has to change to solve it.
Speaker 4:  And if Google wants to do that, it's going to have to keep being focused
Speaker 4:  on making all of its parts work together. Google has a long history of building
Speaker 4:  something, getting sort of bored and then building a new, similar thing that
Speaker 4:  doesn't work with the old thing. That's how you get a thousand Google messaging
Speaker 4:  apps over the years. That's why Google inexplicably operated two
Speaker 4:  competing music services for a bunch of years. It's why it bought nest, but
Speaker 4:  also built its own operating system for the internet of things. It's why
Speaker 4:  Google has worked on countless AR and VR projects, but has never
Speaker 4:  actually had one that took off the history of Google's failed projects is
Speaker 4:  like a crazy alternate universe of the biggest stories in tech over the last
Speaker 4:  20 years. And it's rarely because Google is dead wrong though.
Speaker 4:  Sometimes it is like when it tried to make buzz of wave and Google plus happened,
Speaker 4:  it's because of the culture of Google is to try everything and
Speaker 4:  kill pretty much all of it. Why? Because frankly, Google doesn't
Speaker 4:  need any of those things to work. It can continue to fritter away, all
Speaker 4:  those good ideas. As long as the search ad money keeps chugging along and
Speaker 4:  make no mistake. It is still chugging along, but you've got to think that
Speaker 4:  for Google faced with antitrust reform and new privacy rules, and even
Speaker 4:  companies like Amazon starting to take a bite of the ad business, Google's
Speaker 4:  feeling a little more urgency as it thinks about what comes next. It
Speaker 4:  also has to continue to convince users. Many of whom are increasingly
Speaker 4:  wary of how much Google knows about them, that the trade-off for all
Speaker 4:  that data is worth it. And if you really cast out in the future, there's
Speaker 4:  one other piece of this too. If you think augmented reality is the future
Speaker 4:  of computing and a lot of people at Google do this kind of
Speaker 4:  ambient computer, a Google is building seems like exactly the kind of thing
Speaker 4:  we're going to need. Nobody wants to walk down the street yelling, Hey, Google
Speaker 4:  message Anna. I love you. We're also not going to want to switch between
Speaker 4:  eight devices just to get things done. We're going to need computers that
Speaker 4:  are massively versatile and switch seamlessly from place to
Speaker 4:  place and task to task and input to input. And don't
Speaker 4:  particularly care about their form factor. Google wouldn't tell me much about
Speaker 4:  what it's working on here for what it's worth. This is all I actually got
Speaker 4:  out of Rick Costello.
Speaker 7:  It's definitely a place where we are focusing as well, and we don't see the
Speaker 7:  market as here now, but we definitely see it as a key part of the future
Speaker 4:  For the record. Ambient computing also isn't here now, but Google
Speaker 4:  has built a lot of the pieces to make it work without thinking much about
Speaker 4:  how they work together. Now, the job for Google is to take all those
Speaker 4:  pieces and turn them into something magical, something more than the
Speaker 4:  sum of its parts that comes in really small ways like Google, making it easier
Speaker 4:  to move files or cast video between all your devices. And it comes in really
Speaker 4:  big way. It's like a virtual assistant. You can talk to anywhere about anything,
Speaker 4:  any way you want. And that at least it seems to me is what Google is
Speaker 4:  actually working on. Now maybe for the first time,
Speaker 4:  The ongoing question is will this vision hold Google's interest long enough
Speaker 4:  to get anywhere or will something shiny or come along and just distract the
Speaker 4:  company again? Who knows maybe next year is IO will be all about the
Speaker 4:  metaverse and who cares about your life in the real world. But I would bet
Speaker 4:  that if Google is ever going to find its next big thing after search ads,
Speaker 4:  ambient computing might be the best chance it has that or really awesome
Speaker 4:  AR glasses.
Speaker 4:  That's it for the show today, but we are definitely not done talking about
Speaker 4:  Google IO. We'll be back on Friday with all kinds of talk
Speaker 4:  about all of the announcements from this week. Plus we're going to be spending
Speaker 4:  some time with Sundar Pichai, the CEO of Google and alphabet, getting
Speaker 4:  into all of this stuff about what Google's up to. So stick around
Speaker 4:  this special episode of the Vergecast was produced by me. David Pierce, Liam,
Speaker 4:  James and Andrew Moreno Vergecast is a production of the Vox media podcast
Speaker 4:  network. We'd love to hear from you about this show and everything. Please
Speaker 4:  send us an email@vergecastattheverge.com. Thanks for listening. We'll see
Speaker 4:  you on Friday rock and roll.
Speaker 13:  Hey folks. It's Preet Bharara host of stay tuned with Preet and
Speaker 13:  cafe insider. As you have surely heard a draft
Speaker 13:  majority opinion from the Supreme court that would overturn Roe V. Wade
Speaker 13:  was leaked. This leads countless questions. What does this
Speaker 13:  mean for reproductive rights? Why was it leaked? What happens
Speaker 13:  next here at the Vox media podcast network? We've got you
Speaker 13:  covered I'm Khalfan cider. I sat down with my cohost Joyce
Speaker 13:  vans to discuss the legal substance of the opinion and the potential
Speaker 13:  impact on other constitutional rights. You can find that episode for
Speaker 13:  free in the stay tuned podcast feed. My colleagues at today
Speaker 13:  explained also spoke to New York magazines here in Carmona to
Speaker 13:  break down what this means for reproductive rights and on the weeds.
Speaker 13:  Darra Lynne spoke with Supreme court expert, Ian Millhiser to
Speaker 13:  answer listener questions and dig into the details of the opinion. You can
Speaker 13:  find these important conversations by searching for stay tuned with Preet
Speaker 13:  today explained and the weeds in your favorite podcast app
Speaker 13:  or visit podcasts dot Vox media.com for a full list of
Speaker 13:  shows in the Vox media podcast network.