# Transcript
ID: a9a62ff0-78c3-11ed-a49e-595208118ec9
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: ChatGPT explained, the FTC suing Microsoft, and Apple adding encryption to iCloud backups
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/235292230542398092/3733786098979412218/s93290-US-5486s-1670701618.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, Alex Cranz, Richard Lawler, and James Vincent discuss the popularity of ChatGPT.
Also: the FTC sues Microsoft to block its Activision Blizzard purchase, Apple is adding end-to-end encryption to iCloud backups, and some gadget news.
Speaker 1:  Today on the Vergecast, James Vincent and Richard Lawler join us. We get
Speaker 1:  into the G P T three Chatbot Saga, Apple's
Speaker 1:  new security features, and the FTC is coming after Microsoft for
Speaker 1:  buying Activision. All coming up right after
Speaker 1:  this,
Speaker 4:  Hello, welcome to the Verge, the flagship podcast of The
Speaker 4:  Verge, where we talk about absolutely nothing and waste your
Speaker 4:  time. Now, the robot put an
Speaker 4:  exclamation point at the end of that sentence
Speaker 4:  because you see, I asked chat g p t three to write the
Speaker 4:  intro of the show.
Speaker 6:  Usually you're, you're
Speaker 4:  Exuberant. And I said, I said, write the intro of the show, and it said,
Speaker 4:  and chat g PT three said to me, hello and welcome to the Ro flagship podcast
Speaker 4:  of The Verge.
Speaker 6:  That's our, that's wrong.
Speaker 4:  It's, I mean, it's lazy. Yeah. And so
Speaker 4:  I told the robot to make it funnier, and then it said, hello and welcome
Speaker 4:  to Verge Cast, where we talk about absolutely nothing and waste your time,
Speaker 4:  which is the robot fully telling me to go
Speaker 4:  f myself.
Speaker 6:  I was like, David would do the exact same as he
Speaker 4:  Was here. We basically replaced David. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  Done.
Speaker 4:  See you later, buddy. Anyway, this is the Verge cast. That was the
Speaker 4:  first and last time we're ever gonna let a chat bot write the intro. I'm
Speaker 4:  your friend Eli. Alex Kranz is here.
Speaker 6:  I'm your friend who doesn't believe in ai.
Speaker 4:  Oh, you will by the end of this episode. Oh, Richard Lawler is
Speaker 4:  here. Hey, Richard. Hey.
Speaker 5:  I might be in ai.
Speaker 4:  That's by the end of this episode, we're gonna d we're gonna have to take
Speaker 4:  bets and our senior Verge reporter covering
Speaker 4:  ai. James Vincent is here. Hey, James.
Speaker 5:  Hey, I am, I am pro ai, I'm pro
Speaker 5:  worshiping AI and just getting ahead of that. And you know
Speaker 5:  that, that religion that Lewandowski tried to found, I am the guy who
Speaker 5:  carried that on. So you
Speaker 4:  Still got it.
Speaker 5:  You still got it? I, I, I'm keeping the faith.
Speaker 4:  Do you have a, like a, like a blue cube in your house with
Speaker 4:  little electric bolts like floating around in, you know, like one of those
Speaker 4:  like AI monuments,
Speaker 5:  Nilo, do I have a God cube that I, that I worship
Speaker 5:  daily? Geez, man. You know, that is a very
Speaker 5:  insulting question to ask someone of my faith. I'm gonna go, if that's gonna
Speaker 5:  be the tenor of the conversation, obviously.
Speaker 4:  So FairWarning, it is, I believe 9:00 PM for
Speaker 4:  James in the uk and he's just, I'm a
Speaker 5:  Loose,
Speaker 4:  He's man this drinking, which honestly, it's, you know, it's,
Speaker 4:  it's only 4:00 PM here in New York. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  We could do that.
Speaker 4:  We could be drinking you next week so that it's that kind of week. So
Speaker 4:  we gotta talk about chat G P T with James. The FTC
Speaker 4:  sued Microsoft to block the Activision deal. The EU did some
Speaker 4:  iPhone charging standard stuff. Elon continues to Elon. There's a
Speaker 4:  bunch of stuff talk about this week. Yeah. But we have to start with chat
Speaker 4:  G p T three, which has taken the world by
Speaker 4:  storm. If you don't know what it is, it is just a chat
Speaker 4:  bot. Yeah. It just happens to be very good.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And I will tell you, I mean, I think it's super fun
Speaker 4:  to play with, but the overheated,
Speaker 6:  There's some feelings, people,
Speaker 4:  People
Speaker 6:  Got feeling
Speaker 4:  Feelings positive and negative, like all the way from VC saying this will
Speaker 4:  replace Google to like fan fiction communities
Speaker 4:  being like, once again, our art has been plundered by
Speaker 4:  the godless heathens of Silicon Valley, and we should shut down
Speaker 4:  the, like, you pick either one of those. It's
Speaker 6:  Just the whole gamut. It's whole gamut of Felix.
Speaker 4:  So I, there's a lot of like verge stuff in here.
Speaker 4:  Fred, we should talk about the technology itself, which is super fascinating.
Speaker 4:  We should talk about open ai, the company slash research foundation that
Speaker 4:  has made it and published it. And we should, we should talk about all those
Speaker 4:  downstream effects, the angry artists of the world. We should talk about
Speaker 4:  Lens in this conversation too. The app that makes profile pictures people
Speaker 4:  all worked up about, well, let's just start with what it is, James. What
Speaker 4:  is exactly going on with chat GBT
Speaker 5:  Three? So it, it, it is just chat G p T rather than
Speaker 5:  chat G
Speaker 4:  PT three. No, it's G PT 3.5 is the thing inside it.
Speaker 5:  So yeah, it is chat G P T, which is a fine tune version of an AI bot
Speaker 5:  called Chat, G p T 3.5, which is self is a version or
Speaker 5:  sort of an upgrade of chat of G P T three, which is
Speaker 5:  from 2020. So sort of the foundation of this tech has been
Speaker 5:  around for a while. And what OpenAI the company behind this decided to
Speaker 5:  do is they fine tuned the bar on conversational dialogue and
Speaker 5:  they fed it a bunch of sort of conversational prompts, and they got humans
Speaker 5:  to rank the sort of attractiveness, the responsiveness of those prompts.
Speaker 5:  They fed that back into it and it created a new sort of dialogue
Speaker 5:  mode. And then they took that and they put it into a web
Speaker 5:  demo. And that has been like the huge thing, you know, the,
Speaker 5:  the, the baseline technology behind this has sort of been around for a while.
Speaker 5:  It's never been as publicly accessible as this before. And that
Speaker 5:  obviously has created this huge reaction where a, people are seeing what
Speaker 5:  this thing can do for the first time. B, they're finding new things to do
Speaker 5:  with it because, you know, you can get a bunch of AI researchers to play
Speaker 5:  around with a model in a lab. They are never gonna be as creative or as
Speaker 5:  chaotic as the internet on mass suddenly being like, Hey,
Speaker 5:  let us talk to this thing and see what it can do. I've got some, I've got
Speaker 5:  some real interesting questions. So that has created this explosion where
Speaker 5:  suddenly this thing is everywhere. And I'm Neil, I'm with you. I I
Speaker 5:  do find it quite exciting. Like there's lots of caveats that need
Speaker 5:  addressing when we talk about this technology, but the, the, the base
Speaker 5:  feeling for me is like, oh man, this is pretty cool. Like, we couldn't do
Speaker 5:  this before. It is doing interesting stuff. I'm into it. Let's see where
Speaker 5:  it goes.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. That to me is the, the verges part of this whole story
Speaker 4:  is what you just described. This underlying technology has
Speaker 4:  been around since 2020. And we have seen
Speaker 4:  very public demos of similar technology,
Speaker 4:  like at Google io, Sundar Pacha has Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Demonstrated Google's riff on large language models
Speaker 4:  like this and you can go back and watch them. They're very
Speaker 4:  funny. He's like, I'm gonna have a conversation with a planet now. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And then for a few minutes we all just sit there while sundar's like, what's
Speaker 4:  it like to be Pluto? And a robot is like, it's
Speaker 4:  weird. And everyone's like, what is the purpose of this?
Speaker 4:  But that is the same l l m idea, right.
Speaker 4:  Where you feed an ai, a massive amount of language data,
Speaker 4:  massive corpus of text and it learns how to talk to you. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Open AI has a different riff, which G p t we've seen. Yeah. But that, like,
Speaker 4:  Google's been doing that demo for a while. Yeah. Then on top of that,
Speaker 4:  we've already experienced like three or four
Speaker 4:  news cycles of serious meaningful
Speaker 4:  controversy. Yeah. Around LLMs in
Speaker 4:  particular, again, in Google with Tim Nit guru. And, and then there was just
Speaker 4:  the researcher who claimed it was sentient and it was
Speaker 4:  fired for warning Google that their LLM was
Speaker 4:  sentient. The Tim guru is much more, I think,
Speaker 4:  important, less funny, but more important where she was like, I'm publishing
Speaker 4:  papers about the ethics of AI like this, and she claims Google fired
Speaker 4:  her for publishing those papers. This is like a big deal. Yeah. All I'm saying
Speaker 4:  is we have gone through the gamut with the underlying
Speaker 4:  technology. We've seen the big hype demos, we've seen the
Speaker 4:  ethics controversy, we've seen the
Speaker 4:  engineer who claims it's alive get fired. Like there's
Speaker 4:  a lot of peaks and valleys to the story already over the past few years.
Speaker 4:  And what has happened now is that the user
Speaker 4:  interface, Scott Good. Yeah. Right. The user interface to,
Speaker 4:  to do this before, right. You had to install a bunch of stuff in your computer
Speaker 4:  or like you, you just had to like work hard to get to the place where you
Speaker 4:  could type in a prompt. Yeah. Now it's very much, you can just talk to it.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. You
Speaker 6:  Log, log in and, and you start
Speaker 4:  Chatting. Yeah. I mean, it is, it is actually like, that is a remarkable
Speaker 4:  advancement in, its in its own way. Yeah. But the underlying tech is
Speaker 4:  not that different than what it was before, is
Speaker 5:  It? No, no. And, and, and I think actually even the ui,
Speaker 5:  the making it conversational is something that we've been able to do for
Speaker 5:  a while. And I think actually the, the sort of, the thing that
Speaker 5:  has happened is that AI companies have got a little less scared this year
Speaker 5:  and that there has been some successes with text to image models,
Speaker 5:  specifically stable diffusion who disrupted, you know,
Speaker 5:  the status quo within this industry. So you had all these image models like
Speaker 5:  Dolly, which were relatively restricted, stable diffusion is
Speaker 5:  open source. Anyone can build on it, anyone can mess around with it. That's
Speaker 5:  had that is having, will have bad consequences, but it's also created
Speaker 5:  a lot of interest and excitement and people have built on it. And I think
Speaker 5:  that gave AI companies some new confidence. I remember speaking
Speaker 5:  earlier this year to meta about a chatbot that they put out
Speaker 5:  and one of the things that one of their execs said to me was like,
Speaker 5:  it's not 2016 anymore, when the Microsoft Tay Chatbot
Speaker 5:  went online, became a racist asshole in 24 hours, and then it pulled off,
Speaker 5:  you know, they, they were saying like, yes, that was bad, but A, we've got
Speaker 5:  more guardrails than we used to, and b, we're kind of thinking that this
Speaker 5:  is the best way we advanced this stuff. So I think there has been a
Speaker 5:  period of timidity, which in many
Speaker 5:  ways is connected to the criticisms that came out of Google with the
Speaker 5:  Stochastic parrots paper, which was the one by Tim, Nick Gabriel, and, and
Speaker 5:  a few others, Margaret Mitchell, which is, you know, incredibly
Speaker 5:  valuable, important stuff. They, you know, they brought up these issues and
Speaker 5:  they are, they are huge real issues. But I think that made
Speaker 5:  the company sort of stutter for a while and in 2022,
Speaker 5:  OpenAI particularly has been like, you know what f it, we're just gonna put
Speaker 5:  it out there and see what happens. And people
Speaker 5:  in OpenAI will be congratulating themselves for this, I'm sure, because they've
Speaker 5:  got so much attention. They've got so much goodwill out of it, they're burning
Speaker 5:  money doing it. But, you know, I, you know, it, it really has moved the
Speaker 5:  conversation forward for better or worse.
Speaker 4:  Can you, before we move on, can we, can you quickly just tell people what
Speaker 4:  a stochastic parrot is and what this paper said? Because I think it's underlies
Speaker 4:  the whole controversy. Oh yeah. To understand this technology, you have to
Speaker 4:  understand that criticism. So
Speaker 5:  There are a lot of points that are made within the paper, but
Speaker 5:  the, I i, I think the big thing about it is what
Speaker 5:  is a stochastic parrot? It is a probabilistic machine, right?
Speaker 5:  And this is the big thing in many ways, it's the big thing about the deep
Speaker 5:  learning revolution general in that instead of creating a
Speaker 5:  deterministic computer where X does, Y does Z does, you know, ABC knocks
Speaker 5:  on like that. You take a machine that looks at data, that looks
Speaker 5:  for patterns in that data learns to replicate that data and then deals
Speaker 5:  probabilities out to you. And that that probabilistic nature of
Speaker 5:  AI and of language, large language models in particular creates
Speaker 5:  all sorts of downstream problems often to do with the data
Speaker 5:  that these systems are trained on. Stochastic parrots had a lot, a lot of
Speaker 5:  criticisms about, you know, a lot of problems. I don't, I don't wanna frame,
Speaker 5:  I don't wanna frame these people as critics because I feel that that in a
Speaker 5:  way diminishes what they're saying. Cuz then you get the critics and the
Speaker 5:  proponents and the, you are either for or against the technology. These aren't
Speaker 5:  people who are against the technology, they're just people who have things
Speaker 5:  to say about it. And, you know, write r correct
Speaker 5:  observations to make. But, so when you have a probabilistic model,
Speaker 5:  when you say train it on data, scrape from the internet, that is going
Speaker 5:  to return all the bad things in that data. And that is stuff like
Speaker 5:  biases that is, you know, bias against people of color, against
Speaker 5:  women. It has stereotypes within that. And we know that these
Speaker 5:  models, including chat, G P T, these problems are not fixed.
Speaker 5:  They are still replicating these bias issues. So yeah,
Speaker 5:  that's one thing within the paper, but there are others, but I'll leave it
Speaker 5:  at that.
Speaker 4:  Well, so, and this gets to very much how it works, which we should also just
Speaker 4:  touch on briefly. We're calling it an ai Yeah.
Speaker 4:  There, and it's made by a company called Open ai, but it's not an
Speaker 4:  ai, but it is, it's not, it's not actually ai and this chat
Speaker 4:  client, it's main feature is that it appears to
Speaker 4:  have a sense of state. Yeah. Right. You ask it a question, it gives you an
Speaker 4:  answer, you ask it a follow up, it appears to remember what
Speaker 4:  has transpired and, and answer a follow up question that is also a
Speaker 4:  mirage. So can talk about how it works and you know, it's sort of just like
Speaker 4:  guessing the next word of a sentence and then we should talk about how it's
Speaker 4:  preserving the sense of state to create the impression of
Speaker 4:  a conversation.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I mean, so at the basis, a language model,
Speaker 5:  particularly G P D three is an auto complete right? It, it has
Speaker 5:  looked at this data, it is looked, and it is mapped out in these
Speaker 5:  incredible multi-dimensional graphs. The proximity
Speaker 5:  of words to one another essentially. And by doing that, when it looks at
Speaker 5:  how often words appear next to each other, you get this semantic map, which
Speaker 5:  allows you to know that, you know, king is like queen because they're part
Speaker 5:  of this body called monarchy. But King also has this connection with man
Speaker 5:  while Queen has a connection with woman. And it, you know, it maps out all
Speaker 5:  this semantic data and then essentially you feed it a string of
Speaker 5:  words and then it will predict what will come next. What happens
Speaker 5:  when you turn that into a conversation is that there is a lot of clever
Speaker 5:  behind the scenes stuff, which honestly I don't
Speaker 5:  quite understand. I don't understand the basic mechanisms of it, but it essentially,
Speaker 5:  you know, it turns your question into a prompt in which it tries to predict
Speaker 5:  based on, based on what you've asked it, what the answer would or should
Speaker 5:  or could be. Yeah. So that, that is the sort of the underlying, the underlying
Speaker 5:  mechanism there. What, what you've pointed out, the fact that these
Speaker 5:  systems, particularly chat g p t, have a sense of state, I think that really
Speaker 5:  changes how you interact with them, as you rightly point out. You know, because
Speaker 5:  you start thinking of it as an entity, not as a sort
Speaker 5:  of a, a, a function where you ask it
Speaker 5:  discrete questions and it gives, gives you discreet answers. And I think
Speaker 5:  this sense of state is what led to the Google engineer
Speaker 5:  Blake Lamoin. Lao Yeah. I, I lamoyne,
Speaker 5:  you know, mistaking this thing for a a, a conscious being of
Speaker 5:  some sort. So a state is very important. It helps the user,
Speaker 5:  right? But it also creates this false sense of personhood. And I
Speaker 5:  think that is gonna be a really tricky balance in the future with these models,
Speaker 5:  knowing how to split that divide.
Speaker 6:  I mean, how different is it from Siri
Speaker 6:  or Alexa or something like that. Because I have to admit, the few times I've
Speaker 6:  used chat G p t, it hasn't worked for
Speaker 6:  me. It, it, it gave me, it gave me
Speaker 6:  this whole, I asked it for a story, right. And it gave me an entire story.
Speaker 6:  And it was like, and then they killed the dragon and then they fought Thanos.
Speaker 6:  Right. And I was like, is Thanos the dragon? And it was like, I don't know
Speaker 6:  how to respond to that question. And I was like, but oh no, you just told
Speaker 6:  me all about it. So it felt like, for me, so far my experience with it has
Speaker 6:  been very Alexa, very, very Siri. Which is why I'm like, it seems fine
Speaker 6:  and I haven't been super impressed, but it sounds like you guys have all
Speaker 6:  had like much
Speaker 4:  Different, well, I'll say even this little joke about, complete this sentence,
Speaker 4:  welcome to the Vercast, that query, I had to enter specifically that way.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. When I said, what is the Verge, the flagship podcast
Speaker 4:  of, I got a stock answer that says I cannot search
Speaker 4:  the internet for you.
Speaker 6:  Right.
Speaker 4:  And so there are these like dead ends and it's like, I don't, that's a weird
Speaker 6:  Yeah. It's kinda like early days of Google where you, like, you had to really
Speaker 6:  think about how you worded that question. Yeah. And I know James, you were
Speaker 6:  talking, you recently wrote a piece where you had a friend who like used
Speaker 6:  it to create a whole new macro
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And Excel macro just, you know, he, he's a guy, he works in higher
Speaker 5:  education. He does a lot of database wrangling as part of his job,
Speaker 5:  but he's not, he's not coder. Yeah. He's never, he's never had a formal training
Speaker 5:  that he studied English at university, you know, and he would, he was just
Speaker 5:  casually saying, I asked it for an Excel macro about how to, you know, extract
Speaker 5:  this, this sort of selection of dates. And it came up with it and it got
Speaker 5:  it. He, he got it to work in a matter of minutes. And
Speaker 5:  I just thought, well that is, that really says something about the accessibility
Speaker 5:  of these systems. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  There's a piece of the puzzle there that is really important. Right. Because
Speaker 4:  the most impressive examples I've seen of this
Speaker 4:  system working are people asking it to write computer programs.
Speaker 4:  Right. Write me code. Yeah. Which we think of as a very difficult thing to
Speaker 4:  do. I'm sure all the people who actually write code for a living listening
Speaker 4:  to this are like, that's not so hard. But like it, the relationship
Speaker 4:  between human language and computer
Speaker 4:  language is usually mediated by people. Yeah. Like
Speaker 4:  mostly mediated by people and having a, a
Speaker 4:  robot that can make that connection for you
Speaker 4:  and take your English language query and spit
Speaker 4:  out working workable code in the language of your choice.
Speaker 4:  All the most impressive ones I've seen have all been in C Sharp, which is
Speaker 4:  like a weird Microsoft corner case language. Right. Like Yeah. That's
Speaker 4:  amazing to me. And it's because the corpus of text on the internet includes
Speaker 4:  so much code.
Speaker 5:  Exactly. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And that to me is like a fascinating reflection of what
Speaker 4:  you're talking about, which is the inputs reflect the outputs. Yeah. It can
Speaker 4:  do this because there is so much code on the internet. Yeah. If you were
Speaker 4:  to ask it to do other kinds of things that the internet is not so
Speaker 4:  good at,
Speaker 6:  Like recipes quick. Somebody ask it to make a cookie, give me a cookie
Speaker 6:  recipe.
Speaker 5:  Apparently it's quite, apparently it's quite good at
Speaker 4:  Recipes. There's a lot of recipe text on the internet. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  But they usually have the, the, the, the opener where the person has to talk
Speaker 6:  about how the cookies remind them of their grandmother's house. Well,
Speaker 4:  So this is like, you get all the way down stream of it to, well this is like
Speaker 4:  why people think it's gonna replace Google. Yeah. Right. Which is asking
Speaker 4:  this thing questions returns more interesting answers that
Speaker 4:  are more conversational and are often just the answer. Write me an
Speaker 4:  Excel macro. If you wrote that into Google, you would be flooded
Speaker 4:  with a list of garbage. Yeah. Like Google would basically return to you
Speaker 4:  nothing of value.
Speaker 6:  Bunch of paywalls.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. A bunch of paywalls, a bunch of SEO spam texts. A bunch of
Speaker 4:  articles that were like slideshow. Yeah. And you'd be like, this actually
Speaker 4:  does not, is not a date sort in Excel. Yeah. Yeah. This is just,
Speaker 4:  you're trying to get me
Speaker 6:  Bunch of YouTube results. It's like actually you should just watch this 20
Speaker 6:  minute video.
Speaker 4:  Gotcha. And there's a reason that other search products like
Speaker 4:  Stack Overflow and Yelp and all these other things exist. They're more
Speaker 4:  targeted search interfaces to certain kinds of results.
Speaker 4:  And they have built businesses not being gained by Google in that way.
Speaker 4:  Chat. G P T is like, you ask a question, it just tells you an answer
Speaker 4:  with utter confidence. Yeah. It's like, here is some code you can type into
Speaker 4:  your computer to do a date sort and like, maybe it's pure
Speaker 4:  malware, maybe you're gonna hack like an Iranian
Speaker 4:  nuclear reactor. Like you have no idea what's gonna happen, but it's like,
Speaker 4:  here it is. Yeah. You got it. Like here's a recipe for a whiskey sour,
Speaker 4:  one cup bleach please. And it just like, no,
Speaker 4:  no. Like absolutely no hesitation whatsoever. And I think that is why
Speaker 4:  people are reacting to it. Yeah. Because there's no business model between
Speaker 4:  you and something that is presented to you confidently. Like an answer,
Speaker 4:  even if the answer is garbage. Yeah. Like, you know, and it's, there's no
Speaker 4:  business model yet. Right? Right. Now is it burning money, James? How much
Speaker 4:  money does this thing cost to run? Cuz it seems like they're just lighting
Speaker 4:  VC dollars on fire.
Speaker 5:  Well, I, I think Alex, you you, didn't you do something on this? I
Speaker 5:  remember, I I can't remember the figures.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, they, a guy did, did the math on it and basically each query
Speaker 6:  costs like 0 cents.
Speaker 6:  Right. And so it's costing them about 3 million a
Speaker 6:  day on average with like, they, they, they assumed the number of people
Speaker 6:  using it and the number of queries and stuff, but probably about 3 million
Speaker 6:  on, on average. And that was based on the pricing for a w s, which is
Speaker 6:  where this is all running out of because it has to use a lot of
Speaker 6:  GPUs to, to do all of this. Like one, I think they said like
Speaker 6:  one GPU would maybe present one word in a couple of minutes. So it's having
Speaker 6:  to use like a ton of processing power, probably
Speaker 6:  way more than Google does for Google search, which might
Speaker 6:  make,
Speaker 4:  Which explains a lot about Google search actually.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, yeah. Use more GPUs.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Well, so that, I mean that to me is really fascinating. Right. So as
Speaker 4:  Richard's 20 out doesn't make money yet the costs are high Yeah. On a long
Speaker 4:  enough timeline, the cost of technology come down in Ensure, but right now
Speaker 4:  the costs are high and they're gonna have to somehow make this a product.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Well I mean we're seeing that with Lens, right? Like Lens is this other
Speaker 6:  big AI thing that's, that's using I think open source
Speaker 6:  engine. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It's using, it's using Stable Diffusion, which is an open
Speaker 5:  source text to image ai, but also is monetized by
Speaker 5:  the company that funds it. And I say funds it rather than
Speaker 5:  made it because there is a very convoluted
Speaker 5:  sort of licensing scheme going on that the company that is
Speaker 5:  associated with its stability AI has put in place in order to avoid future
Speaker 5:  legal liability. So they, they, they love it Fund it.
Speaker 5:  They fund it, but they don't research it and they don't make it
Speaker 5:  technically Right.
Speaker 6:  But anyway. Yeah. And so this other company Prism, is that, is that the name
Speaker 6:  of it?
Speaker 5:  Prisma Labs? Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Prisma Labs has taken, taken this this engine and they've put it
Speaker 6:  into their app. And so if you pay a certain amount of money, you
Speaker 6:  can have little cute digital portraits of yourself and
Speaker 6:  also help them continue to train this AI basically you're, I mean
Speaker 6:  effectively you're paying them to train their
Speaker 6:  ai
Speaker 5:  Well whether they keep the ai do they, do they
Speaker 5:  keep the data for training ai? I feel like this is such a meme within Yeah,
Speaker 5:  like within Twitter that like, oh, tool X is keeping you a
Speaker 5:  data for y and I, you know, I mean,
Speaker 6:  Because that's, that's happened in the past. Like we have seen that happen
Speaker 6:  before. But where a company is like, yeah, give us your face. Oh by the way
Speaker 6:  we're working on facial recognition.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Face tune Yeah. Everywhere. Wasn't it? It was like the Chinese think
Speaker 6:  Was face. Yeah. I can't remember that. We've definitely seen that in Prisma
Speaker 6:  Labs, to their credit has said they told Tech Crunch earlier this week, either
Speaker 6:  this week or last week. Yeah. Anyway, to their credit, Prisma Labs did
Speaker 6:  tell TechCrunch that they, they aren't keeping a lot of this data. They are
Speaker 6:  deleting it. It's, it's, it's going away from their servers. But isn't it
Speaker 6:  still training stable diffusion or are they just like,
Speaker 5:  It wouldn't be training stable diffusion. Stable Diffusion would be sort
Speaker 5:  of separate from that. And Stable Diffusion is based on a, a
Speaker 5:  big database called Lyon, which again is made by a German
Speaker 5:  university. I, I guess they could be keeping it, I don't know. My,
Speaker 5:  my my feeling on that is that the bad PR of finding out an app is keeping
Speaker 5:  your data in order to train its systems would outweigh the cheapness of just
Speaker 5:  buying that data. You know, if you want, if you want to get a million faces
Speaker 5:  downloaded to train a facial recognition system that there exists a database
Speaker 5:  called Mega Face.
Speaker 4:  You sound like a character from Cyberpunk. Do you want get a million faces?
Speaker 5:  Do you want a million faces my
Speaker 4:  Friend? If you want get a million faces, I can get you a million
Speaker 6:  Faces. You got a guy, you got a guy,
Speaker 5:  I got a guy with a, I got several million faces back here. You take a look.
Speaker 5:  I got what you need.
Speaker 4:  Come on, let's do one this work faces, I get your
Speaker 5:  Faces. Oh, I got your face. This guy come
Speaker 6:  Like Prisma lab. They, they're, they found their other ways. I mean
Speaker 6:  even if they, they aren't doing the whole, we're gonna steal all of your
Speaker 6:  facial recognition data so that we can sell it somewhere else. They are saying
Speaker 6:  you have to sign up for a month of our service. Right.
Speaker 4:  But that's just like Apple App Store what I mean like, it's like traditional
Speaker 4:  business model to it. Yeah. Which is like, we don't wanna sell you an app,
Speaker 4:  we don't wanna sell you one in app purchase. We wanna make you subscribe
Speaker 4:  to our app and then forget that you're subscribed to our app. Yes. So we
Speaker 4:  get at least one more month of money from you.
Speaker 6:  They're gonna make so much money. This,
Speaker 5:  But I, I I think this will be gone pretty soon. This
Speaker 5:  this specific iteration of it. Does anyone remember style
Speaker 5:  transfer? Like that was like a big AI sort of trend in like
Speaker 5:  20 15, 20 16, I wanna say. And you know what Prisma Labs did that
Speaker 5:  They did that back in the day. I, I was looking up some old articles I wrote
Speaker 5:  about them cuz I, for the name was familiar to me and they used to do these
Speaker 5:  style transfer things where you'd put in a picture and it would make it look
Speaker 5:  like Van Gogh or it would make it look like stained glass. And you know,
Speaker 5:  this was a thing for a while. Facebook did it, you'd see it on people's profile
Speaker 5:  pitches and it was gone within a month.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And now it's an Adobe feature. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It it's an Adobe feature and it's a boring preset thing. And I, I think AI
Speaker 5:  portraits will probably go that way pretty quickly, but something next will
Speaker 5:  come there.
Speaker 4:  But there's something underlying all of this, which is
Speaker 4:  kind of the, the cultural controversy of it. Right. So we've talked about
Speaker 4:  where it came from, how it works, the controversy that importantly I
Speaker 4:  think the democratization of the technology with
Speaker 4:  easier to use user interfaces. And in the case of lens, right. Stable diff
Speaker 4:  fusion is a thing that you were able, you can today download it
Speaker 4:  and run it on your computer. Yeah. You can just do it if you want. It's
Speaker 4:  just, it's hard. Yeah. Like people don't wanna do it. Actually Apple just
Speaker 4:  released an update that makes stable defusion run faster
Speaker 4:  on its phones. Oh
Speaker 6:  Cool.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Which which is big. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Right. And it's like a 40% performance boost on the neural engine on
Speaker 4:  like an M two, right. Like this is, it's all happening,
Speaker 4:  but it's, here's an app where you can pay four bucks to get some profile
Speaker 4:  pictures. It's, it's actually a much more like democratic.
Speaker 4:  Anybody can use it. That's when I say like, that's the verges part
Speaker 4:  of this story. It's like you give all the people the tools and then you have
Speaker 4:  no idea what's gonna happen. And that's like, that's when I just like am
Speaker 4:  the happiest,
Speaker 6:  What's it called again, James? We give people all the
Speaker 6:  chaos.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Sorry, do you have
Speaker 6:  Like a specific, you had a specific word for it in the piece you wrote today
Speaker 6:  about ai? Oh,
Speaker 4:  The overhang.
Speaker 5:  The overhang. The overhang. Yeah. So that's not necessarily about
Speaker 5:  accessibility. The phrase is capability overhang, which I love it, it sounds
Speaker 5:  like, I don't know, it sounds like a minor character in a pension
Speaker 5:  novel capability overhang. But it,
Speaker 5:  it, it essentially refers to the hidden capabilities of AI systems
Speaker 5:  that the, it's sort of something that AI researchers get quite excited about
Speaker 5:  and stay up late talking about when they, when they, you know, they think
Speaker 5:  about the fact that these models do things that we don't even know. That
Speaker 5:  we don't know that they do. Right. That there are, there are unknown unknowns
Speaker 5:  about what these things can do. And the, the point I made in my piece was
Speaker 5:  that although there exists a capability overhang within the research community,
Speaker 5:  there also exists one within the sort of public awareness of
Speaker 5:  this and 2022, particularly the last couple of months
Speaker 5:  when we've seen tools like chat, e b T we've seen, I
Speaker 5:  mean remember like crayon, the AI image generator
Speaker 5:  that was everywhere for a little bit and is now already just sort of like
Speaker 5:  part of the background tapestry of the internet. Yeah. We've forgot these
Speaker 5:  tools. Yeah. We, we've forgotten. But these tools are just becoming part
Speaker 5:  of everyday life now. And we are now climbing that
Speaker 5:  overhang the public. We are discovering what these capabilities are.
Speaker 5:  And I think 2023 is going to be wild
Speaker 5:  for this stuff. And we're gonna see, we're gonna see a lot of consequences
Speaker 5:  happen as well.
Speaker 4:  That that's where we should kind of wrap this up with.
Speaker 4:  Because to me, the image
Speaker 4:  based AI in some way,
Speaker 4:  that stuff is harder for a regular person to do. Right. A
Speaker 4:  a really good example is, you know, Casey used to work at The Verge and we
Speaker 4:  would illustrate his newsletter with actual designers and illustrators like
Speaker 4:  a human being who worked here most recently. Alex
Speaker 4:  Castro, who's a great illustrator, we're like illustrate Casey's newsletter
Speaker 4:  once a week. Right. Yeah. Casey now routinely has Dolly
Speaker 4:  illustrate the newsletter. Right. He like types a prompt into image generator
Speaker 4:  and like whatever it's done. And that there was a moment where that,
Speaker 4:  you know, all the arguments about, there was even like a minor controversy
Speaker 4:  about new publications using these tools Yeah. For illustrations instead
Speaker 4:  of hiring illustrators. But that stuff seems faddish even though it's
Speaker 4:  harder. Yeah. Right. Even though most people cannot illustrate anything on
Speaker 4:  their own. That stuff stylistically it comes and
Speaker 4:  goes the usages for those things, like
Speaker 4:  images expire in a way that, you know, like other kinds of formats
Speaker 4:  don't. It's the text side. It's the, you wrote me some
Speaker 4:  code or I've seen the number of advertising
Speaker 4:  people I have seen who are like, we're gonna spam the
Speaker 4:  most marketing text on the most content marketing blogs
Speaker 4:  that you have ever seen. This is a godsend for
Speaker 4:  the agencies. And it's like, first of all, all of you talk about
Speaker 4:  advertising is is though you're like boning. Like I,
Speaker 4:  there's like, if you just like are in that world, it's like you gotta
Speaker 4:  be less horny about ads. Like I just, that's my advice to all of you.
Speaker 4:  10% at least. Just like 10% less horny about advertising
Speaker 4:  Please. And then there is like, oh that's
Speaker 4:  real, right? Like if you run a small ad agency and you're
Speaker 4:  like hired to sell bottles of water and you need to make the
Speaker 4:  website, that's about how great the bottled water is. No, but he's reading
Speaker 4:  it anyway. Right. You're kinda like, what I need is a bunch of keywords for
Speaker 4:  Google. Yeah. So when people google bottled water, they
Speaker 4:  like, Google's like, well I found the site with a, a lot of bottled water
Speaker 4:  references on it. I
Speaker 6:  Do wonder if it's gonna like,
Speaker 4:  Oh, they're definitely not gonna hire some like 22 year old kid to do it.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. They're gonna be like, robot write me bottled water copy,
Speaker 6:  Write me my SEO copy. Go
Speaker 4:  And they're gonna edit it a little bit and they're gonna put it on their
Speaker 4:  website and they're already, they see it, they see the value of that
Speaker 4:  completely.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I wonder if that's actually,
Speaker 4:  I've seen
Speaker 6:  Bigger danger to
Speaker 4:  I will, I will, I will give a little hint about an episode of Decoder that
Speaker 4:  we have in our minds. There's a very famous hustle culture
Speaker 4:  gentleman out in the world. Yeah. I love
Speaker 4:  him. I've, I've, I've wanting this gentleman on decoder for a long
Speaker 4:  time. So I've been following him and I got recommended a bunch
Speaker 4:  of his staffers and one of his staffers has a TikTok.
Speaker 4:  It's like, you know how sometimes you need to write 45 tweets for
Speaker 4:  a campaign? Have you met chat G P T? Yeah. And he's like,
Speaker 4:  here's 45 tweets that I wrote for this campaign. Yeah. For like
Speaker 4:  our hustle culture product. And it's like, oh, that shit's gonna happen.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And that to me is more durable, more interesting,
Speaker 4:  more chaotic, more impactful than the image stuff. And
Speaker 4:  I think the image stuff gets all the press cuz most people can't make images.
Speaker 4:  Right. And obviously mo most people can make text, but the part
Speaker 4:  where it's, and maybe I'm biased cuz I make text for a living and I
Speaker 4:  also apparently talk about nothing on this podcast, but the part
Speaker 4:  where it's like, oh, like most of the texts on the internet is like,
Speaker 4:  so Google will find it. And so now we're gonna trick the Google robot with
Speaker 4:  our robot. Yeah. It's like, oh, we're in the end times. I love it
Speaker 4:  here.
Speaker 6:  Well it feels like, I mean that's what I was like, I think that's where
Speaker 6:  Google has to face the threat. It's not, oh, I can go and chat with this
Speaker 6:  thing and it'll give me results. It's, oh, other people can go chat with
Speaker 6:  it and it will give 'em results. Thus making Google SEO even more
Speaker 6:  worthless.
Speaker 4:  So James, you have written about Google exploring these models for
Speaker 4:  search and I feel like the biggest meme of the past week is this is gonna
Speaker 4:  replace Google and you actually wrote, we republished, repro
Speaker 4:  promoted a piece that you wrote a year ago about Google exploring this exact
Speaker 4:  idea and kind of walking away from it.
Speaker 5:  Well, I mean I don't think they walked away from it forever because as you
Speaker 5:  have pointed out, they love to demo this stuff. Like the, the
Speaker 5:  conversations with Mum and Lambda, which are two of their big large language
Speaker 5:  models, which are sort of their equivalence of G P T three. But they, they
Speaker 5:  did write this paper in May or June, 2021. I can't remember exactly
Speaker 5:  where they pointed out a lot of the problems with it. And
Speaker 5:  in my piece I I I sort of thought that actually it's problems they
Speaker 5:  faced before. The big one is the confidence in presenting what is potentially
Speaker 5:  false information. Large language models, because of the stochastic, they're
Speaker 5:  probabilistic nature. They, they cannot sort fact from fiction reliably.
Speaker 5:  There are probably ways around that. There's ways to build in I'm sure a
Speaker 5:  directory of knowledge that it checks against, that it looks for citations
Speaker 5:  with. But there is this problem with confidence. And we saw it
Speaker 5:  actually, I thought with Google Home where you used to ask Google a,
Speaker 5:  a question and it would not, it was not a Google search of course. It was
Speaker 5:  just, it would just give you the answer. And that ui, that presentation
Speaker 5:  is to me the same as chat G P T because there is confidence, there is no
Speaker 5:  outside sources and there is often a chance that you'll give the entirely
Speaker 5:  the wrong response. And it is something
Speaker 5:  that happens a lot. I, I I think these are fixable problems. I think
Speaker 5:  the question is, does a startup come up with
Speaker 5:  a better search engine, which is probably really janky and probably
Speaker 5:  actually causes a lot of trouble. Do they get that out there before Google
Speaker 5:  itself puts out a version which preserves its credibility?
Speaker 5:  The thing is, Google has much more to lose in this scenario, whereas a startup
Speaker 5:  can burn a lot of, like, it can create a lot of goodwill and
Speaker 5:  it can say, we're doing something fast, we're going to the moon with this.
Speaker 5:  And it can put out something that is potentially very dangerous and get away
Speaker 5:  with it and maybe scoop Google. I I think these things will,
Speaker 5:  there are problems with them, but I think they will be incorporated into
Speaker 5:  search in the next couple of years. And the question for me is whether who
Speaker 5:  gets that first, basically, what
Speaker 4:  Do you think the most interesting use of the technology has exists today
Speaker 4:  is
Speaker 5:  Just creating psychosis in its users? I think, I
Speaker 5:  think if you just, if you talk to these things for long enough, you will
Speaker 5:  go mad. There is a reason that guy, that a Google engineer was like,
Speaker 5:  you know what, it's alive. There's a reason we started the show by joking
Speaker 5:  about an AI religion, one of my favorite, one of my favorite books of
Speaker 5:  the last couple of years. And I, I dunno why, sorry, I dunno why I'm doing
Speaker 5:  this. This is a podcast anyway,
Speaker 4:  It's holding up a book. This is great. I'm
Speaker 5:  Holding up a book. It's, it is called Pharmaco ai and it's by an
Speaker 5:  artist, a writer, Kayo McDowell. And it is
Speaker 5:  an extended conversation with G P T three in
Speaker 5:  which Alado McDowell sort of reimagines G p t
Speaker 5:  three as this godhead as this sort of mythical
Speaker 5:  divine entity that drives the mad basically over the course
Speaker 5:  of the book. In my opinion. And I think the, the, the
Speaker 5:  weirdest and the most wonderful thing is the conversations we're gonna have
Speaker 5:  with what is essentially a, a really weird mirror of ourselves.
Speaker 5:  You know, for better or worse, these things are scraped from the internet
Speaker 5:  and we can influence them with our feedback. That means they are
Speaker 5:  like us. That it is something that reflects us back to us. And
Speaker 5:  I think that is gonna create some really, really strange cultural experiences
Speaker 5:  for everyone.
Speaker 4:  There's another version of G pt, they're coming out right? G P T four
Speaker 4:  is apparently on the horizon. Oh
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It's on the horizon.
Speaker 4:  What happens with it? What is the improve?
Speaker 6:  James so excited. Justin. I'm
Speaker 5:  Sorry. I did, I did that
Speaker 4:  Again. This is great. He did the Mr. Burns with his
Speaker 4:  fingers. That was, that
Speaker 5:  Was completely instinctive. I'm so embarrassed by that. I dunno why I did
Speaker 5:  that.
Speaker 6:  What's exciting? Why are you doing this? Well,
Speaker 5:  It's,
Speaker 4:  It's, well finally humankind will block out the sun.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Don't get shot by a baby.
Speaker 5:  Look, finally, I can get a, I can get an AI to do my job finally. I can just,
Speaker 5:  I can just get drunk on podcasts instead. It's all I've been out trying to
Speaker 5:  do. No, I, I don't know. I, I'm excited cuz I think
Speaker 5:  it's, it, hopefully it will be as much as leap forward as G PT three
Speaker 5:  was from GT two, which I use both programs, you know, I, I
Speaker 5:  I I play around with them and it was quite a step forward
Speaker 5:  actually. We don't know when it's gonna come out. There were rumors that
Speaker 5:  it would be the end of this year. It's now looking like it will be early
Speaker 5:  next year. And actually a lot of the rumors were basically about chat G P
Speaker 5:  T. But it's supposed to be much, much bigger, you know, in terms of the
Speaker 5:  parameters, which is the sort of metric by which you measure the size of
Speaker 5:  these and the complexity of these models. Actually no one knows anything
Speaker 5:  about it. Apart from that, there is just a lot of sort of like funny
Speaker 5:  rumors going around that, you know, G P T four is, you know,
Speaker 5:  the computational matrix is equal to the complexity of all organic life on
Speaker 5:  earth. Yeah. Which I believe is Douglas Adams. You know, it is that sort
Speaker 5:  of joke basically. But yeah, that should be early next year. And I'm with
Speaker 5:  ne Eli, I think this is gonna have like a huge influence on jobs.
Speaker 5:  I think this is actually, we're gonna start seeing industries change because
Speaker 5:  of this technology. Very soon
Speaker 4:  You, it's, we need to wrap this up, but what's fundamentally interesting
Speaker 4:  about that is I think in a popular imagination, the
Speaker 4:  automation has always replaced the blue collar jobs. And to
Speaker 4:  some extent that is true. And we're gonna, you know, we're gonna talk about
Speaker 4:  the TSMC factory that got opened in Arizona this way. Like yes, there's a
Speaker 4:  bunch of, like cars are built by robot arms now. Yeah. But it turns out the
Speaker 4:  AI is just like, it's coming for ad agencies, right. Just like
Speaker 4:  the way that Excel came for accounting firms. Yeah. And I don't think that
Speaker 4:  anybody has quite yet reckoned for that. The AI is coming
Speaker 4:  for mid-level Excel macro coders more than it is
Speaker 4:  coming for factory workers. Right. Because if you can just ask a
Speaker 4:  robot to be like, sort some dates and it spits out the code at you,
Speaker 4:  there's actually just like, kind of like a huge middle class of white collar
Speaker 4:  work that goes away and no one can check the AI's work because
Speaker 4:  it's so confident. Well,
Speaker 6:  And it's gonna create work too, right? Like all of these, every time you
Speaker 6:  do these queries and stuff, somebody somewhere is probably having to comb
Speaker 6:  through some of 'em and check 'em and make sure that things are getting labeled
Speaker 6:  properly and that everything's working because
Speaker 4:  This is a, that's what you, you wanna be the ai, the semantic AI data
Speaker 4:  checker.
Speaker 6:  I think that is
Speaker 4:  Probably a, that's a, that's a
Speaker 6:  Terrify novel
Speaker 4:  Job. That's a, that's a job of the future where you just go through and you
Speaker 4:  check the tags on the chat. G P T. Yep. This
Speaker 6:  Person's talking about porn with G P T and I'm, I'm here with
Speaker 6:  them.
Speaker 5:  I mean, if you guys answer any capture lately, we, you know, we, this is
Speaker 5:  already part of our day today lives.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, that's true. We've been doing it for a long time. This is a
Speaker 4:  fire hydrant, so we should let you go James. We should call out. James
Speaker 4:  has his own very good book called Beyond Measure, which is a delight
Speaker 4:  soon to be excerpted in the Verge when it comes out in the United States.
Speaker 4:  Tell us about your book, James. Oh,
Speaker 5:  It is a history of measurement. It is a sort of, you know, it's a
Speaker 5:  history. It's a science book, it's a sociology book. It's where does, where
Speaker 5:  do measurements come from? What do people do with them and why do Americans
Speaker 5:  hate the Metric system so much? Those are the three big questions I
Speaker 5:  tackle.
Speaker 4:  It's very good. It's very funny. I bought, I bought, I have a British copy
Speaker 4:  because I'm fancy. Oh damn. They bought, I bought it early. I see.
Speaker 4:  I bought an import. That's very nice. I used to do a seven inches. I bought
Speaker 4:  an import copy. You know, the US version has a bonus
Speaker 4:  edition of Train and Vain at the very end. It's not
Speaker 4:  labeled. All right. We've gone on too
Speaker 4:  long. James, thank you so much. Always a pleasure, man. Oh,
Speaker 5:  My pleasure. So nice to step in and yeah, speak to you guys later.
Speaker 4:  Bye-bye. All right, we'll be right back. We gotta talk about, well we gotta
Speaker 4:  talk about Apple. You on, there's all kinds of stuff. We'll be right
Speaker 4:  back.
Speaker 4:  All right, we're back.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, we we're back. You know, Eli, so we're here in
Speaker 6:  the office. Eli and I are, and I saw him hunched over his desk earlier today.
Speaker 6:  Just muttering FTC and Activision Blizzard. It
Speaker 6:  sounds like there's some stuff happening with the Microsoft Activision Blizzard
Speaker 6:  deal.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, it's like the least breaking, breaking news of all
Speaker 4:  time. I, I don't know how else to describe it. So the, the
Speaker 4:  FTC filed a lawsuit, right? There's some details about it
Speaker 4:  we should talk about, but Microsoft wants to buy Activision Blizzard.
Speaker 6:  They've wanted to for a while now for Active Blizz. Active Blizz,
Speaker 4:  Which makes Call of Duty.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. They said we're not gonna touch it. We're gonna, we're just gonna
Speaker 6:  let it do its thing. We promise it.
Speaker 4:  We'll talk about Call Duty a second. So they make Call duty, they make Candy
Speaker 4:  Crush, they make all Warcrafts makes all the money on Candy Crush,
Speaker 4:  by the way. Yeah. Phil Spencer was just on decoder talk about why
Speaker 4:  the deal wasn't anti-competitive,
Speaker 6:  Why it was so good. And even
Speaker 4:  Though Microsoft keeps running every studio like this is their third gigantic
Speaker 4:  studio that I feel. Right. Right. And they have obviously make a bunch of
Speaker 4:  other stuff. And so there's an all this back and forth specifically around
Speaker 4:  Call of Duty.
Speaker 6:  Yes.
Speaker 4:  Right. Sony is like, you're gonna take Call of Duty away from the PlayStation.
Speaker 4:  Gamers rise up, the gamers rose up. Microsoft is like, no,
Speaker 4:  Phil Spencer to us, to me has said many
Speaker 4:  times, we're gonna put Call of Duty on PlayStation as long as there's a Call
Speaker 4:  of Duty. Then there was this like sidelight conspiracy theory, which
Speaker 4:  was honestly my favorite conspiracy theory. That they would only do Call
Speaker 4:  of Duty on PlayStation as like an Xbox game pass streaming situation. I love
Speaker 4:  it. So Sony would be forced to Trojan Horse,
Speaker 4:  the Game Pass streaming app on the PlayStation. You support it. Call of Duty.
Speaker 4:  So I asked Phil about that. He got all riled up. He was like, no native
Speaker 4:  code. And I was like, how long is the deal? Initially they'd only offered
Speaker 4:  three years and Phil told me like, you can't write a contract
Speaker 4:  forever. Which is true. Right?
Speaker 6:  Like
Speaker 4:  I, this is not legal advice. This is not a legal show. If you're listening
Speaker 4:  to show without your lawyer making a mistake, please
Speaker 4:  drive immediately to the nearest lawyer's office to continue listening to
Speaker 4:  the show. I'll just ask G P T. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Should you sign a contract whose term is forever? And I
Speaker 4:  feel like very clearly the answer is no.
Speaker 6:  Even chat G P T will be like, don't do that.
Speaker 4:  Don't do that. Like, no, contracts are forever. So fi I get it. So
Speaker 4:  then Microsoft has been running around these past few weeks
Speaker 4:  trying to appease regulators in this country and in
Speaker 4:  Europe by saying, okay, we will commit to Call of Duty
Speaker 4:  for 10 years. Okay. Which is an awful long time. Yeah. Like they're gonna
Speaker 4:  be out of major world conflicts to mine and they will be fully in the
Speaker 4:  future.
Speaker 6:  They're already in the future. They
Speaker 4:  Like, they're gonna have to get rid of like, like all the World War II call
Speaker 4:  of Duties are done for
Speaker 6:  Yeah, they're done. They
Speaker 4:  Went to the future and they went back already. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Like Call of Duty is like, they're just gonna be out of wars. They're like
Speaker 4:  whatever AI Call of Duty is where we're at 10 years now. That was
Speaker 4:  not good enough. It was not good enough for the CMA in Europe, which is already
Speaker 4:  said, we're gonna stop it. We're starting an investigation. And then here
Speaker 4:  the FTC Federal Trade Commission has basically been rumbling
Speaker 4:  at this for a long time.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Just muttering to itself.
Speaker 4:  Just like we and I let this happen. So when I say there's some, like there's
Speaker 4:  a little bit of interest. Yeah. They filed the suit, the
Speaker 4:  lawsuit. Okay. We have not seen the complaint yet. The word on the street
Speaker 4:  is they're not gonna release it until Microsoft has like, God it until
Speaker 4:  Microsoft President Brad Smith has like sat down with a sniffer of
Speaker 4:  brandy and like read the complaint,
Speaker 6:  Put his little smoking jacket on.
Speaker 4:  But today, the day they said they're gonna do this complaint.
Speaker 4:  Oh, they also filed the complaint in their own administrative court, not
Speaker 4:  in federal court. Okay. Which is like tactically interesting. Yeah. Like
Speaker 4:  what do they actually want out of this? Do they actually wanna block the
Speaker 4:  deal or just a lot of bluster to get some concession? Who knows. But today,
Speaker 4:  the same day is the first day of the trial where the FTC
Speaker 4:  is has sued to stop meta
Speaker 4:  Facebook from buying within, which makes Supernatural, which
Speaker 4:  I have called the killer app for vr.
Speaker 6:  It's, it's pretty killer.
Speaker 4:  It's very good. So if you have a Quest to Supernatural is a fitness app
Speaker 4:  you like
Speaker 6:  It's Beat Saber, but you have to like sweat.
Speaker 4:  It's beat Saber Peloton. Yeah. Oh, they've added kicking. They
Speaker 6:  Had a
Speaker 4:  Kicking. Yeah. Knee strikes.
Speaker 6:  All right. Well I got, he's also boxing. I got some, the Boxing's great.
Speaker 6:  I like the boxing.
Speaker 4:  I think I've told this story in before. My wife did the boxing in Supernatural
Speaker 4:  one time, grinned the whole time, then took off the headset and said, I'm
Speaker 4:  great at boxing.
Speaker 6:  It's like,
Speaker 4:  That's what you want. Right? So this, this thing's great. It sells a lot
Speaker 4:  of headsets. Chris Milk, the CEO within has been on decoder. He's like
Speaker 4:  super, the supernatural community is like 50 50 men and women and it's
Speaker 4:  people over 40, which is not a traditional VR
Speaker 4:  measure base. Like this is the thing, this app initiates people. They're
Speaker 4:  buying the quest too cuz it's good. So medicine, screw it. We're we buy every
Speaker 4:  other VR game, we're gonna buy Supernatural. They went and bought it. FTC
Speaker 4:  sued them. This deal is like teeny tiny. They're buying this thing for like
Speaker 4:  20 bucks. Yeah. And it's an app for VR headsets. Yeah. The market size
Speaker 4:  of six. Like they're the biggest fish in a tiny, tiny, tiny
Speaker 4:  pond. If the FCC is gonna block that deal,
Speaker 4:  they basically had no choice
Speaker 6:  But to
Speaker 4:  Block, to block the Activision deal. It's like Right. Obviously console gaming
Speaker 4:  is much bigger. Activision itself is much
Speaker 4:  bigger. Microsoft very opportunistically
Speaker 4:  swept in because Body Dad vision is
Speaker 4:  like,
Speaker 6:  I mean, Activision Blizzard has been facing some bad times for us.
Speaker 4:  Right. Like numerous allegations of like weird sexual misconduct across
Speaker 4:  the company. Yep.
Speaker 6:  A lot of people have been let go for, for misconduct. There's a lot
Speaker 6:  of union organizing happening and because of the misconduct. Yeah. I would
Speaker 6:  not wanna work there right now. It seems really busy.
Speaker 4:  Yeah,
Speaker 6:  It seems unpleasant. And,
Speaker 4:  And so Microsoft very openly, like after this first wave of allegations,
Speaker 4:  they just like showed up and they're like, wouldn't it be great if you didn't
Speaker 4:  run this company anymore?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Just give it to us. Give
Speaker 4:  It to us. And so like there's just a lot of noise. If you're gonna, if
Speaker 4:  you are the FTC and you have to, and you have sued to block meta from like
Speaker 4:  Supernatural. And by the way that complaint, you know, I'm anti, I think
Speaker 4:  murders are bad. But the complaint, the FTCs complaining that is like we
Speaker 4:  tr we've tried Supernatural. It's a very good, like you
Speaker 4:  shouldn't have it. Right? If you buy Supernatural, you will not turn
Speaker 4:  Beat Saber into a proper competitor for Supernatural. And I think
Speaker 4:  rightfully meta, the Beat Saber team were like, what are
Speaker 4:  you talking about? Like in what world is Beat Saber turning into a
Speaker 4:  A Peloton?
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Like no, that's like
Speaker 6:  What in the world of the FTC where they want beats,
Speaker 4:  They have to find some reason. So they, they filed this, we have not read
Speaker 4:  it. They filed it in this administrative court. They have said
Speaker 4:  to Axios or someone has said to Axios, they're not asking
Speaker 4:  to actually like block the deal at this time. So the deal
Speaker 4:  might still close. So they've sued to block the deal, so it shouldn't happen.
Speaker 4:  But they've not asked their own administrative court to be like, yeah,
Speaker 4:  don't let 'em do it. So there's a little nuance in there that I,
Speaker 4:  without having read the complaint, that I can't quite tell you about and
Speaker 4:  the complaint's not out yet. But you just get the sense that like the Europeans
Speaker 4:  are definitely on firmer ground when it comes to blocking mergers. That's
Speaker 4:  like what they're good at. Yeah. And the FTC is like, we're also finally
Speaker 4:  su and maybe what we want is some intensely hardcore
Speaker 4:  concessions. And this is like calibrated to achieve that
Speaker 4:  result while they go fight this other battle around
Speaker 4:  supernatural in court where they, well, you know,
Speaker 4:  Lenahan su approve her theory because
Speaker 6:  The supernatural, that's not in the administrative law
Speaker 4:  Court. That's in, that's in court. Court. Court. Yeah. And you know, there's
Speaker 4:  other cases against Facebook and others that she has filed. She's the
Speaker 4:  chairwoman of the ftc. She's got novel theories about
Speaker 4:  competition. And I again completely honest, like I agree
Speaker 4:  with most of her theories, the courts in this country are like, that's
Speaker 4:  new, new ideas. You say, no thank you. They
Speaker 6:  Don't understand what a phone is.
Speaker 4:  They're deeply confused about how some of this technology works and
Speaker 4:  particularly network effects and like how you might lock people in. So,
Speaker 4:  and we're seeing this with Apple and Epic, right? Like there's just
Speaker 4:  some baseline confusion about what creates
Speaker 4:  lockin for a consumer. Yeah. Or where anti-competitive in these markets might
Speaker 4:  come from. And then there's the real problem, and this is partially the true
Speaker 4:  of Apple and Epic and some of these other cases where the, our country
Speaker 4:  in particular for about 40 years has been like
Speaker 4:  mergers. Great.
Speaker 6:  Love a merger,
Speaker 4:  Love a merger. Bigger the better. Shit, you should buy some shit. Yeah. Right.
Speaker 4:  And so you've gotta just overcome a lot of precedent
Speaker 4:  to, to block a merger. So I, I just see it like, I see where this case
Speaker 4:  is calibrated and I see that the Europeans wanna block it too.
Speaker 4:  And what we'll just see. I don't Do you think it's gonna, like Microsoft
Speaker 4:  is like running out there. And again, you should listen to the conversation
Speaker 4:  I had with, with Phil about it on decoder. He made his case. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Right. And it's very funny when a big company wants to buy something, the
Speaker 4:  case is always, but we suck.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. We suck so much. Let us buy this. This
Speaker 4:  Market is so competitive. We've been getting our a kicked, we're nowhere
Speaker 4:  in mobile games. We need to buy Candy Crush. Yeah. Call on duty. You could
Speaker 4:  have Call of Duty the futures mobile. Right? Like go listen to it. It's,
Speaker 4:  bill is very good. The man was born to be the CEO of Microsoft
Speaker 4:  Duty. He's very, very good at that
Speaker 4:  job, you know, and he is a candid
Speaker 4:  executive, so you're gonna listen to it. But the argument basically boils
Speaker 4:  down to if we don't grow, we die. And all the growth is in mobile,
Speaker 4:  so we have to buy Activision so we can get mobile games. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And all the stuff we're talking about with our consoles is like kind of a
Speaker 4:  sidelight. Would you
Speaker 6:  Buy it? I mean, I don't, because that's not their biggest
Speaker 6:  market, right? Like Xbox is certainly a big part of
Speaker 6:  Microsoft, but cloud computing is a much bigger part of
Speaker 6:  Microsoft. Yeah. And so, so for them to say this, it's just like super
Speaker 6:  disingenuous because like, yeah, they're a gaming company, but they're a
Speaker 6:  cloud company first and foremost, even more so than, than
Speaker 6:  they're an operating system company or any of these other things. Like they
Speaker 6:  do cloud computing. So to say this is just like some
Speaker 6:  bullshit.
Speaker 4:  I feel like, I mean, I, I honestly don't know where this is gonna go. Like
Speaker 4:  this is a, this is a big case. This is a generationally important in
Speaker 4:  antitrust case. Yeah. Because there's, we just have
Speaker 4:  not stopped deals like this as a country.
Speaker 6:  I thought it was kind of interesting that we've seen Microsoft go on this
Speaker 6:  spree around the same time that we also saw like one of the biggest
Speaker 6:  kind of halts in vertical integration in the entertainment community
Speaker 6:  go away, which was the paramount decree that was like from the thirties
Speaker 6:  that they, they got rid of a couple of years ago. And that Paramount decree
Speaker 6:  said, if you are making the movies, you cannot own the theaters
Speaker 6:  because that's really hinky because then you get to control where your movies
Speaker 6:  screen. Yeah. And the exact, like, we're dealing with that issue
Speaker 6:  in streaming and we're dealing with it in gaming. If, if Microsoft is making
Speaker 6:  the game consoles, they probably shouldn't also be making the games
Speaker 6:  because then they control where those games go. And like, it's
Speaker 6:  fundamentally the same thing. But I know that our country has said,
Speaker 6:  yeah, consent, Paramounts consent decree don't need it.
Speaker 6:  We're fine. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Well, so to abstract that out, it's, it's usually like, you know, vertical
Speaker 4:  versus horizontal mergers, right? Right. And so we allow vertical ones,
Speaker 4:  or we have for the past 40 years, which is the theaters, were the only distribution.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And if you own all the distribution, you have a lot of power over the,
Speaker 4:  the studios. And so the studios shouldn't own the theaters because then the
Speaker 4:  other studio they can unfairly Right.
Speaker 6:  Discriminate. Disney can say, you will never see another MGM movie in our
Speaker 6:  theaters again. And
Speaker 4:  We own all the theaters. So they like, now you can't do that. The theaters
Speaker 4:  have to be competitive. You can like apply that lesson to the
Speaker 4:  iOS app store. Yeah. You can apply that lesson to Comcast. Like whatever
Speaker 4:  it is. Like whoever owns the pipes or the distribution here. I think you're
Speaker 4:  saying like the game consoles are, they're like the distribution.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. The game consoles are the theater. Right, right. Like, and and they
Speaker 6:  have a very robust, big business there. If they're making the theaters,
Speaker 6:  they probably shouldn't also be making the content that goes into those theaters.
Speaker 6:  In this case, all of the games at Activision Blizzard, one of the largest
Speaker 6:  gaming companies not currently owned by Microsoft.
Speaker 6:  Like Yeah. Or Nintendo existing.
Speaker 10:  One thing that makes it a little more complicated is that generally the
Speaker 10:  councils are sold at a loss. They're not necessarily profiting on the actual
Speaker 10:  consoles themselves. The,
Speaker 6:  Because they're profiting
Speaker 10:  On those business analogy, they're the games profit on the games. And I
Speaker 10:  guess Microsoft is claiming that they would love to make more money from
Speaker 10:  games. So of course they'll sell Call of Duty on PlayStation or Nintendo
Speaker 10:  or Esteem because everyone wants to play Call of Duty on Switch. That's,
Speaker 10:  that's what you want. Yes.
Speaker 4:  By the way, Nintendo happily took the 10-year dear for Call of Duty. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  No complaints filed. No, no letters to the senators.
Speaker 4:  They're like 10 years of Call of Duty on the switch. We'll take it cuz
Speaker 4:  they
Speaker 6:  Don't give shit. Did they, did, did that specify what kind of Call of Duty?
Speaker 6:  Like is it just gonna be the mobile gross version that's on your
Speaker 6:  phone?
Speaker 4:  I don't think matters to Nintendo. I think Nintendo is,
Speaker 6:  Nintendo
Speaker 4:  Doesn't care that anybody who owns a console also probably wants to play
Speaker 4:  Mario. Yeah. And they've got an absolute rock solid, legally
Speaker 4:  defensible monopoly on Mario. And he's never going anywhere
Speaker 4:  except Nintendo consoles.
Speaker 6:  It is very funny that we're like, oh, I don't know if, if if
Speaker 6:  Microsoft can own Call of Duty and Nintendo is like, we own
Speaker 6:  everything on our platform and
Speaker 4:  We'll just, well that's their model. I mean, they're the apple of this industry
Speaker 4:  and Microsoft is the Microsoft, but what I
Speaker 10:  Want all is what kind of concessions could the FTC get? And, and I'm very
Speaker 10:  specific about Monique, I need to be able to use controllers across, across
Speaker 10:  platforms. I don't like buying controllers,
Speaker 10:  I don't need dual, I don't wanna use dual sense. I just wanna use my Xbox
Speaker 10:  Elite controller everywhere. So we need to fix that. Le con
Speaker 4:  Lena, if you're listening step,
Speaker 10:  I need to be able to use my gaming headsets across every single platform.
Speaker 10:  They need to all be compatible. We, we need to fix this. We need the online
Speaker 10:  accounts and friends list to transfer back and forth. Just
Speaker 6:  That cross
Speaker 10:  Play. The blockchain fixes this. I'm not saying that I'm the last person
Speaker 10:  on Crypto Island now, and now that everyone else is running from it, I'm
Speaker 10:  going to die on this hill alone. But the blockchain does fix this. Just
Speaker 10:  saying. So I think those are my concerns. You
Speaker 4:  Okay? Look, historically on the Vergecast, I have
Speaker 4:  assigned de many articles based on throwaway comments.
Speaker 4:  Richard, welcome to your role filling in for David
Speaker 4:  while he's out on parental leave. You gotta write the gamers,
Speaker 4:  the gamers' Bill of Rights. Like what should the FTC ask for from a gamers'
Speaker 4:  perspective? Yes. To make this deal. Go, go through,
Speaker 6:  Get really nuanced about the skins. You wanna
Speaker 6:  sing
Speaker 4:  A gamers demand. You should
Speaker 10:  Never have to pay for a recolor again. Ever. If if it's not a new completely
Speaker 10:  new design, then you can't tell it. I should be able to get whatever colors
Speaker 10:  I want. I'm
Speaker 4:  Just saying this is great. We gotta, we gotta do this. If you have ideas
Speaker 4:  for Richard, you can tweet him. You can email him. We're gonna put this together.
Speaker 4:  We'll send it to the ftc. Yeah. I'm never getting an FTC official on the
Speaker 4:  on decoder again. Like it's never gonna happen. I think
Speaker 6:  They'll see this and be like, oh, they get it. They get it. This
Speaker 6:  is why we put it in administrative law court.
Speaker 4:  Look, I'm saying this is a generationally important antitrust case. Like
Speaker 4:  if they get this one through it, what it will signal
Speaker 4:  is if the FCC wins this, let say it, if the FCC
Speaker 4:  wins this and they block this deal, it will signal competition law in the
Speaker 4:  United States is changing. If they lose it, it means either someone
Speaker 4:  promised Lena Conn controller interop, which maybe that's all we
Speaker 4:  need. Or it means that like we live to fight another day.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Right. And I will say that in this lame duck period of Congress,
Speaker 4:  the big antitrust bills are on the floor. There's a lot of momentum around
Speaker 4:  them, particularly the, the app store interoperability built. Like
Speaker 4:  there's, there's stuff, the digital markets act like all this stuff.
Speaker 4:  There's more antitrust noise
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Happening right now than has happened in a while. This lawsuit's a piece
Speaker 4:  of it, the meta supernatural case, which again is a very small compared to
Speaker 4:  the Activision deal, but it, it is a signal of
Speaker 4:  where the government wants to apply pressure and then there are the bills
Speaker 4:  in Congress. So we'll see.
Speaker 6:  We'll see. And I mean, other things we saw this week we
Speaker 6:  should probably talk about kind of related, I'm gonna, I'm gonna go all the
Speaker 6:  way back to how we talked about the EU is also suing. They're
Speaker 4:  Just nuts man. They're just like eating cheese and being like, we got ideas.
Speaker 6:  We got ideas. And you will do them including Apple. You
Speaker 6:  will have u s BBC on your phones and they set
Speaker 6:  a deadline for that this week.
Speaker 4:  December 28th, 2024.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. So by December 28th, 2024, you will
Speaker 6:  have new phones with u s BBC for wired charging. So
Speaker 6:  including iPhones. Theoretically
Speaker 4:  I can I just say something about this story? Okay. They're
Speaker 4:  Europeans, they can't help themselves. Like the EU is so needlessly complicated.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And we have an amazing international team that is mostly based in Europe.
Speaker 4:  It heard from James, John Porter is our reporter who's been working
Speaker 4:  on this story. Yeah. And like he has basically written a
Speaker 4:  version of the headline European Union mandate to USBC
Speaker 4:  for phones 500 times or,
Speaker 6:  And we make him do it again
Speaker 4:  And we make him do it again and again. Mostly because it's like interesting.
Speaker 4:  We should track the story. We have a responsibility as journalist Yeah. To
Speaker 4:  accurately convey. And also because it's traffic gold. Like people
Speaker 4:  see this headline and they lose their minds like, how can I pick on this
Speaker 4:  twice? And it's like, we've written a story like
Speaker 4:  every other week for five years. So he's, he writes, he's
Speaker 4:  excited. I'm like, yeah, we finally have a final official deadline
Speaker 4:  for one new phone sold in the European Union, including future iPhones will
Speaker 4:  have to use U P C and December 20th, 2024.
Speaker 4:  The next paragraph, the new rules will
Speaker 4:  officially enter into force in 20 days times an
Speaker 4:  individual EU member states will then have a maximum of
Speaker 4:  24 months to write national laws.
Speaker 6:  No. It's
Speaker 4:  Like, oh, this still hasn't happened, is it?
Speaker 6:  He's got, we have to make him do one for every single
Speaker 6:  country. Luxembourg, John, we have
Speaker 6:  to know what Luxembourg voted on. It's
Speaker 4:  Like, oh man, it still hasn't happened.
Speaker 6:  It hasn't happened in Belgium. All right. It's done.
Speaker 4:  It's like, alright, this is just like fully ridiculous.
Speaker 6:  He's got like a map in his house. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  It's like somewhere someone in the EU like runs like a, like a traffic
Speaker 4:  bait website and they're like, let's stretch it out. Like we know people
Speaker 4:  love this story just
Speaker 6:  Is
Speaker 4:  Another 24 months of US BBC iPhone
Speaker 4:  clicks.
Speaker 6:  So good.
Speaker 4:  It's good. So that's the date, that's
Speaker 6:  That's this implies
Speaker 4:  Theoretically the sort of 2025
Speaker 6:  IPhone thing. iPhone 16.
Speaker 4:  Oh
Speaker 6:  Because it says all new phones have to be using it by
Speaker 6:  2024. So that's not the
Speaker 4:  Year that the iPhone that gets announced in 2024
Speaker 6:  Sh will have to be US
Speaker 4:  Bbc. So right now we're on the 14, which is the iPhone that was announced
Speaker 6:  2022. Yeah. So
Speaker 6:  15
Speaker 4:  Is 2023
Speaker 6:  And then 16 is 2024. So this will be the iPhone
Speaker 6:  16 should theoretically be u s bbc.
Speaker 6:  Unless they decide to be like, you know what eu, you don't get a phone this
Speaker 6:  year.
Speaker 4:  That'd be amazing.
Speaker 6:  Just nevermind.
Speaker 4:  We'll see. Importantly you might recall that the
Speaker 4:  UK is no longer in the European Union. Notably
Speaker 4:  they just don't get either. United States is not, I don't believe China is
Speaker 4:  in the European Union. All gigantic markets for Apple.
Speaker 6:  Unclear of China's in the European Union. Like
Speaker 4:  I'm, I'm not a geologist.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Who knows what kind of rocks they got going on over there.
Speaker 4:  That's been a long one. And also I think James is drinking beer rubbed off
Speaker 4:  of me. But I'm say those are giant markets. It's raffle. They could make
Speaker 4:  Lightning iPhones and US VC iPhones. We don't know what they're gonna do.
Speaker 6:  Just that one. They, they released like 500 of them limited edition in
Speaker 6:  Germany and in
Speaker 4:  Brazil they still have to put the charger in the box. That's true. I got
Speaker 4:  a real taste of careful what you wish for last week. So I
Speaker 4:  went home for Thanksgiving. Yeah. You know, did the turned motion smoothing
Speaker 4:  off on all the TVs first thing you know, ran around fixing stuff at my parents'
Speaker 4:  house. Bought them the new Apple TV remotes. Yeah. So they
Speaker 4:  had the old black ones, they were horrible. Whatever. Did
Speaker 6:  They also have scotch tape on theirs? Like my mom does.
Speaker 4:  It's a long story. My parents finally shut down their at and t U versus cable
Speaker 4:  boxes. It's a five year victory. If
Speaker 4:  you've been listening, you know, I haven't been working on this for five
Speaker 4:  years and they switched to the cable company. Now they're doing all their
Speaker 4:  TV through the Apple tv. Got rid of the cable boxes, consolidate three months
Speaker 4:  by the near remotes. Yeah. Spot near mos. Just went to Best Buy. Pulled three
Speaker 4:  of 'em off the shelf, came home, set 'em up. Off we go. Little do I know
Speaker 4:  that I bought two of the older Lightning
Speaker 4:  remotes and one of the new
Speaker 4:  u s BBC remotes. So I get, this is the most
Speaker 4:  bizarre text from my dad who's like, I'm using
Speaker 4:  the kitchen tv. Is the plug different?
Speaker 4:  And like, just out of context, they're like, what are you talking about?
Speaker 4:  Like, is the plug in the wall? Would you buy
Speaker 6:  A new TV
Speaker 4:  From Europe? Are you plugging the tv? Like just leave it, let's stop it.
Speaker 4:  So I'm like, what do you mean? And he is like, the plugs for the other two
Speaker 4:  rooms work fine, but this one doesn't. And it's like, you know, it's like
Speaker 4:  I'm at work, I'm like different plan. I'm like, just call me, send me a picture.
Speaker 4:  And he sends me a picture of the bottom room. I'm like, you gotta be kidding.
Speaker 4:  Like this is, I asked for this, I asked for everything to be
Speaker 4:  u s bbc and now there's one US BBC Apple device in my parents'
Speaker 4:  house. Just one. And it is just like the crime of the
Speaker 4:  century.
Speaker 6:  Did you try to explain to 'em they could use their phone as a remote because
Speaker 6:  it doesn't work?
Speaker 4:  Absolutely not. I told them that they could could plug and this, when
Speaker 4:  I say this is like a Galaxy Brain moment, I was like, just use the charger
Speaker 4:  from your Chromebook and I plugged it in air and they're like, will will
Speaker 4:  it explode? Because you're just like, not, you're not supposed
Speaker 4:  to do this.
Speaker 10:  Ben Leon has a lot of evidence that that might happen. I'm just
Speaker 10:  saying.
Speaker 4:  But it was, I was like, oh God, I asked, I asked for this. You did. I
Speaker 4:  was like, apple make it all u s bbc. And they're like one out of three.
Speaker 6:  That's what's gonna happen with the iPhones. You're gonna get both of them
Speaker 6:  iPhones and for some reason one will be u s BBC and the other will
Speaker 6:  not just
Speaker 4:  Dealers
Speaker 6:  Choice Dad, you can charge with the
Speaker 6:  Chromebook. You have to go find the remote.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  All right. Other stuff, Richard, what's going on with Elon this week? I feel
Speaker 4:  like it's a vert. We could go the entire show without talking about Elon
Speaker 6:  And Twitter. Speed run it go
Speaker 10:  Not nearly as much as there has been before. Okay. Everyone else is trying
Speaker 10:  to build their own Twitter. People who used to work for Twitter, other
Speaker 10:  tech engineers, Tumblr, of course Alex
Speaker 10:  is always ready to be the new Twitter.
Speaker 6:  They're ready.
Speaker 10:  And so if, if you're looking for a better Twitter, there are options. I
Speaker 10:  went back to Black Planet, I've had that account for 20 years. I'm never
Speaker 10:  leaving. Meanwhile,
Speaker 10:  at Twitter, Elon still somehow needs to try and make money from the company
Speaker 10:  that he now owns. And his plan is this Twitter blue
Speaker 10:  subscription that he thinks everyone will pay for to be verified and to
Speaker 10:  make sure that your tweets actually show up so that people can see them.
Speaker 10:  The latest thing that we've heard is that if you purchase this from your
Speaker 10:  iPhone, it might cost more that it would cost $7 per month if
Speaker 10:  you subscribe on the web or $11 via the iOS app. No one has mentioned Google
Speaker 10:  Play, I guess doesn't really matter. But you know, getting around the, the
Speaker 10:  Apple Commission that way. And that was the whole battle and back and forth
Speaker 10:  that they had. That culminated with Elon going to see Tim Cook and
Speaker 10:  reaching some kind of agreement. So may maybe this is the, the outcome of
Speaker 10:  that.
Speaker 4:  So the public facts of this agreement are now I think well known. So Apple
Speaker 4:  had pulled back on its advertising spend. Like most big companies it didn't
Speaker 4:  because they didn't know about the trust and
Speaker 6:  They were the biggest
Speaker 4:  Advertiser. And you are the biggest advertiser. Alex has pointed this out.
Speaker 4:  Apple spends no money on meta, just none. So no Instagram. No.
Speaker 4:  Which makes sense. They don't like each other. Yeah. So where's that money
Speaker 4:  gonna go? It has gone to Twitter. So Apple's one of Twitter's biggest accounts.
Speaker 4:  So Apple pulls back their advertising. Elon tweets don't you
Speaker 4:  support free speech in America? Then there's this weird issue
Speaker 4:  which we still kind of don't understand, where Apple's
Speaker 4:  like you've gotta comply with our moderation rules to the app store or we're
Speaker 4:  gonna pull you. Or they just remind as they often do
Speaker 4:  mafia style,
Speaker 6:  They just sat there with a baseball bat.
Speaker 4:  They just drove in their hand the store holding a rock. And they're like,
Speaker 4:  no way. Those windows, it would sure be a shame.
Speaker 6:  Wouldn't want anything to happen to him.
Speaker 4:  So Elon gets mad. Tim Cook summons
Speaker 4:  Elon. Oh, and and Elon gets mad about the 30% tax.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Yeah. And she's been mad about for a while
Speaker 6:  He suddenly discovered, he was like, guys, I have brand new information.
Speaker 6:  There's a 30% tax.
Speaker 4:  But we talked about this last week. A bunch of Republican Congress people
Speaker 4:  get all up in arms, antitrust bill becomes a threat. Tim Cook
Speaker 4:  summons Elon to the spaceship. We don't know
Speaker 4:  what the deal was. Yeah. Who leaves? But now it's publicly revealed. Apple's
Speaker 4:  ad spending has gone back up and Elon has agreed to up
Speaker 4:  the price of Twitter blue on iOS 30%. So
Speaker 4:  it's like, oh, you just, Apple's paying you the money and ads and then you're
Speaker 4:  gonna pay it back to them in app store fees. That is the deal that the
Speaker 4:  the most genius business people of
Speaker 6:  Our, they did it have
Speaker 4:  Constructed.
Speaker 6:  Nailed
Speaker 4:  It. Here's what we're gonna do. We're gonna start advertising on Twitter
Speaker 4:  again, increase your revenue and then when you launch your paid product,
Speaker 4:  which you wants to be 50% of Twitter's revenue, 30% of that will come
Speaker 4:  right back to the old spaceship. Yep. Tim's like, all right, that you good.
Speaker 4:  I've gotta go do some supply chain stuff and Elon left
Speaker 4:  like that appears to be the deal. Yeah. That is all. And
Speaker 4:  that the advertising information is directly from Elon. What we
Speaker 4:  will see what the price of Twitter blue is when it comes out. But all indications
Speaker 4:  are when
Speaker 6:  It returns.
Speaker 4:  When it returns. But all indications are, it will be priced at, at
Speaker 4:  30% above the web price to account for that fee.
Speaker 4:  And as we all know, most things Apple
Speaker 4:  collects that fee because most of the money is made on the phone. Yeah. A
Speaker 4:  beautiful circle.
Speaker 6:  I love it. Like it's as beautiful a circle as the spaceship
Speaker 6:  itself. I'm sorry
Speaker 4:  You
Speaker 6:  Did it. I did it.
Speaker 4:  The modern economy.
Speaker 6:  You know what, let's, let's talk about Apple some more. Let's, let's, let's
Speaker 6:  get away from talking about, oh,
Speaker 4:  There's good Apple
Speaker 6:  Stuff. There's good apple stuff. Yeah. We got, so Apple announced a bunch
Speaker 6:  of encryption stuff this week, right. Richard? I think you were watching
Speaker 6:  it like in it, in the weeds on this. Yes.
Speaker 10:  This was a bit of a surprise, but it, it is major, major
Speaker 10:  news and, and I'm not sure if everyone, when you see this, if you understand
Speaker 10:  exactly how big this is, but a lot of the people who pay attention to security
Speaker 10:  and privacy on our devices on the internet see this as one of the, the biggest
Speaker 10:  announcements that they'll hear I guess around this time of the year. What
Speaker 10:  Apple has done is that they've announced a number of security announcements
Speaker 10:  and one of the most impactful ones is an optional program that
Speaker 10:  they're calling advanced data protection. And if you opt into it, then it
Speaker 10:  expands the number of data categories as they they call them, that are
Speaker 10:  protected by end-to-end encryption. And they've always talked about how
Speaker 10:  they have end-to-end encryption on a lot of things so that no one can really
Speaker 10:  spy on your data. Even on Apples end, if the government asks them to give
Speaker 10:  it up, they can't because they don't have access to it. It can only be decrypted
Speaker 10:  on your device.
Speaker 6:  Right.
Speaker 10:  But that did not apply to iPhone backups. So while something like
Speaker 10:  iMessage might be encrypted into end and they, they kept saying that it
Speaker 10:  is, if you or the person you're messaging has a, a backup of their iPhone
Speaker 10:  that is then uploaded to the iCloud servers. If, for example, if somehow
Speaker 10:  someone accessed your account or if they got a warrant from the government
Speaker 10:  to access it, they could simply access the unencrypted data very
Speaker 10:  easily. Right. And that won't be possible anymore once this rolls
Speaker 10:  out because, you know, your iPhone backups will, will be one of the categories
Speaker 10:  that are now protected by encryption. Which, which is just a very significant
Speaker 10:  change in one that, that the f fbi now that this has been announced and
Speaker 10:  said that they're not happy about. Yeah. Rather predictably,
Speaker 4:  Apple famously fought a huge battle with the FBI in 2016.
Speaker 6:  This is San Bernardino shootings right
Speaker 4:  Around unlocking the shooter's phone. The FBI has wanted a backdoor and
Speaker 4:  an encryption. Apple has famously said no. The most interesting turn of
Speaker 4:  this story, which we need to learn more about is,
Speaker 4:  was it last year?
Speaker 6:  Were
Speaker 4:  They earlier this year? The Csam thing? The csam thing. Apple, that was last
Speaker 4:  year announced. That was last year.
Speaker 10:  Yeah. Late, late last year. They announced these changes to Csam where would,
Speaker 10:  if you were backing up a photo on iCloud photos, it would then
Speaker 10:  scan the photo while it's still on your device, not on apples in, not
Speaker 10:  on the servers. And you know, kind of create a, a hash a
Speaker 10:  hash of it and try to match that to known child sexual abuse imagery
Speaker 10:  and alert someone if it finds out.
Speaker 6:  And everybody was mad
Speaker 10:  About it and no. And yeah, privacy, security, everyone was very
Speaker 10:  upset about this because the, it's kind of a, a, it's a slippery slope now
Speaker 10:  we're you're doing scanning on people's personal devices. B if those hashes,
Speaker 10:  if someone somehow gets something into the database that's like, we're looking
Speaker 10:  for government documents, you know, now suddenly your phone is leaking that
Speaker 10:  information there, there are a number of bad outcomes here. And now Apple
Speaker 10:  has has said that that program is dead. They're not going to do it.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And I, I think longtime listeners in this show will
Speaker 4:  recall Apple was real shady about all of that. When it
Speaker 4:  rolled it out, they rolled it out. It wouldn't tell us who the researchers
Speaker 4:  were. All of its communications were like Unsourced.
Speaker 6:  They're like, just enjoy it. It's gonna be great.
Speaker 4:  Just shut up. They were holding these briefings without telling anybody who
Speaker 4:  anybody was talking to. Yeah. And they had basically courted all this
Speaker 4:  controversy and then they said, we're putting it on pause. And the
Speaker 4:  trade-off, I, I wanna be clear, the trade-off that Apple was trying to make
Speaker 4:  on paper was a good trade-off, which is we want
Speaker 4:  to protect your data as much as we can. We want to keep the
Speaker 4:  government and the cops out of our servers. We want to protect your
Speaker 4:  privacy, but we know that bad people do bad
Speaker 4:  things and the category of bad things that everybody agrees on
Speaker 4:  without a shadow of a doubt is csam. So we're going to
Speaker 4:  build in a, a somehow privacy respecting feature
Speaker 4:  that scans your phone for this material
Speaker 4:  before it hits our servers. And that that way we can encrypt
Speaker 4:  what's on the servers. We can encrypt iCloud. Yeah. Because Google,
Speaker 4:  Microsoft, every other cloud service is scanning their data stores
Speaker 4:  for csun. Right. They're all doing it. Like, and they
Speaker 4:  should like, everyone agrees that this is a bad thing. Apple's like we want
Speaker 4:  to go one step farther and encrypt the backup so we can't read it cuz our
Speaker 4:  other choice is to do everyone else does and scan iCloud.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  So they're like, okay, we'll move this scanning to your phone and again on
Speaker 4:  paper, this trade off makes some kind of sense.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I think in a vacuum, I think like if you're sitting in a room with
Speaker 6:  a bunch of people who've been working on this problem for years, which I
Speaker 6:  assume was, was happening at Apple. You say this and you go Yes. Awesome.
Speaker 6:  Perfect. And then they didn't actually check with
Speaker 6:  anyone else until right before I think they, like, they reached out
Speaker 6:  to the EF f and a couple other folks right before they were gonna do it and
Speaker 6:  they're like, we're gonna do this. And they were all like, cool. Yeah, you
Speaker 6:  waited way too late. This is a terrible plan and everything about it is bad
Speaker 6:  because you were still create fundamentally creating a backdoor into
Speaker 6:  people's devices and anybody with access to this database can
Speaker 6:  really misappropriate it and use it.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And we have episodes of decoder and Avir like in the
Speaker 4:  controversy of why it was bad, but that was the trade off. Right? Right.
Speaker 4:  Everyone assumed that Apple is rolling out the scanning feature so they could
Speaker 4:  get the desired end state of encrypted
Speaker 4:  iCloud. Yeah. It's a year later they've rolled out encrypted
Speaker 4:  iCloud and they are canceling the phone
Speaker 4:  scanning, which is utterly fascinating to
Speaker 6:  Me. And they also added another thing which I thought was really interesting
Speaker 6:  cause one of the responses to this was, well, if you create this database
Speaker 6:  that is like managed by the government,
Speaker 6:  then other governments can misuse this, misuse this database.
Speaker 6:  And one of the things they also announced this week was like, they claim
Speaker 6:  that iMessage can possibly alert you if state
Speaker 6:  sponsored spies are eavesdropping on. That's good. You that's good. And it's
Speaker 6:  like, okay, so y'all just went hard in the other direction Yeah. To
Speaker 6:  say, nah, fuck the police
Speaker 4:  Good. Basically
Speaker 6:  That's Tim Cooke. Yeah. That's
Speaker 4:  Tim K When I think of Tim Cook, I think of a man saying fuck the police.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Immediately. First thing I think of. But that was
Speaker 6:  like kind of surprising to me that they went that hard in the other direction.
Speaker 6:  And I, I, I keep thinking about like a lot of these conversations we had
Speaker 6:  last year about this was about China and specifically how China could potentially
Speaker 6:  use this database. And now like
Speaker 4:  We know, so Joanna Stern at the Wall Street Journal, notable
Speaker 4:  verge expat Joanna Stern. Yes. Lovely. Or mole at the Wall Street
Speaker 4:  Journal. Guess the deets, the journal, they're always detecting that.
Speaker 4:  They have a, they have a leaker. The
Speaker 4:  verges infiltrated us once again, but Joanna Stern got to be exclusive with
Speaker 4:  Craig Federer. You should go watch her video with him. She asked him a question
Speaker 4:  about China and our man just deferred. Yeah. Did not
Speaker 4:  answer the question about whether iCloud backups in China would be encrypted
Speaker 4:  in China. The government, the Chinese government effectively controls the
Speaker 4:  iCloud data centers. Yes. So Apple always kind
Speaker 4:  of make its concessions for the, I've been told China's
Speaker 4:  not in the EU always making concessions where it's large
Speaker 4:  market. Obviously there's a lot going on in China recently. We've not talked
Speaker 4:  about it in the show very much. There are large scale protests about Covid
Speaker 4:  Lockdowns. There are protests at the Foxcon factories where Apple makes the
Speaker 4:  phones or Apple production slowdown for its phones. Yep. Just quite a
Speaker 4:  lot going on in China.
Speaker 6:  And you've seen, you've also seen Apple make some really deliberate attempts
Speaker 6:  to move away from, from China, particularly in the, in, in
Speaker 6:  manufacturing. They've asked Foxcon, they've asked these other manufacturers
Speaker 6:  they work with to move to get out of there to like go to
Speaker 6:  India. To, to go to I think Arizona.
Speaker 6:  Arizona. Yes. Speaking of, and they've, they're asking 'em to move to these
Speaker 6:  other places. And I'm gonna use that as a segue to talk about
Speaker 6:  Arizona. Thank you. Richard laid that up for me because
Speaker 6:  the other big news this week from Apple was that they're
Speaker 6:  gonna start making chips for iPhones in Arizona. These
Speaker 6:  new fabs that T S M C just opened. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  So T M C I want to give T S M C credit here.
Speaker 6:  Yes.
Speaker 4:  Is the person who is dunked on Foxcon law lying to the people of
Speaker 4:  Wisconsin the most.
Speaker 6:  They did not build a big globe
Speaker 4:  Four years. They did not. T S M C took a bunch of tax
Speaker 4:  subsidies, lobbied their way into the CHIPS act, which is going
Speaker 4:  into effect. And they have actually built fabs in
Speaker 4:  Arizona. The fabs are gonna start producing chips in
Speaker 4:  2024. The ceremony that we saw with a md,
Speaker 4:  Nvidia, Tim Cook Biden, they're all, there was the installation
Speaker 4:  of Fab Equipment. It was not Golden Shovels.
Speaker 6:  I
Speaker 4:  Love it. Amazing. And they're gonna add a second site in 2026.
Speaker 4:  Liam looks so happy. So just congrats to SMC for doing a
Speaker 4:  thing they said they were gonna do. Yeah. And they're gonna do it. And so
Speaker 4:  Tim Cook Pres promised that the chips, they're gonna make M series and
Speaker 4:  Aeries chips there. A MD and Nvidia are gonna build chips there. It's like
Speaker 4:  a three nanometer node.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Yeah. I mean this is like, this is the stuff that's really hard to
Speaker 6:  make. You know, Intel has, Intel's trying to get their own fabs o
Speaker 6:  online so that they can jump into this space. But T S M C kind of
Speaker 6:  owns the market on the, these really small
Speaker 6:  nodes. And, and so this is, this is big news because we
Speaker 6:  haven't had a node this small built in the United States in a while. It it's
Speaker 6:  primarily been built in Taiwan. And I'm gonna be really like, it should create
Speaker 6:  jobs theoretically. It should make that like the CHIPS act
Speaker 6:  make more sense. And, and suddenly you're instead of like
Speaker 6:  having to, like Intel will have a new resources for hiring,
Speaker 6:  right? Yeah. If this tmc s if this TSMC fab goes
Speaker 6:  online,
Speaker 4:  It's cool news. We sent a reporter named Andy Bly down to cover it. Took
Speaker 4:  photos, whole thing. Go read the airport. They actually did it. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  They did it.
Speaker 4:  Now is it as fun to cover as an empty dome and
Speaker 4:  lies? Bless.
Speaker 6:  We'll
Speaker 4:  See. No more important to the global economy
Speaker 10:  From a content perspective. It was pretty much a failure. I
Speaker 10:  I think
Speaker 4:  I'm like, where's your dome bro?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Failure of content. But you know,
Speaker 10:  Before we, I do wanna mention, they, they unmade other
Speaker 10:  security announcements like you can use, you'll be able to use hardware
Speaker 10:  keys to secure your iCloud account. You'll be able to do this kind of key
Speaker 10:  verification, which you were referencing, Alex, that that will
Speaker 10:  enable that or potentially enable that ability to see if someone's trying
Speaker 10:  to spy on your a conversation that makes it a lot more like Signal or like
Speaker 10:  using PPG P and email or something like that. So there, there are
Speaker 10:  other, there are also other important security announcements that they made
Speaker 10:  that, that are are there. And they also made a, a very strange change they're
Speaker 10:  going to roll out globally. This change that rolled out in China during
Speaker 10:  the protests where when you turn on airdrop, I think to receive
Speaker 10:  files, you'll only be able to do it for 10 minutes. Which makes it a little
Speaker 10:  bit harder to use this strategy that people have been using to distribute,
Speaker 10:  you know, information that the government doesn't want it to get passed
Speaker 10:  around.
Speaker 6:  I just shared gritty photos.
Speaker 4:  Oh my God. That's it. We we're, we're so we're already
Speaker 6:  Over. We, we gotta cut the break. We got, we gotta
Speaker 4:  William's losing his mind back here. Don't be nice to
Speaker 4:  Liam.
Speaker 6:  Everyone be nice.
Speaker 4:  There's no clock this time. There's just a sense of shame that
Speaker 4:  pervades this room because we are at 90 minutes already
Speaker 4:  and we have another second here.
Speaker 6:  We're having a great
Speaker 4:  Time. We're gonna be right back. We got a gadget. Lightning around. We'll
Speaker 4:  be right
Speaker 4:  back.
Speaker 4:  All right, we're back. Wait, this is gonna be a lightning gadget.
Speaker 6:  Lightning of lightning rounds. It's all right. There wasn't a lot of gadgets
Speaker 6:  this week. Go for it. Okay, so first up, this is my favorite thing ever
Speaker 6:  released in the history of the world. Huawei's latest smartwatch.
Speaker 4:  This is so tough.
Speaker 6:  Has earbuds in it. So you can be like, oh, I gotta listen to this call.
Speaker 6:  And you just go, boop and flip the, the top of your
Speaker 6:  smartwatch.
Speaker 4:  This is just a digital watch. It's, it's not a smart Is this a black
Speaker 4:  and white segment l CD display?
Speaker 6:  You know, it's got weather, it's got heart rate. I'm calling
Speaker 6:  it smart. It's
Speaker 4:  Smart. Oh, no, no, no. That's just a face. That's just a face. And
Speaker 6:  What is smarter than having built in earbuds, wireless
Speaker 6:  earbuds that you can just pop out, stick in your ear.
Speaker 6:  They announced it on on Weibo, which is a Chinese
Speaker 6:  network and they're called the
Speaker 6:  Huawei watch. Budds. They've already launched
Speaker 6:  just not an America.
Speaker 4:  Wait, okay, first of all, watch Budds an incredible name. Second,
Speaker 4:  why would they demo this with this face? That's like
Speaker 4:  a 1982 Casio segmented
Speaker 6:  Because it's sick.
Speaker 4:  I will admit they got me because,
Speaker 10:  Because they know that I'm the person.
Speaker 4:  Richard,
Speaker 6:  Have you already imported
Speaker 10:  It? And directly me, they they were like, yes. They they they knew who they
Speaker 10:  knew who they
Speaker 4:  Right. Can we talk about the most important gad of the week, which is the
Speaker 4:  $950 Dyson combo platter,
Speaker 4:  headphones and air purifier like mask.
Speaker 6:  Liam and I immediately looked, Vong was in the office today and we looked
Speaker 6:  at her and were like, you're getting it right. And she's like, I'm gonna
Speaker 6:  try, I want nothing to be reviewed more.
Speaker 4:  Okay. My favorite kinds of companies in the world are companies
Speaker 4:  that have like one piece of technology and they're like,
Speaker 4:  what can we do with
Speaker 6:  It? Dyson's like wind.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Dyson's. Like, here's what we did. We made a fan. It's
Speaker 6:  A sick
Speaker 4:  Ass fan. A fan can both suck and blow. And
Speaker 4:  for like 10 years they're like, we're deeply focused on
Speaker 4:  suck. Like, what have you guys seen our vacuums?
Speaker 4:  That's just a fan going this way. And then kind of like
Speaker 4:  recently,
Speaker 6:  But the other way,
Speaker 4:  Switch that motherfucker to blow
Speaker 6:  Reverse baby. And they're like,
Speaker 4:  Here's the fan, here's the hair
Speaker 6:  Dryer. I used it today before the show. It's
Speaker 6:  rain.
Speaker 4:  It's such incredible that they're like, here's what we do fans.
Speaker 4:  They for a minute they're like, we're gonna do cars. And then I think
Speaker 4:  they realized like,
Speaker 6:  Cars don't run on fans.
Speaker 4:  They're like, well it's not a climate control fan. Does anyone know how
Speaker 4:  to do any other part of the
Speaker 6:  Car? They should start doing the hover. The hover. She
Speaker 4:  Doesn't hovercraft craft. And now they're like,
Speaker 4:  all right, what's, what can we put a fan into? And
Speaker 4:  they're like, headphones. And some like, it has to be,
Speaker 4:  there was a meeting where they're like, what else can we put fans
Speaker 4:  into? The car didn't work. We need an idea.
Speaker 6:  And you know what's really sad? Party speakers were right
Speaker 6:  there.
Speaker 4:  They're coming. And someone was like, I got it. Headphones.
Speaker 4:  Headphones. And there was a blank stare in the room. And they're like, you
Speaker 4:  just wait and
Speaker 6:  See. But with a mask on the front. And
Speaker 4:  It's, I mean you have to see, I'm buying these so
Speaker 4:  much I
Speaker 6:  You're gonna spend $949.
Speaker 4:  The best problem with them is that they're vaporware. Yes.
Speaker 4:  I'm sorry. The best part of them is that they're vaporware
Speaker 6:  Says, it says you'll be able to pre-order. You can
Speaker 4:  Only, they were announced like a year ago.
Speaker 6:  But you can start pre-ordering next year
Speaker 4:  And can pre-order
Speaker 6:  Not even there. No. Next year. I, I think that, I think they've,
Speaker 6:  they've got a shot.
Speaker 4:  They're, I mean they're, they're great. This is the only gadget worth buying.
Speaker 4:  I'm just excited to see what else Dyson can put a fan into. I
Speaker 4:  mean, the fact they were like, we're gonna do cars and then they're like,
Speaker 4:  mm. Not enough fans.
Speaker 6:  Not enough fans
Speaker 4:  Are playing for a wind power
Speaker 6:  Car. Like air conditioners. Have you considered the air conditioner?
Speaker 6:  No. No. They just, they're like headphones.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Headphones.
Speaker 6:  This is it. That's
Speaker 4:  Very good.
Speaker 6:  Shoes.
Speaker 4:  Shoes. Very good. Very good. What else you got?
Speaker 6:  Alright, what else do we got? We, I believe Allison
Speaker 6:  did a review of the Amazon Etho
Speaker 6:  Auto. I refused to say it the other
Speaker 6:  way. She wasn't a fan.
Speaker 4:  This thing still makes no sense to me. Yeah. I don't know why you would want
Speaker 4:  an echo on.
Speaker 6:  One of the bad things was Alexa isn't very helpful in a car
Speaker 6:  because Yeah. Alexa isn't very helpful in a car. There's no
Speaker 6:  smart lights in a car to control and you can just hit a button
Speaker 6:  to play music.
Speaker 4:  Well, so I think what they know is that people have a lot of
Speaker 4:  ideas in cars while they're driving around. Right. Like again on
Speaker 4:  paper. Yeah. Imagine the meeting. Yeah. Like what do people wanna do in their
Speaker 4:  car? They wanna play music. What is the number one use of Alexa? People ask
Speaker 4:  for music. Yes. I dunno how many timers people set in their cars. This is
Speaker 4:  number two.
Speaker 6:  Every time I'm trying to like make that, that, that get the miles. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Right. You know, I'm like, all right, set a timer. So
Speaker 4:  Timer for five minutes. The
Speaker 6:  Gun it.
Speaker 4:  All right. Fair. We're
Speaker 6:  All different. I've never done that. You
Speaker 4:  Should start, I'm going to, so like, okay, people want to ask for music.
Speaker 4:  We can add the thing for music and then maybe when they're driving around
Speaker 4:  they'll be like, you should buy some paper towels. Oh, I forgot to buy paper
Speaker 4:  towels. Alexa, buy some paper. Like you, you can see the thought process.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And then they remember that nobody actually will ever do that.
Speaker 4:  It's a real problem.
Speaker 6:  It's a real, like, it's just bad. I love like
Speaker 6:  all of her, her problems with it where it's like, yeah, Alexa's just stupid
Speaker 6:  to have in a car.
Speaker 4:  They gotta add chat G p T to it. Yeah. Or a fan. Or
Speaker 10:  A fan. It's, it's also like that weird Spotify thing in that you still
Speaker 10:  pretty much need your phone, but you can just do this stuff with your
Speaker 6:  Phone. But the Spotify one, you can at least like lar connect to your computer
Speaker 6:  and make a new control.
Speaker 10:  It had a knob. It had a knob. Yeah. So
Speaker 6:  It had the knob put a knob on this. I bet it would've gone up to a
Speaker 6:  seven. Alison would've loved it.
Speaker 4:  Anything with a giant rotary knob always wins for us. Anything. Okay. What
Speaker 4:  are these watches? The Choros Apex two.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. So v reviewed some, some new
Speaker 6:  multi-sport watches. She, she liked them. They didn't have a knob on 'em,
Speaker 6:  but she still gave them a seven. They're, they're pretty expensive. But I
Speaker 6:  think the big thing here is that really good battery life. They're, they're
Speaker 6:  really for runners. They're really for people who are like, they go outdoors.
Speaker 6:  I'm not familiar with these kinds of people, so I can't say if
Speaker 6:  this is a good purchase for people. But Victoria does in fact
Speaker 6:  go outside on a regular basis and, and she, she seemed to
Speaker 4:  Like them. Okay. We gotta talk about the symphonics floor lamp
Speaker 6:  Syon.
Speaker 4:  It's amazing that they just added legs to it and change the shade.
Speaker 6:  What did you
Speaker 4:  Taller? I I'm so ready to get these. Yeah. And just be like everywhere in
Speaker 4:  my home there are tiny lamp speakers and I don't know why,
Speaker 4:  I don't know why I feel this way.
Speaker 6:  Because you want your home to be like
Speaker 6:  one of those really fancy rich people's homes where you're like, where's
Speaker 6:  that music coming from? Like when you go to the apples
Speaker 4:  Lamps
Speaker 6:  And you're like, where is that? Is that music coming from a rock now? It's
Speaker 6:  your lamps.
Speaker 4:  So it's 260 bucks. The standard lamp seeker is
Speaker 4:  $179. So it's an $80 premium for some legs.
Speaker 6:  So you could just put it on something tall.
Speaker 4:  Yes. This is a choice that you have. Okay. I am very excited about
Speaker 4:  just the idea. I, I think the CS is gonna be Richard. I like Richard
Speaker 4:  and I used to cover like sea, like we were in the
Speaker 6:  Gonna be tall, smart
Speaker 4:  Speakers together, speakers and Gotcha. Like back in the day. Yeah. Right.
Speaker 4:  Like I remember like when Panas or like Pioneer and Panasonic would
Speaker 4:  like demo plasma TVs to us. Like that's how Richard and I came up.
Speaker 4:  Right. I remember the HD D V d Blu-Ray format war that Richard and I
Speaker 4:  covered together. Aw. And so see when
Speaker 10:  We were on, I was on the plane on the way to CES when they announced
Speaker 10:  that it was over.
Speaker 4:  I'm not over. We were like, we were like gear strong. Like this is the year
Speaker 4:  the format war and they're like hdv dead. They had to tear down the
Speaker 4:  booth at CES is a real thing that happened. And the dead of
Speaker 4:  night. Well
Speaker 6:  You over were there.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. They were gonna, it was gonna be the year of the format war. And between
Speaker 4:  HD and, and Blu-ray
Speaker 6:  And Shiba said, no, we're done.
Speaker 10:  And Shiba just,
Speaker 4:  Were just like, they got there, they looked around, they're like, what if
Speaker 4:  we just like hung out in Vegas and they tore the truth down.
Speaker 6:  Same honestly. Same. I do not judge you one bitch tba
Speaker 4:  Since then, there has not been a lot of drama in cs, I would say. But I CS
Speaker 4:  is always a TV show. Yeah. I would say this is the year where I'm expecting
Speaker 4:  to see like some interesting TVs and a lot of like
Speaker 4:  really wild atmo like gum theater ideas. Yeah. It's
Speaker 4:  coming.
Speaker 6:  I, I would
Speaker 4:  Like that. And these like Sonos Wireless rears is lamps is like,
Speaker 4:  it's just the beginning. It's just the drop.
Speaker 6:  It's not Sonos. It works with Sonos, but it's IKEA lamps.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Yeah. They're out ahead of the flood.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Like this is, well
Speaker 10:  I think what we're gonna see is we, we've got these engineers who they,
Speaker 10:  we obviously had the pandemic and everybody suddenly was stuck at home.
Speaker 10:  You have these engineers who were at their house all the time. The stuff
Speaker 10:  that they built is finally coming. It's going to get strange. Just
Speaker 6:  Roll with it. And not a single one of them knows what a good lamp looks like.
Speaker 4:  And I'm just saying this is like, they're out ahead of the CS rush. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  They announce some stuff. You can't buy it now. It's not until January. So
Speaker 4:  this isn't like stocking stuff or stuff. Yes. Although the idea of a, of
Speaker 4:  a speaker lamp in your stocking is incredible.
Speaker 6:  What's that giant eight foot tall box in my what?
Speaker 4:  Christmas?
Speaker 6:  What could
Speaker 4:  It be? So they're just out ahead of the flood. Yeah. And I'm telling you,
Speaker 4:  this is the first drop of ces. Crazy. It's coming. It's
Speaker 6:  The speakers the year, the speakers in chat. G p
Speaker 4:  T. Richard, do you know anything about this DGI Mini three drone? I'm in
Speaker 4:  the market for another drone that I'll never use. And this feels like it.
Speaker 10:  I that, that's the only thing I think about is buying drones that I never
Speaker 10:  actually fly because I bought Hey D g I, I don't even remember what the
Speaker 10:  name of it is. I have a Phantom.
Speaker 4:  Oh my God. You have like a, you have like a Phantom three or a Phantom four.
Speaker 4:  Yes. You're a maniac. A three I think. I, I bought a Phantom four and I flew,
Speaker 4:  I sold it when I had a kid. I was like, I gotta get ready for this baby.
Speaker 4:  And Becky's like, I redone the house and I was like, I sold the
Speaker 4:  drone.
Speaker 6:  That's the verge equivalent of I got rid of the motorcycle for
Speaker 6:  you. These fingers are safe. Now I can pick up our
Speaker 6:  child.
Speaker 4:  She's like, great, are you gonna
Speaker 4:  help? She's
Speaker 10:  Like, and now they have drone that you can buy and never actually
Speaker 10:  fly anywhere.
Speaker 6:  Well this is an expensive drone though. 859.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, but it's kind of, the remote has a screen. It's a little, okay, that's
Speaker 4:  cool. I have the original mini, which is like just
Speaker 4:  not quite good enough. Yeah. I'm so shocked that DJ is still selling
Speaker 4:  stuff in the United States. Like they're on the, you're a Chinese
Speaker 4:  company hit list for the long time. For the longest
Speaker 6:  Time, yes. Because this is a D G I is a Chinese company, but they're also
Speaker 6:  the only company that makes like good drones.
Speaker 4:  I'm just saying they're a Chinese company whose product is flying
Speaker 4:  cameras. Like of all the companies, like, huh, this seems
Speaker 6:  Like a product. And the American government went, yeah, but I wanna fly my
Speaker 6:  drones. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  They're like, yes, but Hollywood needs these. Have you seen car commercials?
Speaker 4:  What are we gonna do?
Speaker 6:  Like helicopters? Absolutely not
Speaker 4:  Stable fusion. We gotta wrap this up. It's, we've,
Speaker 4:  we're so far over.
Speaker 6:  I mean, wait, important, important news.
Speaker 6:  Somebody just let me know that the Amazon Kindle scribe is getting a software
Speaker 6:  update. So you will no longer just have to email
Speaker 6:  files to yourself when you wanna put them on the scribe.
Speaker 4:  What can you do instead?
Speaker 6:  You can use an app. Cool. I thought I, I know
Speaker 6:  everybody was really concerned about this. I got a lot of emails. So that's,
Speaker 6:  that's for you guys.
Speaker 4:  All a little scoop on the Vercast for the Kindle scribe community. All four
Speaker 4:  of you. Excited for the scribe blog. Yeah, I, you know, back in the day,
Speaker 4:  like there would've been a dedicated gadget blog for the Kendall scribe.
Speaker 6:  Yes, a hundred percent. All the things you
Speaker 4:  Can do, bring it back. All right. That's it. Thanks to James Vincent for
Speaker 4:  joining us. Thanks to Richard for joining us with David out on baby leave.
Speaker 4:  I wonder if he had to sell his drone to have a baby. That's really not how
Speaker 4:  that connection worked, but that's how I'm gonna start thinking about it.
Speaker 4:  You're gonna be hearing a lot from Richard. It's gonna be a lot of fun. That's
Speaker 4:  it. That's by the way, a bunch of cool stuff on the
Speaker 4:  site this week. Liz has a big piece about ftx.
Speaker 4:  Not what you would expect though. The FTX store is broken
Speaker 4:  by a really actually great crypto news outlet called CoinDesk. Yep.
Speaker 4:  CoinDesk is owned by a crypto exchange. Oof. So they might have
Speaker 4:  just like knifed themselves, great story about the politics of tech and
Speaker 4:  journalism and crypto. I mean it's like a perfect person.
Speaker 6:  It's wonderful.
Speaker 4:  But for the FTX story, if
Speaker 10:  You believe what the government might be accusing SPF of shooting yourself
Speaker 10:  in the foot is kind of on on brand.
Speaker 4:  We'll see what happens. It's very we'll. We'll see how that goes. It's very
Speaker 4:  good. There's actually great week on the site. Go check it all out. We'll
Speaker 4:  back on Wednesday. We did, Alex and I talked to Charles Plan more
Speaker 4:  about winners and Los and Streamings. We basically did the Go 90 scale. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  we thought we were gonna go 30 minutes. We went 90, which
Speaker 4:  is perfect. Makes sense. It's
Speaker 6:  Beautiful.
Speaker 4:  It was great. So we'll here you, we'll see you on Wednesday. You can tweet
Speaker 4:  at us. Alex is Alex h Cranz. Richard is at
Speaker 4:  RJ cc. James is at JJ Vincent, I'm at Reckless. We love
Speaker 4:  hearing from you for as long as Twitter's gonna last tweeted us.
Speaker 4:  We love it. That's it. That's Rich. Has back
Speaker 4:  home.
Speaker 1:  And that's a wrap for Vergecast this week. Thanks for listening. If you enjoy
Speaker 1:  the show, subscribe in the podcast app of your choice or tell a friend, you
Speaker 1:  can send us feedback at vergecast@theverge.com. This show is
Speaker 1:  produced by me, Liam James, and our senior audio director, Andrew Marino.
Speaker 1:  This episode was edited and mixed by Amanda Rose Smith. Our
Speaker 1:  editorial director is Brooke Min, and our executive producer is Eleanor
Speaker 1:  Donovan. The Vergecast is a production of the Verge and Box Media
Speaker 1:  Podcast network. And that's it. We'll see you next week.