# Transcript
ID: 9a58ca70-a13d-11ec-b7ee-5dcdb1c8f633
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Apple announces new iPhone SE, Mac Studio, M1 Ultra, and more
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/1229048793527009389/4114633715853380726/s93290-US-4727s-1647002452.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, Alex Cranz, and Dan Seifert discuss all the announcements from Apple's Peek Performance event this week.
Speaker 1:  This week and diverse cast Al trans dancy for joined the show. We go over
Speaker 1:  Apple's peak performance event. The new iPhone se the new iPad air
Speaker 1:  and the Mac studio with Mon ultra and studio display. Then do a little lightning
Speaker 1:  round. That's going up on the red chest. Now when your payment platform knows
Speaker 1:  no boundaries, neither does your business. That's what makes Payoneer the
Speaker 1:  world's go-to partner for digital commerce everywhere. Payoneer gives businesses,
Speaker 1:  the technology connections and confidence to pay and get paid globally. Learn
Speaker 1:  more at payoneer.com/verge. That's P a Y O N E
Speaker 1:  r.com/verge. Payoneer a universe of opportunities
Speaker 1:  open to you. Good news. You reached your Q1 benchmarks. Now you still have
Speaker 1:  three more queues. When you look out into the seat of CRMs, it can look extremely
Speaker 1:  blue, but HubSpot is here to give your company a more human approach. It's
Speaker 1:  a CRM platform. That's easy to use aligns all of your teams seamlessly and
Speaker 1:  delivers a better experience for your customers. So you're a business is
Speaker 1:  like a friendly neighbor and not some forceful sales company that will stop
Speaker 1:  at nothing to close the deal, learn how to grow better by connecting your
Speaker 1:  people, your customers, and your
Speaker 1:  business@hubspot.com.
Speaker 1:  Hello, and welcome to the verge cast flagship podcast to 5g
Speaker 1:  shenanigans. That's our new, it's like one of the worst
Speaker 1:  bars and grills. You can go to 5g
Speaker 1:  shenanigans on your friend. Dan
Speaker 1:  Seaford is here. Hello? I am here, Alex. Cranz is here. I'm really excited
Speaker 1:  about the shin. Annie's yeah, it's going to be great. There's a lot of shenanigans
Speaker 1:  talk about on the show this week. I will know that our friend Peter bone
Speaker 1:  is not here and I went to a bunch of apple like briefings and they were like,
Speaker 1:  where's Dieter. And I was like, you know where he is? She said your
Speaker 1:  rival, like Dieter wants to work for Google. So at some point we're
Speaker 1:  going to, I don't know if we should disclose it, but there it is. That's
Speaker 1:  the news. We talked about it a bunch last week. If you missed it, we had
Speaker 1:  a goodbye episode with Walt Mossberg and Dieter was very touching and poignant,
Speaker 1:  and now the world moves on you
Speaker 1:  ready? Enthusiasm. Okay. We've got to start. There's an apple event
Speaker 1:  this week. Tons of apple news. Talk about new chip new phone, new
Speaker 1:  display, new Mac, old USBA ports. Very
Speaker 1:  exciting. I will say that in addition to that, our team is doing just
Speaker 1:  excellent coverage on the tech aspects of the
Speaker 1:  war in Ukraine. That is obviously happening. It's the biggest news in the
Speaker 1:  world. Aside from COVID lots of internet companies, content
Speaker 1:  filtering, major backbone providers are shutting off service in
Speaker 1:  Russia. McKenna had a great scoop about a tech executive that is
Speaker 1:  privately funding, a mercenary army of private soldiers in the
Speaker 1:  country. You know, we talk about policy a lot in the show, the we're
Speaker 1:  just going to block a bunch of Russian channels from American
Speaker 1:  social media companies. Amazon's gonna stop shipping packages
Speaker 1:  and Russia and prime video, that stuff, all the themes
Speaker 1:  that we talked about in the policy side are all just coming to a head there.
Speaker 1:  So we're covering it very deeply. It's the flip side, right? Of
Speaker 1:  like, how should we regulate tech? The tech companies here are sort of pulling
Speaker 1:  out of Russia and then Russia is running its own tech based
Speaker 1:  misinformation campaigns shutting down speech across the country. It's all
Speaker 1:  on the site. I know you don't come to us for Ukraine news on this podcast.
Speaker 1:  I just want to point out because our team is working really hard on it. And
Speaker 1:  there's actually really interesting deep coverage of how plant. So that is
Speaker 1:  that. Okay. Now a hard segue to the apple event. Good
Speaker 2:  Morning. And welcome back to apple park.
Speaker 1:  So big apple event, medium apple event, small Atlona what do you think
Speaker 3:  Need to get with medium? Yeah,
Speaker 1:  Medium. It was the first one. They try to fake everyone out with this like
Speaker 1:  peak performance thing in
Speaker 1:  AR I promise you. And I talked to a lot of
Speaker 1:  people. Everyone is ready to go back to in-person apple events. I think
Speaker 1:  including apple. I don't think they can ever do the glasses about in-person
Speaker 1:  events.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, they can't. You're going to have to bring all of the, the
Speaker 4:  competitors with you to that first in-person apple
Speaker 4:  event. You can have a little purse full of them. Like
Speaker 4:  don't pay attention to my person, my bag of, of AR headset.
Speaker 1:  It's gonna be great. And I brought my little HTC, Vive, like room-scale
Speaker 1:  cameras
Speaker 4:  Come over here. We're going to do this
Speaker 1:  Together. And he cute. He did. He bring a ladder because I need one. So this
Speaker 1:  one is like, they still did it in the format. We were used
Speaker 1:  to Tim cook on the stage at the apple, the Steve jobs
Speaker 1:  theater zooming out to other parts of the campus. Very
Speaker 1:  infomercial lightning, fast, very fast, especially the first
Speaker 1:  half. They just race through this thing. The theme of it was
Speaker 1:  like, we make our own chips or chips are great. Look, we put our chips in
Speaker 1:  everything. We did it. Okay. So let's just start with it. They did a new
Speaker 1:  iPhone se they did a new iPad. Then they announced what they are
Speaker 1:  saying is the last of the M one family of chips. Same one
Speaker 1:  ultra. They're putting that in a computer called the max studio, which there's
Speaker 1:  a long history of people wanting a computer, just like this from apple and
Speaker 1:  the United States. Despite let's take them in turn, let's start at the
Speaker 1:  iPhone.
Speaker 2:  And today we're bringing our extraordinary  bionic
Speaker 2:  chip to another iPhone. The new I
Speaker 2:  phone.
Speaker 1:  I see, I think the story of this iPhone is, is 5g shenanigans. But Dan, tell
Speaker 1:  us about the new iPhone se
Speaker 3:  Some 5g shenanigans in that this supports 5g, but it
Speaker 3:  doesn't support millimeter wave, which we can get into. So it supports what
Speaker 3:  we commonly refer to as sub six 5g or the 5g that you can
Speaker 3:  actually use, which you might actually experience. Otherwise it
Speaker 3:  is the same se that they released in 2020
Speaker 3:  with a new processor and a slightly bigger battery.
Speaker 1:  That's it? Yeah. Same 4.7 inch screen. Same bezel, same
Speaker 1:  touch ID. Yep. Same camera. But the gap, they got the new processor.
Speaker 1:  So the camera should be better.
Speaker 3:  They're saying, they're saying like, you know it, the processor can unlock
Speaker 3:  some things with the camera, but I would not get your hopes up super high
Speaker 3:  for dramatic camera improvements. That it's the same hardware. It's the same
Speaker 3:  single
Speaker 1:  It's got deep fusion dude. It's winter mode. I mean,
Speaker 1:  they're sweater, pictures. Look this phone, sir, grandparents,
Speaker 1:  grandparents get
Speaker 4:  Cold. They
Speaker 1:  Need sweatpants. I called their auto wearing sweaters. It has sweater
Speaker 3:  Mode and it has the single camera portrait mode. But I don't
Speaker 3:  believe it does the night mode. That is like the thing that is
Speaker 3:  like not available on this one, at least to my understanding, it could be
Speaker 3:  wrong. But anyways, so it's a single camera unit. It's got the same front
Speaker 3:  facing camera, which I believe is seven megapixels. It's you know, like you
Speaker 3:  said, the 4.7 inch screen LCD it's got the button. Right? It's got a
Speaker 3:  button. It's got a home button. It's
Speaker 1:  Yeah, no, no nightmare. Yeah. That's okay.
Speaker 1:  I don't, I don't understand that. Like
Speaker 3:  I think that the processor would have be powering that, right? And like it's
Speaker 3:  got the eight, 15 chip, which is the best a series chip that you
Speaker 3:  can get. Right? So that's how they get ya.
Speaker 1:  That's how they get you. That's how they bracket you right up there. Like
Speaker 1:  iPhone, a C customers are never in the dark,
Speaker 1:  never happens to carry a flashlight wherever they go. They get
Speaker 1:  so sleeping in bed by 6:00 PM,
Speaker 4:  Curls up in their little sweaters, going to bat.
Speaker 1:  It's a very, it's a cozy phone. It's also
Speaker 3:  The dollars more expensive, which you can almost certainly attribute to the
Speaker 3:  fact that it supports 5g. Hi, I'm on our team has looked at
Speaker 3:  many times into the cost of 5g in phones. I believe there's some
Speaker 3:  reports about the iPhone twelves 5g modem is like its most
Speaker 3:  expensive component. So it's very likely that the price here is
Speaker 3:  related to the fact that it supports 5g. Even though it doesn't support millimeter
Speaker 3:  wave
Speaker 4:  Support, the mid one that like the FCC got up or the FAA
Speaker 4:  got upset about.
Speaker 3:  Yes, yes. It's, that's the C band, which at
Speaker 3:  and T and Verizon are very excited about because it's their only
Speaker 3:  real 5g that you can get and they are rolling it
Speaker 3:  out. And this is fully compatible with it. As far as I understand, it's also
Speaker 3:  compatible with all of T-Mobile's 5g. Sure.
Speaker 4:  Is the millimeter wave thing. Is that a great loss? I feel like it's not
Speaker 4:  a great loss because everybody talks about how terrible it is.
Speaker 1:  It was a lie. And now we can all admit that it's a lie. And
Speaker 1:  before I talk about that, I'm just gonna point out that you can get it in
Speaker 1:  green and you can get the pro in a nice screen. Great. That's all the news
Speaker 1:  where the iPhone,
Speaker 3:  I can get the 13 in green and you can get the pro at Alpine green, but
Speaker 3:  the se is it midnight Starlight and product
Speaker 3:  red?
Speaker 1:  That's it like? Okay, sorry. If you
Speaker 1:  want to curl up by fire and go to bed early
Speaker 1:  with millimeter wave was a
Speaker 1:  lie. Let's just come back to this. I feel very strongly about this. I'm the
Speaker 1:  only person in America who feels very strongly about this, but I'm going
Speaker 1:  to transmit my energy to you through this microphone. You're already
Speaker 4:  Transmitting more energy. The millimeter wave
Speaker 1:  Dead. Do you remember when the iPhone 12 came out? Yes. Hans Vestberg from
Speaker 1:  Verizon stood on stage with apple and he was like, 5g is finally
Speaker 1:  here. It was great. It was a great moment. He's got a great accent
Speaker 1:  and very handsome man. He is like, I did it all. This other 5g has been lies.
Speaker 1:  But now that Verizon has millimeter wave on this iPhone and
Speaker 1:  then Dieter and I, in our reviews, we had to like go find street
Speaker 1:  corners. Like I literally was like walking the streets of Manhattan being
Speaker 1:  like that looks like millimeter wave and like standing under the thing. I'm
Speaker 1:  pretty sure Verizon put one fire out on purpose and we would test it.
Speaker 1:  And then Joanna like did her video at giant stadium and was like, it works
Speaker 1:  great here. And it's nowhere else. And that was 5g on
Speaker 1:  Verizon and Verizon was insane about this. And they
Speaker 1:  demanded that every phone on its network have millimeter wave
Speaker 1:  because it defined 5g. Ultra wide band
Speaker 1:  is millimeter wave. It's like ultra fast,
Speaker 1:  extremely low range, high power. You need a
Speaker 1:  special antenna. The iPhones had special antennas on them,
Speaker 1:  custom phones, all this stuff because millimeter wave was the
Speaker 1:  5g that Verizon had and at. And T was like, we
Speaker 1:  honestly are all, most of what we have is lies, but we're along for this
Speaker 1:  ride too. Right? We have a
Speaker 4:  Label we're going to put on the top of the phone,
Speaker 3:  We've got five GE. So we're
Speaker 1:  Good. And underneath that was a bunch of crazy stuff.
Speaker 1:  Like my technology called the dynamic spectrum sharing, where they would
Speaker 1:  reuse the LTE spectrum, but give you a 5g logo. And that was five
Speaker 1:  G and it was slow. And I would get on the, you know, we would get on review
Speaker 1:  calls with various phone manufacturers, big 5g slows at DSS. And they'd be
Speaker 1:  like, whoa, there are carriers. It was horrible when
Speaker 4:  You use it in the UK, get some real time.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Meanwhile like I would get tweets from people in like South Korea being
Speaker 1:  like, what are you talking about? Are you complain about 5g? We get six gigs
Speaker 1:  down. This is why we're great at league of legends. Like our
Speaker 1:  Internet's better than yours. It's true. By the way, latent latency is a
Speaker 1:  big thing in e-sports. It was like a real fact. Look, if America wants to
Speaker 1:  dominate the international e-sports scene, we have to upgrade our
Speaker 1:  networks.
Speaker 4:  The reason we need an infrastructure bill to improve our internet and it's
Speaker 4:  country legal legends, we're getting crushed guys, how are
Speaker 4:  we, how are we supposed to like beat them at any,
Speaker 1:  What do you do in Biden? Come on, fix it. So then
Speaker 1:  this past few months that, you know, there's a spectrum auction, they bought
Speaker 1:  the sea band, the disaster with the FAA, the FCC
Speaker 1:  happened. They finally slowly started launching their mid band
Speaker 1:  networks, Verizon redefines,
Speaker 1:  5g, ultra wide band. They're like, well, we made this up.
Speaker 1:  So now this doesn't mean the millimeter wave. This means
Speaker 1:  both millimeter wave and this mid band spectrum. And they just
Speaker 1:  sort of like announced it sort
Speaker 3:  Of announced it. I don't know how much
Speaker 1:  Announcing they did. Well. They announced it such that Alison was able to
Speaker 1:  write a piece explaining what all the terms meant, but it was like very under
Speaker 1:  the table, like under the table that I had to go on the way back
Speaker 1:  machine and look at Verizon's website and be like, sometime in January, they
Speaker 1:  changed it, right. There was no
Speaker 3:  Press release that said 5g ultra wide band now
Speaker 3:  means
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Which for two years, they've been saying it means millimeter
Speaker 1:  wave. So the eye, and they've been demanding that every phone on their
Speaker 1:  network that supports 5g, I'm making extremely sarcastic air quotes here
Speaker 1:  that has 5g was a millimeter wave and phones were
Speaker 3:  Compromised for that. Like a, the great example is the pixel for a
Speaker 3:  5g. When the unlocked version came out, it did not support millimeter wave.
Speaker 3:  And it was $400 I think. And then Verizon
Speaker 3:  insisted on the millimeter wave in it. And now the price was $500 for that
Speaker 3:  version or the, I think it was the galaxy as
Speaker 3:  20. That base model did not support millimeter
Speaker 3:  wave, but the Verizon version did. And therefore it was more expensive. So
Speaker 3:  yeah, we've been dealing with that for awhile. And now, now the iPhone se
Speaker 3:  doesn't support.
Speaker 1:  So they announced his phone and like, literally Dan was like, I wonder if
Speaker 1:  it will be on Verizon because it is a millimeter analysts are like,
Speaker 1:  huh, I wonder if it'll be on Verizon or if apple will have a second
Speaker 1:  secret, more expensive millimeter wave version. Cause I'm like, we like
Speaker 1:  ask and is like, no, we're gonna carry it in. All it is. Is it because it
Speaker 1:  supports ban? They can claim it's 5g ultra wide
Speaker 1:  man. And they can just stop pretending to give a shit about millimeter
Speaker 1:  wave.
Speaker 4:  There was like a conversation between apple and Verizon about this, where
Speaker 4:  apple was like, we're not going to put your stupid thing in here and market
Speaker 4:  this phone because of your stupid technology deal with it. An apple
Speaker 4:  and Verizon was just like, okay, sure. We'll deal with
Speaker 4:  it.
Speaker 3:  I'm sure there was conversations. I just wonder how much the conversations
Speaker 3:  were like. Verizon's like, okay, we're closing on the C band where we
Speaker 3:  almost have apple. Can you wait like four months before you announce it so
Speaker 3:  that we can actually roll out this C-band and then the FAA was like, wait
Speaker 3:  a minute. What are you doing? And then that through
Speaker 1:  I guarantee you, this thing would not have launched if CBN hadn't rolled
Speaker 1:  out. Yeah. They would have just held it. Right. I fantasy was doing fine.
Speaker 1:  They have, you know, whatever phones to support the millimeter
Speaker 1:  wave deception that they need to have. But if
Speaker 1:  you hadn't rolled that, C-band, I assume the Verizon would have either
Speaker 1:  insisted on a more expensive phone with millimeter wave
Speaker 1:  or the apple. And I just held it and I bet apple would have just held it.
Speaker 1:  They don't care. Right? It's like, I'm just saying, we
Speaker 1:  have spent two years listening to these companies, at least two years,
Speaker 1:  at least listening to Verizon and at and T
Speaker 1:  ramble on about millimeter wave and ramble on about 5g. It's been
Speaker 1:  at least 10 years of 5g. Bullshit. In fact,
Speaker 3:  I would say it's been at least four years of millimeter wave lies
Speaker 3:  because Shawn Hollister wrote about this whole situation
Speaker 3:  about that we're talking about now. And in his article, he
Speaker 3:  cited in 2018, he was at Qualcomm's event in
Speaker 3:  Maui. And like 5g was supposed to be like the
Speaker 3:  ultra wide band millimeter wave demo there that didn't work. And it was just
Speaker 3:  all lies. And that was in 2018. So it's been at least four years of
Speaker 3:  this.
Speaker 1:  And I will say, people have told us, we've seen the tweets. We see like
Speaker 1:  some people can get millimeter wave.
Speaker 4:  I could actually get it. They have a, my old
Speaker 4:  house, my old apartment had the Verizon
Speaker 4:  transmission thing on top of it. I had to deal with like months of
Speaker 4:  construction as they built their little like air con, they got
Speaker 4:  air conditioning. And I didn't, I was still upset about it. Verizon got air
Speaker 4:  conditioning and I didn't, and it's all there and I can look at it even now
Speaker 4:  and get just incredible speeds.
Speaker 1:  Really? Do you, I called your phone out the window and like, yeah, just
Speaker 4:  Hold my phone out and just kinda hope.
Speaker 1:  But yeah, let's do
Speaker 4:  It, but just me, nobody else can get it.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, because you're probably the only one in the millimeter wave. This industry
Speaker 1:  has for four years now, at least four or five, 10
Speaker 1:  years told us 5g will be transformative. Right? If you
Speaker 1:  remember their early hype, like I would go to dinners with the cell
Speaker 1:  carriers. They would tell me that they were going to compete with AWS.
Speaker 4:  5g robots were going to save lives.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. The amount of telemedicine and telesurgery that would happen
Speaker 1:  like, like robot surgery on demand was like
Speaker 1:  gonna definitely happen because of 5g. Like we were shown pictures
Speaker 1:  of, of, of just like rural towns in America
Speaker 1:  that had no access to healthcare. And the self-driving robot on 5g was
Speaker 1:  gonna show up and just do surgery and everyone and keeps
Speaker 1:  out right. All that stuff has really not happened. They told me that they
Speaker 1:  were gonna, they were going to disintermediate AWS because to control these
Speaker 1:  networks, they needed to put the data centers closer to the
Speaker 1:  edge, which would allow for the extremely low latency applications that we
Speaker 1:  have been promised this whole time. None of that stuff has happened, but
Speaker 1:  they have increased the prices of the funds and they have absolutely
Speaker 1:  increased the prices of the plans for no appreciable benefit and is a
Speaker 1:  scandal that I would say no one is talking about, except we constantly
Speaker 1:  talk all the time. And this phone is great and I'm happy. It's a
Speaker 1:  cheap iPhone. And I know people will be excited about it, but this phone
Speaker 1:  is just like proof that all of this fake out
Speaker 1:  was just a lie and it achieved nothing. There's actually a wall street
Speaker 1:  journal story last week. It's like, it was a
Speaker 1:  journal. So they've made these huge investments in these network and they've
Speaker 1:  created no new revenue for themselves and created no new applications
Speaker 1:  that anyone is using. Whereas if you think about LTE, the
Speaker 1:  amount of revenue they created, cause everyone rushed to get faster
Speaker 1:  phones. Cause they could feel the speed increase over 3g. And then the applications
Speaker 1:  that were delivered on top of it were all like video applications. Like it
Speaker 1:  was fast enough to support streaming video, which is why they all went and
Speaker 1:  tried to put video providers
Speaker 4:  Kind of reminds me of, of like TV's and
Speaker 4:  they're the 4k like when they went from 10 80 P to 4k and now they're doing
Speaker 4:  like four K to eight K and they're like, aren't you excited about eight K
Speaker 4:  and HDR. And everyone's like, no,
Speaker 1:  Like,
Speaker 4:  Like, you know, 10 80 to 4k. That was a big
Speaker 4:  leap. And yeah, my eyes bled. It was gorgeous. But most people didn't
Speaker 4:  like eight K is not a significant jump, but 5g
Speaker 4:  for most people. And like the mid band speeds is not a significant jump
Speaker 4:  to be like, yeah, I need it. I gotta, I gotta go get my new phone.
Speaker 1:  But we've, we've just spent so long, particularly for Isen. So
Speaker 1:  long hearing about millimeter wave and paying higher
Speaker 1:  prices. Right? That's the killer to me is they
Speaker 1:  found ways to increase the prices of the plans. They found ways to increase
Speaker 1:  the prices of the devices and they provided nothing.
Speaker 1:  And now with this phone, you can see that at the end of the day, it
Speaker 1:  really all that was just, they needed to be able to market that
Speaker 1:  stuff. Now they've got a real network, right? They've
Speaker 1:  got the mid band 5g network. Dan we've seen it perform. It seems
Speaker 1:  fine. I mean, it's, you know,
Speaker 3:  If the typical 4g experiences anywhere from like 30
Speaker 3:  megabit down to 125 megabit down, if you're in a
Speaker 3:  good mid band 5g area, you might see 500 megabit down or 600 megabit
Speaker 3:  down. That's not unrealistic
Speaker 4:  On your phone that you did 500 megabit down. Just
Speaker 4:  like, nevermind,
Speaker 3:  Download legal legends. There you
Speaker 3:  go. I will tell you, there was
Speaker 3:  one, there was one instance I don't get mid band where I live. I'm
Speaker 3:  stuck on the still the low end garbage 5g that might as well be 4g where
Speaker 3:  I am. But there was one instance last year when I was in New York city
Speaker 3:  for our ten-year anniversary event
Speaker 3:  and I could get T-Mobile's mid band and out
Speaker 3:  sitting in my hotel room and I was like downloaded movies to watch on the
Speaker 3:  train ride home. And I was like, this is it.
Speaker 4:  This is a future right now,
Speaker 3:  Three years. This is the first time I've appreciated 5g.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. It's the other thing is that most phones, Android phones,
Speaker 1:  you can figure out what you've got because there's Android utilities and
Speaker 1:  an iPhone. It's just like, whatever carrier letters are at the top of your
Speaker 1:  phone. And it's almost impossible to know if you're getting what you paid
Speaker 1:  for. Like my iPhone right now. It just says 5g. And I, I know
Speaker 1:  it's
Speaker 3:  Sometimes mine says five G. Sometimes mine says, cause I'm on T-Mobile they'll
Speaker 3:  say 5g, you see not UWC. You
Speaker 3:  see got a glossary on the site. Alison
Speaker 3:  wrote that. So
Speaker 1:  What's what is UC? Is it ultra cool? I had
Speaker 3:  No idea, but it's the same as without the USI.
Speaker 3:  So I'm that nerd
Speaker 3:  who's like driving his car and sees you see pop up on his car, play and pulls
Speaker 3:  over and is like, I got to run a speed test and see how much faster this
Speaker 3:  is. And then it's the same speed as, without the UC and without the
Speaker 3:  5g. So like, I don't know. It's all lies.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Anyhow, I'm just saying this has been, if
Speaker 1:  people in rural areas can actually get 500 down
Speaker 1:  from their phones to wirelessly
Speaker 4:  Pay you a hundred dollars, if they can do that,
Speaker 1:  But that's actually transformative.
Speaker 3:  But, but, but that is transformative. I agree, but that doesn't exist yet
Speaker 3:  because like that 500, 600 down is still only in the
Speaker 3:  dense urban areas I'm in suburbia. And I don't get that 560 if you're
Speaker 3:  in rural, you're getting two down.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Yeah. I've got like a friend. Who's got a two who is still held onto
Speaker 4:  like a to G phone because when he'd be out writing
Speaker 4:  horseback, checking on cattle is cowboy these not
Speaker 4:  just random man, checking on cattle.
Speaker 1:  I've got a friend whose hobby is checking on cat. He
Speaker 4:  Just likes to look at them and say a lot, but he couldn't get any other
Speaker 4:  connections. So if he like fell off his horse or something or hurt himself,
Speaker 4:  the only way to contact his family was with a super old phone. Like 3g didn't
Speaker 4:  work, 4g didn't work. He's just out there with a flip phone
Speaker 4:  and he didn't care that 5g is coming because they still
Speaker 4:  haven't really gotten 4g fully in his part of Colorado. So he's like, why
Speaker 4:  I don't, I don't need these speeds cause you'll never get them to me because
Speaker 4:  nobody wants to build the infrastructure to the rural spaces where
Speaker 4:  5g would be transformative.
Speaker 3:  I'm never going to harness our legal legends talent from the rural areas
Speaker 3:  of this country. If we don't fix this connectivity
Speaker 4:  Using so many of the talented league of legend players right
Speaker 4:  now, because we cannot properly build out
Speaker 4:  rural,
Speaker 1:  But just do the underlying that everyone in area needs 500
Speaker 1:  down there, which is still crazy. We're all going to be wearing the headset.
Speaker 1:  It's just like wandering through life. And like real-time VR feeds. Well,
Speaker 1:  you definitely need a fiber connection to all those towers support
Speaker 1:  all of that bandwidth. And like that's the actual problem in these rural
Speaker 1:  areas. And if you can get fiber to the roads, you might as well run the rest
Speaker 1:  of the fiber. Cause you already spent so much money. We have done endless
Speaker 1:  coverage on this problem on our site, on this podcast, I won't belabor it.
Speaker 1:  I'm just, it's a very nice phone. It's very cool. It comes in multiple colors,
Speaker 1:  including midnight and Starlight.
Speaker 3:  It's not black and not silver. It's not black.
Speaker 1:  It's Starlight midnight and Starlight, but it's just hard to not look
Speaker 1:  at it and look at the F the entire 5g hype cycle and be
Speaker 1:  like, oh man, like Verizon was just head faking us. And what their
Speaker 1:  5g plan actually was this whole time
Speaker 2:  Today, I'm excited to talk about iPad air. We're
Speaker 3:  Bringing the breakthrough M one chip to iPad.
Speaker 1:  Let's talk about the iPad real quick. Cause I think we can get through it
Speaker 1:  really quickly.
Speaker 3:  Again, it is an iPad air that you may be familiar with from
Speaker 3:  2019, same exact appearance. And now it's got an M one inside of it.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 1:  And 5g.
Speaker 3:  And it does have the 5g. It has the same sub six 5g that we've been talking
Speaker 3:  about. So it's really like they took the upgrades that the iPad
Speaker 3:  mini got last year and applied them to the air design, except they
Speaker 3:  upgraded the processor also all the way up to the , which means that this
Speaker 3:  is the same chip in it as the Mac book air as the
Speaker 3:  13 inch MacBook pro as the Mac mini as the iPad pro
Speaker 3:  both sizes of the iPad pro. So for 600 bucks, you are
Speaker 3:  getting one of Apple's most performance processors that it uses in its
Speaker 3:  mainstream, most widely sold laptops, which is pretty incredible. Can you
Speaker 3:  do anything with that performance? I mean, it's an iPad,
Speaker 3:  so sure. Maybe there's something, well, you can
Speaker 4:  Download your movies real fast,
Speaker 1:  Intelligent
Speaker 3:  Movies, real fast, and it's got the center stage front facing camera.
Speaker 3:  So it will, if you're doing video calls, it will automatically follow you,
Speaker 1:  But it's still in the wrong spot, still in the wrong spot. Yes. Baffling
Speaker 1:  decision. And it, because you can use this thing as a laptop replacement,
Speaker 1:  as you can with,
Speaker 3:  I mean, it's, it works with all of the same accessories as before. So he
Speaker 3:  works with the magic keyboard, works with the smart keyboard. It works with
Speaker 3:  the same pencil, apple confirmed that it is exactly the same dimension. So
Speaker 3:  if you have an old iPad air and have cases and accessories and all that stuff,
Speaker 3:  they're just going to work with this new one right away. There's no, no nothing
Speaker 3:  really new. You need to buy, but it is a 10.9 inch
Speaker 3:  screen and it's running iPad a Wes. I do not know how many people would
Speaker 3:  really want to use that as their only computing device. If they have an
Speaker 3:  opportunity to have a laptop with a larger screen and a more capable
Speaker 3:  pro operating system on it. But it looks to be like a very
Speaker 3:  nice iPad. The thing that's interesting about it is
Speaker 3:  this kind of happened last time with the last refresh of the iPad air is
Speaker 3:  now it steps on the toes of the iPad pro a lot. And the
Speaker 3:  only differences between the air and the pro 11 inch
Speaker 3:  now are you get promotion or the 120 Hertz screen on the
Speaker 3:  pro you get face ID on the pro and you get a second
Speaker 3:  rear camera and LIDAR sensor on the pro oh, you get four
Speaker 3:  cameras or four speakers instead of two.
Speaker 4:  So
Speaker 1:  I mean, if there's one thing that's going to sell me in slide our sensor
Speaker 1:  and just slide our hang all over town.
Speaker 4:  Well, the pro though, the 11 inch pro was always kind of like the ugly
Speaker 4:  stepchild of the lineup because it didn't
Speaker 1:  Get the .
Speaker 4:  I love it. I have, I have the one from the previous
Speaker 4:  generation, but it was, it was really frustrating when they announced that
Speaker 4:  when they did their last refresh, because really, really cool
Speaker 4:  display in the 12 edge. And then the 11 inch, he was
Speaker 4:  like, Nope, you get some, you get faster than the iPad air. Like that
Speaker 4:  was the big difference between it and the iPad air and why I bought it
Speaker 4:  stupidly. But now I feel I've got just a lot of FOMO.
Speaker 4:  This is just me processing my feelings.
Speaker 1:  Well, so you can, you can see the, what they would do in
Speaker 1:  almost any other case would be, they're going to upgrade the iPad pro
Speaker 1:  to the mini led display. Maybe still keep the old one in there. That's
Speaker 1:  fine. But you get a better display, a better speakers, one more
Speaker 1:  camera, face ID and LIDAR who doesn't love
Speaker 4:  LIDAR. We have to wait like a year and a half for that to happen.
Speaker 1:  All the rumors are that the, the mini led is still too
Speaker 1:  expensive. So I do think it's stuck in the middle. You
Speaker 1:  know, the price difference is vanishingly small, right?
Speaker 3:  Between the 11 pro and the iPad air is 200 bucks, but
Speaker 3:  you do get twice the storage and the probe. So the air, this is like the
Speaker 3:  one criticism I have against the air is that they are still keeping it at
Speaker 3:  64 gigs in the base storage. And then getting more storage is
Speaker 3:  $150 upgrade to 2 56.
Speaker 1:  They absolutely have done that on purpose, right? That's the one that's
Speaker 1:  where they know that if you spend $150 to get the storage, you might as
Speaker 1:  well just buy the pro.
Speaker 3:  I mean, it's like it gets this annoying, like matrix because the
Speaker 3:  $150 that you spend on the air gets you 256 gigs of storage.
Speaker 3:  And the pro starts at 1 28. So you aren't getting as much with the pro,
Speaker 3:  but I think most people on an iPad are going to be perfectly fine with 108
Speaker 3:  gigs, 64 gigs might be pushing it. If you are trying
Speaker 3:  to actually replace a laptop with this kind of thing,
Speaker 3:  if all you're doing is like iPads stuff, tablets stuff, you
Speaker 3:  know, I think 64 would probably be cover you. But if you are trying to
Speaker 3:  replace your main computer or trying to make it your main computer, you're
Speaker 3:  probably going to run into some issues with storage. I
Speaker 3:  think gets you an impact is like 16 gigs. So, you know, there's a
Speaker 3:  quarter of your storage gone if you play that game. So it's, it's a little
Speaker 3:  frustrating that they've kept that storage level, but like you said, it is,
Speaker 3:  it seems perfectly designed to get you to be like, well, if I'm going to
Speaker 3:  spend the upgrade, I might as well spend a little more and get the pro and
Speaker 3:  the other nice features because I will say face ID on the iPad. I think I
Speaker 3:  said this last week face ID on the iPad is a lot nicer than touch ID on the
Speaker 3:  iPad.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I answered apple is historically very smart at being
Speaker 1:  like, no matter how many dollars you have, we will have a
Speaker 1:  product within $50 of how many dollars you have, right? Like, you know, either
Speaker 1:  direction, you just tell us an amount of dollars and we have an
Speaker 1:  iOS device for you. Right? And like, I think there's a little bit of muddle
Speaker 1:  there because right. The, the upgrade cycles are not
Speaker 1:  perfectly aligned, but I think it's part of that as chip shortage. I do think
Speaker 1:  all the rumors about the display technology not getting cheaper fast enough
Speaker 1:  is real. They're the only company shipping many led screens. Like
Speaker 1:  at scale,
Speaker 3:  I have a very harebrained theory that does not have a lot
Speaker 3:  of evidence backing it off, but I was very
Speaker 3:  surprised when they announced the M one ship was coming into the air and
Speaker 3:  they were just using the eight 15 because the predictable thing was the last
Speaker 3:  one, used a 14, I believe. And so this one would have the eight,
Speaker 3:  15, and the iPad mini had the eight 15 a and they just went straight up to
Speaker 3:  the M one. And my theory is Apple's producing
Speaker 3:  as many a fifteens as it possibly can. And it's putting them in all the I-phones
Speaker 3:  like we just said, it's in the iPhone se it's in all the iPhone models. And
Speaker 3:  so it is reserving them for that and figured it could just put the M one
Speaker 3:  in the air because it, now it doesn't have to take stock away from the
Speaker 3:  iPhones. And
Speaker 1:  This is based on the fact that the mini is almost impossible yet.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Mini's really hard to get. And there's been a lot of reporting that
Speaker 3:  apple was diverting production to the mini towards the iPhone so
Speaker 3:  that it could keep up with demands for the iPhone,
Speaker 1:  Anything on it, all that said this on our earnings call trip shortages finally
Speaker 1:  sort of caught up to them. This is all by the way, you have to wear a tie
Speaker 1:  with this event, they're putting eight 13 in the display. So it's
Speaker 1:  like, I think it's catching up to them in an extremely odd
Speaker 1:  ways. Right. They're just making as much as they can
Speaker 3:  Until they have to just use a series chips for like all the little, little
Speaker 3:  things like, like the display controller and the iPad is now in a
Speaker 3:  13.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. For no reason. So I do think there's a little bit of awareness there.
Speaker 1:  I don't know that M ones are not also constrained. Like
Speaker 1:  they're making, they're selling every Mac that they can, but the
Speaker 3:  Is based on the 14. Right? So it's got a
Speaker 3:  longer life cycle in terms of development for that process.
Speaker 3:  Whereas a 15 is a new process. They only
Speaker 1:  Started a new process. Know what you mean? Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 3:  So that's where my theories come from. Like I said, I could be way off and,
Speaker 3:  and I don't have like actual hard evidence backing this up, but it, it, it
Speaker 3:  kind of slots together if you squint really closely.
Speaker 3:  And
Speaker 1:  If you've been drinking, this makes a lot of sense.
Speaker 4:  The other theory is this is all just a long lead up to
Speaker 4:  killing iPad with.
Speaker 1:  That's not a theory. That's just your fond hope. I've not heard this theory.
Speaker 1:  I would like to hear this. This is Alex. Just, you're just a manifesting.
Speaker 4:  I don't believe it. I fully do not believe it, but I was hearing it a
Speaker 4:  lot the last couple of days. And people being like, oh, this is all just,
Speaker 4:  they put the one in there. Just put Macko S on it, be done with it, kill
Speaker 4:  iPad. O S
Speaker 1:  They're never going to you're 1000% manifesting. Like I
Speaker 1:  wanted them to do that,
Speaker 4:  But I do I a little bit feel iPad. iOS has a short
Speaker 4:  lifespan now, because one in one, right. That's
Speaker 4:  that's on all the, most of the major iPads with the exception of the
Speaker 4:  original iPad and the iPad mini, right? Yes.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And then the other thing is we're going to get a folding device at
Speaker 4:  some point, right? We're going to get, we're going to get a full list. We're
Speaker 4:  going to get a folding device and it's got to either run iOS or iPad
Speaker 4:  iOS. It can't run both. So you're not going to kill
Speaker 4:  iOS.
Speaker 3:  And I always had the
Speaker 3:  same
Speaker 3:  But
Speaker 4:  The Apple's going to have to explain that, and they're just going to kill
Speaker 4:  it. They're just going to take care of,
Speaker 1:  We're not going to kill it. We talked to a bunch of folks after the event
Speaker 1:  and their position. Cause I asked very directly like, Hey, you used to
Speaker 1:  run around telling us that the iPad was the future of
Speaker 1:  computing. And you took your eye off the Mac and you've admitted it. You
Speaker 1:  had meetings with people to be like, we are sorry. We forgot about the
Speaker 1:  Macintosh because you were all in on the app. Like this was a real thing
Speaker 1:  that happened apple. And Apple's pretty direct about it. They had the
Speaker 1:  meetings and say, we took our eye off the mat, and now they're putting out
Speaker 1:  Macs that everybody's wanted forever. And I get that happened, but
Speaker 1:  everybody buys a Mac, buys an iPad. And it's still our vision
Speaker 1:  of what this kind of computing could be like.
Speaker 1:  They are in no way trying to blur those lines. Like if you
Speaker 1:  are apple, you're Tim cook. And you're like, so my choices are, I can
Speaker 1:  sell people to computers or one. They're always
Speaker 1:  going to pick two because that is currently what's happening. People like
Speaker 1:  the amount of, I own every product in the apple, apple
Speaker 1:  ecosystem is the envy of the computing world. And so I just, at some
Speaker 1:  point, yep, the lines are getting real blurry and Apple's going to be like,
Speaker 1:  well, are they blurry enough for you to buy two computers or one?
Speaker 1:  And keep you buying two. They're just going to keep you buying
Speaker 4:  Two, one day, man, it's going to happen.
Speaker 1:  They're going to keep, I think, tried to kill the Mac is what I'm
Speaker 1:  saying.
Speaker 3:  They did everything in their power. They put a terrible keyboard in it. They
Speaker 3:  took all the ports away it over here. People
Speaker 3:  still want this. What would we have to do to kill this product?
Speaker 1:  Yeah. That original Mac book air, or the, I guess it was a second-generation
Speaker 1:  aggregator. They just persisted in that design forever.
Speaker 1:  Like literally their, their stated explanation was people won't stop buying
Speaker 1:  this. They're like, no retina
Speaker 1:  display like ancient processor,
Speaker 4:  Like 14 by 900
Speaker 3:  Had mini display port on it.
Speaker 1:  And people like, they were just like, we don't know. We're like, it's cause
Speaker 1:  it's the only good back. Like everything else is kind of a
Speaker 1:  disaster. So like, I think that they are, they're pretty
Speaker 1:  committed to not necessarily iPad OS,
Speaker 1:  but I think they're committed to their strategy of selling more
Speaker 3:  Stuff,
Speaker 1:  More computers, selling more. They were very committed to the strategy of
Speaker 1:  selling more computers that we know for sure.
Speaker 1:  It's very sincere that they would like you to buy
Speaker 1:  more, no confusion there. But I think they
Speaker 1:  are actually committed to the Mac is this
Speaker 1:  platform where like pros
Speaker 1:  make pro stuff and lots of consumers want consumer max
Speaker 1:  to work from home. And we've got this vision
Speaker 1:  of a, another kind of computer where every button pays us
Speaker 1:  30% of every dollar, like right. And like, they're just gonna
Speaker 1:  keep rolling in that direction for a long time. But I,
Speaker 1:  I hope you speak this into truth.
Speaker 4:  I just feel like we're, we're careening towards an end game. Like Apple's
Speaker 4:  going to have to lay
Speaker 1:  For so
Speaker 4:  Long when the folding iPad comes, when the full or folding whatever
Speaker 4:  comes, that will be the moment. Like that will be the moment. We're all.
Speaker 4:  We're all gonna be like, wait a minute, wait a minute. iPad. OOS is
Speaker 4:  just a rescreened iOS. Why are we doing two of these?
Speaker 4:  It's dumb. And like, it's coming and we're going to have to kill it.
Speaker 1:  We'll see. Well, what's your prediction. When a folding apple
Speaker 1:  product comes, I think if ever
Speaker 4:  It's like a year or two, right. Where we keep hearing, maybe even next
Speaker 4:  year,
Speaker 3:  I thought the last reporting was like 20, 24, 20, 25.
Speaker 4:  But I need, I need it now. Like Samsung did
Speaker 4:  it Samsung. It's usually Samsung does it at an apple. Does it? Three years
Speaker 4:  later
Speaker 3:  We have, we have history to lean on. Right? The galaxy note came out in
Speaker 3:  2011, proving that big phones were something people
Speaker 3:  wanted. And three years later apple had the iPhone six
Speaker 3:  plus.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  But three years from the galaxy full launch would be like now, so that doesn't
Speaker 3:  like work. If you use that logic,
Speaker 4:  That's what I said, they're there, they're behind. So it's going to be, it's
Speaker 4:  going to be next year. I'm manifesting that part.
Speaker 1:  The apple feels like they're behind. I think they're looking at Samsung fully
Speaker 1:  feeling like they're being the phones are good, but Samsung is like,
Speaker 1:  yeah,
Speaker 4:  Apple's looking at his record sales. And it's like, wait, we don't have to
Speaker 4:  do that.
Speaker 1:  I do not think they feel pressure. Like Lisa said the slot, like new
Speaker 1:  form factors at what prompts people to switch.
Speaker 4:  Right. Oh man, that means we're going to have to like, it's going to be like
Speaker 4:  four or five years. Cause the Mac mini just came out.
Speaker 5:  Oh, this is upsetting.
Speaker 1:  I have to leave this cast. I'll talk to you later. If you're, I just don't
Speaker 1:  think the iPhone team is looking at any of Samsung's foldables and like
Speaker 1:  quake and then they're good.
Speaker 1:  Phones are very cool. I'm not denigrating them. I just think no one
Speaker 1:  is switching in that direction. Right? This was the sat they said about the
Speaker 1:  se, right? We've like attracted more new customers, the iPhone with these
Speaker 1:  products and ever before. And as long as they can just like wedge a
Speaker 1:  message into the American discourse. They're good.
Speaker 1:  The phones Nashville. Okay. We should take a break. We, I don't know how
Speaker 1:  we got to. I message. Everything just leads to
Speaker 1:  blue bubbles. I am not to blame Ivan. I have this theory about like things
Speaker 1:  the verge believes. And that's just on my list is that the
Speaker 1:  entire phone market is like distorted by a
Speaker 1:  message. And we all know it and we can't, you can't just like
Speaker 1:  walk the streets, proclaiming this. Like everyone will be like, who are you?
Speaker 1:  Like we're just in Cinnabon. Leave us alone.
Speaker 1:  But it's extremely true. Okay. We've got to take a break. We're gonna come
Speaker 1:  back and talk about this Mac. We'll be right
Speaker 1:  back.
Speaker 1:  It's 2007 and people are hustling. Two roommates need some cash. They start
Speaker 1:  renting an air mattress in their apartment. Strangers stay with them. Those
Speaker 1:  roommates earn some extra spending money and Airbnb is born. What happened
Speaker 1:  next? That company exploded with rentals available in more than 100,000
Speaker 1:  cities. One of those cities was prepared to go to battle on behalf of renters
Speaker 1:  and hotels to keep Airbnb at bay business wars wonder is a
Speaker 1:  podcast that looks at the world's biggest company rivals their new season,
Speaker 1:  Airbnb versus New York city examines. How that struggle became a symbol for
Speaker 1:  the tug of war, between startups and regulators. What started as a clever
Speaker 1:  way to learn a little extra cash quickly transformed into something a lot
Speaker 1:  more complicated, which begins to impact the housing and rental markets.
Speaker 1:  When New York city officials decided to curb down the expansion of Airbnb
Speaker 1:  into the city, the tech giant refused to back down. And that's when things
Speaker 1:  got really interesting. Listen to business wars on apple podcasts, Amazon
Speaker 1:  music, or listen, ad-free by joining Wondery plus in the Wondery
Speaker 1:  app,
Speaker 5:  Important conversations around what it means to be a professional or happening
Speaker 5:  right now on LinkedIn members are talking about things like adding flexibility
Speaker 5:  to where and how we work. They're talking honestly about taking time away
Speaker 5:  from work, to focus on their families and mental health, because those things
Speaker 5:  should not stuck to career development and showing up to work on our own
Speaker 5:  terms. As our full selves, isn't an impediment to growth. It's actually the
Speaker 5:  key to unlocking it. LinkedIn members are adding vital new information to
Speaker 5:  their job. Titles and workers everywhere are defining themselves more
Speaker 5:  completely. There are radio hosts slash activist slash moms,
Speaker 5:  finance managers slash poets slash dog dads. And so many
Speaker 5:  more professional is our acidifying. So if your LinkedIn doesn't
Speaker 5:  reflect who you really are, update your job title, post your
Speaker 5:  truth, show the world, the authentic professional you and
Speaker 5:  join the conversations redefining professional on LinkedIn,
Speaker 5:  LinkedIn welcome
Speaker 5:  professionals.
Speaker 1:  All right, we're back. This
Speaker 7:  Is Mac studio and studio.
Speaker 1:  I am very excited about this Mac, the Mac studio, new Mac got a
Speaker 1:  new chip in it. It's basically just a tall Mac mini. It looks like a
Speaker 1:  toaster. So a bunch of ports has got, it's got a two USB
Speaker 1:  C or Thunderbolt ports, depending on the chip. We'll talk about that SD card
Speaker 1:  on the front front facing ports from facing towards fan. What a
Speaker 1:  beautiful thing. All kinds of IO, new chips. I'll
Speaker 1:  just preface this. I will say this weekend, we're going to have Jason
Speaker 1:  Snell he's to run Macworld magazine. I have a piece on the site about the
Speaker 1:  history of people demanding a product. Exactly
Speaker 1:  like this from apple, like easily, since the nineties,
Speaker 1:  can you ship a mid range, powerful tower
Speaker 1:  ish computer with a lot of IO that we can just bring
Speaker 1:  our own monitor and keyboard to like since the nineties, like, it's
Speaker 1:  hilarious how long people have wanted something exactly in the slot from
Speaker 1:  apple and it, you know, who wrote the headline and site
Speaker 1:  was a John that's. Apple's just doing what people want now. Yes. Yes. Like
Speaker 1:  that's their whole max strategy is like, what do people always wanted? We
Speaker 1:  should make this things. So like, I, I am excited
Speaker 1:  about that just because it's interesting to see
Speaker 1:  apple just deliver a thing that people have wanted for easily
Speaker 1:  20 years. There's they've never made a product like this
Speaker 4:  Mac book, like the refreshed Mac book, air, the MacBook pro they're
Speaker 4:  like, oh wait, if we actually give computer users what they're
Speaker 4:  requesting, they will buy computers from us.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I mean, I think, I think that came to like the most
Speaker 3:  clear way with the MacBook pros last year, right? Like people were
Speaker 3:  waiting for so long to buy Mac book pros and then apple finally rolled out
Speaker 3:  everything. Everyone was been asking for in MacBook pros and everybody bought
Speaker 3:  them.
Speaker 1:  My M one pro 16 inch Macro-Pro is by far
Speaker 1:  the best computer I've ever had. Yeah. Without a doubt, no
Speaker 1:  questions. I've there. I've had many stupid
Speaker 1:  computers. I've many computers I've been very fond of, but this is just by
Speaker 1:  far the most capable computer. That's great. But what's
Speaker 1:  interesting to me about this is this is the first time they've done it in
Speaker 1:  a new category where people were demanding as apple enter a category.
Speaker 1:  They were not in for 20 years. The last time that they made a
Speaker 1:  computer, like this was the G4 Q
Speaker 7:  This is a stunning product, quite possibly the most beautiful
Speaker 7:  product we've ever designed. The computer is in an eight inch queue
Speaker 7:  and it's suspended in a stunning crystal clear and close.
Speaker 4:  It was actually a terrible, terrible device, but it looked so
Speaker 4:  cool.
Speaker 1:  It looks so cool. And I worked in the, when I was in college, I was like,
Speaker 1:  the, it support the science library. It was great. It was a great job.
Speaker 4:  You had all the G4S, the little cube.
Speaker 1:  We had tons of little cubes. I mean, that job was like, sit around and do
Speaker 1:  your homework for like 12 bucks an hour. It was great. It was an amazing
Speaker 1:  job out of college, but people would like lose a file or they would get
Speaker 1:  confused or like they couldn't figure out a plan. And then he was like, go
Speaker 1:  help him in the science library, it was full of G4 cubes. And so
Speaker 1:  everyone would sit down and they get all excited and they would put their
Speaker 1:  papers on top of the cube on the top. So it blocked the vet and
Speaker 1:  the thing would overheat and it would shut down in the middle of the work.
Speaker 1:  And so we had to put signs on the G4 cubes to be like, do not put shit on
Speaker 1:  top of this computer thoroughly ruined the aesthetic of the entire thing.
Speaker 1:  Anyway, that's the last time apple has ever made anything like that.
Speaker 3:  Notably the vents are on the back of the
Speaker 3:  bed. Can not the top.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Eric comes in, there's two fans, air comes in from the bottom, the
Speaker 1:  fan spin. They go out. It's like 20,000.
Speaker 3:  It's basically the same concept as the Mac mini, just bigger with more
Speaker 3:  fans and a bigger heat sink area, but same
Speaker 4:  Flow and bigger processors.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. We'll get into those. Yeah. I'm just saying it's the first time they've
Speaker 1:  entered a category that people demanding for 20 years after this one,
Speaker 1:  notorious failure was Steve jobs announced that the queue
Speaker 1:  was only putting put on hiatus by saying it was going on ice because it was
Speaker 1:  a cube. So now it's back. It's not on HIAs anymore. It's
Speaker 1:  back. This thing looks, you know, people are excited about it. It is basically
Speaker 1:  the replacement for the iMac pro. I would like to say, it's paired
Speaker 1:  with this studio display, which has
Speaker 1:  1599. And then it's got these chips in it, which actually
Speaker 1:  really changed the pricing. So the base models and one max,
Speaker 1:  same as the 16 inch tweet we know and love the same as the 16 inch
Speaker 1:  MacBook pro that configuration costs
Speaker 1:  $2,000. Yes. And then there's a new chip called the
Speaker 1:  ultra, which is effectively two M one. Max is stitched
Speaker 1:  together, which we should talk about. And that configuration starts at
Speaker 1:  $4,000.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, you can, you can like whittle it down a little bit and get it for like
Speaker 3:  3,800, if you're willing to go with five, 12 gigs of storage instead of
Speaker 3:  one terabyte. But everything in
Speaker 1:  These computers is soldered in. So
Speaker 3:  Like, yeah, you probably should just spend the 200 bucks. If you're spending
Speaker 3:  3,800, you probably should just spend the 200 to get at least a terabyte
Speaker 3:  of storage in it. So, yeah, but it's kind of funny because it's like the
Speaker 3:  base model, a Mac studio, it comes with the M
Speaker 3:  one max 32 gigs of Ram and five 12 gigs of storage for two
Speaker 3:  grand. And then for four grand, you get the  ultra,
Speaker 3:  which is two M one maxes. You get 64 gigs of Ram
Speaker 3:  and one terabyte of storage. So you get two of
Speaker 3:  everything
Speaker 4:  That makes sense.
Speaker 1:  I like it. So Alex, this, this chip is like fascinating. The
Speaker 1:  ultra.
Speaker 4:  I think Tom Warren did a great piece about this too. Probably the
Speaker 4:  most interesting thing about it is the ultra fusion tech, which
Speaker 4:  is what's allowing them to stitch two processors together
Speaker 4:  because like everybody's kind of started embracing something called triplet
Speaker 4:  design where you take lots of little smaller components, put them together,
Speaker 4:  make a big, fast chip. I think just last
Speaker 4:  week there was a new standard announced for triplet design Hein wrote a wonderful
Speaker 4:  piece about it. So Apple's like not using that same standard. They're
Speaker 4:  focusing on this thing called ultra fusion tech, which is more like
Speaker 4:  AMD's infinity fabric. And if you don't, if you've never heard
Speaker 4:  of AMD is infinity fabric, it's why you've probably been hearing all about
Speaker 4:  AMD for the last couple of years. This is absolutely was a huge game changer
Speaker 4:  for AMD when they rolled it out with the new Ryzen
Speaker 4:  chips, like when the Ryzen line launched huge, huge game
Speaker 4:  changer. And it just allowed the D various triplets to communicate really
Speaker 4:  quickly. And it allowed them to start being really competitive with
Speaker 4:  Intel in the integrated CPU space, because they could integrate
Speaker 4:  and have those, the GPU and the CPU talk faster than an
Speaker 4:  Intel product could Apple's is 2.5
Speaker 4:  terabytes of bandwidth between the two sides. And that's just
Speaker 4:  like unreal. That is so much faster. They're, they're
Speaker 4:  basically faster than the infinity fabric. They're basically
Speaker 4:  faster than NVIDIA's like
Speaker 4:  comparative product, which is called link in
Speaker 4:  feeling. And it's just, it's wild. And it's
Speaker 4:  neat. Tom talked about how it's aiming to be
Speaker 4:  the NVIDIA's RTX 30, 90. I don't quite agree with him
Speaker 4:  there because I think most people are still
Speaker 4:  buying GPU's are those like 30 nineties and stuff
Speaker 4:  are gamers for the most part.
Speaker 4:  And apple, I say this as someone who tried to build a
Speaker 4:  gaming beat around apple in the late two
Speaker 4:  thousands. Wow. Do you know, I'm not famous for it? And there's a
Speaker 4:  reason.
Speaker 3:  So apple made the claim with the M one pro and what max
Speaker 3:  launched that it was comparable to an RTX 30, 60. And we found out that
Speaker 3:  that was not really the case with any reasonable
Speaker 3:  tests that you might do. So now they're making the claim against the 30 90
Speaker 3:  with the ultra we're going to have to do
Speaker 1:  So with this trip, I w the claims are hard to even
Speaker 1:  describe, right? They did the thing again, where they put up a bunch of
Speaker 1:  graphs, the graphs, the, if they have labels at all, a lot of the
Speaker 1:  graphs are like, it's 3.7 X faster than a 27 inch
Speaker 1:  iMac. And the 27 inch iMac has a bar that goes to a hundred. And
Speaker 1:  then the other graph is just longer. So it's like extra
Speaker 1:  vibes and then it's longer, but it's also more colorful. So
Speaker 1:  if that speaks to you and you, you know how to test that, let me know. Cause
Speaker 1:  we're, you know, we had to figure it out. The other graphs are like the classic
Speaker 1:  power performance graphs that apple does. It's relative
Speaker 3:  Performance versus blotted.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. And so they measure the Watts and then give you relative performance
Speaker 1:  in tiny print on those graphs, which flashed by
Speaker 1:  extraordinarily fast, during this already extremely
Speaker 1:  fast event, you find out that it's a 30, 90, you find out that, you know,
Speaker 1:  it's a various PCs that are powerful, but it's
Speaker 1:  impossible to know what they're running. Yeah. So like, if, if
Speaker 1:  we are reviewing the same, we want to like verify their claim. I don't
Speaker 1:  even know what to do.
Speaker 4:  It could be like, it's faster than the 30, 90 at the AI
Speaker 4:  test on civilization six, you know, like cool. That
Speaker 4:  only tests the CPU that was
Speaker 3:  Faster than 30, 90 at running final cut
Speaker 3:  pro.
Speaker 1:  So it's just like, oh, that is just like hard to understand. What I will
Speaker 1:  say about this ship is that I think that the fundamental technology is very
Speaker 1:  cool. There's because apple makes both the hardware in the
Speaker 1:  software and it doesn't nothing else runs than these chips, except I pad
Speaker 1:  iOS, I guess. But like they make all that too.
Speaker 1:  They are able to abstract the fact that it's
Speaker 1:  triplets in that way in a way that other companies cannot.
Speaker 1:  So like a lot of like metal, the graphics system, the Maxwell
Speaker 1:  metal metal developers were freaking out about a tweet from an apple
Speaker 1:  engineer. Who's like the M one ultra only presents one metal
Speaker 1:  interface. Like it's not two GPU's to your software.
Speaker 1:  It's only, it's just one ship. That's extremely powerful. That is
Speaker 1:  somewhat revolutionary. And it's one, one
Speaker 3:  Pool of
Speaker 1:  Shared unified memory. And that, and that's crazy. So if you can get 128
Speaker 1:  gigs of memory to a GPU, like no one has ever been able to do that, you get
Speaker 1:  128 gigs of memory to a CPU that runs as fast as graphics
Speaker 1:  memory. No, one's able to do that. I will say. And I asked about this
Speaker 1:  and we're just going to have to see Apple's big bet has been on
Speaker 1:  this unified memory architecture. Yeah. And with the early and
Speaker 1:  ones that only ship just gigs of Ram, people do just run out of
Speaker 1:  memory, right? Like the video card and the CPU are competing for memory and
Speaker 1:  you can just max it out, which is not something you're used to on a modern
Speaker 1:  computer at 128 gigs. And I ran up, I'll try it. Like if
Speaker 1:  you're are doing gigantic 3d scenes or you're doing this other
Speaker 1:  memory intensive stuff, like, I think I have to order is gonna have to be
Speaker 1:  careful. It's unclear if apple reserves Ram for the
Speaker 1:  system like that stuff is just, it's a big bet that is now playing out
Speaker 1:  at the high end of the market. We've already kind of see how it plays out
Speaker 1:  at the low end.
Speaker 4:  We're singing in that base model studio too. Right? Like most people's
Speaker 4:  base model stuff is still say eight or 16 gigs like
Speaker 4:  windows PCs and stuff. They're all going to be in
Speaker 3:  The studios is starting at 32.
Speaker 4:  Right. And that's what I mean is the studio is starting at 32 gigs because
Speaker 4:  this is a little bit more memory hungry, like set
Speaker 4:  up than an Intel or an AMD processor.
Speaker 4:  So I think apple is very like cognizant of it. That's what I felt like I
Speaker 4:  was winning when I saw I was not going to have to pay extra for 32 gigabytes
Speaker 4:  of Ram. I was like, Ooh, a surprise for me. And I was like,
Speaker 4:  oh, actually I need it. I'm going to really need
Speaker 4:  it.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. So I think this computer, it's the first computer of
Speaker 1:  this kind we've seen from apple with M one chips in it. Yes, the macro crows
Speaker 1:  exists, but in the context, people are going to use this computer. I think
Speaker 1:  the memory issue will be more complicated. I don't think it'll be bad.
Speaker 1:  I think it's just going to play out differently because this is a professional
Speaker 1:  desktop machine and people are going to do that kind of stuff with it. So
Speaker 1:  we'll see. It's a, it is a huge bet. What is interesting?
Speaker 3:  And to me is that, like you said, Apple's saying this is going to show up
Speaker 3:  as one processor in the systems and will show up as one processor, one pool
Speaker 3:  of memory, one GPU to the apps that
Speaker 3:  access it. But you get all the benefits of two
Speaker 3:  processors because you get twice the head room for memory. So now, you know,
Speaker 3:  you start at 64, you have 1 28 as an option. You can only go to
Speaker 3:  64 on the max. So if you have two maxes, now you've got 1
Speaker 3:  28. And it quite literally is a north and south bridge. That memory that
Speaker 3:  is like a pool of 64 and a pool of 64 that's blended together. Then
Speaker 3:  you get more Thunderbolt ports on the IO with the ultra,
Speaker 3:  because it has more lanes of PCI bandwidth because it is two chips
Speaker 3:  as opposed to one that are fused together. So it's, it's, you're like getting
Speaker 3:  a little benefits of having two processors, but you're also getting all the
Speaker 3:  benefits of one super fast processor
Speaker 3:  that can communicate very quickly between all of these lanes of,
Speaker 3:  of memory and, and whatnot. So it's a pretty fascinating set
Speaker 3:  set up.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. And I will say apple is very clear. This is the last chip in the
Speaker 1:  M one family. And they were very clear that the only computer left is
Speaker 1:  the Mac pro. They did that on purpose. They were very clear that they were
Speaker 1:  like, we needed to say this. So people like know, like this isn't the
Speaker 1:  replacement for the Mac pro this is the Mac studio. We're, they're still
Speaker 1:  doing a Mac pro, but we're not, there's no, like
Speaker 1:  tremendous chip coming here. Like whatever, whatever words they have,
Speaker 4:  What's the big differentiator. Is it going to be GPU and having a
Speaker 4:  S AMD GPU on it? Will that be the big difference between the
Speaker 4:  two?
Speaker 1:  It'd be fascinating if they'd stick with other people's GPU's I don't know.
Speaker 1:  That'll be it.
Speaker 3:  I just have a feeling that the pro is going to come out with an M two, like,
Speaker 3:  that's just my gut.
Speaker 4:  You don't think it's going to be like seven  bolted
Speaker 4:  together.
Speaker 3:  I suppose they could scale this ultra fusion. They can, so that
Speaker 3:  they're doing two here and they could do four in it, but like then what
Speaker 3:  do they call it? Ultra squared.
Speaker 3:  Like, I mean, like, they, they, they said that it's not going to be any
Speaker 3:  other chips in this M one family. Right? So
Speaker 4:  They don't, they don't call the various builds of the  ultra because
Speaker 4:  you can get it there. There's a couple of, couple of different thread counts
Speaker 4:  for,
Speaker 3:  But those are just like cores being turned on and off on the diet, right?
Speaker 3:  Like if they wanted to do two and one ultras fused by ultra
Speaker 3:  fusion, that would be like twice the dyed bandwidth or twice the dye
Speaker 3:  footprint.
Speaker 1:  I think that might be overthinking it. They might just do a Mac pro and have
Speaker 1:  two I'm on ultra ship center or whatever they could do that if they wanted
Speaker 1:  to. I doubt it. But,
Speaker 3:  But they communicate like that's the magic of this is that the ultra fusion
Speaker 3:  is two M one Max's communicating really quickly.
Speaker 4:  Like I think in one ultra is just when we start fusing chips together,
Speaker 4:  that's our ultra. And like I said, they're not
Speaker 4:  going to do this. Is it? This is it. And it would be really weird to
Speaker 4:  announce. I mean, I guess it wouldn't be weird if they do the
Speaker 4:  the Mac pro as an  device, but
Speaker 4:  that means they have to announce the entire M two
Speaker 4:  lineup.
Speaker 1:  They don't have to dance the entire, let me see Atlanta. So there are some
Speaker 1:  rumors that they'll do some more stuff at WWDC. We'll
Speaker 1:  see. I would say the thing you get rid of that a Mac pro is
Speaker 1:  expansion slots. Yeah. Like that's the thing that, that category of user
Speaker 1:  needs, there's all kinds of weird accelerators, stored
Speaker 1:  solutions. They're going to have to figure out some kind of
Speaker 1:  expansion slots.
Speaker 4:  I got to figure out how to Frankenstein your old eight year old
Speaker 4:  Nvidia processor in there.
Speaker 1:  I don't know if they think about GPU is expansion, right? I don't think that
Speaker 1:  that's the case. I think it is weird accelerators, weird storage
Speaker 1:  solutions, weird controllers for specialized provocations
Speaker 1:  that need high bandwidth.
Speaker 4:  Well, pro stuff I say actual, because we all think like, I
Speaker 4:  definitely am like, oh, I got to get the pro device. I'm a pro, but I'm not
Speaker 4:  a pro I'm not a real,
Speaker 3:  I was looking at buying guides and they say recommended for pros. And I'm
Speaker 3:  like, yeah,
Speaker 4:  It's a real pro gets excited about those weird accelerators
Speaker 4:  on the Mac pro lineup. They're like, yes, I need that. And I do not care.
Speaker 1:  Look, I'm a professional podcaster and a, this 2015 iMac that I'm looking
Speaker 1:  at right now is no longer. It's like, it's all I need. Right. I get it. So
Speaker 1:  I just think that that will be the differentiator is they're going to figure
Speaker 1:  out that kind of IO, which they've not had any call to
Speaker 1:  do it. We should talk about the actual computers are one second. It is
Speaker 1:  port city on these, on these machines. It's beautiful. It is
Speaker 1:  beautiful. I mean, this has USB,
Speaker 3:  This has the rectangles. As Monica put on the site today, it
Speaker 3:  has the rectangles. It's got two USB ports. The back has
Speaker 3:  four Thunderbolt ports. If you get the ultra there's two
Speaker 3:  Thunderbolt ports on the front. If you get the max chip there's those are
Speaker 3:  USB-C ports. We already mentioned the SD card slot. It's going to HTMI
Speaker 3:  out, which is still HD mic 2.0, not 2.1. This
Speaker 3:  isn't for gamers, I guess.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. What are you going to do with H 2.1 and the computer that plays no
Speaker 1:  games and doesn't switch.
Speaker 3:  I want to scroll really fast and with 120 Hertz and we
Speaker 3:  screen,
Speaker 1:  Yeah, I just had fun Jack. Put that out there. It's a headphone Jack.
Speaker 1:  So the two USB ports are fascinating. So the Mac mini has had USB
Speaker 1:  too. Yeah. I think it's half a concession to reality
Speaker 1:  that some people just, especially for a desktop computer, there's lots of
Speaker 1:  USBA floating around. I think we've also heard there's
Speaker 1:  lots of weird pro software that has USB DRM,
Speaker 1:  dongles, and you just need to plug them in and wasting a Thunderbolt
Speaker 1:  port on like a little authentication key. It's just the saddest thing I've
Speaker 1:  ever heard in my entire life. So you just like stick it in the back, but
Speaker 1:  I do. But even that is concession to reality, right?
Speaker 1:  Like apple has tried this. I mean, I complained about
Speaker 1:  5g. Like the USBC cycle has
Speaker 1:  been a decade in the making and it has utterly failed to
Speaker 1:  win. And like, the reality is USB is still here. It's
Speaker 1:  still functional, still cheap as hell. And so even on your
Speaker 1:  fanciest new Mac, you're like, here's two USB ports because you might
Speaker 1:  have a ProTools dongle or something else that just needs to
Speaker 1:  off and wasting a for report on that
Speaker 1:  is, I mean, it's a crime. Like I'll come, I'll come to your
Speaker 1:  house.
Speaker 3:  The last desktop computer that apple introduced, which was the M
Speaker 3:  one iMac had no USB ports. And it was all
Speaker 3:  USB-C,
Speaker 1:  I'd love to hear from our listeners on us. I think Apple's belief is a
Speaker 1:  consumers don't play anything on their computers, which is like half, two
Speaker 1:  and a half. Not right. Like I think they just believe
Speaker 1:  that everything a consumer does on a computer is wireless and that's fine.
Speaker 1:  And that's the way it should be. And then if you have, if you are a
Speaker 1:  pro, you're plugging everything in your computer all the time and there's
Speaker 1:  no middle ground, as far as I can tell that apple thinking, it's
Speaker 1:  like, you get one Porter, you get 9,000. And that's it. I
Speaker 1:  don't know. Like whenever we do these reviews, I hear from people. I was
Speaker 1:  like, I haven't plugged anything in my computer all the time. And then I
Speaker 1:  hear from another class of people it's like, thank God the ports are back.
Speaker 1:  And I'm like, thank God the ports are back. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  I mean, this is the kind of computer where like, I love these Thunderbolt
Speaker 3:  docks because they turned my laptop into like a port
Speaker 3:  monster. Like you could legitimately not need a
Speaker 3:  doc of any sort with that.
Speaker 1:  It's kind of computer. If you need a doc for a desktop computer, I will come
Speaker 1:  to your house or
Speaker 4:  You could get four docs and just have
Speaker 4:  all the ports in
Speaker 3:  Every single port occupied.
Speaker 1:  It's actually, I don't want to listen to you. I mean like, yeah, we always
Speaker 1:  want to hear from you. If you buy this computer and you buy four Thunderbolt
Speaker 1:  port box and then fill all those ports, like
Speaker 4:  I want to please send us that picture is incredible. I
Speaker 4:  think my favorite thing about this product though, is that the
Speaker 4:   ultra version has a two
Speaker 4:  pound heat sink. There's a two pound difference
Speaker 4:  between
Speaker 3:  The two pounds heavier. Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 4:  It's two pounds heavier than the M one max version because of
Speaker 4:  pounds of hate heat. So that is so like, it's a lot of
Speaker 4:  heat.
Speaker 3:  Oh, it's twice as much as every it's twice a week.
Speaker 3:  Right? So it only makes sense that you're going to have twice as big of a
Speaker 3:  heat sink.
Speaker 1:  Apple did confirm to us, it is a different heat sink. It's copper. It
Speaker 1:  weighs two pounds more, which is great. I would say the one thing we haven't
Speaker 1:  really talked about is where this thing fits. I think people tend to
Speaker 1:  forget the Mac mini exists. The Mac mini is like a great
Speaker 1:  computer. People love it. This thing is $2,000. There
Speaker 1:  is no more 27 inch iMac. There's just the 24 inch
Speaker 1:  iMac. Yeah. You can still buy an Intel Mac mini, which is wild to me. He
Speaker 4:  Should not be allowed to.
Speaker 3:  It's like the only Intel computer left in the store. Right?
Speaker 1:  Know the macro and micro course, but I, where the sits is
Speaker 1:  really apple announces your computer tends to, for everything else exists.
Speaker 1:  But this one's really interesting because there's a 24 inch iMac. Then if
Speaker 1:  you want a 27 inch display, they now will sell you
Speaker 1:  at $1,600 display, which we can talk about, but you have to connect it to
Speaker 1:  a computer. And everyone's like, oh, now the 27 inch iMac has been replaced
Speaker 1:  by a $3,500 setup. And I'm like, no, the, the Mac mini is still
Speaker 1:  there. Yeah. So I think the second year, like want something slightly bigger
Speaker 1:  than 24 inches. They assume you're going to jump to a Mac mini and then a
Speaker 1:  large display. And if you want more processor, you're going to jump to this
Speaker 1:  thing. But the Mac mini has been so ignored for
Speaker 1:  so long, not by apple, but just like by the world
Speaker 1:  at large
Speaker 4:  Ignores it too, because when apple did its refresh, it, it didn't, it
Speaker 4:  kept the same casing. Like the  Mac
Speaker 4:  mini. It looks the exact same. That was totally why I didn't buy it.
Speaker 3:  And so to see, I'm want to air the M one air is the same model as the 2018
Speaker 3:  Medicare. They didn't change it. The only change that they made was when
Speaker 3:  they moved to the 14 and 16 inch pros
Speaker 4:  Mini it hadn't been updated for
Speaker 3:  Years in 2018. That's not that old compared to the
Speaker 3:  air.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I guess that's true. I just felt, it just feels like
Speaker 4:  apple itself ignores the Mac mini. And I think part of it is also, I feel
Speaker 4:  like apple doesn't take advantage. A Mac
Speaker 4:  mini costume was the exact same as an
Speaker 4:  MacBook air. Right?
Speaker 3:  It's a few hundred bucks less. It's like six or 700
Speaker 3:  versus a thousand.
Speaker 4:  Like I like, I'm getting a keyboard, I'm getting a
Speaker 4:  monitor. I'm eating so much. When I get a Mac book, air
Speaker 4:  and a Mac mini, I'm like, no, you need to be, you need to be like five, $600
Speaker 4:  cheaper.
Speaker 3:  You'd know what you get in a Mac mini. You get some ports. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  I do get support. Yeah,
Speaker 1:  No. I just think that this weird place and apple I'll tell you the Mac studio
Speaker 1:  is a professional machine, but this place between Apple's consumer
Speaker 1:  products and their pro products, there is like a yawning gap. Like I think
Speaker 1:  a lot of people would buy a 27 inch version of the
Speaker 1:   iMac. I wouldn't have that computer.
Speaker 3:  I've always been bigger streets. That's like your mantra. They always want
Speaker 3:  a bigger,
Speaker 1:  Cheap, big screens. All anybody wants it. So it's interesting that just sort
Speaker 1:  of like once you're done at 24 apples, like, well, by
Speaker 1:  one of our desktop computers,
Speaker 3:  It's telling that when they did the imag M one,
Speaker 3:  they moved from 21 to 24. Like they upgraded like the
Speaker 3:  base IMAX size. And that is kind of telling that like, this is as far
Speaker 3:  as it's going to go, like, this is the size of the iMac now. And if you do
Speaker 3:  want some more screen for whatever reason, then you do have to move into
Speaker 3:  a more professional setup if you're buying from apple.
Speaker 1:  But I don't know if the mini is like a professional setup. Like, that's the
Speaker 1:  weird thing about
Speaker 3:  If you stick it with the studio display, which we need to talk about, then
Speaker 3:  it becomes a professional setup.
Speaker 1:  We should take a break and talk about that, but maybe it does, or you just
Speaker 1:  buy whatever garbage monitor you want. Like Vox media,
Speaker 1:  it will fire a garbage Dell
Speaker 1:  monitor. All right. We should
Speaker 1:  take a break and come back and talk about this monitor. I just, that's the
Speaker 1:  thing that like we were talking about with the iPad as
Speaker 1:  well. If you just kind of look at apples, various segments, there's some
Speaker 1:  weird little corner cases where it's like, I just want to
Speaker 1:  consumer Mac with a big screen. And now the choices
Speaker 1:  you got to put one together,
Speaker 3:  Or maybe you want a iPhone se with a big screen,
Speaker 3:  which you wrote about today, terrible,
Speaker 4:  Terrible opinion. Despite everybody on this call, agreeing with it,
Speaker 4:  and
Speaker 1:  we're back. One more apple they talking about. Then we got to the lightning
Speaker 1:  round. The studio display is in a class of its
Speaker 1:  own 27 inch 5k studio display 60
Speaker 1:  99. I will say, this is one of the most controversial things that
Speaker 1:  has ever entered the verge. Like we had our like usual after the event
Speaker 1:  call and the fury that erupted on both sides. This
Speaker 1:  is the best thing that's ever happened is the apple should always make as
Speaker 1:  garbage. I hate it. Like we had to like calm him down. There was definitely
Speaker 3:  The only two camps. There was the camp of the
Speaker 3:  PC owners who are maybe more likely to be gamers who are
Speaker 3:  saying, you can get so much more for your money than this. This is
Speaker 3:  awful value proposition. And then there's the camp of like
Speaker 3:  people who have owned the LG 5k and are
Speaker 1:  Like, this is actually great. This is
Speaker 3:  What I wanted for six years and oh, 1600 bucks. I thought it was going to
Speaker 3:  be three grand.
Speaker 1:  So apple did the pro way XTR it was our first external display and forever
Speaker 1:  was a $5,000 thousand dollars. Standard is incredibly expensive. Some people
Speaker 1:  love it if you love it. That's fine. I think a lot of people have
Speaker 1:  found maybe not all the way up to the
Speaker 1:  hype. There's
Speaker 4:  Probably other ways to spend your $5,000.
Speaker 1:  This is way cheaper, contains a lot of the same display language. The
Speaker 1:  stand comes with it and not a thousand dollars extra, unless you want to
Speaker 1:  adjust the height. In which case you pay $400 more, which is
Speaker 1:  crazy for all we can tell, we have not seen a thing
Speaker 1:  yet. It is the same 27 inch panel
Speaker 1:  from an iMac that we have been looking at forever.
Speaker 3:  It's got a slightly brighter. Yeah. So that it can get that HDR
Speaker 3:  600 rating because it can do
Speaker 1:  600 words. I think that is a quote unquote HDR. We'll see. But
Speaker 1:  typically it's a hundred nits of brightness is what they told us. We, again,
Speaker 1:  we don't know. So we'll see. No mini led.
Speaker 1:  No, it's a single
Speaker 3:  Backlight backlight. So there's no multiple same
Speaker 1:  Old tech. You can get an nano Tasha coating. Do we know for
Speaker 4:  Sure it's the same backlight tech and there's not zones.
Speaker 3:  It's a single
Speaker 1:  Zone. If apple was doing backlight zones, like the amount of backlight zone
Speaker 1:  graphics that we would have been exposed to through the risks, love that
Speaker 4:  Our
Speaker 1:  Announcement can't get enough of backlights zones in, in the, in the
Speaker 1:  spaceship. The thing about it that is just mind blowing to me is that as
Speaker 1:  an eight, 13 chip inside of it, it has a 12 megapixel front
Speaker 1:  camera. That is an iPhone. They just put an iPhone in this thing
Speaker 1:  just to run the camera and the speakers. I love it. It
Speaker 1:  has what, six speakers, four woofers, two tweeters, apple, happily tell
Speaker 1:  you it's the best sound they've ever put on any of their computer
Speaker 1:  products. They claim it does still be Atlas and spatial audio. We will
Speaker 1:  see the whole point of Atmos is like height. You know, it's like, is
Speaker 1:  the, is the monitor going to rise above you? Yeah,
Speaker 3:  You have, you paid $400. You can lift the monitor higher and there's
Speaker 3:  your height.
Speaker 1:  You hear this helicopter versus $400. You got to lift it above your head.
Speaker 1:  But the eight 13 is nuts that it's in there. It does not do
Speaker 1:  iPhone things. It supports center stage and like the
Speaker 1:  bokeh effect, the portrait effect that you can get off. And I'm one
Speaker 1:  Mac my read on it is that if you have
Speaker 1:  an M one Mac modern and one Mac with a
Speaker 1:  webcam, like the Macro-Pro or the iMac or whatever, it's going to
Speaker 1:  look a lot like that. But because the camera slightly better, it's a 12 megapixel
Speaker 1:  camera. It'll be better, but that's it. So like, what is the point of this
Speaker 1:  eight, 13? It's running the audio, turning the camera, but it's not
Speaker 1:  doing iPhone tracks. It's not doing night mode. It
Speaker 3:  Was the chip they could
Speaker 1:  Get. I think it's just the chip that could get,
Speaker 3:  We're going to end up with, I like apple watches with eight fifteens
Speaker 3:  because we got all, we can get our hands
Speaker 3:  on. And I mean, like I I'm joking. It's, it's
Speaker 3:  probably the most efficient way for them to
Speaker 1:  Do it.
Speaker 4:  Sure. I think you're right in that it is, it is probably influenced by the
Speaker 4:  shortage because otherwise they were going to have to, if they want to do,
Speaker 4:  to do center stage, if they wanted to do all of this, they're going to have
Speaker 4:  to put a processor in there. And they're either gonna have a big accustomed
Speaker 4:  one, which means then they have to go and start that process of
Speaker 4:  getting a custom processor bait. And that's takes a lot that that's a
Speaker 4:  ramp up that takes time. And there's a shortage. Like everybody's going to
Speaker 4:  be like, no, I'm not going to do this for your, like one off small Blake
Speaker 4:  monitor. Everybody's going to say, I could get way more money. What
Speaker 3:  Has the eight 13? Now this occurred apart. I think the base model iPad has
Speaker 3:  occurred has an eight 13 in it that does center stage. It has these
Speaker 3:  features. So it's yeah. Pretty drop it.
Speaker 4:  They're pumping out these eight thirteens already. And I think it just was
Speaker 4:  like super cost efficient for them to be like, yeah, we don't need to make
Speaker 4:  something new. We'll just use this processor because it probably doesn't
Speaker 4:  like the 13th does not cost them a lot of money at this point.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. You know, you could do with an eight, 13 in a giant sway though is
Speaker 1:  make it a touchscreen and just run iPad apps on it. And they, I will
Speaker 1:  tell you, I said this and they're like, no, you can run iPad apps on the
Speaker 1:  Mac already through our wonderful blah, blah, blah. Like they're like, no,
Speaker 1:  we're not doing that.
Speaker 4:  Are people going to figure out how to run an iPad? Oh, S like on this
Speaker 4:  thing at some point,
Speaker 3:  Yes. He plug an iPad into
Speaker 3:  it.
Speaker 1:  It's not a touch. It's not a touch screen. So that's like your first
Speaker 1:  problem
Speaker 4:  Now support.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, it's true. But at some point someone's going to try to crack this thing,
Speaker 1:  right? Like, I hope there's like a huge student display jailbreak community.
Speaker 1:  That would be amazing. But I don't know that this thing is connected to the
Speaker 1:  display controller. Right. I think like, from Apple's
Speaker 1:  perspective, this thing like runs the camera and it runs the
Speaker 1:  speakers and it runs the micro.
Speaker 4:  So we're looking at like a couple of years before, someone's like, yeah,
Speaker 4:  I'll buy this and crack it open and figure out how
Speaker 1:  No one's seen one yet. So I'm sure someone's going to pull this thing apart
Speaker 1:  right away. But it is wild to me that it's expensive, especially
Speaker 1:  compared to that LG 5k, which everyone has hated forever. It's a good, bad
Speaker 1:  product. And everyone's always been like, why don't you just take the 5k
Speaker 1:  this way out of the iMac and sell to us? Well, they did it. It's just really
Speaker 1:  expensive. And part of the reason it's really expensive is it has most of
Speaker 1:  an iPhone in there.
Speaker 3:  I mean, they also did it like five years later. Like, I feel like if they
Speaker 3:  pulled this out five or six years ago, people would have been like 600 bucks.
Speaker 3:  Okay, cool. You know, this is kind of a new screen. It's like, you're getting
Speaker 3:  the latest technology. Now. It's like six years later and it
Speaker 3:  is, you know, no HDR, no
Speaker 3:  promotion. It is only 27 inches, which I don't know about you, but like
Speaker 3:  27 inches is pretty small at this point. It just feels dated
Speaker 3:  already. Even though it looks gorgeous, it'll probably function very well.
Speaker 3:  It'll integrate, it's got a whole iPhone jammed in there. It just, that,
Speaker 3:  I think that is a lot of the visceral reaction to the price. But
Speaker 3:  I went into this event thinking they were going to announce a display those
Speaker 3:  $3,000.
Speaker 4:  I see. I think it's actually that expensive. I mean, yes, it is
Speaker 4:  $1,600. That is a lot of money. But when you're looking at like
Speaker 4:  high-end 27 inch monitor,
Speaker 3:  I'm staring at a 49 inch monitor that runs at 240 Hertz that I paid a
Speaker 3:  thousand dollars for it.
Speaker 4:  Like I'm looking at a 27 inch monitor that I spent a
Speaker 4:  thousand dollars on. Maybe I just got bamboozled therapy, but I'm
Speaker 1:  Looking at a 2050 and
Speaker 3:  You already know what
Speaker 1:  You're doing.
Speaker 4:  I don't think it is for what you're getting in this product. I think,
Speaker 4:  yes, it's expensive, but it's not as expensive as we think, because one,
Speaker 4:  it's got a really nice webcam and nobody else has a really nice
Speaker 4:  integrated webcam. Who's making a really nice integrated webcam and a 27
Speaker 4:  inch monitor.
Speaker 1:  Well, so this is actually my question, why that they should sell a version
Speaker 1:  without the webcam. If you buy three of these, which some people will do,
Speaker 1:  or
Speaker 4:  You should just sell the
Speaker 1:  Webcam, your zoom situation is going to be bring back the
Speaker 1:  eyesight you coward. Like everyone is going to become like one of those Twitch
Speaker 1:  streamers with multiple angles on a zoom when they buy three. But you only
Speaker 1:  need one way. There's an
Speaker 1:  arguments who made they should definitely sell a cheaper version without
Speaker 1:  the webcam. Yes.
Speaker 4:  I think that would have taken a little bit of the sting out of the price,
Speaker 4:  even though the price is still not $3,000, which Dan and I like, I think
Speaker 4:  before the event, Dan and I were both like, yeah, it's going to be, it's
Speaker 4:  going to be 3000. I was
Speaker 3:  Like 2,500.
Speaker 1:  I'm excited to look at this thing. I'm going to display ner. I'm very
Speaker 4:  Excited for it.
Speaker 3:  I'll tell you, you are looking at it right now.
Speaker 1:  I'm definitely looking at this thing already right now. I'm sure it looks
Speaker 1:  beautiful in person though. It does. It does work with windows, including
Speaker 1:  the camera, but you don't get any of the camera features because that's software
Speaker 1:  integration. So that's good. It's not the end of the world. It is
Speaker 1:  only Thunderbolt input. It can charge any Mac laptop, which
Speaker 1:  is good. It's actually pretty hard to find 96 watt power
Speaker 1:  supplies for like the top end laptops out of a
Speaker 3:  Monitor. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  I mean, Apple's just doing what I want at the end of the day, you know, just
Speaker 1:  like give me a couple of ports and I had fun Jack.
Speaker 3:  Oh, we can not forget. It also has, Hey Siri.
Speaker 3:  Yes. Why? Because it has a whole life on
Speaker 3:  it.
Speaker 1:  Fair enough. Let's still a quick little lighting
Speaker 1:  round, apple updated all of its peripherals to make
Speaker 1:  black versions for the new studio, magic mouse keyboard. Trackpad magical
Speaker 1:  house. We written this story every year for fast five years. We'll keep writing
Speaker 1:  it still charges on the bottom, which is hilarious. That team, when they
Speaker 1:  were like, make a black one, do you think they're like, I dunno. And they
Speaker 1:  just like rolled the Photoshop dropper over and like announced black carry
Speaker 1:  on apple TV plus is going to do live sports, which is a huge deal. Katie
Speaker 1:  khaki is, is written about this. You know, sports are the stickiest thing
Speaker 1:  for a streaming platforms is shamed. They
Speaker 3:  Chose baseball though
Speaker 1:  This year. And it's two games on Friday. It's to me free at first
Speaker 1:  it's and yes, it's true that baseball is on the
Speaker 1:  streets.
Speaker 3:  Is there going to be a season this year? Is that
Speaker 1:  Question, you know, I'm, I'm a cynic about apple TV, plus I think they do
Speaker 1:  it mostly to say they have a services product. Like they can try that
Speaker 1:  Reese Witherspoon instead of like a candy crush whale, when they talk about
Speaker 1:  services, revenue, like I think that's important to them, but
Speaker 1:  it's interesting that it's going to sports sound because sports are expensive
Speaker 1:  to get, and they are the thing that makes people sign up
Speaker 1:  for streaming, sir.
Speaker 4:  But baseball also has like how many games, way more games than
Speaker 4:  football or basketball
Speaker 3:  Games.
Speaker 4:  And they're only doing Fridays. I don't think we know yet. If they're going
Speaker 4:  to be blackout dates, if like what kind of games we're going to get,
Speaker 3:  We have to have a baseball season. So we're putting the cart before the horse.
Speaker 3:  They're they need to actually like have an opening day.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Other letting your own stuff. They have three meters on a real for
Speaker 1:  cable. It's $160. That's hilarious.
Speaker 3:  A great price because you can not buy a three meter four cable from anyone
Speaker 3:  else.
Speaker 1:  It's a great, it's like the ultimate monopolist, like a great
Speaker 1:  price. There's all sorts of other stuff we talked about. Google
Speaker 1:  did a big Android feature drop and then their new SVP of
Speaker 1:  tablet stuff, rich miner went on their own
Speaker 1:  Android show and talks about the future of Android tablets is bright.
Speaker 3:  Yep. We'll see that
Speaker 1:  They hired a guy.
Speaker 4:  I mean, maybe he could
Speaker 1:  Do it. Andrew also finally rolled out their iOS friendly emoji
Speaker 1:  reactions and Google messages in case, you know, you have
Speaker 1:  chosen a Google messaging product and it's that
Speaker 1:  one Pixel
Speaker 1:  feature drops are in beta. So you've got pixel. You can do that. We've got
Speaker 1:  a bunch of cool gadget stuff on the site. Yes.
Speaker 4:  I'm going to plug something here. That is very, very cool. And I'm super
Speaker 4:  excited about that. You could. Now, if you want 3d print
Speaker 4:  and build your own track ball mouse, that's pretty cool. And
Speaker 4:  we have a great story about it. You guy wet, he's built a
Speaker 4:  bunch. It's called . Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Oh yeah. I might, as in route, as we speak, I'm going to go buy
Speaker 4:  some, like I'm going to sand it down to get it nice and smooth. I am
Speaker 4:  never been more excited to build track
Speaker 3:  Ball hacks in 2022. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  It's great.
Speaker 1:  Victoria reviewed the Yves Saint Laurent lipstick printer, which is
Speaker 1:  actually really cool magic screw
Speaker 1:  that the Steenbeck neurons windows, Shaun officers
Speaker 1:  obsessed with steam deck. Can't get enough of it all day long. I'm like,
Speaker 1:  what are you working as like steam deck stuff. I'm like, okay, keep, keep
Speaker 1:  bleeding that try. We have a cool hands-on alien, senior monitors. Alienware
Speaker 1:  has a gigantic QD OLED monitor.
Speaker 3:  The, the thing that's significant about this is the first QT Olin screen
Speaker 3:  that's actually shipping. And you can buy a, there was a bunch of qto led
Speaker 3:  stuff announced at CES, including this monitor. Bunch of TVs were announced,
Speaker 3:  but you can't yet buy those. So like, this is the first experience. So people
Speaker 3:  are getting a QD OLED, which is pretty exciting, pretty interesting. And
Speaker 3:  it's also interesting that it's in a gaming monitor, which is usually one
Speaker 3:  of the most demanding places for a new panel tech to go.
Speaker 1:  I mean, I'm definitely gonna buy this motor then my favorite headline of
Speaker 1:  the week, because I can't believe this company it's called nothing. So I
Speaker 1:  read this headline. I was like, what are we talking about? Nothing. Can't
Speaker 1:  stop smart from weeks. And I thought it was like a large piece about the
Speaker 1:  state of smartphone, this company, this credit. Cause I wrote this headline.
Speaker 1:  I was like, what, what does this mean? This company is called nothing is
Speaker 1:  the greatest role in tech history. There's other stuff going on, actually
Speaker 1:  both Peloton and Oculus have now integrated themselves in an apple health,
Speaker 1:  which is like pretty interesting just from a lock-in that's this
Speaker 1:  weekend lock-in like Paul's on finally gave in, but also I got a new CEO
Speaker 1:  and they started doing stuff they should have been doing forever. Like letting
Speaker 1:  you sync to apple health, they're trialing a program where you get the bike
Speaker 1:  and the software subscription for one fee, like the
Speaker 1:  new guy showed up and he's like, what are you doing? Just
Speaker 1:  like
Speaker 6:  Grabbing
Speaker 1:  This low hanging fruit. Exactly. But it's fascinating that Oculus
Speaker 1:  is Mehta is doing with Oculus too. It's fascinating to me that there's
Speaker 1:  rumors of a Facebook watch too. We're all over that. That's it. That's it.
Speaker 1:  We've done a lot of apple. There's a lot of news on the site. It's been a
Speaker 1:  great week. It's creative maker's week on the site. It's another DIY week.
Speaker 1:  There's a ton of amazing stories about people making stuff, including a guide
Speaker 1:  you'd sense. Tintype photography should read that. And then we have a big
Speaker 1:  feature on trust and son who is a crypto
Speaker 1:  entrepreneur just keeps getting away with it. And that as most of the best
Speaker 1:  art traction we've ever had on the site. So go read that. That's it we've
Speaker 1:  gone over. No he didn't. No. We went over. You can tweet at
Speaker 1:  us. I'm at reckless Dan's DCC for Alex is Alex H
Speaker 1:  Kranz Dakota. This week was really fun. It was the CEO of raspberry PI. I've
Speaker 1:  been Upton. And he was like, I'm never doing recurring revenue software.
Speaker 1:  Like we just make cheap hardware and it beguiles kids and
Speaker 1:  becoming software programmers. Great episode. One of my favorites, that's
Speaker 1:  it we'll be back next week. We're like in the thick of it, like the tech
Speaker 1:  news cycle is like off to the races. So there's, there's more to
Speaker 1:  come actually. Next week on decoder is the CEO of WordPress. So that'd
Speaker 1:  be Matt long. That was really good on too. That's it?