# Transcript
ID: 4507ce40-63c5-11ed-a47b-fd2bca75ad72
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Meta announces job cuts and Twitter prepares for difficult times
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-1134901488950748107/2300059821430801362/s93290-US-4911s-1668393361.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, David Pierce, Alex Cranz, and Alex Heath discuss week two of Elon Musk as CEO of Twitter and Meta announcing job cuts.
Later in the show: What's next for Binance and FTX, a stretchable screen by LG Display, and the Surface Pro 9 review.
Speaker 1:  Before we get to the show, I have a really quick favor to ask. What makes
Speaker 1:  this show special, as you know, is you, it's the listeners, it's the people
Speaker 1:  we get to hang out with every week and talk about tech, and that's why we'd
Speaker 1:  like your help. Planning for our future, the future of the Vergecast. All
Speaker 1:  we need you to do is fill out a short survey. You can go to the link in the
Speaker 1:  show notes or directly to vox.com/pod survey. Take
Speaker 1:  couple of questions. Super easy. Tell us about the vergecast, say main things
Speaker 1:  about Eli. We would absolutely love to get your feedback to help
Speaker 1:  us understand who's listening, what kinds of things you want
Speaker 1:  us to talk more about and do. And hopefully how we
Speaker 1:  can convince everyone you know, all of your friends and neighbors and
Speaker 1:  coworkers and random people you encounter on the street can come to be part
Speaker 1:  of our awesome Vergecast community. That's it. Fill out the survey. Thank
Speaker 1:  you so much.
Speaker 4:  It is the season of giving and the season of stressing Shop
Speaker 4:  Amazon this holiday for decompressing Save on
Speaker 4:  Silk Road and bound there refreshing when your parents in
Speaker 4:  Inlaws just aren't really meshing or when your kid brother
Speaker 4:  won't pass the red dressing and the thought of dry Turkey
Speaker 4:  gets way too distressing.
Speaker 4:  Whatever's holidays are depressing,
Speaker 4:  I'm fine.
Speaker 5:  Hello and welcome to the Verge Cast, the flagship podcast of
Speaker 5:  verified users on Twitter. I'm your host Eli Patel.
Speaker 6:  See, this is the problem
Speaker 6:  no one would've known. That wasn't me.
Speaker 5:  No one
Speaker 6:  If not for this dastardly blue check that Alex has purchased
Speaker 6:  for
Speaker 5:  Herself. We sound exactly the same.
Speaker 6:  How can anyone know who anyone is?
Speaker 5:  Our audio engineer is like, I can't tell 'em apart.
Speaker 6:  Do do have you? Have you seen? There's like a really good TikTok where they
Speaker 6:  speed up Sam Smith's voice and they slow down Adele's voice and then they
Speaker 6:  have the same voice. That's Twitter Blue. That's for
Speaker 6:  $8 a month. You can speed up Bedell's voice and slow down Sam Smith's voice.
Speaker 6:  You can't tell 'em apart
Speaker 5:  If you can't tell other Eli Patel is here.
Speaker 6:  Hi, I'm your friend Eli. That's Alex Kranz. That's me. David Pierce
Speaker 6:  is here. Oh yeah,
Speaker 5:  I thought I was Eli. Oh my god. David Pierce
Speaker 1:  Is here. There. There are several ne Elis on this podcast. No one can confirm
Speaker 1:  which ne Eli is, which Neli, only that there are many.
Speaker 6:  Truly the real problem on the show is that there's two Alex, so Kranz is
Speaker 6:  here and then Alex Heath is joining us. Hey Alex.
Speaker 7:  Hey Rust And peace carries from Chicago.
Speaker 6:  We'll get into
Speaker 7:  That, get that on the way up front.
Speaker 6:  It's a huge week of news. Yeah, so obviously
Speaker 6:  Elon and Twitter, Alex, I don't think you've slept, you've been breaking
Speaker 6:  story after story. They all seem to happen at two in the morning, which is
Speaker 6:  a real problem for you. Yes, Meta had massive layoffs this week.
Speaker 6:  11,000 people. Zuck wrote a very nice note, real contrast in
Speaker 6:  leadership styles between our nation's social media CEOs this week, I would
Speaker 6:  say including Gary from Chicago, who, Alex and David made
Speaker 6:  famous in a feature earlier this year. And then
Speaker 6:  ftx, the huge crypto exchange I'm pretty sure just
Speaker 6:  ruined Tom Brady and Giselle's marriage. I'm, yeah, I don't, I can't make
Speaker 6:  the causal connection. I don't have any evidence of it, but it seems obvious
Speaker 6:  what's happening there a hundred percent. So
Speaker 1:  We gotta, and that is the main consequence of everything going on with ftx.
Speaker 1:  If you stop listening to this podcast right now, just know the only thing
Speaker 1:  you need to know about FTX is that it ruins Tom Brady's relationship. That's
Speaker 1:  very important.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Tom Brady nows to play football until he is 85 years old to just
Speaker 6:  crawl out of the hold at crypto Doug for him. So we gotta talk about all
Speaker 6:  that stuff. We obviously have to start with Twitter, which is a minute to
Speaker 6:  minute, moment by moment just out of
Speaker 6:  control, car crash hurdling towards yet another car crash,
Speaker 6:  which itself is hurdling into the sun. Like,
Speaker 6:  I dunno how to describe the current state of Twitter. People are quitting.
Speaker 6:  Heath, tell us what you know so far. Well,
Speaker 1:  We should say just real quick before we, before we get too far in, we should
Speaker 1:  just say it's four 11 Eastern time on Thursday. Wow. If
Speaker 1:  all of Twitter is different by the time you listen to this, which there's
Speaker 1:  like a 60% chance it will be, just know that it is as of
Speaker 1:  this moment, here is what we know, everything subject to change at all times.
Speaker 1:  We'll just dub in whatever change is.
Speaker 6:  Just to be clear about how real that is. We are in a product meeting today
Speaker 6:  about our redesign and what's coming next and all this stuff we wanna do.
Speaker 6:  And someone very casually, like a V Media product person was like, Oh,
Speaker 6:  then we gotta think about Twitter, like Twitter integration. It's like, and
Speaker 6:  then there was like a beat and then everyone was like, will
Speaker 6:  Twitter still be around when the ships? And we were just like
Speaker 6:  crossing off the list because no one knows the answer.
Speaker 6:  Hold off on that one. Yeah. Anyways, Alex, tell us what you know.
Speaker 7:  Well as we are recording this, Musk is addressing Twitter
Speaker 7:  employees for the very first time in a meeting that he scheduled 15 minutes
Speaker 7:  before and showed up about 10 minutes late too. Feels right. And
Speaker 7:  we will have a read out of that hopefully after this podcast. He is
Speaker 7:  literally addressing them over, you know, video for the first
Speaker 7:  time since he took over. He sent a very terse email at
Speaker 7:  almost midnight the other day, basically saying, Get ready for
Speaker 7:  pain. He said he is not sure that
Speaker 7:  Twitter will survive the coming recession, which is like a very, you know,
Speaker 7:  heartwarming message to get from your new ceo. And then I guess my
Speaker 7:  favorite part was he just sent a quick follow up email, like less than five
Speaker 7:  minutes after, which was just one sentence and it was like, by the way, our
Speaker 7:  top priority is fighting spam and bots and trolls.
Speaker 7:  So very erratic inside Twitter right now. And
Speaker 7:  I think all of that had a very fine bow put on it
Speaker 7:  with this story we published today. So the day before this podcast
Speaker 7:  comes out that a Twitter lawyer posted a Slack message
Speaker 7:  to the whole company, basically encouraging them to seek whistleblower
Speaker 7:  protection. So totally normal things happening inside Twitter right
Speaker 6:  Now. So let's try to walk through the week
Speaker 6:  of things. I'm not, There are many ways to tell a story. Welcome to the
Speaker 6:  Verest. There are many ways to tell a story. You can start with the most
Speaker 6:  important thing for us. You could lead with a conflict. Sometimes you're
Speaker 6:  just beaten in the submission and the only proper way to tell a story is
Speaker 6:  chronological order.
Speaker 5:  I can do it. You want me to do it?
Speaker 6:  Let's go it. Let's see if
Speaker 5:  He can pull up. Okay, last week Elon said, I'm going to
Speaker 5:  revamp Twitter blue and we're gonna start charging people
Speaker 5:  more money and they're gonna get a blue check mark. So I immediately went
Speaker 5:  out and I reserved Reckless Patel.
Speaker 6:  That's how you're telling the
Speaker 5:  Story. That's how I'm telling the story. Okay. And I immediately went out
Speaker 5:  and I reserved Reckless Patel as a handle because I knew
Speaker 5:  exactly what I was gonna do. This
Speaker 6:  Is the story. This is just self-congratulation
Speaker 5:  Exa. Hundred percent, a hundred percent Go Cowboys.
Speaker 5:  Anyway, over the weekend they, they released a new version of
Speaker 5:  I of the Twitter app on iOS and said, Okay, Twitter blues here,
Speaker 5:  but it wasn't here. Right. That was all lies.
Speaker 6:  Well, because they made a last minute determination that they should not
Speaker 6:  roll out verification that is easily gamed to
Speaker 6:  interate people right before the
Speaker 5:  Election. Right. They realized, oh no, we should not do
Speaker 6:  That. So game time decision to not ruin America's
Speaker 6:  democracy with Twitter.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So they, they released this new version, it
Speaker 5:  did absolutely nothing. People were very confused and then they all
Speaker 5:  stopped caring for at least two days. Then there was a whole
Speaker 6:  Election. There was an election. I will say, by the way, if you, I don't
Speaker 6:  believe this is true, but if you are one of the many people who believe that
Speaker 6:  Elon Musk bought Twitter to push his right wing agenda
Speaker 6:  didn't
Speaker 5:  Work,
Speaker 6:  Just 44 billion to send the least effective political
Speaker 6:  message of all time. He was like, I think you should vote for Republicans.
Speaker 6:  And America was like, Not as much as you want us to. And then they didn't
Speaker 6:  do it. Yeah. So I just
Speaker 5:  Red trickle,
Speaker 6:  Red trickle my thesis was Seehan is going to destroy his reputation
Speaker 6:  and potentially cause grievous damage to his other companies.
Speaker 5:  That's, that's happening. And
Speaker 6:  The first one appears to be happening. Anyway, continue your story about,
Speaker 5:  Okay. And then
Speaker 6:  Flagrantly breaking Twitter's rules.
Speaker 5:  Then yesterday Richard Lawler hit me up and he said, Alex, they
Speaker 5:  did it blue. This is how I learned. By the way, Richard Lawler, our news
Speaker 5:  editor, you've all heard him on the Verge cast, He's amazing, slacked me.
Speaker 5:  And he said, They've rolled out Twitter blue, it's finally here, What are
Speaker 5:  we gonna do? And I was like, eating a banana. And I was like, I don't know,
Speaker 5:  what are we gonna do? And then I remembered that I, did
Speaker 6:  You remember that you,
Speaker 5:  I had reserved Reckless Patel and so I immediately went
Speaker 5:  and I had to log out of my Twitter account on my phone because it only works
Speaker 5:  on your phone. Only iOS.
Speaker 6:  Right. So by the way, they, they're only rolling this out and Elon said this,
Speaker 6:  he said at a financial conference, right, that they're piggybacking on
Speaker 6:  Apple's user verification and credit card Yes. Security.
Speaker 5:  Yes. So it only works on iOS. Yeah. And you
Speaker 5:  have to have a Twitter account that was reserved before November
Speaker 5:  9th. Yeah. So I, I was ready to go. I
Speaker 5:  immediately reserved it using my, my Verge email and
Speaker 5:  my account that very clearly does not say Eli Patel anywhere in
Speaker 5:  it. And I had a blue check mark
Speaker 6:  And now she's just running around impersonating me. And, and here's what
Speaker 6:  I'll tell you. Alex has gotten herself up to 200 followers. Yes.
Speaker 5:  Over 200
Speaker 6:  Dier just sent me a text message noting that the fake account
Speaker 6:  now auto completes when you search for my name, it's being
Speaker 6:  that account was recommended to me and my should follow
Speaker 6:  today. It's great's great. It's, it's, it's amazing. It's
Speaker 6:  everything that you've ever wanted from identity verification system that
Speaker 6:  basically comes down to do you have $8? Yeah. So that, the reason I brought
Speaker 6:  up the piggybacking is right, Elon's, like the $8 will deter spammers, it
Speaker 6:  will make spam too expensive. And also the credit card payment
Speaker 6:  processors and apples iOS protections are additional layers of
Speaker 6:  security. This thesis has proven to be about as false
Speaker 5:  As it can be, Right?
Speaker 6:  Like there is, there's just spam all over the plat. Like Mario is flipping
Speaker 6:  you off from an account that looks like the Nintendo account. It's it's still
Speaker 6:  going. There's a fake Eli Lilly account that has been promising
Speaker 6:  free insulin for a day. Which is, I mean, maybe they should just
Speaker 6:  do it just like that's a good idea, but it's a good policy. He's completely
Speaker 6:  lost control over the platform. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  A hundred percent. This,
Speaker 1:  This seems like a useful time to note that this is what
Speaker 1:  he wanted. Like this is, this is the whole thing.
Speaker 1:  And like this is, this is the guy who said comedy is back on the platform
Speaker 1:  and then said actually if you impersonate somebody, you'll get suspended
Speaker 1:  from Twitter and then forced a bunch of comedians to do that and get suspended
Speaker 1:  from Twitter. Like Crans. You get to do kind of a victory lap on this after
Speaker 1:  last week because this was never, ever, ever actually about verifying
Speaker 1:  users. Right. And anyone who thought it was, it was wrong. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  What this is about is getting people to pay $8 to feel fancy
Speaker 1:  and you get, you get to be up ranked in people's search results and algorithms
Speaker 1:  and you get to have a check mark. And even that has now been like completely
Speaker 1:  undermined by the explanation. That's like some people are verified
Speaker 1:  because they're important and some people are verified because they paid
Speaker 1:  and like instantly being verified because you paid has become like the thirstiest
Speaker 1:  dumbest thing to possibly do. It's just this whole thing has gone so
Speaker 1:  horribly awry in so many ways. But the thing that is like
Speaker 1:  useful is the idea that like, the idea that this was ever actually about
Speaker 1:  verifying Twitter users on Twitter, we can just, we can just put that to
Speaker 1:  bed. Cause that's not what's happening. It's
Speaker 5:  Total Well and the
Speaker 6:  Rest Heath went, Heath is just like cracking up what's going on.
Speaker 7:  We haven't even talked about the other check mark yet.
Speaker 6:  I know. All right. He explained the other check mark which came and went
Speaker 6:  in a, like a frenetic burst defense.
Speaker 5:  Sandra O was so important for 30 minutes
Speaker 1:  I think all thanks to marque Brownlee. Like it seems like Marque Brownlee
Speaker 1:  killed the other check mark. But Heath you should explain.
Speaker 7:  No. So Marque did not kill it. What actually happened is,
Speaker 7:  well first you
Speaker 6:  Have to explain what it is.
Speaker 7:  So basically as they were rolling out blue, someone inside Twitter
Speaker 7:  realized, oh shit, what do we do about all these government
Speaker 7:  agencies that are not going to pay us $8 to have a check mark
Speaker 7:  NGOs, et cetera. So they roll out this gray check mark
Speaker 7:  that's a second verification check mark that is
Speaker 7:  the same as the old check mark in that it's literally managed
Speaker 7:  in a spreadsheet inside Twitter. And it's like people
Speaker 7:  from different parts of the company submitting names and
Speaker 7:  Twitter accounts to be verified. Right. Which is how it used to work. That
Speaker 7:  goes on for what? What? I don't even know. Was it, this is like an hour?
Speaker 7:  Yeah, it was like a half a day. Okay. You could've told me half a day. You
Speaker 7:  could've told me an hour, whatever. Then Elon tweets, I just killed this.
Speaker 7:  I think it was maybe to Marques. Yeah, yeah. When everyone just got confused
Speaker 7:  and they're like, wait, why do, why do some people have two check marks?
Speaker 7:  What is this great check mark? And his whole thing was like Lords and
Speaker 7:  peasants. Right? He was like, the original way verification works was bullshit,
Speaker 7:  you know, power to the people, everyone gets it for $8 and then that wasn't
Speaker 7:  the case the day it rolled out. And so then he
Speaker 7:  cancels it and I think they may actually bring it back guys.
Speaker 7:  I think there's like, right now the problem is, is that
Speaker 7:  a bunch of Twitter people frantically started trying to add names to
Speaker 7:  this great check mark list because they wanted their respective partners,
Speaker 7:  agencies, et cetera to have it
Speaker 5:  Right. So that's why
Speaker 7:  Sandra sit out and was like, No, like this is too much
Speaker 7:  and shut it down temporarily. But I think they're gonna bring it back. So
Speaker 7:  I think there's gonna be this still two-tier verification system
Speaker 7:  and it's just check marks all the way down. You know, it's just,
Speaker 5:  It wouldn't be two tier, it would be technically three tier because there'd
Speaker 5:  be the gray check mark for people. Then the blue
Speaker 5:  if you click on it says this is an important person check mark.
Speaker 5:  And then finally the blue if you click on it, This is Reckless Patel?
Speaker 7:  No, the mid, the mid blue one is going
Speaker 7:  away. The mid-tier blue check mark, that's the legacy one will go
Speaker 7:  away. Okay. But Right. I for now there's going to be three.
Speaker 5:  So are they gonna change who gets the gray
Speaker 5:  check mark? Like is if you're currently have the blue check mark without
Speaker 5:  paying, will you move to the gray or are they gonna like audit that and be
Speaker 5:  like, Sandra O can keep it Alex Kranz? Absolutely not. Which I would
Speaker 5:  respect
Speaker 6:  Kranz. Only Elon knows. Okay. Only Elon knows.
Speaker 1:  No, I, I would pause it that even Elon doesn't know that literally no one
Speaker 1:  on this earth knows how that
Speaker 6:  Is. Wait, I just wanna put this out there. We are at the point with all of
Speaker 6:  this chaos, Did I receive notes from like two or three people
Speaker 6:  who are like tech company operators just floating the
Speaker 6:  idea that he's trying to destroy the company on purpose. Like it's the,
Speaker 6:  the amount of chaos is so Yeah. Like irresponsible
Speaker 6:  that like smart people are like, you should look into whether he's
Speaker 6:  doing this on purpose to destroy Twitter.
Speaker 5:  No, he's just
Speaker 6:  Risked. We haven't even gotten to the FTC violations yet. Yeah. We haven't
Speaker 6:  even gotten to like the other, the looming shadow of the government. There's
Speaker 6:  like random people are like, you should look. I'm like, I don't, That seems
Speaker 6:  like he wouldn't just light 44 billion on fire.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Especially like he's
Speaker 6:  Had to, he's, he's definitely the point with the whiplash decisions and
Speaker 6:  the sort of just, I don't know, disregard for the
Speaker 6:  reality of running a company at Twitter scale that other smart people
Speaker 6:  are like, there's an actual method here and the goal is to destroy the company,
Speaker 6:  which I think is a, a remarkable place to
Speaker 1:  Be. I've had multiple people over the last several days use the phrase,
Speaker 1:  never ascribe anything to malice that can be explained by incompetence.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Like, like that exact phrase over and over. And it's like, it's because
Speaker 1:  of that thing. It's like you look at it and it's like, okay, the simplest
Speaker 1:  explanation here is that Elon Musk is systematically trying to ruin Twitter.
Speaker 1:  Like that's
Speaker 6:  The only
Speaker 1:  Simple explanation for what's going on here. But it's like, then you look
Speaker 1:  around and it's like, okay, it's, it's Elon Musk who has no idea how to run
Speaker 1:  a company like this who brought in a bunch of people who have no idea how
Speaker 1:  to run a company like this. Tried to change it all in 15 minutes, fired half
Speaker 1:  the staff. And it's like, of course this is gonna be a disaster. Like you
Speaker 1:  could, you could do all those things and try your absolute hardest and it
Speaker 1:  would go exactly like this. Like it's craziness.
Speaker 5:  This is the guy who beta tests, self-driving cars on
Speaker 5:  public roads where anybody could theoretically be hit by it. Of course he's
Speaker 6:  Gonna like the, There's a real difference there. And I i's
Speaker 5:  Is that
Speaker 6:  Okay? And I, I've been thinking about this a lot. Okay. Elon does not
Speaker 6:  have absolute disdain for the people who work at Tesla
Speaker 6:  and buy Tesla's. Yeah. And his open disdain for the
Speaker 6:  people who make Twitter is so obvious and it's
Speaker 6:  like, dude, you're addicted to Twitter. The thing they made is your
Speaker 6:  favorite thing. This is like if you walked into the Oreo factory
Speaker 6:  and you were like, who are the people who made Oreos? Fuck them. Get
Speaker 6:  in the, here I'm doing Oreos my way and then you ruined Oreos.
Speaker 6:  Like it's, it's absolutely bizarre. And I get that
Speaker 6:  maybe the company was burning too much money and it, I think we have to say
Speaker 6:  this every week criticizing Elon's tenure, Twitter is
Speaker 6:  a no way. Praise for the previous disaster chief executives
Speaker 6:  of Twitter. They did a bad job running the company. I mean Prague
Speaker 5:  Yes. Made
Speaker 6:  Bank the operation of the, Actually he hasn't made bank yet, right? He's
Speaker 6:  he's gonna have to, He's he didn't, he got fired for cause Oh, and the cause,
Speaker 6:  cause was you made me look bad and forced me to buy Twitter. So
Speaker 6:  like I just, it's just crazy to me that he doesn't, if you are,
Speaker 6:  if you think you can do a better job managing an organization
Speaker 6:  just by making slightly different decisions and not actually like changing
Speaker 6:  how the organization works, like you're in for a bad time and here
Speaker 6:  with verification all this stuff, there's like really good reasons
Speaker 6:  that smart people made rigorous decisions to get where they landed. Right.
Speaker 6:  And he's not taking them into account. Okay.
Speaker 7:  Which
Speaker 6:  Leads us, You guys want some Alex to the ftc?
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Yeah. Well before that I was just gonna say, to kind of add to what
Speaker 7:  you were saying, this is live kind of updates from the all hands. That
Speaker 7:  was just, and that he told employees that bankruptcy
Speaker 7:  is not out of the question and that he expects Twitter to have
Speaker 7:  negative cash flow of several billion next year. So yeah,
Speaker 7:  your theory that he may actually be just setting it on fire
Speaker 7:  is, is definitely not unfounded.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. But then like how are you gonna do all the things you want do? Like
Speaker 6:  he's filed paperwork to start a payment service and like building everything
Speaker 6:  out. What
Speaker 5:  If he just bought it for the tech stack?
Speaker 6:  There's not, I mean it's like a, it's fine.
Speaker 7:  I'm just, I'm kind of speechless with all this. I mean this is certainly
Speaker 7:  the wildest story I've ever recovered. Do you wanna talk about the FTC thing?
Speaker 7:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  This is the big scoop that you had this morning. Oh my
Speaker 7:  God. Well props to Casey for skipping me on
Speaker 7:  Twitter. But yeah, we have this full memo
Speaker 7:  that a company lawyer, a senior counsel on the privacy team
Speaker 7:  sent us kind of like a falling on your sword. I mean she clearly is
Speaker 7:  expecting to be fired after this. Basically saying that
Speaker 7:  Elon is pushing the company to violate this
Speaker 7:  FTC consent decree, which has very, you know, stringent rules
Speaker 7:  about certifying how data is used and you know, privacy
Speaker 7:  review that Twitter has been caught violating before and that the
Speaker 7:  company is standing to face billions of dollars
Speaker 7:  in fines. And that the most alarming thing I think was that
Speaker 7:  engineers, individual engineers are now being asked to
Speaker 7:  self-certify their, their code under this
Speaker 7:  consent decree. And the three executives who were actually in
Speaker 7:  charge of enforcing this internally all resigned the same.
Speaker 7:  Well the evening before this memo went out. And this is a company in-house
Speaker 7:  lawyer ending a message saying, By the way, here's how
Speaker 7:  you can contact the FTC to whistle
Speaker 6:  Blow.
Speaker 7:  I'm gonna take PTO now. Salute emoji. Which is the emoji they're all giving
Speaker 7:  when they get
Speaker 6:  Laid off. Amazing.
Speaker 7:  So just like a truly incredible thing to,
Speaker 7:  to have sent inside a company by one of your own lawyers.
Speaker 6:  What
Speaker 5:  Is the self certifying?
Speaker 6:  Well throw this back up, up. We can explain kinda the mechanics here. Okay,
Speaker 6:  so in 2011, right, Twitter got in trouble because they were
Speaker 6:  using personal information to target ads. Okay. So you'd sign up for Twitter,
Speaker 6:  you'd tell 'em your email address, your phone number, your whatever pii it's
Speaker 6:  called personal identify information. And they were using it to target ads.
Speaker 6:  Okay. The FFC got mad at them, made them sign a consent decree saying you're
Speaker 6:  not gonna do this May of 2022, Twitter pays fine.
Speaker 6:  150 million. Cuz guess what they did? They used your personal information.
Speaker 6:  Target the ads. No, So re-up the consent decree. Modified order.
Speaker 6:  This requires them to have a group of
Speaker 6:  people. We don't know who that group of people is that is accountable to
Speaker 6:  the ftc.
Speaker 7:  Oh, it's the people who resigned eli. Yeah, yeah, yeah. It's the chief privacy
Speaker 7:  officer, Chief compliance officer and chief security
Speaker 7:  information officer. All three of whom resigned together. Right.
Speaker 6:  Okay. So we didn't, I didn't think we had this when we wrote the story, but,
Speaker 6:  so Alex has now confirmed it, the people responsible to the
Speaker 6:  FTC for filing compliance reports, keeping Twitter
Speaker 6:  and compliance with this FTC order not
Speaker 5:  Getting fined
Speaker 6:  Again, but for, Well no, but they're accountable to the ftc. So if they're
Speaker 6:  on the hook, Twitter's on the hook for billions dollars in fines. They're
Speaker 6:  on the hook personally. Right.
Speaker 7:  And we should say like, yeah, going to jail,
Speaker 6:  They can go to jail. So one of the clauses
Speaker 6:  in this consent decree is 14 days after a change in ownership or
Speaker 6:  control of the company Twitter, these people have to file a
Speaker 6:  compliance report. So if anything happens to the company, company changes
Speaker 6:  control. 14 days later the FTC wants a document saying data practice is still
Speaker 6:  good.
Speaker 7:  They
Speaker 6:  All quit yesterday. They don't wanna be in the hook,
Speaker 6:  they don't wanna go to jail for Elon's. Crazy. Right?
Speaker 6:  And the FTC has owed this thing, the FTC had a statement, they gave it to
Speaker 6:  us, they're watching this very closely, they're alarmed. In the meantime,
Speaker 6:  Elon's rushing out features that take your credit card number
Speaker 6:  and purport to identify you without going
Speaker 6:  through as Alex reported all the necessary reviews, including
Speaker 6:  hilariously the red team review, which is like, here's all the
Speaker 6:  things that could go wrong.
Speaker 6:  They didn't take any of the recommendations. Nothing. All of the things immediately
Speaker 6:  went wrong. Exactly the way that you would expect them to. Right.
Speaker 7:  To be clear. So there was an emergency red team review
Speaker 7:  the night before Blue launched the night before.
Speaker 7:  And all of the things that we were just talking about with impersonation,
Speaker 7:  this was all raised, I'm told internally as like, hey, we should be
Speaker 7:  thinking about this. This is gonna happen immediately. Obviously none of
Speaker 7:  it was implemented. And yeah, so that's just a sign of how
Speaker 7:  breakneck the company is operating. And I mean this lawyer in this
Speaker 7:  note says we're on one to two week from product
Speaker 7:  inception to release sprints and how in the world are we supposed to get
Speaker 7:  that through R FTC requirements? And
Speaker 7:  I mean I just like, I know I already said like this is like a
Speaker 7:  remarkable thing for someone to write, but this is, this is a
Speaker 7:  company lawyer literally saying like people are gonna go to jail basically.
Speaker 7:  Right. And this person was still on the payroll when they sent it, so
Speaker 7:  obviously unclear what's gonna happen. But yeah, that's the state of things.
Speaker 5:  Could Elon go to jail? Could he Yeah. Buy
Speaker 5:  Twitter and get sent to
Speaker 6:  Jail? I mean I don't, I don't think that causality is that direct, but
Speaker 5:  Yes, my head, it will always be
Speaker 7:  His personal attorney Alex Burrow, who is also Twitter's acting
Speaker 7:  head of legal told the, the person who wrote this memo
Speaker 7:  that I reported, Elon puts rockets into space. He's not
Speaker 7:  afraid of the ftc. So that's
Speaker 6:  Good.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Wow.
Speaker 6:  I mean it's a good line.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, it's a very good line. I
Speaker 6:  Would say the
Speaker 5:  Threats that gets you sent to jail,
Speaker 6:  The threats from space conceptually. Yeah. And
Speaker 6:  government lawyers are different in form, which is one of those things like
Speaker 6:  if you're good at one thing, you're not always good at the other thing. Like
Speaker 6:  yeah
Speaker 5:  One is going
Speaker 6:  Up, i, I type really well. I'm not afraid of playing NFL football. It's like
Speaker 6:  that's, it's the same form of argument, you know. But
Speaker 6:  that to me is this is the ultimately
Speaker 6:  what, what I think Elon has failed to grasp
Speaker 6:  is that Twitter is a deeply complicated company and
Speaker 6:  a lot of it's dysfunction is because of the, the
Speaker 6:  conflicting pressures it's under from all directions at all times.
Speaker 6:  Some of which is self-inflicted. Right. The FTC consent decree, Twitter
Speaker 6:  should not have used data in a way that Twitter
Speaker 6:  should not have used your personal information in a way that violated people's
Speaker 6:  privacy. Right. And so now they have to be extra careful or some
Speaker 6:  officers of the company go to
Speaker 7:  Jail. Well I was just gonna say, it's worth noting too that in this Twitter
Speaker 7:  spaces that Elon hosted with advertisers the other day, he
Speaker 7:  talked about merging Twitter's tech stacks and he's done this internally
Speaker 7:  already in terms of like he's created a new central engineering organization
Speaker 7:  Twitter used to have its advertising stack and its
Speaker 7:  tweet kind of relevant stack for consumers separate.
Speaker 7:  And he's talked about frantically trying to merge all of it together.
Speaker 7:  And I think his quote was like, we need to be adventuresome or something.
Speaker 7:  But he wants the same technology that powers ads to power
Speaker 7:  tweet relevance. And this gets it at the heart of this FTC thing,
Speaker 7:  which is like you cannot just merge data sets without going
Speaker 7:  through us. And he literally said that on a call with a hundred thousand
Speaker 7:  people listening a couple
Speaker 6:  Days ago.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I mean this is like straightforwardly, the thing Twitter has gotten
Speaker 1:  in trouble for in the past is promising to use people's data one way and
Speaker 1:  then using it another, which would be a huge issue in
Speaker 1:  for any other company and a particularly huge one for Twitter, which has
Speaker 1:  basically signed a thing saying you, you were allowed to destroy us if
Speaker 1:  we do this again. And yet I get, I just keep coming
Speaker 1:  back to this thing that we talk about a lot on this show, which is that Elon
Speaker 1:  Musk believes the rules don't apply to him. Yeah. And has a fair amount of
Speaker 1:  evidence that says that they don't and like the SCC has not stopped him from
Speaker 1:  tweeting whatever the hell he wants overall this time. So like if I'm Elon,
Speaker 1:  I have a lot of evidence that says these government agencies are gonna yell
Speaker 1:  and yell and yell and then I'm gonna get my way.
Speaker 7:  And maybe he thinks that because he took it private, like it
Speaker 7:  doesn't matter. I don't know. Like I'm, I mean
Speaker 7:  I'm just like, is it, is it cuz it's the his like his toy
Speaker 7:  now that he can do whatever he wants with it. I mean I really, I don't get
Speaker 7:  it.
Speaker 5:  What's the over under on his personal lawyer who is clearly
Speaker 5:  calling a lot of like the legal shots, having any knowledge of
Speaker 5:  how an FTC consent decree works.
Speaker 6:  Who knows? Right? Like,
Speaker 5:  Like this is not, but this is not like, you know, usually you have lawyer,
Speaker 5:  like this lawyer sounds like you specialized lawyers. Yeah. Specialized lawyers
Speaker 5:  and this guy's not that and
Speaker 7:  Well they all quit. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Well
Speaker 7:  So it's interesting his, his lawyer Alex Spiro is also
Speaker 7:  this week representing Megan the stallion in a
Speaker 7:  feud with Drake according to tmz. So he might be busy
Speaker 7:  actually
Speaker 5:  Little busy.
Speaker 6:  He was also just on an NBA podcast about crisis communication. So
Speaker 6:  it was good. I I, you know, I listened to it. Here's my big question about
Speaker 6:  all of this, right? He's not in a fight with the FTC yet. He,
Speaker 6:  I don't know if he's pissed off Twitter users with the blue stuff. I dunno
Speaker 6:  if he's ruin the experience. He's keeps claiming by the way that the numbers
Speaker 6:  are way up. Which is hilarious because he tweeting
Speaker 6:  MDO charts the same charts he said were full of bots when he tried to get
Speaker 6:  out of the deal. So who knows, maybe more bots have been added to Twitter.
Speaker 6:  Can't tell. But he says the numbers are up, usages up. He has driven away
Speaker 6:  a bunch of advertisers. They don't appear likely to come back. Especially
Speaker 6:  if reckless patellas out there just like given Nintendo the bird.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Seems unlikely that advertisers wanna
Speaker 5:  Be tweeting at Mariah all
Speaker 6:  Day. I mean I would just do that Mariah, if you're out there, that's very
Speaker 6:  awkward Mariah, if you're out there,
Speaker 6:  in fact you would understand. I think she's a verge cast listener. Do you
Speaker 6:  know Mariah really cares about charging standards? Does
Speaker 5:  She? Yeah, I feel, I believe it. I believe it. This is, this is how you guys
Speaker 5:  are gonna meet. This is, this is the connection.
Speaker 6:  She's like USB three gen tube version one. What is that bullshit?
Speaker 6:  She's up this
Speaker 1:  Year. All I want for Christmas is Mariah Carey sneaking up on you in spatial
Speaker 1:  audio.
Speaker 6:  That's all I want in the world. That's the only use for spatial audio. That's
Speaker 6:  Mariah Carey. Anyhow, the advertiser seem extremely wary they're not going
Speaker 6:  back. My question is, Elon's companies are
Speaker 6:  effectively monopolies in their spaces. Like SpaceX
Speaker 6:  in particular, the United States has no other way of going
Speaker 6:  to space. It's SpaceX or the Russian government,
Speaker 6:  the SLS was on the launchpad, a hurricane came by and
Speaker 5:  They're like, Nope, nevermind, nevermind, nevermind.
Speaker 6:  Like it's a permanently
Speaker 5:  Can't get all the way like
Speaker 6:  The, the blue origin rocket lends itself to the most incredible jokes about
Speaker 6:  not being able to go all the way to space. We just gotta set those aside.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Is SpaceX is the vendor for the United States government. One of the
Speaker 6:  reasons Elon gets away with everything is cuz they got no other
Speaker 6:  choices. Tesla for years only viable electric car
Speaker 6:  company. Right. And you know, people really like the cars and the software
Speaker 6:  experience is great and there's all of that.
Speaker 5:  It's changed the automotive industry.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Like huge congratulations to the Tesla team. You made this thing happen.
Speaker 6:  But he's in markets where he's the only player next
Speaker 6:  year. You know, I've heard from auto advertisers in particular who are
Speaker 6:  like, well why would we go back to Twitter? Like why would we
Speaker 6:  put our marketing plans on Twitter? Alex was mentioning this last week, I
Speaker 6:  talked to some folks this week. Like that's their vibe. They think Tesla's
Speaker 6:  gonna have to compete against all of these cars that are coming out the next
Speaker 6:  year if they ever come out. Right. But if the auto industry succeeds in actually
Speaker 6:  shipping cars next year, Tesla's in a competitive environment. Yeah. Might
Speaker 6:  have to advertise. Twitter is the only business Elon runs
Speaker 6:  that is not just like a full monopoly. Right. Where
Speaker 6:  his actions might have consequences in a way that he, they can't over
Speaker 6:  can't be overcome because there's no other choices. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I mean historically he's bought into these companies when they're still
Speaker 5:  barely companies. There are these tiny little things. This is the first time
Speaker 5:  he's like, I'm gonna buy in and own this company that's been chugging along
Speaker 5:  in the public realm for years. And now like
Speaker 5:  I think he's learning some lessons, although I don't think he necessarily
Speaker 5:  wants to admit it.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I just, there's just a piece of, I mean am I ranting about competition
Speaker 6:  on the vercast? I ranting about competition on the ver chest? There's just
Speaker 6:  a piece of me that says he gets away with it all the time goes, what are
Speaker 6:  you gonna do if you want electric car, not buy a Tesla? What are you gonna
Speaker 6:  do if you wanna put a satellite in the space, not sign up with SpaceX,
Speaker 5:  Get the guys back from space.
Speaker 6:  Like what, what are you gonna do if you want the astronauts back from the
Speaker 6:  space station in your fighting a proxy war with Russia?
Speaker 6:  Well it's one choice. Yeah. So here
Speaker 6:  it's like what are you gonna do if you don't wanna spend money on Twitter
Speaker 6:  in your general Mills? It's like, oh I can just spend money anywhere else.
Speaker 6:  Anywhere. Alex, I wanna, I wanna recapitulate a conversation that you and
Speaker 6:  I have been having like all week. Cause I've been saying if I'm Mark
Speaker 6:  Zuckerberg famously ultra competitive Mark Zuckerberg,
Speaker 6:  I'm like I could just kill Twitter tomorrow,
Speaker 5:  Just
Speaker 6:  Body it. I can just take all those advertising dollars and put them on my
Speaker 6:  platform in some way. And you have been pointing out that that's actually
Speaker 6:  not a huge incentive.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. I mean we'll get into this but like the, the, the people
Speaker 7:  that Zuckerberg laid off, you know, he's probably gonna save Twitter's
Speaker 7:  annual revenue and just like the people he laid off, like we're talking
Speaker 7:  about a scale that is just so much larger
Speaker 7:  and the dollars that are spent on Twitter are the kind of
Speaker 7:  dollars that would flow more to like billboards than
Speaker 7:  they would meta. Right. They're not performance advertisers. Elon even
Speaker 7:  said this in a memo to employees that we reported on the Twitter's
Speaker 7:  advertising base is 70% brand, which is, you
Speaker 7:  know, code for large big brands doing campaigns without a
Speaker 7:  verifiable kind of outcome. Right. Just to spread brand awareness. Those
Speaker 7:  dollars they go other places. They don't necessarily go to search or
Speaker 7:  meta.
Speaker 6:  Wait can we just, I just wanna clarify for the listener what you mean by
Speaker 6:  performance and brand. We, this is our world, right? Versus is like an advertising
Speaker 6:  supported publication. Performance advertising or direct advertising
Speaker 6:  is like search ads. Like you search for a thing, you search for a flight
Speaker 6:  and United Airline shows you a price and you click the button and
Speaker 6:  you're like all the way at the bottom of the advertising funnel where you
Speaker 6:  have like expressed intent to buy something. Yeah. And then they can track
Speaker 6:  that you bought something And the reason it's called performance is cuz that
Speaker 6:  you, the advertising performs, brand advertising is all the way at the other
Speaker 6:  end where you're just, you're just aware that United Airlines
Speaker 6:  exists. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  It's just Matt Damon saying crypto is good. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Basically that's brand. So all those AWS ads on football or
Speaker 6:  all the weird IT solution vendors ads at the airport. Like when
Speaker 6:  you push on like why they exist. Like is anybody watching an NFL
Speaker 6:  football game? Like I should sign up for aws. Like that's
Speaker 6:  all brand advertising And the reason they all do it is so that when they,
Speaker 6:  when people go to their CIOs or their vendors, there's like a
Speaker 6:  baseline level of familiarity Right. That makes you more inclined
Speaker 6:  to, to do a thing as opposed to being like, I've never heard of ADA
Speaker 5:  And that's why he's concerned about it right now. Yeah. Because we
Speaker 5:  are in a weird economic space and one of the first things to go is, well,
Speaker 5:  do we really need people to be that aware of aws? We're
Speaker 5:  probably good. We can probably cut that budget. Yeah. And I thought that
Speaker 5:  was really interesting that in that letter he sent or that email, whatever
Speaker 5:  it was he sent, he was like, we're getting 50% of it here. We need
Speaker 5:  50% or more of our revenue from Twitter,
Speaker 5:  blue subscriptions,
Speaker 6:  Subscriptions.
Speaker 5:  You need to make billions of dollars on Twitter. Blue
Speaker 5:  subscriptions is basically what he's saying.
Speaker 6:  Oh, so you think they're, they're close to making Twitter bank's what, four
Speaker 6:  or 5 billion a year? Are they gonna make two and a half billion in
Speaker 6:  $8 Twitter blue subscriptions
Speaker 7:  If they up the price to what Musk originally wanted before Stephen King
Speaker 7:  got involved maybe I will note it. I
Speaker 7:  will note that the $8 a month is labeled as an introductory price.
Speaker 7:  I do think he has every intention to raise
Speaker 6:  The price. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Next
Speaker 1:  Week. I noticed that too. I thought that was interesting. But I would just
Speaker 1:  say one more thought on the, the meta thing. Like let's not forget that Mark
Speaker 1:  Zuckerberg literally rebranded his company because he wanted to get away
Speaker 1:  from dealing with all of the nonsense that comes with running a social network.
Speaker 1:  Like nobody knows better the perils of running Twitter than Mark Zuckerberg.
Speaker 1:  And he and he like dude decided he wanted no part of it and he doesn't
Speaker 1:  talk about it anymore. He doesn't answer questions about it anymore. He's
Speaker 1:  like, have you heard about legs? Yeah. And avatars. Let's talk about that.
Speaker 1:  And it's like, even if Facebook could and thought it was interesting
Speaker 1:  monetarily to kill Twitter, which it obviously doesn't. It's just
Speaker 1:  everyone who has been through this has discovered the gigantic headache that
Speaker 1:  it is trying to do this. This is why nobody bought Twitter in the past because
Speaker 1:  people kept kicking the tires and kept going, Oh this is a shit show. We
Speaker 1:  want no part of this. And and it took Elon Musk like putting
Speaker 1:  his hand on the stove to figure out that oh actually everybody was right
Speaker 1:  the whole time.
Speaker 7:  Oh and guys, since we are just, you know, we're doing this in real time,
Speaker 7:  it's Twitter, everything is changing at all times. I'm now getting pings
Speaker 7:  that UL Roth Twitter's head of trust and safety that Elon has
Speaker 7:  elevated in the last couple weeks is on the way out. Unclear if
Speaker 7:  it was because he was forced out or voluntarily resigned.
Speaker 7:  This is the guy that was on the call with advertisers. The on his set is
Speaker 7:  the one he trusts to implement his content moderation policies.
Speaker 7:  And UL is now,
Speaker 6:  He was the face, he was the one sent out to say the content policies
Speaker 6:  haven't changed. I've decreased hate speech on the platform. He's
Speaker 6:  tweeting charts the charts by the way. He's like here's charts of hates school
Speaker 6:  speech. And it's like that's a chart of people tweeting the N-word. I just
Speaker 6:  want be clear when you say this is a chart of tweets with slurs
Speaker 6:  in it, this is how often people tweet the n Oh
Speaker 7:  My god. Oh my god. Yeah. I'm sorry. The head of I just, we
Speaker 7:  gotta just have this in the pod cuz it's all gonna be out by the time Robin
Speaker 7:  Wheeler, the head of advertising has also left who was on the call with Elon
Speaker 7:  the other day talking to advertisers. Yeah. That he just made, he just put
Speaker 7:  her in charge of all ads and marketing and she's also
Speaker 7:  leaving
Speaker 1:  With you all. So that, just to put a point on this, there was a Bloomberg
Speaker 1:  story this morning that named those two people as two of the three
Speaker 1:  most important people at Twitter who he had decided were like his inner circle
Speaker 1:  who were ascending to be leaders of the company. That's two of the three
Speaker 6:  Names. This is the danger, the people who know how Twitter works, who have
Speaker 6:  the relationships with the customers who understand the complexity
Speaker 6:  of content moderation, they're all looking at this and saying this isn't
Speaker 6:  worth it.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  There's a part of me that feels bad for
Speaker 6:  Elon Musk. Like he wakes up every day and this is
Speaker 6:  the loneliest place you can be. And his only release
Speaker 6:  is tweeting clown emojis at Tom Warren. With Tom Warren
Speaker 6:  is like, look at how bad Twitter verification is going. Like
Speaker 6:  I'm not, it's not a lot of pity. Yeah. But like
Speaker 6:  the walls are just closing in. Well
Speaker 5:  I wonder if he recognizes that because we were also seeing him this week
Speaker 5:  tweet like yeah, our our our average user base is growing.
Speaker 5:  Right? So like maybe in his head it's like well, you know,
Speaker 5:  at least one important number still go up. We still good. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  He's been saying this a lot that like, you know, it's, it's messy but
Speaker 1:  it's at least it's interesting and it's like, okay, that's all well and
Speaker 1:  good Elon and and it is certainly interesting like
Speaker 1:  it is our audience is interested in it, we're interested in it. The internet
Speaker 1:  is interested in it. Like I, I was at, I was at a doctor's appointment this
Speaker 1:  morning and we talked about what Elon Musk is doing to Twitter. Like this
Speaker 1:  is, this is a captivating thing. But then there comes a minute
Speaker 1:  where Elon Musk has to pay a billion dollar interest payment
Speaker 1:  to make this money work and it's just not
Speaker 1:  interesting. Doesn't eventually pay the bills here and it, it looks like
Speaker 1:  all the money is walking away even if the thing is more interesting from
Speaker 1:  day to day.
Speaker 6:  Here's the thing that's gonna really get Elon in trouble. A fake Taylor Swift
Speaker 6:  account just tweeted that her tour is canceled and it has 5,000
Speaker 5:  Likes and oh God, she pissed off the BTS
Speaker 5:  fans.
Speaker 6:  It's all over
Speaker 5:  Man. The BTS army is mad now you got the swifties mad.
Speaker 5:  We gotta get the, I believe they're called the lamb blaze. That's your people
Speaker 5:  Eli. Hmm. The lambs. That's what, that's what Mariah calls her
Speaker 5:  fans.
Speaker 6:  The lamb blaze
Speaker 5:  The lamb like family but lambs
Speaker 6:  Right. There's a limit to my Mariah fandom and it really ended with,
Speaker 6:  we found how very single I was when I was a teenager.
Speaker 6:  There's a little box right? My just like fandom.
Speaker 5:  I don't know this and I don't
Speaker 6:  Want to again and end with the heartbreaker video. That's all I'm saying.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, that sounds right. But like this has been happening like there was
Speaker 1:  a fake LeBron James who tweeted requesting a trade that that
Speaker 1:  became a whole thing. Like this is just, this is gonna happen over and over
Speaker 1:  and over again. And it sounds like basically there are somewhere between
Speaker 1:  zero and four people at Twitter who are just like manually chasing this
Speaker 1:  around the platform trying to delete stuff as it goes and it's like this
Speaker 1:  just isn't gonna work. Yeah. And it's gonna get so much worse
Speaker 1:  so quickly
Speaker 5:  You're seeing other companies dunk on it. I think both Tumblr
Speaker 5:  and Sub Stack, neither company doing terrifically well have both
Speaker 5:  announced that they're now doing Blue Check marks Tumblr's offering you two
Speaker 5:  for the price of one.
Speaker 1:  We, we should not put those two in the same category because sub stack is
Speaker 1:  like doing this very earnest thing where they're like, Twitter sucks, we
Speaker 1:  are your great home and our check marks represent actual writer success
Speaker 1:  on the platform and Tumblr just like give us eight bucks, we'll give you
Speaker 1:  two check marks. They don't mean anywhere. It's very good. Fuck you. And
Speaker 1:  it's
Speaker 6:  Amazing. It's very good. Sorry I'm also catching up on the
Speaker 6:  you off news. I mean it is crazy. I'm just gonna read
Speaker 6:  this tweet from Casey and then we gotta take a break because we can't keep
Speaker 6:  talking about Twitter in this moment of flux. Like
Speaker 6:  I'm just gonna read this tweet Casey right now the timeline kind of feels
Speaker 6:  like the day the Lamas escaped except this time the LLAs are loose at
Speaker 6:  Twitter headquarters and are trying to shut the company down.
Speaker 6:  That's it is incredible how much all of this platform
Speaker 6:  has turned its gaze inwards and it's just washing the company
Speaker 6:  collapse. Yep. I don't know what's going to happen next. Heath. I don't think
Speaker 6:  you know what's gonna, Do you know what's gonna happen next? Cuz it would
Speaker 6:  be really helpful
Speaker 7:  To say it. I, I don't know. I mean this FTC thing may
Speaker 7:  sink the company because my understanding is the people who are being
Speaker 7:  asked to self-certify product launches and code at
Speaker 7:  the risk of facing possible jail time are all quitting. So everyone on like
Speaker 7:  the security and privacy team under the executives who who left
Speaker 7:  are all kind of quitting together. And so I don't know what
Speaker 7:  how much of a company he's gonna have left next week, to be perfectly honest.
Speaker 5:  Even tomorrow.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Or tomorrow. And
Speaker 6:  And we should say we have not talked about the technology of Twitter very
Speaker 6:  much on our tech podcast. Twitter is starting to subtly break in weird
Speaker 6:  ways like follower accounts have gone up. The retweet button was
Speaker 6:  doing manual retreats for a
Speaker 7:  While. I should note because this happened because Twitter had a code
Speaker 7:  freeze in place until the day after the midterms when they launched Blue
Speaker 7:  where basically you couldn't push anything through production unless you
Speaker 7:  got VP approval. And that lifted Wednesday evening and I'm
Speaker 7:  told that once that lifted, it was kind of like all hell broke loose and
Speaker 7:  now that the site can be changed, you're seeing all this dramatic stuff
Speaker 7:  with what the lawyer sent and all these resignations because everyone's realizing
Speaker 7:  like, oh when Elon actually has the keys and can make changes, this
Speaker 7:  is what happens.
Speaker 6:  Oh boy. All right. We gotta stop talking about Twitter because literally
Speaker 6:  the more we talk about it, the more we summon chaos. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  More people are leaving invalidates everything we just said. We'll see what
Speaker 6:  happened. We're obviously gonna talk about next week, we gotta take a break,
Speaker 6:  come back. Heath is gonna walk us through what's going on at Meow, which
Speaker 6:  is going through equal chaos. But I would say in a
Speaker 6:  more controlled way. Yeah, we'll be right back.
Speaker 6:  Okay, we're back. I've struggled to keep all these stories apart in
Speaker 6:  my head. Like Twitter, chaos, meta chaos, ftx, chaos, collapse,
Speaker 6:  chaos. Just across the board. Let's talk about meta though.
Speaker 6:  11,000 people let go. A very different tone from Mark
Speaker 6:  Zuckerberg and letting those folks go. Very generous terms. He wasn't like
Speaker 6:  your all audience by the way, we should note that in the all hands that Elon
Speaker 6:  just had. He said that even after the 50% layoffs, Twitter still
Speaker 6:  overstaffed, which just cannot be motivating for the people who
Speaker 6:  remain meta in a very different place.
Speaker 1:  Elon also said if you're physically able to come to the office and you don't
Speaker 1:  resignation accepted, which is a pretty bull
Speaker 1:  like I think starting like today was the, he told me yesterday and it was
Speaker 1:  starting today was the end of their remote work policy. So yeah,
Speaker 1:  I would say Mark Zuckerberg handled this significantly more gracefully is
Speaker 1:  probably the word I would use.
Speaker 6:  And strange to me in the timeline where Mark Zuckerberg is the revered older
Speaker 6:  statesman of tech. But here we we're, right? Alex walk, What's going on with
Speaker 6:  Meow?
Speaker 7:  Sure. Let's contrast this quickly at the top. So Twitter
Speaker 7:  layoffs were unsigned emails, no message from Elon, very
Speaker 7:  terse also like potentially violating the war Act TBD on that
Speaker 7:  about minimum severance you could offer. And meow by
Speaker 7:  contrast, it's a lot of people. So this is the largest tech
Speaker 7:  company layoff to date. One of the largest I think ever. It actually may
Speaker 7:  be the largest ever. It's 13% of the company, over
Speaker 7:  11,000 people. And the way this happened was Mark gathered all the
Speaker 7:  directors and VPs the day before on a call where I'm told he was very
Speaker 7:  remorseful looking like kind of hazy eyed and took responsibility.
Speaker 7:  Which you know you can laugh at that, right? Cuz it's like billionaire
Speaker 7:  Co takes responsibility. What does that actually look like? But said like
Speaker 7:  this was my fault. I thought that the trends we saw during Covid where
Speaker 7:  there was a pull forward as all these tech executives were talking about
Speaker 7:  in people's online activity, commerce, et cetera, people thought
Speaker 7:  this was going to, and I kept hearing this at the time too, I'm sure Eli
Speaker 7:  and others did too. All these tech executives were saying during Covid like
Speaker 7:  this has pulled forward 10 years of growth in a matter of
Speaker 7:  18 months. And Zuckerberg said on this call with kind of management that
Speaker 7:  he expected that growth to sustain and to not you know, retreat.
Speaker 7:  And certainly I guess no one expected J Powell to just raise rates
Speaker 7:  the way he did and that certainly affected everyone. And then the
Speaker 7:  following day, you know, emails start going out and Mark actually gets on
Speaker 7:  a call with everyone who was laid off kind of reiterates again there was
Speaker 7:  video of this that leaked. Looks like he's basically tearing up, said thank
Speaker 7:  you guys so much. He's giving everyone four months of severance and
Speaker 7:  it's just couldn't be handled, you know, differently. But in terms of
Speaker 7:  like the impact to meta, I think what's been interesting based on my
Speaker 7:  conversations with employees and including some who were laid off, is that
Speaker 7:  everyone was kind of shocked at how sporadic these cuts were because over
Speaker 7:  the summer Meta has been doing quiet layoffs. Essentially they asked
Speaker 7:  managers to build lists of bottom performers, about
Speaker 7:  10%, 10 to 15% of their team, which matches the layoffs that they
Speaker 7:  just did that need support. And they were also, they had frozen
Speaker 7:  internal transfers, they had frozen external hiring. There had been a real
Speaker 7:  ramp up in attrition and everyone thought that these layoffs would just hit
Speaker 7:  those people on that need support list. And instead I'm hearing about
Speaker 7:  directors and AI people working on the AR glasses
Speaker 7:  areas that you wouldn't necessarily expect that are still key bets.
Speaker 7:  Obviously some stuff that that you would expect. Like meta had like almost
Speaker 7:  7,000 recruiters. So that word got
Speaker 7:  decimated. And also in marketing and some of those other areas,
Speaker 7:  comms pretty hit hard but it wasn't like really
Speaker 7:  focused on I would say reality labs with the metaverse division
Speaker 7:  that everyone's saying he needs to be cutting on as much as it was kind of
Speaker 7:  spread randomly throughout hitting senior and low level people. And what
Speaker 7:  I heard was they didn't wanna focus it on one org because they didn't
Speaker 7:  want their that to breed resentment in the company. Oh my god. Or
Speaker 7:  getting hit more than the other, even though Reality Labs everyone
Speaker 7:  acknowledges internally is very bloated, it has over
Speaker 7:  25,000 people. This is the part of the company that makes Horizon,
Speaker 7:  which I wrote the VP is having a hard time even getting the people building
Speaker 7:  it to use and Horizon has a thousand people on it
Speaker 7:  and this isn't a product that has like maybe 150,000
Speaker 7:  users. Well
Speaker 6:  We should wait, we should talk about that for one minute cuz we haven't published
Speaker 6:  our Quest Pro review yet. We will just,
Speaker 6:  it's been a very busy week but Addie's working on that review, it's going
Speaker 6:  up. We're working on the video. Alex, you have a Quest Pro. I have a Quest
Speaker 6:  Pro. A Quest Pro. We've tried now several times to hang out in both Horizon
Speaker 6:  work rooms, which is the Metaverse conference room
Speaker 6:  situation and Horizon Worlds, which is the
Speaker 6:  the fun one. It's bad. And I'm just gonna offer
Speaker 6:  you this one snippet of a moment not to totally tease this from you.
Speaker 6:  I don't wanna spoil it. Too bad. You, you should probably tell from the tone
Speaker 6:  of my voice,
Speaker 5:  Oh I'm ready.
Speaker 6:  We, we, Alex was, Alex Heath was trying to join me
Speaker 6:  and Addie in work rooms and he couldn't get on it just like didn't work.
Speaker 6:  So then he invited us into his world in
Speaker 6:  Horizon worlds and so he beam in there,
Speaker 5:  No legs
Speaker 6:  And no legs and suddenly we are
Speaker 6:  surrounded by the sound of teen boys saying there's a
Speaker 6:  girl on the server. Oh boy, there's a girl here.
Speaker 5:  Oh no.
Speaker 6:  And then they said ask her if she's over 18.
Speaker 6:  And then dozens of avatars ran across.
Speaker 5:  So just Xbox in 2002.
Speaker 6:  It was like terrifying. And the funniest part about this was we
Speaker 6:  don't even know if that was Addie, cause Addie, you hear
Speaker 6:  her clearly talking to someone else.
Speaker 7:  It was pure chaos And it's just like imagine, you know,
Speaker 7:  scrolling through Twitter but in 3D where you're embodied and
Speaker 7:  it's a bunch of people
Speaker 5:  Yelling, I don't want that. Is there a girl on the platform?
Speaker 5:  Is she over aging? I
Speaker 6:  Mean it was, it was like instance after we like I hit the button to
Speaker 6:  Beam to where Alex was just like dozens of of boys,
Speaker 6:  like teen boy voices being like there's a girl, she's the only
Speaker 6:  girl on the server.
Speaker 5:  You don't see that as often as you used to cuz like early internet days you'd
Speaker 5:  be like, I'm a girl. And oh no, it was those
Speaker 5:  AOL chat rooms got spicy for this 12 year old girl,
Speaker 5:  but but like you don't see it as often now, so it's like woo.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, that's, that's something.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, there's no, I don't think there's a button in the metaverse that lets
Speaker 6:  you type asl, but that's, it was very much that vibe.
Speaker 6:  So I won't give away the whole thing, but like it's a lot of money going
Speaker 6:  towards an experience that I would say is not very good at this point in
Speaker 6:  time. Yeah, but Alex you're saying they didn't cut reality labs
Speaker 6:  because they didn't want the reality labs people to be resentful
Speaker 6:  of Instagram or
Speaker 7:  Whatever? No, I just, I'm saying throughout the company the
Speaker 7:  cuts were relatively spread because they
Speaker 7:  didn't want certain teams and there were, to be clear, there were some product
Speaker 7:  teams that got hit a lot harder. There was actually still a remnant
Speaker 7:  of a consumer smartwatch team trying to figure out if their meadow was gonna
Speaker 7:  do a consumer smartwatch,
Speaker 7:  which I didn't even know. Are they still, there was still, No, that team
Speaker 7:  got really sacked, so Oh, there were some teams that got hit
Speaker 7:  hard, but in terms of where the cuts were spread throughout all of
Speaker 7:  meta, it was fairly distributed and that was on purpose to not breed
Speaker 7:  resentment.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Well and I also think it's, it's kind of emblematic of this
Speaker 1:  impossible position that meta is in and that Mark Zuckerberg continues
Speaker 1:  to put himself in, which is that everybody wants him to pull
Speaker 1:  back on the metaverse bets and start investing in the stuff that actually
Speaker 1:  makes the company money. But he is now so all in pot
Speaker 1:  committed to the idea that the metaverse is the future of the company. That
Speaker 1:  he almost can't afford to like retrench on that and be like, Okay, actually
Speaker 1:  we need to focus on the stuff that makes us the money. We'll worry about
Speaker 1:  that someday in the future. Like then you inspire a whole different kind
Speaker 1:  of panic. Like he has to project confidence in this idea
Speaker 1:  that he has sort of loudly bet the company on even as it
Speaker 1:  sort of systematically destroys the company. Yeah, yeah. And it's, I don't
Speaker 1:  know how you navigate that.
Speaker 7:  Well, I just wanna be careful that yeah this is super precarious for
Speaker 7:  him. Obviously, like they're losing a lot of money and investors don't believe
Speaker 7:  in this mission at the same time. Like this is not Twitter, like meta
Speaker 7:  is wildly profitable. They did like 5 billion in profit last
Speaker 7:  quarter. So it's a very, this last quarter different situation that
Speaker 7:  said, I think the cuts put meta back to where it was like less than a year
Speaker 7:  ago. Like this company has hired so much that was that
Speaker 7:  feature featuring Gary from Chicago, you know, rest in peace salute
Speaker 7:  that David, you and I wrote over the summer where
Speaker 7:  like men have hired like 40% headcount growth
Speaker 7:  during the pandemic all remotely. So they went from like 30 ish
Speaker 7:  thousand pre pandemic to like 87,000 now
Speaker 7:  and the offices are empty, you know, so it's like people are still working
Speaker 7:  remote and it's just, it's this, I think bigger story
Speaker 7:  that's, we've seen across tech of these companies thought that the
Speaker 7:  punch bowl that they were giving during Covid would never be taken away.
Speaker 7:  And they're all realizing very forcefully and frighteningly
Speaker 7:  at the same time that it's totally gone and they're left out, you know? But
Speaker 7:  what does Buffet say? Like if, if when the tide come comes back in, you get
Speaker 7:  to see who's swimming naked. So that's like what's happening right now.
Speaker 1:  I was just gonna say, this is a thing I've heard from a bunch of people over
Speaker 1:  time and it's been really interesting to track this over the last like six
Speaker 1:  months cuz there was like we've been talking about, there was this moment
Speaker 1:  where basically for two years everybody was like, okay, we have essentially
Speaker 1:  fast forwarded a decade into the future. Yeah. And that growth is gonna keep
Speaker 1:  going. This stuff is never going back. We're all gonna order groceries and
Speaker 1:  have them delivered. We're all gonna hang out in the metaverse, Zoom is the
Speaker 1:  future, all this stuff. And then there was this period after that where everybody
Speaker 1:  was like, okay, we've made all these changes but maybe the pace from here
Speaker 1:  isn't gonna be quite as fast as we thought. So everybody sort of slowed down
Speaker 1:  a little bit. And more recently I've started talking to people who are like,
Speaker 1:  Oh my God, we're just going back to 2019. Yes. Like all of the stuff that
Speaker 1:  happened is now being sort of systematically undone as people go back to
Speaker 1:  work and back to the ways that they were doing things before now that they
Speaker 1:  could. And so like not only are we not moving forward as fast, we're actually
Speaker 1:  going backwards. And to me that's one of the things that has really like
Speaker 1:  combined that with all the macroeconomic stuff and all of these companies
Speaker 1:  have gone like, Oh my God, we are no longer anywhere near
Speaker 1:  actually set up to be the kind of company we need to be to succeed right
Speaker 1:  now. And it's just, it, everybody is sort of feeling that crunch
Speaker 1:  simultaneously, which has been really interesting to hear about.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I think we, we talked about this a lot on the vergecast, which is there
Speaker 6:  the first order pandemic effects in like the second order ones.
Speaker 6:  And like my favorite second order effect is everyone cares more about their
Speaker 6:  webcams. Like does Maca West continuity cam and that little be
Speaker 6:  mount exist if not for the global Covid pandemic? No,
Speaker 6:  definitely not. Right? Like, no, everyone had to care about it. So we care
Speaker 6:  about it and now there's like an entire category of of AI powered webcams
Speaker 6:  that exist and that's like a hilarious second order effect. The problem is
Speaker 6:  everyone overestimated the first order effects. Yeah. And the way that like
Speaker 6:  tech people, computer people often do, which is, oh my gosh, you've moved
Speaker 6:  all of your stuff to this computer platform, it's so much faster and
Speaker 6:  more efficient. Why would you ever go back to the old way? And it turns out
Speaker 6:  the old way of doing lots of things has benefits as well.
Speaker 6:  Like, like I, it's, it's not
Speaker 1:  Well the answer is cuz schools are open again, right? Like that's, they,
Speaker 1:  they let us go back to school.
Speaker 6:  I was on CNBC the other day and we were talking about the gaming companies
Speaker 6:  and their earnings and the way that you do on cnbc and they sent me a bunch
Speaker 6:  of research to prepare and one of them was a note from Jeff's about Roblox
Speaker 6:  earnings and the analyst note was we expect Roblox to be soft at
Speaker 6:  the end of the year because the kids are in school and it was just like dead
Speaker 1:  Ahead. Literally. That's like
Speaker 6:  The kids are in school and when they're in the classroom they cannot be
Speaker 6:  playing Roblox. Right. And it turns out that for two years kids at
Speaker 6:  school, at home were kind of playing Roblox on the side
Speaker 6:  and like that's just reality for so many of these companies. And I think
Speaker 6:  it's, the thing with Meta though is they didn't
Speaker 6:  launch a bunch of pandemic products. They
Speaker 6:  hired a lot of people for coming shifts and I think
Speaker 6:  Zuckerberg's view was, everyone's at home on their computer now this
Speaker 6:  is the right time to make a face computer. So your whole life is the computer
Speaker 6:  all the time. Yeah. Because I think he was running head first into
Speaker 6:  app tracking transparency and 30% platform
Speaker 6:  fees and all this other stuff and he was like, I have to make a new platform
Speaker 6:  for the coming change and the new platform. Again, not to spoil
Speaker 6:  our review, I think they probably should have just kept that one on the shelf.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it's really bad. I mean it's, it's, I think
Speaker 6:  Addie said that Addie said Horizon is like the worst software
Speaker 6:  experience she's ever had, like ever. Which, yeah,
Speaker 6:  I mean I, I mean I do think the hardware
Speaker 6:  is, you can see the quality, you can see the, the design and that
Speaker 6:  they clearly have a lot of X apple people there and they,
Speaker 6:  they, I think they did an okay job with the hardware. It's just the software
Speaker 6:  is so atrocious on this thing. And yes, there were Meta
Speaker 6:  Quest Pro employees and engineers laid off like this
Speaker 6:  is a product that just shipped and I think just goes to show like kind of
Speaker 6:  how in disarray this whole strategy is. Yeah. So we'll see.
Speaker 6:  I mean, again, I don't think that there has been a really
Speaker 6:  definitive review of the Quest Pro yet. There's a reason we're taking a lot
Speaker 6:  of time with ours, I think to make some of the claims you're gonna make,
Speaker 6:  you gotta take a lot of time. Yep. That review will come out. But I think
Speaker 6:  it will put a pin, I think on this era of meta in a way that the layoffs
Speaker 6:  are putting a pin on this era of meta and really this era of tech. Like
Speaker 6:  Apple's doing a hiring freeze. I would expect Google to be doing some sort
Speaker 6:  of changes soon. We were just seeing it across the tech industry. Right.
Speaker 6:  We gotta take a break. We're gonna come back. We're gonna talk about one
Speaker 6:  more disaster. Alex, I think you're, you're not second with us, right?
Speaker 6:  I think you gotta, you gotta go do some reporting. I, All
Speaker 6:  right. Alex is gonna go and figure out what's going on with Twitter. We'll
Speaker 6:  be back. David's gonna take us through ftx. We'll be right back.
Speaker 9:  Hey, it's Kenny man. This is a promotion of Haman. The Kenny Mane talks to
Speaker 9:  famous people podcast. We got lots of famous people, Dan Patrick and
Speaker 9:  Keith Overman. We gotta work 99% of what we
Speaker 10:  Tried to do. I'm mad at him because I know that he'll regret it, but I
Speaker 10:  know that he has to leave.
Speaker 9:  Sue Bird is involved. Re's Chapman, Dan Levard, Katie
Speaker 9:  Nolan, Allison Becker, Sorry for all the others I interviewed who I
Speaker 9:  left out. Oh yeah, Solo O'Brien. She was good. Get it on the Odyssey app
Speaker 9:  or wherever you get your podcast.
Speaker 11:  Support for this episode comes from brx, the corporate card and
Speaker 11:  spend management software teams actually love. If you're a CFO
Speaker 11:  or finance leader today, you know we are operating in
Speaker 11:  transformational times. It can be hard getting people all in the same
Speaker 11:  place and not over another Zoom call now more than
Speaker 11:  ever before. You need to help build a connection with not only your team
Speaker 11:  but with your clientele in real life. Thankfully
Speaker 11:  brx can help. BR is an integrated solution of corporate cards
Speaker 11:  and span management software that drives 100% compliance
Speaker 11:  and zero receipt chasing in over 100 countries. Brx
Speaker 11:  is easy to set up and easy to use with dedicated implementation
Speaker 11:  software and intuitive consumer great design and the brx mobile
Speaker 11:  app. And if you ever need support, you can always reach out by phone
Speaker 11:  app or chat twenty four seven. It's that simple.
Speaker 11:  Brx makes it easy to manage every aspect of spending from the
Speaker 11:  smallest purchases to the biggest procurements. No matter where your team
Speaker 11:  works, they help empower employees to do the right thing and
Speaker 11:  spend responsibly and compliance is built in. So with everything
Speaker 11:  from restaurants to retail stores to your work platform, all going
Speaker 11:  cloud based, isn't it time for your company to use a spend management solution
Speaker 11:  for modern times? Learn more at brx.com/podcast.
Speaker 6:  All right, we're back. Let's see if we can do this quickly. David,
Speaker 6:  alongside all of the social media disasters, there's a giant
Speaker 6:  crypto exchange called ftx.
Speaker 1:  Yes.
Speaker 6:  Which just ate itself this week. What, what happened?
Speaker 1:  That's, it's a pretty solid description actually. So, okay. The, the piece
Speaker 1:  of context that is useful to understand here is that Sam Bankman Freed,
Speaker 1:  who is the CEO of ftx, which is one of the biggest crypto exchanges and
Speaker 1:  there's ftx.com and there's ftx.us,
Speaker 1:  ftx.us is a separate thing that is also potentially falling apart. But
Speaker 1:  for the purposes of this, we are not going to be talking about ftx us. Is
Speaker 11:  It also an
Speaker 6:  Exchange?
Speaker 1:  It is also an exchange and that is the one the people in the US actually
Speaker 1:  use. But basically because a lot of people are confused
Speaker 1:  and or mad at crypto rules, a lot of people run their crypto stuff
Speaker 1:  offshore. Okay. So that is a thing that has been happening and that is what
Speaker 1:  ftx.com is Sam Banque free, the CEO of FTX has been,
Speaker 1:  I would, I think beefing is like a fair way to describe it with
Speaker 1:  Cheang, the CEO of Binance, which is the largest crypto exchange.
Speaker 1:  So they've been fighting for various reasons over time.
Speaker 1:  And FTX has been on this crazy run during the crypto downturn of
Speaker 1:  basically just buying everything it could find, right? Like they
Speaker 1:  definitely seem to sort of sense that this was a moment to gain market share
Speaker 1:  and win in a big way. But all of this is to say basically this week bin
Speaker 1:  specifically started a huge run on
Speaker 1:  the token that FTX gives out, which is called ftt.
Speaker 1:  Basically they, they decided they didn't want own any of it anymore and sold
Speaker 1:  a gigantic amount of it all at once. Very publicly, very loudly announced
Speaker 1:  that they were doing this. And when somebody like the CEO of Binance decides
Speaker 1:  to do this and when they sell this much, the price goes down. So
Speaker 1:  the price goes down, which means more people wanna withdraw, which means
Speaker 1:  the price goes down further, which means more people wanna withdraw. This
Speaker 1:  is what they call a run on the bank. Yes. So this now becomes a gigantic
Speaker 1:  disaster. And then it turns out that FTX didn't have the money to
Speaker 1:  pay all the people who wanted to get their money out, which
Speaker 1:  is a problem for a lot of very complicated reasons. But if you don't have
Speaker 1:  people's money to give them, that's generally considered to be a problem.
Speaker 1:  So there was a minute where FTX was going
Speaker 1:  to be sold to Binance and Binance was gonna essentially take it over
Speaker 1:  in an effort to give customers their money back and sort of make all of
Speaker 1:  them whole while swallowing ftx.com Binance,
Speaker 1:  from what we can tell, basically did like six minutes of due diligence went,
Speaker 1:  Oh my God, this is so much worse than we thought. Nevermind, we're at,
Speaker 1:  we're out, we're not doing this. And again, announces this very publicly
Speaker 1:  makes a statement about how essentially saying like, FTX sucks so bad, we
Speaker 1:  don't even want to buy it for $1. Like we're out.
Speaker 1:  And then over the course of the last 24 hours, it has come out that basically
Speaker 1:  the most egregiously wrong thing that FTX did
Speaker 1:  was use the money that people had invested to fund its own trading
Speaker 1:  with this separate firm called Alameda that was basically
Speaker 1:  a hedge fund using FTX assets. So now
Speaker 1:  it has come out that FTX was using customer money to do its own trading.
Speaker 1:  Crypto goes down, that trading doesn't work, so you don't have the money
Speaker 1:  to give back to people, it just spins outta control, right? Like money, money
Speaker 1:  goes down, everything falls apart. And so now what it basically looks like
Speaker 1:  is sandbank free, the CEO is out trying to get somewhere in the
Speaker 1:  range of nine and a half billion just to like
Speaker 1:  make customers whole and make this work. And And
Speaker 5:  By work you mean pay all those people because no one wants to invest in
Speaker 5:  that
Speaker 1:  Now. Yeah. So essentially what I mean I think if he can't make
Speaker 1:  customers whole and then shut his company down, it's gonna get much worse
Speaker 1:  for him. Yeah, right. There's like, this gets very ugly when people can't
Speaker 1:  get their money out and right now those people can't get their money out
Speaker 1:  because it literally doesn't exist. And so he, he has explored a bunch of
Speaker 1:  different avenues. There are other crypto people who are like, oh, turn your
Speaker 1:  crypto into our crypto for very expensive exchanges and that's
Speaker 1:  a disaster. So it's like scams on top of scams on top of scams and it,
Speaker 1:  it seems like at the end of this FTX and Sam Freed was like
Speaker 1:  the crypto guy. Yeah. Right. Like he's on billboards in San Francisco. He's
Speaker 1:  like, he is the face of crypto in a very real way. He was a
Speaker 6:  Cover of Forbes or Fortune.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Like recently. And this is, this is all
Speaker 1:  absolutely just crashing around him and I
Speaker 1:  don't know exactly how it's gonna end, but it seems very unlikely that
Speaker 1:  FTX continues to be a thing for much longer after this.
Speaker 5:  Does this just kind of like prove that
Speaker 5:  a lot of crypto not the, the underlying technology blockchain is cool?
Speaker 5:  Is it Blockchain is like the technology has,
Speaker 1:  Blockchain is a thing that exists. It's a thing that's like the most I'm
Speaker 1:  willing to give you for
Speaker 5:  Sure. And I feel like it could be cool when not used in a
Speaker 5:  multibillion dollar pyramid scheme,
Speaker 5:  which is like, that's what this is. Like everything you're saying, I'm like,
Speaker 5:  that's just like the time it's, I gave money to get an Xbox to
Speaker 5:  someone online. I didn't get my Xbox, I lost
Speaker 5:  $40. It's
Speaker 1:  Less pyramid scheme and more Ponzi scheme. Okay. In the sense that I'm gonna
Speaker 1:  take your money and I'm gonna do some stuff with it and then I'm gonna take
Speaker 1:  someone else's money and give it to you while I'm still doing the stuff.
Speaker 1:  And then at the end all of us are gonna be so rich that you're not even gonna
Speaker 1:  be worried about it. Except then crypto goes down.
Speaker 5:  So real Bernie Madoff energy.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Super Bernie Madoff energy, unintentional Bernie Madoff thing is like, is
Speaker 1:  that a thing? Can you like accidentally,
Speaker 6:  He just lied to everyone. He was very intentionally doing this. So Sam
Speaker 6:  Bankman freed Sbf as people know, like the profiles are
Speaker 6:  glowing and he was the one in like the halls of Congress
Speaker 6:  pitching the regulation. So you gotta change the laws to the
Speaker 6:  reason there's FTX and ftx US is cuz Fdx does riskier
Speaker 6:  trades than are allowed in the United States. There's a real thing. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. So he's like running around saying they should be crypto regulation
Speaker 6:  and he should allow me to do these kinds of trades. And the crypto industry
Speaker 6:  has a
Speaker 6:  pretty conflicted relationship with him. They didn't like the bills he was
Speaker 6:  proposing. There's, there's like a medium chance he just got taken down
Speaker 6:  for proposing crypto regulations that would've,
Speaker 5:  But also
Speaker 6:  Because his own position
Speaker 5:  He was doing a Ponzi
Speaker 6:  But also the, I mean there's that element for
Speaker 5:  Sure. Yeah, yeah. Well
Speaker 1:  But also the, the this, this is why I bring up the beefing that's been going
Speaker 1:  on between Sam and Angia, the CEO of Binance. Like Sam
Speaker 1:  did this whole long tweet thread basically apologizing for
Speaker 1:  being horrible and making a lot of horrendously bad decisions and
Speaker 1:  like to some extent took, you know, acknowledged all the stuff that he did
Speaker 1:  wrong and the mistakes that they made and all this stuff. But then at the
Speaker 1:  very end was basically like, you know, I don't wanna, I don't wanna pick
Speaker 1:  fights but like I think the last thing was like you did it, You
Speaker 1:  won. Which is like very clearly directed at
Speaker 1:  who just like cemented his own place and bins power
Speaker 1:  in this industry by sort of systematically destroying a competitor.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I think he said, I think he said, and I don't wanna like name any names
Speaker 5:  here, but you won and everybody's like, okay it's it's finance. It's obvious
Speaker 6:  Though it's not this and let's talk about the most important part. FTX ran
Speaker 6:  a lot of ads. They ran a Superbowl ad,
Speaker 5:  They own a stadium,
Speaker 6:  They own a stadium, they
Speaker 1:  Own a bunch of stadiums, like hundreds of millions of dollars of right steals
Speaker 1:  that FTX has has paid for some of them I think in crypto.
Speaker 6:  Can we just skip to the important part of this, which is the FTX did a
Speaker 6:  lot of advertising. Yeah. Like a lot of advertising they
Speaker 6:  owned I think that Miami Heat Play and FTX Arena,
Speaker 5:  Right? They got a lot of arenas. Tons.
Speaker 6:  They did a super ad. It's like the super A is like just Tom Brady
Speaker 6:  calling people and being like, are you in? And it's like an escalating series
Speaker 6:  of famous people. You know,
Speaker 1:  My favorite is that Major League baseball umpires wear an FTX logo
Speaker 1:  on their uniform. Sure.
Speaker 6:  So Tom Brady and Giselle have an equity deal,
Speaker 6:  they own a huge chunk of FTX and they poured like some significant
Speaker 6:  amount of their net worth into it. We don't know how much, but they were
Speaker 6:  like on the record being like, we're bit big on ftx.
Speaker 5:  Well they just, they just finalized their divorce and I wonder if part of
Speaker 5:  it was Giselle was like, you take all the crypto holdings
Speaker 1:  Cash,
Speaker 5:  You're taking the crypto. So she's just sitting there being like, Wow man,
Speaker 5:  suck to be you.
Speaker 6:  Let me just read from this press release a seven times Super Bowl champion
Speaker 6:  and one of the greatest athletes of all time. Tom is a natural fit in his
Speaker 6:  new role as ambassador for ftx. Given that the platform has quickly
Speaker 6:  risen to be one of the leading exchanges worldwide. The first part of that
Speaker 6:  sentence and the second part of that sentence have nothing to do with each
Speaker 6:  other. Nothing being the greatest athlete
Speaker 6:  in the world. That's nothing. I'm
Speaker 5:  A great writer. That means I'll play football.
Speaker 6:  There's a lot of that on the Verge cast this week.
Speaker 1:  Can we rec con deflate gate to be about the lowering
Speaker 1:  price of crypto instead of about footballs? Do you think we can
Speaker 6:  Do that somehow? Giselle was named the environmental and Social
Speaker 6:  Initiatives advisor to the Crypto Exchange. Oh
Speaker 5:  Wow.
Speaker 6:  And she talks about how much she cares about the environment in the context
Speaker 6:  for crypto investment. I'm fairly convinced and there's like a lot
Speaker 6:  of Tom Brady noise. He's gotta play football for the rest of his life now
Speaker 5:  Forever. That's he, he can never
Speaker 6:  Stop. He's he's gonna be hustling Gatorade and like whatever
Speaker 6:  forever. Now
Speaker 5:  People are like not gonna tackle him at some point cuz they're like I don't
Speaker 5:  wanna break his bones.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. We just,
Speaker 1:  It's also, this is perfect proof of the long
Speaker 1:  running thesis that as soon as a company puts its
Speaker 1:  name on a sports stadium, you can assume that that company is about to fall
Speaker 1:  apart. Yes. Yeah. Like it just, it it is, it has never not been
Speaker 1:  true and like blessings to fdx it. It continues to be true.
Speaker 1:  Kudos to everybody.
Speaker 6:  We'll just see what happens with this. But this is like the weirdest fallout
Speaker 6:  of all this crypto noise is the number of celebrities and
Speaker 6:  athletes who bet huge on crypto in the middle of the pandemic.
Speaker 6:  And now that's all getting wiped out. Aaron Rogers, she points out and that's
Speaker 6:  the deal where he was gonna get paid in Bitcoin, which is a
Speaker 6:  horrible deal now. Like that dude just took care of cut on.
Speaker 5:  I
Speaker 6:  Love it. And there's like lots of athletes who, who took deals like this
Speaker 6:  to, to promote and he did it by the way, with our friend Jack Dorsey and
Speaker 6:  Cash app. Okay. Jack Dorsey, you know, the extremely
Speaker 6:  good CEO Jack Dorsey,
Speaker 5:  He knows how to run a company.
Speaker 6:  So just a lot of chaos in tech this week.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Well and FTX was supposed to be one of the like
Speaker 1:  responsible future of crypto companies that it was like a lot
Speaker 1:  of people bet on it because it was like, okay, when all of the noise
Speaker 1:  goes away there's gonna be a handful of sort of good stewards of crypto
Speaker 1:  left and FTX is gonna be one of them. And now you have people like
Speaker 1:  Brian Armstrong, the CEO of Coinbase, who like could not
Speaker 1:  have reacted quicker to distance Coinbase from FTX. And
Speaker 1:  even he was like, we looked at it and oh boy, it's bad news. Meanwhile
Speaker 1:  Coinbase is, doc is down like 80% this year. Like it's, it's been a disaster
Speaker 1:  for everybody. And even he is coming out being like, Oh I, I wouldn't touch
Speaker 1:  that with a 10 foot pole. Yeah, it's
Speaker 6:  Rough. I would imagine now that the midterms over the politics are down
Speaker 6:  well down the, Yeah we're down to a low boil
Speaker 6:  of American democracy. Not a full rolling boil. Yeah, it's still
Speaker 6:  hotter than you'd like
Speaker 5:  Supreme Court announced a case soon we'll be back at it.
Speaker 6:  But you imagine that a crypto regulation is gonna pick up in Congress cuz
Speaker 6:  a lot of famous people just got wrecked by some shady crypto
Speaker 6:  dealings that is gonna require some regulation people from doing. How
Speaker 5:  Many politicians do you think got
Speaker 6:  Wrecked? That's the story. Yeah. If you're a politician and you got
Speaker 6:  wrecked by ftx,
Speaker 5:  Send us your bill.
Speaker 6:  Yes. Just let us know. We'd love to write about it. We should end on some
Speaker 6:  GAD news end on a high note also. We gotta check Twitter to see if anything
Speaker 6:  else changed in Twitter in the last five minutes. The answer is yes, but
Speaker 6:  you'll have to check the ver.com to see what happened. We should with some
Speaker 6:  GA stuff. Yeah. Monica reviewed the service Pro nine. I would say that
Speaker 6:  Microsoft's attempt to put an arm ship in a service laptop cause once again
Speaker 6:  been fell and Monica says you should just buy the Intel one. Great.
Speaker 6:  It was very pretty. She had, we're in the office, we saw I got to play with
Speaker 6:  it for half a second yesterday when she was in a meeting with me. It's beautiful.
Speaker 6:  You just get that laptop or you should get the surface on.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, Microsoft has like done everything with the surface that you would
Speaker 1:  want it to do except make like that next leap to this next
Speaker 1:  magical place of great battery life and perfect connectivity. But in terms
Speaker 1:  of like regular old surface things, it's like they, they continue
Speaker 1:  to be very good. Seems nice. If you wanna surface by this surface it's very
Speaker 1:  good. Yeah. Like that's all you can ask for.
Speaker 6:  LG has a stretchable display now.
Speaker 5:  LG display.
Speaker 6:  Oh not lg. Lg. LG display.
Speaker 5:  LG display. They have very different PR companies and they get really,
Speaker 5:  they're fine actually if you confuse them but they cannot help you. But yeah,
Speaker 5:  LG display has a stretchable prototype that hopefully
Speaker 5:  we'll be seeing at ces. Hopefully that will be one of the things LG display
Speaker 5:  shows off and it's different because you know, they've done rollable and
Speaker 5:  they've done like foldable and this is more like you could
Speaker 5:  theoretically put this on clothes or furniture. I,
Speaker 5:  I think that's a ways off. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  But would the furniture be like those vinyl covers that like grandma's used
Speaker 5:  To have? I think so. I think it would be like,
Speaker 6:  Yeah, like, like animated florals on the
Speaker 5:  Couch. Just like a mouth opening as you go to sit down. Absolutely
Speaker 6:  Not. That's pretty good. Monica also review the HQ affiliate plus 14. I just
Speaker 6:  like OED laptops and I will read any review of an OED laptop. Just something,
Speaker 6:  I just want one. I'm like, and this is not the one apparently it's, she said
Speaker 6:  it was very confusing but shouldn't, shouldn't we just be at a place where
Speaker 6:  Ed's and laptops sort of thing like all the time.
Speaker 1:  Well I just, I like this one cuz it, it got the o led part right. And the
Speaker 1:  laptop part wrong. Like what if the screen was really
Speaker 1:  good but the laptop felt like it was gonna break every time you
Speaker 1:  picked it up or touched it. It's like well yeah, we've, we've done,
Speaker 1:  we've done the hard part. Right, but you kind of forgot about the easy part.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. But the screen does look really nice.
Speaker 6:  Pixel watch already bug and how it counts calories
Speaker 6:  amazing.
Speaker 5:  Wow. Shocking. Just shocking.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. All that AI and they're like, we know we're bad at counting. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  that's good.
Speaker 5:  A very expensive controller is coming from this is where
Speaker 6:  End. Yeah. Tell
Speaker 5:  Tell me about this. Yeah, I'm, I'm a little excited about this cuz for years
Speaker 5:  you could not get a really customizable controller for, for Sony
Speaker 5:  products. You had to go to SC SCUFF was basically it and they would
Speaker 5:  modify them themselves. But we started to see more of these and this is
Speaker 5:  kind of like the Microsoft Xbox controller
Speaker 5:  Elite I believe is the name, the elite controller. And
Speaker 5:  this is the Wolverine version two pro.
Speaker 5:  I think that's what the V stands for. It's the Wolverine V2
Speaker 5:  Pro $250 and
Speaker 5:  still more expensive than Sony's own first party super
Speaker 5:  fancy customizable controller.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, this thing looks like a chunk. It
Speaker 5:  Looks like a big boy.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I immediately think of Kirby, the
Speaker 1:  entire character. Every single time I look at this, it's just, it's it's
Speaker 1:  a Kirby controller. I love this thing and I love what Razor is doing where
Speaker 1:  they're like, oh there's a lot of gaming stuff out there. What if we made
Speaker 1:  something that was so much more aggressive than
Speaker 1:  anything else you've ever had? Is that something you'd be interested in?
Speaker 1:  And it turns out the answer is yes. Yes. And this is like, this is what Razor
Speaker 1:  has always done well. They're just like, here's some like deeply
Speaker 1:  like capital E, extra gaming gear.
Speaker 1:  Would you like that? And I'm like, yes, I would.
Speaker 5:  Thank you. I do have one concern about it cuz it looks like the, the handles
Speaker 5:  on the side, it's called
Speaker 1:  The Wolverine might be what's, what's there to be The
Speaker 5:  Last Wolverine was great. The last Wolverine was wonderful. The buttons were
Speaker 5:  really nice. Some of the best buttons in these kind of controllers. But this
Speaker 5:  one looks like it might have a different texture on the sides. And I'm not
Speaker 5:  about that. I want like the smooth, sweaty plastic texture
Speaker 5:  everywhere. Gross. I don't want, I don't want like
Speaker 1:  I'm actually with Alex on this. If it's not like slipping out of my hands
Speaker 1:  all the time, I'm not
Speaker 5:  Interested. Yeah, yeah. I don't want sticky controllers.
Speaker 6:  Oh, I see what you mean. Yeah. This is But this looks like a textured
Speaker 5:  Plastic. Yeah, I'm hoping that's what it is. It's got a lot of lights on
Speaker 5:  it. You can expect the buttons to be pretty good. The triggers on the back
Speaker 5:  are different. A lot of people do these like flipper style triggers, but
Speaker 5:  there's
Speaker 1:  Four
Speaker 5:  Triggers. Oh yeah, four triggers.
Speaker 1:  I'm looking at this picture, it looks like there's four
Speaker 5:  Triggers. Oh yeah.
Speaker 1:  Hell yeah. Dude.
Speaker 5:  They're all programmable. So you should be able to like be like, I wanna
Speaker 5:  jump by just using my middle finger on the back of the controller and do
Speaker 5:  it. But then you have to like train your body to remember that. That's why
Speaker 5:  I never can use them because I always forget. And then I'm like, why am I
Speaker 5:  jumping so much? And I'm like, oh it's, I've just been holding this trigger
Speaker 5:  on my back.
Speaker 1:  I'm gonna buy this just to play skateboarding games on Apple arcade and it's
Speaker 1:  gonna be absolutely glorious. Just ripping it. I have zero regrets.
Speaker 5:  $250. All
Speaker 1:  Right. The most overkill possible move. I'm all in. I
Speaker 6:  Love it. We should end there on overkill controllers with RGB
Speaker 6:  lights. I'm so excited. We gotta end on a high note. Yeah, there's like other
Speaker 6:  stuff to talk about, but we gotta,
Speaker 5:  The thing that's not collapsing is customizable
Speaker 5:  controllers for your PS
Speaker 6:  Five gamer lights are the one thing you can rely on in 2022. America
Speaker 6:  invest, you get in, buy high,
Speaker 6:  don't sell
Speaker 5:  Hold gamer
Speaker 6:  Lights. All right. That's it. That's a verge cast. Somehow
Speaker 6:  we've gone over but we're still right on time. Yes. That's what that feels
Speaker 6:  like to me. Nailed it. We got right to where we need to be. We're gonna just
Speaker 6:  have Twitter coverage. Look, we made our entire site look like Twitter,
Speaker 6:  right? Because we wanted to move faster. Prettier close.
Speaker 6:  Little did we know that the perfect use for our new product would be
Speaker 6:  covering Twitter. It's not what I expected, but it's working
Speaker 6:  out. The site's a lot of fun. It's every minute of
Speaker 6:  every day. Also first little tweak to the redesign and come in next week.
Speaker 6:  Ooh. I think people, I think people are gonna like,
Speaker 5:  I think so too.
Speaker 6:  We're we're gonna bring back some, We're gonna bring back some old flows.
Speaker 6:  You're gonna, you're gonna like it, but we're still have the new flow. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It's gonna be sick.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it's, you're gonna like it, but just check out cause
Speaker 6:  it's every minute, every minute of every day. Something's crazy happening.
Speaker 6:  And who knows how long Twitter will stay around. What's your over under
Speaker 6:  90 days?
Speaker 5:  120.
Speaker 6:  120. So one more month. Okay. What do you got?
Speaker 1:  It's, it's not going anywhere. I'll take, I'll take any over. You give me,
Speaker 1:  but will I be there in 120 days? No.
Speaker 6:  Just like
Speaker 1:  I've already drafted the like, you know what everybody does the like, here
Speaker 1:  are all the other ways you can reach me. Not on Twitter tweet. I have drafted
Speaker 1:  that like three or four times already in the last week. And then every time
Speaker 1:  I type it on, then I'm like, who am I kidding? I'm not done with Twitter.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. But one of these days I'm gonna send that tweet and be done with Twitter.
Speaker 6:  And the place you're gonna find us is the Verge Doc. We're gonna add comments
Speaker 6:  to the quick posts,
Speaker 5:  But Reckless Patel will be there, Reckless Patel until the end.
Speaker 6:  Right? We gotta wrap this up. Here's my last, if any of you know Mariah
Speaker 6:  care,
Speaker 6:  you know, like I hadn't thought about it a long time, but if,
Speaker 6:  you know, just let me know.
Speaker 5:  Slide into those dms.
Speaker 6:  It's Christmas time. That's all I'm say
Speaker 1:  This is, no one should underestimate this NE's
Speaker 1:  entire profile and career success has built to the moment where
Speaker 1:  he can ask a lot of people to get him in touch with Mariah Care. This is
Speaker 1:  that moment. Do not let him
Speaker 5:  Cheer for me. Let him shoot his shot.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I think actually like the funniest thing about this, like I think Becky
Speaker 6:  like would like to be in the room
Speaker 5:  Shoot phone just slowly come up record.
Speaker 6:  She'd be like, I know what this is, but I wanna watch a good down. I've known
Speaker 6:  her since I was 18 years old. She's gonna be like, I want be in that room.
Speaker 6:  All right. That's it. That's the ver again, if you know Mariah, just
Speaker 6:  let it be known. She's a business. She can come on to go
Speaker 5:  Hit him up at at Red,
Speaker 6:  That's, that's a Verge chest rock and roll. And also the sweet DT sounds
Speaker 6:  of Mariah.
Speaker 12:  And that's a wrap for Vergecast this week. Thanks for listening. If you
Speaker 12:  enjoy the show, subscribe in the podcast app of your choice or tell a friend,
Speaker 12:  you can send us feedback at vergecast@theverge.com. This show is
Speaker 12:  produced by me, Liam James, and our senior audio director, Andrew Marino.
Speaker 12:  This episode was edited and mixed by Amanda Rose
Speaker 12:  Smith. Our editorial director is Brooke Miners and our executive producer
Speaker 12:  is Eleanor Donovan. The Verge Cast is a production of the Verge and
Speaker 12:  Box Media podcast network. And that's it. We'll see you next week.