# Transcript
ID: d372b6a0-2dbe-11ed-8a44-39a86fcd7092
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: The future of Apple: our biggest questions and hottest takes
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/5114846044506699269/5038972409907799123/s93290-US-4137s-1662453231.mp3
Description: The Verge's David Pierce, Nilay Patel, and Alex Cranz each discuss the big open questions they have about the future of Apple, and the hottest takes about the company.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (6 ads detected)
Speaker 2:  Welcome to the Vergecast the flagship podcast of planned obsolescence. I'm
Speaker 2:  your friend, David Pierce. And as you probably know, there's a big apple
Speaker 2:  event coming up really soon. We're expecting new iPhones, new apple
Speaker 2:  watches, probably new AirPods, a bunch of new software, all kinds of stuff
Speaker 2:  coming. And that means it is time for what I have come to consider my
Speaker 2:  annual moral obligation, which is to go to the mall, go to the apple store
Speaker 2:  and tell everybody who's shopping for phones, not to buy a phone because
Speaker 2:  there's a new one. Just about to come out. We are also going to be spending
Speaker 2:  this show, talking about apple, but not so much the event. We didn't want
Speaker 2:  to make a bunch of predictions that turn out to be totally wrong or have
Speaker 2:  feelings about things we don't even necessarily know are coming yet. So we're
Speaker 2:  going to save that all for the Friday show. It's going to be a big one on
Speaker 2:  this show. We're going to talk more about apple in general. It's the most
Speaker 2:  valuable company on earth. It makes some of the most influential products
Speaker 2:  that anyone uses, and we want to get into where the company is right
Speaker 2:  now. What changes for apple now that it's so big and so popular? What are
Speaker 2:  the next big products for apple? Why is apple so obsessed with making TVs?
Speaker 2:  Why is Nila is so obsessed with apple being obsessed with making TVs? We're
Speaker 2:  going to get into all of that. I gave Nila and Alex some homework, which
Speaker 2:  was to come with big questions and just spicy,
Speaker 2:  spicy takes. And we're going to dig into all of the things we want to know
Speaker 2:  about the future of apple. But first, before we get to all of that, I need
Speaker 2:  to go save this person who looks like they're about to buy an iPhone 12,
Speaker 2:  which just honestly seems like a terrible idea. This is the Vergecast, we'll
Speaker 2:  be right back
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. Okay. Apple questions, apple hot takes. Let's do
Speaker 2:  this Nila. Hello? Hey buddy. Alex. Hello.
Speaker 2:  Hi. Both of you had homework, which was to come with
Speaker 2:  five big or small, but like open questions
Speaker 2:  about apple things you think are interesting going forward that we're paying
Speaker 2:  attention to. And we're going to talk about them and see if we have answers
Speaker 2:  for any of them. And then too, I think I called them overheated
Speaker 2:  takes, and I should just say right off the top, I'm just ruthlessly stealing
Speaker 2:  this from the ringer, done their fantasy football show. They have a thing
Speaker 2:  called the take purge, which is just a whole episode where the hosts
Speaker 2:  just say the things that they don't actually believe, but feel deep in their
Speaker 2:  bones anyway. So we're just going to, we're going to steal that from them
Speaker 2:  and do some overheat. It takes that you don't really believe, but you kind
Speaker 2:  of believe Alex, you started last, you did your
Speaker 2:  homework while we were sitting here getting ready to record. So you get to
Speaker 2:  go first. You get to present first because that's what the cool teacher does
Speaker 2:  is try to terrorize you in front of everybody.
Speaker 4:  I really want to know why everybody won't shut up about an apple car that
Speaker 4:  I have yet to see.
Speaker 2:  This was one of mine too, which is why am I supposed to care that the
Speaker 2:  apple car is a thing?
Speaker 4:  Like I can't care about it. It's hard.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I mean, at this point, apple could just fall along with every other
Speaker 5:  car maker and just show us a 3d render of a car and be like, here's our
Speaker 5:  car. They would just match what every other car maker is doing. Give us a
Speaker 5:  hundred dollars on a pre-order in two years from now, maybe we'll ship a
Speaker 5:  car. And like, maybe that's actually a great business
Speaker 5:  model. I think a lot of people will give them a hundred bucks for a vendor.
Speaker 5:  I will answer your question with my first question has that. Yes. I think
Speaker 5:  this is a biggest open question for apple. Can they find another market?
Speaker 5:  That's big enough to make a dent and is that even the thing they should do?
Speaker 5:  So the reason they are chasing cars and the reason they are chasing health
Speaker 5:  and the reason they're chasing everything else they're doing is because
Speaker 5:  they need something that will generate enough money to be
Speaker 5:  like 10% of the biggest company that has ever existed on earth. And the
Speaker 5:  only way you can do that is if you eat a whole industry,
Speaker 4:  I know the industry though, it shouldn't be cars.
Speaker 5:  It's a,
Speaker 4:  It should be federal government, like
Speaker 4:  systems, like, you know, they, they got COBOL and all that stuff.
Speaker 4:  That's, that's basically dead. Nobody's running it. Apple could be that
Speaker 4:  company. Apple could do that.
Speaker 5:  It's all going to be swift UI. The buttons won't make any sense. Be every
Speaker 5:  couple of years, it'll change for no reason. Have you ever wanted to do an
Speaker 5:  insurance claim in piles? Now you can like, but that's, that's
Speaker 5:  their problem, right? Like the answer to why are they doing a car? Is the
Speaker 5:  car industry is big enough so that if you become a dominant player
Speaker 5:  in cars, you can tell your investors. You can tell your
Speaker 5:  employees. You can tell everybody who makes money on your stock. We have
Speaker 5:  growth here. That is meaningful. Yeah. I mean like every question I'm
Speaker 5:  asking, by the way, David, this is my warning to you. All of my
Speaker 5:  questions are just, will they make a TV expressed in slightly different ways?
Speaker 2:  That's good. Cause that's about half of mine too. So it's gonna be fine.
Speaker 2:  But no, I think it's funny. You bring that up. Cause I I've been rereading
Speaker 2:  the new, new thing, which is Michael Lewis's book from like the late nineties
Speaker 2:  about Jim Clark who founded Netscape. And it is like precisely
Speaker 2:  what you're describing. It's like guy starts a computer company gets very
Speaker 2:  big. Guy goes, okay, well what do I do next? I have to top that somehow.
Speaker 2:  So he starts an internet company, which feels very big, get, make some, a
Speaker 2:  lot of money gets very excited. And then he's like, okay, well what do I
Speaker 2:  do next? I have to build something even bigger. And he goes healthcare. And
Speaker 2:  it's just like, that is the thing, right? It is like, it is this massive
Speaker 2:  industry that seems like it's a mess. And everyone who is like, well, if
Speaker 2:  I can just take a slice of that, I can make a lot of money and I seem smart.
Speaker 2:  So I bet I can convince somebody that this is plausible. It's like, there's
Speaker 2:  only a handful of those. And I feel like cars is one of them and
Speaker 2:  health is one of them. And so it makes sense that apple just has to keep
Speaker 2:  like pointing at those things how serious it is, is hard to
Speaker 2:  know. It seems very serious in a way that you can be very serious when you're
Speaker 2:  the richest company on planet earth. But I don't know how much
Speaker 2:  I'm supposed to believe that there is ever going to be like a good car that
Speaker 2:  people care about and drive that apple makes, I have no idea.
Speaker 4:  Couldn't it be like Sony? And they just like pivot to party
Speaker 4:  speakers
Speaker 5:  As always. I renew my call that if you are on the Sony party speaker team
Speaker 5:  and you've been in the meeting in which the third generation of party speakers
Speaker 5:  has been greenlit, I'll give you the whole show. You'll get a week long of
Speaker 5:  at Vergecast episodes just to talk about that product. So Sony is like the
Speaker 5:  classic example though. We don't perceive Sony this way in this
Speaker 5:  country, but Sony historically its balance sheet
Speaker 5:  is it's a big insurance company in Japan that happens
Speaker 5:  to make TVs and party speakers, right? And they pivoted that
Speaker 5:  company to a much larger business because the
Speaker 5:  consumer business was fading. And that's like, I don't think apple should
Speaker 5:  sell life insurance, which is something Sony sells in Japan.
Speaker 5:  But you can see why they're moving in the same general direction,
Speaker 5:  which are, what are the next biggest industries? And we had trip metal on
Speaker 5:  the verge house several months ago. I was just flipping through his book
Speaker 5:  again about apple after Steve, which is excellent. And like, this is
Speaker 5:  explicit in Apple's thought process in Tim Cook's thought
Speaker 5:  process. What is the next biggest market I can go after? Right?
Speaker 5:  Because we, in order to grow, we have to attack the big markets. That
Speaker 5:  is what led to the car. It is what has led to a bunch of their health efforts,
Speaker 5:  which by the way, everyone also keeps talking about and has generated virtually
Speaker 5:  nothing. And to some extent, it's why they went to watches instead of
Speaker 5:  TVs.
Speaker 4:  Well, and it's also why they went to entertainment, right? Like it's why
Speaker 4:  they went into that space to
Speaker 5:  Yeah. That's why they went to services. Yep. They were just chasing
Speaker 5:  revenue. And I don't mean like usually when we say that, we mean that is
Speaker 5:  like cynically as possible, but in the case of apple, like they
Speaker 5:  really had to go chase growth because they were already so big
Speaker 5:  that trying to find another category as big as the iPhone was a less good
Speaker 5:  option than selling iPhone customers. More things
Speaker 4:  Like, I guess this is not one of my five questions. This is a
Speaker 4:  brand new, fresh question. Oh
Speaker 5:  Boy.
Speaker 4:  Why are they pursuing these really known
Speaker 4:  categories when they effectively invented some
Speaker 4:  categories? Right? Like apple figured those out and did them really well.
Speaker 4:  And in these other cases, apple is going to like places where there's a really
Speaker 4:  established competitors, like what is the disruption to
Speaker 4:  be had? And Apple's like, I know we're going to disrupt cars.
Speaker 4:  There's feels like there's lower hanging fruit to go disrupt.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. But they're all smaller. I think that's even the TV industry is like
Speaker 5:  too small. That's why apple won't do it. Right. And it's th that doesn't
Speaker 5:  turn over enough and people aren't shopping on their TVs enough. Like they
Speaker 5:  can't make the case that getting that screen in everyone's living room
Speaker 5:  is more valuable than the screen they already have in everyone's living room,
Speaker 5:  which is the phone. Right. So they might as well just put their software
Speaker 5:  on other people's hardware and then do whatever they're going to do there.
Speaker 5:  Right. There just aren't many industries that are bigger than the
Speaker 5:  iPhone. And so like, they are, you know, they are inventing, you know,
Speaker 5:  AR glasses. We know they are heard about them. They're going to start with
Speaker 5:  mixed reality. And they're trying to invent a big new category. I just think
Speaker 5:  in the meantime, cause that's going to take a long time in the meantime,
Speaker 5:  right? They're trying to run some of the playbook that they've run, which
Speaker 5:  is everybody hates the software in their car. What if apple did it? Everybody
Speaker 5:  hates their mobile phone when apple, like they want apple to
Speaker 5:  replace their razor.
Speaker 2:  Speaking of big industries, that apple should be playing more into my first
Speaker 2:  question, which is when is apple going to get like actually serious about
Speaker 2:  winning at video games? Video games is a gigantic industry. Apple
Speaker 2:  arcade is like kind of working. And to me it's like stop making
Speaker 2:  fancy TV shows that win awards, but nobody cares about, and like go
Speaker 2:  buy some video games, like make me a game console,
Speaker 2:  do a game streaming thing. Like give one whole shit about gaming. And it
Speaker 2:  seems like apple has like real moves to make here.
Speaker 4:  I think there's a lot of problems though. Right? Microsoft and other companies
Speaker 4:  have consolidated that industry a lot. It's a lot smaller industry than it
Speaker 4:  was. And we talked about indie games and everything, but indie games are
Speaker 4:  a relatively small piece of that puzzle. Most people are like call of duty
Speaker 4:  and all of that. And Microsoft is up there being like, Nope, we'll take that.
Speaker 4:  We'll take that. And also they're watching Google.
Speaker 4:  They've seen like Google went and was like, yeah, we're going to get serious
Speaker 4:  about video games. And for most people serious equates with consoles and
Speaker 4:  doing these big immersive, you know, 20 hour experiences,
Speaker 4:  not what Apple's really good at, which is mobile gaming. And I think they're
Speaker 4:  the biggest in mobile gaming. They're the most successful. So if that
Speaker 4:  serious is console gaming, that would be so bad for them.
Speaker 5:  Well, I mean, there's still a lot of transactions that take place in consoles,
Speaker 5:  right? The future of all this though, it has to be streaming. So they're
Speaker 5:  going to do something. I don't think they're going to ship AMD
Speaker 5:  processors in a box that runs an operating system that
Speaker 5:  is, will largely irrelevant to them playing a game
Speaker 2:  Apple's version of game pass feels like where it would have to go.
Speaker 4:  Isn't that arcade?
Speaker 5:  It is, but that's for mobile games. I think David's question is like, why
Speaker 5:  is it that this huge industry that's growing primarily based on
Speaker 5:  microtransactions, right? Fortnite is free and you buy stuff in Fortnite.
Speaker 5:  Like the apple and epic are in a gigantic fight over the fees of buying things
Speaker 5:  in fortnight. But epic happily pays the fees to Sony in epic. Happily pays
Speaker 5:  the fees to Microsoft. Why won't apple get to that next
Speaker 5:  turn and be like, now, when you play games in your living room,
Speaker 5:  aren't you paying us fees. And I think the answer is they just
Speaker 5:  can't see it. Like it's been three decades of this
Speaker 5:  question, right? They deprecated open GL. They went with
Speaker 5:  metal, no one went to metal with them. They had their own wacky GPU
Speaker 5:  ideas. The industries, they hate Nvidia. They just hate
Speaker 5:  Nvidia. At one time, Nvidia made some GPU's that made Mac books get hot and
Speaker 5:  apple is never free. And there was a recall and Apple's never forgiven that
Speaker 5:  company. And they're like, literally is dead to them. It's 100% what
Speaker 5:  happened. And it's just like their aversion to the two,
Speaker 5:  doing the foundational work to be good at games in the current
Speaker 5:  ecosystem of games has kept them away from forever. I don't think they're
Speaker 5:  averse to let's build a data center and run games there and
Speaker 5:  stream them to you. But even that data center, what do you need to fill it
Speaker 5:  full of other people's GPU's you need that data center probably needs to
Speaker 5:  run open. Like it needs to run direct X, like whatever it is, the games
Speaker 5:  run on, because none of Apple's foundational technologies can run the games.
Speaker 4:  It comes down to that courting of those, those developers and
Speaker 4:  those studios. Right. And apple has very little interest there.
Speaker 4:  Like they they've worked with them, they got Capcom to do stuff. They've
Speaker 4:  gotten these big studios that we all know to do. Some
Speaker 4:  development, produce some games for arcade, but they're a
Speaker 4:  meme in, in the game development space. Everybody's like, oh yeah, apple,
Speaker 4:  one day they'll do gaming. And I don't know how apple could ever
Speaker 4:  show that it's serious enough for them to believe it. Especially after we
Speaker 4:  saw like Google, be like, yeah, we're serious about gaming and
Speaker 4:  stadia frequently becomes a punchline. Sorry. So when I say,
Speaker 4:  oh, no one mentioned stadia on this. A bunch of stadia fans come into my
Speaker 4:  Twitter to say that I clearly hate stadia.
Speaker 2:  All four of them that exist. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  All four of them are, they're saying I hate stadia, but
Speaker 4:  like it's, you know, big tech has kind of shown that they want to be
Speaker 4:  interested in this space because they know it's funny, Amazon's doing the
Speaker 4:  same thing with Luna. Right. And they're doing it really badly. The
Speaker 4:  Stu everybody isn't participating the few who are like Ubisoft, one of
Speaker 4:  the biggest game development studios. Yeah. They'll do it. There'll be on
Speaker 4:  everything. Sure. You can play Assassin's creed on every device that was
Speaker 4:  ever made
Speaker 5:  And notably Ubisoft as an indie. Right. I mean, they need
Speaker 5:  that widespread support.
Speaker 4:  And most like the consolidation of the industry means that it's just really
Speaker 4:  hard for apple, even if it did decide to be serious about it. And
Speaker 4:  Microsoft is just this elephant in the room,
Speaker 2:  Alex, I think to your point, like the 30 years of not doing this is a
Speaker 2:  really interesting point that I had not thought of. Cause it seems to me
Speaker 2:  like what we're talking about streaming is like, this is the moment, right?
Speaker 2:  Like if you're ever going to say we apple are serious about like turning
Speaker 2:  the apple TV into a game console, which they've like hinted at before, I'd
Speaker 2:  never done in any real way. Game streaming would be the moment to be like
Speaker 2:  this technology all exists. We have an unusual ability to make it all
Speaker 2:  work. And I, one of my like throw away overly hot
Speaker 2:  takes was that if apple and epic weren't being sued,
Speaker 2:  apple would have just bought epic by now, which I have no reason to believe.
Speaker 2:  That's true. But it's just like, that is a neat solution to a lot of like
Speaker 2:  things that apple wants to be in the future. I, it is an interesting point.
Speaker 2:  I wonder if anyone would take apple seriously, if they were like, we care
Speaker 2:  about games now everybody like, yeah. Okay.
Speaker 4:  They also did this big fight too. Right? They did this fight with Microsoft
Speaker 4:  and Sadia and all the other streamers where they were like, no, we don't
Speaker 4:  want you on our service because we don't get a cut of it. And you bypass
Speaker 4:  us entirely. We don't want that. And they were all like, yes, we are not
Speaker 4:  going to give you a cut of a $60 game that somebody buys on our service F
Speaker 4:  off. We're just going to run out of the browser. And I think apple has to
Speaker 4:  make a really compelling case for why these companies don't need to run off
Speaker 4:  the browser anymore. And apple, isn't going to do that because apple wants
Speaker 4:  a cut of the money. And what is the cut that Microsoft and
Speaker 4:  Google are willing to say? Yeah, I'll pay that to get my stuff on the apple
Speaker 4:  TV.
Speaker 5:  Well, so I'll give you this example though. Microsoft is going to ship
Speaker 5:  X-Box game, pass the streaming version. There's like a lot of bad
Speaker 5:  names in Microsoft world. So Xbox streaming, let's just call it that
Speaker 5:  they have been hinting. Phil Spencer's said it on decoder. Like
Speaker 5:  they're gonna put it on smart TVs. Yeah. It's coming. And so that's a
Speaker 5:  deal you gotta make with a smart TV vendor. You got to go to a Samsung and
Speaker 5:  LG and Sony, whoever and say, okay, we're going to start
Speaker 5:  transacting on your platform. And you know, there's some business relationship
Speaker 5:  there for sure. You could make that deal with an apple. Microsoft could make
Speaker 5:  that deal with an apple and say, okay, we want to be in your box too. And
Speaker 5:  we want to string games and apple could make that deal with Microsoft and
Speaker 5:  say, okay, like, please don't take office away. We'll let you onto our
Speaker 5:  thing. Like there's a lot of leverage on both sides of that agreement, right?
Speaker 5:  On both sides of that relationship. And what are the terms who knows the
Speaker 5:  hard part for apple is apple now runs
Speaker 5:  effectively a nation state on its phone,
Speaker 5:  where it makes effectively legal
Speaker 5:  decisions. And there's a lot of government regulators and
Speaker 5:  lawsuits that look at those decisions and epic will say, why
Speaker 5:  does Microsoft get this preferred treatment? And we don't and
Speaker 5:  Google will say it, and Amazon will say it. And once you do that, now you've
Speaker 5:  just opened the door to it, to game streaming on your platform. And you don't
Speaker 5:  get to see inside of the transactions. And I think apple is just like kind
Speaker 5:  of hamstrung to make a, what should be a no-brainer deal
Speaker 5:  with Microsoft to say, X-Box games streaming now available
Speaker 5:  on the iPhone. And that's kind of a no brainer deal for Microsoft,
Speaker 5:  right? Like, but I think the larger context is then
Speaker 5:  people on a podcast like this will show up and say, what is game streaming?
Speaker 5:  And why? Like, why doesn't it? Why, why can't I stream apps to the
Speaker 5:  phone and transact inside of the apps? Like, what is it, what is a
Speaker 5:  game, but a type of application, right? And you just end up apple in
Speaker 5:  particular right now ends up having to defend these very fine
Speaker 5:  gradations between the kinds of code that run on its platform.
Speaker 2:  It makes sense. Okay. We should keep moving. Nia. We like only
Speaker 2:  halfway did your questions to give us another one. What's what's on your
Speaker 2:  list.
Speaker 5:  Well, this one just says, why don't you build a
Speaker 5:  TV on this thread? I think apple
Speaker 5:  overreacts to external competitors, the iPhone a lot. Yes.
Speaker 5:  They tow into things and then they, they realize it's not a real
Speaker 5:  threat. And then they back off in the product fails. And the thing I'm
Speaker 5:  specifically thinking about is the home pod, right? They were early with
Speaker 5:  Siri and then Amazon shut up with Alexa and Google shut up with
Speaker 5:  assistant and apple completely overreacts to it. Right? They think series
Speaker 5:  should do all the same things. Those products should do. They rush out the
Speaker 5:  home pod, which had been brewing in the background forever and they
Speaker 5:  couldn't get it together. And they finally are like, all right, we're just
Speaker 5:  gonna let this team do it. And they ship it. And then they're like, wait,
Speaker 5:  these things are not actually eating the iPhone. It turns out an Amazon,
Speaker 5:  Alexa is not a viable replacement for the iPhone, even in
Speaker 5:  your home. It's, they're very useful. And people like them and
Speaker 5:  Amazon is, it has nowhere else to bet. So it's going to bet on it. I don't
Speaker 5:  know what Google is doing this assistant neglecting it, I think is the
Speaker 5:  answer it's
Speaker 2:  Around,
Speaker 5:  It's around, but you just see apple kind of like rushed itself into a corner
Speaker 5:  and then forgot to iterate because there was no, the pressure didn't actually
Speaker 5:  exist to compete. And I think this is just sort of a pattern with them. And
Speaker 5:  so the one I would give you right now is we keep hearing about AR
Speaker 5:  from literally mark Zuckerberg on the short Rogan podcast. And
Speaker 5:  apple seems like they're gonna get to market with a super
Speaker 5:  expensive mixed reality headset. I'll see if it's reported on it. And it
Speaker 5:  just feels like, are they, is this also an overreaction? Yes. Is it?
Speaker 5:  They're so afraid of not being dominant in the end that they're
Speaker 5:  gonna make a move and then recognize the pressure isn't there. And then like,
Speaker 5:  let it wither away, which I think is more or less what happened at home.
Speaker 2:  I would also put the watch in that category as things that were kind
Speaker 2:  of an overreaction to what apple saw as the thing that
Speaker 2:  might kill the iPhone. Like there was, there was that moment where it was
Speaker 2:  like, okay, the future of this all is wearables, right? It's like biometric
Speaker 2:  sensing, more accessible computers on your body. And that was
Speaker 2:  the thing that was going to kill the iPhone. As we've discussed many times
Speaker 5:  Tablets. I think they did that to the Mac in some way. Right. They went all
Speaker 5:  in on tablets. Cause I thought it was going to eat the Mac. And then it turns
Speaker 5:  out the Mac was surprising, re resilient,
Speaker 2:  And then they made the mat good again. And people liked it. Like it turns
Speaker 2:  out if you just make it good, people will like it. No, I mean, I think the,
Speaker 2:  the flip side of that is that the iPhone has been like
Speaker 2:  astoundingly durable over time. Like a lot of things have shown up and
Speaker 2:  nothing has even been any kind of real threat. If anything
Speaker 2:  else, everything else that has happened has like entrenched the smartphone
Speaker 2:  because it is now like the center of all of these universes that like you
Speaker 2:  manage Alexa on your phone. Like, that's how you do Alexa. You
Speaker 2:  talk to it on the thing. But you do all the Alexa work on your phone.
Speaker 2:  And apple has always talked about this, right? That like, if you don't cannibalize
Speaker 2:  your own stuff, somebody else will. But it does kind of feel like
Speaker 2:  apple is, is like chasing its own demise. Even when it's not
Speaker 2:  there, like sees boogeyman everywhere.
Speaker 5:  If you don't cannibalize your own thing, somebody else was as a statement
Speaker 5:  of confidence. Sure. We know what's next. We're going to make the thing.
Speaker 5:  That's so good that people won't buy the old thing anymore. And usually the
Speaker 5:  times they have said that we're Steve jobs introducing a slightly
Speaker 5:  smaller iPod. Yeah. It's just like
Speaker 5:  historically when apple says that thing, it's
Speaker 5:  right. They made a big thing. And now they've made a small thing. That's
Speaker 5:  like 85% as good as the big thing. Like that's the iPod to the iPad mini
Speaker 5:  that's the mini to the nano, you know, Mac book to Mac book air, right? Like
Speaker 5:  there's a pattern to when they say that, but it's usually within the same
Speaker 5:  category. They've rarely done it outside the category, even the
Speaker 5:  iPhone. So the Mac book wasn't that thing in that
Speaker 5:  moment. Right? They were like, here's a phone, you have to plug it into your
Speaker 5:  computer to set it up. It took a decade to get
Speaker 5:  there. And so I just think lately apple has been, it's been reactive to
Speaker 5:  perceived threats instead of creating its own. I mean, this is my other
Speaker 5:  big question is who will take, take over after Tim cook?
Speaker 2:  Ooh. Okay, wait, let's come back to that one. First. We're going to take
Speaker 2:  a break. We'll be right
Speaker 2:  back.
Speaker 2:  We're back. Okay. So who takes over after Tim cook? Do you have a theory
Speaker 2:  on this or is this just a genuinely open question?
Speaker 5:  My, my theory is that a chef Williams,
Speaker 7:  We just focused on making products that we're excited about and let the
Speaker 7:  chips fall where they may.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. That's he seems to be like the leader in the clubhouse. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It seems like the leader in the clubhouse, everyone really likes him. He's
Speaker 5:  been becoming more and more prominent, which is a very only apple cuts. That
Speaker 5:  kind of attention. Right. You can measure the amount of minutes people get
Speaker 5:  on stage right back. I'll be the new CEO. Like no other company does that
Speaker 5:  or very few. But Jeff Williams is almost as old as Tim cook.
Speaker 4:  That seems to be like the big reasoning, right. That everybody says he's
Speaker 4:  not going to be. The person is because we'd be just having the conversation
Speaker 4:  in two years.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Or, or five or whatever. I mean, they're not like elderly. There's
Speaker 5:  no like 60 five-year-old apple. It's not a 1960s iron
Speaker 5:  planet or whatever. Take your watch and leave. Yeah, exactly. It's him
Speaker 5:  cook. Keep going. He's told care social in the past, he doesn't expect to
Speaker 5:  be doing it for another 10 years. So there is some sort of looming event.
Speaker 5:  Jeff Williams is a natural choice, but again, it's are you getting five years?
Speaker 5:  Are you getting 15 years? It will he be as successful? Right? Like every
Speaker 5:  leader changes the culture of the organization. That's just true. Again,
Speaker 5:  Tripp's book is basically a book about how Tim cook changed the culture of
Speaker 5:  apple to focus more on growing products are still good, but like
Speaker 5:  that's the whole book. Yeah. I think it is a remarkable open
Speaker 5:  question because Tim cook inherited the company
Speaker 5:  from Steve jobs, but whoever takes over the company next we'll inherit it
Speaker 5:  from Tim cook.
Speaker 2:  What is the like overall sense of, of sort
Speaker 2:  of what Jeff Williams thing is? Cause right. Like Steve jobs was like the
Speaker 2:  visionary and then Tim cook was like the ruthless executer. Right. That was
Speaker 2:  like, when he came in, that was like, what everybody understood was like,
Speaker 2:  it is now Tim Cook's job. He is the, the operations king of the
Speaker 2:  universe. He's the
Speaker 5:  Supply chains guy.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. He's just going to come and make this, the tightest most efficient
Speaker 2:  company in the world, which like by all accounts he has basically
Speaker 2:  done. Is there a thing floating around about Jeff Williams in that sense?
Speaker 2:  Like, does he have a vibe?
Speaker 5:  No. Right. I think that's by design. Okay. I don't think there's
Speaker 5:  any way you could describe the CEO of apple is just a
Speaker 5:  guy that's not right. But I, I think
Speaker 5:  apple is a very secretive company. They show you who they want to show
Speaker 5:  you. Even Tim cook, he does not get onstage and be like this next
Speaker 5:  iPhone. I squeezed 3 cents of margin out of a tiny supplier
Speaker 5:  in Asia you share, heard of, and to apple at our scale that represents $5
Speaker 5:  billion, right? Like that's his thing. I think there's a real
Speaker 5:  sense that Jeff Williams is that person. He still does that
Speaker 5:  thing there. They apparently bile conflict similar in that way. And I
Speaker 5:  think it is true that apple is not apple without that
Speaker 5:  operational excellence. Like you cannot be the company that
Speaker 5:  ships a billion iPhones every minute and then a new one every
Speaker 5:  year, unless actually the core of the company is operations, right?
Speaker 5:  And supply chain management and logistics management. Like they
Speaker 5:  operate at a skeleton in comprehensible to anyone else. So I think maybe
Speaker 5:  you need, you just need a leader who respects that. And I buy all kinds of
Speaker 5:  jobs respected that element of cook, but jobs never ran a company as big
Speaker 5:  as apple. So now Tim cook runs a company that's as big as Tim cook made the
Speaker 5:  company. Who are you going to find to do that? There might only be one natural
Speaker 5:  choice versus somebody who existed in that company already.
Speaker 5:  Because again, what are the other companies at this scale? And it's like,
Speaker 5:  oh, you really do have to go find a defense contractor
Speaker 5:  executive to manage something this complicated and
Speaker 5:  managed by the way, your geopolitical relationship with China and
Speaker 5:  sit down on Trump's right hand when Trump is like, I'm going to ban every
Speaker 5:  import from China and get them to, to back off like that. These are all things
Speaker 5:  Tim cook had to do, right. That have almost nothing to do with are
Speaker 5:  the icons on the iPhone. And he did. Yeah. And partially I think his skill
Speaker 5:  is like letting that be to maybe his detriment, because I don't know if you
Speaker 5:  have seen some of apple software design and recently
Speaker 2:  The icons are
Speaker 5:  A little, all over the place. I
Speaker 4:  Love a pile.
Speaker 5:  Right. But like they are still doing it at that scale, which is, I think
Speaker 5:  is the victory.
Speaker 2:  Okay. So Alex now it's your turn. What's next? What do you got?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, this one's kind of adjacent to some of the stuff we've been talking
Speaker 4:  about, but can apple like do the whole, we love
Speaker 4:  privacy. We care about privacy. We are your privacy. Warrior's
Speaker 4:  protecting you from everybody, infiltrating you. And also do the ad
Speaker 4:  business. They're quietly growing, maybe not quietly growing, but they're
Speaker 4:  definitely growing an ad business.
Speaker 2:  It's like increasingly not quiet.
Speaker 4:  It kind of reminds me of the whole Google do no evil, but also be the biggest
Speaker 4:  ad business in the world. And eventually they had to decide and they said
Speaker 4:  money.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. They said, oh, we're, don't be evil. It's not a thing anymore for us.
Speaker 2:  It's like, cool, Google. That's a good look. I kind of think no. And I think
Speaker 2:  even just on like a public perception level, like I think we've seen that
Speaker 2:  as possible to do good advertising in a more privacy preserving way, right?
Speaker 2:  Like how well you can do that remains to be seen. But like, there are ways
Speaker 2:  to do ads that are not as sketchy feeling as the way that
Speaker 2:  like Facebook and Google have done ads over time. But from a public
Speaker 2:  perception standpoint, I think it's very hard to be
Speaker 2:  simultaneously the privacy company and shove more
Speaker 2:  personalized ads into people's apps. I think people are just like awake to
Speaker 2:  what that is now and what it feels like. And I think it's really
Speaker 2:  hard, even if you're doing both of those things genuinely, I don't
Speaker 2:  think people will believe you anymore.
Speaker 5:  Right. The evidence of your privacy being violated is you talk
Speaker 5:  to someone and then an app shows you an ad for something that
Speaker 5:  you just talked about. Right. And then it's like, oh, Instagram is listening
Speaker 5:  to me. And whether I answered them as listening to your, not whether it actually
Speaker 5:  just happens to be your two people in your twenties, in the same place at
Speaker 5:  the same time. And of course you're talking about spring break,
Speaker 5:  like, right. Like maybe the answer is like, everyone's a
Speaker 5:  little bit more predictable than they think, right. Or maybe the answer is
Speaker 5:  that mark Zuckerberg has a microphone embedded in your body. Like no one
Speaker 5:  really knows. Right. But the answer is usually like you showed up at your
Speaker 5:  friend's wifi network. We assume the thing that your friend is searching
Speaker 5:  for is the thing that you are searching for and what a
Speaker 5:  coincidence to happen to talk to you about the thing that they were searching
Speaker 5:  for. Right? Like, right. That's usually the, how that goes. I think
Speaker 5:  apple, right. They're going to claim they have defined tracking
Speaker 5:  is taking data from the user and then using it somewhere else. There is no
Speaker 5:  somewhere else for apple. They, they like the definition of
Speaker 5:  tracking does not apply to data that remains in the apple
Speaker 5:  ecosystem. So they're like, we're not tracking you. We're just keeping it
Speaker 5:  all in house. And it never leaves here. But then the outcome is going to
Speaker 5:  be personalized advertising, which the other process is the
Speaker 5:  data goes everywhere. Right? I don't think they can do it unless they, and
Speaker 5:  this is just, I think this will be hard for apple. You can't, if you're like,
Speaker 5:  we're the privacy company, you're promises, we never use your data. And you
Speaker 5:  can keep that promise because the evidence of your data not being used is
Speaker 5:  easy to see. It's proving a negative in some way, but like there's no personalization
Speaker 5:  really. Once you start using the data, now you have to like, let an art,
Speaker 5:  you have let some independent auditor in to prove it out.
Speaker 5:  Like here's where the data goes. Here's how apple uses the data. Here's how
Speaker 5:  the ads are generated. Like we understand the system and it's as private
Speaker 5:  as they say, apple can make that claim. But unless you have a third party
Speaker 5:  of some kind validating that it's true. You just end up back with personalized
Speaker 5:  advertising. That feels,
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I was thinking about this with all in the context of all these like
Speaker 2:  privacy companies who are now starting to say, like, we don't collect your
Speaker 2:  data. We don't want your data. We don't want to do anything with your data.
Speaker 2:  Like we are taking all the steps we possibly can to avoid getting it in the
Speaker 2:  first place. And that was like a thing that apple could have started to pretty
Speaker 2:  credibly say for a long time where they're like, we have no use for your
Speaker 2:  data except to like help you with these small things in Siri. Right? So like,
Speaker 2:  if you want to opt into that, great, if not, no problem. The rest of it,
Speaker 2:  we don't even want to know, like we have no upside to allowing our
Speaker 2:  stuff to listen to you 24 7, because we wouldn't want to know. And now there
Speaker 2:  is an upside, like there's a reason apple would do that. And even if it doesn't,
Speaker 2:  it's still, it just becomes much harder to prove that you're not doing it
Speaker 2:  when you have a reason to be doing it.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And they were going to hire Antonio Garcia,
Speaker 5:  Martinez from Facebook to build an ads business. Like it is not
Speaker 5:  quiet, what they're doing. I think they'd just have to prove that they don't
Speaker 5:  need the giant weird third party data brokers to do
Speaker 5:  it. And maybe they, you know, maybe they don't, but that's not a claim you
Speaker 5:  should just trust. That's a claim you should trust when someone else goes
Speaker 5:  in and investigates and tells you it's true.
Speaker 2:  My next one. Cause I think it's my turn is, do we want a
Speaker 2:  new idea for an iPhone it's iPhone season? You know, everybody's like, this
Speaker 2:  is the year. It's a, this is a tick year. We're going to get to redesign
Speaker 2:  new ideas. Everything's going to be great. And part of me is like, maybe
Speaker 2:  we need to start treating smartphones as like a fundamentally solved problem
Speaker 2:  that like, this is what they look like. It's fine changing. It would actually
Speaker 2:  be more hassle than it's worth, stop having new ideas, just make my battery
Speaker 2:  last longer and keep making everything slightly better. And I'll be happy
Speaker 2:  forever.
Speaker 4:  No, I think there's a lot to be done to the phone. Right. I still have to
Speaker 4:  put a case on mine less. I drop it and shatter a
Speaker 4:  thousand dollar device and have to go get the glass on it replaced.
Speaker 4:  Like that's a problem. I shouldn't have to worry about that. I think it's
Speaker 4:  like battery is obviously the biggest thing, but, but the district
Speaker 4:  ability of these things is really, really bad. And given that people are
Speaker 4:  holding onto phones longer because they are no longer being as heavily
Speaker 4:  subsidized and they're just like more useful and do all the stuff
Speaker 4:  we need. I want it to be able to like last all three years or four
Speaker 4:  years that I use it.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I think the big challenge for phones is that they actually kind
Speaker 5:  of do last a long time. So I might disagree with you, right? Like
Speaker 5:  people hold on to phones for an awful long time. And the idea that that only
Speaker 5:  happens because you need a case is like not the worst thing. I think people
Speaker 5:  like putting cases on their phones, like if the big next turn in phones is
Speaker 5:  you don't need a case. And it'll say the last three years, like, I don't
Speaker 5:  know that we've accomplished. I think people will still put cases on this
Speaker 5:  phone.
Speaker 4:  It'll just be me. I'll just be like in the crowd cheering very loudly. Tim's
Speaker 4:  like calmed down.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I think there's a bunch of stuff around how we use phones that
Speaker 5:  could change and be meaningfully better.
Speaker 2:  What
Speaker 5:  I still think typing on a phone kind of sucks.
Speaker 2:  That's a good one.
Speaker 5:  Right? Like it's, it's no fun. I don't want to do it whenever I have to type
Speaker 5:  anything long. I start hunting for a real keyboard. It's it's just like
Speaker 5:  that. We haven't innovated there in a long time and maybe that's not flashy
Speaker 5:  enough for apple to be like, we've invented a way that makes typing on this
Speaker 5:  phone superior or better. It's
Speaker 2:  A revolutionary input device.
Speaker 5:  Right. But it's just like, I think there's a lot of the basics that we take
Speaker 5:  for granted now were actually a little bit of improvement would go a long
Speaker 5:  way and maybe that's it all just comes back to what you're saying, right?
Speaker 5:  Maybe that's on the order of the camera's a little bit better and the battery
Speaker 5:  lasts a little bit longer, but I think we have settled into
Speaker 5:  most people know how to use a phone, any radical change in how you use a
Speaker 5:  phone will irritate more people than will be excited about
Speaker 5:  it. So no more radical changes are coming. And that always just feels
Speaker 5:  like it's like that's when things get boring.
Speaker 2:  I don't know though. I like, I I've been thinking about this in the context
Speaker 2:  of Mac books and like laptops in general, because if you rewind, I don't
Speaker 2:  know, eight or nine years, there was this moment where everybody's like,
Speaker 2:  okay, laptops have basically looked and worked the same way for 40
Speaker 2:  years. Let's blow it all up. Let's change some things. It's time for new
Speaker 2:  ideas about laptops. And we tried, I mean everything. What if your laptop
Speaker 2:  detached? What if it looked different? What if it did a spinny thing? What
Speaker 2:  if it had three screens? Like we tried all of these ideas and then when it
Speaker 2:  turned out, everybody wanted was just a better laptop. And so we've come
Speaker 2:  back around to like, this is just what a laptop does. This is how it's
Speaker 2:  supposed to work. It doesn't solve all of your problems, but it solves a
Speaker 2:  lot of them. And we should just keep making this thing better in
Speaker 2:  ways that are not different. And I'm like, maybe that is just where
Speaker 2:  we've arrived with smartphones. And maybe that says something about like
Speaker 2:  the maturity of the market. But I feel like there's still this itch to like
Speaker 2:  have a new idea about smartphones. And part of me is like, maybe,
Speaker 2:  maybe that's not where we should be going with smartphones. Like maybe we've
Speaker 2:  had the idea for smart phones and let's just like, keep making them better
Speaker 2:  and then have different ideas about other stuff.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Very few cars get sold with three wheels instead of four, you know?
Speaker 5:  No, one's like seven wheels. Like there's some basics that I think are
Speaker 5:  locked,
Speaker 4:  But what about like, we're seeing, you know, everybody's got, everybody loves
Speaker 4:  old, led a lot of older displays that allows for that flexibility. So we're
Speaker 4:  seeing both in watches and in laptops let's play with things.
Speaker 4:  Let's close it, flap it shut. Is that a whole new
Speaker 4:  thing or is that just an iteration?
Speaker 2:  That's fair. And I will give you, I actually think that like the more I talk
Speaker 2:  to people about the Z flip for the more I'm like, this is the future of phones
Speaker 2:  and I want a flip phone forever and ever, and like, maybe that's that's big
Speaker 2:  enough. That might count as like a genuine new idea about a phone should
Speaker 2:  work. Except that the thing where Samsung is like put it on an L shape and
Speaker 2:  take selfie videos that is bad and not interesting and not a new idea about
Speaker 2:  smart phones. But I think, I, I guess you're right that like on the display
Speaker 2:  front, there is probably some interesting stuff left to do,
Speaker 5:  You know, my like general theory about the tech industry is that you can
Speaker 5:  tell what's going to happen. If you just know where displays are going. Like
Speaker 5:  if we hadn't invented LCDs, there wouldn't be phones. If you invent folding
Speaker 5:  OLED, someone will come along and like put them to good use. And maybe that
Speaker 5:  is a phone that turns into a tablet, or maybe it's a phone that gets smaller
Speaker 5:  or maybe it's something else entirely. And we just haven't seen it yet. That's
Speaker 5:  probably the next order of real change. Like obviously Samsung is four
Speaker 5:  generations deep into it, but it's still kind of iterative.
Speaker 4:  We're all going to have the like sick fallout cuff
Speaker 5:  To this is my dream. What's my brand
Speaker 5:  cuffs.
Speaker 4:  I guess a little spikes on it. Yes.
Speaker 5:  I'm so down for this, make me a spiky cuff with a rolling
Speaker 5:  Owlette around it.
Speaker 2:  You guys can't see this, Neil. I just started throwing money at the screen
Speaker 2:  as he's talking. All right. Let's keep going. So let's do let's do, we're
Speaker 2:  not gonna get to all five, but let's do one more. Each Alex, you went first.
Speaker 2:  So you get to go first. What's what's next on your list.
Speaker 4:  So my final question, totally real apple TV. It's this big
Speaker 4:  deal that apple wants to bake. They want it to be a TV, like
Speaker 4:  service streaming service. They want it to be a box. They want it to be an
Speaker 4:  app on the box and the phone, sometimes the
Speaker 4:  Mac book. And it's all the same thing. Like, is it gonna work? Is
Speaker 4:  it successful? I think it's like, I watched the
Speaker 4:  shows.
Speaker 2:  Your question is just why apple TV question mark.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And my question is, why won't you just make me a
Speaker 5:  TV? Right? Like the game that apple
Speaker 5:  is playing is one where they kind of don't have leverage if
Speaker 5:  they put the screen in your house and then Netflix
Speaker 5:  wants to be on the screen, then apple can be like, you have to be in our
Speaker 5:  recommendation system. And it's just weird that they haven't made the connection
Speaker 5:  to owning the hardware, gives us control over the software
Speaker 2:  Or the other way to do that, which is the thing Alex and I have talked a
Speaker 2:  ton about is building the best interface, which is like,
Speaker 2:  people are desperate for an app that it just has all the stuff I want to
Speaker 2:  watch and shows me the things I like to watch.
Speaker 5:  Right? But Netflix has an out there, right? You, you make that app and you
Speaker 5:  ship it to Android TVs. And Netflix is like, we're not going to participate
Speaker 5:  in your app. You want Netflix drive to survive. Is this other app that we
Speaker 5:  control? If apple has the hardware, they get to say
Speaker 5:  no, like to be on T V O S on our
Speaker 5:  TV, you have to participate in universal search and
Speaker 5:  enough people will buy those TVs that Netflix will have to feel the pain
Speaker 5:  and do it.
Speaker 4:  Do you think that's true though, because we've seen Netflix play really
Speaker 4:  hard ball. And this situation in the past,
Speaker 5:  Netflix is not so much in a position to pay full
Speaker 5:  disclosure. We have made a Netflix show
Speaker 5:  disclosure. The disclosure block is here.
Speaker 5:  We make a lot of TV. Our company makes a lot of TV shows a lot of companies.
Speaker 5:  I'm just saying Netflix, isn't it. This is the time to say, if you
Speaker 5:  want to be on our hardware, which people will buy unlike the car,
Speaker 5:  right? If apple makes a TV, it is a guarantee that people will run out
Speaker 5:  and buy that TV. They make a call, like, what would I just beg?
Speaker 5:  People, send us renders of what you think. An apple mid-sized
Speaker 5:  crossover, the most popular kind of car in America. How
Speaker 5:  does apple make anything that doesn't look like every other bubble on the
Speaker 5:  road today? Right?
Speaker 4:  It's the Homer Simpson car that would have an logo I'm like done
Speaker 4:  sold.
Speaker 5:  Right? But you can see how apple would make a great TV. That looks
Speaker 5:  cool. Studio display. Not withstanding. Can you,
Speaker 2:  Yeah. It w how do you make a TV that doesn't just look like a
Speaker 2:  TV.
Speaker 4:  I got it. I got it. So apple historically has really, really good
Speaker 4:  calibration on their TVs. I'm not saying this will be a selling point for
Speaker 4:  90% of people, but the other 10%, everybody listening to
Speaker 4:  this podcast will absolutely go out and buy this. If you were like,
Speaker 4:  this is like home theater technician, dude,
Speaker 4:  $500 an hour grade calibration out of the
Speaker 4:  box.
Speaker 2:  So, okay. A thing we have been talking about a bunch on this episode is that
Speaker 2:  apple is only interested in large markets and people
Speaker 2:  who want to buy the TV, you just described is like 11
Speaker 2:  people.
Speaker 4:  That's just a selling point. That's just a selling point. I think you've
Speaker 4:  just say we're doing an apple TV. They got out with the backlights
Speaker 4:  get the micro LEDs. They would do
Speaker 4:  to all ed. And you would probably be able to replace the apple TV in the
Speaker 4:  back, like would come with the apple TVN you would just pull it out and put
Speaker 4:  a new one in when it's time to upgrade. That's the killer feature.
Speaker 4:  Apple send me my money.
Speaker 5:  I just want to point out the people who are making this prediction for like
Speaker 5:  20 years straight. I have probably done it. Gene monster built a career on
Speaker 5:  this prediction. This is like a real thing. My point is
Speaker 5:  unlike the car, which again, I just challenge
Speaker 5:  you to be like, what apple has to compete with is
Speaker 5:  midsize crossovers. That is the market. I have to make a Tesla model
Speaker 5:  line. That is the market for cars. People like their midsize crossovers.
Speaker 5:  They sell lots of them every day. That's hard in software differentiation
Speaker 5:  and cars is not the thing that sells cars. Yeah. TVs are different, right?
Speaker 5:  If you apple said, we're making a TV, people would give their money to apple
Speaker 5:  tomorrow. Like they just would the same way that when apple says it's making
Speaker 5:  AirPods, people just like buy the AirPods and they assume it'll be good.
Speaker 5:  And the software will work. And all the stuff they have the ability to ship
Speaker 5:  a thing that is not at the top of the technology curve, but still be
Speaker 5:  good. Like a 65 inch Ola display is now squarely in
Speaker 5:  that sweet spot, right? Where you had just said the standard, LGO a
Speaker 5:  display with apple software. Apple's calibration
Speaker 5:  runs the thing. And then you can say, a lot of people bought
Speaker 5:  these peacock. You want to like participate. We want a cut of all your
Speaker 5:  ads. You want a new video on demand. We want a piece of every transaction.
Speaker 5:  Like that's what Roku does. That's Roku's business. So the argument against
Speaker 5:  the TV right now is people don't buy them often enough. But the actual
Speaker 5:  business for Roku, for the fire TV for
Speaker 5:  everybody is a cut of the transactions, a service
Speaker 5:  business. And that's what Apple's really good at now. And so that's
Speaker 5:  again, is that the question is to take, is it just a bald face
Speaker 5:  demand tin build me a TV.
Speaker 2:  I have never hoped more that you're right, because I so
Speaker 2:  violently disagree with the idea that apple can make a differentiated television
Speaker 2:  that like now I hope we get to prove it out. Like all the things you just
Speaker 2:  described, like Bluetooth headphones, mostly suck. Most cell phones
Speaker 2:  are a pain in the ass. Most things are bad when apple
Speaker 2:  assaults them, right? Like apple comes in and says, we have made a thing
Speaker 2:  that works better. There is none of that with television that apple has
Speaker 2:  any track record or potential to solve. Like my
Speaker 2:  TV is too large for me to carry around as like
Speaker 2:  not a real problem that exists. My TV is ugly as like not a real problem
Speaker 2:  that exists. My TV software sucks is real. And apple has
Speaker 2:  precisely no track record of doing any better.
Speaker 4:  There's a thing that sucks on TVs that everybody complains about the moment
Speaker 4:  they buy, they upgrade their TV. Apple does suck at it though, but
Speaker 4:  really good audio.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Like a thin TV that you can put on the wall and don't need a sound bar. Can't
Speaker 4:  be done. Hasn't been done. If apple was like, we solved that one. I'd be
Speaker 4:  like, okay, sure. And two, that would actually be like a compelling
Speaker 4:  thing for a bra. Like that's a problem that people want solved with their
Speaker 4:  TVs.
Speaker 5:  Five home pods, the apple TV
Speaker 5:  strategy.
Speaker 4:  We'll ship you five home pods for
Speaker 4:  free.
Speaker 5:  You could see like that's a, that's a hardware design challenge. That apple
Speaker 5:  is up to the task of doing right integrate speakers
Speaker 5:  around the TV that do all the bouncy stuff. Like they love spatial
Speaker 5:  audio. Apple wants nothing more than for the cast of Bridger tend to be
Speaker 5:  sneaking up behind you. It's true. They
Speaker 5:  could do it. They have to actually do it. And I think, I think they get trapped
Speaker 5:  in, we need a market. That's big enough to be worth it. So we're going to
Speaker 5:  chase healthcare and cars instead of what is a thing people have in their
Speaker 5:  house that could be substantially better. That then turns into
Speaker 5:  transactions over time. That turn into a big market like apple of all companies
Speaker 5:  right now, apple could do the thing where they rescue
Speaker 5:  theatrical, right by saying, you're actually going to a movie theater. You're
Speaker 5:  going to buy the movie on iTunes for a hundred dollars. And it's going to
Speaker 5:  stream once on your beautiful TV. Apple has the clout to do it
Speaker 5:  right there. Our studio, like you have to invent this stuff that is risky
Speaker 5:  and say, it will turn into a market. Instead of saying, here's a market.
Speaker 5:  You understand what the big number that has a T at the end of it. And we're
Speaker 5:  going to go take that one with no track record.
Speaker 2:  All right, Neil, what's your next one? And this can't be about the TV.
Speaker 5:  This actually relates to kind of our privacy conversation. And it's more
Speaker 5:  of what will they build right there in this privacy conversation. We know
Speaker 5:  they take a lot of money from Google every year to be the default search
Speaker 5:  engine in the iPhone. We know their privacy stance puts them in conflict.
Speaker 5:  With that moment. We know there's an advertising business. Are they just
Speaker 5:  going to build a search engine? It's the thing that they can take the most
Speaker 5:  easily by saying goodbye to Google's money and making their own search
Speaker 5:  engine, that a fault on the iPhone, they will instantly have massive share
Speaker 5:  in search, which they can do all kinds of things with
Speaker 4:  Don't. They kind of suck at algorithms. Like I never think of apple as a
Speaker 4:  really powerful player in the algorithm space, given
Speaker 4:  how often they, who will not be named activates on
Speaker 4:  my wrist every day. And it answers my questions poorly.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I don't, I mean, apple can be good at whatever it wants the richest
Speaker 5:  company in the world. They can, they can be good at whatever they want. I
Speaker 2:  Think. Yes and no, I think would is the answer to your question. Cause I
Speaker 2:  think like spotlight is pretty clearly what apple perceives to be
Speaker 2:  a search engine, right? Like it, it searches the stuff on your computer,
Speaker 2:  but also like it does, it does web image search going forward and that's
Speaker 2:  like, you can search for images in spotlight is that it's like not
Speaker 2:  quite a search engine, but it's like kind of a search engine. And I think
Speaker 2:  what apple seems like it's going to do is start to try to like abstract
Speaker 2:  more stuff away. Like, I don't know that building the sort of general
Speaker 2:  informational Google search thing is all that interesting to apple, but
Speaker 2:  in the sense of like, can apple build an all in one travel
Speaker 2:  product and like, can apple take shopping, share away and start to
Speaker 2:  like pull some of that stuff into its other products? I think.
Speaker 2:  Absolutely. And it's like pretty clear that that's what apple is going to
Speaker 2:  do. So I think like is apple going to buy, I don't know, some small
Speaker 2:  search engine or like try to roll its own from scratch. Maybe it certainly
Speaker 2:  could, but I, my guess would be, it tries to just like pull a search engine
Speaker 2:  into like its component parts and then just like eat them one at a time.
Speaker 5:  But at some point you have to build web search
Speaker 2:  Maybe, but also like that's fairly commoditized, right? You just like buy
Speaker 2:  the Bing search index, put your stuff on top of it. And like
Speaker 2:  people searching, like who was this 16th president of United States? It's
Speaker 2:  like, that's a solved problem. Right? Like you don't need to go reinvent
Speaker 2:  the wheel to do that.
Speaker 4:  Oh, I disagree. I think you have to really? Yeah. The
Speaker 4:  reason everybody makes fun of being is because it doesn't always serve what
Speaker 4:  you actually want. And Google has obviously gotten really
Speaker 4:  far field is a lot harder to find what you want on Google. Nowadays, it takes
Speaker 4:  more work if you're not just looking for the most obvious questions on the
Speaker 4:  planet. And even sometimes then it takes a while. That's the
Speaker 4:  problem that that's happened is like Google is so invested in selling you
Speaker 4:  stuff. Being is so invested in like, not doing
Speaker 4:  what I need it to do and giving me points and all sorts
Speaker 4:  of other junk. Like I need the thing that just takes me where I want to go.
Speaker 4:  And I don't know if Apple's necessarily capable of doing it. Like nobody's
Speaker 4:  really good at it. Duck, duck go is pretty close. Obviously Google, if you
Speaker 4:  like add a bunch of like little negative signs and say don't
Speaker 4:  include Pinterest, don't include weird forums from the
Speaker 4:  1990s. Like very helpful, but I don't know if apple can do
Speaker 4:  that. I just, yeah, I, I, I would love it. I would love a really
Speaker 4:  strong search engine, but search engines can't be like
Speaker 4:  hand coded. Like you can't just like have somebody pick it
Speaker 4:  all and make that a super strong, powerful search engine. That's why Google
Speaker 4:  is successful.
Speaker 2:  They try to do it like apple music, like hand curate the internet for you
Speaker 2:  every day,
Speaker 5:  Jimmy Eileen will personally return your search results to,
Speaker 4:  And I think that that was like a thing, but we can't do that. Like that's
Speaker 4:  effectively what a lot of websites do, right? Like that's what the verge
Speaker 4:  does. Like a lot of us are about that curation, but that curation at
Speaker 4:  scale, have we seen it done successfully? No.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, but can apple keep its privacy branding
Speaker 5:  when they accept a ton of money from Google to give your search data
Speaker 5:  to them, that's literally what, like next to your physical
Speaker 5:  location, all the things you search for is a pretty
Speaker 5:  enormous Corpus of information about you. And they basically sell it to
Speaker 5:  Google for iPhone users, right? Even if you switch it to being, they're still
Speaker 5:  selling it to Microsoft, like they're giving it away in some massive
Speaker 5:  meaningful way. And you kinda know that you're searching Google. So
Speaker 5:  like it's not as shady is making it out to be here, but it's still
Speaker 5:  like, you're the privacy company and you're not protecting this thing as
Speaker 5:  hard as you could by building your own product that actually respects it
Speaker 5:  more than Google does. I don't know. Like I think there's, there's a point
Speaker 5:  at which that decision around spotlight gets fraught because you have to,
Speaker 5:  apple has to give up the money and the money is important for a lot of reasons.
Speaker 5:  One it's money, but two, it like, you know, Google wants that position. So
Speaker 5:  they want to be in a place where Apple's good to them for all
Speaker 5:  kinds of reasons. They want the YouTube app on your phone, but it also just
Speaker 5:  like cuts both ways. Like it's the, to me, whenever we talk about apple and
Speaker 5:  privacy and the complexity of it, the, you take a bunch of money from
Speaker 5:  Google and then slap Google around. It's like weird.
Speaker 5:  Yes. Right? It's like the first counter-argue
Speaker 2:  No, I agree. I think that's right. And I think apple has spent a long time
Speaker 2:  hiding behind like people like Google search. So we're going, it's fine.
Speaker 2:  And I don't know how much longer that works. All right. We're going to take
Speaker 2:  a break and then we're going to come back and talk about all of our overheated
Speaker 2:  most spicy, not even sure. We totally believe them takes about
Speaker 2:  apple. We'll be right
Speaker 2:  back.
Speaker 9:  You listened to this show weekend and week out because, well, we'd like to
Speaker 9:  think we offer sharp unfiltered insights into the biggest stories in tech
Speaker 9:  business and politics.
Speaker 2:  Okay. We're back. I'm just bursting with hot takes here. So let's, let's
Speaker 2:  move on and run through some of those quick before we go, I'm going to go
Speaker 2:  first. Cause it's my turn. This actually I think jives with a lot of the
Speaker 2:  stuff we've been talking about, but the first one I wrote down is apple is
Speaker 2:  too popular and it's killing apple. Yeah. Back in the day when
Speaker 2:  apple was like this high-end thing for people who appreciated
Speaker 2:  beautiful hardware, apple could sort of do whatever it wanted because it
Speaker 2:  had this like built-in group of people who cared about this stuff and were
Speaker 2:  interested in, played along. And now when you're in a world where everybody
Speaker 2:  uses an iPhone and everybody uses an iPad and Macs are
Speaker 2:  massively popular, you end up in this world where apple can't get
Speaker 2:  rid of one of its multitasking options on a Mac, because there's
Speaker 2:  a small, but statistically relevant people, number of people who use
Speaker 2:  it. And so they have a million ways to do everything. And like
Speaker 2:  Macko S is turning into windows because as long as some people use
Speaker 2:  something, apple can't kill it. And apple is, is too big. And it's making
Speaker 2:  apple not able to do anything.
Speaker 5:  It's not even windows, correct comparisons, Microsoft word, like the
Speaker 5:  Microsoft word team will tell you this every day,
Speaker 5:  if you ask them that the reason the menu bar is cluttered is because every
Speaker 5:  button is 10 million people that use it. You can't clean it up because
Speaker 5:  some massive amount of the population that isn't, you cares about it and
Speaker 5:  you don't. And I think that is true. I would actually put the apple is too
Speaker 5:  popular and it's killing them in a different way, which is they're so
Speaker 5:  popular. They often don't feel real competition. So they just can
Speaker 5:  do everything. And like their hardware teams still need the things to be
Speaker 5:  more beautiful than the next thing on the shelf. And they care a lot and
Speaker 5:  you can see the hardware's gotten better. They've added the ports back, right?
Speaker 5:  Like very simple things that everyone can see and they can feel the pressure,
Speaker 5:  their software teams are more insulated than ever. And
Speaker 5:  I think you can see it in a software design. It doesn't matter if apple
Speaker 5:  software is 10% easier to use anymore. Like what are you going to do?
Speaker 5:  Switch? And I think that attitude has permeated a lot of
Speaker 5:  what they do.
Speaker 2:  What are you going to do? Switch is like, definitely written in large letters
Speaker 2:  on us, on a wall, somewhere in apple. And they'll just like tap it as they
Speaker 2:  walk in every morning. Okay. Nila, what's your, what's your first
Speaker 2:  hottest take
Speaker 5:  My overheated take.
Speaker 2:  We should say again, these, these are not things that we definitely for sure.
Speaker 2:  Believe. They're just things that exist inside of our souls that we need
Speaker 2:  to get out on microphone.
Speaker 5:  I think actually apple, this is overheated. I don't know if I believe
Speaker 5:  this at all. Apple's complacency in like
Speaker 5:  software will be the thing that, that hurts them and we'd see. End of
Speaker 5:  apple. It's maybe true. Maybe not. But I think a lot of developers
Speaker 5:  are angry at apple. I think apple to recruit people, they have to
Speaker 5:  buy into Apple's way of doing things, which means if you are
Speaker 5:  young and you want a job at apple, like maybe you're not allowed to invent
Speaker 5:  as much stuff as you would be somewhere else. Maybe the iPhone interface
Speaker 5:  isn't up for grabs. And I think fundamentally like, unless they get more
Speaker 5:  aggressive, like, like all giant companies, like all went up, like what's
Speaker 5:  the best argument against antitrust action. It's at large companies inevitably
Speaker 5:  fall apart in their own. Right. And I think apple, like I see the
Speaker 5:  software. It's not just me. It's like John Gruber will tell you apple
Speaker 5:  software is like pretty messy lately. The hardware is beautiful. It's
Speaker 5:  some of the best they've ever done. The software is like weirdly messy. My
Speaker 5:  overheated take is it's the software that brings them down more than any
Speaker 5:  outing government, regulator or anything else. It's not having the focus
Speaker 5:  there.
Speaker 2:  I buy that honestly. And I think I was talking to the
Speaker 2:  folks at Dashlane, the password manager about pass keys and
Speaker 2:  this like passwordless future that we're all heading into. And I asked
Speaker 2:  them about mobile. And they said in this very diplomatic way that, you know,
Speaker 2:  desktop is one thing because of the standards are much more open and on mobile,
Speaker 2:  apple and Google really controlled their ecosystems and apple in particular
Speaker 2:  is on very much this like annual cadence of software releases.
Speaker 2:  And because of that, we're probably not going to get any of the tools. We
Speaker 2:  need to do some of this interesting stuff on mobile for at least a year,
Speaker 2:  because that's just what apple does. They just don't release the new stuff
Speaker 2:  for 12 months. And like, it just got me thinking that it's like it, this
Speaker 2:  is the new equivalent of like Microsoft shipping windows in a box every five
Speaker 2:  years that it's like, the world just moves faster than this now.
Speaker 2:  And not only is apple not, you know, necessarily
Speaker 2:  known for its thrilling software anymore. It's just behind.
Speaker 2:  And it's like a running joke that Android is way ahead. And eventually it
Speaker 2:  doesn't seem crazy to me that that would catch up to apple in a bigger way.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I mean, that take is really overheated, right? Then eventually Andrew,
Speaker 5:  it will become so superior to apple that people will have. What are you going
Speaker 5:  to switch? But over the longterm,
Speaker 5:  does Apple's lack of discipline in its software design catch up to, I
Speaker 5:  think, I think absolutely. Yes.
Speaker 2:  I like it. Alex got
Speaker 4:  My hot take is wireless as bad. Like Apple's kind of
Speaker 4:  obsession with wireless is bad.
Speaker 5:  More
Speaker 2:  Wires.
Speaker 5:  No, actually I can back this up, Alex, I have a stat for you.
Speaker 4:  Happy with
Speaker 5:  It. You know how apple is like they showed CarPlay WWDC and I was a big
Speaker 5:  Panther and in a car and they're basically their response to every car
Speaker 5:  maker being like no right Apple's responses. People won't buy a car. That
Speaker 5:  car play. Yeah. That's, that's what they're banking on. Turns out
Speaker 5:  that since CarPlay went wireless, consumer happiness,
Speaker 5:  consumer satisfaction with CarPlay it's plummeted because it's not as
Speaker 5:  consistent as plugging your phone in
Speaker 4:  The
Speaker 5:  Cation. It's as direct as it gets. It's a little slower, a little
Speaker 5:  flakier sometimes it doesn't connect. Sometimes. I dunno. It's it's a
Speaker 5:  wireless CarPlay is a weird combo platter of Bluetooth and wifi, right?
Speaker 5:  Like it pairs it phone over Bluetooth. It says I can do wireless CarPlay.
Speaker 5:  It switches the connection to wifi. Cause it's got a mirror, the screen,
Speaker 5:  all this stuff. Right. It turns out that it's just a lot of wireless radios
Speaker 5:  in the mix. And your phone acts weird when you do it. And people are like,
Speaker 5:  I don't like this as much as plugging my phone in.
Speaker 4:  Exactly. Yeah. I think that's the point is like you see with that, you see
Speaker 4:  with Bluetooth headphones, like apple has the best ones. They still suck.
Speaker 4:  At least a fifth of the time. I wear them every day and at least
Speaker 4:  once a week, something happens. So at least a seventh of the time,
Speaker 4:  sorry, I was getting wrong with my, my stats there, but there there's that
Speaker 4:  lack of consistency. And at this point we have like wires are
Speaker 4:  consistent and a lot of spaces, wires, willpower, your phone faster,
Speaker 4:  still wires will connect your phone to your car more
Speaker 4:  consistently and your headphones. And it's just like, people care about that
Speaker 4:  consistency. So maybe care about like
Speaker 4:  that.
Speaker 5:  Yes. The most overheated take at the verge is that wired
Speaker 5:  connections are faster and more reliable than wireless ones. There's a
Speaker 5:  hill we're going to die on it's that fact.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I don't know that that's an overheated take. That's just true.
Speaker 5:  I know people get mad at me all the time. Like when I did the Starlink review,
Speaker 5:  I was like, okay, well your house is better. People like you're in the pocket
Speaker 5:  of Comcast. So I was like, no, I'm just saying her connections are fast and
Speaker 5:  reliable.
Speaker 2:  We just forget the part where it's, you know, wired connections are faster
Speaker 2:  and more reliable parentheses. And it turns out nobody really
Speaker 2:  cares. It's like, which
Speaker 2:  is, it's just, this is where we live now. Okay. My second overheated
Speaker 2:  take and I like every day, this becomes less overheated and more just how
Speaker 2:  I feel. But I can't believe I'm starting to feel this way, which is that
Speaker 2:  I think the apple TV might be the best set top box on the market. Yes. I
Speaker 2:  have spent a long time, like a long time talking shit
Speaker 2:  about the apple TV because it was bad and expensive and apple should
Speaker 2:  feel bad about itself. And then I bought two Roku TVs that over the
Speaker 2:  course of the roughly 12 months that I have owned them seem to get slower
Speaker 2:  and worse every single day. And then I turn on like
Speaker 2:  my fire TVs, which seems to get slower and worse every single day. And then
Speaker 2:  I opened up the apple TV, which is like too big and too expensive. And the
Speaker 2:  Siri remote is still stupid, but like, boy, it's fast. And it just like,
Speaker 2:  it opens the apps when it's supposed to open the apps. And I'm like,
Speaker 2:  I ha I just, I feel like a bad person that I'm like, I'm going
Speaker 2:  to use the apple TV now.
Speaker 5:  But you feel like a bad person. I
Speaker 2:  Have talked so much shit about the apple TV. Like I cannot tell you
Speaker 4:  No, it's it's like home theater makers are not home theater makers, but home
Speaker 4:  theater like designers and the guys who set them up and everything, they
Speaker 4:  actually prefer the apple TV. Like that's the set top box that they go
Speaker 4:  to because it does have like, it's really good at doing most of the outputs
Speaker 4:  and it's fast. And it pairs with a bunch of their super expensive crap
Speaker 4:  that none of us will be able to afford. But it's really neat, you know, fireplaces
Speaker 4:  that come on and I'm sure like coordinate with whatever you're watching on
Speaker 4:  house of dragons that week. Yeah. It's a good box. I have got
Speaker 4:  two, I've got one in my bedroom. I never turned the TV on in my bedroom,
Speaker 4:  but if I do six months down the line, I don't have to be like, okay, I have
Speaker 4:  to find all my logins again. Okay. I have to update the app so I can watch
Speaker 4:  Netflix. Like it just does it. The things are there, it
Speaker 4:  works. And like the worst thing in the world is if you're like, boom, nobody's
Speaker 4:  here at the house tonight. I'm going to like sit down in front of the TV
Speaker 4:  and eat this dinner and watch a show. And then you sit down and you turn
Speaker 4:  on the TV and the set top box sucks. Like the things aren't
Speaker 4:  loading. And I don't have that issue with apple. As often,
Speaker 5:  We very much tried to be a Chromecast for the Google TV family for a
Speaker 5:  variety of reasons. Most of which is letting the kid just yell at
Speaker 5:  the Google home to turn on the show is like really good.
Speaker 5:  And the thing is just, they just promised to update it to make it fast. And
Speaker 5:  it's like, there's a part of me that believes that the reason the apple TV
Speaker 5:  is successful is because it just gets a draft on the operating system
Speaker 5:  work that apple does for its real computers. And no one else has to do that
Speaker 5:  work. So like, yeah, Roku runs an O S or the world's best
Speaker 5:  operating system engineers working at Roku to do memory
Speaker 5:  management.
Speaker 2:  Well, it also, all those companies are now on this like crazy downward
Speaker 2:  spiral. Like Roku's job is to basically figure out how to sell you a set
Speaker 2:  top box for $1. Like that seems to be Roku's job. They either want to put
Speaker 2:  it into television or just make it like a free thing that they hand out at
Speaker 2:  fairs. Right? Like that's what, that's what Roku wants to be. And I'm just
Speaker 2:  like, what if you made a good one? Like, that's, that's an idea. Like what
Speaker 2:  if, what if you made a set top box? That was good.
Speaker 5:  Amazon makes really high powered boxes. Right? I mean, at every, at every
Speaker 5:  price went from nothing to a couple like 150 bucks maybe.
Speaker 4:  And have you ever used, like, it's ugly, like Amazon does not put
Speaker 4:  it's like, I don't think there's one UI designer in
Speaker 4:  all of Amazon and they have to work on every single project. That's the only
Speaker 4:  explanation for how bad across the board Amazon UIs are.
Speaker 5:  They just redid it all. It's not like great. You know, it's, it's not, it
Speaker 5:  looks like everything else. But I do think
Speaker 5:  fundamentally Apple's scale gives them a
Speaker 5:  huge advantage with the hardware of the TV box. Again, I think the software
Speaker 5:  is pretty messy, but yeah, the thing's a little iPad. It gets all of
Speaker 5:  the benefits of the iPad, like engineering team. It gets all the benefits
Speaker 5:  of the, the M one engineering team. It gets all the benefits of the iPhone
Speaker 5:  engineering team to just operate as a computer. So it's a really good
Speaker 5:  computer and it doesn't kill its own memory and require a
Speaker 5:  restart every two days. Like that's weird. That's just a weird thing. My
Speaker 5:  Google TV requires. Yup.
Speaker 2:  Alex would he got,
Speaker 4:  I think it isn't the most important product hardware product at
Speaker 4:  apple is the Mac book or like the, like the computer,
Speaker 4:  not the phone.
Speaker 5:  Oh, that's really overheated.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Coming in hot. No, because we saw
Speaker 4:  during the pandemic that people actually do care about their
Speaker 4:  computers that we all have. Like we're very quietly caring about our
Speaker 4:  computers and then we all had to go buy them. And I think like
Speaker 4:  computers are still the core of the heart of things everybody's using phones,
Speaker 4:  but Quimby thought that phones were going to be a great deal. How'd that
Speaker 4:  go for you? Watching entertainment people don't actually like watching movies
Speaker 4:  on their phones. If they don't have to, they, they would prefer a computer.
Speaker 4:  They don't like having to type out their school
Speaker 4:  book reports. I'm thinking of the kids here, like computers
Speaker 4:  still do a good task and they do it really, really well. And phones
Speaker 4:  are really, really important. They're critical. We all use them every day,
Speaker 4:  but you go to your computer a lot and that's their core
Speaker 4:  business. And from which everything else Springs,
Speaker 2:  I would quibble with the idea that it's their core business at this point.
Speaker 4:  It should be their core business. There we go.
Speaker 2:  I do think, I mean, one of my alternate overheated takes was going
Speaker 2:  to be that Apple's Silicon investment is actually going to be the legacy
Speaker 2:  of apple and might turn out to be the most important thing you've ever spent
Speaker 2:  its money on. And I think that sort of drives at this point too, right? Is
Speaker 2:  that like, at least for a while longer, our
Speaker 2:  computers are like a central device in our lives and this doesn't apply to
Speaker 2:  everybody. It doesn't apply everywhere in the world, but like the centrality
Speaker 2:  of the PC is as obvious as it ever was to a lot of people right now, I
Speaker 2:  think. And I think in that sense, apple like seems to have fashioned
Speaker 2:  itself as a computer company again for the first time in awhile, which I
Speaker 2:  think is kind of exciting
Speaker 4:  And they're changing everybody else. Like everybody's now chasing them to
Speaker 4:  some degree. Intel like went from fi it's wild to me that five
Speaker 4:  years ago, Intel was so big. It could not fail it.
Speaker 4:  Like had this huge monopoly like net, what was it? 95,
Speaker 4:  90 9% of, of like computers and
Speaker 4:  servers were, were them. And it's just collapsed
Speaker 4:  because apple and AMD came along and apple in particular is forcing
Speaker 4:  everybody to rethink how they design these things and rethink how
Speaker 4:  operating systems work. And that's awesome. And it's
Speaker 4:  because of the Mac book, I'm bringing it all back.
Speaker 5:  I here's how it's definitely overheated. Like apple
Speaker 5:  could shut down the Mac line and still be as big as apple.
Speaker 2:  Listen to me, like we're not here for reality for things.
Speaker 5:  No, but I, I agree that the feeling is important. Like a reason
Speaker 5:  that I will not buy a windows computer is because I can't text from it as
Speaker 5:  reliably as I can from my Mac book. And that's a really important
Speaker 5:  feature to me. Cause I spend actually more time now in my
Speaker 5:  laptop than I do on my phone. I don't even know that's true. It just feels
Speaker 5:  that way. Right? Like while we've been doing this, literally using my
Speaker 5:  laptop, I've picked up my phone three times. That's
Speaker 5:  ridiculous.
Speaker 2:  Glad to know we're keeping your attention. You know, I thank you for being
Speaker 2:  present. Awesome.
Speaker 5:  I don't know what this TV take is. David's mad at himself, again. What's
Speaker 5:  going on on Twitter. But I think fundamentally it's where you're
Speaker 5:  productive. And I think Apple's argument for a long time is you will soon
Speaker 5:  be productive on your iPad. You'll assume to be as productive on your phone.
Speaker 5:  And certainly people are productive and iPads and phones, but like most businesses
Speaker 5:  are run on Excel and Excel happens on your laptop. And that's
Speaker 5:  like, that reality is not going anywhere for anyone.
Speaker 2:  I like it. All right. And you know, you get to go last, then we're going
Speaker 2:  to get out of here. What's your last overheat to take.
Speaker 5:  Apple will not reach its final form until it builds a
Speaker 5:  TV.
Speaker 2:  I feel like I should've seen that coming. I regret
Speaker 5:  Apple is not a successful company. It cannot be counted as a
Speaker 5:  success until it builds a TV until it takes over the single device in our
Speaker 5:  lives. That is responsible for America's cultural hush
Speaker 5:  money.
Speaker 2:  All right, well, we're done.
Speaker 5:  We had a good ride and it's
Speaker 2:  True this far, the last episode ever with the
Speaker 2:  Vergecast. This is, this turns into the Neal. I spends an hour begging apple
Speaker 2:  to make a TV. Every week
Speaker 5:  We got to do it. Why don't we do it here, man? There's millions of people
Speaker 5:  out there running ties in, in their living rooms. What are
Speaker 5:  you doing?
Speaker 2:  So you're saying apple has like a moral obligation
Speaker 5:  Moral.
Speaker 2:  It's not just a business thing. It's like, like what Tim cook says about
Speaker 2:  like saving lives.
Speaker 5:  You want to be the privacy company. Do you know what the single most like
Speaker 5:  intrusive wackadoo privacy like
Speaker 5:  destructing device in your home is your television.
Speaker 2:  You're not wrong.
Speaker 4:  An apple TV with built in ad
Speaker 4:  blockers.
Speaker 5:  I think that might kill my model by services model,
Speaker 5:  but like it knows everything you're watching. Most of the TVs have
Speaker 5:  automatic content detection that can tell what games you're playing on your
Speaker 5:  console. It's like the amount of data that your TVs
Speaker 5:  collect and send out to data brokers is out of control. So
Speaker 5:  if they do have a moral obligations, it's sitting right there.
Speaker 2:  There you go. You heard it here. First
Speaker 5:  Apple will not be successful until they make a TV.
Speaker 2:  I feel like apple is just going to ship you one. They're going to make one
Speaker 2:  TV just to shut you up. And then
Speaker 5:  It's just, yeah, it's, it's an LGO led with LTV glued to the
Speaker 5:  back. Like this is why you wanted, we turned the
Speaker 5:  wifi off on this TV input, our existing product on it and solved
Speaker 5:  your problem.
Speaker 2:  All right, we need to go. But there's an apple event coming really soon.
Speaker 2:  By the time you listen to this, it's possible, already happened. So we're
Speaker 2:  going to get a lot more information on all this. We're going to have a lot
Speaker 2:  more to talk about on Friday with all of the announcements. Thank you both.
Speaker 2:  This was really fun, man. All right. That's it for the
Speaker 2:  Vergecast today. Thank you so much for listening. There is tons more coverage
Speaker 2:  of everything that apple is up to and the apple event, and so much
Speaker 2:  more, frankly, at the virgin.com and you can also follow all of us on Twitter.
Speaker 2:  Alex is Alex H Kranz Nila is reckless and I'm Pierce. This
Speaker 2:  show is produced by Andrew Marino and Liam James Nori. Donovan is our executive
Speaker 2:  producer and Brooke Minters is our editorial director of audio. The Vergecast
Speaker 2:  is a verge production and part of the Vox media podcast network. If you have
Speaker 2:  thoughts, feedback, feelings, apple hot takes, or you just want to make
Speaker 2:  me feel better about liking the apple TV. Again, you can always email
Speaker 2:  vergecast@verge.com or call us on the verge cast hotline at 8
Speaker 2:  6, 6 verge, one, one, we're going to be doing some apple stuff on the hotline
Speaker 2:  soon. So get your calls in now, Alex Nila. And I will be back on Friday to
Speaker 2:  talk about everything that happened at the event, all of our feelings, all
Speaker 2:  of our reactions, everything it's going to be a big one. See you then rock
Speaker 2:  and
Speaker 2:  roll