# Transcript
ID: 48a62bb0-8106-11ed-b55d-57f99e1262fa
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: The Bluetooth Holiday Spec-tacular
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-2193725185036004093/-1808338667386181260/s93290-US-4911s-1671609846.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, Alex Cranz, Chris Welch, and Sean Hollister celebrate the holiday season with a full show dedicated to Bluetooth.
03:57 - We play Bluetooth Jeopardy! Play along here
30:38 - The crew discuss the many codecs layered onto the Bluetooth spec, and where the standard is headed.
46:56 - Former Bluetooth SIG executive director Dr. Mike Foley joins the show to discuss his time in charge of Bluetooth.
Happy Holidays!
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we'd love to hear from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Disabled
Speaker 2:  Connected to mobile device.
Speaker 3:  Hello and welcome to the Vergecast Bluetooth, holiday Spectacular,
Speaker 3:  the flagship podcast of the holidays of all of
Speaker 3:  the holidays,
Speaker 4:  All
Speaker 3:  Of them. The one episode a year where we dive deep into a
Speaker 3:  speck that makes all of our lives go. We've done hgm I this year
Speaker 3:  we're doing Bluetooth. Alex Kranz is here. Hey Alex.
Speaker 4:  Hey, I am wearing Bluetooth headphones just this once in
Speaker 4:  honor of the holidays. Spectacular,
Speaker 3:  And that's why Alex sounds bad. Thank you, Alex, for joining us
Speaker 3:  Compressed audio. We love it. Chris Welch and Sean
Speaker 3:  Hollister are gonna join us. We're gonna have a bit of a discussion about
Speaker 3:  Bluetooth, the standard, where it's going, what it means, what it could
Speaker 3:  turn into. We're gonna play a round of Bluetooth jeopardy, which is
Speaker 3:  so hard. Let me tell you
Speaker 4:  So hard.
Speaker 3:  Whatever you think Bluetooth jeopardy is, when I say we're gonna play Bluetooth
Speaker 3:  jeopardy, it is so much harder than you think it's gonna be. You're gonna
Speaker 3:  watch a struggle through that.
Speaker 4:  We do. Great. We
Speaker 3:  Did. It was fun. We had a good time. Yeah, and then we're gonna
Speaker 3:  interview the former executive director of the Bluetooth
Speaker 3:  sig, Dr. Mike Foley. We tried to get the current director of the Bluetooth
Speaker 3:  sig. That's the standards body that oversees Bluetooth. It's the holidays,
Speaker 3:  so he couldn't do it. Mike Foley, the former director, he's the one who launched
Speaker 3:  Bluetooth 3.0. He oversaw Bluetooth. Man's a shark
Speaker 3:  key joined us. He had some very interesting things to say about the status
Speaker 3:  of Bluetooth, how political it is and where it might be going. I mean it
Speaker 3:  all in all, when you think of the holidays, you think of one hour
Speaker 3:  of extremely deep Bluetooth conversation. Alex, I don't know what you think
Speaker 3:  of.
Speaker 4:  That's all I think about. I wanna know the Codex.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, I think about Codex. The children are sleeping, the gifts are
Speaker 3:  wrapped. The little blue pairing lights are blinking. It's gonna be great.
Speaker 3:  Alex, what headset are you on right now?
Speaker 4:  I'm on my AirPods Pro, I think.
Speaker 3:  How's the Bluetooth?
Speaker 4:  You know, it's fine. It's not shutting off right now because I'm not leaving
Speaker 4:  my house. Every time I leave my house, it dies like just instant
Speaker 4:  shuts down, but I'm, I'm on the road to Texas
Speaker 4:  and it, it sounds, it sounds good enough.
Speaker 3:  I'm very happy to be with you in this moment, in this holiday season
Speaker 3:  and season of giving and love. When I think about how to
Speaker 3:  express my love for you and the Vergecast audience, it is
Speaker 3:  definitely one hour of talking about Bluetooth.
Speaker 4:  A hundred percent. It was actually on my Christmas wishlist this year
Speaker 3:  And get ready everyone. All right. Like I said, Bluetooth
Speaker 3:  jeopardy. It is so much harder than you think.
Speaker 4:  We brought it.
Speaker 3:  Get your minds in the holiday spirit. We're gonna take a break. We're gonna
Speaker 3:  come back. We're gonna play around with Bluetooth jeopardy
Speaker 4:  Cue. The Lays
Speaker 5:  Support for this episode comes from Airbnb. If you've stayed in
Speaker 5:  one of Airbnb's unique homes all around the world, you may be wondering,
Speaker 5:  could my place be in Airbnb and what could I earn? You could be sitting
Speaker 5:  on an Airbnb right now. That might mean your extra guest room or maybe
Speaker 5:  even Airbnb in your entire home. While you're away on a long trip,
Speaker 5:  whether you could use some extra money to cover some of those surprise
Speaker 5:  expenses or maybe just a little something for yourself, your home
Speaker 5:  might be worth more than you think. Find out how much at
Speaker 5:  airbnb.com/host
Speaker 6:  Stream, the new Paramount Plus original series 1923, A
Speaker 6:  Yellowstone origin story starring Helen me in Harrison Ford
Speaker 6:  1923. A new series streaming now exclusively on Paramount Plus.
Speaker 6:  Go to paramount plus.com to try it for free.
Speaker 5:  This is Bluetooth jeopardy.
Speaker 5:  Now entering the studio are today's contestants
Speaker 5:  originally from Fort Worth, Texas, master of Plex
Speaker 5:  Media Server, Alex kras,
Speaker 5:  our resident earbud quality tester. Originally from Rockland County,
Speaker 5:  New York, Chris Welch and the
Speaker 5:  Verges editor in chief from Ray Scene Wisconsin,
Speaker 5:  Eli Patel. And now here is the
Speaker 5:  host of Bluetooth Jeopardy, Sean Hollister.
Speaker 7:  Thank you ladies and gentlemen and welcome. If you know how to play Jeopardy,
Speaker 7:  you know how to play this, except every question is related to one of our
Speaker 7:  favorite short rage wireless standards. The person
Speaker 7:  to pick first is the first person to hold up a Bluetooth device
Speaker 7:  on the screen. Let's hear from our contestants. What are you holding, deli?
Speaker 3:  It's an iPhone 14 promax. Does that count? That counts. Sure.
Speaker 7:  I'll take it. Alex, is that a Bluetooth track ball you have there? Yes,
Speaker 4:  But it was also, I was holding up my iPhone 14 pro, not
Speaker 4:  max, because I have
Speaker 3:  Small hits. Oh my god. I'm literally holding a Bluetooth mouse and I forgot
Speaker 3:  to hold up the Bluetooth mouse and I held up my phone instead.
Speaker 7:  And Chris, what is your Bluetooth pick?
Speaker 3:  I've got a Pixel seven in my hand. Is this how Jeopardy works?
Speaker 7:  Alright. Alright, good luck and let's go to work. Let's look
Speaker 7:  at today's categories.
Speaker 7:  We have Genesis, the early days of
Speaker 7:  Bluetooth. Pair me please. Each answer
Speaker 7:  will be a Bluetooth device. Spectacular.
Speaker 7:  We get into the specs of Bluetooth, bluetooth.com,
Speaker 7:  some PR messaging from Bluetooth we found on their site
Speaker 7:  Hack week, the security concerns of Bluetooth and of course
Speaker 7:  ri. Will you start us off? Alex Kratz?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I'm gonna take Pot Parri for 200.
Speaker 3:  Alex,
Speaker 7:  That is Pori at the answer is
Speaker 7:  the first Bluetooth device, a hands-free mobile headset earns the best
Speaker 7:  of show award at this trade show. Chris Welch,
Speaker 8:  I will be there in a matter of weeks. What is c e s?
Speaker 4:  Be wrong. Be wrong.
Speaker 7:  Be wrong.
Speaker 8:  Yes.
Speaker 7:  Alex Kranz.
Speaker 4:  What is Mobile World Congress?
Speaker 7:  Incorrect. Nii.
Speaker 3:  What is cia?
Speaker 7:  I'm afraid that's not the correct answer. What is Comdex
Speaker 4:  Old ass standard
Speaker 7:  Predated ces Technically
Speaker 3:  Yes. Comdex turned into ces. Can Chris get like half a point?
Speaker 7:  No.
Speaker 3:  Is this how Jeopardy works? Are we allowed to use Jeopardy as much as we're
Speaker 3:  saying Jeopardy?
Speaker 7:  Eli, you may pick the next category.
Speaker 4:  It's my turn still.
Speaker 7:  It should be I'm seating consideration to our editor
Speaker 7:  Achieve.
Speaker 3:  I will take Perme please for 200.
Speaker 7:  If you really want to hone Noobs, we'll connect
Speaker 7:  this SC system, which was the first to use both Bluetooth and
Speaker 7:  Blu-ray technologies. Alex Kranz,
Speaker 4:  What is the PlayStation three?
Speaker 7:  That's correct.
Speaker 3:  Oh, she got it.
Speaker 4:  Yes, I'm in the zeros.
Speaker 7:  You picked the next category.
Speaker 4:  Gen five SIS for a thousand.
Speaker 7:  Bluetooth was originally conceived as a wireless alternative to
Speaker 7:  this data cable. Alex Kranz, I
Speaker 4:  Want you to know my strategy today is to just hit the buzzer as soon as
Speaker 4:  Sean starts asking the questions every time, but I think
Speaker 4:  maybe what is scuzzy?
Speaker 3:  Wow, I know that's wrong.
Speaker 7:  Wrong. Eli Patel.
Speaker 3:  What is the 2.5 millimeter headphone cable
Speaker 7:  Incorrect?
Speaker 3:  No. Well, I was worth the shot. If it's U usb, I'm gonna be so mad. Chris,
Speaker 3:  can you just try and see if it's u sb?
Speaker 8:  I'm gonna keep my lead here.
Speaker 7:  The correct response in this case is RS 2 32. Wow. I
Speaker 7:  would've also accepted cereal.
Speaker 8:  Definitely had the one right in the back pocket.
Speaker 4:  Scuzzy is like cereal.
Speaker 3:  No, it's
Speaker 7:  Not crayons. You're next.
Speaker 4:  I'm gonna do Jenna five sis for
Speaker 4:  800.
Speaker 7:  Oh God. This was the data transfer speed of
Speaker 7:  Bluetooth 1.0 in 1999. Alex Crad,
Speaker 7:  slam Baam is the exact text I have in my buzzer window.
Speaker 4:  What is one megabit
Speaker 7:  Close? Anyone else?
Speaker 4:  Does that mean I lost? Yes.
Speaker 3:  What is 750 kilobits
Speaker 7:  That is also very close.
Speaker 3:  What is 751 kilobits?
Speaker 7:  The correct, sir is
Speaker 7:  721 kilobits per
Speaker 7:  zero per second.
Speaker 7:  Would any of you like to take a moment to reflect on how we all have negative
Speaker 7:  scores until we get to this?
Speaker 3:  We're doing great.
Speaker 7:  Eli is the lead with negative 2000.
Speaker 3:  Is that the lead? I think Chris is in the lead with negative 200.
Speaker 7:  That's correct. Cred. Pick the next please.
Speaker 4:  I'm gonna mix it up a little bluetooth.com
Speaker 4:  400.
Speaker 7:  This is a new Bluetooth audio capability that would allow
Speaker 7:  multiple devices to find and join an audio podcast via Bluetooth
Speaker 7:  in areas like concert venues and airports. And this question is very logged
Speaker 7:  Welch. What
Speaker 8:  Is Aura?
Speaker 7:  That's correct.
Speaker 8:  Wow.
Speaker 3:  I'm
Speaker 8:  Very proud of myself. For one correct answer.
Speaker 7:  We have a positive score on the board. Pick the next, let's
Speaker 8:  Get Wow. Let's do hack week for a thousand.
Speaker 7:  This open source USB device could sniff at monitor Bluetooth
Speaker 7:  signals from nearby devices using an antenna powered by an arm Cortex
Speaker 7:  M three chip cran slab. Abara,
Speaker 4:  What is the coconut?
Speaker 7:  No.
Speaker 3:  Can I have a clarification on the rules? Am I allowed to Google
Speaker 3:  the
Speaker 7:  Answers? No. The correct answer is the buer
Speaker 7:  tooth one.
Speaker 3:  Okay.
Speaker 4:  Stupid name?
Speaker 7:  Chris Welch.
Speaker 8:  Oh, okay. Let's go for bluetooth.com for 600
Speaker 8:  please.
Speaker 7:  Competing with standards like ZigBee and Thread, this standard
Speaker 7:  is designed to allow multiple Bluetooth devices to operate as beacons for
Speaker 7:  large scale device networks. Chris Welch,
Speaker 8:  What is Bluetooth mesh?
Speaker 7:  Yes, you pick. Next,
Speaker 8:  Let's do pair me please for 800.
Speaker 7:  This model of this fruitful computer introduced both wifi
Speaker 7:  and Bluetooth for the first time in 2016.
Speaker 4:  What is the raspberry pie?
Speaker 7:  Yes.
Speaker 4:  Yes. NEA and I are tied now
Speaker 3:  You're going down Cranz.
Speaker 4:  I'm gonna do Pop Piri for 800
Speaker 7:  FCC filings by GameStop in 2020. Depicted a Bluetooth speaker that looked
Speaker 7:  like this Pokemon ne Eli Patel.
Speaker 3:  I only know the name of one Pokemon and it's Pikachu and it's gotta be Pikachu,
Speaker 7:  No
Speaker 3:  Dammit.
Speaker 7:  Alex Kranz.
Speaker 4:  What is Charmander
Speaker 7:  Incorrect?
Speaker 3:  Paul? Oh an now we just have to name Pokemon for the rest of the show.
Speaker 4:  Chris Buzz in. Buzz in. You got this.
Speaker 8:  Those two? No, I'm wanna throw in the towel on this one.
Speaker 7:  The correct response in this case is jiggly puff.
Speaker 4:  I was gonna say jiggly puff and I was like it's gotta be one of the starters.
Speaker 7:  Mili at Alex. Give it that you are currently in negative numbers. How
Speaker 7:  do you plan to pay back the money?
Speaker 3:  I'm gonna go with spectacular by 200.
Speaker 7:  This system introduced with Bluetooth 2.0 increased the security
Speaker 7:  provided by a Bluetooth link as well as baking the pairing process.
Speaker 7:  More user-friendly. Eli Patel.
Speaker 3:  What is edr?
Speaker 7:  No, Alex Kranz.
Speaker 4:  So actually is Bluetooth even secure?
Speaker 3:  No, just says increase the security. It didn't say secure.
Speaker 4:  Who's determined that? Can I get some clarification?
Speaker 7:  I'm sorry, we're out of time.
Speaker 3:  How is filibustering Jeopardy?
Speaker 7:  The correct answer is simple. Secure paring.
Speaker 7:  Eli, you go again.
Speaker 3:  Spectacular for 400.
Speaker 7:  One of the most significant changes in this version of Bluetooth was
Speaker 7:  the ability to transfer data. Oprah, wifi. Eli,
Speaker 3:  What is Bluetooth 2.1?
Speaker 7:  No,
Speaker 3:  What is Bluetooth 4.0?
Speaker 7:  Eddie, what else? Wanna ask Alex? Kratz,
Speaker 4:  What is Bluetooth 3.0?
Speaker 3:  Yes. No. Yes.
Speaker 4:  Thank you for narrowing it down.
Speaker 3:  Chris is just never gonna answer a question again.
Speaker 8:  Exactly. I'm just gonna sit on this lead.
Speaker 7:  Currently we have Chris Welch at the lead with 800 points. Alex
Speaker 7:  Crad with the command dig second at negative $2,400
Speaker 7:  and Eli bringing up the lead at negative 3,200.
Speaker 3:  I appreciate that you continue referring to it as the lead. Thank you for
Speaker 3:  that
Speaker 7:  Alex, it's your pick.
Speaker 4:  I'm gonna do spectacular for a thousand.
Speaker 7:  This is Sony's own Bluetooth Kodak, which enables transmission
Speaker 7:  of high res audio at a maximum bit rate of 990
Speaker 7:  kilobits per second. Chris Welch,
Speaker 8:  Time to pad the lead here a little bit. What is l a?
Speaker 7:  Correct?
Speaker 8:  Let's do pair me please. 600.
Speaker 7:  This was the first Kindle to support Bluetooth audio.
Speaker 7:  Oh, Alex Cranz.
Speaker 4:  What is the original Kindle?
Speaker 7:  No,
Speaker 4:  I have to go away now.
Speaker 3:  There are so many Kindles you can just make up names.
Speaker 4:  It has not worked for either of us before this.
Speaker 8:  What is the Oasis?
Speaker 7:  No, the Oasis was not the first with Bluetooth audio. That was
Speaker 7:  the eighth generation Kindle. Of course I did not know
Speaker 7:  until today.
Speaker 4:  I should have just said Kindle. You
Speaker 3:  Should have just said Kindle
Speaker 7:  Chris, you'll continue
Speaker 8:  Apparently. So let's do bluetooth.com for 800.
Speaker 7:  According to ABI research, this many Bluetooth
Speaker 7:  data transfer devices will ship in 2022.
Speaker 4:  Can I ask a clarification question?
Speaker 7:  Sure, let's do it.
Speaker 4:  Does that mean like phones? Just anything with Bluetooth
Speaker 4:  in
Speaker 3:  It? No, it's a standard. It's a new standard. It's a thing.
Speaker 4:  Well, I'm not gonna try to answer this.
Speaker 3:  Will you? Just like hell at the spelling bee, you're like, can I define
Speaker 3:  every word please?
Speaker 4:  I lost to Buffalo
Speaker 7:  And we're out of time. The answer is 1 billion.
Speaker 4:  Oh, I was gonna guess that.
Speaker 3:  I've been burned too many times. Let's
Speaker 7:  Keep going Chris,
Speaker 8:  Let's do hack week for 400.
Speaker 7:  Often seen as a security threat, sending a picture or message from one
Speaker 7:  user to an unsuspecting user through Bluetooth wired list technology
Speaker 7:  is called this. Alex Kranz.
Speaker 4:  What is my ride home on the subway?
Speaker 7:  I like it, but no, Chris Welch.
Speaker 8:  What is Beam?
Speaker 7:  No.
Speaker 3:  Okay, I buzzed in and I wanna say if I guess, and it's close to
Speaker 3:  right? I want the points.
Speaker 7:  I'll consider it.
Speaker 3:  What is Blue Nerfing?
Speaker 7:  The correct answer is what is Bluejack?
Speaker 3:  See, I knew it was something like that. It's close enough,
Speaker 7:  Not close enough, but unfortunately
Speaker 8:  He had blue and the verb part down. Yeah, it's you know,
Speaker 3:  See I I knew it was something
Speaker 7:  Like that. Once again, Chris Welch had the last correct answer so let's continue
Speaker 7:  on.
Speaker 8:  Okay, let's see what happens when we do Pair me please for a
Speaker 8:  thousand.
Speaker 7:  This Bluetooth speaker with the most recent number one on our
Speaker 7:  best Bluetooth speaker list@theversion.com. This is claiming it
Speaker 7:  offers pristine, detailed sound quality with a surprising
Speaker 7:  amount of bass for its size. All at a rugged design you
Speaker 7:  could take anywhere. Chris Welch,
Speaker 8:  It's possible that I wrote this article possible.
Speaker 8:  What is the bows SoundLink Flex.
Speaker 7:  Unfortunately that is the correct answer.
Speaker 3:  Unfortunately
Speaker 4:  This was
Speaker 8:  Cheating. That's good. That's not very fair. Even I can acknowledge that.
Speaker 7:  Good. Let's keep the good times. Rolling. Chris Welch, your next category
Speaker 8:  Hack week for 600, please.
Speaker 7:  In 2004, Nokia and Sony Ericks had admitted some of their
Speaker 7:  handsets were vulnerable to this, a method of hacking into
Speaker 7:  a Bluetooth-enabled device and accessing personal information.
Speaker 7:  Alex Kranz,
Speaker 4:  What is Blue Nerfing
Speaker 7:  Correct?
Speaker 9:  Yes. Come
Speaker 3:  On man. It's the worst outcome
Speaker 7:  And be like do continuous. To slide into oblivion.
Speaker 3:  First of all, I would like some points for even knowing that Blue
Speaker 3:  Scarfing was a term and having that in my brain. I can't remember
Speaker 3:  people's names. I forgot my own child's name the other day and I'm hold it
Speaker 3:  on to blue scarfing. That's worth a thousand points. With
Speaker 7:  The last correct answer, we have Chris Welch with 1800 points,
Speaker 7:  Alex at negative 2,800 and negative 3,600.
Speaker 3:  I'm sorry. The moral victory of knowing that Blue scarfing was a real word
Speaker 3:  is very high and I'm currently the winner. I'm just putting that out there.
Speaker 4:  I want you to know, I did not know it was a real word. I thought you made
Speaker 4:  it up.
Speaker 3:  I can't believe I confused Blue Scarfing and Bluejack. That's a rookie Bluetooth
Speaker 3:  jeopardy mistake.
Speaker 7:  Crad, wanna continue this?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I'm gonna do a RI for 1000.
Speaker 4:  That was my really good Sean Connery impression.
Speaker 3:  That's good, thanks.
Speaker 7:  This year the Bluetooth standard organization thought this company
Speaker 7:  was trying to get a free ride by putting Bluetooth brand
Speaker 7:  in cars without paying requisite product declaration fees. Those
Speaker 7:  last five words are in air quotes. We're getting its cars certified.
Speaker 7:  Nelia Patel,
Speaker 3:  Who is Stelmanis or fca? It's one of, they're the same company.
Speaker 7:  Yes, it's
Speaker 3:  Correct, yes. I'm deeply aware of when Chrysler is doing dumb things.
Speaker 3:  My zone.
Speaker 7:  Nela, you're next.
Speaker 3:  Oh no, I can't. I can't. You can't follow the highs with the lows.
Speaker 3:  Let's go with spectacular for 600.
Speaker 7:  This subset of Bluetooth War 0.0 was previously known as
Speaker 7:  wiry, which was intended for such industries as fitness, security and home
Speaker 7:  entertainment. It later tried to track the novel Coronavirus
Speaker 3:  Wiry.
Speaker 7:  I will accept wiry as a pronunciation
Speaker 3:  And we know what wiry is.
Speaker 7:  You probably know what the answer to this one is.
Speaker 3:  I do because I can guess. I mean, just,
Speaker 7:  Just, just, just guess
Speaker 3:  What is Bluetooth? Ellie?
Speaker 7:  The correct answer is Bluetooth, low energy
Speaker 3:  There. Kick
Speaker 7:  Us off again.
Speaker 3:  Spectacular for 800.
Speaker 7:  These are sets of specifications or rules that determine how a Bluetooth
Speaker 7:  device is used, whether it's hand three has land access or even an
Speaker 7:  iPod accessory. Nii.
Speaker 3:  What are Bluetooth profiles?
Speaker 7:  Yes,
Speaker 3:  I knew this is my category.
Speaker 7:  And one more.
Speaker 3:  Now I want to stop.
Speaker 3:  Let's go with bluetooth.com for 200.
Speaker 7:  This is the standards organization and they've already buzzed in
Speaker 7:  the standards organization that oversees the development of Bluetooth standards
Speaker 7:  and licensing of the Bluetooth technologies and trademarks to manufacturers.
Speaker 7:  The answer. Chris Welch,
Speaker 8:  What is the Bluetooth sig?
Speaker 7:  Yes.
Speaker 4:  How did he
Speaker 8:  Know? Just got in ahead of Eli.
Speaker 7:  Next one, Chris.
Speaker 8:  Okay, let's do RI for 600
Speaker 7:  On the company's website. This speaker is listed to have
Speaker 7:  nine ways to listen to audio, none of which is pairing via
Speaker 7:  Bluetooth. Alex crayons.
Speaker 4:  What is the Sonos? Chris?
Speaker 4:  Nod or or or turn away.
Speaker 3:  Give gimme,
Speaker 4:  Gimme tips.
Speaker 7:  We're moving on. Anybody else? Wanna try the Eli Patel?
Speaker 3:  What is the HomePod mini
Speaker 7:  Dad might be true. The answer is the apple HomePod.
Speaker 8:  I think the judges can accept that. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Next ne Eli, you're up again. I
Speaker 3:  Gotta say the exhilaration of this run. It's too much.
Speaker 4:  You're almost into the
Speaker 3:  Positives. Pair me please for 400
Speaker 7:  And the answer. A daily double. Just kidding.
Speaker 7:  There's no round two.
Speaker 3:  Thank God.
Speaker 7:  In 2021, this device had a surprise upgrade
Speaker 7:  that added Bluetooth audio support four years after its initial
Speaker 7:  release. Chris Welch,
Speaker 8:  What is the Nintendo Switch?
Speaker 7:  That's correct, right pick again.
Speaker 8:  Let's just close out the bluetooth.com for a thousand.
Speaker 7:  And here's the clue. Recently it was announced Bluetooth would be
Speaker 7:  expanding into this frequency spectrum band and according to
Speaker 7:  bluetooth.com it will pay of the way for the next 20 years
Speaker 7:  of Bluetooth innovation.
Speaker 7:  And we're running out of time. Well
Speaker 4:  I'm trying to type faster into my phone to Google it but it's not working.
Speaker 3:  I was just like I can't cheat fast enough.
Speaker 7:  And the correct response response in this case is
Speaker 7:  the six gigahertz spectrum band.
Speaker 3:  I could have guessed
Speaker 7:  That. Also handy for certain forms of wifi. Next
Speaker 7:  let's go again with Chris.
Speaker 8:  Let's do hack week for 203.
Speaker 7:  Former campaign aids to this elected official told
Speaker 7:  West Wing playbook. She does not use Bluetooth headsets for security reasons
Speaker 7:  and insists on using wired headphones instead. Eli,
Speaker 3:  Who's Kamala Harris?
Speaker 7:  That's correct.
Speaker 3:  This story is great.
Speaker 7:  Go again.
Speaker 3:  I'm so close to the positive. Let's go with hack week for 800.
Speaker 7:  Limited to class two Bluetooth radios. This form of Bluetooth attack
Speaker 7:  creates a backdoor for hackers, which could allow them to list it
Speaker 7:  on the phone conversations.
Speaker 4:  Give us a hint just like a
Speaker 7:  Little hint. I have a hint. It is not blue snrp.
Speaker 4:  Is it Jingly
Speaker 7:  Puff? Okay, we're out of time. It's blue. Bu
Speaker 3:  So far in this episode of Jeopardy, we've heard about Bluejack, blue snaring
Speaker 3:  and now blue bugging. There's
Speaker 4:  Nothing left in hack
Speaker 3:  Week. I was gonna say tooth spoofing with no G at the end.
Speaker 7:  I like it.
Speaker 3:  All right, we gotta knock down this Genesis category. Let's
Speaker 3:  go to Genesis for 200.
Speaker 7:  The king with a dental problem. United, Denmark, and
Speaker 7:  Norway in 9 58 ad Alex Kranz, who
Speaker 4:  Is Harold Bluetooth.
Speaker 7:  I will accept that it is King Harold Bluetooth goon.
Speaker 4:  That's misspelled. Someone misspelled this. His name is
Speaker 4:  Harold.
Speaker 7:  Go again.
Speaker 4:  I'm gonna do Genesis for 400 and hope Eli doesn't get it
Speaker 4:  right.
Speaker 7:  Intel Nokia and this industry leader met to plan
Speaker 7:  the standardization of Bluetooth in 1996. Chris
Speaker 7:  Welch.
Speaker 3:  What is Qualcomm?
Speaker 7:  No nela.
Speaker 3:  Who is Sony Erickson?
Speaker 7:  Erickson is the correct answer. Dammit. We'll give you the points.
Speaker 3:  Yes. Oh, I'm at zero. I'm done. No more answers from me. I
Speaker 3:  bought myself bags in negative territory. You're not bluejack this away
Speaker 3:  from me. Pori for 400.
Speaker 7:  He said this about Bluetooth. There are quality issues. The bandwidth
Speaker 7:  isn't high enough and even if it does get there someday, people don't want
Speaker 7:  to recharge their headphones. Ni Eli.
Speaker 3:  Who is Steve Jobs?
Speaker 7:  Yes.
Speaker 3:  That's a classic Steve Jobs
Speaker 7:  Quote. As we go into our last two questions, we have Chris Welch, the lead
Speaker 7:  with 2000 ni Eli at 400 and Alex
Speaker 7:  at negative $3,000.
Speaker 4:  I can still bring this around.
Speaker 7:  That leaves our final question, Genesis for 600
Speaker 7:  and the answer is this was the first mobile
Speaker 7:  phone to include Bluetooth in 2001.
Speaker 3:  Somewhere Deiter Bone is crying that he can't be answering this question
Speaker 3:  right now
Speaker 7:  And nobody is buzzing in.
Speaker 3:  Can we say company?
Speaker 7:  You can say whatever you like. Whether you get the points or not. We'll depend
Speaker 7:  on how close it is. Eli,
Speaker 3:  What is the Nokia N 92.
Speaker 7:  Not even close. Anyone else?
Speaker 7:  3, 2, 1.
Speaker 7:  The answer is the Sony Erickson T 39.
Speaker 7:  I would've also accepted T 36.
Speaker 3:  Okay, I would like some points for saying brand name and letters and numbers.
Speaker 3:  You get that? I got the format of the answer correct.
Speaker 7:  Don't take his points away. He was in the
Speaker 1:  Positive.
Speaker 3:  I wasn't like, what is the HCC bacon? I was like, what are some letters
Speaker 3:  and
Speaker 7:  Numbers? Alright ladies and gentlemen, we'll be right back with
Speaker 7:  final jeopardy.
Speaker 10:  This is David at The Verge and this is the Motorola hint. This is sort of
Speaker 10:  the smallest of the announcements that Motorola had today. It's a tiny
Speaker 10:  little Bluetooth headset. They don't want to call it a Bluetooth headset
Speaker 10:  cuz there's all sorts of stigmas with that, but it's a Bluetooth headset.
Speaker 10:  It's made to be super discreet and nice looking. It comes in this wood plus
Speaker 10:  a bunch of other materials that are designed to look really, really nice
Speaker 10:  in your ear. And on one level it's just a Bluetooth headset. You put it
Speaker 10:  in your ear, you make phone calls, you can do voice control on the phone
Speaker 10:  and there's all this cool Motorola assist in Motorola actions and stuff
Speaker 10:  that all work. But on the other hand, it's kind of extra special for a
Speaker 10:  Bluetooth headset for the one thing, it's time for another thing. It's super
Speaker 10:  sensitive so it's made to go in your ear just like this. And there's a sensor
Speaker 10:  on it that recognizes when it's in your ear and it'll automatically turn
Speaker 10:  on and connect and then as soon as you take it out, it'll disconnect. And
Speaker 10:  even if you're on a call, it'll route it straight back to your phone. So
Speaker 10:  it's made to be super simple and to basically be worn all day. But you can
Speaker 10:  have it come and go as you please. So it's $149. It's designed
Speaker 10:  to be used with the new Moto X and the Moto G, but it'll work with lots
Speaker 10:  of other phones too. There's some special stuff with the way that one x
Speaker 10:  works that makes it even better for voice actions. But the Moto hint is
Speaker 10:  designed as really, it's a wearable, it's not a Bluetooth headset though,
Speaker 10:  it's kind of a Bluetooth headset. So the hint is kind of a weird little
Speaker 10:  accessory. I'm not sure how many people are gonna get into it. I kind of
Speaker 10:  like it, but we'll see how it does when it comes out with the Mox. This
Speaker 10:  fall
Speaker 3:  2014.
Speaker 7:  Okay, we're back. This is our final jeopardy question.
Speaker 7:  The first version of Bluetooth used a modulation scheme
Speaker 7:  called this, which modulated carrier shifts between
Speaker 7:  two frequencies representing ones and zeros.
Speaker 7:  You have 30 seconds. Good luck.
Speaker 1:  I
Speaker 3:  Mean the police are coming because we're playing this music. I'm very,
Speaker 7:  All right, let's see what our contestants wrote. Chris, you're in the lead.
Speaker 7:  So let's begin. You have 2000 points. What was your
Speaker 7:  answer?
Speaker 8:  I have no answer, but I also wagered no money and I drew a
Speaker 8:  smiley face to,
Speaker 8:  to signal my victory.
Speaker 7:  Well played nek.
Speaker 3:  All right. I wagered $5,000 and I wrote
Speaker 3:  frequency shift pulsing.
Speaker 7:  Hmm
Speaker 3:  Huh
Speaker 8:  Interest.
Speaker 7:  That was not the answer. Let's see how much it's going to cost you. $5,000.
Speaker 7:  Okay,
Speaker 7:  Alex Cranz with negative 3000. What did you decide to dip your
Speaker 7:  pockets into?
Speaker 4:  So I put a billion dollars on the line
Speaker 4:  for binary baby shuffle.
Speaker 7:  Excellent, excellent. The correct answer was
Speaker 7:  gf, sk
Speaker 4:  I was close.
Speaker 7:  Gaussian frequency shift. Keach,
Speaker 3:  I got some words in there. Yes, that
Speaker 7:  Counts. I feel like some of your random words were, were among the right
Speaker 7:  words. Something
Speaker 8:  To do with the frequency.
Speaker 3:  You might use the word frequency and the word shift, which you
Speaker 3:  earned in the question.
Speaker 4:  He gets 2,500, give him 2,500. He earned it. Don't
Speaker 4:  put 'em in the
Speaker 7:  Negative. And the winner of today is Chris Welch with
Speaker 7:  2000 FTX tokens. Thank you. Her pledge.
Speaker 3:  Chris has won nothing. You know I would be in the lead if I'd
Speaker 3:  under, if I remembered the difference between Bluejack and Blueing. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  I just wanna put that out there.
Speaker 7:  We'll be right back with more of the Bluetooth holiday
Speaker 7:  spectacular.
Speaker 5:  Today's episode is sponsored by Airbnb. Airbnb lets you
Speaker 5:  book comfortable stays all around the world. So comfortable, they might even
Speaker 5:  feel like home, which might lead you to wonder could my place be an Airbnb?
Speaker 5:  And if it was, what could it earn? The exciting answer to that question
Speaker 5:  is that right now you could be sitting on an Airbnb and not even know it.
Speaker 5:  Maybe you have a spare room that's already a haven for visiting friends and
Speaker 5:  family. So why not make it an Airbnb and make some extra cash
Speaker 5:  instead of letting it sit empty. Some people Airbnb their entire homes
Speaker 5:  when they're away for holidays or a big trip. That's a great way to help
Speaker 5:  cover the plane tickets. Whether you could use a little extra money to stash
Speaker 5:  away for a rainy day or you're saving up for something fun, your home
Speaker 5:  might be worth more than you think. Find out how much at
Speaker 5:  airbnb.com/host
Speaker 5:  Support for this episode comes from another bite. If you're a Shark Tank
Speaker 5:  fan or business junkie, then you'll love another bite. Each week the
Speaker 5:  host breaks down the biggest success stories and most disastrous failures
Speaker 5:  to come out of Shark Tank. From the Squatty Potty to the Waken Bacon, they
Speaker 5:  dive into each company's pitch, analyze the deals that were or
Speaker 5:  weren't made and answer the million dollar question. Is that company
Speaker 5:  still a company? Basically they cover all the things you need to know to
Speaker 5:  survive the tank or scale a company on your own. Whether you're
Speaker 5:  an entrepreneur looking for tips or a fan looking to relive the show's most
Speaker 5:  dramatic moments, another bite offers a deep dive into the world of Shark
Speaker 5:  Tank. Just search for another bite in your favorite podcast app
Speaker 5:  like the one you're using right now.
Speaker 3:  Happy holidays and welcome back to the VER has Bluetooth
Speaker 3:  holiday spectacular full hour of audio about
Speaker 3:  Bluetooth. We've got an all-star panel here on a holiday Bluetooth
Speaker 3:  spectacular talk about Bluetooth, where it is now, the future of it
Speaker 3:  and the many threats that face our favorite
Speaker 3:  low range. And quite honestly, taxed wireless standard.
Speaker 3:  Chris, it's, it's all the same people who played Jeopardy. Like what am I,
Speaker 3:  what are we doing here? I'm here. I'm Eli. Chris Welch is here. Hey Chris.
Speaker 3:  Hey Sean. Haler, who was the host of Jeopardy now finds himself on
Speaker 3:  the other side of the equation. Welcome Sean.
Speaker 7:  It it is horror. I I am your friend who, who wishes I had some
Speaker 7:  earbuds that had pairing to multiple devices at once. That'd be great.
Speaker 3:  And Cranz is here. Hey
Speaker 4:  Cranz, I'm your friend who's pissed at Sean for his rude
Speaker 4:  scoring of me during Jeopardy.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, Sean, I don't know if you understand the point of this segment is revenge
Speaker 3:  taking, of course our inspiration from Bluetooth Notorious Pirate
Speaker 3:  who sought only revenge. I have not read anything about said pirate.
Speaker 3:  I just tease a pirate.
Speaker 7:  The Verge has been about a revenge for a very long time. It's, it's, it's
Speaker 7:  fitting that we bring it back for Christmas.
Speaker 3:  Sean and I are, we are, these are founders. We founded this whole site on
Speaker 3:  revenge. So this is all fitting. Okay, let's talk about Bluetooth in the
Speaker 3:  context of the holidays, Chris, it's, you cover the, the headphones space
Speaker 3:  pretty carefully. It seems like the moment for Bluetooth
Speaker 3:  right now is everyone has hit the bandwidth limits of Bluetooth as
Speaker 3:  we know it and they're doing stuff next to it. They're doing stuff
Speaker 3:  on top of it. What is going on here?
Speaker 8:  Yeah, I mean I think they're all trying to just kind of stand out with their
Speaker 8:  headphones quality. Samsung has their own Kodak. You've got Sony with
Speaker 8:  ldac, which is actually kind of spread between a bunch of headphones makers
Speaker 8:  and then there's, there's Qualcomm Snap track and sound, which might
Speaker 8:  be CD quality sometime soon. But you're gonna need new earbuds and who knows,
Speaker 8:  probably a new phone. I
Speaker 7:  Got pitches literally today.
Speaker 4:  We're not just CD quality yet.
Speaker 8:  I mean Sony's close-ish. Samsung says they can do
Speaker 8:  a 24 bit audio on the Buds two Pro, but like the actual bit rate is
Speaker 8:  unclear. So who knows what quality it actually is. It's all just a mess.
Speaker 8:  But like yeah, the idea is that they can say like these products are now
Speaker 8:  hi-fi or just sound better than they did before. So you upgrade and buy a
Speaker 8:  new set of headphones your buds or
Speaker 4:  They'll now work with title.
Speaker 8:  Yeah title but no Spotify hi-fi which was announced almost two years ago
Speaker 8:  and has yet to come to fruition.
Speaker 7:  So the protocol itself is like just a few megabits per second,
Speaker 7:  right? That's, that's all you can transmit between Bluetooth devices at a
Speaker 7:  time. And so that's the the hesitation here.
Speaker 8:  Yeah that and plus like the actual, so the file codex that's Apples used
Speaker 8:  the AAC codec forever. They felt no need to ever go beyond that
Speaker 8:  so far.
Speaker 3:  By the way, apple will claim that the actual Kodak they use between
Speaker 3:  the phone and AirPods is they're tweaking it all the time
Speaker 3:  and improving it all the time. This is what they claim. Is it stock AAC
Speaker 3:  or is Apple messing with it AC on the edges all the time to do
Speaker 3:  some proprietary AirPod stuff that no one else has access to?
Speaker 3:  We don't know. We can't verify what they're actually doing between their
Speaker 3:  own devices and their closed ecosystem. And this is what everyone else seems
Speaker 3:  to be doing right? Like you, you are stuck with a handful of codex that you
Speaker 3:  can license from Snapdragon or Sony or whatever, but you're stuck with some
Speaker 3:  basic limitations of Bluetooth and then you have to add
Speaker 3:  on to them or do something proprietary to add more features or
Speaker 3:  more sound quality. And that doesn't seem like the industry is settled on
Speaker 3:  standards. It seems like Samsung is basically like what wouldn't it be cool
Speaker 3:  if everyone bought Samsung headphones and they bought the Oxy phone?
Speaker 8:  Yeah, I mean when you have like seven different codex, there's just a lot
Speaker 8:  going on and I don't know how anybody really keeps it straight. Like someone
Speaker 8:  who just goes and buys a new pair of headphones from like Sennheiser or Bowers
Speaker 8:  and Wilkins, like they support stuff like Apex and like Apex HD and
Speaker 8:  Apex Lossless. Even that one standard has like four
Speaker 8:  tiers of different supporters. So it's gotten
Speaker 8:  a bit jumbled. I
Speaker 7:  Think part of this is that the standards aren't very good.
Speaker 7:  Like I j I just wrote about this with the steam deck. If you wanna set up
Speaker 7:  your Bluetooth earbuds and hear what you're doing on your game system, the
Speaker 7:  default is that it uses a profile that is not low
Speaker 7:  latency. It's supposed to be like high quality instead of low latency. And
Speaker 7:  so you have this tremendous lag and I swing a sword and I don't hear it till
Speaker 7:  almost entire second is passed. Where's my woosh? I wanna hear my woosh.
Speaker 7:  But they have to, they have to choose between the high quality of their low
Speaker 7:  latency. You don't get both automatically.
Speaker 8:  So it's Sony if you use the LDAC Kodak and you choose like the highest setting,
Speaker 8:  I think it's like nine, 960 like kilobits per second. It gets like really
Speaker 8:  unstable when it cuts out constantly. So even that like at its best quality
Speaker 8:  just doesn't work very well. So I think if there is like a next step to come
Speaker 8:  and it sounds like Qualcomm has new chips coming for phones that ends
Speaker 8:  some for headphones too. That'll like make things more stable and hopefully
Speaker 8:  keep that higher quality and actually so you can enjoy it, not just have
Speaker 8:  cutouts all the time.
Speaker 3:  So Apple uses a C, other people are using other proprietary code acts like
Speaker 3:  ldac and Snap Track and sound. Yeah, great name. But
Speaker 3:  it sounds like there's an actual Bluetooth audio Kodak
Speaker 3:  upgrade coming with lc three. It sounds like there's
Speaker 3:  functionality updates coming with or cast. What's going on there?
Speaker 8:  So I haven't really looked into AutoCast much. I think it's just gonna be
Speaker 8:  one of those things where you can compare with like multiple devices at once
Speaker 8:  or like, like several phones can compare to one speaker. Things like that.
Speaker 7:  Theoretically I love this idea you're gonna be in your airport or your hospital
Speaker 7:  and you're listening to your music on your earbuds, but you've also apparently
Speaker 7:  opted in to connect to like the local acast access point.
Speaker 7:  And so you'll hear your airport at Outspent and instead of them trying to
Speaker 7:  like pump up the sound to a ridiculous level which blows at everybody's
Speaker 7:  ears just so they can get through the earbuds that you have on, it'll just
Speaker 7:  go directly there and hopefully also not blow out your ears
Speaker 4:  Like magic.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. They're gonna find a way to use that for advertising in in one second.
Speaker 3:  I'm just,
Speaker 3:  I just, I just know how this goes. Yeah that seems interesting, right? Like
Speaker 3:  everything is wireless, there are new seat back. I think United has new seat
Speaker 3:  backs entertainment units that have Bluetooth but the actual
Speaker 3:  like lc three Kodak functionality, it's not
Speaker 3:  out yet. When's that coming?
Speaker 8:  I think it's starting to rollout my latest version of Android supports it
Speaker 8:  and there's some earbuds that will get updates for it but it's not so much
Speaker 8:  about quality. Like it's about more efficiency and so it's not so much gonna
Speaker 8:  like change the game in terms of like you know, like lossless streaming or
Speaker 8:  any of that. It's just gonna be more efficient and should work better
Speaker 4:  So it'll approve battery life.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, stuff like that.
Speaker 3:  So Chris just like let's run down the list here. So Sony has l a,
Speaker 3:  it tops out at nine 90. You're saying it's unreliable. There's standard
Speaker 3:  Bluetooth SBC which tops out at 3 28.
Speaker 3:  The fact that we're only at CD quality and I get why people say CD quality
Speaker 3:  cuz once you get above it it's very hard for people to hear the difference.
Speaker 8:  Like right, I mean most people say that you can't even tell the difference
Speaker 8:  between like AAC and CD quality and that's what Apple said for years and
Speaker 8:  years and years until suddenly there was spatial audio and and
Speaker 8:  lossless on Apple Music.
Speaker 3:  But Apple stuff even over wireless, there's no lossless over any wireless
Speaker 3:  connection to an Apple product. Right? Right. And even on a phone they kind
Speaker 3:  of want you to plug in a different DAC to get lossless out of it. So just
Speaker 3:  compare and contrast these, these codex for me, like inside of
Speaker 3:  Bluetooth there's a bunch of ways to get audio out
Speaker 3:  and most of them are hitting a limit and then
Speaker 3:  there's the functionality stuff like or cast pair stuff to any TV you're
Speaker 3:  walking by simply there's Apples H one
Speaker 3:  and H two chips where they're, they're controlling the connection more
Speaker 3:  directly in a proprietary way than no one else has access to. There's fast
Speaker 3:  pair and Android. What's left of this standard? Like what's the point?
Speaker 8:  I think it's just a case where people just build on top of it and build on
Speaker 8:  top of it and build on top of it and CFR they can push it. I mean you've
Speaker 8:  also got like spatial audio and all that stuff that's on the AirPods coming
Speaker 8:  soon to the pixel buds pro that's already on Samsung earbuds. So let's just
Speaker 8:  like how can we build on top of just the core earbuds experience and keep
Speaker 8:  selling new pairs? Cuz if they sound great then that's not all that matters.
Speaker 8:  Obviously they want to like isn't
Speaker 4:  The core experience though kind of crummy Like I, I think
Speaker 4:  we, we all make the sacrifice of using these earbuds because they're way
Speaker 4:  more convenient and also because everybody got rid of the port to plug
Speaker 4:  in regular ear earbuds but they're still kind of crummy. Like we were talking
Speaker 4:  about this before we started recording. Anytime I leave my house, if I touch
Speaker 4:  the door just right, it'll disconnect my
Speaker 4:  earbuds consistently. Right. And for
Speaker 4:  years like it has to actually send the audio signal to both
Speaker 4:  earbuds because it can't communicate through your body
Speaker 4:  because Bluetooth's like biggest problem is dealing with the fact that water
Speaker 4:  exists, right? Like it feels like we Bluetooth has a limit and everybody's
Speaker 4:  just like we're gonna keep piling on top of the garbage pile because we don't
Speaker 4:  have anything else.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, I think it's gotten a bit better in that regard. Like I think most
Speaker 8:  of the recent earbuds and headphones I reviewed have much fewer cutout to
Speaker 8:  them. They used to like there are like parts of the city where I would walk
Speaker 8:  down and most stuff from like a few years ago would always drop out and constantly
Speaker 8:  cut out. But now it's gotten a lot better.
Speaker 4:  The Union square station was like an earbud killer
Speaker 4:  for years,
Speaker 8:  Right? That and like Bryant Park in a lot of areas,
Speaker 7:  I think it's one of the most intriguing things about the standard is that
Speaker 7:  you know, the one constant with every standard is that companies
Speaker 7:  love to rebrand it to sell you shit, to make it seem like you need
Speaker 7:  their proprietary shit to make things work. Even though it's actually a standard
Speaker 7:  like H D M I C C or USB versus
Speaker 7:  Thunderbolt. But here this is, this is a situation where
Speaker 7:  each of these companies is actually improving Bluetooth
Speaker 7:  in some way and it's a problem that the standard isn't
Speaker 7:  good enough that they are pulling it in all these different
Speaker 7:  proprietary directions.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, I don't think Apple ever says that AirPods or Bluetooth headphones,
Speaker 3:  I think they're over it, right? They're just AirPods, you connect 'em to
Speaker 3:  your iPhone and they work great and they pair to iCloud to your Mac and your
Speaker 3:  Apple TV and whatever else. You just see Samsung trying to run the same
Speaker 3:  playbook. You see Google trying to run the same playbook and underneath
Speaker 3:  it all is the sense that okay Bluetooth is a connectivity
Speaker 3:  protocol and we can just run whatever Codex and whatever control software
Speaker 3:  over that protocol to make the connection more stable. And I do not see
Speaker 3:  a ton of investment into making Bluetooth itself better for all the
Speaker 3:  devices in the ecosystem to play better together. The way that you honestly
Speaker 3:  see it with wifi, you actually do see it with h dmmi
Speaker 3:  like when we did the h dmmi spectaculars cuz of HDMI 2.1 and like
Speaker 3:  VR R came out and now all the TV support variable refresh and it all, I
Speaker 3:  would say it sort of works like it works more than it doesn't in a way that
Speaker 3:  Bluetooth, you know, the refrain is it'll be better next year. Then
Speaker 3:  there's all the other stuff Bluetooth is supposed to do, like run
Speaker 3:  your smart home and form Bluetooth le connections to pair wifi
Speaker 3:  devices to your phone and it's fine at that stuff. I think
Speaker 3:  in that, in those cases it's a utility, right? You bought a smart
Speaker 3:  plug you need to get it into home kit, you can just like wave your phone
Speaker 3:  at it and it'll like pick up a Bluetooth connection and pair your smart plug.
Speaker 3:  But that's neat. But I fundamentally like Bluetooth as a
Speaker 3:  protocol has now been shoved into like this thing that
Speaker 3:  headphone makers have to use that they would like to run away from as fast
Speaker 3:  as they can or they would like to hide as much as they can.
Speaker 7:  If you look back at the last 15 years of Bluetooth and, and I always think
Speaker 7:  back to like the Motorola, like HT eight 20 like
Speaker 7:  cinnamon bun stereo headphones that I bought my wife.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Which were like the first Bluetooth stereo headphones and I think about
Speaker 7:  how shitty those were in so many ways.
Speaker 7:  Not like the pairing and the audio quality everything you had to do the
Speaker 7:  memorization of like like how many seconds do I hold down which button on
Speaker 7:  which side to make them pair properly? And like if I look at every like
Speaker 7:  five year span, I wanna say that audio quality and connectivity
Speaker 7:  and pairing have improved substantially from like one five year block to
Speaker 7:  the next.
Speaker 3:  Chris do you think audio quality is improved substantially from one five
Speaker 3:  of your block to the next? I think this is like the heart of what we're kind
Speaker 3:  of talking about here is yeah sort of
Speaker 8:  It's easy to fall down a well of like what matters most like the Kodak or
Speaker 8:  like the mastering of a song like Apple even has their own like custom mastering
Speaker 8:  of songs. They've got this whole program called Mastered for iTunes or not
Speaker 8:  iTunes anymore but Apple Music. And so they have like their own files of
Speaker 8:  songs that you don't get on Spotify from Amazon. So like is that what sounds
Speaker 8:  good or is it the Kodak or is it the he headphone tuning or what on the whole
Speaker 8:  I think they sound better than like five years ago. Like if you compare something
Speaker 8:  like the SONY thousand XM five versus the thousand XM three or
Speaker 8:  twos. Yeah there's been some improvements. I mean it's a slow incline. I
Speaker 4:  Mean I've got the the XM threes or the the noise
Speaker 4:  canceling ones to the 1000 XM threes.
Speaker 4:  Is that what they were called?
Speaker 8:  Love the name. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Would I really notice a difference not in the noise
Speaker 4:  canceling but in just like listening to music would I really notice a
Speaker 4:  a big difference on the
Speaker 8:  Fives? Depends how much of an audio person you are. I think that that's part
Speaker 8:  of it too. Like most people have like the first, well not most people, like
Speaker 8:  a lot of people still have it their first pair of AirPods and they love those
Speaker 3:  Spoken like a true audio person Chris.
Speaker 8:  Exactly.
Speaker 4:  I remember here being like it's CD quality, not yet. Yeah
Speaker 3:  And he's like yeah how smart are your ears? Crayons. Exactly. Really
Speaker 3:  saying
Speaker 4:  Very dumb.
Speaker 3:  I think there's that but it's also just you've got whatever the artist
Speaker 3:  made, you've got music, then you've gotta compress it to deliver it over
Speaker 3:  a streaming service because most of them are still not lossless. Then you've
Speaker 3:  gotta compress it again to send it to your headphones and then your headphones
Speaker 3:  have to do a bunch of work to like reproduce the sound. And that chain is
Speaker 3:  like, I agree with you. It's hard to isolate it Chris, but it's also this
Speaker 3:  is, this is the last thing Bluetooth is actually in charge of, right? Right.
Speaker 3:  Like I don't think most people want to use like Bluetooth
Speaker 3:  mice like right like any, like if you're a gamer, a Bluetooth
Speaker 3:  master's, I'm not gonna do it for you. Like they could not make this protocol
Speaker 3:  fast enough or reliable enough for that purpose. Right?
Speaker 3:  If I was like I'm gonna run my smart home on Bluetooth. Most vir cast listeners
Speaker 3:  know that as there's like a suicidal idea. Like you shouldn't just
Speaker 4:  Don't do that,
Speaker 3:  Right? Bluetooth in cars is whole like today,
Speaker 3:  like the dumbest thing, I was sitting downstairs, my wife got in our car
Speaker 3:  and drove away and my phone just paired to the car and the phone call I was
Speaker 3:  on transferred to the car, she drove away, right? It's still
Speaker 3:  just like dumb for that stuff in like hilarious ways. Google
Speaker 3:  Maps is still faking phone calls to send navigation guidance to
Speaker 3:  car stereos across the country because Bluetooth are like too stupid to
Speaker 3:  communicate well in all those scenarios. That's weird. So what
Speaker 3:  you're left with like the innovation appears to be in music and they are
Speaker 3:  just up against hard bit rate constraints that make it
Speaker 3:  impossible to do the next thing. And so you get, I
Speaker 3:  think Chris, you and I have laughed at this kind of like yo-yo from Apple
Speaker 3:  where last year they're like yep we're outta space and Bluetooth, wink wink,
Speaker 3:  we're do some Apple stuff and this year they're like, wait actually special
Speaker 3:  audio's a thing we might not need the room. Bluetooth is just fine because
Speaker 3:  I think they know if AirPods ditch Bluetooth, that's like a nuclear
Speaker 3:  move for them but people still need AirPods to connect to their Windows PCs
Speaker 3:  or whatever.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. So like what happens next year they have some kinda like custom code
Speaker 8:  decorator platform that they use like on top of Bluetooth or like beside
Speaker 8:  it I think like maybe last year that person spoke out of turn and then all
Speaker 8:  of a sudden this year there were rumors of the AirPods Pro two having some
Speaker 8:  new Kodak or like Lossless streaming that didn't happen. So now all of a
Speaker 8:  sudden they're like, yeah, you know what, Bluetooth works great, we love
Speaker 8:  it. Good, good times when the AirPods max two come along And
Speaker 8:  if those still use Play-Doh Bluetooth and aac, I'll be kind of
Speaker 8:  surprised cuz like two generations of $500 headphones that
Speaker 8:  still stick to this old very buggy standard that we've all talked about here
Speaker 8:  is not the best thing. So we'll see what happens I guess next year.
Speaker 3:  Happy holidays everyone. Bluetooth will be better next year.
Speaker 3:  We gotta take a break. We're right back with more of the Vergecast Bluetooth
Speaker 3:  holiday spectacular.
Speaker 12:  For 120 years Cadillac has been an industry leader in luxury
Speaker 12:  vehicles. Now they're redefining their future, starting with the all
Speaker 12:  electric lyrics. U v Cadillac's first ever electric vehicle isn't
Speaker 12:  a gasoline powered model with an electric system swapped in. It's something
Speaker 12:  completely different, built from the ground up to be truly original.
Speaker 12:  The Cadillac lyric pairs high performance luxury with the latest automotive
Speaker 12:  technology including available super crews. The first true
Speaker 12:  hands-free driver assistance technology of its kind. It comes with
Speaker 12:  an easy to use 33 inch diagonal advanced L E D screen and the
Speaker 12:  lyrics. LTM Battery has a balanced weight distribution and lower center
Speaker 12:  of gravity that provides a sporty, responsive, and spirited drive
Speaker 12:  as you travel down long highways and city streets. The 2023
Speaker 12:  lyric rear wheel drive offers an EPA estimated 312 miles of range
Speaker 12:  on a full charge. Actual lyric range will vary based on several factors
Speaker 12:  including temperature, terrain, battery, age loading, use and maintenance.
Speaker 12:  Always pay attention while driving and using super crews. Do not use a handheld
Speaker 12:  device requires active SuperCrew plan or trial terms apply. Visit
Speaker 12:  cadillac.com/super crewse for compatible roads and full details with the
Speaker 12:  Cadillac lyric and all electric future can be yours. 2023 Lyric
Speaker 12:  orders. Our full C dealer for 2024 availability
Speaker 13:  Details.
Speaker 14:  My favorite story this year was the cut cover story
Speaker 14:  on Megan Markle by Allison p Davis. I have read
Speaker 14:  probably a zillion pieces about Megan Markle that hardly told me anything
Speaker 14:  I didn't know already. And Allison who's really I think one of the
Speaker 14:  best profilers writing profiles right now, just did a
Speaker 14:  really impressive job painting a picture of what it is actually like to
Speaker 14:  be her or even in her presence right now and how sort of
Speaker 14:  weirdly normal but also weirdly abnormal it is
Speaker 14:  to be her. And it was just one of those pieces that I wanted to put directly
Speaker 14:  into my veins. David Haskell editor-in-chief
Speaker 14:  the other day was saying how the magazine just feels so alive.
Speaker 14:  And that really is very true. As soon as we're bored of something, we
Speaker 14:  do something else and try something else and it's just
Speaker 14:  a really exciting place to work and also to
Speaker 14:  experience as a reader.
Speaker 13:  That's Alexis Sword Law. The deputy editor of New York
Speaker 13:  Magazine. Get stories like Megan of Montecito and everything else,
Speaker 13:  New York for up to 70% off through the end of the year.
Speaker 13:  Head to ny mag.com/holiday and
Speaker 13:  you'll also get our editor approved tote bag plus a set of limited
Speaker 13:  edition stickers with any annual subscription.
Speaker 3:  We're back. So we're onto our next segment of the Bluetooth holiday spectacular.
Speaker 3:  We're gonna interview Dr. Mike Foley, who was the CEO
Speaker 3:  and executive director of the Bluetooth sig with me on that.
Speaker 3:  Alex Kranz here. Hey Alex, is she here?
Speaker 3:  Oh, are you on the right microphones? No,
Speaker 3:  yeah, you're in your, you're you're using your car's mic and speakers right
Speaker 3:  now. That's what's happening.
Speaker 15:  I have no idea the switch. It's
Speaker 3:  Fine. The car sounds worse than ever. We're gonna definitely gonna talk
Speaker 3:  to Mike Foley about why the car sounds bad that's coming up. Chris
Speaker 3:  Welch is also here. Hey Chris. Hey. Hey Chris. Do me a favor.
Speaker 3:  In the spirit of the holidays, describe to people what the Bluetooth sig
Speaker 3:  is. So
Speaker 8:  The Bluetooth sig SIG stands for special Interest group is a collection of
Speaker 8:  all these companies from Microsoft, from Intel, from Apple that kind of like,
Speaker 8:  you know, guide the way and choose what goes where and what to focus on for
Speaker 8:  each version of Bluetooth spec.
Speaker 3:  I always think of the people that run these trade groups as being
Speaker 3:  politicians more than engineers. What should people be listening for
Speaker 3:  in our conversation with Dr.
Speaker 8:  Foley? Yeah, it does seem like a lot of politics and a lot of just, just
Speaker 8:  sitting down and talking and trying to just find some common balance between
Speaker 8:  like what the Bluetooth sig wants and what these companies want. Be it Samsung
Speaker 8:  or Apple or whoever to kind of build out features or include them in the
Speaker 8:  spec. Cause we talked about, you know, like Apple and Samsung having their
Speaker 8:  own kind of side things on top of Bluetooth. And so you'll hear kind of what
Speaker 8:  that tussle entails about like when companies wanna keep things for themselves
Speaker 8:  or just bring them over to the spec in general at wide. And so it's a pretty
Speaker 8:  interesting conversation. Mike's been gone for a while, but even back when
Speaker 8:  he was there you can hear that there was a lot of fascinating stuff going
Speaker 8:  on.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, and honestly the, the current director of the Bluetooth said couldn't
Speaker 3:  do it cuz it's the holidays. But I would say, I said this to Chris right
Speaker 3:  after this conversation that having the former person is actually
Speaker 3:  better cuz he was raw, he was not shy, he
Speaker 8:  Was very raw.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. So this is a great conversation again, truly
Speaker 3:  the the holiday spirit comes through in every moment of talking to Dr.
Speaker 3:  Mike Foley, former CEO and executive director of the Bluetooth
Speaker 3:  sig. Let's run that interview.
Speaker 3:  Dr. Michael Foley. You are the former executive director and
Speaker 3:  CEO of the Bluetooth sig. I'm currently the CEO and founder of
Speaker 3:  I Y S. Welcome to the holiday. Spectacular.
Speaker 16:  Well thank you. It's a pleasure to be here.
Speaker 3:  I can't tell you how excited I am to talk to you about Bluetooth in this
Speaker 3:  the holiday season. Let's start, you were at the SIG for
Speaker 3:  a a while. From 2004 to 2012, you let it,
Speaker 3:  you brought Bluetooth 3.0 to market. You let a
Speaker 3:  merger with another standards body called the library forum. Tell me,
Speaker 3:  in your role is the person who leads the standard, what's the
Speaker 3:  structure of your day? Do you wake up and say, I gotta take over the library
Speaker 3:  of people or they're gonna come get us? Do you do politics all day?
Speaker 3:  What is that tribe like?
Speaker 16:  It, it's interesting. I looked at kind of my role within the
Speaker 16:  SIG as kind of three prongs. One, I led the
Speaker 16:  organization, you know, we had a team at the time of about 60
Speaker 16:  people that worked for the Bluetooth sig. So I led that
Speaker 16:  group in that group, did the websites, did the tools
Speaker 16:  for Bluetooth, helped with members create the specifications
Speaker 16:  and publish them. So that in and of itself was a fairly
Speaker 16:  big role. And then kind of the second pillar
Speaker 16:  was evangelizing the technology and working with
Speaker 16:  member companies on having them
Speaker 16:  implement Bluetooth in their products. Cuz remember when I started
Speaker 16:  this, there were very few products that had Bluetooth in them.
Speaker 16:  So getting Bluetooth just into products and being kind of a real
Speaker 16:  technology was key at that point in time.
Speaker 16:  It's not like today we're 5 billion devices a year shipped with Bluetooth.
Speaker 16:  I mean there was 50,000, a hundred thousand very small numbers at
Speaker 16:  that time. So it was a different beast. And then the other
Speaker 16:  one was more marketing and PR
Speaker 16:  and analyst relations to promote the technology
Speaker 16:  within the industry, but also to the consumer
Speaker 16:  and try to convince them that the scenarios
Speaker 16:  that Bluetooth was enabling was good for them, better for
Speaker 16:  them. So that we'd create consumer demand to try to get companies to
Speaker 16:  adopt the technology into them as well. So I kinda looked at it
Speaker 16:  as three key areas.
Speaker 3:  You led the Bluetooth sig in what you're describing as a pivotal
Speaker 3:  moment. I would agree it was a pivotal moment. It's before phones were everywhere.
Speaker 3:  It was certainly before wireless headphones were everywhere. We have a quote
Speaker 3:  here from you in 2005 when you gave an interview and gadget where I
Speaker 3:  used to work. The quote is probably next year to be able to stream music
Speaker 3:  to your car stereo from your phone. I mean that's like incredible,
Speaker 3:  right? We're far beyond that. But in that time, 2005,
Speaker 3:  2006, it wasn't clear that Bluetooth was gonna win, right? There was like
Speaker 3:  a competitive dynamic between Bluetooth, other wireless standards with
Speaker 3:  wifi for a while, which I thought was always very fascinating. And then now
Speaker 3:  with other things like thread and matter, there was a moment when Bluetooth
Speaker 3:  was competitive for like smart home networking. How did you think about where
Speaker 3:  Bluetooth was in the market in 2005 and where do you think it is now?
Speaker 16:  Well, you're right, it's hard to believe back then. But there
Speaker 16:  was a real question whether Bluetooth would ever be adopted
Speaker 16:  or used in products. And that was highlighted by
Speaker 16:  I, I worked for Microsoft before I joined the Bluetooth
Speaker 16:  sig. And one of the first things I did was an analyst
Speaker 16:  who were to get some feedback on where analysts thought the technology and
Speaker 16:  try to convince them where it was going was a good idea and the like.
Speaker 16:  And the first call I had with an analyst, his first
Speaker 16:  question was, you know, how stupid are you? You le left a great
Speaker 16:  job at Microsoft to run this technology that will be dead in a
Speaker 16:  year. You know? And so that that made me think a little
Speaker 16:  bit, well may maybe I'm not that smart, you know, maybe this wasn't such
Speaker 16:  a good idea, but the scenarios that Bluetooth
Speaker 16:  was enabling I thought were compelling and so
Speaker 16:  did many other people. So convincing, you know, companies
Speaker 16:  to adopt those and things was very important. And
Speaker 16:  Bluetooth had, you know, some technical features, some other
Speaker 16:  features that made it appealing for those scenarios and
Speaker 16:  better than the other technologies for the initial
Speaker 16:  scenarios that Bluetooth was used. You mentioned wifi and
Speaker 16:  WiFi's, you know, at the time. Excellent and still excellent
Speaker 16:  networking technology and it's used for other things now as well.
Speaker 16:  But you know, home routers and laptops, networking was
Speaker 16:  its killer scenario, if you will. And at least at
Speaker 16:  the time, the 2004 56 timeframe,
Speaker 16:  it really wasn't appropriate for, you know, the
Speaker 16:  earpiece, the headset that you mentioned purely because
Speaker 16:  of power requirements, latency as well, but
Speaker 16:  primarily power and and cost. And so Bluetooth really
Speaker 16:  was a good technology for those initial scenarios.
Speaker 16:  And then of course we were able to keep adapting it and
Speaker 16:  tweaking it for other use cases. And now today,
Speaker 16:  which this kind of second wave of scenarios really started
Speaker 16:  with Bluetooth four, Bluetooth low energy,
Speaker 16:  which was the last speck that came out while I was
Speaker 16:  running the organization. And that's really enabled Bluetooth to go
Speaker 16:  into the health and fitness devices, the sensors
Speaker 16:  that are just all sorts of new devices that
Speaker 16:  really, even in the 2004, 2005
Speaker 16:  timeframe, even Bluetooth wasn't properly suited for
Speaker 16:  at that point because it wasn't low enough energy for these sensor type
Speaker 16:  devices So, you know, once we got a foothold into the market, we were
Speaker 16:  able to expand and improve the technology for more
Speaker 16:  and more use cases.
Speaker 3:  Tell me what that sales pitch was like, you go into Apple or
Speaker 3:  Samsung or Dell or whatever, they're evaluating
Speaker 3:  their range of standards to support. Do you have like a PowerPoint deck
Speaker 3:  where there, do you do bribes under the table? What does that sales job look
Speaker 3:  like? You take 'em golfing.
Speaker 16:  I did that, yes,
Speaker 16:  because I'm a golfer as as well. So it, there were
Speaker 16:  some rounds of golf involved, but more times you would, you'd
Speaker 16:  go meet with companies and yes, you'd have a PowerPoint
Speaker 16:  deck that you would present. You know, the, the numbers, the
Speaker 16:  faxes, you saw 'em and lots of conversations with them
Speaker 16:  and gonna typically one meeting and one, you know,
Speaker 16:  PowerPoint deck wouldn't be enough to, to close the deal. So
Speaker 16:  there was a journey and they developed relationships and friendships
Speaker 16:  with these, you know, people that are building the products
Speaker 16:  and go from there. One meeting that stands out vividly
Speaker 16:  with that was as going into Sony and trying
Speaker 16:  to convince their TV team to use Bluetooth for
Speaker 16:  your remote control, you know, the, at that time they were
Speaker 16:  mainly IR based, but Sony was
Speaker 16:  promoter or a proponent of using a different
Speaker 16:  RF technology for the remote control. So it's a,
Speaker 16:  it wasn't a very easy sell or, or meeting and stuff, but you,
Speaker 16:  you start that way and go from there. And now Bluetooth is
Speaker 16:  used in the vast majority of TV remote
Speaker 16:  controls. You know, it didn't happen overnight but over time and
Speaker 16:  continuing and you know, they told me the couple of things that were really
Speaker 16:  needed and the spec before they could use 'em in a TV remote. So then you
Speaker 16:  fix the spec to address those issues then
Speaker 16:  you know, eventually it gets used there
Speaker 3:  All. If you're gonna talk about Sony and Bluetooth, I gotta throw to Chris
Speaker 3:  here so we can talk about some Codex stuff. Chris.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, I guess, I mean I guess you were kind of gone before they
Speaker 8:  came out with ldac and the whole spec to raise the bit rates,
Speaker 8:  but I guess like what part of that did you play? Did you see it coming and
Speaker 8:  like how do you feel now about like where things are headed? You've got Samsung,
Speaker 8:  their earbuds do like 24 bit audio now. Like what's the ceiling for what
Speaker 8:  is possible with the Bluetooth audio in your mind?
Speaker 16:  Oh, I mean I pretty much the audio is migrating
Speaker 16:  towards being run over the low energy channel rather than
Speaker 16:  the, you know, a traditional Bluetooth channel and a couple
Speaker 16:  of, I think really exciting things where the specs
Speaker 16:  were just updated for that one running over low audio
Speaker 16:  to be able to broadcast a, a stereo stream to
Speaker 16:  multiple headphones. I think, you know, for sharing music between people
Speaker 16:  or you know, in a a bar type environment where they have
Speaker 16:  three games on, you can put your headphone onto whichever
Speaker 16:  games you know you wanna listen to do hear that
Speaker 16:  audio stream. And so I think there's a lot of cool things
Speaker 16:  where, you know, Bluetooth audio is going to and
Speaker 16:  being able to have though a basic functionality
Speaker 16:  that allows interoperability between products from different
Speaker 16:  manufacturers but then also enable manufacturers if
Speaker 16:  they wanna put improvements on top of that. Whether, you know it's a
Speaker 16:  different Kodak or different bit rates, things like that to
Speaker 16:  enable, you know, their own products or products with their
Speaker 16:  partners to work better. I think that's a positive, you know, that
Speaker 16:  you keep the interoperability so you can use products from different
Speaker 16:  manufacturers but manufacturers are able to innovate on top
Speaker 16:  of that as well and add their own, you know, special sauce if you will
Speaker 16:  to make what they believe even improve products. And I, I,
Speaker 16:  I think that's great. I think the technology should enable that.
Speaker 3:  Wait, is that the political answer or is do you believe that because I don't,
Speaker 3:  I just to be clear, I do not like that. Is
Speaker 3:  Microsoft doing embrace Xtend extinguish, right where Apple uses,
Speaker 3:  I'm just pick on Apple cuz everybody knows AirPods, but I know Samsung wants
Speaker 3:  to use this and I know Google wants to do this. Apple gets used AirPods,
Speaker 3:  they leverage Bluetooth, this spec, they build proprietary extensions
Speaker 3:  that no one else can access. Eventually everyone loves AirPods and then they
Speaker 3:  leave the spec behind and they leave everyone else high and dry. And I can
Speaker 3:  pick on Apple, but Microsoft invented this playbook, it was called
Speaker 3:  Embrace extended extinguish with the web. Do you believe that that
Speaker 3:  outcome can be managed by the Bluetooth SIG or you can avoid it or
Speaker 3:  is that just the dynamic of the tech industry?
Speaker 16:  Well I, you know, when I was involved with the
Speaker 16:  SIG you would see some of that and a lot of
Speaker 16:  the initial innovation was done that way and then it would be
Speaker 16:  rolled back into the specification and now, you know,
Speaker 16:  I can't speak for Apple with what they've done with some of their products
Speaker 16:  and stuff if they'd ever want to roll that back into the spec.
Speaker 16:  But back in my day when I was there, things like
Speaker 16:  usability to make, you know, one of the early issues with
Speaker 16:  Bluetooth was nobody could figure out how to pair devices and, and
Speaker 16:  get them to work together
Speaker 3:  And let tell you that's not an early issue.
Speaker 16:  Yeah, fair enough. But it is better now Yeah,
Speaker 16:  than it was then. And there was a, a major push in
Speaker 16:  a whole spec, you know, it's Hallmark feature was secure
Speaker 16:  simple pairing, which made pairing easier and that
Speaker 16:  introduced a lot of the ways you pair today with it just works and things
Speaker 16:  like that. And a lot of
Speaker 16:  that spec came from companies that, you know,
Speaker 16:  had already been working to improve the pairing
Speaker 16:  experience because, you know, they, they saw the flaws in it
Speaker 16:  at, at the time and those were rolled back into the spec.
Speaker 16:  Now some of the things that have done since then to enhance pairing
Speaker 16:  hasn't been rolled back into the spec yet. Whether that ever will or
Speaker 16:  not, you know, I'm, I'm not close enough to the Bluetooth organization now
Speaker 16:  to know if there's an appetite for members to do that or not,
Speaker 16:  but I think it can work and I don't believe that all
Speaker 16:  companies when they're extending a spec or improving upon
Speaker 16:  it, you know, are are trying to, to wipe out the
Speaker 16:  competition. Sure they're trying to win and have the best products out there.
Speaker 16:  If the spec is so complete, if
Speaker 16:  you will, then it doesn't allow for that innovation. And that was something
Speaker 16:  we discussed a lot with each spec is where you
Speaker 16:  draw that line, you know, how much is in the spec and
Speaker 16:  how much is company Inno company's innovation on top of that. And
Speaker 16:  that was debated, you know, with with every spec all the
Speaker 16:  time. And again, I'm not in those meetings today,
Speaker 16:  but I would assume that is still a major conversation piece
Speaker 16:  is how much you put in the spec and how much you lead for company innovation.
Speaker 4:  Can you kind of walk us through how you have those conversations where you
Speaker 4:  wanna roll it back?
Speaker 16:  Well that, that's may sound like an absurd thing
Speaker 16:  to do, but maybe I was just shameless, I would do that all the time
Speaker 4:  And it worked. That's awesome.
Speaker 16:  That didn't bother me at all. Well sometimes it worked, sometimes it didn't.
Speaker 16:  But you know, what's the old saying, the worst they can do is say no,
Speaker 16:  you know, and, and I'm no worse off than I was before
Speaker 16:  having the conversation or or asking. And
Speaker 16:  a, a lot of times also though, you would go and speak not
Speaker 16:  only to Apple but also companies that were building
Speaker 16:  the products to work with the Apple products because
Speaker 16:  they would be more motivated to want that stuff standardized. So
Speaker 16:  those features could also work with Android phones or you
Speaker 16:  know, o other products depending on what they were making and
Speaker 16:  they, you know, would then have those conversations with Apple as well
Speaker 16:  that, you know, we had re really like to see this feature, that
Speaker 16:  feature rolled into the standard and you know, obviously
Speaker 16:  those companies would have a lot of pull as well.
Speaker 4:  So when you have companies like Apple who are pretty vertically integrated
Speaker 4:  now and they make the iPhones, they make the AirPods and everything else
Speaker 4:  that kind of disincentivizes them from like working with
Speaker 4:  the standard more closely because yeah, they can just say, say go kick rocks
Speaker 4:  Jabra.
Speaker 16:  Well yeah, any company that's in that situation and
Speaker 16:  you know, the Samsung of the world, you know, there, there's a lot of
Speaker 16:  companies that are in that position. So you're using Apple as an
Speaker 16:  example. I'm not trying to pick on them, I don't think what you're saying
Speaker 16:  is very true, but there's also the chip
Speaker 16:  manufacturer, you know, the, the Qualcomms of the world
Speaker 16:  that want to be able to create their silicon and
Speaker 16:  have it work in products to all their customers, not just
Speaker 16:  Apple or Samsung or, or whomever and not have to do
Speaker 16:  special, you know, spins for the one company. Obviously,
Speaker 16:  you know, a company like Apple or Samsung, they will, you know,
Speaker 16:  but, but they'd prefer to be able to have that be as
Speaker 16:  versatile as possible. So even when a company
Speaker 16:  has their complete vertical solution, I forget exactly how
Speaker 16:  you phrased it, but you know, creates their own ecosystem, there's still
Speaker 16:  different layers in it, as I said, like the chip manufacturers and other
Speaker 16:  people that are motivated to standardize some of this
Speaker 16:  stuff as well.
Speaker 3:  When you talked about stuff being in the standard and some stuff being built
Speaker 3:  on top of it and there's always a debate about where the line is, who's in
Speaker 3:  that debate, who go, who gets to be in those rooms. Are you all around a
Speaker 3:  whiteboard drawing lines at different heights and like angrily pointing
Speaker 3:  at them, like who's in the room and what does that debate actually sound
Speaker 16:  Like? So the Bluetooth specifications are
Speaker 16:  created by members and there's work groups
Speaker 16:  where various members that are interested in that
Speaker 16:  use case or that spec would participate in.
Speaker 16:  So there's the radio work group work group
Speaker 16:  for hands free in the car work group, you know, for the low
Speaker 16:  energy audio just e everything that comes out of Bluetooth. There's a
Speaker 16:  work group involved and member companies that have
Speaker 16:  expertise in opinion for lack the different word of,
Speaker 16:  of how that should be implemented are sitting in the room
Speaker 16:  and they'll, they'll debate that and they'll contribute to the spec
Speaker 16:  and then also at the end of the day it's the board of
Speaker 16:  directors that adopts the specification and that's
Speaker 16:  when it gets published and companies can start building products based on
Speaker 16:  it. And so the board of directors sets the
Speaker 16:  goals for the specification, you know, these are the
Speaker 16:  scenarios we wanna enable the enable, these are the new features we
Speaker 16:  wanna enable, stuff like that. And then it goes to the work group and then
Speaker 16:  when it's done, it comes back to the board of directors to, to sign off
Speaker 16:  on. So I mean that's a way 10,000 level over simplification
Speaker 16:  of how it's done. But those are the two main groups
Speaker 16:  that are kind of around that table, if you will,
Speaker 16:  for what goes in the spec and what doesn't go in the spec and where
Speaker 16:  that line is drawn.
Speaker 3:  So you got the members, you got the board of directors, they're talking about
Speaker 3:  different parts of the, the spec. Just as a consumer, somebody who experiences
Speaker 3:  Bluetooth every day, is there a part where you're like, all
Speaker 3:  right, the world's great consumer technology and computer companies are gonna
Speaker 3:  implement our spec, we don't have to worry about them, the car
Speaker 3:  companies are now gonna put Bluetooth radios in their cars and
Speaker 3:  that's a little dicey and maybe we should go babysit them a little bit cuz
Speaker 3:  that like that's where the breakdown is, right? In the actual execution and
Speaker 3:  the implementation of the standard. And some companies
Speaker 3:  historically very good at it, some gigantic category of companies
Speaker 3:  historically very bad at it. How do you make sure that consumer experience
Speaker 3:  stays good?
Speaker 16:  Well that's, that's a difficult one because the consumer
Speaker 16:  experience isn't in the specification itself and that
Speaker 16:  actually with Bluetooth anyway is very entrenched within the
Speaker 16:  original grue of the organization and how it
Speaker 16:  was formed that the user experience not be in the
Speaker 16:  specification that that's something that really yes. That the companies
Speaker 16:  can do on their own.
Speaker 3:  Why is that?
Speaker 16:  Well the, the, when Bluetooth
Speaker 16:  formed, it was a lot of big companies
Speaker 16:  coming together to do this specification and all of
Speaker 16:  'em had very strong opinions on what
Speaker 16:  the user interface should look like and how it should
Speaker 16:  be. And you know, one of the things that when I first started
Speaker 16:  working with Bluetooth, I worked for Microsoft and I was on the board of
Speaker 16:  directors, I chaired the board of directors and things like that and I negotiated,
Speaker 16:  there was part of the team that negotiated the deal for Microsoft
Speaker 16:  to join the Bluetooth sig and back in Redmond in
Speaker 16:  the meetings, you know, one direction that I received very loud
Speaker 16:  and clearly is, you know, some group of other companies
Speaker 16:  is not gonna tell us what the user dinner base in Windows
Speaker 16:  is. And you know, and one time when
Speaker 16:  I, I went to Ericsson, you know, this was 99,
Speaker 16:  2000 timeframe. So at that time Ericsson was a very
Speaker 16:  big cell phone manufacturer and I had what I thought was
Speaker 16:  a great idea for how Bluetooth should be in the phone and how it should
Speaker 16:  implement with Windows and some with their head UI guy for
Speaker 16:  phones and give them this idea. And he kind of
Speaker 16:  stares blankly at me and I said, come on, I couldn't take you more than
Speaker 16:  a week to implement this feature. And he said, no, it'll be
Speaker 16:  six months because it'll take five and a half months for you to
Speaker 16:  convince me to do it and then two weeks for me to do it. You know,
Speaker 16:  so, so all these companies had very strong
Speaker 16:  impressions of how the UI on
Speaker 16:  the devices that they made and their experts at should
Speaker 16:  work and you know, some kid from another company
Speaker 16:  shouldn't come and tell them how it should be. And
Speaker 16:  you know, know when I worked at Microsoft they wouldn't allow it. Erickson
Speaker 16:  wouldn't, Nokia sure as heck wouldn't allow it. And so, you know,
Speaker 16:  none of the companies involved back then would allow
Speaker 16:  that. And so to kind of roll back to your question though,
Speaker 16:  one of the things we did do is we had put out,
Speaker 16:  you know, guidelines and the Bluetooth sig
Speaker 16:  you, you mentioned the car scenario. One of the things we did is we
Speaker 16:  did consumer focus groups and brought, you know,
Speaker 16:  consumers, regular people that may or may not have ever used
Speaker 16:  Bluetooth and stuck 'em in a car and stuck them in, you know, many, many
Speaker 16:  different types of cars. Not always the same person but you know, different
Speaker 16:  people in different cars and had them try to pair a
Speaker 16:  phone with the car and sometimes as you
Speaker 16:  said, it went very smoothly, sometimes it didn't. But there was some
Speaker 16:  very clear things that consumers
Speaker 16:  expected and kind of wanted to follow the flow through and
Speaker 16:  some that the cars did that they weren't expecting at all. And so we
Speaker 16:  were able to put that into a, a paper and give some guidelines and
Speaker 16:  share that with all the car manufacturers that were members. And that
Speaker 16:  helped some, you know, as you said, they're, they're still not all perfect
Speaker 16:  than things, but I, I do think it's better than
Speaker 16:  when cars first started implementing Bluetooth.
Speaker 3:  So you have a PhD or an engineer by training. You used to work
Speaker 3:  on the actual wireless standards at Microsoft. Every time
Speaker 3:  I talk to someone in your position or someone who's been in your position
Speaker 3:  as standards body, I come away thinking, oh this is a politics
Speaker 3:  job. This person had to become a politician. Cuz what you are describing
Speaker 3:  is less engineering and way more politics. Is that how you see it, that this
Speaker 3:  is a, a political job?
Speaker 16:  Well there's definitely that part of it and you're a salesman
Speaker 16:  who's as well, no doubt about that. But I
Speaker 16:  think at least in my own experience, having
Speaker 16:  the technical background enabled me to
Speaker 16:  speak to the people that were making the specifications, you know,
Speaker 16:  at the radio level I understood that level at the upper
Speaker 16:  layers, I understood that level and I think at least with Bluetooth and
Speaker 16:  my personal experience, that helped a lot with the
Speaker 16:  specifications. But as you said, with talking with
Speaker 16:  members and press and analyst and stuff,
Speaker 16:  I, I didn't use that part of my background nearly as
Speaker 3:  Much.
Speaker 3:  I wanna let Alex and Chris ask some questions to wrap us up. But here's my,
Speaker 3:  my my final question. I look at the state of Bluetooth today
Speaker 3:  and it can do a lot of things. It has more capabilities than ever,
Speaker 3:  but it, it's narrowed to the audio use case in
Speaker 3:  almost every circumstance, right? Like air AirPods and Galaxy Buds
Speaker 3:  and Pixel buds are all great and they have all these capabilities and that's
Speaker 3:  great and pairing with your car is great and spatial audio is
Speaker 3:  whatever it is. But the universe of other things that
Speaker 3:  Bluetooth could do has been supplanted by other
Speaker 3:  lower power technologies has been supplanted by things like wifi, Bluetooth
Speaker 3:  and wifi work together now in many cases, do you see that narrowing or
Speaker 3:  am I missing something big?
Speaker 16:  Well, it audio was the original killer use case and it
Speaker 16:  went from voice audio to stereo audio and now it's going
Speaker 16:  stereo audio over the low energy channel. And so
Speaker 16:  audio has been, and I think will continue to be a,
Speaker 16:  a major, major feature or part of what Bluetooth is
Speaker 16:  and enables. I do think though in a lot of other
Speaker 16:  devices like the medical, the fitness and things like that,
Speaker 16:  Bluetooth can still be adopted and used there
Speaker 16:  as well. Having the connection to pretty much every
Speaker 16:  smartphone out there is still a, a big advantage for
Speaker 16:  those other type of use cases and makes
Speaker 16:  some other technologies, at least for the consumer
Speaker 16:  side, harder to enter because you don't have that cell phone connectivity.
Speaker 16:  Now in the industrial world and things like that where
Speaker 16:  you're doing the entire vertical, you know, in-house if
Speaker 16:  you will, if you're doing automation on a
Speaker 16:  manufacturing floor, you know that that cell phone
Speaker 16:  connection may not be as important because you'll just create your
Speaker 16:  own basically access point or connectivity point for whatever
Speaker 16:  technology you're using. So you use the best technology that's fit
Speaker 16:  for that particular job. So I think that's a harder
Speaker 16:  nut, if you will, for Bluetooth to crack than the more consumer
Speaker 16:  ones where the phone is such a vital component in it.
Speaker 8:  So I've been at the Verge for a while and I feel like there was a period
Speaker 8:  a few years ago where we often wrote about BLE low energy and these
Speaker 8:  beacons and this notion that you would like welcome into a store and the
Speaker 8:  app for like Walmart or Target would like guide you to the aisle or shelf
Speaker 8:  where the thing you wanted was, and that never really happened.
Speaker 8:  So do you think like there are times where the tech industry just gets maybe
Speaker 8:  too ambitious with Bluetooth and uses it in ways that sound nice and concept,
Speaker 8:  but in practice or a hassle or not really what it's meant for when it comes
Speaker 8:  down to it?
Speaker 16:  Well, you're right, the, the low energy beacons, there's a lot of
Speaker 16:  hype around those for a while and it might have been
Speaker 16:  one of those, if you build it, they will come type of things, but
Speaker 16:  not as many people came as, as some people had hoped.
Speaker 16:  You know, even back at the beginning I was talking about the scenarios
Speaker 16:  that you're enabling, you know, I tested with
Speaker 16:  Bluetooth, low energy beacons around a target and you know, it'll
Speaker 16:  show you where the item is and map you to it and stuff,
Speaker 16:  but you know, I I don't really know how compelling that is. You know,
Speaker 16:  most people can walk around the target and, and find the stuff and,
Speaker 16:  and part of walking around the, the target is, is the journey
Speaker 16:  that people enjoy when they're shopping it, you know, so
Speaker 16:  pulling out your phone and having it do all of that, yeah, maybe
Speaker 16:  has some value, but I don't know if it's really a killer type
Speaker 16:  scenario. So the the, the scenarios have to be good and consumers
Speaker 16:  have to, you know, want them and, and be willing to use them
Speaker 16:  where the beacon scenario might not have been there. Now if you
Speaker 16:  easily push good coupons to them and things like that and
Speaker 16:  it saved them some money, then people might be more inclined to use
Speaker 16:  that sort of application.
Speaker 4:  What element of Bluetooth that you worked on was like just the part
Speaker 4:  you really, really are super proud of and like you probably bring up
Speaker 4:  in a conversation with people who know nothing about Bluetooth.
Speaker 16:  Well, it was mentioned earlier about how
Speaker 16:  Bluetooth and, and y came together and that turned
Speaker 16:  into Bluetooth low energy in the, in the Fort Auto spec and
Speaker 16:  that whole process and going through and working
Speaker 16:  out the deal for that and getting this specification
Speaker 16:  done, you know, that was really something and that really set
Speaker 16:  the foundation for what Bluetooth is and became for the,
Speaker 16:  for this last decade, you know, for the next 10 years af
Speaker 16:  after that was done. So, you know, that was very
Speaker 16:  good, very proud of that. And how, how that's turned out.
Speaker 3:  Were you like, I gotta take these library guys, they're coming from me.
Speaker 16:  No, no, no, no. They, they
Speaker 16:  actually believed that the Bluetooth sig was probably the best way to get
Speaker 16:  the technology out there as well, rather than
Speaker 16:  recreating everything that the Bluetooth sig had. Because people I
Speaker 16:  don't think realize, and the consumer shouldn't have to
Speaker 16:  realize this, but you know, creating a standard like that and
Speaker 16:  getting the technology out there takes a lot of time,
Speaker 16:  energy, money, resources, infrastructure, just all
Speaker 16:  these things and duplicating that for each technology is
Speaker 16:  very wasteful in the industry. And so being able to
Speaker 16:  bring those two together, you know, saved companies a lot of
Speaker 16:  money, I think made it easier for the consumer when the actual
Speaker 16:  low energy came out because it got put into phones right away because people
Speaker 16:  made dual mode chip sets right away. And so it,
Speaker 16:  it was definitely a win-win for both organizations, for
Speaker 16:  the consumer, for the members, et cetera. So,
Speaker 16:  no, it wasn't like you're going out and saying, you know, we, we have to
Speaker 16:  just take over these guys.
Speaker 3:  It's a nice low power wireless speck you have there. It would be a shame
Speaker 3:  if anything happen
Speaker 16:  To, yeah, exactly.
Speaker 3:  All right, let's wrap it up here. Thank you so much, Mike for joining us
Speaker 3:  on the Vergecast Bluetooth holiday. Spectacular. It would be
Speaker 3:  a crime if I didn't ask this, our listeners would kill me. The joke we've
Speaker 3:  had that a lot of folks, a lot of people who report on consumer technology
Speaker 3:  have for years about Bluetooth is that Bluetooth will be better next year.
Speaker 3:  And that has just always been the answer for a decade plus of Bluetooth
Speaker 3:  in the spirit of the holidays. Will Bluetooth be better next year?
Speaker 16:  Maybe? I dunno,
Speaker 16:  it's, it's pretty damn good now and it, it will continue
Speaker 16:  to do more things.
Speaker 3:  That's amazing. Mike, thank you so much for joining the broadcast Bluetooth
Speaker 3:  holiday spectacular. This is great.
Speaker 16:  All right, thanks.
Speaker 3:  And with that, the Vergecast Bluetooth holiday spectacular
Speaker 3:  comes to a close, children are sleeping or headsets are charging
Speaker 3:  and Bluetooth. Well, honestly, we don't know if Bluetooth will be better
Speaker 3:  next year, which we'll just have to try again. Thank you for joining us
Speaker 3:  on the Vergecast Bluetooth holiday spectacular. We enjoyed having you. I
Speaker 3:  hope you have an excellent holiday season. There's lots of coverage of Bluetooth
Speaker 3:  on the verge.com, there's lots of coverage of Bluetooth in all of our hearts.
Speaker 3:  You can follow us on the website@theverge.com. We're thinking about what
Speaker 3:  other social platforms you can follow us on. But the verge.com right now,
Speaker 3:  it's pretty good. So check out the verge.com. We're on it. We're writing
Speaker 3:  up Bluetooth every day. We're writing about the holidays. The vercast Bluetooth
Speaker 3:  Holidays Spectacular is produced by Andrew Marino and Liam James Brooke Mentors
Speaker 3:  is our editorial director of audio. The vercast is a VER production and part
Speaker 3:  of the Vox Media podcast network. If you have thoughts, feedback, feelings,
Speaker 3:  even just some Bluetooth tips and tricks, you can always email
Speaker 3:  vergecast@theverge.com. And if you have questions, call the hotline.
Speaker 3:  Eight six six Verge 11. Send us all of your big thoughts,
Speaker 3:  concerns, and questions about the world of tech. That's it for the Verge
Speaker 3:  Test in 2022. Happy holidays and we'll see you at
Speaker 3:  CS 2023.
Speaker 17:  Device is now disconnected.