# Transcript
ID: 16e401a0-cadc-11ec-a66d-73a26e10f335
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: How the mechanical keyboard went mainstream again
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-11595383150327717/1063322227035571263/s93290-US-2969s-1651580662.mp3
Description: For the next three weeks on Tuesdays, Verge managing editor Alex Cranz hosts some shows focused on the creator space and, in Vergecast fashion, the nerdiest part of the creator space we can think of.
In this episode, Alex talks with Jacob Alexander, a member of Input Club, one of the first groups to start making their own mechanical keyboards, and Julie Muncy, a writer and consultant who runs a service called Keyboard Concierge, which helps customers navigate the keyboard space for personalized customization.
Ad Filtering: Disabled
Speaker 1:  This episode is brought to you by grain your
Speaker 1:  life from the shoes you wear to how you make your coffee is
Speaker 1:  fueled by recommendations, maybe from your favorite artists, your
Speaker 1:  sister-in-law or your friend. Who's so cool. It's actually kind of
Speaker 1:  intimidating. Grin is the leading influencer marketing
Speaker 1:  software that allows you to build relationships with creators directly.
Speaker 1:  It's used by top e-commerce brands like Allbirds, skims,
Speaker 1:  Warby Parker, and more find out how grim can help you grow your
Speaker 1:  friend. Watch the demo@grin.co that's. G R
Speaker 1:  I N dot C O.
Speaker 3:  Hey Vergecast listeners it's Nila for the next three weeks on the show. We're
Speaker 3:  going to be doing some extra episodes on Tuesdays focused on
Speaker 3:  creators, but in true verge has fashion the
Speaker 3:  nerdiest parts of the creator economy. We can think of. It's going to be
Speaker 3:  hosted by verge managing editor, our friend, Alex Cranz. Alex is
Speaker 3:  here with me right now, Alex.
Speaker 4:  Hey, very excited to talk to all of the nerds. That's all I've been doing
Speaker 4:  for the last couple of weeks.
Speaker 3:  I mean, what else are we here for the first episode of your mini series on
Speaker 3:  creators is running today, but tell us what the whole series about,
Speaker 4:  Okay. So the idea is that there's a lot of these really cool gadgets out
Speaker 4:  there that are really awesome, but they've kind of gotten a little stagnant,
Speaker 4:  like big companies like Logitech and razor. They're not really making these
Speaker 4:  products that we really want, but there are other people they're weird,
Speaker 4:  fun, nerdy, creators out there doing this stuff, and they're making it
Speaker 4:  on YouTube and on Reddit and on their weird own
Speaker 4:  websites. So we went out and we found them and we talked to
Speaker 4:  them to see like what they're doing, why they're doing it and like
Speaker 4:  how they're changing these really cool gadgets.
Speaker 3:  I love that. That's very much in our, with us. What's this week's episode
Speaker 3:  about,
Speaker 4:  So this week's episode, I mean, obviously we had to start with keyboards.
Speaker 4:  I think there's like no other product out there. That's quite like
Speaker 4:  proven this theory I had then keyboards. So we talked to some
Speaker 4:  keyboard people, and we're going to figure out like what's happening in this
Speaker 4:  space right now. How much has changed in the last eight years
Speaker 4:  and what it's going to look like going forward.
Speaker 3:  All right, well, first episode about mechanical keyboards. I'm sure this
Speaker 3:  will cause no controversy at all and no one will have opinions on it. I'm
Speaker 3:  excited for this one. Take it away, Alex,
Speaker 4:  If you're still in an office or you're on a zoom call or nobody mutes, you've
Speaker 4:  probably heard this sound.
Speaker 4:  That's a mechanical keyboard, practically ubiquitous in the eighties by the
Speaker 4:  mid nineties, they'd started to fall out of fashion and were being replaced
Speaker 4:  by much cheaper to make and LaMer to type on membrane
Speaker 4:  keyboards.
Speaker 4:  I don't know about you, but I can feel the unpleasantness of that keyboard.
Speaker 4:  Just listening to it. A membrane keyboard is squishy and quiet.
Speaker 4:  A mechanical keyboard is louder, But if you're
Speaker 4:  typing on it all day, it's a hell of a lot nicer to type on.
Speaker 4:  And in 2010, I had to finally say goodbye to membrane and track down a mechanical
Speaker 4:  keyboard to make me feel like I was typing on a Tandy or an IBM
Speaker 4:  again, but in 2010 there weren't a lot of options. You could track down one
Speaker 4:  of those old keyboards and use an adapter to connect it to your computer.
Speaker 4:  Or you could spend a lot of money on something like the apple friendly lineup
Speaker 4:  of keyboards from a terrace. But 12 years later, the keyboard
Speaker 4:  landscape is a lot different companies like razor,
Speaker 4:  Logitech and Coursera have huge lineups of mechanical keyboards and
Speaker 4:  newer companies like key crown or something really cool, really affordable
Speaker 4:  mechanical keyboards for anyone who wants to try them. What
Speaker 4:  changed between then and now is a whole industry of smaller companies. A
Speaker 4:  lot of which are one person shows has started experimenting with making their
Speaker 4:  own keyboards and all the individual parts of a keyboard, improving that
Speaker 4:  there's a big eager market of people like me willing to open their
Speaker 4:  wallets, to take on something a little more customizable and a little more
Speaker 4:  fun to type on.
Speaker 4:  I'm a huge keyboard nerd. And I've written about this community a lot,
Speaker 4:  but the space is moving so fast that it's hard to keep up. If you look away
Speaker 4:  for a month, there's a half a dozen new, big names that you have to get to
Speaker 4:  know so better, understand the space, how it's changed and
Speaker 4:  where it's headed. I reached out to interview Jacob Alexander.
Speaker 7:  My name is Jacob Alexander. I really liked keyboards a lot.
Speaker 4:  Jacob has over 600 keyboards that has amassed over the
Speaker 4:  last decade. And he's a member of input club, one of the first groups to
Speaker 4:  start making their own mechanical keyboards. Since I first met him way back
Speaker 4:  in 2017, his team has launched the Konos store, which sells mechanical
Speaker 4:  keyboards and he's invented his own switch. That's the key
Speaker 4:  part between the key cap and the keyboard.
Speaker 7:  You better have the halo switch, which is kind of basis of the holy Panda
Speaker 7:  variants. The switches
Speaker 4:  Look, this guy seriously knows keyboards. So yeah,
Speaker 4:  I had to talk to him again. So here's my interview with
Speaker 4:  Jacob Alexander.
Speaker 4:  I feel like you probably have more than 600 keyboards at this point.
Speaker 7:  Absolutely. I
Speaker 4:  Know you started initially kind of as a collector and then you
Speaker 4:  moved into building your own keyboards. Is that the
Speaker 4:  trajectory?
Speaker 7:  Yes, sort of initially I started collected keyboards, but around
Speaker 7:  2009, when I got into the stuff, the older keyboards, the only
Speaker 7:  interest was the ones that you could plug into your computer because what's
Speaker 7:  the use of the keyboard. If you can't type on it. And I got a couple of
Speaker 7:  older keyboards, well, I can't plug the sentence, like, wait a second. I
Speaker 7:  I'm taking computer engineering and a decent engineering school. I should
Speaker 7:  be able to like make this work. So I actually got into kind of
Speaker 7:  the TNC slash R do we know development to reverse engineer protocols?
Speaker 7:  So like when you plug in USB, like how do you reverse engineer it to USB
Speaker 7:  or PST or at T or XD or whatever the heck else. It's
Speaker 7:  some weird esoteric Japanese keyboard. So that's
Speaker 7:  how I got into keyboard development was I want to use the keyboard. That's
Speaker 7:  really cool. And all these things that I'd be like, oh, I'll make cute cats
Speaker 7:  there. I'll never make switches. Let's just use this cool things that were
Speaker 7:  done before. I,
Speaker 4:  And then you started showing off your projects, right?
Speaker 4:  Like you, you, were you on forums mainly.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. So mainly I was on forum, so I was on Geekhack cause I was bored at
Speaker 7:  work one day when I was working in Japan and I had all these keyboards. It
Speaker 7:  really cool though. I was like, well, it's kind of, I don't know, rude of
Speaker 7:  me to like, just keep everything to myself. Right? So like, I want to take
Speaker 7:  pictures and collect the pictures, but keyboards, aren't just a visual thing.
Speaker 7:  Like it's as beautiful as the pictures people take online these days of like
Speaker 7:  fancy keyboards and get decafs. That's not the experience of actually using
Speaker 7:  it. Keyboards are very tactile and very, very functional things. So I started
Speaker 7:  doing keyboard, beat ups in the bay area, initially monthly, and then it
Speaker 7:  went to bi-monthly and then like, as they got larger, I had to make them
Speaker 7:  take longer. Cause it takes too much energy to organize. We've got,
Speaker 4:  So you started kind of showing off your stuff on Geekhack and I think that's
Speaker 4:  how I first heard about you is you had a very, you had a name on Geekhack,
Speaker 4:  like you were known, what was that name?
Speaker 7:  Hot class. So H a T a it came about
Speaker 7:  because of it's somewhat related to martial arts that were
Speaker 7:  hot on a sensor. That's kind of a mispronunciation of that. But at the
Speaker 7:  time when I was picking a name online, talk about like
Speaker 7:  2006 or five, I hate numbers and names. That's like, like
Speaker 7:  one of the things like when you see like 1926 or whatever, like I hate that
Speaker 7:  it has to be no numbers in my name. And so that's kind
Speaker 7:  of how it came about.
Speaker 4:  So you, you, you kinda got started there and I feel like for you, it was
Speaker 4:  almost a natural evolution from being
Speaker 4:  this guy. Who's just making cool stuff and putting it on the
Speaker 4:  forums and connecting it to these slowly giant collection of
Speaker 4:  keyboards you you'd acquired. When did it start to shift into something that
Speaker 4:  became a business that became like something more?
Speaker 7:  So that was a little bit organic kind of happened as
Speaker 7:  I was doing these meetups, I gave a presentation on KLL.
Speaker 7:  So KLL was kind of like a language DSL for the
Speaker 7:  technical people, the main specific language, like a programming language,
Speaker 7:  just for keyboards to say, like, this is how I want it to my layout. And
Speaker 7:  the purpose of that was so I could use it on all these converters I'd use.
Speaker 7:  I didn't want to make my callback for every keyboard I did. I got paid, I
Speaker 7:  got tired. You had to be Cordy first. And then Cole Mac. And it was a pain
Speaker 7:  in the ass. So I wrote a language to do that. And as I gave a presentation
Speaker 7:  for this, Jesse from keyboard IO walked up to me and they go,
Speaker 7:  do you want to work for me? Like, not really, but at the time I wasn't
Speaker 7:  interested in like working on things. Like, I, I don't even know if I was
Speaker 7:  on an H1B visa yet I'm Kadian. So I, I, there's lots of
Speaker 7:  complications with me, like working for like a small startup,
Speaker 7:  especially cause I just graduated basically. And so I was like,
Speaker 7:  ah, okay. And then a few months later I was also
Speaker 7:  hosting meet ups at a mass stop. We're not dropped. And Andrew
Speaker 7:  who's one of the co-founders of it book club. He approached me and says,
Speaker 7:  Hey, can you make us a keyboard? And so for those that aren't
Speaker 7:  aware the keyboard market at the time was really difficult.
Speaker 4:  What year was this?
Speaker 7:  This would have been 2014.
Speaker 4:  Okay. 2014. I think at that point we just
Speaker 4:  see in like the DAS keyboard was still the main keyboard that people
Speaker 4:  used if they wanted to seem cool. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Dusky board or Phil CO's. And if you're really cool, you're into real
Speaker 7:  force and you bought them from elite keyboards.com Greg website at the
Speaker 7:  time.
Speaker 4:  Absolutely wonderful. So 2014 Andrew reaches out
Speaker 4:  and he asks you to build a keyboard.
Speaker 7:  And the problem was they had these group buys and they would sell out
Speaker 7:  immediately. They could not buy enough keyboards from the manufacturers.
Speaker 7:  And it turns out that they could get quote unquote, black market
Speaker 7:  switches. So cherry was all the giant contracts at the
Speaker 7:  time. So you could only buy it for people who bought these giant orders,
Speaker 7:  like millions and millions of switches at a time. But of course the community
Speaker 7:  is very small. Nobody in the community, you can dos like buy millions of
Speaker 7:  switches, right? And so there are ways to buy these switches in
Speaker 7:  like a gray market area from like Chinese suppliers and things. So they could
Speaker 7:  acquire all the parts for a keyboard, but they could actually build a
Speaker 7:  keyboard. And so they asked you, look, could you, could you please build
Speaker 7:  us a keyboard? And that's where the infinity 60% came on. So I called a couple
Speaker 7:  friends, mechanical engineer, PCB, I entered and I saw for firmware and
Speaker 7:  software overall design and build it.
Speaker 4:  Those keyboards, those initial keyboards were a success like when, when I
Speaker 4:  first met you, it was because people were saying, you've got to talk to this
Speaker 4:  guy. He's incredible. He's doing these great keyboards. And he's
Speaker 4:  building this movement. Was that, was that interactions on those forums
Speaker 4:  was, was working there part of why you had that success?
Speaker 7:  I think so a lot of it has to do with, like you said, my
Speaker 7:  interactions, I was very active at the time on desk
Speaker 7:  three for the desk already awards. By the time I had sort of stopped doing
Speaker 7:  it and there's a fucking get it too. Why later I hit, I had the most
Speaker 7:  awards of anybody at the time. I just kept getting them.
Speaker 7:  And I tried really hard to like make things interesting. So to me, it's,
Speaker 7:  there are collectors who collect things just for collecting things. I don't
Speaker 7:  do that. I collect hands because I'm searching for
Speaker 7:  answers. And I'm looking for information that was kind of like previous and
Speaker 7:  gloss. Like it's, it's keyboard archeology to me at that. That's kind of
Speaker 7:  what it is. And one of the things I'm like really happy to hear
Speaker 7:  about is like when other groups or other random
Speaker 7:  YouTubers or podcasts or streamers started using terms that I
Speaker 7:  point, and that's when I know, like I was like, oh, I actually made a
Speaker 7:  difference in total. Like, so people understand what things are.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Cause when, when people first started talking about keyboards, we weren't
Speaker 4:  talking about force curves. We weren't talking about, about like the pressure
Speaker 4:  on a key. And now we do. And the first time I saw those curves
Speaker 4:  was you were making them, you you'd built a machine in your
Speaker 4:  space to test these. What are some of the big terms that you kind of
Speaker 4:  coined that I'll now hear from other creators and YouTube and stuff
Speaker 7:  Interrupted, like force curves and things like that. All those terms, drawing
Speaker 7:  them like forest curves have always existed. They've been like more
Speaker 7:  artistic data sheets, but there's like, in my
Speaker 7:  articles, I referenced like a pretty famous Japanese keyboard or
Speaker 7:  enthusiastic who did a lot of the stuff like that. It was by admiration.
Speaker 7:  Like I want that. That's kind of how I got this up. But a lot of things like
Speaker 7:  switches. So the one that made me really smile was a
Speaker 7:  YouTube person, LTR Liza game reviews.
Speaker 7:  And he talked about a Tandy personal computer and he
Speaker 7:  called the oh and uses Fujitsu, least sprigs switches.
Speaker 8:  I a little bit different than a lot of the photos that I've seen online.
Speaker 8:  But apparently these are Fujitsu leaf Springs, the third
Speaker 8:  generation of them. They're not clicky keyboard keys, but they are pretty
Speaker 8:  darn satisfying.
Speaker 7:  So I'm like, wait a second. He's not a keyboard enthusiast. Why the heck
Speaker 7:  does he know that name? Cause he had to look that up like that. And at the
Speaker 7:  time, the only place you'd find out about that was articles on desktop already
Speaker 7:  that I wrote.
Speaker 4:  That's awesome.
Speaker 7:  And so like, it's, it's like little hints like that. It's like I, or like
Speaker 7:  switches and people talk about magnetic separation switches. So one of the
Speaker 7:  cool projects it's today, someone called a risk of
Speaker 7:  fall on the internet. So the voice switches are 3d printed magnetic switches.
Speaker 7:  I don't know if you've seen solos,
Speaker 9:  The body magnet and the stem magnet are attracted to each other. They want
Speaker 9:  to pull each other together. Right. So when you're pressing on the switch,
Speaker 9:  you've got the magnetic separation feeling. So if you've ever held two magnet
Speaker 9:  together and then pull them apart, it's that sort of feeling.
Speaker 7:  So the magnetic separation switches, the idea for a lot of that stuff
Speaker 7:  comes from keyboard. As I kind of discovered from the
Speaker 7:  sixties and seventies, do you need that keyboards? And so I talk about magnetic
Speaker 7:  separation switches. So like those terms I coined because I didn't know what
Speaker 7:  the heck they're called, the people using those terms like that. And to me,
Speaker 7:  that's the fun part. It's like, I I've done my part and sort of got people
Speaker 7:  excited about old things, but keyboard things in general, right?
Speaker 7:  Like I no longer feel like at the time and especially like
Speaker 7:  20 14, 20 15, there are so few people interested
Speaker 7:  in vintage keyboards or making
Speaker 7:  interesting things with switches. So like the handle and Hako switches and
Speaker 7:  all the things I did like is now holy Panda is like a category of
Speaker 7:  switches down
Speaker 10:  And we overlay Hatas. How does hatters forced graph of the
Speaker 10:  Panda over the halo clears. We can clearly see that actuation point and
Speaker 10:  bottom out forces are lower
Speaker 7:  And that's based off the work I did on that slider. It did not exist prior
Speaker 7:  to that. There's a patent on it. And so like, there's all these things to
Speaker 7:  me, like just make me smile. It's like, I've, I've been doing my part in
Speaker 7:  sort of getting people interested in keyboards, making sure that it gets
Speaker 7:  better. Right? Nope. There's all these things that the larger
Speaker 7:  companies do because they only think about money like that, that at the end
Speaker 7:  of the day, that they just think of what money and their reasons why they
Speaker 7:  do their things, but it still makes it frustrating as someone's like
Speaker 7:  uses tools. Like why can't tools be great.
Speaker 4:  Right. But I find really interesting is when you started doing this, most
Speaker 4:  of the main keyboard manufacturers weren't focused on mechanical keyboards,
Speaker 4:  they all got ignored them. There's I think like a single guy at
Speaker 4:  Corsair who really liked keyboards and would periodically be like,
Speaker 4:  we're going to do a mechanical keyboard at Corsair, but otherwise that was
Speaker 4:  it. And now everybody has a mechanical keyboard. Logic
Speaker 4:  tech has built their own switches. How much of that is because
Speaker 4:  of this kind of movement that you were a part of
Speaker 7:  My main theory on mechanical switches for sort of the
Speaker 7:  mainstream one, th the main initial driving force was
Speaker 7:  e-sports like, that's, that's the, the main part. Like, that's how I got
Speaker 7:  into it. Some famous e-sports players were using some Philco
Speaker 7:  keyboard or whatever it's like, and all of the fans want to use the same
Speaker 7:  thing they're using. Right. It's just like fancies Nike shoes and
Speaker 7:  that kind of stuff. So that's how it got started. And for people who
Speaker 7:  are a little bit more elitist in the community, I was like, ah,
Speaker 7:  e-sports blah, blah, blah, blah. But to me, that's not important. It's more
Speaker 7:  that people are learning like the marketing material, not saying this is
Speaker 7:  a mechanical switch. So if I tell you, ask me what a mechanical switch at
Speaker 7:  2014, he probably wouldn't have known it that right now I can go, I can talk
Speaker 7:  to almost anybody about keyboards and though vaguely know what
Speaker 7:  a mechanical keyboard is.
Speaker 4:  And they'll say that's pretty good.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Pretty good or whatever. But it doesn't matter, like before it was
Speaker 7:  by any mechanical keyboard, it will be better than what you have today. Now
Speaker 7:  I was like, oh, well, what kind did I have to ask more questions? So like,
Speaker 7:  you could do better. Like, what are you looking for? Kind of thing. Seeing
Speaker 7:  it actually progress has been very rewarding actually.
Speaker 4:  Was that part of, kind of what drove you to do it? Not just, I
Speaker 4:  know that you, you really care about these switches and stuff, but was it
Speaker 4:  always kind of this backseat desire of wanting to get the
Speaker 4:  bigger companies to pay attention?
Speaker 7:  Yes. That was a really big part of it. And it comes back to my
Speaker 7:  original frustration. Like while small companies build really cool
Speaker 7:  things and definitely should support them at the end of the day, most people
Speaker 7:  don't buy from small companies because they're small. Right. And so
Speaker 7:  having things like a mechanic, he were like, when I first got into
Speaker 7:  mechanical keyboards, this was
Speaker 7:  2007 or
Speaker 7:  eight. At that time I was looking for a computer. And it's like, if money
Speaker 7:  were no object for each part, like if you look for like building a PC, that's
Speaker 7:  how you look at it. You look at the fanciest thing and then you go back and
Speaker 7:  see, like, what can you afford for keyboard? Is this, the fanciest thing
Speaker 7:  was garbage. EA the paint was like some logic tech,
Speaker 7:  rubber, dumb thing with a little screen on it. I typed it out on the store.
Speaker 7:  Like this feels like garbage, but crappy keyboard at work feels better than
Speaker 7:  this thing. And so like, why is that? And like, there were no
Speaker 7:  options. It doesn't matter if I had money or not. There's no options in
Speaker 7:  terms of like, I could buy something. There's also no options for me to search
Speaker 7:  for anything. I had no idea about anything.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. You know, I got into keyboards like in 2009,
Speaker 4:  2010 or something. I think one of my first keyboards was the Mathias. It
Speaker 4:  was their keyboard built for Mac users and it had these outs,
Speaker 4:  mechanical keys. I still have the thing I will never part with it. Cause
Speaker 4:  it was my first one. And I just have this affection for it.
Speaker 4:  And there was no way to talk about these things online. There
Speaker 4:  was no language. The, the, the companies didn't seem to
Speaker 4:  care. And there were these very small groups of people who liked
Speaker 4:  cherry switches or who liked topiary switches. And that was like me and two
Speaker 4:  other people who liked Alps. And that was it. And then it just slowly, this
Speaker 4:  community built up and it seems like it primarily built up in places like
Speaker 4:  dusk authority. Is that accurate?
Speaker 7:  Yes. So like these keyboard communities, they're not built full
Speaker 7:  of people who play games. They're built people who use keyboards and like
Speaker 7:  typing, like initially a large majority of
Speaker 7:  the key card members were actually writers. People who
Speaker 7:  type a lot, also like coders and programmers. They also type a
Speaker 7:  lot. So they, they, they care. And of course, gamers also characters. They
Speaker 4:  Gotta get the speed, the
Speaker 7:  Speed, but there's going to win. But also what's really fascinating about
Speaker 7:  this is that all of these different people have different kinds of
Speaker 7:  requirements and tastes and none of them are wrong. And that what was
Speaker 7:  really interesting about, especially about the early Reddit, I don't know
Speaker 7:  if this is the case anymore, but at one time the art mechanical keyboard
Speaker 7:  was the second boast, positive subreddit next to
Speaker 7:  makeup, because basically it was all, oh, you should just get this skateboard.
Speaker 7:  Oh, you see this one? Like basically there are no wrong answers at that time,
Speaker 7:  because anything you got was better than when you had before. And because
Speaker 7:  the difference is so striking, especially when you got your first mechanical
Speaker 7:  keyboard going from like years of having a terrible one and not being old
Speaker 7:  enough to actually experience what they were before. It was a big
Speaker 7:  shift. Like it's like a, it's a hard moment of like, oh, that's
Speaker 7:  nice. It's like having really nice headphones for the first time. It's like,
Speaker 7:  oh, I'm, that's the money. Lots of money now.
Speaker 4:  And so are you using Reddit? Are you using social media? How are you
Speaker 4:  getting people excited?
Speaker 7:  I like to get people excited through other people. And
Speaker 7:  so like, one of the things I realized, and this was a while ago is
Speaker 7:  that I'm not really scalable online to make posts. Like
Speaker 7:  I really like communicating with people one-on-one because I can,
Speaker 7:  I can see the light in their eyes when they get it. I can tune the
Speaker 7:  analogies to that person. Like I like to get to know the person a little
Speaker 7:  bit and I can like use their prior knowledge to explain to them, but it gets
Speaker 7:  really hard in a written article to do that because you have to talk to the
Speaker 7:  masses, right. Talking to the masses is actually a really hard problem
Speaker 7:  because like you're not talking to the person anymore. And so
Speaker 7:  if I can explain and talk to individual people who are
Speaker 7:  really enthusiastic about things, then they can kind of also promote
Speaker 7:  their thing in their own way. Right. And so like, I really like not
Speaker 7:  being the only like central focal point because it's, I'm only
Speaker 7:  so scalable. I'm not, I, I can't, I can't cloud computing myself.
Speaker 7:  Unfortunately,
Speaker 4:  Kickstarter seems to have been a really big, important tool for
Speaker 4:  input club over the years to get people excited. What about
Speaker 4:  kickstart? Like why is Kickstarter so successful for you guys?
Speaker 7:  The blood's answer of this is they have an audience. There are
Speaker 7:  the largest of the crowdsourcing audiences in terms of
Speaker 7:  services they provide, they're usually a little bit lacking on that. So
Speaker 7:  in order to compete, the other companies tend to give you a little bit
Speaker 7:  more on the services side. Like when we got started Kickstarter, wasn't really
Speaker 7:  viable. Like there's a reason why most hardware Kickstarters end up like
Speaker 7:  failing and flopping. I'll get into that in a second one that's really annoying
Speaker 7:  for arc arc group is they're hard.
Speaker 7:  And there's a lot of things that can fail very easily.
Speaker 7:  Like, oh, everyone knows about the chip shortage. Now that can affect
Speaker 7:  these kinds of projects extremely poorly. Like when we did
Speaker 7:  the white Fox Kickstarter, we had the initial order, but we
Speaker 7:  ended up having to quickly buy an alternate part
Speaker 7:  because apparently the fab burned down and it was going to be a year and
Speaker 7:  a half for them to get more parts.
Speaker 4:  Wow.
Speaker 7:  And I had worked years and years and years on this Ferber just
Speaker 7:  to, just for this part. And there were no alternate parts I'd
Speaker 7:  have to like completely rewrite everything. And I'm like the
Speaker 7:  vehicles, all the testing, all the users, right.
Speaker 7:  As like this was before the pandemic. Right. And so like,
Speaker 7:  I was very well aware of like with the chip short has happened. Like this
Speaker 7:  is really painful. Right. And so you
Speaker 4:  Were like, I know, I know all about chip shortages. Yes.
Speaker 7:  It's not fun. It sucks a lot. And when they come back, they could be
Speaker 7:  2, 3, 4 times the cost when you can get them. And so that
Speaker 7:  this can really affect how, like when you collect money for a Kickstarter,
Speaker 7:  like, can you succeed? Like, do you just pull into your own pocket?
Speaker 7:  You may have already spent half the money or all the money on developing
Speaker 7:  the prototype or gathering materials. Right. So a lot of these
Speaker 7:  Kickstarters, they just can't be good either way. Working with
Speaker 7:  originally Massdrop was nicest because they would actually front the bill
Speaker 7:  for the, like the initial production costs and stuff like that. And then
Speaker 7:  the prototype it got, cause we didn't have any money. We started with zero
Speaker 7:  basically, no seed money at all. Right. So like even with the Kickstarter,
Speaker 7:  you have to get all of the ad and marketing stuff. Like actually
Speaker 7:  getting the word out is a big deal. Like there's a, a measure that be
Speaker 7:  used for like, if a kickstart is actually successful you'll know in the first
Speaker 7:  like 24 hours at that point, generally, if it's does
Speaker 7:  dog good, then he's fine. We'll just cancel it. Wow. And there it goes, all
Speaker 7:  the PR money and most PR firms are vultures.
Speaker 7:  Unfortunately
Speaker 4:  You spend all this money, you spent all this time. And if it's not that first
Speaker 4:  24 hours, you're done. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Basically you might as well just like pack up and just take your losses.
Speaker 7:  Cause you spent money on that fancy video on all that marketing. You don't
Speaker 7:  get that back. And then there's all of the integration costs with,
Speaker 7:  oh, your fulfillment for actually fulfilling something or like
Speaker 7:  shipping or people like lose packages for whatever reason. It doesn't actually
Speaker 7:  matter. Like all of that back on you because you're a business. So kind of
Speaker 7:  card companies. Don't like you, they like the consumer. So there's all these
Speaker 7:  problems fulfilling with these Kickstarters. But they're interesting. And
Speaker 7:  there's no other mechanism to actually make it happen because a large company
Speaker 7:  is not going to fulfill your dream or like build your thing. And they're
Speaker 7:  not going to give you the time of day. Right.
Speaker 4:  That's wild though. It does kind of continue to baffle
Speaker 4:  me that we have these very large companies that are clearly very aware of
Speaker 4:  what's going on in the keyboard space. They're paying attention. Why aren't
Speaker 4:  they teaming up with you? Why aren't they teaming up with other keyboard
Speaker 4:  creators?
Speaker 7:  So here's an anecdote that I learned kind of offhand
Speaker 7:  from someone else who went to CES this past year,
Speaker 7:  they were talking to was HyperX, which is owned by
Speaker 7:  HP now. And it turns out that HP is not
Speaker 7:  interested in doing anything with, with another like sourcing firms,
Speaker 7:  like an Amazon or Walmart, unless it's like a hundred million dollar deal.
Speaker 4:  So it costs a lot of money
Speaker 7:  So that that's not like an ending PO, they want that PO for a hundred million
Speaker 7:  dollars to go through and then they'll put something behind it. But it's
Speaker 7:  almost impossible to think at that scale, unless you have led an army of
Speaker 7:  MBAs behind you to like actually plan it out, as well as the
Speaker 7:  market research and all this stuff like that. That's not feasible. Like I'm
Speaker 7:  sure that's like a ridiculous number and it's not actually that high, but
Speaker 7:  that's the kind of like hurdles that these large companies end up having.
Speaker 7:  They're like they have their duty to their shareholders. They have to make
Speaker 7:  money. And so the people at the top will do the take the easy stuff first.
Speaker 7:  But if they don't take the chances on, on basically anything.
Speaker 4:  And so that's where we, we, we, we kind of look at you. We look at, we look
Speaker 4:  at Jesse, we look at these other guys making these keyboards to say, build
Speaker 4:  us the small, take the risks, build us a smaller stuff.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. And a lot of the stuff, especially if you look at kind of the, the
Speaker 7:  audio file space, there is a way to be successful by
Speaker 7:  not making a lot of things. You could make a larger impact.
Speaker 7:  That's what like wall street and Silicon valley like is the impact and where
Speaker 7:  people were money. But in terms of you don't have to be a
Speaker 7:  fancy investors startup to have a successful business.
Speaker 7:  They're not the same thing, right? You can, you can have a successful business
Speaker 7:  with a small business right now. It's not sexy. And you can't
Speaker 7:  like proclaim yourself all the time. But if you, if you
Speaker 7:  actually have a vision and you actually want to succeed, do it your way,
Speaker 7:  the way you want it, that's generally the way you want to do it. As long
Speaker 7:  as you can pull it off course, right? You still have to make money at the
Speaker 7:  end of the day. Just a
Speaker 4:  Little bit of money
Speaker 7:  Stuff costs money, unfortunately.
Speaker 4:  Well, thank you, Jacob. This has been an absolutely wonderful
Speaker 4:  conversation,
Speaker 4:  Man. I think he was only talking to Jacob that I really realized
Speaker 4:  how much the space has changed over the years. But while Jacob has given
Speaker 4:  me and hopefully you a really great idea of how much this industry has blown
Speaker 4:  up over the last eight years, I kind of want to know what's happening
Speaker 4:  right this second in the space. There's just a lot of
Speaker 4:  options. Compared to the last time I went on a keyboard buying spree. After
Speaker 4:  the break, we're going to talk to someone who is making the sheer volume
Speaker 4:  of choices in the keyboard world, their actual business,
Speaker 1:  Thanks to grin for supporting this episode. So you and your
Speaker 1:  business have finally taken the leap into influencer marketing. It's going
Speaker 1:  great. And you're excited to connect with your audience in a powerful new
Speaker 1:  way, but you've noticed you're spending a lot of time on busy work checking
Speaker 1:  to see if the creator has gotten your product, moving through a tangled web
Speaker 1:  of emails and DMS. And now you're wondering, Hey, did that
Speaker 1:  Instagram post they promised ever even go up. Influencer marketing
Speaker 1:  can be super effective, but not if it's a drain on your time. That's
Speaker 1:  where green comes in. Grim is the number one creator management platform.
Speaker 1:  It helps you find and recruit the perfect ambassadors for your brand and
Speaker 1:  streamline the communication process. You can collect all creator content
Speaker 1:  in one, easy to find place and track your return on investment in
Speaker 1:  mealtime influencer marketing doesn't have to be complicated.
Speaker 1:  Grim makes it simple. So you can treat your creators like your brand
Speaker 1:  revolves around them because in the creator economy, it does
Speaker 1:  influencer marketing is easier with grain. Find out
Speaker 1:  why@glenn.co that's, G R I
Speaker 1:  n.co.
Speaker 4:  Okay. We're back to recap. The keyboard industry has
Speaker 4:  exploded. Thanks to people like Jacob Alexander, building the dang things
Speaker 4:  and showing the world. There's a huge market for super customizable mechanical
Speaker 4:  keyboards. It's moved beyond the forums and even subreddits. And they're
Speaker 4:  now Twitch, streamers, YouTubers, even folks on Kik talk, pushing the keyboard
Speaker 4:  agenda and giving us all, some serious keyboard MV to get a
Speaker 4:  better understanding of what's happening right now. I reached out to Julie
Speaker 4:  Muncie,
Speaker 6:  Hello, I am Julie Muncie. I am a writer
Speaker 6:  and also a person who builds keyboards.
Speaker 4:  We worked together once upon a time as journalists and Julie's work has appeared
Speaker 4:  on Gizmodo and IO nine and wired. And she's really fantastic
Speaker 4:  when Julie isn't writing about the best lube for your key switches or the
Speaker 4:  best game to play on your PC. She spent an increasing amount of time on a
Speaker 4:  very cool side hustle called keyboard concierge. The
Speaker 4:  keyboard landscape is confusing and for a prize, Julia is trying to help
Speaker 4:  customers navigate it. And hopefully she's going to help me figure out
Speaker 4:  what the space actually looks like right now. So here's my interview with
Speaker 4:  Julie Muncie.
Speaker 4:  Well, I've, I've known you for a couple of, for many years now. And I remember
Speaker 4:  that first time you mentioned you were doing the service. And I was like,
Speaker 4:  that makes a lot of sense because I feel like the keyboard space
Speaker 4:  itself has transformed a lot in the last few years and gotten
Speaker 4:  harder to kind of parse for most people.
Speaker 6:  Absolutely. Over the past few years, it's really exploded.
Speaker 6:  The amount of options have increased dramatically
Speaker 6:  and it's a lot to learn and a lot to navigate. You have to learn, you
Speaker 6:  know, not only how to build a thing, but also where to find
Speaker 6:  the parts to build. And you have to follow complex
Speaker 6:  group buys, which are like pre-orders, but worse
Speaker 6:  and all of these things. And it's just, it's a lot.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I mean, I got, I bet I I've been very into the keyboard community for
Speaker 4:  years. I bought my first mechanical keyboard and like the late two thousands,
Speaker 4:  right before I guess this huge kind of kickoff. But if I, if I
Speaker 4:  take a break from that community for even a year, there's suddenly all
Speaker 4:  these new switches, there's all these new keywords. Like the GMM K
Speaker 4:  was something I had never even heard of. And everybody I talked to, who's
Speaker 4:  a keyboard fanatic. Now. I was like, oh yeah, everybody knows the GMM. K
Speaker 4:  that's the best keyboard you can get. And I'm like, what, what is it? I don't
Speaker 4:  understand what's happening. Do you think there's a reason that it just kind
Speaker 4:  of exploded like this and gotten so complex?
Speaker 6:  I think there are a couple of reasons. I think one reason is
Speaker 6:  that a lot of people like me got into
Speaker 6:  it around the time of the pandemic when it hit, I got
Speaker 6:  my first keyboard ordered a keyboard from a company called IQ next in
Speaker 6:  China. They have really great keyboards. So I ordered it in like
Speaker 6:  January 20, 20. So I was waiting for it for quite a while, as you
Speaker 6:  might imagine. And during that time, I just did a lot of reading
Speaker 6:  and obsessing and hyper fixating and learned about keyboards. And I think
Speaker 6:  a lot of other people did the same. Also video games in the gaming space
Speaker 6:  have been a really big deal here. I think for a lot of people, gaming
Speaker 6:  keyboards have been an entry point that, you know, they
Speaker 6:  get a gaming keyboard. There's the reputation that may or
Speaker 6:  may not be true that mechanical switches, you know, give you better gaming
Speaker 6:  performance and people get into that. And then they want to
Speaker 6:  customize and explore and learn and like
Speaker 6:  all of the gaming keyboards, most of them and okay, this is changing
Speaker 6:  now to be fair. But up until like the past year, they're all like
Speaker 6:  black and red and like lime and green and really
Speaker 6:  garish. And if you want a mechanical
Speaker 6:  keyboard to play games on, but you don't want it to look like that
Speaker 6:  up until the past year, you had to go make your own basically.
Speaker 6:  And so that was a big thing. I think there have also been
Speaker 6:  an increase in streamers and content creators in the scene. And I
Speaker 6:  think they both arrived the trend and add to it.
Speaker 4:  I definitely see a lot of Twitch streamers and stuff. I admittedly do not
Speaker 4:  watch a lot of Twitch, but when I do, I do see people are really
Speaker 4:  focused on their keyboards and it's this kind of like nerdiness that reminds
Speaker 4:  me that old movie hackers where it's like these people are just like wanting
Speaker 4:  to, to show themselves, wanting to explore their own
Speaker 4:  personalities in this piece of technology that most of us can't
Speaker 4:  even see. But we definitely hear on a zoom. Is that accurate as
Speaker 4:  this really like this kind of like form of self-expression?
Speaker 6:  Absolutely. I mean, one of the things that initially drew me to
Speaker 6:  mechanical keyboards and kept me getting into them was that like,
Speaker 6:  it was a piece of consumer technology that I use for myself
Speaker 6:  every day that I can understand and build and
Speaker 6:  customize. I mean, you can do that to an extent with gaming PCs,
Speaker 6:  right? But they're complicated and very expensive keyboards are
Speaker 6:  expensive, but not as expensive as a good gaming PC. And it's
Speaker 6:  a thing where you, you know, w some time you can understand them well enough
Speaker 6:  that you can be designing your own keyboard PCBs, if you want to.
Speaker 6:  I not quite smart enough for this haven't cracked that yet, but a lot of
Speaker 6:  people have, and you can do all of these things. So it's very much,
Speaker 6:  it becomes this piece of tech that you can understand
Speaker 6:  and customize and build yourself and have ownership of. And then there's
Speaker 6:  very few other pieces of technology we use nowadays
Speaker 6:  that has that allure and that power and that like,
Speaker 6:  customizability that sense that this is mine and I own it.
Speaker 6:  And I understand and picked every single part of it.
Speaker 4:  When you entered into the space and you realized there was kind of this
Speaker 4:  need, was it just only yourself that, that, that drove
Speaker 4:  this? Like you realized how hard it is and you're like, I want to help others.
Speaker 4:  Or were you finding other people really having this difficulty too?
Speaker 6:  A couple of things first was I did it become a part of a
Speaker 6:  keyboard community that a Milo worked on and then joined. And actually
Speaker 6:  I'm a mod there now at mint Lada because acute keyboard
Speaker 6:  club just scored. It's a great, and so a lot of people talking, asking
Speaker 6:  questions and just realizing that there's a big barrier to entry,
Speaker 6:  a lot of learning. And I had to do a lot of research and I
Speaker 6:  became very fascinated by it and just learned
Speaker 6:  all these things. And then I came up to a couple of problems. The first
Speaker 6:  problem was that I didn't have the money to do all the building I wanted
Speaker 6:  to do. And the second thing was, I saw that
Speaker 6:  there were people in the space who will help others build
Speaker 6:  keyboards, but they tend to be big streamers people
Speaker 6:  like Tahoe types go and make these really, really nice
Speaker 6:  keyboards in front of a large audience. And they make a lot
Speaker 6:  of commissions and they make the rest of their money off of streaming.
Speaker 11:  What am I cutting? Oh, yes. I forgot to explain. So your stabilizers come
Speaker 11:  like this, so you can see how there's these two little prongs that are
Speaker 11:  sticking out. So when you bought them,
Speaker 6:  And this is really cool, but it's deeply inaccessible to just a normal person
Speaker 6:  who wants to build a keyboard. You're probably not going to get Teo types
Speaker 6:  or one of them to build you a keyboard. So I thought I could do a similar
Speaker 6:  sort of building service, but on a much smaller
Speaker 6:  scale. And that's where it really originated from, from
Speaker 6:  wanting to build, but not having the money to build a bunch of
Speaker 6:  projects myself. Cause it does get real expensive real quick. And like I
Speaker 6:  said, my day job is a writer, so I not making it bank
Speaker 6:  and seeing that people were doing this work. And the other thing was
Speaker 6:  just the recognition that I had built all of this
Speaker 6:  knowledge and that I was not bad at this and that it took a
Speaker 6:  lot of time and effort and that a lot of people like these things, but
Speaker 6:  don't have that time or just don't care enough. And that it might be fun
Speaker 6:  to share that knowledge with other people.
Speaker 4:  You mentioned you, you kind of were in this discourse group. I definitely
Speaker 4:  have spent so much time in the mechanical keyboard, subreddit.
Speaker 4:  How are these communities kind of like escalating this
Speaker 4:  attention? The mechanical keyboards are receiving?
Speaker 6:  I think part of it is just that there are more and more
Speaker 6:  eyes on these communities and that is drawing in
Speaker 6:  bigger corporate players and hobbyists and people who
Speaker 6:  think that there's something interesting here and maybe a way to make money
Speaker 6:  here. And maybe a lot of money here like razor. If you look at their
Speaker 6:  offerings over the past few years, they've become more and more
Speaker 6:  interested in trying to release prestige products that
Speaker 6:  core, the more snobby mechanical keyboard,
Speaker 6:  hobbyists that look different and have different
Speaker 6:  switches and like achieve a certain field
Speaker 6:  that hobbyists really want. Because I think V these companies have seen how
Speaker 6:  much money people spend on these things. And like you have players
Speaker 6:  like glorious, which you mentioned the G MMK. And
Speaker 6:  that is a company that is building itself as a bigger and
Speaker 6:  bigger brand in the peripheral space and doing it largely
Speaker 6:  off of the back of interest in mechanical keyboards. So I think a
Speaker 6:  lot of it is corporate tech realizing that there's money here,
Speaker 6:  which, you know, that's both a good and a bad thing for the hobbyist.
Speaker 6:  And another is I think, you know, the interest in the
Speaker 6:  hobby moving beyond the white nerd
Speaker 6:  gamer boy crew, which of course has caused a lot of friction in the
Speaker 6:  community. There's, you know, people who love that, people who hate that,
Speaker 6:  but I think it's become less of sort of an identity Tarion
Speaker 6:  gamer boy thing, and more of a thing, dial up people who are interested in
Speaker 6:  tech and video games who aren't white boys have
Speaker 6:  become more and more engaged in and interested in. And that
Speaker 6:  has also led to the scene.
Speaker 4:  You're doing these, these customizations that, that
Speaker 4:  you do. And these, these kinds of, I guess, not customization, they're more
Speaker 4:  like a concierge service, right? Like people come and they ask
Speaker 4:  you, I want to do they come to you with like big ideas or they come to you
Speaker 4:  and say, I want a pink keyboard. I want some cool flowers on it. I
Speaker 4:  want it to really pop. And I want it to make my fingers feel nice.
Speaker 6:  It's usually the latter, but it varies.
Speaker 6:  And yeah, the way it usually works is someone comes and
Speaker 6:  either they want help shopping or help building or both, it's usually both.
Speaker 6:  And so what I do is I just use the knowledge I have
Speaker 6:  of where to look for stuff what's popular. What's good.
Speaker 6:  And based on their interests, I find them stuff. And I'm like, what do you
Speaker 6:  think of these key caps or, or this keyboard shape? What are your
Speaker 6:  needs and what do you want to express? And then
Speaker 6:  once I find that out, we get it and I build it and send it to
Speaker 6:  them.
Speaker 4:  And how are, how are they finding you? Are they finding you through like
Speaker 4:  Twitter? Are they finding you through like discord or Reddit?
Speaker 6:  I think it's mostly Twitter and discord. And
Speaker 6:  like, honestly I have gotten way more interest than I was
Speaker 6:  prepared for that necessarily able to handle. So I'm pretty backed up.
Speaker 6:  If you're listening to this, if you reach out there will be a long wait,
Speaker 6:  but yeah, I have a website keyboard,
Speaker 6:  concierge.com and at KB underscore
Speaker 6:  concierge on Twitter, you know, I have my main Twitter
Speaker 6:  that I built up a following and tech and gaming spaces as
Speaker 6:  a writer there. And I know people, you know, like you
Speaker 6:  and people at a bunch of other publications. And when I launched this,
Speaker 6:  everyone was very supportive and retweeted. And I think a lot of people,
Speaker 6:  you know, through that, just kind of learned who I was.
Speaker 4:  You think this is going to be a service that we're going to see more people
Speaker 4:  really embracing?
Speaker 6:  I think probably, yes. I think right now it is very tied up
Speaker 6:  in being a content creator and most people who do this service
Speaker 6:  also stream or make YouTube videos of builds. I think
Speaker 6:  it's just because that's what the prominent names in the space do. And
Speaker 6:  because it gets you a dual income stream, the only reason why I
Speaker 6:  necessarily don't do those things is I just haven't had the space in time.
Speaker 6:  I have my hand in like five different things and then given time. But yeah,
Speaker 6:  I do think more and more people are going to emerge in this
Speaker 6:  space and be sort of concierge shoppers slash
Speaker 6:  builders slash content creators. And there are already a lot out there.
Speaker 4:  Let's talk about some of those content creators, because what is the
Speaker 4:  appeal do you think of watching other people build these
Speaker 4:  keyboards? Cause that's like kind of the primary thing that's happening with
Speaker 4:  these content creators, right? They're like explaining it. It's, they're
Speaker 4:  showing it as they're almost like gadget bloggers right here. They're showing
Speaker 4:  it off. They're giving you the unboxing it and then they're putting it
Speaker 4:  together.
Speaker 6:  Lots of unboxing videos. Yeah. I think there are a few things. I
Speaker 6:  think one is the sort of showcasing and
Speaker 6:  voyeurism of seeing really nice, expensive things like
Speaker 6:   types to how types went really viral
Speaker 6:  in like 20, 19, 20, 20. I'm
Speaker 6:  not sure precisely, but he built a keyboard for the Fortnite
Speaker 6:  streamer T Fu
Speaker 12:  Oh my God, dude, this thing is
Speaker 12:  nuts.
Speaker 6:  And that keyboard costs $3,500. That was like the most
Speaker 6:  expensive keyboard you could possibly build. And people
Speaker 6:  loved it and were fascinated by it seeing like, you know, the case was made
Speaker 6:  out of like Chrome steel or something. It was wild.
Speaker 6:  And seeing that come together and how it looks and how it sounds.
Speaker 6:  I think that's really interesting. I think the other thing
Speaker 6:  is just, it's a means of learning and knowledge.
Speaker 6:  I consume a lot less keyboard content than I used to when I
Speaker 6:  was first learning because I watched a lot of that content to build
Speaker 6:  my own knowledge base to see, okay, how do you build this? And
Speaker 6:  what is good for this and this, what sort of customization techniques
Speaker 6:  and modern techniques, because that's another big thing in this scene is
Speaker 6:  modding parts of the keyboard to sound and feel better like
Speaker 6:  lots of little mechanical lubricants and like a little
Speaker 6:  mods. You do it with tape and all these things. And these are techniques
Speaker 6:  invented by people. And if you want to learn them the best way to do it is
Speaker 6:  on YouTube or Twitch. Watching people build things.
Speaker 4:  That's very fascinating to me cause I'm gonna make you listen to this right
Speaker 4:  now. I've got a keyboard over here. This is why my
Speaker 4:  Leopold . I
Speaker 4:  went ahead and I'm it's, it's got the toe prey stems.
Speaker 6:  Nice, nice.
Speaker 4:  They're very, very good stems. Very good stems. But I replaced them. I replaced
Speaker 4:  the stems because I wanted to use my own Cary stem key
Speaker 4:  caps and just listened to my regular toll-free keyboard.
Speaker 4:  Okay. You hear that?
Speaker 4:  My other, this keyboard sounded exactly like that until I replaced the stems.
Speaker 6:  Cool.
Speaker 4:  Does it sound different? Like, to me, it kind of sounded different when I
Speaker 4:  did it and I was like, oh, did I break my keyboard? But it does. It
Speaker 4:  sounds different. So like
Speaker 6:  Massively
Speaker 4:  People are, I guess, really focused on that and wanting to, I'm just now
Speaker 4:  learning that there is apparently a large community of people who would tell
Speaker 4:  me how to fix that noise.
Speaker 6:  Yes. There absolutely are. Yeah. In fact, in
Speaker 6:  my head I was thinking of, okay, so that's readily on the upstroke if you
Speaker 6:  loop this specific thing, et cetera, et cetera. And it was going on in my
Speaker 6:  head, but
Speaker 4:  I know what I'm going to be talking to you about after we finished this
Speaker 4:  conversation.
Speaker 6:  Yes. But people are very invested in how their keyboards
Speaker 6:  sound. So most build
Speaker 6:  videos, feature a typing section where the person just types
Speaker 6:  into a microphone.
Speaker 11:  They all sound that funky. Yeah. I mean, these are, Telio still, Telio,
Speaker 11:  aren't generally known for their,
Speaker 6:  And they're even like break off videos of just typing
Speaker 6:  a SMR where like you just listened to a nice keyboard type and
Speaker 6:  people really like these. I enjoy them. I think it's a nice sound.
Speaker 6:  I mean, part of my fascination with mechanical
Speaker 6:  keyboards is when I went to undergrad, we had a
Speaker 6:  collective printer in the library and it had an old keyboard attached to
Speaker 6:  it. And it was really loud and clacky and very satisfying. And I
Speaker 6:  love that fan. And so when I was first got into it, I
Speaker 6:  got into mechanical keyboards. I wanted to build something
Speaker 6:  that felt and sounded like that because it was nostalgic. It made me feel
Speaker 6:  cool. Like you mentioned the movie hackers earlier, it made me feel like
Speaker 6:  a character in that movie,
Speaker 4:  Angelina Jolie. And that movie was awesome, man.
Speaker 6:  Yes, exactly. And like that fantasy was
Speaker 6:  something that I was chasing on a tactile and aesthetic level. And
Speaker 6:  I think a lot of people have similar memories
Speaker 6:  of like an old apple two or IBM
Speaker 6:  model M keyboard that was lying around the house or they've
Speaker 6:  seen, or felt a keyboard somewhere, something that's streamer has or something
Speaker 6:  where they just dug the sound in the field and they want something
Speaker 6:  like that.
Speaker 4:  Do you think there is like that YouTube and that Twitch and
Speaker 4:  video has kind of helped increase the
Speaker 4:  popularity of this community because people can hit here or this stuff. Cause
Speaker 4:  like when I started doing this, there weren't a lot of YouTubers. This wasn't
Speaker 4:  a thing. And now that seems to be where a big chunk of the community is.
Speaker 6:  Absolutely. Like in my submissions for keyboard
Speaker 6:  concierge, I will regularly, you know, there's a space in the form where
Speaker 6:  people can write what they're looking for. And a lot of times it's happened
Speaker 6:  more and more people link me to videos of keyboards say saw on YouTube and
Speaker 6:  they're like, I want something like this. And all of a sudden I have to tell
Speaker 6:  them, you know, that keyboard costs $1,200 and they waited
Speaker 6:  a couple years for all the parts to come out of group
Speaker 6:  by. Here's how we might be able to approximate this. But
Speaker 6:  absolutely I think being able to see and to hear them is a big thing.
Speaker 4:  Where do you think keyboards are going next? Are they going to get more complex?
Speaker 6:  I don't know if more complex, I think what I've seen
Speaker 6:  mostly the past year or two, since, you know, I've gotten really into,
Speaker 6:  this is a sort of sideways explosion of
Speaker 6:  different styles and shapes and little
Speaker 6:  accessory things like for a while, people got really into having
Speaker 6:  rotary knobs on their keyboards,
Speaker 4:  Very popular at the verge,
Speaker 6:  Extremely popular that you can use as, you know,
Speaker 6:  volume knobs or whatever else. Those got real big. And I
Speaker 6:  think certain aesthetics, like very
Speaker 6:  sleek modernist keyboards and then a move against that
Speaker 6:  to like more outrageous and playful and garish looking
Speaker 6:  keyboards. I don't necessarily see them getting more
Speaker 6:  complex, but I'm seeing more and more aesthetic
Speaker 6:  variety and sort of like in the
Speaker 6:  materials coming out of group bias and corporations, it's very
Speaker 6:  much like its own little art world of like, you know, what is
Speaker 6:  trending, what people think looks good and just a really intense
Speaker 6:  focus right now on aesthetics.
Speaker 4:  Awesome. Well, I feeling bad because all of my keyboards are
Speaker 4:  gray, so I am, I am not in the future going
Speaker 4:  to have to go buy something that looks like an electric guitar. I did see
Speaker 4:  that just recently. That sounds very cool. But Julie, thank
Speaker 4:  you so much for chatting and talking about this.
Speaker 6:  Absolutely.
Speaker 4:  Thanks again to Julie Muncie for talking with me for the show and thank you
Speaker 4:  for listening. The keyboard space really has changed and people like Jacob
Speaker 4:  and Julie are driving that change, but as much as it's them, it's
Speaker 4:  also all the other fans and creators gathering online at places like Reddit
Speaker 4:  discord and that wide variety of keyboard forums, where Jacob made a
Speaker 4:  name for himself. It's the community. Not any company driving
Speaker 4:  that change this. Isn't the only community driving kick-ass change in the
Speaker 4:  gadget space this month. I'm going to be talking to a lot of really cool
Speaker 4:  people doing really cool things to change gadgets. So stay tuned.
Speaker 4:  If you have thoughts about this episode or even just what we're going to
Speaker 4:  be talking about for the rest of the month, we'd love to hear for you. I'm
Speaker 4:  Alex H prance on Twitter, or you can email
Speaker 4:  us@vergecastattheverge.com. Our regular
Speaker 4:  Vergecast chat show will be on Friday and the next week on Tuesday, I'll
Speaker 4:  be back for another episode of this creator series. All about track
Speaker 4:  balls. Be warned. Guys is going to get nerdy.
Speaker 4:  This episode of the Vergecast is produced by me, Alex Cranz lead producer,
Speaker 4:  Liam James in senior audio director, Andrew Marino. Okay.
Speaker 4:  I'll see you guys later be nice.
Speaker 1:  This episode has been brought to you by grin. Top creators are
Speaker 1:  already using and loving your product. So why haven't you partnered with
Speaker 1:  them so they can share that love with their audience. Grin helps you bring
Speaker 1:  creators on board is the ultimate champions of your brand. You can
Speaker 1:  recruit ship sample products and track creator content. All in one
Speaker 1:  place. Grin is the number one influencer management platform,
Speaker 1:  helping e-commerce brands connect with their audience through the power of
Speaker 1:  creator partnerships. Find out how grin can help you grow your
Speaker 1:  brand. Watch the demo@grin.co that's, GRI
Speaker 1:  n.co.