# Transcript
ID: 8e64fb90-1a72-11ed-9a45-f3a167c7804e
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Samsung’s Galaxy Unpacked August 2022 biggest announcements
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-455510094673137304/4696486460651198215/s93290-US-5047s-1660331403.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, David Pierce, Alex Cranz, and Richard Lawler to discuss all the announcement from Samsung's Galaxy Unpacked event this past week.
Speaker 1:  Today on the verge cast, the team breaks down the galaxy unpacked event.
Speaker 1:  And we're sorry to inform you Disney plus not winning the streaming wars.
Speaker 1:  Of course, we'll get into all the gadgets from this week. That's coming up
Speaker 1:  right after this.
Speaker 3:  Hey, I'm Sam Sanders and I host into it. It's a weekly
Speaker 3:  show where we obsess about the culture that matters.
Speaker 3:  Like how do you end a TV show these days, especially when
Speaker 3:  it's part of a franchise.
Speaker 4:  Are you making it up as you go along? Are you just winging it? And
Speaker 4:  the fans wanted the answer to that question to be
Speaker 4:  absolutely not
Speaker 3:  Into it from vulture new episodes, every Thursday,
Speaker 3:  subscribe, wherever you get your podcasts,
Speaker 5:  The flagship podcast with folding phones, you wanted
Speaker 5:  it. You got it. One hour phones are flipping half phones
Speaker 5:  it open are back again. Phones are turning into tablets. That's all. No,
Speaker 5:  we're gonna talk a lot of things. I'm your friend. Eli. David Pierce is here.
Speaker 5:  Hi.
Speaker 6:  I'm. I'm just here to tell you that phones are cool. That don't fold
Speaker 6:  my whole phone. Did you? Doesn't
Speaker 5:  Fold. I'm good. The flagship audience fold, which
Speaker 5:  Alex Kranz is here.
Speaker 7:  I I'm your friend that loves to open the phone with just like one thumb.
Speaker 5:  Just like do a, just
Speaker 7:  Boom pop flip. I'm trying to think of what the noise
Speaker 7:  is. Okay. Cause I haven't used a flip phone in so long
Speaker 5:  In 1999. Yeah. And purchased a cell phone called the Sony
Speaker 5:  Zuma CMC 200. It's the best phone ever made.
Speaker 7:  Okay.
Speaker 5:  It was, seems unlikely. It was amazing. I bought a used one. I have one at
Speaker 5:  my house, like a perfect condition. One D I to talk about this all the time,
Speaker 5:  it had a stock to open, like the mic flips
Speaker 5:  down from the body of the phone.
Speaker 7:  Yes. Nevermind. This is a good
Speaker 5:  Phone. And so when it had the Sony Jo dial, so it had like a,
Speaker 5:  you know, had a multi element, led display that like I love it. The text.
Speaker 5:  So you'd like scroll to a name and then if you could get it exactly right.
Speaker 5:  You could make the call by flipping the stock. That's awesome. And then when
Speaker 5:  you were done, you'd be like,
Speaker 7:  Oh my gosh.
Speaker 5:  And I practiced that move so many times,
Speaker 7:  Like in the mirror, I gotta
Speaker 5:  Google. I was like scroll flip baby. And my friends in high school were like
Speaker 5:  one, why are you the weirdo with a cell phone? And two stop saying
Speaker 5:  scrolling flip.
Speaker 5:  But I have it again. It was the one of the best ever let's do this. And my
Speaker 5:  all town, top five cell phones. Yeah. Sony Zuma. CMZ 200. Just putting
Speaker 5:  it out there. Scrolling, flip. I feel you, Richard Lawler is here by the
Speaker 5:  way. I do exist. And I have bad news about streaming.
Speaker 5:  It's true. So we have been remote for a million years. We're all together
Speaker 5:  in the studio today, which is crazy. It's literally never happened. It's
Speaker 5:  gonna be the, we were it's
Speaker 7:  The first, the first
Speaker 5:  Time we were just sternly told that we can't talk over each other because
Speaker 5:  Andrew can't fix it in post. Like he can when we are all apart.
Speaker 5:  So this one's gonna be nuts. But Richard is actually in town. I don't think
Speaker 5:  he's been with us in person. Since you started at the
Speaker 5:  verge over a year. Now that's crazy. But if you wanna go all
Speaker 5:  the way back to like end gadget, podcast days, Richard and I worked together
Speaker 5:  at end gadget. I used to see you in person all the time, but it was at like
Speaker 5:  CES at like three in the morning. I'd like, there's Richard. My, I, I need
Speaker 5:  to lean over and touch the ground. Richard is here,
Speaker 5:  but it's gonna see you in person. We're all here. There's a lot going on.
Speaker 5:  I wanna start with a little update. Okay. There's a Samsung event. We gotta
Speaker 5:  talk about there's folding phones. There's Disneys happening. There's
Speaker 5:  little GA lightning on, but we gotta start with an update. Last week we talked
Speaker 5:  about HVX maybe dying, maybe live, who knows what's gonna happen? We said,
Speaker 5:  when there's news we'll have an emergency podcast. You had may have noticed
Speaker 5:  we had no such emergency podcast because the news was like
Speaker 5:  just a devastating, nothing. Yeah, it was devastating. And they announced
Speaker 5:  that they will eventually kill HBO max. Right.
Speaker 5:  Sometime next year. But for now, everything is cool.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. It's all gonna go on discovery plus a stack. So if you hate the
Speaker 7:  HBO max app, good news.
Speaker 5:  So does the CEO of discovery.
Speaker 7:  He also hates it. If you hate the HBO content, bad news, he
Speaker 7:  also hates it. Yeah, no,
Speaker 6:  It's so expensive. Yeah. It's so much cheaper to just like rebuild houses
Speaker 6:  in Texas than to do other things. Game of Thrones
Speaker 6:  is way more expensive than that.
Speaker 5:  They did have this slide where they talked about their franchises and they
Speaker 5:  were like game of Thrones and Harry Potter. And
Speaker 5:  then the 90 day fiance universe. This is a real thing they put
Speaker 5:  on the slide. It was incredible.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Those were not good slides. There was like the male skewed
Speaker 7:  males apparently. Oh, that was awesome. You guys love plots. Yeah. You love
Speaker 7:  scripts. Female skewed. We, we just love reality.
Speaker 7:  That's not true though.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I
Speaker 7:  Think I gotta send a note, but it was great
Speaker 6:  If nobody's getting married this episode out, not percent
Speaker 7:  Out, I turned the TV off fling the
Speaker 5:  Remote. So what they've decided to do is they are gonna merge HBO, max and
Speaker 5:  discovery. Plus they haven't decided what it's called. Yeah. They're gonna
Speaker 5:  have a new app. That's like all the content from HBO, max
Speaker 5:  on the technology of the discovery plus app
Speaker 5:  is the discovery plus app. Good. Does anyone know the, they used it. It might
Speaker 5:  only be perceived as good because it never crashes, but that's because no
Speaker 5:  one uses, right? Yes. That's like, I, I think that might be the mistake they're
Speaker 5:  making, but he, they seem to like,
Speaker 6:  It's fine. Yeah. Like it is definitely possible that there are just 12 people
Speaker 6:  using it. And so it's not a problem, but like the app is fine. It's not the
Speaker 6:  like trash heap that HBO max is. So that's good.
Speaker 7:  Well, we think that right because HBO, max people actually use it.
Speaker 6:  No, but the thing, when you go to load HBO, max, and it's like, oh, would
Speaker 6:  you like to see some thumbnails for the shows you're watching come back in
Speaker 6:  30 to 40 minutes, like at least discovery plus doesn't do
Speaker 7:  That. Right? No I'm saying that's because no one uses it. Like you
Speaker 7:  maybe if, if it has 50 more million users, everybody
Speaker 7:  get everyone, you know, and everyone else, you know, to
Speaker 5:  Describe the car and subscribe to discovery, plus right
Speaker 7:  Now
Speaker 5:  Code is
Speaker 7:  See if it works, let us know report back.
Speaker 5:  Could it, could it actually hold up to a game of Thrones premier night ever?
Speaker 5:  We don't know. Yeah. They, they think it will. So like I said,
Speaker 5:  it was this news, as you can hear was not worth an emergency podcast. Yes.
Speaker 5:  But it is true that they're gonna kill HV max the app, and then relaunch
Speaker 5:  it, maybe still called HVX on a new technology platform. And that, that will
Speaker 5:  also have the content of discovery. Plus
Speaker 7:  I think it's gonna be HBO DOE.
Speaker 5:  I mean, they do love the stupid names. Again, this is a company and they
Speaker 5:  decided that their new corporate tagline is the stuff dreams are made of
Speaker 5:  which is the discovery plus app.
Speaker 6:  Just call it 90 day. Fiance, the streaming service. Well,
Speaker 5:  We'll come back to streaming cuz we gotta talk about Disney, Disney, all
Speaker 5:  kinds of stuff happening, Disney and Disney plus. Well, let's start with
Speaker 5:  the gadget news of the week. Big Samsung event unpacked 95 or
Speaker 5:  whatever it was called. It's
Speaker 6:  It's
Speaker 5:  Lost track unpacked. August 20, 22 is the event
Speaker 7:  That's 90. Five's better. Yeah. Send a note. Samsung
Speaker 5:  Unpacked 1000. They adds a bunch of stuff, David.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  So it was, this is like they do two unpacks every year. And the one
Speaker 6:  is like, here are all the phones that regular people wanna buy. So they're
Speaker 6:  like, here's the galaxy S and here's when, like the note is no
Speaker 6:  longer a thing because that used to be their off time. But anyway, so the,
Speaker 6:  the February event, I think it's February, it's usually the one where they're
Speaker 6:  like, here's the phones for regular people. And then this is like, here's
Speaker 6:  the weird stuff we're building in Korea. And that's essentially
Speaker 6:  what this was. So they announced the Z fold four, which is the phone
Speaker 6:  that folds open there's the Z flip for clarification is
Speaker 6:  the flip phone. Go on. I'm ready.
Speaker 7:  It folds open it folds open. They
Speaker 6:  Both fold. They do both fold open one folds in one flips, technically. So,
Speaker 6:  sorry, sorry. There's the Z flip four, which is just a flip phone because
Speaker 6:  the clamshell flip phones are coming back. As Neely said, you can, you can
Speaker 6:  scroll and flip scroll and
Speaker 5:  Flip, maybe it's back.
Speaker 6:  And then there's the Z fold for which is the one that's like a big, long
Speaker 6:  candy bar that opens up sideways into a tablet. And that's like, when people
Speaker 6:  talk about foldable phones, the Z fold is basically the one that everybody
Speaker 6:  talks about. It just like is the foldable phone that exists in the world.
Speaker 5:  I don't know about that. I see more flips. Really? These are so much cheaper.
Speaker 6:  They are a lot cheaper. So yeah, the, the Z fold for, I think is
Speaker 6:  1700 bucks. And the Z flip for is a thousand
Speaker 6:  dollars, which is like, not a lot in the fancy smartphone world, but for
Speaker 6:  the Z flip is for like a foldable phone is kind of cheap, but it's like the
Speaker 6:  same price as an iPhone. But I don't think I've ever seen a Z flip in the
Speaker 6:  wild. Do you see these?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. For Samsung, I was at the doctor's office. The
Speaker 5:  reception had a Z flip two or three unclear, which one? And I was like, oh
Speaker 5:  my God, you got a Z flip. And she was like, I hate it. Oh no, but instantly
Speaker 5:  no thought why? And she's like, well, I have TMO. Well,
Speaker 5:  there's not good service here. And I was like, well, that's not the phone.
Speaker 5:  Like, do you hate the phone? You like the phone? She's like, oh, also it
Speaker 5:  loses all my text messages. My daughter has an iPhone. She can't text me.
Speaker 5:  And like, we never really talked about the phone. We talked about the right,
Speaker 5:  the universe of feelings that networks and messaging platforms have,
Speaker 5:  which really it's like, what we always talk about. I was
Speaker 5:  like, oh, you should come on the V cast. But it was like an immediate, like
Speaker 5:  I hate this phone. Like I wish I had an iPhone on like Verizon
Speaker 6:  Fair. Yeah. I mean, somewhere, someone at Samsung is like, none of this is
Speaker 6:  our fault. We're so sorry. Yeah. Take it up with Google,
Speaker 5:  Like 1000%. Right. Like I was like, but do you like the flippy? She's like,
Speaker 5:  yeah, part's fine. But I don't have any service. And I can't text my daughter.
Speaker 5:  Like at some point that stuff is way more important than whether you
Speaker 5:  have like a sky blue, metallic folding phone, which
Speaker 5:  is like, I would be like, that's all I
Speaker 7:  Want. Isn't that? Why like the iPhone does so much better.
Speaker 5:  Right. Cause it has a proprietary messaging survey.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Like everybody's like, oh, it just works.
Speaker 5:  We'll get to that. It's
Speaker 6:  Coming up. Literally will get the
Speaker 5:  De bone Memorial RCS segment is coming on the verge past.
Speaker 5:  So those are two phones. I will say that the Z fold four is like
Speaker 5:  still ridiculously expensive, right? Yes. It's like $1,800. Yes. And it's
Speaker 5:  a very iterative improvement.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. It's like, it's, it's in sort of a weird spot where it's like now
Speaker 6:  the Z fold four, like basically is as good as Samsung's other phones,
Speaker 6:  which sounds like a small thing to say, but it's actually kind of a big deal.
Speaker 6:  Like it has, it has good specs. It has like a slightly less good camera than
Speaker 6:  like the S 22 ultra, which is its, you know, the note replacement super
Speaker 6:  high end 6.8 inch. It's a monster of a phone, but it's like
Speaker 6:  roughly as good as the rest of Samsung's phones, which has not been true
Speaker 6:  of the fold before, it used to have to make like weird sacrifices for,
Speaker 6:  you know, durability. And the camera was a lot less good and they've
Speaker 6:  like slowly but surely brought that stuff up. And now it's like,
Speaker 6:  it's funny that we're to the point where foldable phones are just like iterating
Speaker 6:  every year. But this seems to be where we are. It's like, they're like, yep.
Speaker 6:  We did it. It folds. Now it doesn't break the first time you try to open
Speaker 6:  it. Yeah. Like it used to, so that's good. But then yeah, it's just weird.
Speaker 6:  It's like before anybody even started really using these things in a mainstream
Speaker 6:  way, we're already at like a mature foldable market. It's very strange.
Speaker 7:  I mean it's just Samsung though right?
Speaker 6:  Of one. Yeah, it is. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  And that's because it's, there's still like a little crease when you open
Speaker 7:  it. Right?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. The crease doesn't really bother me. Is the
Speaker 7:  Film still there? Like if you remove the film, does it still explode?
Speaker 5:  No. You are not meant to remove the film. I know. I think they've, they
Speaker 5:  they've landed on a treatment of the film that does not suggest it is
Speaker 5:  removable. Right. Excellent. And that is the solve.
Speaker 6:  It no longer looks like a screen protector the way that it used to. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Rip, but the screen replacements are much cheaper now it's like $29.
Speaker 5:  If you have the Samsung plan, it used to really the like whatever the Samsung
Speaker 5:  center warranty is. So like they've entered into a territory
Speaker 5:  where they're to David's point. They're just normal phones. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And I think especially the flip four, which a thousand dollars it's
Speaker 5:  got flagship specs, it's got an S 22 camera in it, the right
Speaker 5:  processor, a bigger battery. It's like, oh that is kind of
Speaker 5:  like Samsung swag ship phone.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. That's the one I'd get because you can put it in your
Speaker 5:  Pocket, you can put it in your pocket. But I, the full, the fold four still
Speaker 5:  exists is like the monster that will assure the new paradigm of
Speaker 5:  computing. And I think actually all the attention belongs in the flip for
Speaker 7:  Yes.
Speaker 6:  I totally agree. I think the flip for is like what phones should be like,
Speaker 6:  I'm I'm I want my current phone to say the way that it is, but also be smaller
Speaker 6:  and not be annoying when it's sitting on a desk, I wanna be able to close
Speaker 6:  it. That makes me very happy. Yeah. Yeah. Whereas the, like I got in a bunch
Speaker 6:  of trouble cause I wrote this story yesterday about, I just don't really
Speaker 6:  think there is a point to default as a thing it's
Speaker 6:  like, you can have a big phone where you can have a slightly bigger phone.
Speaker 6:  That's also much thicker and way more expensive. Like, can I interest
Speaker 6:  you in that? Like, no, I just, I but then a bunch of people got really mad
Speaker 6:  at me cuz they were like, no, it's, it's a big screen. You don't understand
Speaker 6:  big screens are magic.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. But it's an Android tablet. Big screen.
Speaker 7:  Yes. If it was an iPad mini that you folded at half, I would
Speaker 7:  buy it in a heartbeat for less than $2,000. I would probably not
Speaker 7:  buy it actually for $1,800.
Speaker 6:  So it's kind of like, do you want, do you want an iPad mini that folds to
Speaker 6:  be the size of an iPhone? Or do you want an iPhone that folds to be the size
Speaker 6:  of an apple watch? I
Speaker 7:  Want both because they're different things.
Speaker 6:  Fair.
Speaker 5:  Wait. Okay. Walk me through the, I want an iPhone that folds into an
Speaker 5:  iPad use case.
Speaker 7:  That's what Dan does with his. So Dan Seifert.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. He's got a fold
Speaker 7:  Three. Yeah. And he just like sits there and he opens it up and then he
Speaker 7:  watches like all of halo on it. Just because his wife is like, we are
Speaker 7:  not watching that on the TV. Yep. You can watch that as you go to bed at
Speaker 7:  night and that's, that would be my use case. Like I just wanna be able to
Speaker 7:  be like having,
Speaker 6:  You know what else you can do that on is every other phone that exists,
Speaker 7:  But big,
Speaker 6:  Not really. It's the, so when you fold out the
Speaker 6:  fold for it is a, it's a 7.6 inch screen. Yeah. Which is like
Speaker 6:  bigger than your phone for sure. Yeah. But is it like
Speaker 6:  life-changing differently, big for
Speaker 7:  Your phone? I'm gonna, so I've got a bunch of purses,
Speaker 6:  Liam. My producer is nodding vigorously at here,
Speaker 6:  Liam, who I would remind you bought a Z fold and then instantly returned
Speaker 7:  Twice.
Speaker 5:  So like not life changing enough. Yeah, exactly. Like life changing as many
Speaker 5:  stages.
Speaker 7:  But, but you can put it like if you have the fold, you can fold it in half
Speaker 7:  and then you can put it in a smaller purse. Yeah. Yeah. Then you could
Speaker 7:  a regular tablet,
Speaker 5:  But the reason you'd want it to be an iPad. Yeah. Is because then you would
Speaker 5:  get the world of iPad software. Right. And instead what you get is the world
Speaker 5:  of Android tablet software.
Speaker 7:  That's why I don't have one.
Speaker 5:  Okay. Just like, okay. So then walk me through the, I have a regular
Speaker 5:  sized phone that folds into half that size
Speaker 7:  Pockets pockets. A lot of us do not have pockets that like
Speaker 7:  work. I'm wearing some pants today and they work and it's great. You guys
Speaker 7:  didn't have to hear me talk about it because I bought these pants, not yesterday,
Speaker 7:  but anytime you get a pair of pants and you can put your phone in it, it's
Speaker 7:  like a huge event. Like you text your friends and stuff. Oh yeah. And so
Speaker 7:  like having a phone that you don't have to text your friends cuz you got
Speaker 7:  new pants, game changer.
Speaker 5:  Okay. I mean I buy all of it. It just, to me, the, I
Speaker 5:  have effectively stopped using my iPad because my phone is so big.
Speaker 5:  Same. I'm like, there's not a lot that I want jump up to iPad size
Speaker 5:  on. And the last time I did it, I was like, all I'm gonna there. You know,
Speaker 5:  there's a TikTok iPad app. So I was like, all right, like I scroll through
Speaker 5:  this, I'm gonna put this on this iPad. And I was like, oh, TikTok, compresses
Speaker 5:  the video for phones. So this is an objectively worse experience.
Speaker 5:  The video looks
Speaker 7:  Horrible and I will still spend, I had to delete TikTok cuz I would just
Speaker 7:  like open my iPad mini and just be like, whoop.
Speaker 5:  Oh so I didn't try it on a mini. I tried it on like a 9.7 inch
Speaker 5:  iPad,
Speaker 7:  Even worse,
Speaker 5:  Even worse. It's like a garbage iPad we had line around
Speaker 7:  And you have to like flip it to the right side. It's terrible. I hate
Speaker 5:  It. Richard,
Speaker 6:  You have spent today talking about the two laptops that you use and
Speaker 6:  the 49 inch monitor that you sit in front of all day. So I feel like you
Speaker 6:  are a person
Speaker 5:  Who appreciates screen
Speaker 6:  Real estate.
Speaker 9:  I love, I love screen real estate. Not necessarily on my mobile device. Okay.
Speaker 9:  And I'm, I'm fine with it being small. What I would like in a foldable phone
Speaker 9:  is number one. What if it gave me iPad? Like battery life. If I didn't have
Speaker 9:  to charge it every day. Okay.
Speaker 6:  Into
Speaker 9:  That you hit dead mark full
Speaker 6:  Do put 'em into the idea
Speaker 9:  Or better yet. If it folded two different ways and it had
Speaker 9:  a keyboard and it was called the Motorola MPX and you would sell me one
Speaker 9:  right now. I would give you all of the money I have for
Speaker 5:  It or the Nokia communicator.
Speaker 9:  Yes. That, that I'm into. But what they're doing, the flip is
Speaker 9:  interesting. I like being able to close my phone and hang up a call. That
Speaker 9:  sounds good.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Also the, the flip flip, when you close it and you open the
Speaker 5:  camera, the selfie camera, cuz it's got that screen on the front back.
Speaker 5:  There's a screen next to the cameras. It has a name. Yeah. That I'm blanking
Speaker 5:  on, but there's a screen back that becomes their selfie camera. And then
Speaker 5:  you can preview on that screen. And I love the idea of a high
Speaker 5:  quality selfie camera
Speaker 9:  And the way it kind of carries it around its own stand that you can have
Speaker 9:  it mounted. You know, you can have just sitting on the desk like in L shape
Speaker 9:  sort of like, I, I like that idea. Wasn't that like, I don't know. I don't
Speaker 9:  know how good that is in practice, but the idea of it sounds good.
Speaker 7:  Wasn't that the entire thrust of the presentation from Samsung, they were
Speaker 7:  just like, you know, what's cool L shape
Speaker 5:  They're no, but this is, this is like every company that makes anything that
Speaker 5:  can fold is like tent mode.
Speaker 7:  Yes. Where was the tent mode?
Speaker 5:  Like all those like Intel two and ones for the longest sign. Like
Speaker 5:  what you want is a tent
Speaker 7:  Because you're cooking. The
Speaker 5:  Future of computing is a tent shape. We need you to
Speaker 5:  believe this and buy an Intel base too. One convert.
Speaker 9:  I bought the XPS two and one, it folded, I used it intent mode once.
Speaker 9:  Yep. It was bad. It, it overheated the battery life
Speaker 9:  wasn't as good. It was a bad idea.
Speaker 7:  Why did you use it in intent mode?
Speaker 9:  I, I was in the kitchen. You're supposed to be able to use it that way. You
Speaker 9:  should be able to have a recipe up and you can scroll through it with the
Speaker 9:  touchscreen. It's gonna be great. It wasn't great.
Speaker 5:  But now you can, what if you had a smaller phone in tent mode, huh?
Speaker 7:  No, it's El mode. It's they don't do tent mode. So it's a little El mode.
Speaker 7:  So you have to like get down there squint at. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  So it is true that Samsung is like the only mainstream provider, foldable
Speaker 5:  phones in this country. They've got the two like
Speaker 5:  carriers discount, the flip all the time. Like that's the, you
Speaker 5:  can get discounts on the fold, like, but they're mainstream products. Like
Speaker 5:  this is what they're launching. It's funny. Cuz Moto was really remember
Speaker 5:  they did that whole razor stuff with all the influencers and the thing. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And it didn't flip. And so this week at the same time, Moto
Speaker 5:  has like launched a new razor only in China.
Speaker 6:  And we missed it. This is, this is how like it launched and we didn't notice,
Speaker 5:  They didn't didn't tell us. Yeah. They were like, like
Speaker 5:  a few hours later. Like by the way we launched a new razor in
Speaker 7:  China. Does that like how many phones did they have to sell in the
Speaker 7:  United States? You just be like, no, we're not even gonna tell anybody
Speaker 6:  Six,
Speaker 5:  By the way, the new razor has a flex view mode. So you can open the screen
Speaker 5:  halfway and use it. Yes. This thing kind of just feels like it's
Speaker 5:  a flip. So it has a bigger screen on the front 2.7 inch cover
Speaker 5:  screen. The flip is that's the name of it by the way, the cover screen? Well,
Speaker 5:  the flip is a 1.9 inch because it's bigger. It has like a full
Speaker 5:  notification interface. It's got a widget on here that looks exactly like
Speaker 5:  an I iOS weather widget,
Speaker 5:  but same sort of like 50 megapixel camera with optical stabilization,
Speaker 5:  13 megapixel, ultra wide. It's like this, another flagship phone.
Speaker 5:  It just seems like, it seems like only Samsung
Speaker 5:  is like willing to make this bet and maybe not get market share because
Speaker 5:  they've got market share all the way at the low end and all the competition
Speaker 5:  here is at the low end of the market now.
Speaker 6:  Yes. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  There's just,
Speaker 6:  It's kind of depressing. There's just no upside to trying to pick the
Speaker 6:  fight anywhere else. Like it's, it's just, everybody
Speaker 6:  is set in what they have. And it's like part of the reason I think flip phones
Speaker 6:  are interesting is it feels like most people who are not that interested
Speaker 6:  in like reinventing their phone experience are not gonna go for the
Speaker 6:  phone that folds into a tablet thing. But if it's like a phone that looks
Speaker 6:  and feels like my phone, but I can close it and put it on my desk. Like that's
Speaker 6:  a thing I think people will like intuitively understand and it doesn't blow
Speaker 6:  up my life to use it. So I feel like if I was gonna bet on either one of
Speaker 6:  these to like actually make noise in the like world of phones,
Speaker 6:  kind of across all of the different price points. That's the one I would
Speaker 6:  bet on
Speaker 7:  Is a flip phone, less breakable. Like when you throw it, like if I
Speaker 7:  threw my phone at something like, ah, I'm scared and threw my phone at something,
Speaker 7:  it would shatter. But if I had a flip phone and it was closed and I threw
Speaker 7:  it,
Speaker 5:  I think in general, anything with more moving parts is like more delicate,
Speaker 7:  But the screen is now protected.
Speaker 5:  It's true. The screen is, but the hinge is now, right?
Speaker 6:  So crack land having to use all that, all those crazy new materials to get
Speaker 6:  the screen that folds, like I wouldn't try it
Speaker 5:  Is what I'm saying. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Like the that's I guess I can't get a flip phone because the urge to do that,
Speaker 5:  I'm throwing it.
Speaker 6:  You need to buy one of those, but also a Nokia 33 10 that you can just hook
Speaker 6:  across the room anytime you need to. Exactly.
Speaker 7:  It's a test. Yeah. This would be a great video.
Speaker 5:  These are basically only renders that motor release about this thing, but
Speaker 5:  yo, this phone looks great.
Speaker 7:  It's got like a real,
Speaker 5:  This is
Speaker 6:  The thing. Like I get flip phones. I want one.
Speaker 5:  I can't can't should have one.
Speaker 6:  I should
Speaker 5:  Certainly can't have this one, but I want one. Well, this is the thing like
Speaker 5:  we should talk about. This is the deed bone Memorial RCS segment. So
Speaker 5:  Google this week full on shaming blitz against apple,
Speaker 5:  like by name, campaign. It's time for apple
Speaker 5:  to fix texting for der did his first like Google executive
Speaker 5:  tweet. People were like, you work for Google now.
Speaker 5:  We love you man. But like, Google's like, it's Apple's fault,
Speaker 5:  like full on this. Isn't like a carrier thing. We haven't gotta push it.
Speaker 5:  It's like apple needs to support RCS to improve texting. Here's all the things
Speaker 5:  that are broken. It's not just screen bubbles. But then there was another
Speaker 5:  part where like also the green bubbles are hard to read. Ooh, it's
Speaker 5:  true.
Speaker 7:  It's true. But
Speaker 5:  Ooh, fundamentally, that's not the problem. My
Speaker 5:  theory has always been that foldables are because they're a different
Speaker 5:  hardware form factor. They can command interest. Like I've probably said
Speaker 5:  this on this show a hundred times, things that look different, always get
Speaker 5:  more interest than yes. Things that look the same with slightly different
Speaker 5:  software. Right? Just true. So like, it looks really different. So it commands
Speaker 5:  your attention. And then people get to the point where they're like, wait,
Speaker 5:  I can't text my daughter, wait, it doesn't work. Like my iPhone that I'm
Speaker 5:  really comfortable with. Yep. Wait, I don't they'll have airplay like whatever
Speaker 5:  bits and bobs, the ecosystem that you're aware of suddenly don't appear for
Speaker 5:  you. And you're like, ah, it's too hard to use. I'm just stick with this
Speaker 5:  iPhone. This
Speaker 6:  Is why people don't switch. Cuz it's just not worth the effort anymore. Like
Speaker 6:  the things are they're close enough, but not exactly the same. And it's just
Speaker 6:  not worth the effort to switch.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. But a hundred percent. Do you think that if I went to RCS,
Speaker 5:  like this is what I think the limit of my theory is being tested. Right?
Speaker 5:  That we've talked about iMessage lock in on the show a million times. And
Speaker 5:  we've talked about people like looking at new kinds of hardware, form factors
Speaker 5:  a million times. If you give them a new hardware form factor and apple goes
Speaker 5:  to RCS, do people switch to Android in any
Speaker 5:  meaningful way? Or is all the other stuff just pure lock in?
Speaker 7:  No, because you still need iMessage. Like RCS. Isn't gonna fix all the
Speaker 7:  problems. It'll fix some of the problems.
Speaker 5:  It'll fix group text, it'll fix picture messaging. It'll it'll fix a lot
Speaker 5:  of things.
Speaker 7:  The little when, when somebody says congratulations and you suddenly get
Speaker 7:  fireworks on your phone, it won't fix that. People will be so upset.
Speaker 5:  I mean, Google can add a, I mean, that's just like recognizing one word.
Speaker 5:  Like I feel like there's enough AI inside of Google to be like, can you detect
Speaker 5:  the word? Congratulations. Like the, the,
Speaker 6:  The tap back thing is the perfect example of that. Right? Cause it used to
Speaker 6:  be, if you were on a group, chat with anybody on Android and you would do
Speaker 6:  the like tap back thing and hit love, it would be like, you know, so and
Speaker 6:  so loved. And then just quote your message. And that was a horrible nightmare.
Speaker 6:  Fix that. Right? So there's like, that's the same kind of thing they could,
Speaker 6:  they could solve some of that stuff. But no, I cannot imagine the answer
Speaker 6:  is yes. To your question. Like RCS does not
Speaker 6:  change enough to really matter. Like I think
Speaker 6:  what, what RCS does is make Android better. It makes like
Speaker 6:  being an Android owner in an iPhone world better. It doesn't make
Speaker 6:  it doesn't change anything about being an iPhone owner, which is, I think
Speaker 6:  why apple doesn't really care and it
Speaker 6:  doesn't change enough to make a meaningful difference to people. I don't
Speaker 6:  think.
Speaker 5:  Right. Cause of all the other stuff.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. It's like I'm people stay on iPhones because they've paid for apps.
Speaker 6:  They use like platform specific things. They're they like airplay. They
Speaker 6:  like know where the browser is. Like how the notification
Speaker 6:  shade works. It's like the, the thing, the muscle memory of using a phone
Speaker 6:  is so intense.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. They love the feeling of getting an Android feature two years later
Speaker 5:  and then saying apple invented it. People love
Speaker 6:  That. Oh it's so the best
Speaker 5:  Hundred and hundred 20 yard screens. Amazing Tim cook invented
Speaker 5:  that
Speaker 6:  Games that actually work. Those are fun. Love those.
Speaker 5:  You know what? My current lock-in feature is, it's not true. Lock in. People
Speaker 5:  are gonna quibble with me though. I'm like saying lock in. It's a thing that
Speaker 5:  I'm like, oh, I can't get this up. When you copy something on an iPhone
Speaker 5:  and paste it on your Mac, like Match's, it's like, oh, oh, you should just
Speaker 5:  hold me tight. Just I'm gonna just open the garden walls and then bring
Speaker 5:  the gate down and pad lock. 'em I'm staying right here.
Speaker 6:  He looks weird about that though, is that at least in my experience works
Speaker 6:  perfectly. And it's amazing. And every other thing that apple does where
Speaker 6:  they're like try to move stuff between your device is garbage, right.
Speaker 5:  Apples moving like text.
Speaker 6:  But the thing where it's like, I have a browser tab open and, and the little
Speaker 6:  thing pops up on the Mac and it's like, would you like to open this? And
Speaker 6:  I say, sure. And it's like, how about it? Different webpage where it's
Speaker 6:  like, I, I turn my headphones on. And it's like, do you wanna connect to
Speaker 6:  all of your devices except the one that's currently ringing. Yeah. And it's
Speaker 6:  like, but then the copy and paste thing is magical.
Speaker 5:  The copy and pasting works. I will say the, what do you want to answer your
Speaker 5:  phone on intelligence? It's like rival Siri
Speaker 5:  in terms of great idea. Completely useless execution. Yes.
Speaker 5:  It's like what, what if everything in your house was written? It's like,
Speaker 5:  what if just my phone was ringing, but then you can't turn off. Cuz he had
Speaker 5:  turn off this stuff. I could talk about this all day.
Speaker 6:  We should finish Samsung though, because there, there were a couple of other
Speaker 6:  things. The now speaking of headphones, there was the, the galaxy buds, two
Speaker 6:  pro people loved the galaxy buds. They do. There were like an deeply
Speaker 6:  underrated set of headphones I think. And these are
Speaker 6:  230 bucks, which is, I think $30, more expensive
Speaker 6:  than they used to be. But by all accounts seem to be very good.
Speaker 5:  What's the Bigsby integration. Like
Speaker 7:  That question. That one person.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. John BBY likes big one for me,
Speaker 6:  Bigsby appears zero times in our story that galaxy,
Speaker 5:  I think BPE appears zero times in Samsung's presentation.
Speaker 6:  You where said yes, Samsung, studiously avoids the word Android every time.
Speaker 6:  Which I find very funny. Yeah. And I think this is true in all of these,
Speaker 6:  like apple says Siri less and less every time. And, and Samsung says
Speaker 6:  Bixby less and less every time. Yeah. And Amazon just says Alexa,
Speaker 6:  more times every, every time you turn around, are
Speaker 7:  We moving away from where they all were? Like, we have to compete and show
Speaker 7:  our stupid AI digital assistant is the best one.
Speaker 6:  I think. So
Speaker 7:  Are we finally past that point? Well
Speaker 6:  They all, now they all now treat them as like, like if you ask apple, Siri
Speaker 6:  is not like a voice assistant. It's just like a generalized intelligence.
Speaker 6:  And they're like, oh thing, this is what they say. They're like the thing,
Speaker 6:  when you pull down their notification shade and it recommends which apps
Speaker 6:  you should open, they're like, that's Siri. It's like, no, it's not. That's
Speaker 6:  my phone. Like I don't, I don't care. We can cool about what you, what it's
Speaker 6:  named. But like Siri is the thing that searches the web. When I ask
Speaker 6:  for a timer, like that's, what's serious
Speaker 9:  Remembering which app I opened the most is not artificial intelligence. That's
Speaker 9:  just account of
Speaker 6:  It's nothing.
Speaker 6:  But yeah. So, okay. So there were the buds, which I believe Chris Welch is
Speaker 6:  reviewing and I suspect we'll turn out to be very good. Cuz the galaxy buds
Speaker 6:  have been very good for a while. And then there was the galaxy watch five
Speaker 6:  and watch five pro, which are, I think
Speaker 6:  280 bucks and 450 bucks respectively. And the big thing here was more
Speaker 6:  battery life.
Speaker 6:  I actually think the galaxy watch is super fascinating because like, especially
Speaker 6:  now that they've gone back to like working with Google and doing S stuff
Speaker 6:  like the, the watch for bio account was like really good. Yeah. And people
Speaker 6:  really liked it. And it was like the first thing that was like, okay, if
Speaker 6:  you are an Android person and want something kind of like the apple watch
Speaker 6:  here is something kind of like the apple watch and the five pro just seemed
Speaker 6:  or the five and the five pro seemed to just like push that slightly forward.
Speaker 6:  Like more sensors, more health stuff. Cause everybody's in on health stuff.
Speaker 6:  The watch pro I think is enormous. It's
Speaker 5:  Enormous. And it has like a touch bezel, right?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Yeah. They both do
Speaker 7:  45 millimeters. That's like, that's a big,
Speaker 7:  chunky, yeah. Chunk. It's big way. Yeah. I used to have, I used to have like
Speaker 7:  a 42 millimeter. My dad gave me and I would wear it to soccer practice in
Speaker 7:  like sixth grade and it just took my entire wrist up. It
Speaker 7:  just looked like I was wearing a large bracelet, like a cuff bracelet. It
Speaker 7:  was great.
Speaker 6:  You said phone on your wrist basically.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. I could stop bullets with that wrist watch,
Speaker 6:  But yeah. And I think especially like this is coming and there's presumably
Speaker 6:  gonna be a new apple watch soon and the pixel watch is coming and it's like
Speaker 6:  this, this is like a cool moment where it kind of felt like everybody was
Speaker 6:  giving up on smart watches except for apple. And now it sort of feels like
Speaker 6:  there's, there's real stuff out here happening again, which is cool.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I will say that the 45 millimeter size, I'm just looking at our photos
Speaker 5:  of this on our wrist. It's like
Speaker 7:  The one on Allison's wrist.
Speaker 5:  Monstrously. Huge
Speaker 7:  Watch. You can put like multiple fingers. I think you could probably put
Speaker 7:  her whole other hand between that's just huge.
Speaker 6:  Oh, ne I have great news for you. Vong who wrote about the, the
Speaker 6:  watches rights and I quote after months of waiting Samsung galaxy watch
Speaker 6:  owners can finally use Google assistant on their devices. Don't panic, Bixby
Speaker 6:  lovers, Samsung promises all five of you. That Bixby is still available on
Speaker 6:  the watch. Five and pro. Yes. So
Speaker 5:  Look, if you
Speaker 6:  Eli and four others
Speaker 5:  Who doesn't want, it's a dog with shoes, he's just here to help you out.
Speaker 5:  Remember when that pitch was like big people just do settings for you. And
Speaker 5:  that was the, the idea that like our settings are so complicated that
Speaker 5:  an AI dog will help you go through the settings.
Speaker 5:  Bluetooth
Speaker 7:  Rich is just shaking his head over here.
Speaker 5:  Don't you have an Android phone. Do you have BBY?
Speaker 9:  I do not have BBY. I have, unfortunately never had a modern Samsung
Speaker 9:  phone. The last Samsung phone, I think was the galaxy S two epic 4g.
Speaker 9:  Oh yeah. If I'm not getting the
Speaker 5:  Epic 4g touch two.
Speaker 9:  Yes, it was, it was a wonderful phone, but no, it did not have
Speaker 9:  any AI or any dogs wearing shoes
Speaker 6:  Missing out.
Speaker 5:  I think Samsung should have just taken our lead and branded Bixby is like
Speaker 5:  helpful dog Butler and shoes and like straight
Speaker 5:  gone Clippy with it. And like, every time you push the button, like is
Speaker 5:  BBY.
Speaker 7:  That would be branding. People would talk about that.
Speaker 5:  They did. I did. I made it up and then we all talked about it.
Speaker 7:  No, but I'm thinking like Clippy, like, like the wider realm
Speaker 7:  would the
Speaker 5:  Realm, the realm, the realm, the realm of Samsung.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. People would talk about it. They'd be on TikTok all the time. BFE dog.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Be like a character would be a meme. Get on this. Samsung.
Speaker 5:  I've been telling them for years. They won't. I know that they're aware.
Speaker 5:  It's your IP inside of Samsung. They're aware that I think it's a dog with
Speaker 5:  shoes and like, just like turn, like what do you have to lose?
Speaker 5:  Stop. Three people are using this thing and you're giving up to Google assistant.
Speaker 5:  Come on, just go full cartoon dog.
Speaker 5:  People should not put me in charge of any type companies. I think that should
Speaker 5:  be very obvious.
Speaker 7:  I disagree. I want the dog.
Speaker 5:  Everyone wants the dog. It's very obvious
Speaker 6:  When you own the green bay Packers, you can make it, you
Speaker 5:  Should roll own only two shares the green bay pack Packers concern,
Speaker 9:  And then we'll know what to do with our Pinterest page.
Speaker 5:  We'll figure out our Pinterest page. All right. We should take a break
Speaker 6:  Before we do. Yeah. One thing. So we, we're gonna talk more about
Speaker 6:  Samsung and foldables and gadgets and why the internet
Speaker 6:  is mad at me about big screens on next Wednesday's show.
Speaker 6:  And if you have questions, call the verge hotline, which is 8, 6, 6 verge
Speaker 6:  one one, which is 8, 6, 6 8 3 7 4 3 1 1, but
Speaker 6:  it's just verge one, one. Don't worry about it and call us and ask us all
Speaker 6:  your Samsung and foldable and phone questions. And we'll get to a bunch of
Speaker 6:  'em next week.
Speaker 5:  Tell us your big speed stories. Yes. Call us and be like one time.
Speaker 5:  I couldn't figure out how to turn on a feature on my Samsung
Speaker 5:  phone. And I asked Bixby to do it and BBY helped. I
Speaker 5:  just want to hear one story like this.
Speaker 6:  And if you have a drawing of a dog with shoes named Bigsby.
Speaker 5:  Oh yeah, please,
Speaker 6:  Please send it. Oh yeah. Eli reckless on Twitter. We all need to,
Speaker 5:  We'll just do a whole run of them on our TikTok. It'll be great. All right.
Speaker 5:  We're gonna take a break. We can come back. Richard's gonna tell us what's
Speaker 5:  going on with Disney in the stream war we'll right back.
Speaker 3:  Hey, I'm Sam Sanders and I host a show called into it.
Speaker 3:  It is a weekly show where we obsess about the culture
Speaker 3:  that matters like revisiting the day when Beyonce
Speaker 3:  dropped her self-titled album in 2013, by
Speaker 3:  surprise.
Speaker 10:  And then we come out and the world is
Speaker 10:  totally a light in a different way because this album
Speaker 10:  has dropped
Speaker 3:  And viewing Beyonce, not just as a musician, but
Speaker 3:  as a business executive
Speaker 10:  People talk about Ford. They talk about Nike.
Speaker 10:  They talk about Coke and Pepsi, and they should talk about
Speaker 10:  Beyonce
Speaker 3:  Or will deep dive into why the internet loves
Speaker 3:  a 24 movies. Can you recall Swiss army
Speaker 3:  man played by Harry Potter? Yes.
Speaker 11:  Played by Harry Potter. And they realized that in the era of the internet,
Speaker 11:  a movie about a farting Corps sells itself
Speaker 3:  Into it from vulture new episodes, every Thursday,
Speaker 3:  subscribe, wherever you get your podcasts.
Speaker 12:  I'm Alex Heath and I'm co-hosting land of the giants. This season,
Speaker 12:  meta the company formally known as Facebook so far. We've
Speaker 12:  told the story of mark Zuckerberg's journey to reaching billions of users
Speaker 12:  from the creation of the newsfeed, to the acquisition of Instagram,
Speaker 12:  but such massive scale that comes at a price in our
Speaker 12:  upcoming episodes. We'll examine how the company has had to grapple with
Speaker 12:  the uncomfortable side of its power, from how to reckon with former
Speaker 12:  president Donald Trump.
Speaker 13:  I think mark in the end felt that if you're gonna start
Speaker 13:  saying that heads of government, can't threaten to deploy force
Speaker 13:  to restore order, that that sets a really quite a virus,
Speaker 13:  impressive
Speaker 12:  To the harms, its own technology amplifies
Speaker 14:  Borderline harmful sensational content fundamentally does
Speaker 14:  better. You know, under user engagement
Speaker 12:  Will Zuckerberg's high stakes pivot to building the metaverse work.
Speaker 12:  And if it does, what does that mean for all of us
Speaker 12:  follow land of the giants, wherever you listen to hear new episodes, every
Speaker 12:  Wednesday
Speaker 5:  We're back Richard Rich, RJ
Speaker 5:  have many Nicks, Rick dog
Speaker 5:  Disney airings this week. Good news, bad news. I was on CBC today and they
Speaker 5:  were like, stock is up, which means like good news. Yeah. I dunno why they
Speaker 5:  let me talk about stocks. It's great. But stock is
Speaker 5:  up PAC, you know, he is one of the bobs. Yeah. Oh Bob.
Speaker 5:  He looked as happy as he could, which is like a medium amount.
Speaker 5:  Happy like you got that theme park money now, man. Yeah. Yeah. So
Speaker 5:  they're doing great subscribers. They have more subscribers now in Netflix
Speaker 5:  Disney, 2 21 around the world, Netflix two 20 disclosure. The ver
Speaker 5:  made a Netflix show, which I'm the EP box media makes shows with all of
Speaker 5:  these companies. Comcast is a minority investor and fucks me whatever
Speaker 7:  Media,
Speaker 5:  If you've listened to the show, you know that it doesn't work. The money
Speaker 5:  has not dissuaded us.
Speaker 5:  Disney's a weird place. Like they're raising prices where the shopper are
Speaker 5:  in. Great. I gotta call out bluey season three, just hit Disney plus, which
Speaker 5:  means if you have a child, you are never unsubscribing, but it's a weird
Speaker 5:  moment for them.
Speaker 9:  The question of who the, of whether or not this is good news, I think depends
Speaker 9:  on whether or not you're a Disney investor or a Disney plus customer. If
Speaker 9:  you're a Disney investor, great news, they have more customers. They have
Speaker 9:  a plan to make more money. They have a plan to be profitable on streaming
Speaker 9:  by 2024. Maybe these are all the things you love to hear. If
Speaker 9:  you are a Disney customer, I have bad news. You are the reason that they
Speaker 9:  will be profitable by 2024. Cause they're raising prices on everything
Speaker 9:  they they've discovered that people will pay for. I don't know, Marvel movies
Speaker 9:  for all of the Disney kids stuff. People will love to watch the, the
Speaker 9:  properties that they have. They will pay for it. Maybe they won't pay for
Speaker 9:  Netflix if they keep raising the price, but they will keep playing for Disney
Speaker 9:  every single time. It's great news for Disney and they're taking advantage
Speaker 9:  of it.
Speaker 7:  Well, it's still cheaper than Netflix too. And like, I think
Speaker 7:  a big part of this is they care about these bundles. These bundles are really
Speaker 7:  actually good deals. Like I looked at the bundles and I was like, oh, that's
Speaker 7:  what I'm gonna do because you can get the Disney bundle with Disney
Speaker 7:  plus
Speaker 5:  Hulu. Is that with ads or without
Speaker 7:  Both of 'em without ads. Okay. ESPN plus with ads. Sure, sure.
Speaker 7:  For 20 bucks. And that basically, if who cares about ESPN
Speaker 7:  plus I'm sorry to you and my brother that's and I guess
Speaker 7:  rookies.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. You're actually podcasting with three ESPN plus
Speaker 7:  Subscribers. So, well then this is a great deal for you guys, cuz I'm over
Speaker 7:  here being like, wow, I don't care about that. That means I'm getting both
Speaker 7:  of these services. I do use for $10,
Speaker 9:  But that's the pitch is that they can tie together all of these things. They
Speaker 9:  cover everybody. Yeah. Whoever you are, they have some stuff that's and that
Speaker 9:  bundle's going to be a pretty good deal. They've really recreated the parts
Speaker 9:  of the cable bundle that people wanted at a cheaper
Speaker 7:  Price and at the same price that Netflix, premier bundle or
Speaker 7:  premier just service.
Speaker 9:  And, and if you're, if you're looking at that versus Netflix and you're looking
Speaker 9:  at what you get and you're, you're thinking I'm going to pick one, you're
Speaker 9:  probably going to pick the Disney one.
Speaker 7:  If you are one of the people who's spending $20 a month on Netflix, I am
Speaker 7:  one of them. I was gonna say same, same. But if you're one of those people,
Speaker 7:  who's like, Ooh, do I want this bundle? Or do I want Netflix? And
Speaker 7:  you chose Netflix, please. I mean, don't call me. But like, well
Speaker 5:  There's a number they can call.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Call, call that number
Speaker 5:  Six, ver one, one just hit the number there it is.
Speaker 7:  Tell us why I knowing you're doing that.
Speaker 5:  So here's what I say. The ESPN plus thing is like, it is valuable in very
Speaker 5:  short windows, right? Cause it's not really ESPN. However, the
Speaker 5:  world Excel championships were recently broadcast. This is a true story.
Speaker 5:  You can watch the money ESPN plus in football season, weird right
Speaker 5:  stuff, NFL prime time, which is like the best NFL clip
Speaker 5:  show that happens at the end of every day, before the Sunday night game,
Speaker 5:  end of every Sunday, before the Sunday night game, ESPN doesn't have the
Speaker 5:  rights to broadcast it because NBC has the rights
Speaker 5:  to all highlights on broadcast on Sundays, but they got
Speaker 5:  the rights to stream highlights. So it's on ESPN plus.
Speaker 5:  So like that alone is worth it for that one chunk of time, time. Do you,
Speaker 7:  Do you like, what about the actual games?
Speaker 5:  Right? You're what you're doing during the games on a Sunday snapping
Speaker 5:  you're in the dull roar of a football game,
Speaker 9:  Fan crying.
Speaker 6:  It's true.
Speaker 5:  And then you wake up and you, while you, I dinner,
Speaker 7:  That's not how we do it in, in Texas. Like that's like a three hour event.
Speaker 7:  If I call my dad at any point during a Cowboys game, he gets
Speaker 7:  so mad. So I do it multiple times and then like, oh, I'm sorry. I forgot
Speaker 7:  the game was still on. Yeah. I know it's at least three hours.
Speaker 5:  But like ESPN has just figured out how to, it's definitely three hours. If
Speaker 5:  you call me at any point during hackers game or Richard during lion's game,
Speaker 5:  there's a lot, there's a lot of screaming
Speaker 6:  Are awful. You can call me. It's fine.
Speaker 5:  Okay. But like they have like very cleverly found their
Speaker 5:  way through its this like highlights rights problem and added value to the
Speaker 5:  streaming product. Yeah. Even though it's only for like however many months
Speaker 5:  of the year and they're kind of doing that around the line with
Speaker 5:  sports. Right. Or they're kind of doing that down the line with sports where
Speaker 5:  it's like, they're adding value to cable subscription. Right. But
Speaker 5:  it's still like, it's only valuable. I would never pay for that. OnOne right.
Speaker 5:  If something that comes in a bundle with Hulu and that's what I'm saying,
Speaker 5:  plus this is the greatest value out of all time.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Like this is, I think it's just a really good value. So everybody's
Speaker 7:  complaining rightfully that that they've raised prices. But also they said,
Speaker 7:  when they launched the service, they were gonna be raising prices. They're
Speaker 7:  like, no, these prices won't last. And they didn't. They raised it like what
Speaker 7:  two years
Speaker 9:  Later they said almost explicitly that they were planning to lose money for
Speaker 9:  the first few years. And then they, when they have the plans to become profitable,
Speaker 9:  that they would raise prices. And that's, that's what they're doing. They
Speaker 9:  raised the price on ESPN last month, they announced that ESPN plus the price
Speaker 9:  raise there on the standalone plan. And now the bundles are getting a little
Speaker 9:  bit, a bit more expensive. They've also been talking about bringing about
Speaker 9:  how you can get full ESPN on streaming. Yeah. More openly than
Speaker 9:  ever.
Speaker 7:  So that'll
Speaker 9:  Be clearly that comes someday. Now that's probably going to come with
Speaker 9:  charging more money. But, but we're looking at it. I
Speaker 6:  Would say the, the only thing that surprised me about this was that Disney
Speaker 6:  just kind of did it all at once. I feel like the thing we've seen with the
Speaker 6:  streaming companies over the years is they all just like raised their prices,
Speaker 6:  a dollar at a time. And like, hope you don't notice. Like Netflix basically
Speaker 6:  raises its prices every three months. But Disney has experience. You're not
Speaker 6:  gonna notice
Speaker 9:  Disney knows something about trying to do this. That I think maybe Netflix
Speaker 9:  is learning like, like Disney has sold bundles. They, they have changed pricing
Speaker 9:  so many times they they've got, they have an advertising business that actually
Speaker 9:  works Netflix. Not yet. So, so they're not learning
Speaker 9:  on the fly with these things and they kind of know which buttons they can
Speaker 9:  press and how hard
Speaker 6:  That's fair. And it does seem like, like we talk about the, the, like who's
Speaker 6:  the zero on the go 90 scale.
Speaker 6:  I think it's
Speaker 7:  It's Disney. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Like Marvel alone is like,
Speaker 5:  No. Yeah. But Marvel's real shaky lately. There's no guarantee
Speaker 5:  if they don't make better movies than they've been making.
Speaker 5:  Like there's no guarantee that the next phases will be sticky.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. I mean, right. Marvel is like in a weird place, cuz it is this big
Speaker 7:  behemoth. It, it does still make a ton of money. Even though the films are
Speaker 7:  getting worse and worse, like accepted. That was a really good movie.
Speaker 7:  Go watch it if you haven't, but it's still a huge franchise for
Speaker 7:  them. And they've got star wars and they have everything Disney's ever made
Speaker 7:  and they have everything's Fox is ever made. So they've got what the
Speaker 7:  Simpsons they've got all of the princess movies. I'm so
Speaker 7:  sorry. The Disney princess movies, whatever you wanna call them.
Speaker 7:  Like they've
Speaker 6:  Got all the Pixar stuff. Yeah. Yeah. Mean the library is unbe.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. They have like, they have all, most of the IP, right? Like Warner
Speaker 7:  brothers is, is recognized that they have IP and they think it's 90 day fiance.
Speaker 7:  That's weird.
Speaker 5:  But so the difference, like that's really weird. The
Speaker 6:  90 day fiance universe
Speaker 5:  Alone, it's, it's real right
Speaker 7:  Up there with it if you're not in it.
Speaker 5:  So actually I think the difference is that HBO still
Speaker 5:  programs itself like a TV network. Right? Right. Like there's a new season
Speaker 5:  of something really high end that comes out in a regular
Speaker 7:  Case. No, doing that too. Like Disney
Speaker 5:  Plus Disney's like we farted out another star wars thing. Do you want to
Speaker 5:  live?
Speaker 6:  We
Speaker 9:  Started the show and you were talking about what is that? The beast? Yeah.
Speaker 9:  On FX, on a
Speaker 5:  Hulu, the bear, the bear, the best, the beast.
Speaker 5:  I'm the that's that's like FX on Hulu. Like that's a TV network that
Speaker 5:  went to Hulu like Disney plus the app is not quite programming.
Speaker 7:  Plus is very much programming. Like they're doing it. They, they specifically
Speaker 7:  are moving shows around. So they have like a night that you're watching Disney
Speaker 7:  plus. So you're watching your star wars and your Marvel overlapped. And you're
Speaker 7:  just tucking in for the night. They're like, that is very much part of their
Speaker 7:  plan. And I think it's pulled from the Hulu, ABC like realm. And
Speaker 7:  I think they're doing it better than HBO max.
Speaker 6:  I think I agree with that. But, but the other thing Disney has done really
Speaker 6:  well is integrate that stuff with an app that
Speaker 6:  shows you old things like yes. And this, this has always been the problem
Speaker 6:  that like Amazon has had where Amazon has this massive library of stuff that
Speaker 6:  they just absolutely refuse to show you. Yeah. And instead they're like,
Speaker 6:  would you like to watch Jack Ryan? And you're like, no. And they're like,
Speaker 6:  ah, well we don't have anything else for you. Like yeah.
Speaker 7:  The other day I finished watching something. I don't even remember what it
Speaker 7:  wasn't miss Marvel, but I finished watching something on Disney plus. And
Speaker 7:  it was like, do you wanna watch captain Marvel? And I was like, you haven't
Speaker 7:  seen it in event. Exactly.
Speaker 6:  Play.
Speaker 7:  Wow. Let's go. And like,
Speaker 6:  And then every once in a while they'll just throw in, be like, remember all
Speaker 6:  those animated movies we made 40 years ago that you left. Like you wanna
Speaker 6:  watch it? You wanna watch that? And I'm like, yeah,
Speaker 7:  I do. Yeah. And whereas Netflix, I'm like you finish watching stranger things.
Speaker 7:  Do you wanna watch anything remotely related to that? And I'm like, sure.
Speaker 7:  And they're like, okay, instead we're gonna show you another like cake wars
Speaker 7:  episode. Yes. I'm like, no, that's, you've misunderstood. You've
Speaker 7:  missed something here. And Disney's like, I don't know. They've they've got
Speaker 7:  a really strong app. They they've got all of the IP, which is like, is that
Speaker 7:  ethically morally right? Probably not. Nope. But they got it.
Speaker 7:  They got the money, they got the, the what, 50 billion
Speaker 7:  or whatever they made from, from theme parks this year. They're doing
Speaker 9:  Great. The fast pass, the lightning lane, the genie pass.
Speaker 9:  I'm sorry. Bringing in tons of money in the theme. Parks turns out that charging
Speaker 9:  people for convenience is a good business model. Yeah. And their ad supported
Speaker 9:  plan is launching in December.
Speaker 5:  So again, I was on CBC day, Bob check was being interviewed visually B. She
Speaker 5:  asked him, can you raise prices in theme parks? And he was like, yeah, we'll
Speaker 5:  see. He was basically like, here's what we do. We like, we
Speaker 5:  see how much the consumer can tolerate. And then like, you know, we push
Speaker 5:  it. I'm not, he's like, we have no plans to at this moment. But like we're
Speaker 5:  always looking and it's like, yeah, you're
Speaker 7:  Yeah. They, they figured out they can nickel and dime you and we'll all be
Speaker 7:  like, yeah. Okay. Yeah. I wanna do the, the guardians of the galaxy ride.
Speaker 5:  I disagree with you about the, the, which the $5,000. Like
Speaker 5:  no, that's the star wars one.
Speaker 7:  Oh, the big place. Yeah. And you get the, the light saver. I'm gonna buy
Speaker 7:  one very excited. Two
Speaker 5:  MacBook. That's how you measure these experiences. Do I want two MacBook
Speaker 5:  or do I want to go to a spaceship,
Speaker 7:  Mad books
Speaker 6:  Then Richard would have four laptops.
Speaker 5:  I'm gonna, I it's true. I think they have the best app. Right? They've built
Speaker 5:  on bam tech. They have the best stack all the way along. Hulu is now it's
Speaker 5:  theirs. They're programming it with more compelling stuff. I'm just pushing
Speaker 5:  back. I think Disney is so big and they're so addicted to their franchises
Speaker 5:  that they are, they're losing sight of like making good stuff.
Speaker 6:  I would, oh, star wars is dying for that exact like star wars is, is
Speaker 5:  Just like milking that thing. And then I think they're milking the MCU in
Speaker 5:  like a, but
Speaker 7:  They're doing good stuff on Hulu. Like Hulu is where they still actually
Speaker 7:  have people who know TV programming it. So that's why you got the,
Speaker 7:  the bear. That's why you're getting, what is it? Little fires. The, the
Speaker 7:  little fires everywhere. Yeah. Little fires everywhere. Like you're getting
Speaker 7:  really good stuff on Hulu. I watch it. I think probably
Speaker 7:  it an HBO max are my two most watched services. And it's because
Speaker 7:  it's got stuff like FX where they've done really, really good programming
Speaker 7:  and they're putting it almost exclusively oftentimes on Hulu. And it's just
Speaker 7:  like super watchable. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I'm sure like to Rich's point, like you're an investor, this is great. It's
Speaker 5:  all just money in Disney from a Disney, like brand perspective. Hulu app.
Speaker 5:  Not as good as even the HBO max app in some ways.
Speaker 5:  Right. It's like a very confusing situation.
Speaker 7:  Remember their linear TV built in part of the Hulu app. Yeah. Yeah. In how
Speaker 7:  they, they decided that they didn't wanna do a menu. Like everybody else
Speaker 7:  does where it looks like cable, TV. And instead they were like, no, we're
Speaker 7:  gonna like decide what you should watch on, on live TV. And you're like,
Speaker 7:  no, that's
Speaker 5:  No, they all do this. This is like cat for product designers. So like we're
Speaker 5:  doing a live TV app and they're like let's reimagine, but
Speaker 7:  They got yelled at so much that Hulu was like, sorry, we're we're working
Speaker 7:  on it. We're gonna do a really good,
Speaker 5:  No, this is the hill. They all want to climb. Like, can you, this is Steve
Speaker 5:  jobs, just gaslighting this entire industry, by saying on his
Speaker 5:  methed, he cracked the user experience for TV without any further
Speaker 5:  explanation. And now everyone thinks they have to crack the user experience
Speaker 5:  for TV. And the entire consumer base is like, we just want a grid.
Speaker 6:  It's the spreadsheet. We
Speaker 5:  Give us spreadsheet, spreadsheet and TV shows.
Speaker 7:  What if he cracked it by just being like, I changed the font.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. That's what he meant. He like made it look nicer. Have you heard of
Speaker 5:  retina screens add more pixels? Yeah. I just, I think the danger
Speaker 5:  for Disney is a real stick right now. Cuz the catalog.
Speaker 5:  But if the show is a movies are bad over time.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Run into the same problem. I
Speaker 7:  Mean, yeah, but they have so much, I don't think people think
Speaker 5:  Blue shows as Disney shows. That's what I meant by the brand thing.
Speaker 7:  Totally and Disney, at least in America
Speaker 7:  wants you to keep that separation. Right? Like they very much said, we're
Speaker 7:  not gonna put Deadpool. We're not gonna put all this like racist stuff on
Speaker 7:  Disney. Plus we're gonna keep that for Hulu. Cuz that's for adults and
Speaker 7:  Disney plus is like general, Sunday night,
Speaker 7:  magic kingdom, whatever that, that thing we all had to watch on channel eight.
Speaker 7:  Sorry, none of you're from Texas. Remember Sunday nights, there
Speaker 7:  was always like the Disney hour of content. Come on. Y'all are
Speaker 7:  old. You know this, there was like a, nothing. There was always like special.
Speaker 7:  I was
Speaker 5:  Watching that whole prime time.
Speaker 7:  There you go. But, but like they, they they're that's
Speaker 7:  Disney plus is their family friendly stuff and they
Speaker 7:  know as well as we all do, the little kids have trash taste for the most
Speaker 7:  part. So like they can pump that stuff out for a while. I think they are
Speaker 7:  gonna see diminishing returns. I think they are already like poisoning
Speaker 7:  their own franchises over and over again because they're not, they're thinking
Speaker 7:  about the money and not about the quality of the content, but
Speaker 7:  everybody else is also kind of thinking the same thing. That's true. Like
Speaker 7:  I buy that. Yeah. Warner brothers last week was even like, yeah, we, we don't
Speaker 7:  care about the money. Like we want the money. We're gonna put out stuff.
Speaker 7:  That'll make the money.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. We'll see. I okay. Let's do the good 90 sale. Yeah. So we think
Speaker 5:  HBO X after, after we complimented HBO X. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It is like
Speaker 7:  It's 90.
Speaker 5:  Well it's not yet. Yeah. It's like a preemptive 90 on the tech side.
Speaker 7:  It's a 60.
Speaker 5:  So it's like, okay. Yeah. It's halfway between 45 and 90. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. It seems right.
Speaker 5:  Oh that's so depressing. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  It's a bummer.
Speaker 6:  It's not HBO. Max's fault. Yeah. It's just, it's it's being,
Speaker 6:  this is happening to HBO. Max's
Speaker 5:  This is why merger should be legal. Yeah. Disney plus
Speaker 5:  is zero. Yeah. By the way, the go 90 scale of gym streaming services,
Speaker 5:  zero is alive 90 instead. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Hulu. I don't know Hulu's higher because I think at some point like
Speaker 7:  Hulu doesn't exist in a lot of other markets. Right. It is pretty much an
Speaker 7:  American market thing. Other markets, everything just is on Disney plus
Speaker 7:  and in the United States they're like, no, no, we must keep these two things
Speaker 7:  separate, but I could definitely see them at some point. Be like, nah, smush
Speaker 7:  'em together.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I, well Hulu has like a long history of people trying to kill Hulu.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Like at any
Speaker 7:  Moment it's immortal at the
Speaker 5:  Time. It might be the last streaming service
Speaker 7:  To go because it was one of
Speaker 5:  The first. Right. Because it's unkillable. It is like so many people have
Speaker 5:  tried to kill Hulu.
Speaker 7:  Yes.
Speaker 5:  I know. Like at any moment, some Disney executive gets a promotion and they're
Speaker 5:  like, finally
Speaker 7:  Disney tried to kill. Hu. They're like, we're gonna buy you and destroy you.
Speaker 7:  I guess we're gonna use you because otherwise everybody's gonna pirate our
Speaker 7:  stuff.
Speaker 6:  And then somebody at Hulu is just like we've signed deals to have next day
Speaker 6:  shows until 20, 68. Like what are you gonna do about it
Speaker 5:  All. So, so Richard, you're making a call that who is like a permanent zero
Speaker 5:  unkillable.
Speaker 9:  Can it, it can, it can never die.
Speaker 6:  Wow. Who is not even
Speaker 5:  It's
Speaker 9:  It's what the drown house. What, what does not live? Can, can never die.
Speaker 9:  There you go. That's who,
Speaker 7:  Okay. Alright.
Speaker 5:  Netflix
Speaker 7:  15.
Speaker 9:  They still have 220 million subscribers.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. There's still huge. I
Speaker 6:  Think we, the last time we did this, I think we landed like high single digits,
Speaker 6:  which feels about right.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. All right. Any other streaming services on the scale this week?
Speaker 7:  Parallel plus. Oh zero. You knew I was gonna say it. Wow.
Speaker 6:  Greatest
Speaker 5:  Look parallel. Plus is a zero all the way through the
Speaker 5:  release of top gun Maverick. Yeah. Right? Like, and then it will be the
Speaker 5:  most popular streaming service for a couple of weeks. Yes. And then we'll
Speaker 5:  be like 90,
Speaker 7:  I think as long as star Trek exists, par like, or as long
Speaker 7:  as people who watch star Trek exist, we're we're dying out. Apparently
Speaker 7:  a friend of mine, she, she teaches college and she's like, alright, who watches?
Speaker 7:  Star track? And it used to be all the hands would raise. And she teaches
Speaker 7:  like video game history. So I was like, these are nerds. Right? And she's
Speaker 7:  like, okay, everybody raise your hand. If you watch star Trek, all the hands
Speaker 7:  raise nowadays. She's like, raise it. And it's like one person in the back
Speaker 7:  of the room who's wearing like a star Trek shirt.
Speaker 6:  She's like, you get an instant, a plus
Speaker 7:  You pass, everybody else fails. So like it it's slowly dying, but like
Speaker 7:  as long as they're all those fans and it's like kind, it's not as big as
Speaker 7:  star wars, but it's got very active community. It's, it's
Speaker 7:  a
Speaker 6:  Zero. It's gonna be interesting to watch paramount plus bleed that to
Speaker 6:  death because in the same way that Disney plus bought star wars and was like,
Speaker 6:  we're gonna make eight star wars things a year until all of you were
Speaker 7:  Said, I'm gonna let them do it somewhere
Speaker 5:  At the paramount plus office. There's an account with a spreadsheet and
Speaker 5:  they're looking at it right now. She's freaking out. Cuz the spreadsheet
Speaker 5:  has like a, a row in it labeled data center costs.
Speaker 5:  And there's another column labeled churn
Speaker 5:  and they're modeling out how many people are gonna sign up for a seven day
Speaker 5:  free trial to stream top gun Maverick and then leave
Speaker 5:  and spike the data center costs and never paid them a dollar. And they're
Speaker 5:  just hoping they can, enough of those people forget to cancel.
Speaker 5:  And I'm telling you, she's like freaking out. Like she's like someone needs
Speaker 5:  to look at my screen right
Speaker 6:  Now. She's like our payment processing systems are gonna
Speaker 5:  Down. She just zoom in random people being like, can I share my screen? I
Speaker 5:  need to share the screen with
Speaker 7:  You. Are they doing, how is, is it gonna be 4k? Is it gonna be, do
Speaker 7:  vision?
Speaker 5:  If they do not stream top gun
Speaker 7:  Maverick 7 23
Speaker 5:  4k HTR, Amos. Like I will drive over there and be like, I'm taking
Speaker 5:  the tapes. I'm starting my own streaming service. It's a 90 all the
Speaker 5:  way, but it's gonna be glorious for a day.
Speaker 7:  Top gun.
Speaker 5:  There's no way. This
Speaker 6:  Is called Tom cruise. The streaming surface.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Tom cruise is all about Mo like he wants you to talk.
Speaker 6:  Tom would never let this happen.
Speaker 7:  He's probably it's like in his contract, if you stream it, it can only be
Speaker 7:  streamed at 4k with Doby Atmos. And if you detect somebody has,
Speaker 7:  is using headphones or watching on a mobile device, their device will
Speaker 7:  explode
Speaker 5:  And he's
Speaker 6:  Figured out how to automatically change your TV to turn off motion smoothing.
Speaker 6:  He's like Tom gets it.
Speaker 5:  There's gonna be a long prelude before top gun Maverick runs on the stream.
Speaker 5:  Oh, there probably is. He's like, I'm moving my hand right now. Does it look
Speaker 5:  too smooth? I'm gonna keep doing this for one hour. I'm
Speaker 6:  Gonna read you the manual of every TV that
Speaker 5:  Exists. He's like skip to five minutes for Samsung. Seven minutes for
Speaker 5:  LG. I'm here
Speaker 9:  With you. There will be a series of blinks in this video will adjust your
Speaker 9:  TV. Just sit back and let it happen.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. He's very serious with this in the depths of the pandemic. By the way
Speaker 5:  I looked, I looked at how much it would cost to buy one of those. Like only
Speaker 5:  in Hollywood dedicated high end streaming boxes. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Cause I was like, whatever, I'm never leaving this house again. It was like
Speaker 5:  $15,000. And I was like, whoa, I don't, I care a lot.
Speaker 5:  I don't care this much.
Speaker 7:  You could get such a nice like projector for that.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Wait, you need content.
Speaker 7:  Just plug that, that Roku
Speaker 5:  In. And then I almost fell down. The Chris wel troll of being like, I'm gonna
Speaker 5:  start buying Blueray
Speaker 7:  I do that. I do that.
Speaker 5:  Oh my God. You like your PL box in your Blueray.
Speaker 7:  I I get the Blueray. I rip them. Wow. Because that's that's
Speaker 7:  legal, right? Like I'm using it for my personal use.
Speaker 5:  Only me. I quit being a lawyer. Ain't you lawyer quick quick. No, no, no,
Speaker 5:  no.
Speaker 7:  That's probably someone I know provides me with
Speaker 7:  copies and I put 'em on my
Speaker 5:  That's me more illegal.
Speaker 6:  I meet a guy in an alley.
Speaker 5:  That's like, here's what I do. I buy pirated movies.
Speaker 5:  Now you wanna stick with, I buy the media. I own the movies and I
Speaker 5:  rip it. There we go. Which for, for, for archival
Speaker 5:  purposes, because
Speaker 9:  PC as
Speaker 6:  Everyone does. Yeah. As one does. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I think if you
Speaker 6:  Were like, David, can you rip this DVD?
Speaker 5:  I have
Speaker 6:  Literally no idea what I would do.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. What's your process for ripping a blue, red,
Speaker 7:  You know, you, you stick it in and to what
Speaker 9:  Microsoft is bringing CD ripping back to windows
Speaker 9:  11. Wait, this ripping is coming back. Yeah. They're testing it in the betas.
Speaker 9:  Now it's a whole thing. Wait, it wasn't in windows media player, but they
Speaker 9:  are beta testing it again in the, in the beta versions in windows 11
Speaker 9:  CD ripping. Are you
Speaker 6:  Supposed to just like wave the CD over your
Speaker 5:  Computer?
Speaker 9:  I don't know where you put the disc, but if you have somewhere to put it,
Speaker 9:  just
Speaker 6:  Slap it on your
Speaker 9:  Keyboard and again, like
Speaker 5:  Automatically in the future.
Speaker 9:  Sure. Oh my God. But if the, the, I don't think the feature is in the
Speaker 9:  media player that exists in windows 11. Like the retail version right now.
Speaker 9:  Right. But in the beta, but in the beta version, if you have it installed,
Speaker 9:  you have a version that will rip a CD for you. I just don't know where you're
Speaker 9:  going to get a CD drive, sick
Speaker 5:  Or a CD. Do you think this is like Nadella himself is like, I have a
Speaker 5:  number of CDs.
Speaker 6:  My blue recollection
Speaker 5:  Is there's a back for me. Okay. First of all, that's
Speaker 5:  incredible. Love that the Plex community freaking out, walk me
Speaker 5:  through your Blueray riffing process.
Speaker 7:  You can buy, buy for like $50. Now it's so cheap. You can just
Speaker 7:  get a little player. Okay. And yet you plug
Speaker 5:  It in a USBC Blueray player. Yeah,
Speaker 7:  Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Yeah, yeah. Is it USBC?
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Yeah. Well, no mine's USB mine's USB, but they got USBC
Speaker 7:  ones now too, because I had to walk my sister through buying
Speaker 5:  One. Oh, okay. Okay. Okay. Because
Speaker 7:  She's
Speaker 5:  Still because she's also a buyer
Speaker 7:  She's still listens to CDs. Okay. And I was like,
Speaker 7:  I was like, you don't need a disc player. Like she held onto her iBook for
Speaker 7:  years cuz she was like, I need a CD player. That's great. And I was like,
Speaker 7:  your
Speaker 5:  Sister's my favorite person.
Speaker 7:  No, she's the worst. But, but no. So
Speaker 7:  you, you plug in your little cheap Blueray player. Sure. You put the disc
Speaker 7:  in. You have to have, I can't remember the name of the app, but you have
Speaker 7:  to have this one cuz it's been like at least a year since I did this, you
Speaker 7:  have this one app that like removes Anem
Speaker 5:  DRM.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Any barriers
Speaker 6:  Year, would you say this app was
Speaker 5:  Most recent legal barriers
Speaker 5:  that I put there to keep you from
Speaker 9:  It? It enables media freedom.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, exactly. And then you just use hand break, like, like
Speaker 7:  you rip it and you put it into
Speaker 5:  Hand break compress it. So you're further compressing it with hand break.
Speaker 7:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  So you're accomplishing very little for all the stuff.
Speaker 7:  Because when I did uncompressed, it was great. And then I put it on my
Speaker 7:  Plex server and my Plex server was like, what are you doing?
Speaker 5:  Shield started smoking. It's
Speaker 7:  Like on fire. It was like, I'm coming to you kill you right now.
Speaker 7:  But
Speaker 5:  Like, why not just play the Blueray
Speaker 7:  Cause I have to like stand up
Speaker 9:  This. This is why I have, this is why we have streaming dozens of blueberry
Speaker 9:  discs that I have never watched. Okay. And I only see them when I move and
Speaker 9:  I have to pick them up and carry them. And I'm like, why do I have these?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. But you keep buying them.
Speaker 9:  I need the best
Speaker 5:  Quality for media freedom
Speaker 9:  For archival reasons. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  What happens if you, you lose internet,
Speaker 7:  you go somewhere without
Speaker 5:  Internet. I try point out that you described your process for this and you
Speaker 5:  are recompress the Blueray
Speaker 7:  It's not as good, but it's still better than if I watched it on
Speaker 7:  Netflix or any of the other places.
Speaker 5:  If you've
Speaker 9:  Ever tried to watch, justify it on Amazon prime you, then you know why you
Speaker 9:  would do this. The video quality on the stream is just terrible. I
Speaker 6:  Feel like you're doing a lot of work that you could just buy it like on
Speaker 6:  iTunes and download it to your computer. And you've, you've done the same
Speaker 7:  Thing. It's it's not quite as good a lot of times.
Speaker 5:  All right. Well
Speaker 7:  Change to
Speaker 5:  Cruise. If you're listening and you wanna come on the show, unless you're
Speaker 5:  Alex about fire C and why that's hurting Hollywood doors open. She
Speaker 7:  Would be on my side because I'm still getting the Blueray. Sometimes I
Speaker 7:  watch
Speaker 5:  Them. You think Tom cruise would be on the side of you should buy
Speaker 5:  $50. USBC Blueray drive.
Speaker 7:  Yes.
Speaker 5:  Remove the Dr.
Speaker 7:  I can. I can. And
Speaker 5:  Then recompress top gun Maverick.
Speaker 7:  I, I got this. Like if anyone knows Tom and I would vibe, it'd be
Speaker 5:  Fine. I'm excited for Tom to be on the show. If anyone out there knows Tom,
Speaker 5:  I'm sure he is listening. If anyone out there knows Tom, tell us what
Speaker 5:  DRM removal tool you use and then we'll let you come on podcast.
Speaker 7:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And if you'd like to come do a 30 minute PSA about how to turn off motion,
Speaker 6:  smoothing on your TV ahead of watching top gun Maverick. We're
Speaker 5:  Here for that. One of my favorite parts just about like modern life at this
Speaker 5:  moment is like, everyone is constantly using computers and every now and
Speaker 5:  again, I like to imagine Tom cruise, like confronting stage manager on
Speaker 5:  his iPad.
Speaker 5:  Like, it's just like you can't none of that works together. You know?
Speaker 5:  Like he's like, oh you gotta send an email and like, oh, he's looking
Speaker 5:  at the same weird Gmail interface as
Speaker 7:  The rest of us. You think Tom cruise sends emails.
Speaker 5:  Oh yeah. No unhinged all caps. Oh absolutely. Sentence.
Speaker 5:  Email.
Speaker 7:  Absolutely enormous. He has somebody he tells
Speaker 7:  no like, no he shouts at someone.
Speaker 6:  No I'm with he shouts at Siri is what he does. Tom cruise is a
Speaker 5:  Monster. So he use his mail app. Just play this game.
Speaker 5:  It's incredibly fun. Imagine any Hollywood celebrity you can think of? Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And be like Kim Kardashian sometimes is like these
Speaker 5:  Google search results are full of ads because everyone is having the
Speaker 5:  same experiences all the time. Like it's all the same.
Speaker 5:  I, Kanye west is like, hi, I gotta get on Instagram. It's all
Speaker 5:  videos. Now
Speaker 7:  They have assistants who do that. They have a Google assistant.
Speaker 5:  No, Kanye's like out there being like, I don't have only pants. I have read
Speaker 5:  it. Like I've heard him say those words and it's all the same.
Speaker 5:  I it's the best. We should just do an entire episode of our chest where imagine
Speaker 5:  celebrities using all right, Liam wants me to wrap this up. Cause I said
Speaker 5:  only cats. We gotta take a break. We're gonna come back. We have a, we have
Speaker 5:  a little lightning round. We'll be
Speaker 16:  Hello. This is Jesse David Fox vulture, senior editor and host of good one.
Speaker 16:  A podcast about chokes. Each episode of guest comes on to play a clip of
Speaker 16:  a joke scene or sketch of theirs and discusses. All that went into making
Speaker 16:  it. Recent guests have included bill hater, Robin, the Nick Glazer
Speaker 16:  and cat Williams. This week, we have an extra, extra special episode with
Speaker 16:  Kate McKinnon speaking at length for the first time about leaving SNL after
Speaker 16:  11 seasons and working on the sketch. He used to say goodbye with
Speaker 16:  what was it like telling Lauren?
Speaker 17:  Oh man
Speaker 17:  telling Lauren was really hard. He knew it was
Speaker 17:  coming. He was very sweet, but he is, has
Speaker 17:  been
Speaker 17:  a father figure to me and so much more and
Speaker 17:  was just really hard. Yeah. Simple human emotions.
Speaker 17:  Not wanting to say goodbye to something you love
Speaker 16:  To listen to the full interview search for a good one. Wherever you get
Speaker 16:  your podcast.
Speaker 5:  Hi, I'm Eli Patel. I'm the editor in chief of the verge. And I'm also the
Speaker 5:  host of decoder. It's a business and technology podcast where I interview
Speaker 5:  a diverse cast of C-suite executives, creators and policy makers.
Speaker 5:  I ask him how they make decisions, what their org charts look like, what
Speaker 5:  keeps him up at night and what the future for their industries hold. We just
Speaker 5:  had Hank green on the show. He's one of the biggest YouTubers around. Here's
Speaker 5:  what he said. When I asked him if he could quit YouTube.
Speaker 19:  No, both culturally and economically. I could not walk away from YouTube,
Speaker 19:  but I it's. It's a little bit like saying, would you walk away from America
Speaker 19:  for me? You know, it's like, there's, there's things I very much don't like
Speaker 19:  about it, but I, you know, I feel a little like a citizen and
Speaker 19:  that would be such a big decision to make for me culturally. But in terms
Speaker 19:  of money, no, also no monetization, like just a sense is really
Speaker 19:  quite powerful.
Speaker 5:  This conversation with Hank green was endlessly fascinating. He has so many
Speaker 5:  ideas on how creators can and should make money. So if you like that clip
Speaker 5:  go and subscribe to decoder in your podcast. Player of choice. That's decoder
Speaker 5:  hosted by me, Neil a Patel. Here we go.
Speaker 5:  All right. We're back lightning round. A lot of little news this week.
Speaker 5:  I just mentioned email. So I gotta mention this one. So politicians wanna
Speaker 5:  send you emails. You may have gotten these emails. You might have thought
Speaker 5:  to yourself, wow. These emails are all written like scams. Yeah. Turns out
Speaker 5:  Google's filters have agreed with you for many years. And
Speaker 5:  politicians emails have been filtered into your spam.
Speaker 6:  And some politicians think Google is, is perpetrating a
Speaker 6:  giant scheme to send some people to your inbox and some email and some to
Speaker 6:  spam
Speaker 7:  Shadow ban. Exactly.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. This is like a real thing that happens. So they yelled at Google enough.
Speaker 5:  And so Google concocted a plan by which politicians could
Speaker 5:  request to be exempted from Google's spam
Speaker 5:  filters. And today the federal election commission said, yep, that's fine.
Speaker 5:  You can do your plan. This is like one of the dumbest things I've ever heard.
Speaker 5:  Like what emails do I want the least any politician
Speaker 5:  asking me for money?
Speaker 7:  I still get asked by Wendy Davis for money and to vote in Texas
Speaker 7:  still. I don't want those emails. Yeah. I marked them as spam on purpose.
Speaker 5:  Now they're gonna get through and it's like the worst political pressure
Speaker 5:  campaign you can pick.
Speaker 6:  I think if politicians should be able to request not to be spam, we as
Speaker 6:  users should be able to request not to be emailed by them. Like if, if, if
Speaker 6:  Gmail can control this, that cleanly on one side, it should be able to give
Speaker 6:  us a toggle that says, no, thank you, politicians goodbye. And
Speaker 6:  just for my email,
Speaker 7:  All politicians
Speaker 5:  Push that button in a heartbeat. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  A hundred percent. The texts, like if I could do that on my phone, like,
Speaker 7:  oh, we know that this is somebody texting you to donate money
Speaker 7:  to your local.
Speaker 6:  Somehow I got on Nancy Pelosi's list as a person named Freddy, I get a
Speaker 6:  text message. Probably five times a week being like Freddy, this is urgent.
Speaker 5:  Oh,
Speaker 6:  It gives me $6.
Speaker 5:  A real clever online harassment. Gamut is people try to sign me up for like
Speaker 5:  all the things. And now they're all filtered. And so they still
Speaker 5:  try to do it. I'm like, no, no, you don't understand. This was five years
Speaker 5:  ago.
Speaker 5:  No, you don't understand. I was already signed up as Freddy for Nancy Pelosi.
Speaker 5:  This like you can't hurt me anymore.
Speaker 5:  Alright, Richard, are you at proof of stake this week? This is like a true
Speaker 5:  light. We're just bouncing around Ethereum for years has promised
Speaker 5:  a switch from proof of work, which is a lot of energy to proof of sake, which
Speaker 5:  different method of mining and validating transaction that I work supposed
Speaker 5:  to be more energy efficient. I forced Richard to listen to a
Speaker 5:  hardcore theory of engineering conference call today. What did you
Speaker 9:  Learn? I listened to an hour and a half of people talking about the blockchain
Speaker 9:  and blocks and every everything they, I don't even
Speaker 9:  know what words they were using. None of them were in the Bible.
Speaker 5:  But
Speaker 9:  I think the, I think what they ended up saying was that they they've completed
Speaker 9:  their last test merge of a network. And it mostly worked. There were,
Speaker 9:  there were a few glitches that they're still working out, but they think
Speaker 9:  they're ready to do it for real to move the full network over to this proof
Speaker 9:  of stake system, that's going to use so much less energy and they have basically
Speaker 9:  a date. Haven't they
Speaker 6:  Been saying almost exactly that for like three
Speaker 5:  Years,
Speaker 6:  Five, five years. Okay.
Speaker 5:  For
Speaker 9:  Years and years and years, but now they have a date for the, the final, final,
Speaker 9:  final, final, final merge.
Speaker 7:  Okay. When is it
Speaker 9:  The terminal date? The, the TTD is
Speaker 9:  September 15 or 16, depending on when the block get mine.
Speaker 6:  Perfect.
Speaker 5:  So maybe it'll happen. Maybe won't I think everyone knows I'm on record saying
Speaker 5:  this will never happen too complicated. Never gonna do it. If it does happen.
Speaker 5:  Here's the wild part. That is horrible news for AMD
Speaker 5:  and Nvidia. Yes. Because the requirements for mining validating
Speaker 5:  will go down. A bunch of Ethereum. Mins will flood the market with used
Speaker 5:  GPUs. The demand for GPUs will go down. But then that's also like when
Speaker 5:  ay and a video will have their new GPS coming out and everyone often big,
Speaker 5:  big decision about whether you wanna use, I mean, this a GP that's been used
Speaker 5:  for mining for years, which maybe you don't cause things been rut and red
Speaker 5:  hot for so long, but like already like the analysts
Speaker 5:  like Morgan Stanley is like bad news coming for GPU vendors for
Speaker 5:  chip makers because Ethereum is going to proof of stick
Speaker 7:  Didn't like invi
Speaker 5:  Ever do
Speaker 7:  Didn't Invidia go out of its way to be like stop using us. Did I make that
Speaker 7:  up?
Speaker 5:  They put in the flag, but yeah,
Speaker 7:  But people just ignore
Speaker 6:  That accomplished nothing.
Speaker 5:  I think it accomplished nothing.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Okay. Sorry. Invidia
Speaker 9:  Sex. Yeah. I think they got around that in like a day. Yeah. Go this
Speaker 9:  place.
Speaker 5:  They tried. So we'll see if, but I would just say like that's, to me, it's,
Speaker 5:  there's the Ethereum story, which would be cool. And then like, I'm happy
Speaker 5:  if anything uses less energy, but then like the main complaints about
Speaker 5:  NFTs of which Richard has many
Speaker 5:  grant, the, the big one is like, this is a lot of power to use
Speaker 5:  for Pokemon. We should cool it. And that, that thing
Speaker 5:  goes away, which I think is
Speaker 6:  Interesting. Yeah. I mean the, the switch to proof of sake is, has like everyone
Speaker 6:  in the crypto community is like any problem. You have anything you, you don't
Speaker 6:  like about crypto or web three proof of stake fixes it. Yeah. It's like
Speaker 6:  it. This is like the magic bullet that will make all of this work and be
Speaker 6:  viable.
Speaker 9:  Well, if it weren't an environmental nightmare, the thing that would be left
Speaker 9:  is that all of their applications are useless and do things that no one wants,
Speaker 9:  but they would get rid of this one problem.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  That's now it's environmentally friendly to have an app that no one uses
Speaker 6:  or wants. Yes. It's perfect.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Beautiful. It's we'll see. We're gonna keep tracking it. I think I'm
Speaker 5:  with Richard even money and they push it another six months.
Speaker 9:  It, it, it has always been delayed. There's no way that it doesn't get delayed.
Speaker 9:  At least once we will
Speaker 5:  Eat Crow, if it I'll, we'll have Richard back on and he can announce that
Speaker 5:  here has switched to proof of stake. And you're, you're here with me. Look
Speaker 5:  at my eyes. You have to come back on and announce it, switch
Speaker 6:  To proof. We will force him to buy an NFT on air.
Speaker 5:  I don't think we can do that. I think what we'll do is
Speaker 9:  We're starting my
Speaker 9:  I'm going to become a web three booster. Yeah. I'm going to all the conferences.
Speaker 9:  There we go. I'm one of those guys,
Speaker 5:  Bunch of apple stuff, rumors, rumors, rumors
Speaker 5:  sounds like the next iPhone might be more expensive, like
Speaker 7:  15%. But, but that number, the 15% is like
Speaker 7:  all the iPhones together. So some iPhones could be way more
Speaker 7:  expensive. Some could be like $5.
Speaker 5:  I bet they do a super expensive iPhone pro.
Speaker 7:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Like if you're looking at Samsung being like $1,800, you're like, yeah, we
Speaker 5:  could, we can charge what's
Speaker 7:  In an $1,800 iPhone.
Speaker 5:  It's pro dude.
Speaker 6:  It's huge. It's just nine inch screen, but they call it an iPhone.
Speaker 7:  It's just the iPad mini with more cameras on back.
Speaker 5:  No, they're, they'll do like a riff on the, a serious processor that like
Speaker 5:  makes it more like an M one they're like add another camera lens. Like you
Speaker 5:  can see how they could just get you to $1,800 phone.
Speaker 7:  I just I'm upset because I always try to justify why I need a pro and I
Speaker 7:  always do. And if they do that, I'll be like, I that's stupid. That's too
Speaker 7:  stupid. I can't do that. Yeah. And that's a bummer for me personally, cuz
Speaker 7:  I like to be like, yeah, it's my pro.
Speaker 5:  Well, so the rumor this year, right? Is that they're gonna do a Mac size
Speaker 5:  regular iPhone because everyone loves the big cheap screen. And so for the
Speaker 5:  longest time you ended up buying the pro cuz you just wanted the bigger screen.
Speaker 5:  So you gotta really scoot something over there to make it
Speaker 7:  Worth it. I would buy the pro because it had the smallest screen too.
Speaker 5:  I
Speaker 7:  Just, the regular pro is always smaller than the
Speaker 5:  Others. I'm just gonna put out there that revealed preferences. Say, people
Speaker 5:  say shit like that all the time. Where's Allison
Speaker 7:  Gotta
Speaker 9:  Get Allison. My wife looking
Speaker 5:  Your phone owns
Speaker 9:  Specifically
Speaker 7:  For Allison,
Speaker 9:  Slightly smaller phone.
Speaker 5:  Say that over again.
Speaker 9:  My wife, my wife owns the iPhone pro specifically for that reason, she, she
Speaker 9:  needs a phone that is slightly smaller to fit her hands and bought it.
Speaker 7:  Thank you.
Speaker 9:  Thank you. I was surprised, but it, it works better for her.
Speaker 7:  If we're not getting Allison on the line, we can get your wife on the line
Speaker 7:  to support me here.
Speaker 5:  Everyone says they want a small phone. Some people buy small phones. Most
Speaker 5:  people are three. They get into the store. And like what's the biggest cheapest
Speaker 5:  screen you have. Liam is holding up his phone. Like
Speaker 7:  He's small, it's a small phone. Right?
Speaker 6:  He will presumably return it in two weeks.
Speaker 5:  I'm just don't do it. Like he's doing the full John QSAC in the window right
Speaker 5:  now at this phone above his head. It
Speaker 7:  Was, was very romantic
Speaker 5:  AirPods cases with USBC. Not this year, but next it sounds
Speaker 5:  like
Speaker 6:  Seems perfectly logical.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. If they move the iPhone to USBC, then they have to move the AirPods.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Yeah. That seems obvious.
Speaker 6:  Even if they don't, I mean it's like apple has rapidly moved everything else
Speaker 6:  to USBC and there's no like giant accessories ecosystem
Speaker 6:  for the AirPods. So that seems like a really easy switch for them to make
Speaker 6:  like the case they're gonna make the case they've made for not searching
Speaker 6:  for lightning is like we have a big ecosystem. People have chargers. People
Speaker 6:  have stuff that they like to use. It's a total nonsense argument, but that's
Speaker 6:  the argument that you cannot make that argument about AirPods. Like I have
Speaker 6:  cool stuff. I plug my AirPods case into is like not a thing that people say.
Speaker 5:  So,
Speaker 6:  So like, I, it does seem like we are headed towards a world where the iPhone
Speaker 6:  is also on USBC, but I don't necessarily see this as like a harbinger of
Speaker 6:  that. This is just like a thing they're gonna do.
Speaker 7:  Is this related at all to the EU saying, everybody's gotta go USBC.
Speaker 6:  I assume so. I mean, that's like, that's gonna be part of where this
Speaker 6:  all has to end up. Right? Yeah.
Speaker 9:  Even if they go port less on the iPhone, which I don't think they would do,
Speaker 9:  you would still wanna move the AirPods to USBC because you would have no
Speaker 9:  reason to ship lightning cables anymore.
Speaker 6:  Exactly.
Speaker 7:  Well you would, if you kept the AirPods on it,
Speaker 6:  No they'd rather sell you really, really expensive USBC cables.
Speaker 7:  That's true. Hundred dollars.
Speaker 5:  Speaking of apple, one last thing I 16 has
Speaker 5:  added a battery percentage meter.
Speaker 7:  It's go
Speaker 5:  It's it's really weird. So you can, you can always get it. You can get it
Speaker 5:  right now in control center. Yeah. But they took it away, causes the notch
Speaker 5:  on the main screen. So now they've added back, but the thing stays full all
Speaker 5:  the time. It just has a number in it.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. So it'll say like in the, in the photo we have in our story, it
Speaker 6:  says 49, but the thing is all filled up.
Speaker 6:  It literally makes it look like you have 49 batteries.
Speaker 5:  Something's going on with apple design right now. There's deeply unsettled,
Speaker 5:  like hardware design on a real high note. Yes. Right? Like
Speaker 5:  laptops are better than ever M one chip SIM two chips. They're like apple
Speaker 5:  hardware engineering can do no wrong. And the software engineers like we're
Speaker 5:  drunk
Speaker 7:  Piles
Speaker 5:  Got piles of windows. Have you ever thought about 49 batteries on your phone?
Speaker 5:  Like I know what's going on there, but it's back, which is good.
Speaker 5:  Talking about Sonos ever so slightly bad quarter for them.
Speaker 5:  Here's the fascinating part. They delayed their next product, which Al
Speaker 5:  police would be the sub mini. That kind makes sense. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Like which Chris Welch has been leaking relentlessly yeah. For months.
Speaker 5:  But this is really interesting. So Sonos sales are all TV,
Speaker 5:  accessory sales. Yeah. And TV sales are down, which means Sonos, soundbar
Speaker 5:  sales are down. So like, there's just a lot of thinking, like maybe all the
Speaker 5:  upgrades happened already. Like all the work from home pandemic
Speaker 5:  upgrades happened and these companies are all gonna be hurting for the next
Speaker 5:  couple years because there's no more upgrade cycle for any of this stuff.
Speaker 6:  I've been thinking a lot about what Adam Messer said. I think last week
Speaker 6:  that like the assumption that all these companies made during the pandemic
Speaker 6:  was it accelerated these trends, but we're never going back to the way
Speaker 6:  that we were before. And actually what might be happening is we are currently
Speaker 6:  in the midst of going back to the way that we were
Speaker 5:  Before, or like even farther. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  A hundred percent,
Speaker 6:  Which is super interesting to me. And I feel like is like, this is the kind
Speaker 6:  of thing. I think we're gonna see a lot of places where it's like, people
Speaker 6:  either bought stuff that they're not gonna upgrade for a long time. Or
Speaker 6:  they're just gonna go back to the way that they were when they were allowed
Speaker 6:  to go outside again. And like the amount of time we spend using these things
Speaker 6:  is going to go down that we're not people don't use zoom as like a normal
Speaker 6:  life behavior. Now we use zoom because we have to, and now that we don't
Speaker 6:  have to, people are gonna stop.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. We saw that with like Netflix. That was part of their earnings. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Narrative. Is that like, yeah. Everybody subscribed and now they don't
Speaker 7:  subscribe because they can go outside and see people.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Yeah. And I feel like, I think you're right. That like the Sonos thing
Speaker 6:  is just like everybody who was gonna buy one of these just
Speaker 6:  did.
Speaker 9:  And now that you have one, like you don't have anywhere to put anymore. It's
Speaker 9:  like the Amazon problem where you buy one thing and suddenly it shows you
Speaker 9:  advertisements for only that project. Yes. Every single time you go to Amazon,
Speaker 9:  but I bought new speakers. I bought a racing wheel. I bought a keyboard
Speaker 9:  gaming headsets. Progressively better headphones. I have them
Speaker 9:  all now. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Yeah.
Speaker 9:  I, for like the next four years, I don't need to purchase any other things.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I know you and you will, you will. Well, yeah, I've done you for a
Speaker 5:  long time.
Speaker 6:  Well, I have one racing wheel when you're have two risking things.
Speaker 9:  What am I expected to carry it from upstairs to downstairs?
Speaker 5:  I think that's like actually a real hard part for SES, right? Like they're
Speaker 5:  in this big patent lawsuit with Google, Google just filed another version
Speaker 5:  of the patent lawsuit for really dumb stuff. Yeah. For how, when you have
Speaker 5:  multiple speakers in a room that you detect, which, which one's closer to
Speaker 5:  you and that's when you let at voice that Googles patent, they file SOS.
Speaker 5:  They should all just sell these lawsuits. But so Google it say Google, try
Speaker 5:  to crush them. They're not in the store, all this stuff. That's like one
Speaker 5:  big distraction. And on the flip side of it, you've got maybe all the
Speaker 5:  TV upgrades happened. And our, the biggest part of our business is selling
Speaker 5:  upgrades under TVs, which are sound bars. Yep. So now you've gotta like get
Speaker 5:  more speakers and more rooms or figure out more service revenue on the speakers.
Speaker 5:  You have Sono owners, famously persnickety about being asked for additional
Speaker 5:  money. It's I think it's just a hard place
Speaker 7:  Or make better stuff.
Speaker 6:  I think it's not even that. I think it's, they, they need to make new stuff.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Like, like Sonos thing has been to basically, they're like, we're gonna
Speaker 6:  make a sound bar. And then our next product is gonna be a cheaper sound bar.
Speaker 6:  And then our product, after that, that's gonna be more expensive soundbar.
Speaker 6:  But if everybody who's gonna have a sound bar already has a sound bar. Like
Speaker 6:  you have to go, you have to go invent a new market of things, power they're
Speaker 6:  going to do.
Speaker 9:  They're also in a situation
Speaker 5:  Where they go,
Speaker 7:  That's all
Speaker 9:  I wanna suddenly don't wanna sell TVs anymore. They wanna make money on the
Speaker 9:  services and the commissions of streaming streaming services and advertisements
Speaker 9:  and selling TVs is suddenly not the biggest part of their business.
Speaker 7:  I mean, they've been TVs have been dealing with this problem for a while.
Speaker 7:  Right? Like they had this big, everybody went out and got moved to high
Speaker 7:  Def and then nobody wanted to move to 4k because it was stupid. And so they
Speaker 7:  kept being like, what are reasons to get people to move to 4k. It was HDR.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. And then that was kind of successful, but not totally
Speaker 7:  successful. And so they they're always, they've always been looking. They,
Speaker 7:  we need a revenue stream besides just selling TVs because selling TVs
Speaker 7:  is not enough to keep the TV lights on.
Speaker 5:  You must still turn there, which is, they all tried to convince us for a
Speaker 5:  long time that 3d TV would drive an upgrade.
Speaker 7:  We don't talk about that time.
Speaker 5:  Rich. And I lived through that time
Speaker 9:  TV appreciated. It's a great way to watch NBA games
Speaker 7:  That is incorrect.
Speaker 5:  What are you talking about?
Speaker 9:  You can see the angle, like the, the three quarter angle of the court. So
Speaker 9:  when people pass and when people shoot, it's very difficult to
Speaker 5:  See Andrew ever broadcast in 3d.
Speaker 9:  I watched all of
Speaker 6:  Them. Are you the person now at
Speaker 5:  Six?
Speaker 9:  It was, it
Speaker 6:  Was a few. So now all these leagues who were like put on your
Speaker 6:  Oculus quest and you can watch it, like you're on the site. It's you? You're
Speaker 6:  the one watching. Yes.
Speaker 7:  The confidence, like just the sureness of that.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. We'll we'll hang out a virtual Allstar game next year. It'll be great.
Speaker 6:  It's gonna be sick.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I will never, this is my favorite CS story. And then we'll wrap this
Speaker 5:  up, cuz we're way over. Do you remember the CS where Sony had Taylor swift
Speaker 5:  perform? It was years ago. This and this was before Taylor swift was like
Speaker 5:  Taylor swift. It was like, yeah, it was early on. So I go
Speaker 5:  in Vegas in the convention center, I sit down and they're like Sony recording
Speaker 5:  artists, Taylor swift. And they gave us all glasses
Speaker 5:  and we were not meant to watch actual Taylor swift.
Speaker 5:  We were meant to watch 3d TVs,
Speaker 5:  broadcasting Taylors, who was right there. And they're like, look at this
Speaker 5:  incredible demonstration of Sony's end to end 3d
Speaker 5:  broadcast capabilities. And I was like, I'm gonna watch Taylor swift. Like
Speaker 5:  I she's right there.
Speaker 7:  How was it?
Speaker 5:  It was incredible. But like, they were like blowing glitter everywhere, like
Speaker 5:  the whole thing. And like, literally they were like, please watch the
Speaker 5:  TVs. And I was like, no, like,
Speaker 5:  absolutely not.
Speaker 7:  They should have had her behind like a curtain. And it slowly raised
Speaker 7:  the curtain. They didn't
Speaker 5:  Reveal the tail
Speaker 7:  Like, oh, she's right here. All along.
Speaker 5:  It was like one of the strangest periods in all consumer technology when
Speaker 5:  they were like, people are gonna buy the shit out of 3d TVs.
Speaker 6:  They told Taylor, I'm just trying to imagine the pitch where the like Taylor
Speaker 6:  swift. So you're you're Taylor swift. Right? Taylor swift,
Speaker 6:  do you wanna come perform? But we're going to actively tell everyone to not
Speaker 6:  watch while you perform.
Speaker 5:  It was utterly. This was like the she's like, this was the high point of
Speaker 5:  Sony CS. Like they never, after that, they're like, yeah, we've
Speaker 5:  got a handful of new action cameras.
Speaker 5:  Do you like PlayStations? There's one over there. Like
Speaker 7:  That short throw projector. They show you
Speaker 5:  Love the short throw projector
Speaker 7:  Is the same one. Every time they're like, oh, is this a new one? No. Wow.
Speaker 7:  But look, it's cool. Isn't it? No, it's been there for five years.
Speaker 5:  They have that. They have that special room. Yeah. It's like dolled up like
Speaker 5:  an ultra minimalist living room. And they're like this projector's only eight
Speaker 5:  inches from the wall. And it's like, I don't know who has rooms like this.
Speaker 9:  I wanna like, and it costs a hundred thousand
Speaker 5:  Dollars.
Speaker 5:  I will never forget that. It was just like one of the strangest moments.
Speaker 7:  How much do you think she got paid for
Speaker 5:  That enough? So that they had no budget for anything for years to come?
Speaker 6:  What do you think? What do you think it's like when Taylor swift sends emails,
Speaker 5:  This is what I need. She's on Tumblr. Like she
Speaker 5:  occasionally is like, why haven't they ever inter updated the Tumblr in her
Speaker 5:  face? Like she has to
Speaker 7:  Be, she definitely has like a custom signature. Like she thought about that
Speaker 6:  With a picture at the bottom. Oh yeah. And like a, like a really nice
Speaker 6:  inspirational quote.
Speaker 7:  Oh no. I guess probably the inspirational quote, quote,
Speaker 5:  Taylor, swift buying a new MacBook to check out Tumblr and being like, why
Speaker 5:  is there so much garbage in the dock? I'm never gonna use numbers. Like
Speaker 5:  everyone has to have these experiences to
Speaker 6:  Him. She's probably mad at catalyst. She's like my apps. They don't work.
Speaker 6:  Like they're supposed to,
Speaker 5:  My God. She's like these electro apps use so much.
Speaker 5:  Everyone has these experiences
Speaker 7:  Just sitting there when her Chrome tag hangs,
Speaker 5:  Liam really wants us to stop doing celebrities, using computers, like never
Speaker 5:  seen him, wants to talk about something less.
Speaker 7:  Well we're, we're, we're stealing from the episode we're gonna do all about
Speaker 7:  that's
Speaker 5:  The one full Liam, one full hour of just us
Speaker 5:  imagining celebrities doing mundane shit with their computers,
Speaker 5:  people he's he's the wrap up.
Speaker 7:  Do you think she put it intent mode at any point?
Speaker 5:  I'm sorry. He's just like Barack Obama and like, Hey Google. And Google's
Speaker 5:  like, I've set a timer for you. Like these things happen to everyone now.
Speaker 5:  All right. That's enough.
Speaker 7:  Common denominator
Speaker 5:  One. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  It's universal.
Speaker 5:  The common denominator is like shitty user experience. Like you can't escape.
Speaker 5:  It, it doesn't matter how famous you are.
Speaker 5:  All. I think we're way over. I mean, there's
Speaker 5:  other stuff. I mean, I wanna talk about this 97 inch OED from LG that
Speaker 5:  they claim can produce 5.1 audio. Sure. By vibrating the screen.
Speaker 5:  But I think we have to go see it in person to, to believe it's true.
Speaker 7:  I think we have to do a lot more than that to believe it's true. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Sure. That's like,
Speaker 5:  So I have Sony. I have a Sony screen in TV that does that thing.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. I mean, sounds good. Sound bars are always like yeah, yeah, yeah. Like
Speaker 7:  the Sono soundbar is great. It'll do 5.1. No, it's
Speaker 7:  three speakers in front of you. It'll do three speakers in front of you.
Speaker 7:  That's what it'll do. It's three. Yeah. 3.0.
Speaker 7:  Don't lie. I'm just, I mean, yeah.
Speaker 5:  I wanna believe it. I wanna leave it true. All right. We're way over at Liam
Speaker 5:  is incredibly mad at me and I've run out of celebrities that I, whose names
Speaker 5:  I can't remember. If you can think of a celebrity that uses technology, please
Speaker 5:  email Liam directly. He wants to hear about it more than anyone in the entire
Speaker 5:  world.
Speaker 7:  Maggie Smith accidentally hitting the touch bar,
Speaker 7:  right? And activating. This is
Speaker 5:  What I'm
Speaker 7:  Saying. Sorry, sorry, Liam.
Speaker 6:  You do a good impression of a celebrity using technology. Please call the
Speaker 6:  vert hotline and do that impression for us. We will play it on the show.
Speaker 5:  Dame, Judy den accidentally engaging control center. Like this is definitely
Speaker 5:  happened like 1000%. She's like
Speaker 6:  She just walks around in their flashlight on
Speaker 5:  24 7. She's like, oh my God, what are focus
Speaker 5:  notes? Like it's real.
Speaker 5:  All right. We're wrapping this up. It's all over. We've gone way over Richard.
Speaker 5:  Thanks for being here, man. He's real. He's real. He's a real person. I,
Speaker 9:  I exist. You can, you can find me on the internet at R JCC. I have a mediocre
Speaker 9:  apex legend highlights clips to
Speaker 5:  Show you. There you go. There it is. Alex she's Alex H Kranz. David is at
Speaker 5:  Pierce. I'm at reckless. That's it? That's the Vergecast rock.
Speaker 1:  And that's a rap for Vergecast this week. We'd love to hear from you. Shoot
Speaker 1:  us an email@vercasttheverge.com. The Vergecast is a
Speaker 1:  production of the verge and the box media podcast network. The show is produced
Speaker 1:  by me, Liam, James, and our senior audio director. Andrew Marino,
Speaker 1:  our editorial director is Brooke miners. That's it. We'll see you next week.