# Transcript
ID: d3a06c40-6f7b-11ed-98db-45c399a3116a
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: A very smart Vergecast Thanksgiving
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/5192457361449789846/-7285037296117601070/s93290-US-4353s-1669681228.mp3
Description: Today on the flagship podcast of connected meat thermometers:
It’s Thanksgiving week, so we’re going to do something a little different. We’re going to make Thanksgiving dinner! Jen Pattison Tuohy, The Verge’s smart home reviewer and reporter, is also an excellent cook. So she’s at home in South Carolina, and she’s going to make us a meal and tell us all about the state and future of the smart home and kitchen gadgets. This episode, fair warning, will make you very hungry. I’m sorry in advance.
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we'd love to hear from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (4 ads detected)
Speaker 2:  Welcome to the Vergecast, the flagship podcast of Connected Meat Thermometers.
Speaker 2:  I'm your friend David Pierce and I am at Trader Joe's two
Speaker 2:  days before Thanksgiving. Pray for me, honestly, all the turkeys are gone.
Speaker 2:  There's like 95,000 people in this grocery store right now and it
Speaker 2:  feels a little like what I imagine it would feel like if they
Speaker 2:  just came on and announced that the apocalypse was happening in two hours,
Speaker 2:  if that makes sense. But I need stuffing. So here we
Speaker 2:  are. Anyway, we have a great show for you coming up today. It's
Speaker 2:  Thanksgiving week, so we're gonna do something a little different than a
Speaker 2:  normal Verge cast episode. We're gonna make Thanksgiving dinner, Jen Patterson
Speaker 2:  two eight, the Verges smart home reviewer and reporter is also an excellent
Speaker 2:  cook. So she's at home in South Carolina and she's gonna make us a meal.
Speaker 2:  And tell us all about the state and future of the smart kitchen and the smart
Speaker 2:  home in general. This episode FairWarning is gonna make you
Speaker 2:  really, really hungry. So I'm sorry in advance about that all that's coming
Speaker 2:  up right after the break, but I just found the stuffing aisle and I think
Speaker 2:  I'm gonna have to fist fight somebody to get it before it's gone. So wish
Speaker 2:  me luck and please come bail me outta jail. This is a verge cast scene in
Speaker 2:  a sec.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. So we had other plans for this episode. We
Speaker 2:  recorded a bunch of stuff. We had big ideas about stories we wanna do. We'll
Speaker 2:  get to all of those later. But we ended up just wanting to spend
Speaker 2:  all of this time talking about the smart home. It's an interesting time in
Speaker 2:  the Smart Home with Matter and a bunch of new gadgets coming out that all
Speaker 2:  promised to make the smart home make a lot more sense. But also it's Thanksgiving
Speaker 2:  week and all I can think about is Thanksgiving food and stuffing
Speaker 2:  and cranberry sauce and all of these other things. So we ended up just spending
Speaker 2:  like a really long time hanging out with Jen Tuey and recording
Speaker 2:  and talking about the smart home and smart gadgets and we made a Vergecast
Speaker 2:  cooking show without even really meaning to.
Speaker 2:  So that's what this episode is now, this is the Vergecast Cooking Show. It's
Speaker 2:  Thanksgiving week. Like I said before, Jen is in her kitchen in South Carolina.
Speaker 2:  She's been cooking like for hours it seems. I think if I
Speaker 2:  remember correctly, we're like mid Turkey. That's what seems to be going
Speaker 2:  on here. So let's just dive into it. Let's see what's going
Speaker 2:  on. Hi Jen.
Speaker 4:  Hey David.
Speaker 2:  Happy Thanksgiving. Happy almost Thanksgiving.
Speaker 4:  Happy Thanksgiving to you too. It's not always my favorite
Speaker 4:  holiday cuz I spend it all in the kitchen. But I have a great
Speaker 4:  smart kitchen so I get to play with my gadgets. So that's always fun.
Speaker 2:  You do a lot of smart home reviewing for us, which means your house
Speaker 2:  is, I would say like a chaotically smart home, which is that you,
Speaker 2:  you don't get to have things that like make sense and work well together.
Speaker 2:  You just have all the things and then you get to figure it out. Is that that
Speaker 2:  fair?
Speaker 4:  That is fair, yes. I have dual competing. I don't have
Speaker 4:  dualling, I have competing voice assistants in my kitchen. I have four cuz
Speaker 4:  I actually have big be built into my fridge. I'm so sorry
Speaker 4:  Siri and Google and Alexa, they're all gonna go off now
Speaker 4:  and that is one of the downsides of being a smart home reviewer. Everyone
Speaker 4:  says to me, oh you know your house must be so smart. I'm like,
Speaker 4:  it is, but I'm always changing things up and breaking things.
Speaker 4:  So troubleshooting things. But the kitchen is the one space that I
Speaker 4:  do actually try very hard to keep, you know, operational.
Speaker 4:  Okay. Whereas you know, the lights might not go in on the bathroom every
Speaker 4:  time you walk in, but I want my kitchen to work cuz I wanna be able to feed
Speaker 4:  my family.
Speaker 2:  That's fair.
Speaker 4:  And there aren't actually that many great smart home gadgets for the
Speaker 4:  kitchen yet. I like to say the reason is probably because the
Speaker 4:  kitchen is already one of the most technologically advanced rooms in your
Speaker 4:  house, right? You've already got a robot that washes your dishes, you've
Speaker 4:  got a fridge and an oven that does its job very well,
Speaker 4:  doesn't really need an internet connection to do what it does well.
Speaker 4:  So I tend to limit my smart gadgets in the kitchen, but I do have one
Speaker 4:  or two that I really
Speaker 2:  Like. Yeah, give me a quick tour. Let's just do kind of a a, a whip
Speaker 2:  around the Jen Smart Kitchen here. The first thing I see is this enormous
Speaker 2:  screen on your fridge behind you. So let's, let's start there. What do, what
Speaker 2:  do we have here? So
Speaker 4:  This is a Samsung Smart Fridge. It's an older model. It does have
Speaker 4:  some hiccups cuz of that builtin Android screen. I did
Speaker 4:  try and order the Turkey and everything through Instacart
Speaker 4:  on the fridge and it kept crashing so I had to use my phone.
Speaker 4:  So that was a bit of a disappointment. I'd never done that before
Speaker 4:  cause normally I'd just go to the grocery store. But yeah, so the Smart Fridge,
Speaker 4:  the main thing I use it for is watching tv.
Speaker 2:  Sure.
Speaker 4:  I mean I have a TV not too far away, but you know, if my family's watching
Speaker 4:  something in the, in the living room, it has the Samsung TV plus
Speaker 4:  app in it. I get like a little screen and I can watch some tennis.
Speaker 2:  Nice.
Speaker 4:  Okay. So it's my kitchen TV primarily. The fridge
Speaker 4:  itself is great though. It's a great fridge, plenty of room. It has cameras
Speaker 4:  in it. So if I am at the grocery store and can't remember if I've got
Speaker 4:  something, you can look on the app on your phone and see what
Speaker 4:  what you've got. It also has recipes and a number of other things you
Speaker 4:  can do with it. It's a smart things hub so I can technically control
Speaker 4:  smart devices from it. But in the kitchen I like to be hands free.
Speaker 4:  So I have my voice assistants and I have to say
Speaker 4:  the Amazon is the one that I use the most in the kitchen. It
Speaker 4:  has some of the better features. I really like its timer feature.
Speaker 4:  I also like the Echo Show 10 because it
Speaker 4:  moves with you. So when if you're trying to follow a recipe
Speaker 4:  and you're walking around the kitchen, it kind of follows you. It's a bit
Speaker 4:  creepy but it's handy.
Speaker 2:  I do feel like you're like one small step away from being like, and here
Speaker 2:  is my tiny robot that follows me around my house and is my sous chef all
Speaker 2:  the like this, this is coming for you. You know this right? It
Speaker 4:  Is. Well I had the astro here for a while. He would've actually, it would've
Speaker 4:  been very helpful as a sous chef. But we we, yes. My
Speaker 4:  favorite sous chef though is the Therma mix, which many
Speaker 4:  people listening may not be familiar
Speaker 2:  With. I'm certainly not.
Speaker 4:  It's a fantastic kitchen gadget. I mentioned not a big
Speaker 4:  gadget fan in general. I like things that just do one thing good
Speaker 4:  and don't necessarily mean that I have to clean a ton of parts
Speaker 4:  afterwards or you know, read a manual to figure out how to use it.
Speaker 4:  I want something that's just gonna cook my dinner, help me cook my dinner.
Speaker 4:  The biggest thing is not have to clean up so many gadgets. You spend half
Speaker 4:  the time pulling them apart and cleaning them. This thing cleans itself,
Speaker 4:  which is like the number one thing you need to know about it. So you don't
Speaker 4:  have any wash to do afterwards. And you can also stick the whole thing in
Speaker 4:  the dishwasher.
Speaker 2:  Oh I love that.
Speaker 4:  But to explain what a Therma mix is, it's a company that's
Speaker 4:  been around for a really long time. European listeners will probably be familiar
Speaker 4:  with it. It started as a blender company and now they've come out, well
Speaker 4:  this has been around for a few years. The Therma Mix is a blender that cooks.
Speaker 4:  So that's kind of the easiest way to explain it. So I just made
Speaker 4:  before we got on air mashed potatoes in my blender or
Speaker 4:  in the Therma mix and they came out perfectly and now
Speaker 4:  I'm going to make pumpkin pie cheesecake in my blender.
Speaker 2:  Is it like a slow cooker in that you just like dump a bunch of stuff in and
Speaker 2:  like stuff happens and then it's done but it does it for like other kinds
Speaker 2:  of food?
Speaker 4:  So actually it can be a slow cooker, it can be
Speaker 4:  multiple things. It, it can be a pressure cooker, a slow cooker. It can boil
Speaker 4:  eggs. I mean it, it does hundreds of things. Wow. It's, it's pretty neat.
Speaker 4:  But what I use it for is, as I said, as like a sous chef. So
Speaker 4:  it does little jobs for me. So for example, I'm gonna make
Speaker 4:  pumpkin pie with a cookie crume crust. So
Speaker 4:  instead of getting out the rolling pin and a plastic Ziploc bag
Speaker 4:  and sticking the ground crackers in and smashing away, although that is really
Speaker 4:  fun, I can just throw the ground crackers into
Speaker 4:  the Therma mix and it has a little recipe so it has a screen,
Speaker 4:  a little Android touch screen and you follow along on the recipes on there
Speaker 4:  and it will blend the CRAs for me and then it will
Speaker 4:  melt the butter and cook them. So then I can just pour the
Speaker 4:  pie base into my pie pan and then I give it a rinse and
Speaker 4:  then I can put all the ingredients for the pie filling and it'll
Speaker 4:  mix them for me. So it's a bit like a like KitchenAid. Yeah as well.
Speaker 4:  Except for if you're cooking something like the pie base, it will cook
Speaker 4:  it for you. Cooked my mashed potatoes. I also did the stuffing in it this
Speaker 4:  morning. Cooked the onions and the sausage before they went in the Turkey.
Speaker 4:  So it's a really handy sort of extra pair of hands. Don't have to do as
Speaker 4:  much chopping, although you know I still have to do some because you can't
Speaker 4:  put like a whole potato in it it cuz it would kind of vibrate and explode.
Speaker 4:  So you do have to chop the potato up before you put it in. And as as
Speaker 4:  I mentioned, it also cleans itself. So all you have to do is put a little
Speaker 4:  bit of water soap, press clean button and it goes
Speaker 4:  and comes out clean and then you do the next stage. I know some people will
Speaker 4:  have two or three of its so it has like a blender, a stainless steel
Speaker 4:  blender, that's what heats up and you can have multiple of those so that
Speaker 4:  you can rotate and cook different things. It also steams, so I'm
Speaker 4:  gonna do the green beans at the end of the cooking process has what's
Speaker 4:  called a aroma dish that you put on the top and it heats up from
Speaker 4:  the blender and steams the food for you. So you could do fish
Speaker 4:  in there as well. And I'm gonna do green beans.
Speaker 2:  This is also like perfectly speaking my kitchen gadget language
Speaker 2:  cuz to me it's like I don't mind figuring out what temperature something
Speaker 2:  needs to be and I don't really mind just like setting a timer and checking
Speaker 2:  it. But if you can prevent me from needing to chop things or do
Speaker 2:  dishes, I'm all in like fall in. Yes.
Speaker 2:  That sounds wonderful to me.
Speaker 4:  It is though. The downside. Oh hang on the Turkey time is going off. Timer
Speaker 4:  is done. All right, time to get the Turkey out the oven before it overcooks.
Speaker 4:  There we go. Alexa, stop Turkey timer.
Speaker 4:  All right, sorry about that. Didn't mean to interrupt you David. You're right.
Speaker 4:  It is a great gadget. It does cost quite a bit though
Speaker 4:  as kitchen getts a want to do. Unfortunately it's
Speaker 4:  $1,500 for the whole sort of package and then there's
Speaker 4:  lots of add-ons that you can, that you can buy basically. I like to say it
Speaker 4:  kind of make everything but the Turkey.
Speaker 2:  How's the Turkey looking? Speaking of the
Speaker 4:  Turkey is is looking really good. Let's have a look. I'm looking at my
Speaker 4:  probes. It looks like we are right on, we have the right temperature
Speaker 4:  but the little red thing is still saying that we don't but I'm not putting
Speaker 4:  it back in there. I'm not coming out with charcoal Turkey.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I think we're good. I'm just gonna let this sit now. I think it can
Speaker 4:  sit an hour or more. So we've got our mashed potatoes, we've got our Turkey,
Speaker 4:  the green means I'm gonna do at the end my foil
Speaker 4:  and then I thought seen as we've got a little party here,
Speaker 4:  it might be a good time to make a cocktail cuz that's kind of the best part
Speaker 4:  of Thanksgiving.
Speaker 2:  I agree with
Speaker 4:  That. I mentioned I have the Echo show 10, which I will use sometime for
Speaker 4:  recipes but I'm a bit of a snob when it comes to recipes
Speaker 4:  and unfortunately the ones that come up on the echo aren't always great.
Speaker 4:  So my go-to is actually my iPad mini.
Speaker 4:  This is the best sort of kitchen companion for cooking I find.
Speaker 2:  I totally agree.
Speaker 4:  Do you do a lot of cooking David?
Speaker 2:  So I like to cook. My wife doesn't really let me cook because
Speaker 2:  she's a control freak is essentially what it is. She'll never hear this podcast
Speaker 2:  so it's okay. I can, I can say all this stuff that I want. I like to cook
Speaker 2:  and I agree, I like experimented with a million different kitchen gadgets,
Speaker 2:  tried all the different, you know, echoes with the screen and the
Speaker 2:  the nest stuff and also landed on an iPad and it's like what I do
Speaker 2:  is I watch, watch a show on the iPad with the recipe in the
Speaker 2:  slide overview and it is, it is perfect. It solves all my problems. I love
Speaker 2:  it.
Speaker 4:  Well my favorite thing about the iPad is actually the New York Times
Speaker 4:  cooking app, which is my favorite cooking app. It's very good. Some really
Speaker 4:  good recipes on there. And then my other favorite thing is
Speaker 4:  she doesn't have an app sadly but is Delia Smith who's England's
Speaker 4:  version of Martha Stewart. She's the woman that taught me how to cook and
Speaker 4:  she doesn't have an app, she's not tech like that but I can just pull up
Speaker 4:  her website. She is who I am following for my Turkey. I've always, always
Speaker 4:  gone to Delia. So yes, use the iPad. That's sort of key
Speaker 4:  for me. And then I also, I love having the Alexa because
Speaker 4:  it has, I have this fun routine set up where when I
Speaker 4:  start running water it'll start playing music for me, which I've turned off
Speaker 4:  for today cuz I didn't wanna interrupt our recording but every time I turn
Speaker 4:  the tap on it'll start the radio for me. So just, you know when you get in
Speaker 4:  the kitchen you start cooking, sometimes you forget to put music on and it's
Speaker 4:  a nice nice little feature. Speaking of water, my
Speaker 4:  absolute favorite gadget in my kitchen alongside the Therma mix is
Speaker 4:  my handsfree voice activated Moen smart faucet.
Speaker 2:  Okay that is so many words that I've never heard people use next
Speaker 2:  to faucet. Is it one of the ones you like wave in front of when your arms
Speaker 2:  are dirty? Is that the kind of stuff we're talking about? Okay,
Speaker 4:  So yes, that's the sort of main function and you don't need to connect it
Speaker 4:  to the internet for that. You can just wave your hand in front, starts the
Speaker 4:  water and then wave again and it stops and then it has a handle for hot and
Speaker 4:  cold. But if you wanna get fancy and when you know
Speaker 4:  when you're cooking, your hands are always busy or covered
Speaker 4:  in Turkey or sausage or you may be a little way away and you want it to
Speaker 4:  be hot when you get over there. So I can say and I can do the little demo
Speaker 4:  for you now if you like please Alexa, tell Moen to
Speaker 4:  dispense two cups of warm water.
Speaker 5:  First I will run the water to temperature, wait for the water
Speaker 5:  to stop when the light is solid you can wave over sensor for two
Speaker 5:  cups of water at 105 degrees.
Speaker 4:  So as a soon to be father congratulations by the way. I haven't
Speaker 4:  had a chance to to send my congratulations yet but
Speaker 4:  this is great. Okay, so now the radio is
Speaker 4:  playing because the water is running.
Speaker 4:  Okay, sorry
Speaker 2:  This is an unbelievably good idea. I'm now all in on the, every time I turn
Speaker 2:  on the water it should, I thought that was crazy until you did it and now
Speaker 2:  I'm like this is the best idea I've ever heard.
Speaker 4:  It was fun. You see it gets a little, you know, festive in the, I love it
Speaker 4:  in the kitchen. So it's now running the water two temperature
Speaker 4:  and as I say, as a soon to be father, it's great for baby bottles because
Speaker 4:  you can get the exact temperature you need
Speaker 2:  Totally
Speaker 4:  For your baby bottle. I'm beyond that stage. So right now
Speaker 4:  I'm running the water to get hot enough for
Speaker 4:  the pie. Once it shows me that it's at the right temperature,
Speaker 4:  it's flashing right now and it's getting hot. Takes a while cuz I have a
Speaker 4:  tankless hot water heater, which is very efficient but also very slow.
Speaker 4:  And then once I go over to it now I'll stop it from running
Speaker 4:  and then I wave again and it will dispense exactly two cups into my bowl
Speaker 4:  for me. So I'm gonna like that. I will do that now. Just gonna grab my bowl.
Speaker 4:  Oh it stopped and now
Speaker 4:  and I got my two cups of water, 104 degrees. I don't have
Speaker 4:  a thermometer handy that's not in a Turkey to test but it
Speaker 4:  feels warm. You
Speaker 2:  Know the thing where you walk over the faucet with like the tablespoon or
Speaker 2:  whatever and you turn on the water too hard and it just like explodes the
Speaker 2:  water all over your entire kitchen. This solves that problem. This is like
Speaker 2:  it does, this is what you're talking about. This is like an actual thing
Speaker 2:  that you do in the kitchen that this makes better and that makes me happy.
Speaker 4:  Yes it is, it's very handy. I mean to be honest the main thing I
Speaker 4:  use is the waving, but when I'm full on cooking a big dinner,
Speaker 4:  it definitely is very helpful
Speaker 2:  And it's fewer dishes. I hate washing measuring cups, I don't know why
Speaker 2:  I just hate it. And for little things like that, like I guess this one's
Speaker 2:  just water so you don't need to wash it anyway but like
Speaker 4:  But you got it wet, you have to put it on the drying rack. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  It's a whole thing.
Speaker 4:  Yeah actually that's another thing that's really fun about the Therma mix,
Speaker 4:  just to go back to it, but it's at the top of the Thema mix, it's lid
Speaker 4:  is a built in measuring cup so it's very well thought out.
Speaker 4:  But yes, so I've got my smart fort, I got my smart fridge, got
Speaker 4:  my semi smart oven, my Thema mix, my smart
Speaker 4:  voice assistance. What else? Oh I have an indoor air quality
Speaker 4:  monitor. Okay. Amazon's indoor air quality monitor and
Speaker 4:  that doesn't have a ton of use but I do
Speaker 4:  like that when I, if I've forgotten or one of my other smart
Speaker 4:  devices have failed me, it will send an alert through one of my
Speaker 4:  smart speakers if the indoor air quality is turned to pour, which often
Speaker 4:  happens when you're cooking on a gas stove, which is what I have and might
Speaker 4:  alert me that something's burning.
Speaker 2:  Well I was gonna say isn't the answer to that. This is, you know what, what
Speaker 2:  we hear in in America have smoke alarms for, I dunno if you're aware
Speaker 4:  Of this, it gets you there a little bit before the smoke alarm comes. Okay,
Speaker 2:  Fair enough. The gas thing actually makes sense that you're like, if I leave
Speaker 2:  a burner on, it'll tell me before my house explodes. Like yeah, that's fair.
Speaker 4:  It gives me a little heads up, reminds me. But yes, by the time
Speaker 4:  it, you know, things start to burn. Yeah I do have some smoke alarms
Speaker 2:  Around. I will say the thing that occurs to me as you're talking is that
Speaker 2:  you have an enormous number of screens in your kitchen and yet you just do
Speaker 2:  everything on your iPad mini. This feels very telling to me about how all
Speaker 2:  of these screens actually do their jobs.
Speaker 4:  Yes, I have a Google Nest hub max right here too, which
Speaker 4:  also has a big screen and yeah they're just not
Speaker 4:  designed well enough yet. The interface isn't good for
Speaker 4:  kitchen use, it's fine for playing a video, you know, or watching
Speaker 4:  TV or music. I mean I use, and the timers are the main thing
Speaker 4:  I use it for. The nice thing about the Nest hub timer is it
Speaker 4:  will show in like really big numbers the timer counting down
Speaker 4:  but actually the echo that I'm using that you heard just recently, it's
Speaker 4:  the echo dot with clock. So that also has the little l e d screen
Speaker 4:  that shows the time counting down. So rather than having to constantly
Speaker 4:  ask how long is left on my timer, I can just glance and have a look.
Speaker 4:  The stove also has a timer on it, but that's not as convenient cuz it's
Speaker 4:  not an eye level. But yeah, I'm looking forward to the Google Nest
Speaker 4:  tablet that's gonna be, yes, that's gonna mount to the speaker
Speaker 4:  because I feel like the tablet experience is what you really need in
Speaker 4:  the kitchen. The smart displays just aren't at that level
Speaker 4:  and this tablet built into the fridge is just a little outdated.
Speaker 4:  It's not fast enough. It's an older Android tablet. It crashes though.
Speaker 4:  I, I don't find that one is useful. So yes, the mini, the iPads the way
Speaker 4:  to go.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, no I, there are a bunch of things you've described here that I think
Speaker 2:  are like very good, very smart ideas. I continue to think smart fridges might
Speaker 2:  just be a terrible idea. Like my fridge is some unknowable
Speaker 2:  number of years old, but like it keeps my food cold and until it doesn't
Speaker 2:  keep my food cold I'm good. But like to worry about like the, the
Speaker 2:  security updates to the Android operating system on my fridge is just like
Speaker 2:  not a thing I need in my life. So I'm gonna, I'm gonna stick to my old ass
Speaker 2:  fridge and an iPad and it's gonna serve me just fine.
Speaker 4:  I mean Smart Fridge has had such great promise when they first came on the,
Speaker 4:  the scene and the idea, the thing that I really liked the concept I was looking
Speaker 4:  forward to and Samsung made some good strides here but it hasn't really
Speaker 4:  capitalized yet, is telling you when you're low on something
Speaker 4:  and automatically we ordering it for you. It does have food
Speaker 4:  recognition based in using the camera and it will tell you what products
Speaker 4:  you have in your fridge and then it can say you are running low on this,
Speaker 4:  you might want to order more, but it's so unreliable, it misses things
Speaker 4:  so they're working on it. And I think once we got to a point where a fridge
Speaker 4:  could really do that, maybe with sensors, you know to see how much weight
Speaker 4:  you had left. So your milk carton weighed, you know, 50%
Speaker 4:  less this morning than yesterday so you probably need to order milk. Those
Speaker 4:  kind of things will be useful, especially if they reorder for you automatically.
Speaker 4:  The one thing my fridge constantly wants me to do though is reorder my water
Speaker 4:  filter every morning it says your water filter
Speaker 4:  expired, would you like to reorder it? I'm like, no, I don't wanna spend
Speaker 4:  a hundred dollars on water filter, I'm just gonna use my tap. Thank you very
Speaker 4:  much.
Speaker 2:  Those are the things that make you realize like I had a Brita for a long
Speaker 2:  time and it was like they would be the thing that would like the red light
Speaker 2:  that would say, you know, you're supposed to change your filter. And it was
Speaker 2:  like, oh I'm supposed to change this thing like 10 times more often
Speaker 2:  than I actually change this thing. Which is just like once
Speaker 2:  every two years when I think about it while I'm at Target is how often I
Speaker 2:  replace it. So yeah, I just, I don't need to know all that stuff I guess.
Speaker 2:  All right, we need to take a break and when we come back we're gonna talk
Speaker 2:  about a bunch of stuff I've seen in your kitchen As we're moving around I
Speaker 2:  see a bunch of beverage things. So we're gonna talk about smart beverages
Speaker 2:  because this is a thing that is near and dear to my heart and we're gonna
Speaker 2:  check on that Turkey, we'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  All right, we're back with Jennifer Patterson Tuy. Jen, I have
Speaker 2:  two gadget questions for you and they're both about beverages.
Speaker 2:  One, have we solved coffee in the smart home? Do you have
Speaker 2:  anything? Have you tested anything? Is there anything That's good cuz that's
Speaker 2:  the one I wanna wake up to. Perfect coffee every morning. It doesn't seem
Speaker 2:  to exist yet.
Speaker 4:  Well I have here a GE cafe smart
Speaker 4:  espresso maker. This is the ATO automatic
Speaker 4:  espresso machine. So I mean it, you know coffee is
Speaker 4:  very subjective so I don't know what your perfect
Speaker 4:  cup is but my husband loves this thing because it's
Speaker 4:  one of the ones where you press a button and it dispenses an espresso for
Speaker 4:  you. So you can connect it to an app and then you can dial in your
Speaker 4:  exact like grind time bruise, strength,
Speaker 4:  how many ounces you want your espresso to be. You can do long
Speaker 4:  espressos, you could do double espressos and all you do is press this one
Speaker 4:  button, it's called my cup in the morning and then it'll just dispense that
Speaker 4:  for you. Which it's pretty handy. It's nice because I mean there's lots of
Speaker 4:  automatic espresso machines out there. They're all quite expensive. This
Speaker 4:  one is two, I wanna say it's around $700. Oof. But this one has,
Speaker 4:  because the app connection gives you that customization. So it has
Speaker 4:  its regular buttons. You've got espresso Americano and
Speaker 4:  then mic up. And the mic up is the one you can customize. And then it also
Speaker 4:  has the milk frother, which is not automatic
Speaker 4:  obviously. You just still have to stand there with your little pot.
Speaker 4:  Who
Speaker 2:  Has the time? Jen who has the time, the time for that. Thermomix should do
Speaker 2:  that for you. You should just be able to pour your coffee into the thermo
Speaker 2:  mix and it'll froth it for you.
Speaker 4:  But he drinks black coffee so it doesn't bother him. But it is been great
Speaker 4:  for eggnog lattes this so far this season.
Speaker 2:  So it sounds like the hybrid of like an espresso and an actual fancy
Speaker 2:  espresso machine.
Speaker 4:  Yes. And it's not like huge either. It's nice and
Speaker 4:  compact which oh nice is because those big fancy espresso machines like take
Speaker 4:  up half your kitchen counter.
Speaker 2:  Oh yeah, they're nuts. I have tried many times to buy one and my wife who
Speaker 2:  doesn't drink coffee is just straight up. I'm always like, that would be
Speaker 2:  a cool present for you to get me sometimes. And she's just like absolutely
Speaker 2:  not. Like I have to look at that thing all day and never use it. Absolutely
Speaker 2:  not.
Speaker 4:  Oh this one's quite pretty actually it's white with rose gold accents
Speaker 4:  so she might like it.
Speaker 2:  All right. Okay so then the other one is another beverage thing
Speaker 2:  that I'm very curious about which is like a, I want something that is like
Speaker 2:  better and more automatic than a soda stream for like making
Speaker 2:  my own fizzy stuff. I've like gone down the road of like
Speaker 2:  should I drill a faucet into my, like I
Speaker 2:  drink an like an inappropriate amount of and I'm like these,
Speaker 2:  I just want a tap in my house where I can just make seltzer. Does this exist?
Speaker 2:  Do you have the answer for me?
Speaker 4:  I do, I do. I'm excited to do this is something you wanted cuz it's not something
Speaker 4:  I'd ever really considered but
Speaker 2:  This is my dream. Like literally like a a better than soda stream, semi
Speaker 2:  smartt way to just make sparkling water all day is like there's a
Speaker 2:  terrifying amount of money and effort that I would spend to do this.
Speaker 4:  $130
Speaker 2:  Sold literally. Yes. Done. Tell me the website. I'm there.
Speaker 4:  So have you used soda streams? Cause I've never used a soda stream. Like
Speaker 4:  I never really got the thing, it was so big in my childhood. But the big
Speaker 4:  selling point of this one, it's called a, it's called the Sparkle and it's
Speaker 4:  also I believe German. Okay. Is you don't need the carbonator, you
Speaker 4:  don't need the like canister I guess is what you need to use in a soda stream.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Okay. And the problem was just to tell you why Soda Stream sucks, there was
Speaker 2:  a whole big controversy about Soda Stream that I never really understood
Speaker 2:  so I didn't worry about that. But the real problem was you have to go like
Speaker 2:  take your canister to get it replaced at like Target or a handful of places
Speaker 2:  and they're always out and nobody ever has any stock so you just have to
Speaker 2:  like go to Target every day and be like, do you new soda streams? And they
Speaker 2:  say no and then you leave and it's like it's a nightmare. And so I
Speaker 2:  eventually just gave up and this is why I'm like, I want a thing that lasts
Speaker 2:  longer at my home that would solve this problem for me.
Speaker 4:  Well so this machine is, I said it's called the Sparkle but it
Speaker 4:  has a little umla thing on the E cuz it's German and it uses,
Speaker 4:  it uses sas.
Speaker 2:  Oh
Speaker 4:  Carbonator sas. So I mean not so environmentally friendly
Speaker 4:  cuz there's lots of little pieces of plastic but as opposed to these big
Speaker 4:  carbonated pressure canisters perhaps I,
Speaker 4:  I'd have to do the the green work there. But so there's two sass
Speaker 4:  that come wrapped together and the sparkle came with a ton of them,
Speaker 4:  like a big bag of them. So you use one every time you have a drink.
Speaker 4:  Oh you just snip the top off and you pour it into a little canister at the
Speaker 4:  back and then it's a very kind of space aging machine. I can actually, actually
Speaker 4:  I will do one right now if you like do it and we can hear it. You can make
Speaker 4:  anything, you could just do yourself. So water if you wanted or you could
Speaker 4:  do like a mimosa.
Speaker 2:  Oh yeah, you were gonna make us a cocktail
Speaker 4:  For today. I was gonna make us a Thanksgiving themed
Speaker 4:  pineapple and sage cocktail. How does that sound? Sold?
Speaker 2:  I
Speaker 4:  Love this. Okay so it's quite the
Speaker 4:  machine, it has this bottle that you fill up with your
Speaker 4:  desired ingredients and the kind of a selling point here is that you can
Speaker 4:  use anything that's in your home like a fresh juice, you can put sage in
Speaker 4:  it, like fresh sage. You could also, I did one with some rosemary spriggs
Speaker 4:  from my garden. It's like an infuse. So as well as doing
Speaker 4:  the carbonating also kind of infuses your water with flavor.
Speaker 4:  So you can put cucumber or lemon, anything you like. And
Speaker 4:  I believe all I need to put in this one for my pineapple surprise
Speaker 4:  is pieces of pineapple which I've got here. So I'm gonna put in
Speaker 4:  a few chunks and then some sage which I
Speaker 4:  also have cuz I had a little leftover from stuffing my Turkey.
Speaker 4:  So we're gonna pop in pineapple chunks, little
Speaker 4:  bit of sage and some water and it
Speaker 4:  says vodka, I'm not a big vodka fan so we're going to put some
Speaker 4:  gin in instead if that
Speaker 2:  I support this, yeah
Speaker 4:  We'll put some pineapple juice
Speaker 4:  and then you just fill it up with water depending on how,
Speaker 4:  how big a drink you like. So one bottle here would make
Speaker 4:  probably three adult drinks and then I'm using the, the
Speaker 4:  smart fridge cuz it the colder the water is the better for
Speaker 4:  the sparkle for some reason I think it's the way the chemicals
Speaker 4:  or are they chemicals? Okay so it uses sodium
Speaker 4:  by carbonate and granulated citric acid. So
Speaker 4:  once you've got your ingredients together and you find the
Speaker 4:  lid pro tip, you have to make sure this thing is on
Speaker 4:  really tight because I sparkled my kitchen floor yesterday.
Speaker 4:  Oh no. Trying to make a apples fizz And I was like, oh that's making
Speaker 4:  a loud noise. And I went over and there was, it was everywhere. That
Speaker 4:  was not fun. But then I called the robot mop over to clean it. So
Speaker 2:  Problem solve.
Speaker 4:  Okay so popping the machine in, there's a little
Speaker 4:  slot at the back here that you lift up and you put your
Speaker 4:  powders in both at the same time. I guess if you mix 'em together, they
Speaker 4:  do something. I'm not, I was never very big at science. So,
Speaker 4:  and then I'm gonna push this big handle down, it'll make a big
Speaker 4:  thud
Speaker 4:  and then can you hear that making its little sparkle noise. And then I've
Speaker 4:  got one through five here. This is the level of carbonation that you can
Speaker 4:  choose. So if you want it super fizzy, you choose five and we'll probably
Speaker 4:  go for four here and then you press the sparkle
Speaker 4:  button and then here it goes
Speaker 4:  and it, it takes a couple minutes but yeah, it'll come out with
Speaker 4:  carbonated water. As I said, I did a mimosa the other day, it was pomegranate
Speaker 4:  and orange juice with white wine.
Speaker 2:  You just found my Christmas present for myself this year. It's very exciting.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I, I was, I'm quite impressed. I dunno how many of those saches, I
Speaker 4:  mean if you drink two or three bottles a day of of sparkling water, you'd
Speaker 4:  be getting through some saches but you'd have to kind weigh that with the
Speaker 4:  Soda stream debacle
Speaker 2:  Or in my case just the number of cans I crush and throw into
Speaker 2:  the recycling, which is bad. Oh
Speaker 4:  There you go. Yeah. This much better. Much better for the environment than
Speaker 4:  that. Yes,
Speaker 2:  I think so. Alright, so let's talk through a couple of of Thanksgiving things
Speaker 2:  just to, just to get a a feel for how this works. So like let's,
Speaker 2:  let's do Turkey first we're at like the end of the Turkey process. You've
Speaker 2:  successfully turkeyed congratulations. But like you,
Speaker 2:  you come home with a, with a frozen Turkey, you throw it in the
Speaker 2:  smart fridge then what? Walk me through the process.
Speaker 4:  Okay, so according to Delia who is my queen of the kitchen, you
Speaker 4:  wanna get your Turkey out the night before because you want the Turkey
Speaker 4:  to be at sort of room temperature or below before it goes
Speaker 4:  in the oven because that helps it cook more evenly because it's so hard to
Speaker 4:  get the balance right between crisping the Turkey and making sure it's cooked
Speaker 4:  nicely inside. So yeah, bring it up. Oh sparkle has stopped
Speaker 4:  sparkling.
Speaker 2:  We are sparkled.
Speaker 4:  We are sparkled. Whoa. It's like a spaceship taking
Speaker 4:  off.
Speaker 2:  Yeah that was quite the noise. That's a sparkly, sparkly sounded thing right
Speaker 4:  There and it might be a little early for gin but yeah here's my,
Speaker 4:  there we go. It's steaming. It's like a witches brew.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Wow. I guess I should have had the cup ready to go
Speaker 4:  so yeah. Oh that's got some, that's got some kick. The nice thing about this
Speaker 4:  machine is you could like leave it out on your counter when your guests arrive
Speaker 4:  and they could each make themselves their own their own Thanksgiving cocktail.
Speaker 2:  That is nice. That's a good looking drink. Cheer well done. Cheers.
Speaker 2:  Next year I just want this on record. I'm coming to your house and we're
Speaker 2:  doing this, we're doing this in person next year. Oh
Speaker 4:  That's good.
Speaker 4:  Okay. Sorry Turkey out the night before and then in
Speaker 4:  the morning and I did this this morning which was kind of cheeky but it was
Speaker 4:  kind of early. You do have to get the Turkey in the oven kind of before dawn
Speaker 4:  if you're going to eat around lunchtime. So I was able to whip out the phone
Speaker 4:  and open the the Home connect app which is the Thermador app.
Speaker 4:  Thermador is owned by Bosch and that's Bosch's main
Speaker 4:  smart home app which actually works with quite a few different manufacturers
Speaker 4:  and it works with Alexa and Google so you've got voice control.
Speaker 4:  But yeah, so I whipped out the app and I was able to set the temperature
Speaker 4:  that I wanted the oven app. Can you say that again, sorry.
Speaker 4:  Alexa is talking to me from my fridge
Speaker 4:  and showing me a polar bear for some reason. Okay. So then I
Speaker 4:  was able to set the oven from the comfort of my bed and didn't need to get
Speaker 4:  outta bed for an extra 45 minutes while the oven heated up and then
Speaker 4:  used the Therma mix to make the stuffing. So we did did
Speaker 4:  onions, sage, some other herbs, popped
Speaker 4:  it in the Therma mix, gave it a little whizz for about three or four seconds
Speaker 4:  and then it cooked for about 10 minutes. So it kind of helps with the
Speaker 4:  flavors. Put a little bit of butter in there too, then mixed that in with
Speaker 4:  some sausage and some breadcrumbs. Stuffed it in the Turkey, popped
Speaker 4:  all the probes in the three probes I had
Speaker 4:  for the Turkey today, including, well the four probes and then
Speaker 4:  went in the oven at 400 degrees for 40 minutes. That's my
Speaker 4:  favorite trick because you wanna blast it with heat to start with and
Speaker 4:  then cook, I think it's like 12 to 15 minutes
Speaker 4:  per pound so depending on how big your Turkey is and then it'll cook
Speaker 4:  like that for the rest of the cooking time. And that's kind of the
Speaker 4:  extent of the smart part for me because then from that point I just keep
Speaker 4:  an eye on the probe temperature, have an alert on my phone that I can check
Speaker 4:  if I'm not in the kitchen. And then the nice thing about the Weber or
Speaker 4:  Weber, I'm not sure how they pronounce it, grilling hub is
Speaker 4:  that it shows it in nice big numbers on the display which is
Speaker 4:  outside the oven. Got it. So you can just keep an eye on that. And then
Speaker 4:  basing key part of Turkey making, once you get through the
Speaker 4:  main cooking part, then every sort of 10 minutes for the last
Speaker 4:  hour you wanna base now it's gonna sit for
Speaker 4:  about, I think they recommend sort of 60 minutes cuz you want all the juices
Speaker 4:  to sort of reabsorb so that you have nice juicy Turkey
Speaker 4:  breast. And so I will transfer the Turkey out of the
Speaker 4:  roasting pan and use the pan to make
Speaker 4:  some gravy.
Speaker 2:  I have two thoughts about this. One is that it feels very much like we're
Speaker 2:  like one Jetson style robot arm away from
Speaker 2:  this being just like completely all I want is the thing that just like
Speaker 2:  opens your fridge or like your, your Samsung fridge should like
Speaker 2:  catapult the Turkey out of the fridge and into the oven.
Speaker 4:  Would you really want it to do that
Speaker 2:  Then? Yes, if I'm being honest, yes. I really, really would.
Speaker 2:  I dunno if this is a good idea but I do want that to be a thing that I can
Speaker 2:  do very badly. And then the other part is I'm trying to decide like there's
Speaker 2:  still a bunch of like steps in the process. It's definitely fewer
Speaker 2:  and part of me is like is the future for the smart oven that you just like
Speaker 2:  hit a button that says Turkey and then hours later it does all the
Speaker 2:  temperature, it does all the cooking, it does the waiting for 60 minutes
Speaker 2:  for you. It has like a tin foil dispenser at the top that it puts down at
Speaker 2:  the right time and then it's just like Turkey accomplished and you like go
Speaker 2:  and take it out and eat it. And that's like, I feel like where a lot of these
Speaker 2:  companies wanna go but it kind of comes back to the same like I still sort
Speaker 2:  of want to do the cooking here. I don't know like is that, does it feel like
Speaker 2:  the right balance for you of like it doing stuff for you versus kind of making
Speaker 2:  you do some of the steps? Yeah
Speaker 4:  And you know it depends on your level of comfort in the kitchen too.
Speaker 4:  I like to cook, my grandmother was a a cook, that was
Speaker 4:  her job, not a chef. She was a cook, a good old English cook and I loved
Speaker 4:  cooking with her in the kitchen. I like having my daughter help me cook in
Speaker 4:  the kitchen. My son son just baked me brownies last night so I'm passing
Speaker 4:  on the, on the gene. So you know, cooking for me is
Speaker 4:  a sort of experience that I enjoy. It's the way I kind of wind down
Speaker 4:  as well. So I really love it and I show my love to my family through food.
Speaker 4:  So I love to present them with a lovely dish even
Speaker 4:  though it's just the four of us for Thanksgiving this year, my husband and
Speaker 4:  my two children and they don't eat Turkey. So what I am eating a lot of
Speaker 4:  leftovers. So for me this level right
Speaker 4:  now is a good level because it's helping me but
Speaker 4:  it's not overbearing. It's not getting in the way which like a robot arm
Speaker 4:  I feel like might feel a little overbearing. I did see at
Speaker 4:  ces I think last year and the year before, you know they had the kitchen
Speaker 4:  arms that Samsung was demoing that will kind of come
Speaker 4:  down from your hood and chop things and I could imagine that could
Speaker 4:  in theory lift a Turkey up and put it in the oven for you. Totally. But
Speaker 4:  GE has, last year they released a Turkey
Speaker 4:  mode which does what you were just describing. So if you have one of their
Speaker 4:  ovens, they're connected smart ovens, they have a number of different modes
Speaker 4:  where you just press a button, say cooking a pot roast or you
Speaker 4:  are cooking a Turkey or some other sort of
Speaker 4:  dish that needs varying temperatures and has different sort of
Speaker 4:  levels as you go through the process of cooking. And the Turkey
Speaker 4:  mode just which GE showed me a demo, they had
Speaker 4:  their Turkey with lots of probes and they had you know, done all the calculations
Speaker 4:  to get the exact temperatures based on the size of your Turkey
Speaker 4:  and the exact cooking process. And all you had to do was press a button
Speaker 4:  and it comes out perfectly done at the end and when it's finished
Speaker 4:  it, the oven goes gobble gobble. So you know, just
Speaker 4:  for that extra little piece of flare, I don't want
Speaker 4:  my Turkey to gobble cuz that's kind of a bit disturbing actually.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, that's true.
Speaker 4:  It's well past that point.
Speaker 2:  It should gobble at the beginning and then at the end it should just be like
Speaker 2:  bleak silence. It's just like don't this is, this is
Speaker 2:  just like Darth Vader music at the end. But
Speaker 4:  Yeah for people who aren't comfortable in the kitchen, I think that's a great
Speaker 4:  feature. You know, you just go by Turkey, stick in the oven, press a button
Speaker 4:  and outcomes a great Turkey. I am not saying that that is what
Speaker 4:  happens. I've never done it myself. If anyone out there has ever done that,
Speaker 4:  I would love to know how good the Turkey mode is. My thermador doesn't do
Speaker 4:  that. My Thermador is much more lets me be in control. Yeah. Which
Speaker 4:  is how I want it in the kitchen to be fair. Other than you know, for
Speaker 4:  mashing the potatoes, I'm happy to have someone else do that for me.
Speaker 2:  Right. Yeah, I think you're right that the right answer is probably that
Speaker 2:  there should kind of be a whole spectrum of stuff and even that your oven
Speaker 2:  should be able to give you lots of options, right? Cause there's probably
Speaker 2:  some days where you're just like, I need this to be made and I don't have
Speaker 2:  time to make it Right. And you should be able to just like open a door, shove
Speaker 2:  some stuff in and have it be made. And then there's other times where it's
Speaker 2:  like I wanna be part of the process. It's like it makes me think about self-driving
Speaker 2:  cars, right? Like there will be times you don't wanna drive yourself and
Speaker 2:  times you do and both of those things should be possible and allowed.
Speaker 4:  Yeah and you know there are the, I mentioned earlier the June oven
Speaker 4:  which I tested a while back and I loved some of the features of that
Speaker 4:  where you could just put dish in or a piece of meat
Speaker 4:  and just say, you know, press a button and it would do the whole process
Speaker 4:  for you. And what I really liked, which I would like in this oven I
Speaker 4:  miss not having is the camera because I like to be able to
Speaker 4:  look inside the oven without opening it. Because as any chef will tell
Speaker 4:  you, every time you open the oven you are messing up the cooking process
Speaker 4:  and being able to look with the camera in at how your
Speaker 4:  turkey's browning or whatever it is that you're cooking is in there, how
Speaker 4:  it's doing. That's useful. That's something I would definitely would like
Speaker 4:  to be able to do with my smart oven. But unfortunately Thermador isn't
Speaker 4:  at that stage. There's also like the air fryers and smart
Speaker 4:  toaster ovens which have these presets and I think
Speaker 4:  it's nice to have the option to be able to, yeah just press a button and
Speaker 4:  you know the chicken nuggets are done and I can focus on the beef bugging
Speaker 4:  on for me and my kids can eat their nuggets.
Speaker 2:  Do all these things talk to each other at all. Obviously you have four voice
Speaker 2:  assistants, which is just absolute chaos and that sounds like a total
Speaker 2:  insane nightmare. But like are they integrated in any meaningful
Speaker 2:  way? All these different gadgets or are you the connective tissue of
Speaker 2:  all this
Speaker 4:  Stuff? So this has been a part of the smart kitchen that has been very
Speaker 4:  slow to evolve and it was an area I think we thought voice assistants would
Speaker 4:  be able to help with. For example, yes my oven can be
Speaker 4:  controlled by the two voice assistants here that Amazon's and Googles.
Speaker 4:  If I had a smart Samsung oven,
Speaker 4:  then the fridge oven would talk to each other. I did not want a
Speaker 4:  Samsung smart Oven cuz I wanted my fma. I'm not, I
Speaker 4:  won't go, won't go further. Samsung ovens don't have a great reputation,
Speaker 4:  but the problem is all of the individual air
Speaker 9:  Quality and your home recently changed to
Speaker 4:  Coral Uhoh. Did you hear that? What are we burning? I think I'm burning my
Speaker 4:  bacon. Have a look. Oh yeah. Ooh it's crispy.
Speaker 4:  Ooh I like crispy bacon.
Speaker 2:  There we go.
Speaker 4:  So this was on top of the Turkey to keep it moist. I, I forgot that to tell
Speaker 4:  you about that step. So yes, the next step in the smart kitchen
Speaker 4:  is this integration and there's been a recent
Speaker 4:  development because the problem is most people have different
Speaker 4:  brands in their kitchen. So I have different smart fridge
Speaker 4:  for my oven and a different brand for my microwave
Speaker 4:  and a different brand for my dishwasher. Sometimes you'll buy all your
Speaker 4:  pieces and parts from one brand but not that often. And then when one thing
Speaker 4:  breaks you might wanna get a different one. So even if you did have
Speaker 4:  all the same pieces, it doesn't necessarily help you with
Speaker 4:  communicating with everything in your home too. For example, my TV
Speaker 4:  can connect to my fridge so when my fridge is telling me the doors open,
Speaker 4:  I get an alert on my tv. But what I'd really like is an alert on my tv.
Speaker 4:  TV that my oven had reached the right temperature. But Thermador,
Speaker 4:  actually Thermador does work with smart things. So it's beginning we're getting
Speaker 4:  these connections. What's happened that's made a big difference and I think
Speaker 4:  will make a big difference probably in the next 12 to 18 months
Speaker 4:  is a new organization called the Home Connectivity Alliance. And
Speaker 4:  this is similar to, and I can't believe we've gotten through this much of
Speaker 4:  a smart home vercast and not mention the word matter. I
Speaker 2:  Blame you, this is all your fault. I'm outrage it took
Speaker 4:  You this long. This is similar to the Matter Alliance, which is where
Speaker 4:  a lot of the big companies in the space have got together and
Speaker 4:  are working on a common protocol and communication method.
Speaker 4:  But the difference between Matter and the Home Connectivity Alliance is the
Speaker 4:  Home Connectivity alliance will be entirely cloud-based. So it's basically
Speaker 4:  a way for all the appliance manufacturers to connect their
Speaker 4:  appliances on the backend. And so lg, ge,
Speaker 4:  which is ha Samsung, a number of large
Speaker 4:  H V A C manufacturers are all on board. I think there's
Speaker 4:  even more like they've been announcing new members. This launched about a
Speaker 4:  year, year and a half ago, John, one of our reporters at EFA
Speaker 4:  saw a demo of how these devices will work together and basically
Speaker 4:  you can use Samsung's app, LGS app
Speaker 4:  to control any appliance that's part of this home connectivity alliance.
Speaker 4:  So that is a beginning to be, you know, a point where when our
Speaker 4:  appliances talk to each other, then maybe you could start to see some artificial
Speaker 4:  intelligent layers being built on top that could help you get
Speaker 4:  to a more useful smart kitchen in terms of like reordering
Speaker 4:  food or sending recipes from the fridge to the oven,
Speaker 4:  telling the dishwasher it needs to do an extra hard load because you know,
Speaker 4:  you used the deep fat fryer, but at the
Speaker 4:  moment I just don't see a lot of really useful
Speaker 4:  compellingly use cases for consumers. I think
Speaker 4:  the appliance manufacturers need to kind of get that connectivity layer
Speaker 4:  sorted and then maybe start building some good experiences on top
Speaker 4:  of that.
Speaker 2:  Okay, I like it. We're, we're making progress. This is what I like to hear.
Speaker 2:  All right Jen, we're gonna leave you for a few minutes. You need to cook,
Speaker 2:  you need to finish some stuff. We're gonna do the cooking show magic where
Speaker 2:  you just put something in the oven, go to a commercial break, come back and
Speaker 2:  it's finished. We have to talk about dessert. We have a lot more to do. We'll
Speaker 2:  be right back.
Speaker 2:  We're back. Okay Jen, last we left you. You were checking on
Speaker 2:  the Turkey, we didn't burn the house down with the bacon. This is all very
Speaker 2:  good. Catch me up. It's been a couple of hours. Tell me what's been going
Speaker 2:  on, what have you been working on?
Speaker 4:  So yes it has been quiet time, just while the Turkey
Speaker 4:  rested, while I have two things left to do, one that we're gonna go through
Speaker 4:  now and then my final thing is the green beans
Speaker 4:  cuz we want those done last so they're nice and crisp and tasty with the
Speaker 4:  Turkey. So I did do some gravy, so I got the Turkey
Speaker 4:  out of the pan and I did pan gravy, which is my favorite way to do gravy.
Speaker 4:  Didn't need any gadgets for that, just a whisk. But now it's time for
Speaker 4:  pie, which is my favorite part of Thanksgiving.
Speaker 4:  Again, I'm coming back to my trusty Therma mix
Speaker 2:  And this is, we're doing Smart pie, right?
Speaker 4:  No ordinary pie and just to make it, you know, take it up a notch in skill
Speaker 4:  level. We're doing pumpkin cheesecake, not just pumpkin pie
Speaker 2:  Fancy.
Speaker 4:  So I have my spring form pan, which is what you need for cheesecake
Speaker 4:  and now my Therma mix is gonna do most of the work for me.
Speaker 4:  So it's pretty straightforward. As I described before, it has a
Speaker 4:  little Android screen, Android powered screen built into the
Speaker 4:  Therma mix and once you powered it on, this is the one thing
Speaker 4:  I find it's a little slow.
Speaker 2:  I was just about to say, as soon as you said Android powered screen,
Speaker 2:  I get, I get nervous like
Speaker 4:  Yeah it's a little laggy once it's up and running.
Speaker 2:  What kind of icons are we talking about here? How, how like what? Give me
Speaker 2:  a design review of the Thermo Makes interface here.
Speaker 4:  It's actually pretty nice. It's very much custom. It's not something you
Speaker 4:  would recognize the keyboard you would definitely recognize just like on
Speaker 4:  any other Android interface. So it's a little laggy
Speaker 4:  and I just managed to spell cheesecake wrong so it's not able to find
Speaker 4:  my recipe. But it gives you the option to save. So
Speaker 4:  like before you start Thanksgiving dinner you can go through and like save
Speaker 4:  all the recipes that you want in a little recipe book. So it's really easy
Speaker 4:  to just pull 'em up and tap them so you don't have to go through the whole
Speaker 4:  laggy Android tablet process.
Speaker 2:  Does this connect to some like outside service that you can do the recipes?
Speaker 2:  Like I want this to like integrate with the New York Times cooking app?
Speaker 4:  That would be great. No, actually this is a key point that I didn't mention
Speaker 4:  before. It integrates with its own cooking app, which is called
Speaker 4:  Cookie. Do
Speaker 2:  I hate that?
Speaker 4:  You have to pay, I did forget to mention that. And that is
Speaker 4:  actually one of the frustrating things about using the device. It's not too
Speaker 4:  expensive. I wanna say it's $23 a year but without the
Speaker 4:  cookie do subscription. It does all the basic functions that
Speaker 4:  you expect. It doesn't take away the functionality but it's just not as easy
Speaker 4:  cuz it's much easier when you're following a recipe and it's all there
Speaker 4:  for you to just hit the button rather than having to figure it out as you
Speaker 4:  go. But yeah, so the cookie Do app, you can download that onto
Speaker 4:  your smartphone. So you can go in and like add everything, get your
Speaker 4:  recipes ready, you don't have to stand in front of the device to get
Speaker 4:  it all set
Speaker 2:  Up. Is there an app for your Samsung Smart Fridge though? That's the real
Speaker 2:  question.
Speaker 4:  No, and they don't, it doesn't integrate at all. There's that whole, going
Speaker 4:  back to the whole, the Smart kitchen just doesn't really talk to it itself
Speaker 4:  yet. There's not enough integration there. Although to be
Speaker 4:  fair, I'm not entirely sure what I would use it for. I was kind of
Speaker 4:  disappointed when I first started using this that it didn't have
Speaker 4:  integrations, but as I've used it, I haven't really found like I needed
Speaker 4:  them. What I do when I'm sometimes going through you working with this is
Speaker 4:  would, you know, add something to my shopping list, which I can do with voice
Speaker 4:  on the Samsung Smart Fridge, which has Alexa built in as well as
Speaker 4:  Bixby. And I do tend to use Alexa
Speaker 2:  For obvious reasons.
Speaker 4:  It's fun to do BPE occasionally. Is it? I feel like someone
Speaker 4:  should use it. It's, it's out there. It's
Speaker 2:  Just a lonely dog butler with shoes just waiting for you to ask it to do
Speaker 2:  something. I get
Speaker 4:  It. So my ther mix is telling me the first step in my pumpkin
Speaker 4:  cheesecake is to preheat my oven. So it's like it gives
Speaker 4:  you all the steps. It's not just what you're doing on the device, which is
Speaker 4:  nice. And then you are gonna grease your pan, which is my spring form
Speaker 4:  pan. And you know, in the grand tradition of all cooking shows,
Speaker 4:  I should have done this earlier. So we're gonna put our unsalted butter
Speaker 4:  cubed into the thermo mix and I'm just gonna grab my knife
Speaker 4:  so we can chop away. So as I mentioned,
Speaker 4:  this doesn't really chop because it's a blender, so if you don't
Speaker 4:  chop things up it gets a bit stuck. So I've added in my butter
Speaker 4:  and then this is the fun part, it uses this thing called a
Speaker 4:  simine basket. So like you can use it to make rice, it's
Speaker 4:  a rice cooker as well. I don't think I mentioned that.
Speaker 4:  I kind of lose track of all the different things this can
Speaker 2:  Do. Well, yeah, I'm kind of, I'm, I'm at the point now where like it does
Speaker 2:  so many things that it's like can it possibly do all of these things well,
Speaker 2:  but it kind of seems like it does.
Speaker 4:  The one thing it doesn't do that well is chop, as I mentioned, like it's
Speaker 4:  good if you want puree, so if you want whipped mashed potatoes, but if
Speaker 4:  you want lumpy mashed potatoes, which you know is a choice, it, it doesn't
Speaker 4:  do that well cuz it'll chop and whip things like a
Speaker 4:  blender. I see again, so if you want like nice little cubes
Speaker 4:  in your stew or something, or if you're doing carrots with
Speaker 4:  your Turkey and you want nice little cube carrots, then you might wanna crack
Speaker 4:  out the cuisine art, food processor for that if you've got the time
Speaker 4:  and energy. Okay, so now I've got my butter in here
Speaker 4:  and it's the little Android screen which is quite handy. It has,
Speaker 4:  it's shown me how long it's gonna cook, what temperature it's gonna cook
Speaker 4:  to, and then I turn the dial for the speed and so the
Speaker 4:  slowest speed won't turn everything into mush. Whereas if
Speaker 4:  I do full speed, it's a blender and then you know, I'd get a smoothie
Speaker 4:  so you probably just heard it. Then it has two
Speaker 4:  arms on either side that clamp the lid down so that you can't
Speaker 4:  accidentally pull it off while it's cooking and then it's gonna go ahead
Speaker 4:  and cook. It's melting the butter for me, which you know, I could do
Speaker 4:  in the microwave. But then I have to get another bowl out and I have to put
Speaker 4:  in the microwave and I have to check every couple of seconds to make sure
Speaker 4:  it's melted enough. And I haven't burnt the butter, which I always do. So
Speaker 4:  that's melting away. And then I'm getting my cookies out cuz my cookies are
Speaker 4:  gonna be our base rather than using graham
Speaker 4:  crackers, which is the tradition I'm going with ginger snaps just to give
Speaker 4:  a little extra flavor.
Speaker 2:  I like that idea. What does your family think of your smart kitchen
Speaker 2:  insanity? Like do they, are they hopelessly intimidated by trying to cook
Speaker 2:  in your kitchen now? Do they love it?
Speaker 4:  So my husband is a bit like you. He loves to cook but I don't let him do
Speaker 4:  it.
Speaker 4:  So he's actually a fireman. So he cooks a lot on
Speaker 4:  shift. So he'll cook for his fire crew. So he gets to do the cooking there
Speaker 4:  and quite often he'll ask me for recipes and stuff, but no, I don't let him
Speaker 4:  actually cook in this kitchen ever.
Speaker 2:  Fair enough. What is this very charming noise we're hearing right now by
Speaker 2:  the way?
Speaker 4:  So this is the Therma mix. It is dumb with the melting of the
Speaker 4:  butter.
Speaker 2:  It's a nice noise. We've heard some hideous noises from this gadget so far,
Speaker 2:  but that was a nice one. I like
Speaker 4:  That one. This is a gentle one. The downside is it will not stop
Speaker 4:  until you come and press the button. Oh. So if it's done and you
Speaker 4:  don't, you know you don't wanna mess with it, you have to get up and shut
Speaker 4:  it up. That's the one thing that annoys me about it. Okay, so now I'm
Speaker 4:  gonna put in my ginger snap cookies and now I can't remember if I mentioned
Speaker 4:  this before, but this is a builtin scale so I don't need to
Speaker 4:  get the scales out to weigh how many ginger snap cookies I need. I just pour
Speaker 4:  it in and it shows me on the screen what quantity I've add.
Speaker 4:  So, oh love the of gingers.
Speaker 4:  I think it's just gonna be the whole bag. Yep, there we go. So the whole
Speaker 4:  bag goes in, this will be
Speaker 2:  Noisy. So now we have basically all the ingredients of your pie crust in
Speaker 2:  there.
Speaker 4:  Oh and sugar, I forgot the sugar. So one ounce of sugar.
Speaker 2:  Do you have to do all the measurement conversion in your head? The difference
Speaker 2:  between like an ounce and a gram and a tablespoon?
Speaker 2:  Does it show you all the different measurements all at the same time?
Speaker 4:  So you can choose in the settings what measurements you want, if you want
Speaker 4:  to use imperial or metric. Okay. And then the
Speaker 4:  on the screen as I added, it's showing me the weight. So it's showed
Speaker 4:  me when I added, I've added 1.2 ounces of sugar, which you know,
Speaker 4:  I don't need to be exact. And then if you want, like
Speaker 4:  I mentioned, it's also got this cup measure up here. So if you're adding
Speaker 4:  liquid you can just measure that, it can weigh
Speaker 4:  or measure. So you've got lots of options, which is nice cuz again
Speaker 4:  I don't, I, I've cooked this whole meal and I haven't got a cup or a
Speaker 4:  tablespoon thing out once it's pretty great. Anything Yeah,
Speaker 4:  which I really like. I've got my ingredients for the crust in
Speaker 4:  and it's telling me it's gonna take five seconds and it's gonna heat it up
Speaker 4:  to 160 degrees for five seconds and go really fast. So this is gonna
Speaker 4:  be noisy.
Speaker 2:  Okay,
Speaker 11:  That's
Speaker 4:  Not too noisy actually. Oh nope. Just
Speaker 11:  Rev up.
Speaker 2:  That's it. It did it. That was so fast.
Speaker 4:  Yep, that was really quick. So the device comes with a spatula
Speaker 4:  so it's asking me to scrape down the sides because obviously when
Speaker 4:  you blend something in a blender it all kind of goes up sides.
Speaker 2:  Is this like a special spatula?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, it comes with it. It's very neat. It's actually designed
Speaker 4:  to use, it has a little hook in it and it hooks onto the
Speaker 4:  simine basket. So like say you're doing rice or boiled eggs or something,
Speaker 4:  it can just lift the simmering basket out for you without you getting burning
Speaker 4:  your hands on the steam cuz it boils. You can boil eggs
Speaker 4:  in this as well
Speaker 2:  And of course you can. I,
Speaker 4:  I literally haven't found anything it can't do yet. Okay,
Speaker 4:  so now we're gonna blend again. 10 more seconds.
Speaker 11:  That
Speaker 4:  Was faster.
Speaker 11:  Yeah.
Speaker 11:  Oh of course.
Speaker 11:  Describe it.
Speaker 2:  Okay. Okay I've I've changed my mind about that noise by the way. If it does
Speaker 2:  that noise until you make it stop every single time, that's a lot of that
Speaker 2:  sound.
Speaker 4:  It is. And yeah and I can't like stop it
Speaker 4:  remotely or anything with the app so yeah that's definitely a downside
Speaker 4:  I would like, I'd like a bit more control there.
Speaker 2:  I also just feel like it should play like three seconds of, of a song or
Speaker 2:  like tell you a joke or just like something different when it's done.
Speaker 4:  Yeah cause it does get quite repetitive. So now I've got my
Speaker 4:  crumb bass so I'm gonna put that in my pie filling
Speaker 4:  spring form pie pan which is what you need for a cheesecake if you're
Speaker 4:  not familiar with cheesecake cooking. Okay. I will make that
Speaker 4:  into a pie just by sort of pressing it down with the
Speaker 4:  spatula. So like into a crust. Sorry graham cracker
Speaker 4:  crusts are normally on cheesecakes. Yeah, yeah,
Speaker 2:  Usually.
Speaker 4:  Yeah so that's what this is a lot like. So I'm gonna just
Speaker 4:  tap that down and then it tells me to just put it in the fridge so that it
Speaker 4:  chills while I'm making the filling and now I've got nice gingerbread
Speaker 4:  hands and now I can go over to my smart faucet and
Speaker 4:  wash them without getting my faucet or covered in gingerbread crumbs cuz
Speaker 4:  it's motion activated. I
Speaker 2:  Was gonna say you can wash your hands without touching anything. Do you have
Speaker 2:  like a temperature you use to wash your hands now? Like how crazy has this
Speaker 2:  sink made you?
Speaker 4:  I probably should have, shouldn't I? Cause it's better to do it when you
Speaker 4:  are to do it with warm water, but I'm, I'm more about speed.
Speaker 4:  Okay. Especially as it's just some butter. But it does have a hand hand washing
Speaker 4:  feature so I can say hey voice assistant start my
Speaker 4:  hand washing preset and then it would dispense the water at certain
Speaker 4:  temperature. So yeah, maybe I'll try and do that.
Speaker 2:  All
Speaker 4:  Right. I just, you know, sometimes there's only so much smart you need.
Speaker 4:  Okay. So I'm just rinsing out the FEMA mix
Speaker 4:  bowl I guess is what you call it. Now we're gonna make the filling so
Speaker 4:  you can, as I mentioned before, it will self clean but for
Speaker 4:  efficiency at this stage it's just quicker to rinse it out and it's
Speaker 4:  not like I'm doing meat and then the pie, it's just
Speaker 4:  got gingerbread crumbs in it so a little contamination wouldn't be a problem.
Speaker 2:  I'm definitely starting to see why people would buy several of the, of the
Speaker 2:  container thing to be able to just sort of hot swap them in and out as you're
Speaker 2:  cooking.
Speaker 4:  If I had my druthers I would have at least two. Okay. Cream
Speaker 4:  cheese, the best part of any pie or cake filling.
Speaker 4:  So again, have to cube it, it doesn't, it doesn't want me to put it in
Speaker 4:  whole so there is a little bit of manual labor and
Speaker 4:  then I'm gonna pop the hued cream cheese
Speaker 4:  into the bowl. It's not cooking this obviously cuz
Speaker 4:  the oven will cook it but like when I was, I did the mashed
Speaker 4:  potato before it cooked a mashed potato in the bowl for
Speaker 4:  30 minutes before we blended it. So it's nice to be able to have
Speaker 4:  that function of doing both.
Speaker 2:  Yeah although it's, it's an interesting thing because like in doing that
Speaker 2:  you're in a good position because you're kind of doing everything in one
Speaker 2:  place that's very handy. But it's also kind of like you have a whole kitchen
Speaker 2:  with only one bowl and, and it's, you know what I mean And nothing
Speaker 2:  is now like monopolized for 30 minutes and it is like the main thing you're
Speaker 2:  using to do your cooking. So it's yet another reason that it would be better
Speaker 2:  if this stuff was like well integrated and everything sort of made sense
Speaker 2:  together. It feels like we need like a universal standard for kitchen gadgets
Speaker 2:  that you can just sort of drop new things into new places and it's like
Speaker 2:  you keep it in the bowl but you move it between devices and that's how it
Speaker 2:  works. That seems like it would be a much cleaner system than a lot of the
Speaker 2:  stuff we've been doing where it's just kind of one all in one system.
Speaker 4:  Exactly. Yeah. That's the biggest issue I have with this device
Speaker 4:  and it was entirely designed as a self-contained system
Speaker 4:  other than you know, using your oven. But yeah, it doesn't integrate with
Speaker 4:  anything else in my house. Although it wasn't sort of designed to be a
Speaker 4:  smart device, which generally is when you find
Speaker 4:  gadgets become actually useful when you know someone didn't think oh I
Speaker 4:  can make this smart, what can I then make it do?
Speaker 4:  They thought, oh I have this function I need and actually adding
Speaker 4:  connectivity would make this function work better, you know, and I like that
Speaker 4:  approach totally because I, there's too much, let's add wifi to this and
Speaker 4:  then figure out why that might be useful later. And that happens in
Speaker 4:  the kitchen a lot.
Speaker 2:  Yeah and by the time you're building a whole Android tablet into your device,
Speaker 2:  like you kind of have no excuse but to make some of this stuff work.
Speaker 4:  Exactly. And you know obviously the connectivity, the best feature
Speaker 4:  of connectivity I would say in the kitchen at the moment is software updates.
Speaker 4:  You know, this has had like new recipes appear every
Speaker 4:  week with a new software update and my fridge gets new
Speaker 4:  functions with software updates. So you know, from from that perspective
Speaker 4:  I think adding the connectivity does, you know, add usefulness.
Speaker 4:  But now I've put sour cream and cream cheese in here so this is gonna be
Speaker 4:  very decadent my, which I suppose
Speaker 4:  that's just the way cheesecakes are. Okay so three and a half ounce of sugar
Speaker 4:  again gonna add the eggs again you have to do this
Speaker 4:  manually. It's not gonna crack the egg for you.
Speaker 2:  So this is one of the things I've been thinking as you've been doing this
Speaker 2:  is like in the kitchen world there is like an infinite selection
Speaker 2:  of super random little gadgets, right? Like are we gonna get the
Speaker 2:  equivalent of that but with Bluetooth next and this is just gonna be the
Speaker 2:  whole new world that we live in. I both hope so and hope not. Simultaneously
Speaker 4:  I just can't see what value they would be but someone will come up with it.
Speaker 4:  And one of the things that we really aren't showcasing here because you know
Speaker 4:  when you cook your Thanksgiving dinner you are in the kitchen all day.
Speaker 4:  But one of the biggest benefits I would say of the smart kitchen to date
Speaker 4:  is remote control and remote monitoring. So if you
Speaker 4:  are out, you know you can put your Turkey in the oven and go out for the
Speaker 4:  day and check in on your thermometer from a distance to make
Speaker 4:  sure that everything's going well. You know, having that kind of remote
Speaker 4:  control or insight into what's happening at home.
Speaker 4:  If you are in the garden or had to go do some shopping, that's a benefit.
Speaker 4:  Unfortunately I had to get out the teaspoons because
Speaker 4:  I know
Speaker 2:  Technology has failed us
Speaker 4:  Using the teaspoon. So there's one thing I'm gonna have to wash.
Speaker 2:  I'm assuming you also have like a smart dishwasher lying around.
Speaker 4:  I do have a smart dishwasher.
Speaker 2:  Of course you do. I didn't even know that was a thing and I just said that
Speaker 2:  and was like if, if this exists, Jen has it.
Speaker 4:  So like the oven though, it's just smart in that I can monitor it,
Speaker 4:  I can like change the program. It does tell me how much RINs aid I have
Speaker 4:  and that kind of stuff. It doesn't do anything special in terms of cleaning,
Speaker 4:  it just cleans like a regular dishwasher. But a dishwasher's a pretty smart
Speaker 4:  gadget to begin with. That's true. I mean it's a robot that is washing your
Speaker 4:  dishes for you. You don't need to mess with that too much. Okay, we're
Speaker 4:  gonna mix our filling for 10 seconds.
Speaker 4:  There's the noise wants a little bit of scraping and you
Speaker 4:  could hear the little robot arms coming off cuz it won't let you in.
Speaker 4:  Sometimes you have to sort of stand here for a few seconds to wait for it
Speaker 4:  to let you in, which can be a little frustrating. Okay. And we're gonna mix
Speaker 4:  again and then almost at the end
Speaker 2:  I'm officially out on this noise just in the time we've been standing here
Speaker 2:  doing this. I'm out on the noise.
Speaker 4:  I know but it's quite loud but it's not too jarring
Speaker 2:  And it is definitely true. At least we've moved past the just like loud
Speaker 2:  truck reversing beeping noises. Yes. So that's something
Speaker 2:  it's progress.
Speaker 4:  Okay so it asked me to pour two-thirds of the mixture
Speaker 4:  over the pie base and now we get to the exciting
Speaker 4:  bit which is the pumpkin. And now I did not
Speaker 4:  go hand scrape a pumpkin for you guys. I went and bought some
Speaker 4:  canned stuff and some brown
Speaker 4:  sugar. So this one is definitely the messiest
Speaker 4:  part of the meal. And then we need to add some pumpkin
Speaker 4:  spice. That should be it.
Speaker 4:  Okay.
Speaker 2:  And every single part of this has happened in this one Therma mix.
Speaker 4:  Yep. Other than obviously the pie crust is now in the Pippa,
Speaker 2:  Are there other devices like this? Like is the Therma mix one of like a
Speaker 2:  whole genre or is it just kind of the one thing? It's
Speaker 4:  Just the one thing as far as I'm aware, I have not come across another gadget
Speaker 4:  like it as said it's pretty popular in Europe but I haven't seen it
Speaker 4:  much in the States yet. Like I said that there are so many gadgets for the
Speaker 4:  kitchen that I think a lot of people are like, oh do I need another one?
Speaker 4:  You know I've already got cuis and art.
Speaker 7:  Sorry
Speaker 2:  It's
Speaker 4:  Just a nice noise. It's just
Speaker 2:  A nice, it just sounds like cooking. I
Speaker 4:  Appreciate that. You getting hungry?
Speaker 2:  Yes. This is the absolute worst part. I feel bad for everyone listening to
Speaker 2:  this but I especially feel bad for me cuz I'm just starving. Now if you're
Speaker 2:  listening to this in your car on the way to Thanksgiving, just know that
Speaker 2:  I'm sorry and I feel your pain.
Speaker 4:  All right and so now we're done. So I'm just gonna pull that onto the top
Speaker 4:  of the pie and then it'll go in the oven for two hours in total
Speaker 4:  10 minutes to start and then an hour and 50 minutes to finish it off
Speaker 4:  And then you have to let it sit for a long time. Cheesecakes take a long
Speaker 4:  time to chill.
Speaker 2:  So the connectivity piece of this, if you were to just like buy
Speaker 2:  all Samsung everything, would all of this be even easier cuz
Speaker 2:  all these companies now are trying to like build out whole ecosystems, right?
Speaker 2:  Like is it Yeah if you went all in on one company would it work?
Speaker 4:  So in terms of what you were asking about this device, like if, if it
Speaker 4:  talked to anyone else, the Therma mix, would it be more useful? So what
Speaker 4:  Samsung's sort of angle is for the smart fridge and the smart
Speaker 4:  oven right now is you know you order your groceries on your fridge,
Speaker 4:  you choose your recipes on your fridge, you can follow along on the
Speaker 4:  recipes on the fridge, although that's not that useful unless cuz your fridge
Speaker 4:  is not right in front of you when you're cooking but then it would
Speaker 4:  know what you were cooking. So the fridge would know I was cooking a pumpkin
Speaker 4:  pie, a pumpkin cheesecake and it would send the
Speaker 4:  correct settings to the oven and you know if this device would
Speaker 4:  could communicate with the oven, I think that would be an extra useful step
Speaker 4:  because right now it's saying turn the temperature of your oven
Speaker 4:  to 250 degrees for 20 minutes and then
Speaker 4:  reduce the temperature to 225 and bake for another hour and a
Speaker 4:  half. So that means I'm gonna have to come back in 20 minutes and adjust
Speaker 4:  it. But if it could could send that to the oven and automatically
Speaker 4:  adjust the oven in 20 minutes down to 2 25 and to
Speaker 4:  continue cooking at one for an hour and a half, then I wouldn't have to worry
Speaker 4:  about it. So that would be a useful connect. You know if there was
Speaker 4:  some connectivity in the background here between these
Speaker 4:  appliances, which could happen if I was using Samsung oven, it
Speaker 4:  could have and the Samsung fridge to do the recipe, it could have talked
Speaker 4:  to each other but it's a small thing at this stage, you
Speaker 4:  know, changing the temperature isn't that hard. True and I can do it
Speaker 4:  from my app on the oven but you know if we're trying to make the
Speaker 4:  smart kitchen a more viable and appealing
Speaker 4:  solution to people, those kind of small but sort of simple
Speaker 4:  steps, taking that out of our brains and having to worry about when we're
Speaker 4:  cooking other things would help. I
Speaker 2:  Think that's where it goes back to the question of like having your family
Speaker 2:  cook with you, right? This is part of the problem with with smart homes in
Speaker 2:  general is you have to learn so many specific things
Speaker 2:  about exactly how it works and what the name of that lamp is
Speaker 2:  and how it'll refer to your faucet and it's like, you know what's great about
Speaker 2:  a light switch is they look pretty much the same everywhere and right and
Speaker 2:  it's like the thing on the oven that you turn to the right to turn the oven
Speaker 2:  on is like pretty self-explanatory most of the time. And I feel like with
Speaker 2:  a lot of this stuff it's so handy but so non-obvious
Speaker 2:  how it works that it's like you have to like build a manual for how to use
Speaker 2:  your kitchen. Little things like the thermo mix seem like they push in the
Speaker 2:  right direction where it's just like here is a screen, touch the screen,
Speaker 2:  we'll figure this out together. But so much of this stuff is all so like
Speaker 2:  behind the scenes in opaque and just impossible to figure out. So if I like
Speaker 2:  walked into your kitchen, I would not know how to do anything.
Speaker 4:  Yeah you would not know how to turn the tap on.
Speaker 2:  Which is a pretty important thing.
Speaker 4:  My husband when I was away a few weeks ago was making something in the kitchen
Speaker 4:  and I said oh we use a Therma mix and he's like, I have no idea how to use
Speaker 4:  that. And it is a bit, as you mentioned, a bit more user friendly
Speaker 4:  than some devices but yes it's, it's foreign, it's different. It's not what
Speaker 4:  he's used to. That's a problem with too many of the gadgets like sous vide
Speaker 4:  is a big thing in the smart kitchen. I have not actually tried it myself
Speaker 4:  but there, you know when you try and sort of break the mold and come out
Speaker 4:  with really new ways of doing things in the kitchen or at least new for the
Speaker 4:  residential kitchen cuz it was obviously a big thing for commercial kitchens
Speaker 4:  that when it gets a little bit harder for the average consumer to
Speaker 4:  say hey yes I definitely want this. The connectivity of devices
Speaker 4:  in the kitchen right now still is a big question mark like why do I need
Speaker 4:  to do that? I, I remember talking to some appliance manufacturers and they
Speaker 4:  say you know, 90% of their smart appliances never
Speaker 4:  get connected to the internet. So no one's really using that. That
Speaker 4:  might be slightly overestimate but it was like they rarely do. Or if
Speaker 4:  they do get connected and then one day someone changes their wifi
Speaker 4:  router, no one ever bothers to reconnect it cuz they just haven't found the
Speaker 4:  value. I think the most useful thing I have found out of connectivity was
Speaker 4:  my LG dishwasher about five years ago stop working
Speaker 4:  and I was able to hold up the phone to the
Speaker 4:  device and it played a sound to the LG app
Speaker 4:  which told the app what was wrong with the dishwasher
Speaker 4:  and how I could fix it cuz it wasn't working and that saved me a lot of money
Speaker 2:  That I like
Speaker 4:  That has got better. This was a while ago. So now you can
Speaker 4:  actually, you know the app will do proper diagnosis for you. My fridge will
Speaker 4:  diagnose itself. Actually it did once when it wasn't working properly and
Speaker 4:  so when the repair man, cuz it did need to be repaired when the repair man
Speaker 4:  came here, he knew exactly what he needed to bring, didn't have to
Speaker 4:  come out twice. So that sort of support for appliances,
Speaker 4:  that connectivity is a bonus because you know you
Speaker 4:  save money, especially if you don't have to have a repairman come out. And
Speaker 4:  I think that's the most compelling use case right now for regular consumers
Speaker 4:  is if you connect it to the internet we can tell you why it broke.
Speaker 2:  That's pretty good. So here, here's the real question. This is what it all
Speaker 2:  boils down to. Does matter, fix everything Matter is
Speaker 2:  matter gonna solve everything for us.
Speaker 4:  I'll tell you what will matter, we'll fix in my kitchen as the lights, oh
Speaker 4:  okay, so we didn't go into this but in terms of my family using my
Speaker 4:  kitchen, the one sort of smart thing they have got used to is the lights.
Speaker 4:  Cuz I have a motion sensor that when you walk into the kitchen it'll turn
Speaker 4:  the lights on and if no one's been moving in the kitchen for a certain amount
Speaker 4:  of time, they'll turn off. Which is useful cuz it's, it's an open plan kitchen.
Speaker 4:  And we have our living room right here. So when you're watching TV you don't
Speaker 4:  really want the kitchen lights on. But I also wanted nice lights. I did
Speaker 4:  a big kitchen remodel a couple years ago. It was kind of my midlife crisis
Speaker 4:  thing. I didn't buy a Corvette, I got a really fancy kitchen, it
Speaker 4:  works. I didn't want like screw and light bulb. I wanted nice light fixtures.
Speaker 4:  So I have like pendant lights and I have a few other kind of fancy light
Speaker 4:  fixtures that aren't smart. So I needed to use smart switches from different
Speaker 4:  brands and getting them all to work with one motion
Speaker 4:  sensor has been difficult. I have done it but it's been a bit of
Speaker 4:  a work around and it's not ideal and it often breaks. So
Speaker 4:  this is the whole point of matter is a common language
Speaker 4:  for all your devices. So I should have much and much faster
Speaker 4:  responsiveness too. So occasionally you'll walk into the kitchen and it takes
Speaker 4:  a couple beats before the lights turn on, which is very frustrating. You
Speaker 4:  want it to be as fast, if not fast than flipping
Speaker 4:  the light switch. I've been here too, you know, everyone's very excited
Speaker 4:  in this space about matter and kind of hyped up for it. But ultimately
Speaker 4:  it's a very simple solution to start with. And
Speaker 4:  I think the easiest way to sum up is that matter is going to make
Speaker 4:  smart lights work as well as dumb lights do now.
Speaker 2:  Okay. I mean even that is is a pretty high bar given kind of where
Speaker 2:  we're coming from with a lot of this stuff. Yes. Like you have to be better
Speaker 2:  than light switches before any of this matters. And I think like, it sounds
Speaker 2:  very small, but it's, I think that's like the real bar. So I'm, I'm, if Matter
Speaker 2:  can get there, that feels like, like good news.
Speaker 4:  That's the hope. My kitchen will be a good test for it once it finally gets
Speaker 4:  here.
Speaker 2:  Okay, we have tortured people enough. I'm starving. I'm gonna
Speaker 2:  go eat everyone else. I hope you have made it to wherever you're going for
Speaker 2:  Thanksgiving by the time you have finished this episode. Thank you so much
Speaker 2:  for listening. I hope you have an awesome, awesome Thanksgiving or whatever
Speaker 2:  you're doing this weekend. As always, there's lots more on smart home,
Speaker 2:  smart kitchen gadgets, Thanksgiving technology, everything on the
Speaker 2:  verge.com. You can also follow us on Twitter. Jen is j p two
Speaker 2:  E and I'm Pierce. Who knows if Twitter will be here by the time Thanksgiving
Speaker 2:  is over, but for now it's still around. This show is produced by Andrew Marino
Speaker 2:  and Liam James Nore. Donovan is our executive producer and Brooke Mentors
Speaker 2:  is our editorial director of audio. The Vergecast is a Verge production and
Speaker 2:  part of the Vox Media podcast network. If you have thoughts, feedback,
Speaker 2:  feelings, recipes, long ride home, you can always
Speaker 2:  email vergecast verge.com. We'd love to hear from you. And if you have
Speaker 2:  questions, call the hotline. Eight six six Verge one one. Send
Speaker 2:  us all your big thoughts and questions about all things tech. We're gonna
Speaker 2:  do a bunch of hotline stuff between now and the end of the year. So get your
Speaker 2:  questions in now. We'll be off for the next week, but we'll be back
Speaker 2:  Friday, December 2nd to see whether Twitter still exists. Plus cover some
Speaker 2:  of the biggest news in tech. Have a great week. Rock and roll.