# Transcript
ID: 9e62d150-6169-11ed-aca7-41187f8e7794
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: The politics and laws changing tech in the US
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-2301102024037155602/4121552452463475932/s93290-US-4220s-1668134088.mp3
Description: This week on
02:10 - The Verge's David Pierce tries out Neeva's Bias Buster, an attempt to get people out of their echo chambers and show them new information in its search engine.
20:25 - Senior reporter Adi Robertson talks about her story How America turned against the First Amendment
42:27 - Policy reporter Makena Kelly explains the CHIPS and Science Act, and how it could reshape the tech industry in America.
Speaker 2:  Welcome to the Verge Cast, the flagship podcast of Semiconductor Foundry
Speaker 2:  Construction. I'm your friend David Pierce and I am currently in
Speaker 2:  Union Station in DC just off an Amtrak home from
Speaker 2:  Connecticut. Big weekend with family time and ironically a lot of
Speaker 2:  technology. There was a floppy disc adapter involved. I got to tell my mom
Speaker 2:  all about the wonders of VLC media player and we did an awful lot of
Speaker 2:  password sharing. Nobody's on Netflix. Anyway, we have a great
Speaker 2:  show for you today. Technically as you're listening to this, the US midterms
Speaker 2:  were yesterday, but we still wanted to spend some time this week talking
Speaker 2:  about politics. So we're gonna talk about how political news works on the
Speaker 2:  internet and whether anyone can build tools to make it work better. We're
Speaker 2:  also gonna talk with Addie Robertson about the state of free speech in America
Speaker 2:  and on the internet, FairWarning, it's pretty bleak. And then McKenna Kelly
Speaker 2:  is gonna come on to talk to us about the Chips and Science Act and
Speaker 2:  which US cities might turn out to be the next big tech hubs. All that
Speaker 2:  is coming in just a second, but I gotta get outta this train station and
Speaker 2:  into a cab and get home. Wish me luck. This is the Verge Cast. See
Speaker 2:  in a second.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. I wanna tell you about this slider I'm looking at. So
Speaker 2:  I'm on niva.com. Niva, if you didn't know, is a search engine which
Speaker 2:  is built by a bunch of ex Googlers who think they can build a better
Speaker 2:  ad-free privacy respecting search engine. Super interesting company.
Speaker 2:  We're gonna talk a lot more about it in a later episode. But anyway, I'm
Speaker 2:  on niva.com and I search for let's say 2022 midterms.
Speaker 2:  They're happening right now. There's a lot going on. I click on the news
Speaker 2:  tab and I get some news midterm elections, latest news, which is a
Speaker 2:  stream of stuff from the Washington Post midterms 2022. The Ultimate
Speaker 2:  Insider's Guide from Newsweek, Charlie Kirk, The hidden parents votes
Speaker 2:  will sway midterm election from Fox News. There's the West Lake
Speaker 2:  Picayune, which is a local newspaper from Texas that's here. So
Speaker 2:  is the Houston Chronicle and the St. Louis Post Dispatch,
Speaker 2:  NBC News, abc, Dallas Morning News, Yahoo, Fox
Speaker 2:  Reuters, fairly standard news stuff. But then there's this
Speaker 2:  slider at the top right, it's like a third of the page wide and it goes
Speaker 2:  from dark blue on the left to a sort of faded white in the middle
Speaker 2:  to a dark red on the right. If I grab the black arrows in the middle and
Speaker 2:  pull them all the way left, the whole thing tilts toward blue
Speaker 2:  and the news changes. Now first step in my
Speaker 2:  search results is the Daily Beast. It says, Go spends
Speaker 2:  fu money in blue seats as polls tilt their way for midterm elections.
Speaker 2:  Then the Guardian Democrats insist Joe Biden's low midterms profile
Speaker 2:  is smart strategy. Then there's a slate story about JD Vance and Tim Ryan
Speaker 2:  in Ohio. Rolling Stones story with an SNL cold open, making
Speaker 2:  fun of Republicans.
Speaker 5:  My name is Hershaw Walker, Texas Ranger and
Speaker 5:  I'm running for president of the United Airlines.
Speaker 2:  You get the idea right? This is deep blue Pro Democrat
Speaker 2:  News, at least according to Neva. Now let's go all the way the other way.
Speaker 2:  Grab the arrow, slide it to the right, the whole thing tilts dark red. Now
Speaker 2:  I have a story from Breitbart. It says, Poll independent voters swing 18
Speaker 2:  points toward G O P on generic ballot. One from Newsmax
Speaker 2:  CBS's Margaret Brennan tries to pin political violence on Republican
Speaker 2:  rep's. Tweet one from the Daily Mail. Newt Gingrich says Biden likely doomed
Speaker 2:  midterms by inviting Dylan Mulvaney to White House. The Daily caller is on
Speaker 2:  here, The Federalist is on here. This is like the who's who of far right
Speaker 2:  news sources. If I tilt back slightly towards the middle, now
Speaker 2:  I'm getting the New York Post and Fox News and the Washington
Speaker 2:  Examiner and the Epoch Times. It's still very right leaning, obviously with
Speaker 2:  headlines about big tech and Democrats being in bed with each other and
Speaker 2:  China's supposed attempt to undermine the midterms. And then if I grab it
Speaker 2:  again and flip slightly left, I get a Yahoo story about the Senate race in
Speaker 2:  Pennsylvania and a political story about Democrats needing Obama to help
Speaker 2:  them and a bunch of CNN and nbc.
Speaker 2:  This slider is called Bias Buster and it's Nivas attempt to get people
Speaker 2:  out of their echo chambers and filter bubbles and show them new
Speaker 2:  information and new perspectives. Here's how Vivek Rahan Nivas
Speaker 2:  co-founder described it to
Speaker 6:  Me. This kind of thing has never existed before. Yeah, sure, you can look
Speaker 6:  up a query like Inflation Reduction Act or you know, election results
Speaker 6:  and add like Fox News or add like you know, Mother Jones or add like
Speaker 6:  you know, Huffington Post and you can get like views from across the spectrum.
Speaker 6:  But what we are really trying to do with Bias Buster is to dramatically
Speaker 6:  reduce the bar to sampling diverse points of
Speaker 6:  opinions from all sides of the spectrum. And so we built that into
Speaker 6:  the product design from the ground up. For example,
Speaker 6:  this bias buster resets itself on every search. We
Speaker 6:  don't want it to be a setting that kind of remembers itself as you go along.
Speaker 6:  We want you to try out and sample different points of the same opinion.
Speaker 2:  My immediate first question on seeing this or even hearing
Speaker 2:  about it was basically says, who is
Speaker 2:  this? Just someone at Niva looking at a bunch of news sources and articles
Speaker 2:  and saying that one's center right? That one's super left. Vivek
Speaker 2:  told me no. In a way it's actually simpler than that.
Speaker 6:  And there are a number of third party publications out there that have, you
Speaker 6:  know, published points of views of where various sources land on
Speaker 6:  various parts of the spectrum. They've often used polling and other techniques
Speaker 6:  that involve like serving users to create a map of the various news sources
Speaker 6:  and where they lie on the spectrum. We are using those as guides
Speaker 6:  to decide where various publications land on various parts of
Speaker 6:  the spectrum.
Speaker 2:  Okay, wait, hang on, quick diversion here. The VEC also told me that
Speaker 2:  Neva tried to not just categorize everything in one specific place
Speaker 2:  because publications aren't the same all the time, which makes sense, but
Speaker 2:  it got me wondering how these ranking systems work. It does kind
Speaker 2:  of sound like someone is just out there reading news articles and going,
Speaker 2:  Oh Mother Jones super left AP very center Brightbart Ultra,
Speaker 2:  right? It feels weird to me that it's that simple or that it's possible
Speaker 2:  to boil it all the way down like that. So I called up Julia
Speaker 2:  Srini who is the director of media Bias Ratings at All Sides, which is one
Speaker 2:  of the best known companies doing this kind of work. Here's how she explained
Speaker 2:  the process.
Speaker 7:  So if we have high confidence in a rating, it means that we've applied
Speaker 7:  multiple high confidence methodologies to the news sources content
Speaker 7:  and that typically means it's undergone two things, an editorial
Speaker 7:  review by a panel of people on the left center and
Speaker 7:  right who are actually looking at the news sources content and assessing
Speaker 7:  it for bias and then coming to a consensus on a rating and a blind
Speaker 7:  bias survey of Americans. So that is when we
Speaker 7:  strip news reporting content of any branding so people don't know that
Speaker 7:  it's coming from CNN or Fox. And we send it out to thousands of Americans
Speaker 7:  and we ask them to tell us what they think the bias of the media outlet is
Speaker 7:  after reading headlines and news reports from the outlet. So we're kind of
Speaker 7:  mixing, you know, expert panels of people who
Speaker 7:  are trained to spot bias with everyday Americans to get the
Speaker 7:  perception of the country.
Speaker 2:  She said this process involves a lot of nuance and that publications change
Speaker 2:  over time. But I definitely don't think this is a perfect system, but it
Speaker 2:  is at least a consistent one and an approach I've heard from a few people
Speaker 2:  building tools like nevas. I definitely think this is better than trying
Speaker 2:  to do like some really complicated personalized AI
Speaker 2:  analysis of every article to figure out where it falls politically. That's
Speaker 2:  something a lot of tech companies would try. I don't think it would work.
Speaker 2:  And in Nivas case, keeping it simple is probably the right call
Speaker 2:  because with a tool like this, giving people a transparent understanding
Speaker 2:  of what they're seeing and why is actually a really big deal.
Speaker 6:  We think any personalization users do should be explicit. We should not be
Speaker 6:  doing implicit personalization on their behalf and we think doing it at a
Speaker 6:  level of granularity they understand in this case sources is very
Speaker 6:  important to building that trust and transparency.
Speaker 2:  Look, do I think this is going to instantly solve all problems of
Speaker 2:  polarization on the internet? No. Do I think stuff like this is worth trying?
Speaker 2:  Absolutely. But honestly my biggest question with all of this
Speaker 2:  is will anyone use it? Sure there's a subset of
Speaker 2:  people who say they'd like to read widely and understand other arguments,
Speaker 2:  all that good stuff. It sounds nice but it's just human nature to seek out
Speaker 2:  stuff we know and stuff that agrees with us and the sources that we
Speaker 2:  feel like get us and we're most comfortable with. Is it even
Speaker 2:  possible to expose people to new things this way? Especially in such a
Speaker 2:  high stakes and constantly argumentative space like politics? I asked
Speaker 2:  that question to Sean Munson who's a professor at the University of Washington
Speaker 2:  and in 2012 he created a tool called Balancer that was meant to
Speaker 2:  do something very similar to what Neva is doing now. It was a Chrome extension
Speaker 2:  designed to help you see a wider spectrum of information about the news.
Speaker 8:  We thought about kind this whole range of options for pushing
Speaker 8:  folks or giving them kind of this nudge or, or at least feedback, some included
Speaker 8:  maybe we actually redirect them, right? So if you've read from a left leaning
Speaker 8:  or a right leaning source to often maybe when you go to read an article on
Speaker 8:  a topic on the backend, there's something that actually takes you to the
Speaker 8:  article on the same topic, maybe on a source you wouldn't choose
Speaker 2:  That last bit. Actually changing the articles you see felt like a bridge
Speaker 2:  too far. So balancer eventually settled on just giving you feedback
Speaker 2:  on your activity, but the goal he says now was fairly simple
Speaker 2:  and matches what Vivek told me about Neva.
Speaker 8:  If I were to have continued the work metrics for success would've been things
Speaker 8:  like are people more aware of other arguments? Are they able to
Speaker 8:  cite the range of opinions that might support another opinion even if they
Speaker 8:  still don't agree with it, right? So are they basically more prepared to
Speaker 8:  have conversations with people who hold different views because they kind
Speaker 8:  of understand a bit of where they're coming from or understand some of the
Speaker 8:  background and it might not change any minds, but at least kind of this the
Speaker 8:  shared understanding or shared reality.
Speaker 2:  You might have noticed that at the beginning of that, Sean said if I were
Speaker 2:  to have continued the work, spoiler alert he didn't continue the work.
Speaker 2:  In part he didn't because he felt like he wasn't actually pressing at the
Speaker 2:  most important information problem we have.
Speaker 8:  Baller is a a tool that works if articles exist in
Speaker 8:  a mostly shared reality, they just have different opinions about what to
Speaker 8:  do about that reality. And you know, if we look at where the information
Speaker 8:  space has gone these days, it's not a shared reality that you did misinformation.
Speaker 8:  Disinformation are much bigger threats and, and I don't think something like
Speaker 8:  baller could really possibly address them.
Speaker 2:  I asked VEC about this too because one thing that jumped out to me using
Speaker 2:  bias Buster was that tools like this seem to think that everything is
Speaker 2:  a matter of what right and left believe. And doesn't that set up
Speaker 2:  a false dichotomy like oh, reasonable people can disagree
Speaker 2:  when in reality some things are true and some people are just wrong.
Speaker 2:  Facts exist.
Speaker 6:  My current sense is the veracity of information is a, an
Speaker 6:  al access to political opinion. There is legitimate political opinion on
Speaker 6:  both sides about whether something is true or not is like the next level
Speaker 6:  of we don't currently or personally I don't feel equipped to tackle
Speaker 6:  misinformation as a completely by myself at the current moment. And so
Speaker 6:  in in V one of the bias, we are not attempting to tackle
Speaker 6:  the veracity of information. We're attempting to tackle different opinions
Speaker 6:  on different sides of the political spectrum.
Speaker 2:  That strikes me as a tiny bit of a cop out. But honestly also
Speaker 2:  the right call, the vexed nevas goal is to match what Google and Bing
Speaker 2:  and others are doing right now to push to be as authoritative and correct
Speaker 2:  as they are without trying to reinvent the wheel and solve everything all
Speaker 2:  at once after playing with it for a few days. Something about
Speaker 2:  Nevas bias Buster does feel valuable to me and I'm clearly
Speaker 2:  not the only one over the years lots of folks have tried to figure out how
Speaker 2:  to do this kind of thing in a responsible way, exposing users to new
Speaker 2:  ideas and sources without just causing flame wars seems good,
Speaker 2:  right? But still I come back to this idea, is this a problem
Speaker 2:  worth solving? While there are such bigger ones out there,
Speaker 2:  I'm torn on all of this, but luckily the verges Addie Robertson
Speaker 2:  has been paying attention to this kind of speech issue a lot longer than
Speaker 2:  I have. So I figured I'd just call her up and ask
Speaker 2:  Addie, hello, thank you for being here. Hey I don't even have a question
Speaker 2:  for you. Just like tell me, tell me how to feel about tools like this as
Speaker 2:  someone who's been paying attention to this for a long time.
Speaker 9:  On one hand I think anything that lets you filter and sort information is
Speaker 9:  kind of just a good, I think that's, it's neat from that perspective. I think
Speaker 9:  also you kind of wanna be clear-eyed about its limitations though. So the
Speaker 9:  first thing I think of is that this doesn't really control for a super
Speaker 9:  key issue in search bias, which is your input. Mm. So
Speaker 9:  as a scholar, Francesca Tripodi who's done a lot of work on this, which is
Speaker 9:  that the way you phrase a keyword or the topic that you're dealing
Speaker 9:  with, they're just inherently different ways that different sites cover that
Speaker 9:  information. So if you, in her example you put in immigrant
Speaker 9:  voting rights, then it doesn't matter how far right you slide the
Speaker 9:  spectrum, there's gonna be a lot more coverage on the left because that's
Speaker 9:  just how the issue is framed and how interesting that's written about. Whereas
Speaker 9:  if you write illegal immigrants voting, then you're just gonna get something
Speaker 9:  that's inherently right biased, because that's not terminology that you know,
Speaker 9:  the New York Times or Mother Jones is gonna use. And the same
Speaker 9:  token, like there are topics that just, there's one side of the political
Speaker 9:  spectrum that's gonna write a billion essays and news stories about them
Speaker 9:  like I don't know, Hunter Biden's laptop and others that they're gonna cover
Speaker 9:  them but there's just not that, not as much data there.
Speaker 2:  That's super interesting cause I'm now thinking about the way I tested this
Speaker 2:  and, and a lot of that has been very sort of generic, right? You searched
Speaker 2:  terms like inflation and Joe Biden and midterms
Speaker 2:  2022 and I think some of that is like how people use the internet, but for
Speaker 2:  the most part it is the stuff you're describing. It's like here's a story
Speaker 2:  about Hunter Biden's laptop. And so you Google Hunter Biden's laptop and
Speaker 2:  just by virtue of looking for that thing, there are places like the New York
Speaker 2:  Post has covered Hunter Biden's laptop to like the N
Speaker 2:  degree. So just by definition you're more likely to get stuff with that kind
Speaker 2:  of bias just because of the fact that you're searching for that thing with
Speaker 2:  those words,
Speaker 9:  Right? And there's some stories where it's just, there's almost a complete
Speaker 9:  data void on one side of the spectrum because this is kinda the problem with
Speaker 9:  describing any news coverage as objective, which is that
Speaker 9:  the stories you decide to cover are sort of inherently from a
Speaker 9:  viewpoint. So that's the first thing. The second thing is that I think that
Speaker 9:  it is increasingly limited to describe the political spectrum as left versus
Speaker 9:  right. That I think there's a lot of intersection now between
Speaker 9:  say issues that matter to the left and issues that matter to the
Speaker 9:  right. They're just motivated by different things and
Speaker 9:  framed sometimes in a different way. And I think that a lot of the sources
Speaker 9:  there are also, from what you've described, they seem like
Speaker 9:  sort of a kind of well known subset of sources. So yes, maybe, you
Speaker 9:  know, you usually don't watch Fox News or read Fox News and you're gonna
Speaker 9:  get more Fox News, but you're not really gonna burst the bubble
Speaker 9:  of a specific subset of media. Like you're not as
Speaker 9:  far as I can tell, going to get, you know, unicorn riot results from
Speaker 9:  like a leftist collective, right? Like you're gonna get
Speaker 9:  things that are still pretty firmly within a specific media bubble.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Well and that's one of the things I've been thinking a lot about too
Speaker 2:  is like I wound up sort of deep down this rabbit hole of these
Speaker 2:  companies that rate media bias and it ends up setting
Speaker 2:  up this weird dichotomy where like I've talked to a lot of people over the
Speaker 2:  years who say like, you know, I watch Fox News for one side of the political
Speaker 2:  spectrum and I watch CNN for the other side of the political spectrum and
Speaker 2:  I sort of get the impulse, but like I would not, I would not agree with the
Speaker 2:  assertion that those are like equal but opposite platforms. And
Speaker 2:  then it's like, okay, what is the like left version of Brightbart? And it
Speaker 2:  just ends up in this like really messy, complicated head space where like
Speaker 2:  these things are not equally weighted. And I think even the idea that there
Speaker 2:  is like a centrist take on everything is not true anymore. And then we
Speaker 2:  wound up down this crazy road of like, is Qan a political question? Like
Speaker 2:  is the earth flat a political question? And I don't know, this is just where
Speaker 2:  my head starts to spin about like where does truth versus
Speaker 2:  fiction and where does right versus left and where does politics versus
Speaker 2:  just nonsense. All of the all these lines feel so blurry that it to
Speaker 2:  me it's like this is a valiant attempt, but I almost wonder like how deep
Speaker 2:  towards that solving the real problems here can a tool actually go?
Speaker 9:  It also kind of cuts against one of the key
Speaker 9:  purposes of a search engine, which is to give you correct information,
Speaker 2:  But then what is correct? This is the world we live in now. None of this
Speaker 2:  makes any sense.
Speaker 9:  But that's the thing is that Google and search engines are comfortable trying
Speaker 9:  to make these judgments for some things. Like if you ask, you know, what
Speaker 9:  year did Snoopy assassinate Abraham Lincoln, which is a real
Speaker 9:  thing that Google at one point had to correct for, they're like, no, this
Speaker 9:  is obviously incorrect. There are things that are just beyond debate
Speaker 9:  and these things were failing if we don't deliver these things.
Speaker 9:  But then I think that as soon as something enters a specific culture war
Speaker 9:  frame, then suddenly people are really afraid to say that something is
Speaker 9:  true.
Speaker 2:  No, I think that's right and I think that question is sort of forever
Speaker 2:  more complicated and from some of the folks I've talked to even talking about
Speaker 2:  this stuff is the bigger sort of more important question, right? It's like
Speaker 2:  we can talk about political bias but only if we sort of exist in this shared
Speaker 2:  reality when we all agree on what is real and true and we don't
Speaker 2:  anymore. And that feels problematic.
Speaker 9:  Yes. And there are a lot of ways to frame stories that evolve
Speaker 9:  agreeing with specific baseline facts but then just
Speaker 9:  spinning them in a completely different way. Like if you read the New York
Speaker 9:  Times versus Fox, even if the facts are right, you can come away
Speaker 9:  with a really different impression, but that's still to some extent, that's
Speaker 9:  just a matter of opinion. And I think that that is clearly
Speaker 9:  distinguishable from sites that just say very clearly wrong
Speaker 9:  factual things with no backup.
Speaker 2:  Right. This is helpful. This makes me feel to it. We need to take a break,
Speaker 2:  but you should stick around because I wanna spend a bunch of time talking
Speaker 2:  about your story about the First Amendment. Do you have few more minutes
Speaker 2:  you wanna hang out? I do. Okay, cool. We will be right back.
Speaker 2:  We're back. Addie still here. Thank you for stick around Addie. Yeah. Hey.
Speaker 2:  Okay, so I want to talk about this, this big story you wrote called How America
Speaker 2:  Turned Against the First Amendment and I wrote down the way I would
Speaker 2:  summarize the thesis of your piece and I wanna know if how good a job I did
Speaker 2:  summarizing the thesis of your piece. You ready? Yeah. Okay. My summary of
Speaker 2:  the thesis of your piece is basically because a bunch of politicians
Speaker 2:  and people on both sides of the aisle want to score political points by capitalizing
Speaker 2:  on the backlash against big tech. They are using Section two 30 as
Speaker 2:  a wedge through which they can stick government speech regulation into the
Speaker 2:  internet. And that's a huge problem and an actual threat to the First Amendment,
Speaker 2:  which guarantees free speech. And even if we acknowledge all of that to
Speaker 2:  be true and agree that it's bad, our legal system basically is not
Speaker 2:  equipped to handle it. How's that? How'd I do?
Speaker 9:  That's pretty fair. Yeah. Yes. At the absolute broadest level it's that
Speaker 9:  everyone claims to love the First Amendment by everyone. I'm a Muslim talking
Speaker 9:  about politicians in courts and then they increasingly just try to
Speaker 9:  undercut it by claiming a bunch of other things that are not First Amendment
Speaker 9:  related are somehow creating problems, right?
Speaker 9:  And so they are using all these things as smoke screens to kind of get around.
Speaker 9:  Really what they want to do is change what speech is legal.
Speaker 2:  You point out that it's basically politically ridiculous to say you don't
Speaker 2:  like the First Amendment. Like just no one would do that in America to say
Speaker 2:  I am against free speech is just political suicide. And
Speaker 2:  yet to come out and say, you know, we should be moderating
Speaker 2:  these companies, I'm, we're banning books, we have all these issues, picking
Speaker 2:  the fight with big tech and in these specific ways seems to work in a
Speaker 2:  way that's saying I'm against free. Speech doesn't work. Why is
Speaker 2:  that?
Speaker 9:  Part of the issue is that free speech in the First Amendment are kind of
Speaker 9:  different things that the First Amendment is the specific legal
Speaker 9:  doctrine that says that the government cannot do this thing
Speaker 9:  and has been interpreted in varying ways over the years. But then free speech
Speaker 9:  also it's this much broader question. And I think that the
Speaker 9:  internet has made it increasingly weird, which is that it's harder and harder
Speaker 9:  to tell what speech and it's harder and harder to tell what is free like
Speaker 9:  in a world say with almost infinite information. If you bury a bunch of
Speaker 9:  speech in a bunch of harassment and weird
Speaker 9:  nonsense is speech meaningfully free? I think that there are really useful
Speaker 9:  intermediary for a lot of people. There is a version of this where it's
Speaker 9:  that a lot of speech in America now is mediated by these corporations.
Speaker 9:  So if you really wanna put your thumb on the scale and make speech,
Speaker 9:  either you want to change the way that these sites work
Speaker 9:  and you want to force them to carry certain information or you want to say
Speaker 9:  that they should ban certain information, but you're not gonna quite say
Speaker 9:  that should be illegal. You're just gonna say it should be really hard to
Speaker 9:  put up that. I think that that's, it's kind of a way to
Speaker 9:  work around the First Amendment and make it kind of meaningless.
Speaker 2:  Right. Okay. So you, you can sort of kneecap the First Amendment without
Speaker 2:  ever actually saying I am against the First Amendment, which is as established
Speaker 2:  a bonkers thing to do.
Speaker 9:  I mean a lot of places in the world don't think it's a bonkers thing to do.
Speaker 9:  A lot of places in the world look at the First Amendment and go, that's ridiculous.
Speaker 9:  Why would you not ban hate speech? Right? But in America it's
Speaker 9:  more or less a foundational principle of just how speech
Speaker 9:  works.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, no, that makes sense. Okay. And then one more concept I want you to
Speaker 2:  explain, because I was actually reading the comments on your story and this
Speaker 2:  came up a bunch and there was a bunch of debate about it. And I think it's
Speaker 2:  one of the things about Section two 30 specifically that people willfully
Speaker 2:  or otherwise misunderstand a lot, which is that what Section two 30 does
Speaker 2:  is actually allow companies to moderate their platforms, not
Speaker 2:  forces them to be neutral, not forces them to have one
Speaker 2:  specific point of view. It allows them to do the things that a lot of people
Speaker 2:  are actually asking them to do. And that's a good thing. Can you just
Speaker 2:  explain how that actually operates? Like what, what does Section two 30 allow
Speaker 2:  these companies to do that is good and useful and valuable
Speaker 9:  If you are a regular vergecast listener? Maybe you already know this, but
Speaker 9:  the reason section two 30 exists is that there were these two cases
Speaker 9:  involving I think libel that were involving these two
Speaker 9:  separate companies, like very early internet service providers.
Speaker 9:  And one of these places did not moderate things, it was just this free
Speaker 9:  for all and somebody said something that was illegal and defamatory and
Speaker 9:  somebody sued over it. And then the other one was trying to be family friendly.
Speaker 9:  It was actively moderating things. It was looking at this content and then
Speaker 9:  someone also said something illegally defamatory allegedly.
Speaker 9:  And they got sued. And the principle at that point, the
Speaker 9:  way that courts decided it was thinking, all right, let's compare this to
Speaker 9:  a bookstore or a newspaper. And let's say that
Speaker 9:  you cannot reasonably expect somebody who runs a big bookstore to have read
Speaker 9:  literally every book that's ridiculous. They're just these sellers, they,
Speaker 9:  they don't really have a a great knowledge of everything that's in
Speaker 9:  here. So they shouldn't be responsible for selling it. But say if you're
Speaker 9:  a newspaper and you're publishing a thing and you're just curating absolutely
Speaker 9:  everything, then you have control over this, but
Speaker 9:  you should be responsible for it. And then they looked at this in the context
Speaker 9:  of the internet and went, Wait, this is actually really counterproductive
Speaker 9:  because what it says is that if you bother to figure out
Speaker 9:  what's going on on your site and make it better, then we're gonna punish
Speaker 9:  you for it by saying that you are responsible for anything illegal that happens.
Speaker 9:  And what is illegal is often not clear, especially with speech law
Speaker 9:  that something that is defamatory, you actually have these
Speaker 9:  really long complicated legal cases about it. And so it's very, very hard
Speaker 9:  for a website to make something that is a judgment
Speaker 9:  that often courts have trouble making. And so Section two 30 basically says
Speaker 9:  that you are allowed to run your site how you want and you don't
Speaker 9:  have to deal with trying to figure out what's legal and illegal with some
Speaker 9:  exceptions.
Speaker 2:  And that flip side would be, and I think this is, this is the concept that
Speaker 2:  it took me a really long time to wrap my head around and I think it's hard
Speaker 2:  for a lot of people is that the flip side would be that the expedient
Speaker 2:  thing for all these companies to do would be to just bury their head in the
Speaker 2:  sand and not try because then you have plausible deniability that says, Oh
Speaker 2:  we didn't even know this was here. It's horrible. We're so sorry you
Speaker 2:  can't sue us about we, we didn't know we didn't do it.
Speaker 9:  Right. It's basically saying you're an internet service provider, whatever
Speaker 9:  you're we're dumb pipes, we do nothing here to moderate. And so it
Speaker 9:  incentivizes either way too much moderation or none at all.
Speaker 2:  Right? Exactly. What a lot of people perceive is that without Section two
Speaker 2:  30 these companies would be forced to do a really, really, really, really
Speaker 2:  good job of moderating. And I think the actual
Speaker 2:  reality of the fact is that it's impossible to do it
Speaker 2:  well enough without section two 30, if not impossible. It is like
Speaker 2:  massively difficult to do it well enough without Section two 30 to be
Speaker 2:  like legally safe. So the easy response then would
Speaker 2:  be to do absolutely nothing and just turn the blindest possible eye to
Speaker 2:  everything happening and just let chaos rain. And that is what companies
Speaker 2:  would do rather than actually invest the like astronomical
Speaker 2:  resources you would have to in order to do this successfully.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. And on their do it really well side I think in helpful comparison
Speaker 9:  here is that one of the things that Section two 30 doesn't protect in the
Speaker 9:  same way as everything else is copyrighted information is piracy.
Speaker 9:  So there distinct laws in the Digital Millennium Copyright Act,
Speaker 9:  you have to actually make this serious effort to try to take down
Speaker 9:  copyrighted stuff that's being put up illegally. No one
Speaker 9:  likes this on the internet. The internet is full of stories about saying,
Speaker 9:  look how, look how terrible YouTube deals with this. Like look at
Speaker 9:  the fact that it takes down, you know, bird songs because it thinks the bird
Speaker 9:  songs are copyrighted. People typically do not think that this situation
Speaker 9:  has turned out well in the way that they often wanna try to make it
Speaker 9:  work for other pieces of content. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  And it, if it's possible to do this successfully, we certainly
Speaker 2:  have never seen it. Right. And like Facebook has, has talked about this forever.
Speaker 2:  They're like, we invest more resources into this than anybody. Like wasn't
Speaker 2:  it Facebook that said like, our moderation staff is the size of Twitter.
Speaker 2:  Like it's, it's just crazy. They put all these resources into it and they
Speaker 2:  still have this like earth shattering gigantic set of problems. Yeah.
Speaker 9:  The only consistent answer I have heard for this is that if you're not able
Speaker 9:  to moderate, well you should not exist at this scale that you do. Which I
Speaker 9:  think is kind of the only feasible and consistent way to say this. And
Speaker 9:  I'm not sure a lot of people wanna go there.
Speaker 2:  Right? That changes I think a lot more than people realize if that ends up
Speaker 2:  being the decision that a lot of these folks have to make. But okay, let's
Speaker 2:  go back to the speech thing because one of the things that I think underlies
Speaker 2:  a lot of your story is this idea that there is
Speaker 2:  a bunch of sneaky political maneuvering going on here and
Speaker 2:  it's hard to sort out what is an actual desire for government
Speaker 2:  speech regulation versus what is sort of a, a political
Speaker 2:  response to the cultural backlash against big tech versus
Speaker 2:  what is just a bunch of relatively out of touch politicians not
Speaker 2:  understanding the unique challenges of the internet. Am I, am I
Speaker 2:  describing the jumble there correctly? Do you, do you feel like one of those
Speaker 2:  things is a bigger push for some of what's happening here?
Speaker 9:  Yeah, I think that's right. Part of this is people maybe genuinely not understanding
Speaker 9:  the internet. Part of this is people identifying real problems with the internet
Speaker 9:  and wanting them to work differently, but in ways that conflict with a
Speaker 9:  lot of basic American law. And then part of it is what I would just call
Speaker 9:  bad faith. Okay. I don't like to assume that, but it's really hard to look
Speaker 9:  at a lot of these projects and see anything except I don't like the
Speaker 9:  way that these companies work politically and I don't like whether or not
Speaker 9:  they take down things that I like and so I'm gonna work the
Speaker 9:  refs and I'm going to punish them.
Speaker 2:  Right? And that's where you see things like the laws in Florida and Texas,
Speaker 2:  right? And I feel like when you look at these like blanket social media moderation
Speaker 2:  bands, it feels very hard to assign anything other than bad faith to those
Speaker 2:  at this point.
Speaker 9:  And is, they're very, very clear about their purpose. That they're all, they
Speaker 9:  start with these preambles about isn't it really terrible that big tech is
Speaker 9:  censoring Republicans? Which there are, I think it was the Florida
Speaker 9:  decision starts with just saying there's the First amendment does
Speaker 9:  not protect you specifically having your particular
Speaker 9:  ideology included on something which is like, I
Speaker 9:  don't want to go too far with this. Like there obviously the First
Speaker 9:  Amendment means that you should not try to create laws that
Speaker 9:  censor specific viewpoints, but the fact that a private company
Speaker 9:  is doing something that ends up incidentally
Speaker 9:  causing collateral damage, that it's not even clear if it disproportionately
Speaker 9:  affects Republicans, they remove a ton of content. That in
Speaker 9:  itself is not inherently a First Amendment problem.
Speaker 9:  Like there's a situation where maybe it would be, but it's not enough.
Speaker 2:  There's a back and forth that you just described that I think is super interesting.
Speaker 2:  Cause like we, we are reporters, which I think probably by definition is
Speaker 2:  going to make us pro-free speech people, right? Like it is better to do the
Speaker 2:  job that we do in a, in a world where free speech is protected, we
Speaker 2:  also just like believe in it generally. And I I I knowing you for a
Speaker 2:  long time, you are a, a free speech person more than most. I would, I would
Speaker 2:  say please correct me if I'm wrong on
Speaker 9:  That. That's fair. Yeah, that's fair.
Speaker 2:  But it's also true, I think, and I think you'll agree with this, that we
Speaker 2:  both sit here and say there are things that happen on social media that are
Speaker 2:  bad and wouldn't it be great if they didn't happen? And so I think how
Speaker 2:  to look at those two things simultaneously and sort of part of this, I guess
Speaker 2:  is just like acknowledging that the world is complicated and you can't have
Speaker 2:  it both ways all the time. But to look at it and say
Speaker 2:  these are places that people live a lot of their lives and we
Speaker 2:  have entered into like a, a style of conversation that like we as
Speaker 2:  humans are clearly not ready for. And we probably do need it to work slightly
Speaker 2:  differently than it is, but also to change these things in these fundamental
Speaker 2:  ways, break this other thing that we believe in really strongly. I don't
Speaker 2:  know, do you just like sit here and wrestle between those two things all
Speaker 2:  the time in your head? Because it feels like I have to do that more and more
Speaker 2:  all the time.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. Oh God, yes. Mostly in two ways. The first is trying to figure out
Speaker 9:  what a speech which was part of the piece. Yeah. Which is that if you just
Speaker 9:  say anything that runs in code is speech then, like Airbnb is speech,
Speaker 9:  like Amazon selling poison is speech,
Speaker 2:  Right? And there's some real legal evidence that that is speech, right? Like
Speaker 2:  that is, that is a definition some people really adhere to, right?
Speaker 9:  And in some places it's complicated. Like if Amazon recommends you buy something,
Speaker 9:  is that speech like maybe, I don't know. But it feels kind of wrong to say
Speaker 9:  that if it happens on the internet, it has to be speech that feels like it
Speaker 9:  just cuts against the intent of the First Amendment, which is that
Speaker 9:  expressing ideas is, I mean, among, among other parts of the
Speaker 9:  First Amendment that is important.
Speaker 2:  My idea is that you should buy toilet paper. That is my, that's my political
Speaker 2:  belief.
Speaker 9:  My idea is literally selling you toilet paper. My idea is goods and
Speaker 9:  services like that feels weird. And then the other part of it is the
Speaker 9:  legalism of what does speech law say and the practical
Speaker 9:  aspects of like what is actually letting people speak like
Speaker 9:  a world where you can say anything, but it's
Speaker 9:  literally impossible for anyone to find it because it's buried under huge
Speaker 9:  amounts of harassment that just feels like it also doesn't fit the spirit
Speaker 9:  of the law. Like a world where you can say something,
Speaker 9:  but the internet also makes it incredibly easy to
Speaker 9:  retaliate against you and to make you afraid for your life. That
Speaker 9:  also, that doesn't really work either. Like if there's a world where
Speaker 9:  the law makes sense and the law is consistent, but I don't wanna get
Speaker 9:  in a position where there, if the law isn't doing the thing that it's supposed
Speaker 9:  to, what is the point of the law? Right.
Speaker 2:  Well, yeah, one of the questions that comes up about the internet in a, in
Speaker 2:  a lot of ways is are the worries about the internet different
Speaker 2:  than some of the things in the past, right? Everybody says, you know, there
Speaker 2:  was a moral panic about newspapers and there was a moral panic about radio
Speaker 2:  and there was a moral panic about television. It's like all these things
Speaker 2:  are true. But it does seem like, and especially to your, your point
Speaker 2:  like the scale of the internet does seem different and it
Speaker 2:  seems like politically and legally that's been an incredibly
Speaker 2:  hard thing to keep up with that like it's, it's cross borders,
Speaker 2:  it's more people, it's just happening at such great
Speaker 2:  pace that it does, even if we haven't yet perfectly
Speaker 2:  defined why it's different, it feels like a different question about
Speaker 2:  speech. Like you go back and the newspapers all said crazy shit about
Speaker 2:  each other and most of it was nonsense because it was all politically motivated
Speaker 2:  and the first Amendment allowed that to happen, right? Like that was not
Speaker 2:  different e even though some people were mad about it. But there is something
Speaker 2:  about the speed and scale of which it's happening now
Speaker 2:  and especially that it's concentrated into these couple of platforms across
Speaker 2:  the, the world that makes it feel different. Like is that part of why this
Speaker 2:  is so much harder for anyone to wrap their heads around just because it's
Speaker 2:  so much bigger now?
Speaker 9:  Yeah, and I have always have trouble with this because among other
Speaker 9:  things, you know, I'm, I'm not 150 years old, but I think it's also that
Speaker 9:  every new medium has created problems and trade offs that people have had
Speaker 9:  to deal with. Sure. Like radio, it's, I think a lot of people
Speaker 9:  accept radio was one of the things that helped Nazis grow,
Speaker 9:  that radio helped instigate the genocide in Rwanda. That
Speaker 9:  radio really all of these things have caused terrible problems
Speaker 9:  that it's just that we decided that speech was important
Speaker 9:  enough and that this technology did enough good things that
Speaker 9:  it's worth those trade-offs and that really any
Speaker 9:  kind of technology is going to create a set of trade-offs and we have to
Speaker 9:  evaluate those. And so I think the internet has a bunch of distinct problems
Speaker 9:  that a lot of these things didn't have. And the internet has a bunch of
Speaker 9:  opportunities that these things didn't create. I don't know, I think one
Speaker 9:  of the issues is that coming, just coming back to what is speech on the internet,
Speaker 9:  that I think there's a world where our lives like, you know, our bank
Speaker 9:  account information and our physical addresses and
Speaker 9:  there are specific other things that we just decide we're cording off that
Speaker 9:  those aren't going to take place in this world where we also just argue
Speaker 9:  with each other all the time because arguing with each other all the time
Speaker 9:  sometimes has value. But it also, I think that when our
Speaker 9:  entire lives are consumed by it and it's incredibly frictionless
Speaker 9:  to tie that to people's real safety that starts getting really difficult.
Speaker 2:  Okay, so before I let you go, let's come back to these laws in Florida and
Speaker 2:  Texas because it feels like in, in the legal system, which has, I think
Speaker 2:  historically as you point out, not done a great job of figuring out how any
Speaker 2:  of this stuff should work. Those two laws, one of them seems like it is probably
Speaker 2:  gonna end up in front of the Supreme Court, right? So we're gonna get this
Speaker 2:  big reckoning about what the government can do to social media and how
Speaker 2:  we feel about speech and moderation and like this is gonna get its moment
Speaker 2:  in the true sun, right? That's coming it feels like.
Speaker 9:  Yeah, almost certainly. And there's, there's also another case that's gonna
Speaker 9:  reevaluate parts of section two 30 that's already come up. But yeah,
Speaker 9:  it, there's gonna be a reckoning.
Speaker 2:  Are you, are you hopeful, terrified nihilists, who
Speaker 2:  cares? Burn it all down somewhere in the middle? How are you feeling about
Speaker 2:  all of that?
Speaker 9:  The people I've talked to are maybe more hopeful than I had expected
Speaker 9:  that they point to that there's still five Supreme court justices
Speaker 9:  that looked at the Texas law and went, you should not be able to enforce
Speaker 9:  that of the four that did not vote for it. It's, there's really only one
Speaker 9:  who seems very, very clearly weird about it
Speaker 9:  and anti the thing we would describe as free speech, which is
Speaker 9:  Clarence Thomas. And so I guess I want to take hard in that
Speaker 9:  I am also just increasingly worried about the
Speaker 9:  legitimacy of courts in general and the way that any
Speaker 9:  part of civic life in America functions. And so I think speech is part
Speaker 9:  of that and that is not encouraging.
Speaker 2:  So reading your piece, it's very hard for me to not end up in this like
Speaker 2:  deep, we're all screwed, everything's a disaster. It's all totally
Speaker 2:  hopeless, nobody knows anything. This is gonna get worse before it gets better
Speaker 2:  place. What does the hope or reason for optimism look
Speaker 2:  like? Do we have a path toward figuring out how to handle this in a way that
Speaker 2:  actually makes logical sense? Or are things about to change in bigger, more
Speaker 2:  fundamental ways than they even have so far? Cause it feels like one of those
Speaker 2:  has to be the case.
Speaker 9:  Oh, optimism is the thing that I am the worst at.
Speaker 9:  But I don't know, I think that there are people who are, even if I disagree
Speaker 9:  with them on some points, really seriously considering those issues. There
Speaker 9:  are people like Daniel Citron who is proposed changes to two 30
Speaker 9:  that I don't necessarily again agree with, but that I think are really thoughtful.
Speaker 9:  So I think that if you listen to a lot of these people and if you really
Speaker 9:  try to identify the tradeoffs and try to figure out where we wanna make changes,
Speaker 9:  if we do, I think that is where I would pin my hope is
Speaker 9:  people who look at these problems and are willing to seriously
Speaker 9:  admit where the problems in tradeoffs in what we think of as American
Speaker 9:  free speech are and try to figure out what you do about
Speaker 9:  them. Like I think specificity is maybe the way I
Speaker 9:  think things may get better.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Well and to that point, actually, one of the things I thought was really
Speaker 2:  interesting about the way you described the Texas Florida laws is they're
Speaker 2:  so like hysterically broad that I think the point you
Speaker 2:  made was that it would make it illegal to reject
Speaker 2:  changes on Wikipedia based on Wikipedia's own community standards.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. This is, it applies to large websites and it applies
Speaker 9:  to anything that involves viewpoints. And I mean, I don't know, maybe they'd
Speaker 9:  sue and maybe they'd discover that it's not part of the law, but who knows
Speaker 9:  because the law is terribly written. Right?
Speaker 2:  Yeah, that's fair. So specificity is a good thing, but I, it also feels like
Speaker 2:  this stuff has become so black and white for so many people that it's like
Speaker 2:  section two 30 in particular is like you're, you're either, you're either
Speaker 2:  in it or you're out on it. And I, I'm increasingly wondering if there is
Speaker 2:  even a middle ground that we're gonna find. But it sounds like maybe somewhere
Speaker 2:  there is one.
Speaker 9:  I think there are corners. Okay. I don't know if it's a middle ground because
Speaker 9:  I don't even know if the middle is really where we want to be fair. But
Speaker 9:  I think that there are pockets of people who are
Speaker 9:  serious and I just wanna try to grow those pockets.
Speaker 2:  I like it. Well thank you add, I appreciate it.
Speaker 2:  All right, we need to take a quick break and then when we come back we're
Speaker 2:  gonna talk to the verges McKenna Kelly about the chips and sciences bill
Speaker 2:  that was passed over the summer and what that bill and all of the billions
Speaker 2:  of dollars that come from it mean for the future of chip manufacturing
Speaker 2:  and the tech industry as a whole. We'll be right back.
Speaker 14:  Fox Creative.
Speaker 15:  This is advertiser content from Amazon ads.
Speaker 16:  Take another deep breath in and on. Exhale,
Speaker 16:  relax your shoulders.
Speaker 13:  I think this meditation series is really helping
Speaker 13:  the
Speaker 17:  Brimstone and steel tour is coming to a city near you.
Speaker 13:  Seriously.
Speaker 15:  A misplaced ad can really ruin an experience according to research
Speaker 15:  commissioned by Amazon Ads and Omnicom Media Group. 68% of
Speaker 15:  consumers prefer ads that are relevant to the content they're embedded in.
Speaker 15:  It can be important for brands to be part of the experience not interrupted
Speaker 15:  At Amazon ads, we make it easier for brands to reach the right audience.
Speaker 15:  Like when they're listening to Amazon Music's ad supported tier on an Alexa
Speaker 15:  enabled device. Getting you more of this
Speaker 16:  Calming essentials, Lavender Royal promotes relaxation
Speaker 16:  and melts your stress away. Just say, Alexa,
Speaker 16:  add to cart to have calming essentials. Lavender Royal
Speaker 16:  delivered to your door.
Speaker 13:  Alexa, add to cart.
Speaker 15:  Learn more at vox.com/museum of Modern Ads.
Speaker 18:  Hey it's Kenny Mae. I'm the host of Haman. The Kenny Mae talks to famous
Speaker 18:  people, podcasts, season ones out there in the universe. You can go back
Speaker 18:  in time, find anybody you want as long as I interviewed them.
Speaker 18:  Season two is coming up Thursday, October 13th. We've
Speaker 18:  got Keith Overman and Dan Patrick together again. Sue Bird is
Speaker 18:  involved. Rex Chapman, Dan Levard, Katie Nolan,
Speaker 18:  Allison Becker. Sorry for all the others I interviewed who I left out. Oh
Speaker 18:  yeah, Solo O' Brunch. She was good. Get it on the Odyssey app or wherever
Speaker 18:  you get your podcast.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. So on August 9th of this year, President Joe
Speaker 2:  Biden signed into law the Chips and Science Act,
Speaker 2:  A 280 billion package meant to invest
Speaker 2:  in American scientific and technological research and progress.
Speaker 2:  Big bill, lots of money, but one of the biggest chunks of that
Speaker 2:  money, 52 billion is specifically meant to boost semiconductor
Speaker 2:  manufacturing in the United States.
Speaker 19:  The future of the chip industry is going to be made in America.
Speaker 2:  This law is a big deal and it could start to reshape not just how
Speaker 2:  chips get made in America, but the whole tech industry in this country.
Speaker 2:  And there are big political consequences in how all of that
Speaker 2:  shakes out. That's what the verges McKenna Kelly has been looking into. She
Speaker 2:  talked to a number of folks over the recent months about the bill and its
Speaker 2:  effects, including New York Senator Chuck Schumer and now she's here to give
Speaker 2:  us the breakdown. Hi McKenna.
Speaker 20:  Hey David. It's great to be here.
Speaker 2:  It's midterm season. Do I need to worry about you like emotionally and
Speaker 2:  spiritually right now? How are you holding up?
Speaker 20:  Honestly, I've been talking to sources all this week and it's always just
Speaker 20:  been like, Hey, how are you? Hope you're staying alive. And
Speaker 20:  they're like, Hope you're staying alive too. Actually I'm dying but we're
Speaker 20:  gonna get through it. This has been a wild one.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I would say so for our purposes today we're gonna talk mostly about
Speaker 2:  the chips and sciences bill, which is like, I think everybody just
Speaker 2:  calls it CHIPS now, right? Like all caps, Chips,
Speaker 20:  Chips. They're yelling this is the best thing to happen to consumer tech
Speaker 20:  in so long chips.
Speaker 2:  Can you put exclamation points in law NAS now it should just say like Chips
Speaker 2:  exclamation point.
Speaker 20:  It might as well be that it took so long to do, everyone was really excited
Speaker 20:  about when it finally got over the the finish line.
Speaker 2:  So okay. And it has these sort of big wide ranging
Speaker 2:  ramifications of like the future of tech in America and geopolitics
Speaker 2:  and all the stuff that I think is really interesting. But the history part
Speaker 2:  of this I think is really interesting cause I was reading your most recent
Speaker 2:  stories about it and realizing that some version of this
Speaker 2:  Bill Chips exclamation point has been in
Speaker 2:  negotiations since 2019, if I'm remembering correctly.
Speaker 2:  So rewind me all the way back to the beginning before the pandemic, before
Speaker 2:  chip shortages and the crazy supply chain stuff we've seen the last couple
Speaker 2:  of years. Like what was this supposed to do in 2019?
Speaker 20:  Right? So this was prior to all that, like you said. And when I was talking
Speaker 20:  to Chuck Schumer, he was talking about the time when he walked into the
Speaker 20:  Senate gym, which is something that exists and
Speaker 20:  he went to do whatever he does, aerobics, weightlifting, I don't
Speaker 20:  know what Schumer does in there
Speaker 21:  Now. I was on the bike panting away and on the bike next to me was a guy
Speaker 21:  Todd Young, a senator from Indiana Republican. And I was talking
Speaker 21:  to him about this and he said, I've had the same anxiety about America
Speaker 21:  losing ground here. Well you gotta do something. And so we agreed to come
Speaker 21:  together and we put together the science in Chips build.
Speaker 20:  He had been looking for some kind of partner to bring, you know, the economic
Speaker 20:  success and you know, funding and money that was, you know,
Speaker 20:  mostly sent to Silicon Valley and like software, Facebook, et cetera,
Speaker 20:  and bring that to, you know, more industrial parts of the United States.
Speaker 20:  We've seen a lot of industries fail over the past 20 years. There's
Speaker 20:  been a change in, you know, what people buy, where things are
Speaker 20:  manufactured. The auto industry in Detroit is a very good example of a place
Speaker 20:  that could really benefit from that kind of money. But there's all of this
Speaker 20:  land, talk about Syracuse, New York, talk about Detroit, talk
Speaker 20:  about Idaho, Ohio that has been a manufacturing epicenter
Speaker 20:  for the United States, but with a lot of things going overseas
Speaker 20:  in manufacturing businesses, I think Schumer and a lot of folks are thinking
Speaker 20:  about how can we readjust our manufacturing sector in
Speaker 20:  a way that positions the United States in a
Speaker 20:  competitive way for the next, you know, 50 years. And they targeted chips,
Speaker 20:  which is something that the US used to do really well, but has become ever
Speaker 20:  more, you know, necessary in literally every product that we
Speaker 20:  have. Like when I was talking to Schumer, my favorite thing, I opened it
Speaker 20:  up asking him if he was using his flip phone, which he infamously uses a
Speaker 20:  flip phone still
Speaker 2:  Amazing.
Speaker 21:  Let me tell you my flip phone, people ask with a 50
Speaker 21:  50 majority, how do you get things done? And
Speaker 21:  I am talking into it, my flip phone, every senator, Democratic
Speaker 21:  senator and some Republicans have my phone number, they talk to me
Speaker 21:  directly. They don't go through staff, they don't do email. And it's a way
Speaker 21:  you can weave a coalition together.
Speaker 20:  Everything from like dumb tech, flip phones, you know, when it comes to
Speaker 20:  refrigerators, things like that, all the way to like artificial
Speaker 20:  intelligence, advanced computing, all of these things rely on these semiconductor
Speaker 20:  chips. And I think that's why Schumer and everyone really targeted that
Speaker 20:  sector for this bill.
Speaker 2:  And obviously like the, the sort of underlying theme of a
Speaker 2:  lot of that is China, right? That like there is very much this like global
Speaker 2:  thing happening, but so much of it is concentrated in China. And it feels
Speaker 2:  like over the last, I don't know a long time, but especially kind of over
Speaker 2:  the course of the Trump administration and into the Biden administration,
Speaker 2:  China has become a big focus in like remembering how to
Speaker 2:  compete with China and not be so reliant on China. Like was it about
Speaker 2:  China the whole time,
Speaker 20:  Right? I, I think the first name of the bill before, of course this
Speaker 20:  is just these bills change, the text changes, the names change. The first
Speaker 20:  one was like the Endless Frontier Act. Oh boy. And it had very much to do
Speaker 20:  with competitiveness with China.
Speaker 21:  I've been for a long time worried that America's losing ground
Speaker 21:  on investments in science and in high end manufacturing and
Speaker 21:  the union of the two. And that if we continued to lose ground,
Speaker 21:  our economy would suffer. If a more authoritarian country
Speaker 21:  like China got ahead of us, they could set the rules, which wouldn't
Speaker 21:  be in the open, entrepreneurial free market way that we
Speaker 21:  like to do things here in America. And that we would suffer in many
Speaker 21:  different ways.
Speaker 20:  So much of American manufacturing has gone overseas that leads to the
Speaker 20:  United States, right? In an anti-competitive advantage. If supply chains
Speaker 20:  fail, if you know for some reason down the line China becomes, you
Speaker 20:  know, a major economic hegemonic
Speaker 20:  right power. And so it's getting to that, you know, national security risk
Speaker 20:  concern about being able to, I guess, you know, American
Speaker 20:  excellence, all that stuff, and national security, right? So chips
Speaker 20:  of course with their military necessity and then also just like daily
Speaker 20:  life, they've become such an, an important factor and such an
Speaker 20:  important piece of equipment for the US to have
Speaker 2:  This seems like what you're describing would be the kind of thing that almost
Speaker 2:  every American politician would immediately get behind, right? Like it's
Speaker 2:  pro America, it's pro-business, everybody wins. We get to
Speaker 2:  yell about, you know, nationalism and America being great and the future
Speaker 2:  and technology, and yet there was this massive political battle
Speaker 2:  that made this thing take forever. Walk me through a little
Speaker 2:  bit of that, like what was the big fight about in getting this bill actually
Speaker 2:  done.
Speaker 20:  Let me work our way from beginning to end here. At first, of course, it
Speaker 20:  was 2019, there was an election coming up, the 2020 election.
Speaker 22:  All the productive activity in the Congress is coming out of
Speaker 22:  the house. The Senate remains a legislative graveyard
Speaker 22:  for so many different issues. Now on impeachment
Speaker 2:  This literally feels like ancient history that you're describing. I
Speaker 20:  Know you
Speaker 2:  Didn't think that it's crazy.
Speaker 20:  It wasn't necessarily a priority at the time. And then of course
Speaker 20:  that also comes down to well who is this going to benefit? You know, when
Speaker 20:  it comes to a senator, they want to bring stuff home to their constituency
Speaker 20:  to be like, Hey, I got you jobs in this bill. So there's a little bit
Speaker 20:  of discussion back and forth on that to make sure that, you know, this benefits
Speaker 20:  everyone's state, majority of folks and then of course slows down
Speaker 20:  2020 election and then the pandemic hits, right?
Speaker 20:  And all of a sudden it is impossible
Speaker 20:  to get your hands on consumer tech goods. And then of course, like
Speaker 20:  just semiconductors period. Like look, when we were in the middle of the
Speaker 20:  pandemic, gosh, it's like, it's so weird to think back to 2020, but at the
Speaker 20:  time, do you remember when like you couldn't get an Invidia graphics card?
Speaker 20:  Oh yeah. Do you remember when like the PS five, you couldn't get that. Yeah.
Speaker 20:  Like this was, all that stuff was rolling out at the same time when people
Speaker 20:  were stuck inside. So we have all these new products, people stuck inside,
Speaker 20:  people working from home, maybe investing in new laptops, investing in tablets,
Speaker 20:  investing in all of this tech equipment. And so demand
Speaker 20:  surges, but supply chains break because of, you
Speaker 20:  know, covid restrictions and things like that. So it became this absolute
Speaker 20:  explosion of just became an explosion of mess, right? That all
Speaker 20:  of a sudden you needed to clean up. And I think that's why, you know, it
Speaker 20:  got to be 2020 and then the bill really got a lot of folks behind it.
Speaker 20:  And, but of course it wasn't until this year that it was actually passed,
Speaker 2:  Was it less about everybody picking fights about this bill and more about
Speaker 2:  it just being maybe not the most immediately
Speaker 2:  important thing as we were dealing with all of this other stuff going on
Speaker 2:  in the world.
Speaker 20:  It's a confluence of there's so much going on. Okay. I mean cuz
Speaker 20:  look like, look at what else the Senate did and like Congress did during
Speaker 20:  the pandemic, it was they were passing the bipartisan infrastructure
Speaker 20:  law. Remember when we got sent money? Yeah. Like they were fighting
Speaker 20:  over that, you know? And so that was happening and then it's also like a
Speaker 20:  confluence of that factor, but also the fact that everyone wants
Speaker 20:  something in this, right? You have the Ohio lawmakers who are like, we have
Speaker 20:  all this land, we need jobs, we wanna be resilient in the future.
Speaker 20:  Let's make sure that this gets everyone equipped. And I think the important
Speaker 20:  thing there, I think something we don't talk about the bill enough of course
Speaker 20:  is like subsidies for like the chip manufacturers, but it also includes
Speaker 20:  money through the commerce department for states and localities to make
Speaker 20:  pitches for funding to create these national tech hubs which
Speaker 20:  lets localities and states fight, you know, and basically
Speaker 20:  pitch to be like, hey, we could use this funding and really make good work
Speaker 20:  with it. Right? And so there was also that, which I think was a part of
Speaker 20:  the negotiations and making sure that everyone is, you know, benefiting
Speaker 20:  from the
Speaker 21:  Bill. We wanted to see parts of the country that had not benefited from
Speaker 21:  advanced manufacturing and science gain. I was thinking of upstate
Speaker 21:  New York, Buffalo, Rochester's, Syracuse, Albany. He
Speaker 21:  was thinking of Indianapolis and Fort Wayne and South Bend and that was
Speaker 21:  another unifying factor for us.
Speaker 2:  I can imagine this got like crazily competitive because everybody's looking
Speaker 2:  at this being like we can be the next Silicon Valley, which everybody has
Speaker 2:  been trying to be for 40 years. And now it feels like there's more money
Speaker 2:  being put to that use kind of than ever, right?
Speaker 20:  Yeah. I mean I'm from Nebraska and I remember it got towards the end of
Speaker 20:  me graduating college and everyone was using the phrase Silicon Prairie.
Speaker 20:  Oh yeah. And so everyone's fighting over, you know, being the next
Speaker 20:  big tech hub. Silicon
Speaker 2:  Slopes was always my favorite for Salt Lake City.
Speaker 20:  Oh I hadn't even heard that one. It
Speaker 2:  Didn't work. Spoiler alert.
Speaker 20:  Right? And so Silicon Valley, you know, of course got all this investment
Speaker 20:  cuz folks are moving there. There was the whole VC craze, it's still going
Speaker 20:  on. You know, this just was kind of like the focus where you went to Silicon
Speaker 20:  Valley if you were interested in tech and now tech has become
Speaker 20:  so, and you know, omnipresent in our lives that it
Speaker 20:  could benefit everyone if they just kind of shake loose.
Speaker 20:  You know the whole Silicon Valley has on the industry.
Speaker 21:  When you need such a huge amount of space for these
Speaker 21:  chip fab companies, you also need adequate water,
Speaker 21:  cheap power. It tends to benefit some areas that
Speaker 21:  hadn't seen those benefits before.
Speaker 20:  And if you have a little bit of subsidizing money, a little bit of incentive
Speaker 20:  to do it, these can crop up everywhere
Speaker 2:  At the end of it. Did everybody get what they want? Did Chuck Schumer get
Speaker 2:  what he wanted? Like who kind of came out ahead in the way that the chips
Speaker 2:  bill actually ended up being written and passed?
Speaker 20:  The corporations
Speaker 2:  Surprise,
Speaker 20:  That's always the way it is. Right? Of course like towards the end of the
Speaker 20:  negotiating phase you had Bernie Sanders somewhere progressive being like,
Speaker 20:  we need some more checks and balances on how this subsidy money is being
Speaker 20:  handed out. Cuz again, like it's touted as this revolutionary thing for
Speaker 20:  the American economy, but who is the money going to? It's going to
Speaker 20:  Intel, it's going to Micron and they're gonna be the ones who see
Speaker 20:  the benefit of this faster than everyone else.
Speaker 20:  And, and we're talking about the midterms, right? This has been something
Speaker 20:  that I've been thinking about a lot cuz a lot of the economic work that
Speaker 20:  the Biden administration has done, whether it's the bipartisan infrastructure
Speaker 20:  law, whether it's the chips bill, all these things take time,
Speaker 20:  you know, to go into effect and they, they do have the ability,
Speaker 20:  you know, to be really revolutionary. But people are really
Speaker 20:  hurting right now. And so as much as we talk about,
Speaker 20:  you know, the benefits of this bill everyday, people aren't seeing it in
Speaker 20:  their pocketbooks right now. And so it's hard to see whether or not it'll
Speaker 20:  have that kind of effect on the voter base.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, there was that amazing Bernie Sanders quote that was basically like,
Speaker 2:  why are so many people in Congress willing to basically bribe intel
Speaker 2:  to stay in the United States?
Speaker 23:  The CEO of a major corporation which made
Speaker 23:  nearly 20 billion in
Speaker 23:  profits last year, is saying to Congress that if you
Speaker 23:  don't give my industry the microchip
Speaker 23:  industry 76 billion, that
Speaker 23:  despite their profound love for our country and
Speaker 23:  their respect for American workers in order to make
Speaker 23:  more profits, they are prepared to go to Europe and Asia. Now as
Speaker 23:  the president, I am thankfully not a lawyer without
Speaker 23:  sure sounds like extortion to me.
Speaker 2:  And that strikes me as a fair criticism, right? Like I think as
Speaker 2:  Pat Gelsinger was on the, the decoder podcast talking about this, that like
Speaker 2:  maybe Intel should have done better if, if
Speaker 2:  Intel wanted to be successful without government intervention, maybe Intel
Speaker 2:  should have been successful without government intervention. And I think
Speaker 2:  there is this funny thing that I feel like this bill is trying to do, which
Speaker 2:  is on the one hand like build new things and prop up new innovation
Speaker 2:  and there's like, there's money for the National Science Foundation I think
Speaker 2:  in there. And so it's, it's like we want to, we wanna start new stuff, but
Speaker 2:  also the lion's share of the money is going to, like you said, this small
Speaker 2:  handful of really big corporations that like Intel
Speaker 2:  didn't do a good job and for not doing a good job, got
Speaker 2:  billions of dollars to stay in the United States and that
Speaker 2:  that seems messy.
Speaker 20:  What else are they going to do? Right? They'll create their manufacturing
Speaker 20:  plants, their fabs and stuff in China, which then of course really hurts
Speaker 20:  the United States. So it's gotten to this point where
Speaker 20:  China has become, we are so reliant yeah. On China
Speaker 20:  for semiconductors and chips and manufacturing that there's no
Speaker 20:  reason for you know, these companies to come back and for the Biden
Speaker 20:  administration, when we talk about how this could take a really long time
Speaker 20:  to be affect, it's probably the fastest way to get this moving. Especially
Speaker 20:  like over the last five years when we've seen, you know, Chinese tech
Speaker 20:  companies, Chinese military, you know, we've seen this rise, this like
Speaker 20:  tension with Taiwan. You know, the Chinese working with a lot of like
Speaker 20:  us adversaries, it's just this feels like a bandaid,
Speaker 20:  a $52 billion bandaid that hopefully
Speaker 20:  heals and hopefully they don't pick the scab, We don't pick the scab off
Speaker 20:  too often and it just like really just, you know, sets in stone and we can
Speaker 20:  get moving on this. But I mean it's, it's hard to tell.
Speaker 2:  Do you think it eventually got done just because this all got so
Speaker 2:  visceral with the chip shortage and the supply chain issues that it like
Speaker 2:  it became really obvious to everyday Americans that this was a thing? I
Speaker 2:  feel like chip supply chains were not a thing that most people were aware
Speaker 2:  of three years ago in a way that I think a lot of people like sort of deeply
Speaker 2:  understand now like I couldn't buy a car because they couldn't get a chip
Speaker 2:  from Taiwan. It's like a thing people understand now in a way that they
Speaker 2:  didn't before. Is that what finally got this across the, the line?
Speaker 2:  Was there some gating thing in the bill that finally got fixed? Like what,
Speaker 2:  what did it at the end?
Speaker 20:  So I was looking at past reporting that even like we did at the version
Speaker 20:  like Sean Hollister was writing at the beginning of this year, the companies
Speaker 20:  were starting to figure it out, right? You were able to get this Nvidia
Speaker 20:  gpu, you're able to get all this stuff at the beginning of the year. This
Speaker 20:  wasn't really affecting consumers in the same way, but what was affecting
Speaker 20:  consumers and what voters were looking at were the midterms. And so this
Speaker 20:  bill got signed this fall, I believe it was September and you know,
Speaker 20:  Biden Schumer, everyone wants to be able to say,
Speaker 20:  wants to have that intel groundbreaking ceremony. They wanna have
Speaker 20:  the CEO of Intel in their state breaking ground and promising,
Speaker 20:  you know, thousands of jobs for folks. Like this is what the Biden
Speaker 20:  administration, this is what Democrats did for you. This is what we pushed
Speaker 20:  it over the lines.
Speaker 21:  Yeah, I mean s Syracuse New York is a place that has suffered for a
Speaker 21:  while carrier, for instance, the air conditioner was conceived
Speaker 21:  and developed and manufactured in Syracuse. They
Speaker 21:  decided to move all the manufacturing to Singapore and it was a sad day
Speaker 21:  for Syracuse. A very, very sad day. Now Microns
Speaker 21:  huge investment, a hundred billion for major
Speaker 21:  chip Fs, 2.4 million feet of
Speaker 21:  manufacturing space and up to 50,000 new jobs. Syracuse has a
Speaker 21:  bright future again and people feel good about it
Speaker 20:  Of course, like they're not gonna feel it immediately. But I think the promise
Speaker 20:  of jobs while paying manufacturing jobs that people in these states, you
Speaker 20:  know, just generations have relied on manufacturing jobs. I think that was
Speaker 20:  really what pushed it over the edge to get that, you know, to tell bring
Speaker 20:  to voters.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, that makes sense. And do we have a sense yet where like
Speaker 2:  geographically that stuff is gonna start to happen? Like obviously Intel
Speaker 2:  has made a lot of noise in Arizona. Chuck Schumer is deeply obsessed with
Speaker 2:  like Syracuse in Buffalo, but do we have a sense of where these other
Speaker 2:  kind of new rising tech hubs are likely to be?
Speaker 20:  Yeah, so if you look at where Micron, intel, these companies
Speaker 20:  are investing money right now. Idaho is a big one with Micron.
Speaker 20:  I think that was like a $15 billion project. Yeah. And then
Speaker 20:  there's the 20 billion project from Intel in Ohio.
Speaker 20:  There's like some smaller companies that are working in
Speaker 20:  like the Carolinas, you know, places like I'm naming states where this is
Speaker 20:  traditionally not happening.
Speaker 2:  Sure, yeah.
Speaker 20:  There's communities, colleges, people who are looking for these jobs, right?
Speaker 20:  And so it's areas like that rather than the more
Speaker 20:  condensed urban, you know, central hubs of tech that we've seen in the
Speaker 2:  Past. Is there a political connection between all of those places?
Speaker 2:  Like can you, can you sort of draw a line between trying to win
Speaker 2:  midterm elections and what happened there? I
Speaker 20:  Mean it's blue collar voters. Sure. You know, these are people who, a lot
Speaker 20:  of them, I was listening to some interviews and reading some polls
Speaker 20:  about people who voted for Obama then voted for
Speaker 20:  Trump, right? And these are, you know, just mostly like
Speaker 20:  blue collar folks who feel like they've been left behind and if,
Speaker 20:  you know, they think about these golden days, of course there's been this
Speaker 20:  like weirdo movement of like return to tradition on the right, right? Yeah.
Speaker 20:  But that people do see, you know, American manufacturing is like the glory
Speaker 20:  days and if we could bring some of that back with like a eye set
Speaker 20:  to the future, I think that really benefits a lot of people.
Speaker 2:  Okay. And I would assume the tech industry is psyched about how all of this
Speaker 2:  turned out, right?
Speaker 20:  Oh yeah. I mean they'll get chips, right? Right.
Speaker 21:  Obviously the tech industry got behind the legislation. They
Speaker 21:  were so entranced by all the investments in science and the
Speaker 21:  high end manufacturing. And so we did have a coalition.
Speaker 2:  What's your sense of how much the goal is, and this is, this
Speaker 2:  is a question I have with like basically every law like this that gets done
Speaker 2:  is the question of like how do we solve the sort of specific problem we have
Speaker 2:  right now as quickly as we possibly can, which is like give money
Speaker 2:  to Intel, it knows how to make chips, give them money to build more buildings,
Speaker 2:  to make chips, right? Like that is, that is the quickest, cleanest solution
Speaker 2:  to an existing problem versus some of this longer term
Speaker 2:  build new tech hubs increase the size of the ecosystem. What's your
Speaker 2:  sense of both, like where the money is going and also the sort of goal of
Speaker 2:  a bill like this? Which of those two things does it try to do more of, do
Speaker 2:  you think?
Speaker 20:  Right. I'm sorry to come with like a left hook from this, but when I look
Speaker 20:  at this and I see like people wanting to build jobs and you know,
Speaker 20:  try and start new industries and benefit people, I automatically go to the
Speaker 20:  labor sector, what's happening in labor? You know, what is happening with
Speaker 20:  these companies that are going to be contracted out to build these fabs?
Speaker 20:  Are these people going to be allowed to unionize? Are they going to have
Speaker 20:  benefits? Is this a way for them to actually provide for their families
Speaker 20:  for the next generation for the next 10 years? And so I would be more
Speaker 20:  glued to seeing how Intel, how all these
Speaker 20:  contracting companies that build these things are treating workers right?
Speaker 20:  And whether or not, you know, once these fabs are built, where do the workers
Speaker 20:  go next? Are they going to go build another fab? What are they going to
Speaker 20:  do? That's my main concern. If we're talking about tech hubs, I think that's
Speaker 20:  fairly predictable in being like there's money, they'll go,
Speaker 20:  people will work on stuff if if it's successful, it's successful, they'll
Speaker 20:  receive more money, blah blah blah. But I'm, I have an eye towards labor.
Speaker 2:  Okay. And that also seems like a more immediate thing. Cause I
Speaker 2:  think part of what you're saying, right, is that like the challenge with
Speaker 2:  all of this is measuring success is gonna take a really long time. Like it
Speaker 2:  takes a long time to build buildings, especially large ones that can make
Speaker 2:  very tiny microchips. Like it takes a long time, the labor stuff is gonna
Speaker 2:  be one way we start to see how this is all gonna go down much sooner. Are
Speaker 2:  there other kind of early measures that you or the government
Speaker 2:  are looking at to figure out how this is gonna work? Or are we gonna get
Speaker 2:  to 2035 and everybody's gonna be like, well we spent a lot of money. Did
Speaker 2:  it go, what happened?
Speaker 20:  So you gotta look at like the last thing that the administration did, I
Speaker 20:  think it was the commerce department a couple weeks ago they issued a new
Speaker 20:  rule restricting import of like Chinese
Speaker 20:  goods or like export of American goods and of course to China
Speaker 20:  when it comes to like semiconductor manufacturing purposes. And that sounds
Speaker 20:  like kind of silly, but China has become like really
Speaker 20:  good at the, you know, basic low level consumer
Speaker 20:  products, semiconductor manufacturing, like they can do a lot of that on
Speaker 20:  their own. But when it comes to the more advanced like
Speaker 20:  artificial intelligence stuff, GPUs, those
Speaker 20:  more powerful things, they need American devices and they need American
Speaker 20:  tech and patents and things. So I think I would pay more attention to
Speaker 20:  how that's going to cripple, you know, China's military, China's
Speaker 20:  ability to, you know, invest in advanced manufacturing, tech
Speaker 20:  manufacturing. Of course that'll play out God, how does America work, right?
Speaker 20:  It'll play out in the military sense, right? And the global dominance,
Speaker 20:  you know, American Chinese deity sense probably before we see much for
Speaker 20:  American people, right?
Speaker 2:  Which is, you just brought us to the final stage of this, right? Which is
Speaker 2:  like massive global geopolitics, right? Like this is now there are like
Speaker 2:  world war three questions baked into intel building
Speaker 2:  fabs in Ohio, which is like insane but seems
Speaker 2:  actually true And right every, everybody talks about national security and
Speaker 2:  it's like that we're starting to think about about chips politically as people
Speaker 2:  think have thought about weapons for a long time. And it's like, it's just
Speaker 2:  it this, this has all gotten so much bigger and so much more
Speaker 2:  high stakes than just like cars and fridges and how
Speaker 2:  much that's really true now and how much that is like useful political posturing
Speaker 2:  in order to get stuff like this done is hard to tell. But it seems like we're
Speaker 2:  certainly headed in that direction and like this is political warfare as
Speaker 2:  much as it is anything else,
Speaker 20:  Right? I mean the thing that I keep thinking of is in 10
Speaker 20:  years, is TSMC going to be viewed as
Speaker 20:  the Boeing, right? That manufactures all of these fighter jets that
Speaker 20:  are really important to the American military na today and like starting,
Speaker 20:  you know, decades ago, or is Intel going to be Boeing,
Speaker 20:  you know, these other, you know, companies you think about in the DMV area
Speaker 20:  that manufacture fighter jets that manufacture military equipment and ballistics,
Speaker 20:  is that going to be Chinese companies that people rely on or is that going
Speaker 20:  to be US companies? And now, you know, when it comes to even visualizing
Speaker 20:  aerodynamic stuff for these, you know, Boeing jets or whatever,
Speaker 20:  like it's getting to the point where you need artificial intelligence to
Speaker 20:  model these things. It's so wild to think like, man, why can't
Speaker 20:  I think of the company name right now? But all the, you know, American military
Speaker 20:  companies, you know, that create these ballistics and stuff, That's what
Speaker 20:  I imagined, like Intel Byron being in like 20 years, which is crazy. Yeah,
Speaker 20:  I don't wanna talk about the morality of it, I have no idea. But that seems
Speaker 20:  to be, you know, where the government is pushing, you know, the next stage
Speaker 20:  of, you know, national security stuff.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, a hundred percent. So now that this bill is done, what's the mood around
Speaker 2:  it? Is everybody like, well we didn't, it's not perfect, but we're glad we
Speaker 2:  got it done. Is everybody, are we still fighting about it? Is everybody thrilled
Speaker 2:  and like waving flags around and throwing microchips at each other? Like
Speaker 2:  what's, what's the mood?
Speaker 20:  I think the mood right now is, it's over,
Speaker 20:  to be honest with you. It's been so many years. I think people are just
Speaker 20:  like, it's over. Thank God. Yeah. And everyone's kind of focused on like
Speaker 20:  the next two years of the Biden administration and what that looks like.
Speaker 20:  And then the tweaks that could be made are going to happen through,
Speaker 20:  you know, the federal agencies and like government bureaucrats and commerce
Speaker 20:  department, dod, et cetera. So that's where I kind of be looking at
Speaker 20:  they Congress put their foot in, they did the money, they did the thing.
Speaker 20:  Yeah. Now it's like the rest of the administration's problem to solve.
Speaker 21:  Whenever we invest in science, it pays off. We invested in NIH
Speaker 21:  and it created the largest pharmaceutical and most advanced
Speaker 21:  pharmaceutical industry in the world. We invested in NSF and
Speaker 21:  darpa and it created the most advanced tech industry in the world.
Speaker 21:  Tens of millions of new jobs, direct and indirect came
Speaker 21:  out because of these ships as the next chapter
Speaker 21:  in that book and it's gonna help America for generation.
Speaker 2:  Fair enough. All right, McKenna, thank you. I appreciate
Speaker 20:  It. Yeah, no problem. Thanks folks.
Speaker 2:  All right, that's it for the Verge Cast today. Thank you as always for listening.
Speaker 2:  As always, there is tons more on everything we talked about on the
Speaker 2:  verge.com especially in case you're wondering, the Elon Musk Twitter saga
Speaker 2:  keeps being nuts. We're still covering it on the site and we're gonna have
Speaker 2:  lots more to say about it on Friday. So stay tuned. You can also follow all
Speaker 2:  of us on Twitter, at least for now. Who knows where that's going. Addie is
Speaker 2:  the Dex Patriarchy. McKenna is Kelly McKenna. And I'm Pierce. This show is
Speaker 2:  produced by Andrew Marino and Liam James Nori Donovan is our executive producer
Speaker 2:  and Brooke Miners is our editorial director of audio. The Vergecast is a
Speaker 2:  Verge production and part of the Vox Media podcast network. If you have thoughts,
Speaker 2:  feedback, feelings, or mystical orbs that can see into the future, you can
Speaker 2:  always email us at vergecast@theverge.com. And if you have questions, call
Speaker 2:  the hotline. It's eight six six Verge one one, and we want to hear all
Speaker 2:  your big thoughts and questions about all things technology. We'll be back
Speaker 2:  on Friday to discuss Elon and Twitter, T-Mobile's, broadband
Speaker 2:  plans, Zoom's plan to take over movie theaters and a whole bunch of other
Speaker 2:  stuff. We'll see you then. Rock and roll.