# Transcript
ID: adc464d0-c17f-11ed-8045-418c99b323f4
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Solo Acts: Tinymakesthings' custom keycaps
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/5954883210561193636/-8377021181568797078/s93290-US-1959s-1678698962.mp3
Description: On today's episode of our Solo Acts mini series, Ashley Esqueda talks with Tiny of tinymakesthings, who makes artisan keycaps for mechanical keyboards. Tiny explains how she got started making her projects on Twitch, the process for designing the keycaps, and the community she built with her art.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Disabled
Speaker 2:  Welcome to the Vergecast, the flagship podcast of
Speaker 2:  little tiny hamburger keys on a keyboard.
Speaker 2:  I'm your friend Alex Kranz, and today we have a new episode of our Solo Acts
Speaker 2:  miniseries. We feature yours interviews from people who are working independently
Speaker 2:  to create great things on the internet. Every Monday on the Verge cast, our
Speaker 2:  friend Ashley Escada is curating and hosting these interviews and sharing
Speaker 2:  with us what she's learned. Hey Ashley.
Speaker 3:  I did not realize I was legally required to learn something.
Speaker 3:  Oh no.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, you're legally required. So who are, what are we learning
Speaker 2:  about today? Who are we talking to?
Speaker 3:  I am very excited to talk to Tiny Makes
Speaker 3:  Things and Tiny Makes Things is
Speaker 3:  a maker and dreamer. She, that's how she describes herself. She's an
Speaker 3:  artisan key cap creator, which means she makes really,
Speaker 3:  really adorable key caps for your mechanical
Speaker 3:  keyboard.
Speaker 2:  I love it.
Speaker 3:  Now you are, you're an in, you are like a mechanical keyboard
Speaker 3:  enthusiast.
Speaker 2:  Oh yeah. I have been in this space since like, ooh 20
Speaker 2:  2009 actually. That was my first big mechanical keyboard. It
Speaker 2:  had Alps, keys, bass, kind of on like an Apple keyboard from
Speaker 2:  the nineties. I spent way too much money on it. I still have it.
Speaker 3:  Are you able to discern like a musician can hear a note? Are you able
Speaker 3:  to discern an MX Cherry from a a I
Speaker 2:  Can hear a tore. I can hear that cuz that's the key that like makes my heart
Speaker 2:  sing. But I was very excited to hear you were talking to Tiny Makes Things
Speaker 2:  because like the little novelly key caps. Oh my god, I love 'em. They're
Speaker 2:  so cute.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, she has got some really adorable key caps.
Speaker 3:  One of my favorite things that she has ever made is an
Speaker 3:  entire keyboard full of open mouthed Kirby.
Speaker 3:  Yes.
Speaker 2:  Just,
Speaker 3:  Which are extremely adorable. And she is a
Speaker 3:  content creator as well. So part of her early career
Speaker 3:  was spent on Twitch making Keycaps and talking about her process
Speaker 3:  and, and building a community there. She also does, I mean she does hand
Speaker 3:  sculpted Clay Keycaps and then she also works with resin.
Speaker 3:  She makes accessories. I mean it's really, it's really impressive stuff and
Speaker 3:  also just outrageously adorable.
Speaker 2:  Well I know our listeners have had to hear me talk about mechanical
Speaker 2:  keyboards a whole, whole lot and I'm super jealous that you got to go
Speaker 2:  and chat with Tiny Makes Things. So let's just like, let's get to this interview.
Speaker 2:  I wanna hear everything you guys learned.
Speaker 3:  She's terribly fascinating. I love talking to her. Let's do it
Speaker 3:  tiny. Thank you so much for coming and talking to me today.
Speaker 4:  Thank you for, for having me Ashley. Really, really happy to be
Speaker 3:  Here. I wanna talk about Tiny Makes things. Can you give
Speaker 3:  listeners just a brief overview of your work?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I just love making keycaps that are silly, funny,
Speaker 4:  cute and just bring joy to you when you like see it on
Speaker 4:  your keyboard. I basically just started out just making things
Speaker 4:  that people, doing commissions, like making keycaps that people would ask
Speaker 4:  me to make of them. I kind of draw a lot of inspiration in general from
Speaker 4:  pop culture, like things that are trending, like memes,
Speaker 4:  anything that I just find funny or entertaining. Mechanical
Speaker 4:  keyboards back maybe, you know, six years ago or so, a lot of it was
Speaker 4:  just the gamer aesthetic of mechanical keyboards. A lot of the darker
Speaker 4:  like black colors with rgb, when people thought about mechanical
Speaker 4:  keyboards they thought about oh it's like for gamers and it's a certain kind
Speaker 4:  of look and I just, I felt like that wasn't true and being part of
Speaker 4:  the mechanical keyboard hobby, I knew that there was a lot more to it. And
Speaker 4:  so doing keycaps and making kind of fun little keycaps was my way of
Speaker 4:  sharing and trying to get people to understand that
Speaker 4:  like, yeah, mechanical keyboards can be for everybody.
Speaker 3:  How and when did you originally get into mechanical
Speaker 3:  keyboards? As a hobby?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, it was maybe like seven years now. I was just in college and I had
Speaker 4:  built my first PC to, you know, play video games on and then
Speaker 4:  the keyboard component actually just, I just went and bought like a $15 keyboard.
Speaker 4:  It was not mechanical because back then I think the only, like the cheapest
Speaker 4:  mechanical keyboard that you could get was something like 80 to a hundred
Speaker 4:  dollars. And I was like, why would I spend so much more money on a keyboard?
Speaker 4:  I don't really see the, the need for it. And I think it wasn't until a
Speaker 4:  little bit later that year that I, it was because I had this crush on this
Speaker 4:  boy and I knew that he was into keyboards and it was a very small hobby
Speaker 4:  back then. I was like, oh, you know, maybe I just, I just used that as an
Speaker 4:  excuse to like talk to him and so I was like, Hey, can you tell me about
Speaker 4:  keyboards? I'm thinking about getting a mechanical keyboard. And I
Speaker 4:  basically just, I kind of used it as an excuse but I definitely got
Speaker 4:  actually interested in it and I learned a lot about it. For me it was just
Speaker 4:  learning about like, oh, you know, like it does really make a big difference
Speaker 4:  how it sounds, how it feels and the typing experience and it being something
Speaker 4:  that you use so often like every day in your life. It
Speaker 4:  feels like it's kind of just a, a good investment to make, to have
Speaker 4:  something custom and that feels good whenever you use it.
Speaker 3:  What do you think it is about mechanical keyboards that sort of
Speaker 3:  capture people's imagination? Because there is so much creativity
Speaker 3:  in this space and I mean your work and the work of others.
Speaker 3:  I've just seen some stunning keyboards just by
Speaker 3:  themselves independent of custom key cap work. Yeah. Which is its own
Speaker 3:  its own separate community of makers. What do you think
Speaker 3:  it is about mechanical keyboards that really just captures all
Speaker 3:  of our nerdy little hearts? I
Speaker 4:  Think it, it's so customizable that it appeals to people in different
Speaker 4:  ways. Some people are really, really into just, for example
Speaker 4:  the, the key cap collecting part of this hobby, which is some people
Speaker 4:  don't even like mount these key caps ever. They just keep it in a display
Speaker 4:  box. And I actually got into that. That was kind of how I got
Speaker 4:  into making the keycaps in the first place because I used to collect them.
Speaker 4:  And it's just one of those things, it's like a, you know, like collecting
Speaker 4:  funko pops or something where you're, you just really like something and
Speaker 4:  you, you'll collect a lot of it and you kind of trade around different keycaps
Speaker 4:  and so that's like one that's just a very small portion of the bigger hobby.
Speaker 4:  But because people can be like, okay, well I wanna keyboard but I really
Speaker 4:  like these cool like little art pieces I can collect and put them
Speaker 4:  on my keyboard if I want to. But there's people who also just really are
Speaker 4:  into like, I really want something that sounds a certain way
Speaker 4:  or I, I want it to sound like nothing at all. I don't want it, I don't want
Speaker 4:  any sounds when I'm typing because I just want it to be quiet or I want it
Speaker 4:  to feel like stiffer or harder or maybe a very
Speaker 4:  light touch. And I think like people can get into it however they want to.
Speaker 4:  And the fact that you also don't really have to get into it if
Speaker 4:  you don't want to think. A lot of people see how crazy like the,
Speaker 4:  the hobby can get and they're like, oh there's so much to to kind of like
Speaker 4:  think about to learn and you could just go in and get
Speaker 4:  something just like a one time thing and that will last you many, many years
Speaker 4:  and you don't ever have to like go really deep into the hobby. You can just
Speaker 4:  kind of pick out something that you like and just stop there. So I think
Speaker 4:  like the flexibility and the kind of the customization of the hobby really
Speaker 4:  allows people to be as much into it in whatever fashion
Speaker 4:  they want to or not at all. I think your workspace and how
Speaker 4:  it looks affects how you function in that workspace.
Speaker 4:  And I think we saw a huge growth in the hobby, like the
Speaker 4:  lockdown and pandemic happened in the start of that because everyone had
Speaker 4:  to kind of buy their own like work from home
Speaker 4:  workspaces. And so the keyboard might actually probably be the most
Speaker 4:  like customizable part of that. So I think people
Speaker 4:  really like to just make something their own and
Speaker 4:  it affects how they, how you see your workspace and how you feel in that
Speaker 4:  space. And I think that's the, the impact that it has is big considering
Speaker 4:  how like it's not really a big thing but it can have a big impact.
Speaker 3:  Now you have mentioned that what a lot
Speaker 3:  of people associate with a mechanical keyboard or sort of these like very
Speaker 3:  loud clicky switches. So there's sort of like clicky
Speaker 3:  switches and linear switches. The linear ones are sort of the higher end
Speaker 3:  ones that a lot of enthusiasts like to use when they build.
Speaker 3:  What setup are you using the most these days? Like what is
Speaker 3:  your favorite keyboard switch profile set? Like what's your,
Speaker 3:  what's your setup for the enthusiasts? Listening
Speaker 4:  I have in front of me is, it's called a Mr suit. It's just the name
Speaker 4:  of the keyboard and the trend or maybe the
Speaker 4:  past year or twos trend is this kind of Marly, like
Speaker 4:  thk. It's just terms that we use. But marbly thoughty sound,
Speaker 4:  I'm not sure if you can, it's really hard for me to like record the sound
Speaker 4:  because I feel like I've tried even with my phone or just to get it in a
Speaker 4:  video even with a nice mic setup, I just feel like it doesn't capture the,
Speaker 4:  like marly sound quite well and,
Speaker 4:  and hearing it in person is kind of like, it just, I don't know how to describe
Speaker 4:  it. It just kind of like hits differently when you're, when you hear I can,
Speaker 4:  I can type on it really quick but this is a, the trend is
Speaker 4:  kind of putting foam into the, the keyboard and
Speaker 4:  it mutes a lot of the kind of like thick, yeah, yeah, it's like a thick,
Speaker 4:  more like dense kind of sound.
Speaker 3:  Okay. We're gonna take a break and then I'll talk with Tiny about her creative
Speaker 3:  process.
Speaker 3:  All right. I'm back with Tiny Makes things.
Speaker 3:  I would like to move on from mechanical keyboards in general to your work
Speaker 3:  with custom key caps and talk about your creative process.
Speaker 3:  So what is the very first key cap that you made?
Speaker 4:  The very first key cap to my recollection because
Speaker 4:  it's been many years was actually this link
Speaker 4:  and Zelda, well I actually made a pair of just like this
Speaker 4:  kind of cheapy like cartoon five version of Link
Speaker 4:  and Zelda and I actually, it was just kind of a thing that I wanted
Speaker 4:  to try out doing and I think somebody actually, I saw
Speaker 4:  a post on like one of the subreddits that was asking about like, oh
Speaker 4:  you know, does anybody know if Link keycaps exist? I
Speaker 4:  wanna get one for like me and my girlfriend or something like that. And that's
Speaker 4:  why I made two of them. And I actually remember reaching out in DMS to this
Speaker 4:  person after I made them and I sent a picture of it and I was like, Hey,
Speaker 4:  do you like want these? I literally like offering them for free
Speaker 4:  cuz I made them and I, back then I wasn't even making them as you know, like
Speaker 4:  as an artist. I don't think they ever responded. So I was just like, oh you
Speaker 4:  know, I guess that's, that's that like it's not good enough or
Speaker 4:  whatever. I think it was just like a random, I, I just thought about it cause
Speaker 4:  I was like, I don't think there are, back then there weren't a lot of people
Speaker 4:  making custom and that's maybe where I got this idea like
Speaker 4:  oh I can make certain characters and designs for
Speaker 4:  people that are looking for looking for those design in the hobby because
Speaker 4:  it doesn't really exist at that point. It wasn't like a full
Speaker 4:  blown thing that it is now. So yeah, that's the one that I remember
Speaker 4:  off, I guess the top of my head that I made.
Speaker 3:  So how did that initial pair of key cap snowball
Speaker 3:  into what you're doing now? Is it, was it a process of like, like you
Speaker 3:  mentioned, was it a process of being on subreddits and joining
Speaker 3:  mechanical keyboard communities and offering those commissions? Or was
Speaker 3:  it more of I'll just start making and then post them and see if people
Speaker 3:  wanna buy them?
Speaker 4:  I would say maybe it is a combination of that. After I started
Speaker 4:  making them, I obviously was like, okay well you know, me reaching out
Speaker 4:  randomly to people, the chances of people being like, oh I would like a
Speaker 4:  key cap or I guess the eventual goal is to to be paid for the
Speaker 4:  keycaps. If it was something that I wanted to do but even in the beginning
Speaker 4:  I would just make them and then we'll see kind of where it goes from there.
Speaker 4:  And I think I made Keycaps that I
Speaker 4:  personally thought were cool or the designs that I
Speaker 4:  really liked. It wasn't one of my first, I would say sales
Speaker 4:  or ideas was, well what I called sus keys, which were just
Speaker 4:  like sushi keys. It would be like a, you know, a salmon or
Speaker 4:  tuna that's like mounted on top of like a white key cap so it kind of looks
Speaker 4:  like a little sushi. And so I made maybe a couple of those and
Speaker 4:  then the way I guess most people go about you, you post on like one of the
Speaker 4:  redheads and you just kinda announce like your sale that it's happening at
Speaker 4:  a certain time and this is how you can buy one. When I first started making
Speaker 4:  keycaps I was very inconsistent about it. I was working a full-time job and
Speaker 4:  when you get home you just wanna like, just like potato and, and just play
Speaker 4:  video games or watch TV and then yeah like you don't wanna do anything PR
Speaker 4:  productive cuz you kind of, you just feel like tired. And then I just felt
Speaker 4:  very kind of like my life was just not going
Speaker 4:  anywhere cuz I was like, I'm working full-time now and is this just what
Speaker 4:  my life is gonna be for the rest? For the rest of it I come home and I'm
Speaker 4:  just like, I wanna watch tv.
Speaker 3:  I feel like everybody asks themself that question at a certain point. They're
Speaker 3:  just like, is this it?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I was, I was like 20 whatever, 22 out of college and I
Speaker 4:  like, I
Speaker 3:  Have 22 when you're already asking, is this it? Oh no.
Speaker 4:  I was like, yeah I guess like for the next what, 40 years,
Speaker 4:  this is what like life is gonna be like. So I was, I was having a hard
Speaker 4:  time like getting myself to make the things even though I wanted to. And
Speaker 4:  so what I did to kind of make myself be more consistent about it is I
Speaker 4:  started streaming on Twitch, just the actual creative like key
Speaker 4:  cap process and a lot of times I wasn't even making keycaps like for
Speaker 4:  anyone specific or even for a sale. I was into Overwatch
Speaker 4:  back then, so I started making all of the characters from Overwatch. I think
Speaker 4:  I still have a lot of those keys that I, I just made the full cast of
Speaker 4:  the Overwatch characters, a
Speaker 3:  Lot of key caps.
Speaker 4:  Yeah it was a lot of key caps but it was a lot of like I, I would do it while
Speaker 4:  I'm streaming so then I had, you know, company, you know, people would stop
Speaker 4:  by so I, you know, I chat with people. It helped me be really consistent
Speaker 4:  because I would force myself to, you know, stream for a certain amount of
Speaker 4:  hours. And I think that really helped me practice and help
Speaker 4:  me kind of get better at the actual key cap making.
Speaker 4:  And then two, I think even though I don't think my stream was,
Speaker 4:  you know, super popular or anything, I think it did help me grow
Speaker 4:  and then I had to, not had to, but when you have a Twitch
Speaker 4:  you're like, okay, I also should be on another social media. So I was also
Speaker 4:  on Instagram and, and to, it gave me other outlets to kind share my work
Speaker 4:  and to really, you know, post about what I was making. And so I
Speaker 4:  think that helped grow my audience and also
Speaker 4:  potential, I guess clientele. And, and then from there I think I
Speaker 4:  started to get actual commissions and I would open up for, you know, like
Speaker 4:  a, hey I can take a certain amount of commissions and then people would request
Speaker 4:  certain things and then I would kind of do commissions and I could also stream
Speaker 4:  that as well. So it kind of like built on itself over
Speaker 4:  time. But I did really kind of start out just making without the
Speaker 4:  intention of like, I want to sell this. It was just like, I wanna make these
Speaker 4:  things cuz I think they're cool and I like them
Speaker 4:  and I wanna practice. And then eventually got to a point where I was
Speaker 4:  like, okay, look people are, people are interested. There's, there's a need
Speaker 4:  for kind of custom key caps in this space. That's how I, that's how I started
Speaker 4:  out.
Speaker 3:  I've heard this from multiple people, at least over a dozen
Speaker 3:  that have attributed their success in a
Speaker 3:  creative field to getting on Twitch and
Speaker 3:  being held accountable by their viewers to, to be consistent.
Speaker 3:  As your community has grown, do you stream the same amount they used to?
Speaker 3:  Do you stream more because now this is your full-time job. Do you find
Speaker 3:  that your community is really supportive or is it
Speaker 3:  more, has it more transitioned into a business
Speaker 3:  and customers situation on Twitch where a lot of your
Speaker 3:  viewers are sort of treated like a business relationship as opposed
Speaker 3:  to that sort of parasocial twitch relationship that we see? That's like very
Speaker 3:  common
Speaker 4:  In the first maybe two years of streaming, I was very
Speaker 4:  streaming a lot. I was very gung-ho about like, I need, you know,
Speaker 4:  I wanna hit partner, I wanna, you know, hit certain numbers or whatever it
Speaker 4:  was. I would just, I put a lot, I would say like 80% of
Speaker 4:  my effort and maybe 20% was still like he kept making but of my efforts into
Speaker 4:  streaming. And it was a really big thing for me to, to have that platform
Speaker 4:  and that community and just that space. And I think you're
Speaker 4:  right in, in that it really helped having that consistency. And I think a
Speaker 4:  lot of people, when I look back and even just thinking about it now, I think
Speaker 4:  what I do is not particularly hard, I would say like
Speaker 4:  the actual craft and, and I don't wanna say that in a way where I'm like,
Speaker 4:  oh this is so easy, but like I, I just, I sometimes I'm like,
Speaker 4:  yeah, I just did it for a long time. And consistently
Speaker 4:  and consistency is key for a lot of people because I would say a lot of people
Speaker 4:  also give up on, you know, on the way to doing something because you don't
Speaker 4:  see results or you're not seeing whatever you're expecting and
Speaker 4:  it's hard to kind of be in those places when you don't feel like you have
Speaker 4:  to hit some numbers or you feel like you're not growing as fast as other
Speaker 4:  people or whatever it is. It's sometimes really tough to stay in,
Speaker 4:  you know, that mindset and, and to keep doing things. So in the beginning
Speaker 4:  I would say streaming was my very kind of, I put all my effort into.
Speaker 4:  And then over time, I would say, especially since I kind of discovered
Speaker 4:  short-term video content was for me and my style and maybe
Speaker 4:  just my own personal like expression, I, I thought
Speaker 4:  that short video content really suited the way that I
Speaker 4:  like to share my art. Most of my TikTok of my art are
Speaker 4:  very quick, maybe like 15 to 20 seconds, like not time
Speaker 4:  lapses, but short kind of parts of me making things. And then you see the
Speaker 4:  final product
Speaker 4:  Sometimes that takes like hours to do and you get to see 15 seconds of it
Speaker 4:  completed really quickly. I just thought that was like easier for people
Speaker 4:  to digest obviously. And I got into TikTok right before the lockdown
Speaker 4:  and everything happened before I think TikTok blew up and when I got on the
Speaker 4:  platform I was like, this is, this is great. I don't have to, streaming is
Speaker 4:  fun but it's also, you know, you're, you're sitting through hour like you
Speaker 4:  have to prep for it, there's hours of it and then afterwards you're really
Speaker 4:  tired. But at least for these videos I could post it and just like leave
Speaker 4:  it there. I don't have to, there's nothing I have to do once I'm done with
Speaker 4:  it. After I started doing more short, short form like video content,
Speaker 4:  I just took a backseat from streaming and I don't
Speaker 4:  stream as often now, I would say like a couple times a month
Speaker 4:  maybe. I really still do enjoy the community and kind of
Speaker 4:  just the people that I've basically hung out with for the last like couple
Speaker 4:  years and the people who are there when I wasn't, you know, whatever
Speaker 4:  influencer or content creator. I think I really value
Speaker 4:  just those connections that I've made in in the past and it's like
Speaker 4:  kind of just like seeing friends from time to time when I, when I stream
Speaker 4:  now. So it's not something that I use particularly
Speaker 4:  to like grow anything. I guess at this point it's more of a hey I wanna
Speaker 4:  hang out with a community, I kind of just wanna relax and like do
Speaker 4:  something. But you know, it's just there to kind of like relax and catch
Speaker 4:  up and not use it as a this is my thing, this is what makes
Speaker 4:  me money, this is like, you know, and I think it was like that in the beginning
Speaker 4:  where I felt like, oh I wanna be, you know, a really big streamer and make
Speaker 4:  lots of money or whatever it is. And for me I just kind of felt like, yeah
Speaker 4:  I, I don't know if I'll ever reach that point and, and
Speaker 4:  maybe I don't want to cuz I feel like when it gets big it's hard to
Speaker 4:  have like close community and I really value that aspect of it.
Speaker 3:  All right, we're gonna take one more break and then I'll chat with Tiny about
Speaker 3:  the challenges of making her keycaps and the accessories
Speaker 3:  she's making for them.
Speaker 3:  Okay, I'm back with tiny.
Speaker 3:  I am curious about the most complicated key cap
Speaker 3:  that you've ever made and how long it took for you to make.
Speaker 4:  So that question is sort of difficult to answer in a sense
Speaker 4:  that sometimes I take like days, weeks, months or
Speaker 4:  whatever to kind of prototype a key cap and that's a lot of
Speaker 4:  design and then you like sand things down, you maybe cast it to see
Speaker 4:  what it would look like and then you kind of go back to the drawing board
Speaker 4:  if something doesn't go back you can sand things off and remake it. So
Speaker 4:  that's hard because it's technically it is one key cap, but then
Speaker 4:  once you finish like the master, the initial key,
Speaker 4:  you can make like tons of it after. So sometimes just things take a
Speaker 4:  lot of like reiteration just based on the design. I'm generally
Speaker 4:  a more fast-paced designer, kind of like
Speaker 4:  less intricate but more like more designs. Like I've made a lot
Speaker 4:  of different designs. I kind of just, you know, hammer them out just to kind
Speaker 4:  of get something on the table. I, I think it's just like the, my style of
Speaker 4:  doing things. One of the design, I'm just gonna name one that I don't know
Speaker 4:  if it is the most difficult one, but it's a little panda
Speaker 4:  and I have it here.
Speaker 3:  But for anyone listening it's an extremely cute
Speaker 3:  panda key cap. And I'm sure you can see it on your
Speaker 3:  Instagram.
Speaker 4:  It is on my Instagram. The, the thing that this makes this hard though and
Speaker 4:  what maybe people don't really recognize from the get-go is
Speaker 4:  that when you make a key cap like this, which has multiple
Speaker 4:  many black and white kind of like layers, the key cap is actually
Speaker 4:  made upside down and it, and what I mean by that is the mold is
Speaker 4:  it's casted upside down before in, in this mold
Speaker 4:  basically it's poured into a mold and so it's a
Speaker 4:  liquid and you have to fill up this liquid in
Speaker 4:  order,
Speaker 3:  It's like a jello mold. Yeah. So you have a clear jello mold you pour in
Speaker 3:  if you're making different color layers. Yes you have to like pour in a layer,
Speaker 3:  let it set, pour in a new layer, let it
Speaker 4:  Set. Yes, exactly. That is a great way to explain
Speaker 4:  it. And so you have to think about like his eyes and his ears, those
Speaker 4:  are all like black and those are not like a whole layer. Those are like,
Speaker 4:  you have to take like a needle basically something very tiny and I'm just
Speaker 4:  tapping it into the resin and like dripping
Speaker 4:  it as carefully as I can into these areas. So this is like a maybe
Speaker 4:  six shots, what we call, so I have to do the, the eyes and the ears
Speaker 4:  and the nose and that's, they're all black and the next layer is white, which
Speaker 4:  is his like face. So that's another layer. And then you do his arms and then
Speaker 4:  you have to do his like toe pads which are white and then you have to do
Speaker 4:  his legs which are black. And then the last layer is the white. So it's like,
Speaker 4:  I think that's six. And any part that you get wrong in the
Speaker 4:  middle, you just, the cap is, I just, I don't usually sell like the what
Speaker 4:  I call B stock or something that's like slightly if, if there's bubbles or
Speaker 4:  whatever if you mess up and the lines aren't clean. So it's just
Speaker 4:  frustrating because if you mess up in the middle you're like, crap, I gotta
Speaker 4:  go back and redo it again. And can't really like undo the
Speaker 4:  layers. You can't go back, you just start over again. So this is more
Speaker 4:  just like a complicated process, one not very like I wouldn't
Speaker 4:  say like the details are super intricate, it's just the process was
Speaker 4:  tiring and, and I didn't get a lot of like the yield wise was very
Speaker 4:  low, the successful pandas that came out of this.
Speaker 3:  So when you are making key caps, you also have
Speaker 3:  what I have deemed accessories for your key caps you ha,
Speaker 3:  which I find extremely adorable but also very clever.
Speaker 3:  For example, you have these kind of little Kirby with open mouths and then
Speaker 3:  you have for a shift key for example, you've got a, a piece of corn
Speaker 3:  like an ear of corn that you can drop onto the top of that and
Speaker 3:  remove if so desired. I would love to hear
Speaker 3:  about how that came about. Your work was
Speaker 3:  the first time I had ever seen accessories for custom key caps or
Speaker 3:  removable parts for custom key caps. And I'd love to know
Speaker 3:  sort of how that experimentation kind of came
Speaker 3:  about.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I think when I think about keycaps and the design of it,
Speaker 4:  a lot of what I think about is how do I make this fun and
Speaker 4:  kind of like a toy And I think maybe not the only
Speaker 4:  source of inspiration, but I was really into hats
Speaker 4:  when I was playing TF two team Fortress two, it's a
Speaker 4:  shooter game, but there was this whole economy that had to do with like literal
Speaker 4:  hats in the game. And I, I think all the time I'm just thinking about key
Speaker 4:  caps, I don't know, just like ideas come and go. So I was like, would it
Speaker 4:  be, it wouldn't be cool if you had a key cap ahead, you know, like hats or
Speaker 4:  something that you could just swap around and give it, like things that it
Speaker 4:  could take off or put it on. I didn't end up doing
Speaker 4:  something specifically like hats for for Kirby, but I think it was just the
Speaker 4:  idea of like either modularity, I always think that's kind of a cool
Speaker 4:  concept of like being able to swap things out with other things or like
Speaker 4:  move things around for keyboards even there's actually keyboards that
Speaker 4:  have like numb pads that are modular, which I think is really cool idea.
Speaker 4:  But I just think about in general when I think, when I think about design,
Speaker 4:  I'm always just trying to think of like what other things can we do with
Speaker 4:  with keycaps and it's hard because it's such a small space. You obviously
Speaker 4:  have like restrictions about what you can really do in a certain space.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, you have a, yeah, there's a few of 'em got a few accessories for the,
Speaker 3:  the little curvy,
Speaker 4:  I think the first ones came as tongues and I think maybe
Speaker 4:  it even came out during a stream, which I, I feel like I,
Speaker 4:  there was one time when I was just making different things for
Speaker 4:  Kirby's face, but it wasn't like magnetic yet. I think I was just adding
Speaker 4:  like teeth, which makes Kirby look very weird or like
Speaker 4:  glasses and yeah, just kind of facial accessories. And
Speaker 4:  I think maybe it came up to meet or to think about like, oh
Speaker 4:  maybe if he did have a magnet in his mouth, it could be a magnetic
Speaker 4:  accessory that you could pop in and out and then it also wouldn't be as
Speaker 4:  haphazard.
Speaker 3:  Yeah it's, it snaps on. Yeah right. It just snaps right
Speaker 4:  On it. Exactly. And if it comes off it's, that's part of the design, right?
Speaker 4:  Like it doesn't, you don't need to for it to be bonded in that position.
Speaker 4:  And I think it might be dangerous if there was actually like a tongue
Speaker 4:  coming out or something like skinny like that. So yeah, I think I, I think
Speaker 4:  I had that idea and I was like oh let me play around with it. I think I thought
Speaker 4:  about magnetic keycaps long ago but I just didn't really, one,
Speaker 4:  it's hard to like mass produce at a scale and I thought it would be fun
Speaker 4:  to have it in between like different artists to have
Speaker 4:  some sort of like base or standard magnet. So like if I make
Speaker 4:  accessories and someone else makes accessories but we use the like different
Speaker 4:  polarity then they won't work with each other. But my original
Speaker 4:  idea was like what if there was a standard and we had all these little accessories
Speaker 4:  and not just it being like, you know, a tongue
Speaker 4:  specifically but like, you know, Kirby could eat anything. So if you had
Speaker 4:  like another key cap that maybe did have hats, Kirby could eat hats, I don't
Speaker 4:  know, you know like it could be something that you could use swap among your,
Speaker 4:  your key caps and you could even, you know, standardize it if you did wanna
Speaker 4:  say like, oh maybe food things. And then we all release like our own food
Speaker 4:  things for our own key caps but then you can swap it among different makers
Speaker 4:  and different, you know, kind of themes or or whatever. And then
Speaker 4:  anybody could make little magnetic things cuz you could buy one of these
Speaker 4:  and just make your own accessories and it would be really easy. And I think
Speaker 4:  like sharing that and having that in a space was something that I was really
Speaker 4:  excited about. I actually have not ever actually released
Speaker 4:  a magnetic cby like to sell. Like I don't think I've ever sold them. I just
Speaker 4:  made them and I just throw them on myself. But yeah, that was the original
Speaker 4:  idea and kind of how I wanted this to go and wanted people to
Speaker 4:  kind of experience this and have, yeah, just like cool things that you can
Speaker 4:  throw on your keyboard at Keycaps at any time.
Speaker 3:  That's so fun and, and I encourage everybody to go look at your
Speaker 3:  Instagram page because there are some very delightful videos there
Speaker 3:  of examples of all of this that we're talking about. It's, it helps put a
Speaker 3:  visual to the description I'm sure. I think my very last
Speaker 3:  question for you is, I would love to hear your advice to anybody
Speaker 3:  who sees your work or the work of another custom key
Speaker 3:  cap creator or mechanical keyboard enthusiast and wants to
Speaker 3:  get into this either as a hobby or a line of
Speaker 3:  work to go into business for themselves. I, I think you have a lot of experience
Speaker 3:  here that is very valuable that you could share. And if you have
Speaker 3:  any advice for those people who feel inspired, what would it be
Speaker 4:  For people who just want to get a keyboard and
Speaker 4:  to learn more about it? We have these, not we, but the community
Speaker 4:  as a whole has these meetups, they're just called keyboard meetups and people
Speaker 4:  just bring their own keyboards and we're just usually in one big
Speaker 4:  space and you just talk to people about keyboards for
Speaker 4:  like hours. It is probably one of the best ways to really
Speaker 4:  get a good deep dive into keyboards
Speaker 4:  if you want to spend the least amount of time like
Speaker 4:  studying or learning or researching about it. It's
Speaker 4:  really easy to go into one of these places and I, I wanna say that they're
Speaker 4:  beginner or like friendly to people who are into the hobby.
Speaker 4:  Obviously if you're there it's likely that you are already in the hobby but
Speaker 4:  everyone is really psyched to talk about keyboards. Like you could probably
Speaker 4:  go up to anybody and be like, Hey can you, you know, I'm new to this, can
Speaker 4:  you explain to me about keyboards? And I would say like a good amount of
Speaker 4:  the people there would happily talk your ears off about keyboards for
Speaker 4:  the entire time. It's a great place to just see a very wide variety of
Speaker 4:  everything. And I'm gonna make take this chance to plug in if
Speaker 4:  you are local to the Bay Area in northern California,
Speaker 4:  I actually opened up a keyboard shop in downtown San Jose.
Speaker 4:  You can just search tiny keyboard shop and it is literally
Speaker 4:  a tiny keyboard shop. But if you're new to the hobby and would just like
Speaker 4:  to learn and you don't wanna go to a meetup, you can go there and kind of
Speaker 4:  experience keyboards and we'll happily explain to you everything you want
Speaker 4:  to know about keyboards and you can also walk away
Speaker 4:  with a keyboard if you would like to or and or any of the
Speaker 4:  accessories that are related to keyboards.
Speaker 3:  Thanks again to Tiny for sitting down and talking to me in this
Speaker 3:  interview. Alex, I just want to know
Speaker 3:  how many mechanical keyboards you've purchased in the time
Speaker 3:  between the start of this interview and now.
Speaker 2:  I don't think I'm allowed to respond to that. Legally. I have to consult
Speaker 2:  with my lawyers. Are you gonna go get one?
Speaker 3:  I think I have to right now. I think I've got to, after talking to Tiny,
Speaker 3:  I'm really excited about it. I wanna learn more about the community
Speaker 3:  and from what I have seen, a lot of people are just super welcoming in places
Speaker 3:  like the subreddits and other, other groups that you
Speaker 3:  can find online, discords, things like that. People have just been really
Speaker 3:  welcoming and they want to help you be an enthusiast. So it's really, it's
Speaker 3:  a great community. It
Speaker 2:  Is a great community. I a hundred percent recommend going to like a meetup
Speaker 2:  cuz everybody brings their keyboards and the thing that everybody wants you
Speaker 2:  to do is like type on their
Speaker 3:  Keyboards. I think that sounds like a great idea. And I'm sure being in Los
Speaker 3:  Angeles, I'm sure there are lots of meetups.
Speaker 2:  I think you will have no problem finding a meetup. All right, well
Speaker 2:  thank you again so much, Ashley, we've got one more
Speaker 2:  episode of our Solo Acts mini-series. What are you gonna be talking about?
Speaker 3:  I am very excited to say that I will be talking
Speaker 3:  to the solo app developer responsible
Speaker 3:  for Overcast Yes. Which is my personal favorite
Speaker 3:  podcasting app. It is the one I use and he didn't pay me to say that
Speaker 3:  Marco Arment is gonna talk to me about being a solo app developer and,
Speaker 3:  and his, his journey into that arena
Speaker 3:  and also the time he has spent in the space and he's been
Speaker 3:  there since pretty much the beginning of the App store. So it's been, it
Speaker 3:  was a really, it's a really good conversation.
Speaker 2:  Oh my God, I cannot wait to listen. Well, thank you again, Ashley.
Speaker 2:  That's kind of it. This show is produced by Andrew
Speaker 2:  Marino and Liam James Brooke Mentors is our editorial director of
Speaker 2:  audio and the Vergecast is a Verge production and part of the Vox Media podcast
Speaker 2:  network. If you've got thoughts, feedback, feelings, you can always email
Speaker 2:  the vergecast@vergecasttheverge.com or you can call the hotline.
Speaker 2:  It's eight six six Verge 11 again,
Speaker 2:  eight sixty six Verge 11. Call us with any of your
Speaker 2:  questions, we love to hear them. And we're gonna be back again on Wednesday
Speaker 2:  with an all new episode of the VER Cast. So see you then. Stay classy.