# Transcript
ID: caaef0fa-7f4e-4445-9b5b-ac381a79e16d
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: The tech trials keep coming
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-4888164994119905567/2230149004350387477/s93290-US-4342s-1699442863.mp3
Description: Today on the flagship podcast of anti-steering provisions:
02:57 - The Verge's David Pierce and Makena Kelly discuss Epic v. Google, a trial about the future of app stores.
The Epic v. Google trial may come down to simple v. complicated
Epic v. Google: a battle over Fortnite fees goes to court
28:49 - Liz Lopatto joins the show to detail her experience covering the Sam Bankman-Fried trial from start to finish.
FTX founder Sam Bankman-Fried is guilty of fraud
Sam Bankman-Fried gambled on a trial and his parents lost
58:27 - Richard Lawler helps answer this week's Vergecast Hotline question.
Disney’s new vision for ESPN might include part ownership by the NBA, NFL
Disney finally revealed how many billions ESPN pulls in.
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or leave a voicemail at 866-VERGE11, we love hearing from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Disabled
Speaker 2:  Welcome To The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of Anti steering
Speaker 2:  provisions. I'm your friend David Pierce and I am currently
Speaker 2:  getting ready to travel. It's 6:47 PM
Speaker 2:  on Monday night. I have a flight Tuesday morning. We're recording all of
Speaker 2:  this a little bit early as a result, I'm going San Francisco And. what that
Speaker 2:  means is I'm about to spend five or so hours on a plane.
Speaker 2:  So I'm doing of course what you always have to do, which is bring
Speaker 2:  45 different devices to use on the plane. I have an iPad,
Speaker 2:  I have a switch, I have my laptop, I have my phone, I have
Speaker 2:  another iPad that I'm just now realizing I don't need to bring. I have a
Speaker 2:  Kindle. Did I mention my Kindle? All of that is full of content. I'm
Speaker 2:  downloading stuff, I'm charging everything. I have Super Mario Wonder
Speaker 2:  to play on the plane, which is the only thing I'm gonna do for the whole
Speaker 2:  flight and I know that already. And yet I'm doing all of this other work.
Speaker 2:  I also have to charge all my gadgets. I have to make sure I have all of the
Speaker 2:  cables that I need, which is a lot easier than it used to be. But there's
Speaker 2:  always still one Stray Lightning cable or micro
Speaker 2:  USB thing I have to bring. It's just a lot. And it turns out that whenever
Speaker 2:  I travel, half the stuff in my bag is gadgets and the other half is just
Speaker 2:  like one pair of jeans no matter how long I'm traveling for.
Speaker 2:  Listen, this is not the life anyone should live, but it's the one I've signed
Speaker 2:  up for. So here we go. Anyway, we have an awesome show coming up for you
Speaker 2:  today. We are gonna talk almost entirely about trials because
Speaker 2:  like we've been talking about on this show all fall, we're in the midst of
Speaker 2:  a couple of really interesting, really important, potentially really
Speaker 2:  consequential things happening in court around the tech industry.
Speaker 2:  Today we're gonna talk about two in particular, Epic v Google, the latest
Speaker 2:  antitrust trial against Google, not to be confused with the other
Speaker 2:  antitrust trial that's happening against Google. And then we're gonna talk
Speaker 2:  about SBF, the trial of Sam. Banin Freed is finally
Speaker 2:  over. He was convicted and we're gonna talk about how we got there
Speaker 2:  And, what it means going forward. All that is coming up in just a sec. But
Speaker 2:  first I have to find the charger for my Kindle because I have
Speaker 2:  two Kindles with two different chargers and I'm just gonna bring whichever
Speaker 2:  one is leased Dead. There's just a lot going on. This is The Vergecast. We'll
Speaker 2:  be right back.
Speaker 3:  This podcast is brought to you by Meta Quest three, the new mixed reality
Speaker 3:  headset from Meta. Expand Your World in ways you never Thought Possible with
Speaker 3:  the new Meta Quest. Three, put on the most powerful quest yet and jump
Speaker 3:  into fully immersive games like Assassin's Creed Nexus or
Speaker 3:  blend virtual elements into your surroundings in games like Stranger Things
Speaker 3:  vr. With over 500 titles, it's easy to dive into
Speaker 3:  whatever you're into. Expand your world with Meta Quest three. See child
Speaker 3:  safety guidance online accounts for 10 and up certain apps, games and experiences
Speaker 3:  may be suitable for a more mature audience. Learn more@meta.com.
Speaker 4:  Lauren, Mike. So we host a podcast for Wired called Gadget
Speaker 4:  Lab. We do, we do. Yes, that is correct.
Speaker 4:  Tell the good people some more about it.
Speaker 5:  Well I think the good people should definitely tune in every week because
Speaker 5:  they get to hear me roasting you. Hey now All, right? No, really what
Speaker 5:  Gadget Lab is is Mike and I tackling the biggest questions in the
Speaker 5:  world of technology. We cover the big news of the week in Tech Land,
Speaker 5:  but we also offer our expert and opinions on all things
Speaker 5:  consumer
Speaker 4:  Tech. We release a new episode of Gadget Lab every week and you can listen
Speaker 4:  and follow us wherever you pod
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. I have like 65 different things plugged in right now.
Speaker 2:  Two different devices are doing software updates and I think I'm downloading
Speaker 2:  like half of Netflix to my iPad. I am ready for this
Speaker 2:  flight. Y'all All right? Let's get into the trials. The first one I wanna
Speaker 2:  talk about today is Epic v Google, which is a trial fundamentally about the
Speaker 2:  future of app stores. Epic says basically that Google charging a
Speaker 2:  30% commission on in-app purchases is anti-competitive and it
Speaker 2:  wants to blow up the app store model altogether. Google says You know
Speaker 2:  no thanks to all of that. If this is ringing deja vu bells in your brain,
Speaker 2:  there is a good reason for that. In 2021, Epic went to trial against
Speaker 2:  Apple alleging pretty much the exact same stuff. This trial
Speaker 2:  has a lot in common with that one, but also some important differences
Speaker 2:  and there's a decent chance that we're gonna get a different kind of outcome
Speaker 2:  here. The trial is already a couple of days old as you're hearing this,
Speaker 2:  we're covering it really closely. Sean Hollister is in the courtroom and
Speaker 2:  the rgs Makena Kelly is here now to help me figure out what to make of all
Speaker 2:  of it. Hi Makena. Hi. I don't know where to start with this trial.
Speaker 2:  I was going back and trying to figure out where do we need to start to catch
Speaker 2:  people up on what is going on between Epic and Google? And I feel like to
Speaker 2:  some extent the answer is we have to go all the way back to the beginning
Speaker 2:  of Epic versus everybody, right? Which is like 2020 mid
Speaker 2:  pandemic. Everybody's outta their mind. Life is pure chaos and
Speaker 2:  Epic just sort of decides to pull the
Speaker 2:  ripcord and pick a giant fight with the two biggest companies in tech all
Speaker 2:  at once. Can you just give us like the 62nd backstory kind of
Speaker 2:  starting there, And, what happened between these companies?
Speaker 6:  Sure. So what happened in 2020 like you're describing is
Speaker 6:  Epic games. The Fortnite maker decided that they were going to just
Speaker 6:  say screw you to Google and Apple in their app stores.
Speaker 6:  That
Speaker 2:  Was like the official plan by the way. That was not, that's not really editorializing
Speaker 2:  like that is what they were attempting to do.
Speaker 6:  It totally was. And Sweeney, I mean that is so like Tim
Speaker 6:  Sweeney. Yeah. Like to do anyways. And so he said Screw you. We are
Speaker 6:  going to allow people to make in-app purchases in our game without it going
Speaker 6:  through the app stores and being subject to this like 15 to 30% tax.
Speaker 6:  And immediately Google and Apple pulled Fortnite
Speaker 6:  from their app stores. And so as a result,
Speaker 6:  Epic Games sued them for that, alleging that they hold these
Speaker 6:  monopolies in the app store markets and that these You know
Speaker 6:  30% taxes are unlawful and should be
Speaker 6:  challenged. And so we're three years from that and the Google one is
Speaker 6:  just going to trial right now.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, it's been a, it's been a long three years. So and then in between we
Speaker 2:  had Epic versus Apple, which is I think not exactly the same thing as
Speaker 2:  the trial we're about to have and we should talk about the differences. But
Speaker 2:  in a lot of ways the bones of the trial are very similar. One
Speaker 2:  side is the app store and one side is Epic. Trying to say the app store is
Speaker 2:  illegal and I would say Epic didn't completely lose
Speaker 2:  the Apple trial. It won the sort of anti steering provision which says you
Speaker 2:  can now link to other ways to make payments, but in general
Speaker 2:  it's fight against App Store monopolies pretty much came
Speaker 2:  up short. So if I'm Epic, why on earth do I keep picking
Speaker 2:  this fight after more or less losing it the first time?
Speaker 6:  Well, to look at Tim Sweeney, I think he really does like to tick these people
Speaker 6:  off. He's kind of a hardheaded CEOI don't think he's worried
Speaker 6:  about losing face in these at all to be honest with you.
Speaker 6:  And so for them, these like taxes that these
Speaker 6:  app stores put on software, what requires them to
Speaker 6:  raise? Well what they'll say is it requires them to raise prices for consumers
Speaker 6:  and it makes whatever it is, V bucks or whatever more expensive in
Speaker 6:  Fortnite. It makes it more expensive for you to, I don't know, get Tinder
Speaker 6:  gold or whatever they're calling it nowadays and all that kind of stuff.
Speaker 6:  So they continue to push this because they don't wanna give
Speaker 6:  any of these profits, any of this money to Apple or Google.
Speaker 6:  They're just operating an app store in their opinion. And it should be You
Speaker 6:  know free for people to access and use as an open
Speaker 6:  marketplace.
Speaker 2:  What's your sense of what's different about this case sort of at a very high
Speaker 2:  level, the two sides of the fight like we were saying are more or less the
Speaker 2:  same thing. Is there anything different about Google Google as an opponent
Speaker 2:  as Apple as opponent a couple years ago?
Speaker 6:  Sure. So I mean looking at Google, the
Speaker 6:  Play store is so huge. Yeah. As much as we talk about
Speaker 6:  You know iPhones being like the elite whatever device to be using,
Speaker 6:  more people use Android. Like it really is just everywhere. And So, I
Speaker 6:  think that lends itself more to Epic's argument here.
Speaker 6:  And then also we already had the ruling in the anti steering provision and
Speaker 6:  that's in in appeals right now with having to be able to link out. So
Speaker 6:  another decision similar, similar to that would really offer some more precedent
Speaker 6:  in whatever appeal comes from the Apple case as well.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, the the Play store thing is so interesting to me 'cause I think if
Speaker 2:  I'm remembering back, apple basically tried to make a security
Speaker 2:  argument about iOS that like if you allow people to side load
Speaker 2:  apps on their phone, bad things will happen. People will install malware.
Speaker 2:  All kinds of awful things will happen to your phone. And essentially
Speaker 2:  users and developers cannot be trusted to do things outside of the
Speaker 2:  app store. And it seems like Google is making a similar
Speaker 2:  case in this case, which is sort of funny because the Play store is like
Speaker 2:  notoriously kind of a disaster. But also Google is slightly
Speaker 2:  different because like you can kind of get around the play store,
Speaker 2:  like you can sort of side load apps on Android, the Samsung
Speaker 2:  store exists, which seems like a really weird sort of wrench in this
Speaker 2:  trial. So even at a platform level, it just seems to me that the
Speaker 2:  case against Google is stronger because the Play Store, like you said,
Speaker 2:  is so big and so important on this platform but also is so
Speaker 2:  much sort of messier and easier to get around
Speaker 2:  than like the unbelievably tight fist that it Apple has
Speaker 2:  on the app store. Does that feel different to you going into this?
Speaker 6:  Oh yeah. I mean 'cause it's, it's easier. You can just download another
Speaker 6:  app store or You know or use like the Samsung Play store or be able to it.
Speaker 6:  It's so much easier. People talk about customization and having more control
Speaker 6:  of your devices. Google has let you do that for a very long time on Android.
Speaker 6:  And so people do of course have more options and I You know it'll be interesting
Speaker 6:  to see how that plays out.
Speaker 2:  And this goes back to, I think one of the things we learned from the Apple
Speaker 2:  case is so much of this is about the fight we end up having. Which
Speaker 2:  is part of the thing I think this is that's gonna be so interesting about
Speaker 2:  this case is like every time you and I talk, I feel like we end up talking
Speaker 2:  about market definitions because all anybody ever wants to talk about
Speaker 2:  in these cases is market definitions because the market you define is so
Speaker 2:  important. And it was some like it was the last time there were
Speaker 2:  questions about like is it mobile apps, is it games? And we ended up talking
Speaker 2:  about the market was like mobile digital transactions or something
Speaker 2:  goofy and in this case it feels like we're we're about to just re-litigate
Speaker 2:  all the same stuff, right? Like what, what is it that we're actually fighting
Speaker 2:  about here? And I wonder if I am Epic if I've learned
Speaker 2:  anything from that first fight that is gonna make them do a
Speaker 2:  better job in this case.
Speaker 6:  Yeah and I mean when you talk about continuing to pick this fight last week,
Speaker 6:  match.com and You know other plaintiffs on this case
Speaker 6:  dropped out seemingly You know settling with Apple. It's interesting how
Speaker 6:  Tim Sweeney and Epic games is continuing to purs pursue this especially with
Speaker 6:  whatever settlements You know Google is trying to make behind closed doors
Speaker 6:  right now. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  What do you make of the match thing? They were the other company that has
Speaker 2:  been really loud in this fight. I feel like it's been Epic, Spotify
Speaker 2:  and Match have been the three companies sort of most aggressively fighting
Speaker 2:  these app store monopolies and Match in particular seems to have just kind
Speaker 2:  of given up the fight. What do you make of that?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I think this case like you're saying is going to be a bit more challenging
Speaker 6:  for these companies to take on. And I'm sure You know whatever agreement
Speaker 6:  they were able to get from Google on this was enough to satisfy You know
Speaker 6:  their concerns with this and that kind of You know lends
Speaker 6:  to the question of what is Epic games? What is their opening argument going
Speaker 6:  to look like this week? What is it that they're You know continuing to push
Speaker 6:  and to continue to fight for that. They probably couldn't have gotten You
Speaker 6:  know in its settlement and it's probably that challenging that monopoly.
Speaker 2:  Do you believe Tim Sweeney when he makes these sort of grand pronouncements?
Speaker 2:  I mean I think one way to look at this is just two very greedy companies
Speaker 2:  fighting over money, right? Like big company wants to keep its money, other
Speaker 2:  big company wants to take some who wins like the Occam's razor version of
Speaker 2:  this argument is that, but the flip side of this is that Tim Sweeney
Speaker 2:  has said resolutely and for years at this point that this is bigger than
Speaker 2:  Epic, this is bigger than money. This is about like principles
Speaker 2:  and software development and who gets to
Speaker 2:  win in society. And normally I would find that to be
Speaker 2:  nonsense but at this point Tim Sweeney seems maybe more likely than most
Speaker 2:  to not be full of it when he says that. I don't know. What do you think?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it's hard to read into the hearts and minds of people like this, but
Speaker 6:  if I was Tim Sweeney and I brought this case, these cases
Speaker 6:  three years ago, even if I didn't buy it in the first place, I definitely
Speaker 6:  had convinced myself by now. Yeah. I have internalized these arguments in
Speaker 6:  a way that I literally cannot give them up after being so loud.
Speaker 6:  So like at the forefront of this issue for so long. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  That is fair. And I think at some point you've said it at enough times that
Speaker 2:  you just kind of have to keep saying it. Yeah. Like at some point if he just
Speaker 2:  testifies and he's like, look I just wanna keep our 30%, I I want more money
Speaker 2:  for my shareholders. Like the whole courtroom is just gonna start booing
Speaker 2:  at him and it's, he can't, he can't do that now.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. The thing about this case that I found really interesting back when
Speaker 6:  it was first announced and we had that big like Apple 1984 yeah
Speaker 6:  Epic games thing is that for the past You know how many
Speaker 6:  years I have been waiting for the tech policy arguments that we're having
Speaker 6:  in antitrust content moderation or whatever to have its like net neutrality
Speaker 6:  moment. Like it's 2015 net neutrality 2017 net
Speaker 6:  neutrality moment. And when I saw that video and I thought about You know
Speaker 6:  how big Fortnite was and think about the player base and the people behind
Speaker 6:  it, I really, I really was like, okay, if it's gonna happen, You know in
Speaker 6:  any case in antitrust it's gonna happen right now. Now. And it
Speaker 6:  didn't necessarily happen. I was waiting to see, 'cause You know, if you
Speaker 6:  remember like the old net neutrality stuff like Google's website, You know
Speaker 6:  Reddit's website where it's plastered with all this stuff and just to have
Speaker 6:  like, I mean Epic games, You know in Fortnite the biggest game Yeah You know
Speaker 6:  that so many young people are playing. I was really hoping that we were going
Speaker 6:  to see that and it just, it never grew to that size.
Speaker 6:  It makes me think about You know what would happen, like if we actually
Speaker 6:  did have a bunch of like young kids and teenagers and young people
Speaker 6:  like riled up over app store markets and like how different
Speaker 6:  this would look right now. Yeah. But yeah, I I'm always wait, I'm always
Speaker 6:  looking for that kind of You know emergence of like this as like a, I don't
Speaker 6:  know, like a public protest movement. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  I mean it's really interesting 'cause I think the thing in recent times that
Speaker 2:  has gotten the closest to that was the, the like would be TikTok ban
Speaker 2:  in terms of like real sort of grassroots rage among young people.
Speaker 2:  That's the closest one I've seen is a lot of people fighting about
Speaker 2:  the TikTok ban for creators and for free expression and all this stuff.
Speaker 2:  But the antitrust thing is really interesting to me because it feels like
Speaker 2:  this right now should be the moment you have the US
Speaker 2:  versus Google antitrust trial ongoing. Like as we speak right now
Speaker 2:  you have Epic versus Google another antitrust trial starting right now. You
Speaker 2:  have this suit filed against Amazon that is increasingly
Speaker 2:  the more we learn about it, the weirder and sketchier and more problematic
Speaker 2:  and all consuming, it seems this should be the moment where antitrust
Speaker 2:  becomes this like big mainstream, everybody's talking about it
Speaker 2:  issue. I certainly don't see that like in the world. Like the people
Speaker 2:  I talk to are not interested in antitrust legislation at this moment. But
Speaker 2:  also I don't even necessarily get the sense that there's a ton of energy
Speaker 2:  like among politicians and in Washington right now about this. What
Speaker 2:  is going on here?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, so when I'm think I'm going back to
Speaker 6:  20 19, 20 20 in the heat of that election cycle when
Speaker 6:  we were in the heat of the Democratic primary and we had Elizabeth Warren
Speaker 6:  and whoever putting out these giant antitrust packages saying that big tech
Speaker 6:  needs to be broken up, all of a sudden we have people who are taking the
Speaker 6:  thoughts of like Lena Kahn and Tim Wu and mainstreaming it in
Speaker 6:  a way that was getting people really, really excited. And
Speaker 6:  as legislation got introduced and as that
Speaker 6:  continued to move in Congress, I think there was one bill that got passed
Speaker 6:  and it was just like a merger filing fee thing, right? Sure. And so it
Speaker 6:  wasn't that major progress and then a lot of the conversations
Speaker 6:  around this has been, okay, well we will wait and see what the
Speaker 6:  courts do You know to see what legislation is necessary
Speaker 6:  for this You know, you would think that people would be paying maybe a bit
Speaker 6:  more closer attention You know to this and maybe talking about it a bit more.
Speaker 6:  But I, it seems like people are just kind of getting ready to see what
Speaker 6:  happens And, what steps that they should take. I know I've been trying to
Speaker 6:  check in and I, there's like bills, like the open apps market act and that
Speaker 6:  would open up the marketplaces. This was something that came out of You know
Speaker 6:  all of these apps store suits. There was that piece of legislation,
Speaker 6:  it didn't really go anywhere. I've heard some stuff about them reworking
Speaker 6:  that and then reintroducing it at some point in time. But again, maybe they're
Speaker 6:  waiting to see what happens in the Google case. It's really unclear to me
Speaker 6:  right now.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, it does seem like there was this underlying argument for a while that
Speaker 2:  Lena Khan in particular was ready to lose some of these
Speaker 2:  antitrust fights in order to make broader, longer term
Speaker 2:  legislative changes. That it's like you need a different kind of precedent
Speaker 2:  and a different kind of case if we're gonna start to make Congress
Speaker 2:  make laws in order to win these fights that the FTC can't win based on
Speaker 2:  like hundred year old law that had nothing to do with tech companies and
Speaker 2:  so far it doesn't seem to have happened. I understand that it's a long game
Speaker 2:  and I feel like one thing you've drilled into my head on this show over and
Speaker 2:  over is that there's just only so much time and
Speaker 2:  energy in Congress to do things and getting anything
Speaker 2:  in tech to be the most important thing at the moment in order for people
Speaker 2:  to actually get something done takes a lot of work. Like I was thinking about
Speaker 2:  this over this weekend because it was daylight saving time and there was
Speaker 2:  the, was it the Sunshine Protection Act every
Speaker 6:  Year?
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Like and as far as I can tell, no one is against this. It's just like
Speaker 2:  no one cares enough to bring it up in Congress and do something about it
Speaker 2:  even though they would be a national hero and they should do something about
Speaker 2:  it. This feels in a certain way, like kind of the same thing. More and more
Speaker 2:  people I think in politics and in the government agree that something should
Speaker 2:  be done and and that changes need to be made. But even right now there's
Speaker 2:  so much more heat on like AI regulation that it just feels like yet
Speaker 2:  again we've bumped what do we do about big tech down the
Speaker 2:  pecking order of tech issues. And I, it just, it feels like as long
Speaker 2:  as it is never the most interesting thing, which if it's not right now, I
Speaker 2:  don't know how it's ever gonna be. It's hard to see what happens there in
Speaker 2:  the immediate future.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And I do think that there might be a turning point. I
Speaker 6:  was listening to this funny enough AI hearing in the house
Speaker 6:  a couple weeks ago and in it republicans and
Speaker 6:  Democrats were both talking about well okay AI regulation, we need that,
Speaker 6:  but how do we even start thinking about that without a
Speaker 6:  nationwide federal privacy framework? You know some lawmakers are
Speaker 6:  reconsidering like, okay, maybe we need to go back to basics. Things are
Speaker 6:  getting too complicated. We have too many issues. Why don't we attack
Speaker 6:  something that will have maybe the best outcome
Speaker 6:  for consumers and for Americans by like going back and
Speaker 6:  looking at an American You know a federal data privacy law and then maybe
Speaker 6:  going back and like rethinking antitrust more holistically
Speaker 6:  instead of doing these You know these bills that just attack little pieces
Speaker 6:  of this rather than just going after AI like Chuck Schumer and all
Speaker 6:  these AI summits, they've been targeting different things. So there's been
Speaker 6:  like innovation ones and work You know labor and workforce ones.
Speaker 6:  And it just, that almost feels like it's making the issue like too complicated
Speaker 6:  at the same time. Like you're trying to teach lawmakers, You know about AI
Speaker 6:  and then you're just completely inundating them with all this information
Speaker 6:  and like how do you make sense of that and turn You know legislation into
Speaker 6:  that and like decide exactly what to focus on. Of course when it comes to
Speaker 6:  AI regulation then it seems like open AI and all the companies are
Speaker 6:  a bit more concerned with Congress going after election focused stuff
Speaker 6:  and like political ads maybe. But at some point, and I think
Speaker 6:  we're starting to see it now, picking these little fights is not gonna be
Speaker 6:  enough. They're going to have to decide to like come back, lay the foundation
Speaker 6:  and then maybe think about those things later.
Speaker 2:  I totally agree with that, but it does seem like there is a certain element
Speaker 2:  of the perfect being the enemy of the good in all of that. Where
Speaker 2:  it feels like with so many of these conversations, I think data privacy probably
Speaker 2:  chief among them, we've had this debate over and over and it just seems like
Speaker 2:  we land in this place where it's like, well if you can't solve the whole
Speaker 2:  problem we, we don't have anything. And so we've gotten to this point where
Speaker 2:  the only solution is just like we have to rewrite the American constitution
Speaker 2:  to explicitly reference Apple and Google and i's like, well we're not gonna,
Speaker 2:  that's not gonna happen. And so nothing happens and it, it just feels like
Speaker 2:  at some point, one of the things I have thought over the last couple of years
Speaker 2:  is that maybe some of these antitrust fights might be a thing
Speaker 2:  where you can actually pick one chunk of what's going
Speaker 2:  on and do something about it. And part of me, like the, one of the reasons
Speaker 2:  I've been so interested in this us versus Google search defaults thing is
Speaker 2:  like that that is a finite sized thing that you could regulate.
Speaker 2:  Right? And and I think like Benedict Evans, the the venture capitalist said
Speaker 2:  this to me years ago and and I think he's right that it's like we don't regulate
Speaker 2:  cars, we regulate every single thing inside of a car and that's how we regulate
Speaker 2:  cars. His case was that's how we should regulate privacy and the internet.
Speaker 2:  We shouldn't regulate the internet, we should regulate all of the things
Speaker 2:  that happen piece by piece because regulating the internet or
Speaker 2:  technology is impossible and it's too big. And I think with all this
Speaker 2:  antitrust stuff, and I think the, the Epic Apple thing is a good example
Speaker 2:  because anti steering is another tiny sort of finite piece
Speaker 2:  that you can break off and make decisions about that has real meaningful
Speaker 2:  change for the industry. And I guess the question is like can you build up
Speaker 2:  a bunch of those over time or are we eventually gonna need this sort of
Speaker 2:  one big giant sweeping something that just like blows everything up and then
Speaker 2:  we see what happens, which tends to be like every 25 years it seems like
Speaker 2:  we get one of those from the government. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  Well also when it comes to enforcement, I think people have been waiting
Speaker 6:  for that too. Like I think that's why we're waiting on legislation, that's
Speaker 6:  why we're waiting on a lot of things. The problem with enforcement is that
Speaker 6:  our enforcers don't have that many resources.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. They're on like Windows 98 computers trying to figure this out.
Speaker 6:  Exactly. So I, that's one problem. And then even if they do go ahead
Speaker 6:  and win a case that is one company You know, look at I, I like to
Speaker 6:  think about all the stuff Facebook had to agree to
Speaker 6:  You know after Cambridge Analytica, there was some AI stuff in there if I
Speaker 6:  remember correctly and all this kind of stuff in this You know agreement
Speaker 6:  with the FTC. The same thing with Twitter. Twitter with its security and
Speaker 6:  safety practices. The reason why the FTC is investigating Elon Musk's Twitter
Speaker 6:  right now is because of this 2011 consent decree
Speaker 6:  with the agency. You know about these things and it gives them the leverage
Speaker 6:  and the authority to go ahead and reinvestigate, but of course You know it's
Speaker 6:  these specific agreements with specific companies and
Speaker 6:  it's a lot harder right, to do something new or like to continue
Speaker 6:  and like investigate everyone. You have to kind of target the
Speaker 6:  people who you feel are the worst actors and then fix things there.
Speaker 6:  But it You know it's, it's one company. It's maybe setting a standard
Speaker 6:  and like a precedent for how other companies act, but they're not going to
Speaker 6:  be You know breaking the law if they act similarly later.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, that that's very fair. One of the things I think is different about
Speaker 2:  a lot of these fights and Epic versus Google is that this is a
Speaker 2:  jury trial, which strikes me as very different from a lot of the stuff that
Speaker 2:  we've seen, which is not essentially the government arguing one side
Speaker 2:  and the company arguing another side and a judge having to decide who's right.
Speaker 2:  Like that's a, that's a thing we've come to understand. There have been a
Speaker 2:  lot of those, this is just gonna be like a dozen random
Speaker 2:  people off the street who are deciding what's going on here. Is
Speaker 2:  is that potentially as different a thing as it seems like it might be to
Speaker 2:  me in terms of how this case might go?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I mean like you're saying antitrust trials are typically bench trials,
Speaker 6:  right? Like it is the judge making the decision and I can't remember
Speaker 6:  really anything else in recent history where we've seen this
Speaker 6:  with people being forced to reckon with like Congress
Speaker 6:  can't even make sense of like old antitrust laws and how we should apply
Speaker 6:  them to tech technology companies right now. And hell I have
Speaker 6:  issues with it sometimes too because it's like having faith that
Speaker 6:  You know these attorneys make the proper case and these
Speaker 6:  folks can make the right decision. But again, like your average
Speaker 6:  person is not stupid either. I think what Epic really
Speaker 6:  wants here is to not get into the weeds on the numbers
Speaker 6:  and You know the sheer size and all of these You know very like
Speaker 6:  granular arguments we can have and they probably wanna see You know the the
Speaker 6:  grander argument, the bigger argument how these app markets should
Speaker 6:  operate And, what these You know taxes and fees and all these things mean
Speaker 6:  and how You know the average person like me and you, the average consumer
Speaker 6:  wants to interact with these You know platforms day in and day out. And I
Speaker 6:  think that lends itself better to this. I think it's like a 10 person yeah
Speaker 6:  jury that will start hearing these arguments on Monday.
Speaker 2:  It seems to me, and this is based on nothing but just the gut
Speaker 2:  feeling that I'm having, that the fact that it's a jury trial would stand
Speaker 2:  to benefit Epic a lot more than it would stand to benefit Google because
Speaker 2:  I feel like if I'm the prosecutor, all I have to do now
Speaker 2:  is tell a convincing story basically about David and Goliath,
Speaker 2:  right? About a gigantic tech company that is preventing not just me
Speaker 2:  but I'm fighting on behalf of every small developer everywhere who is having
Speaker 2:  to essentially give a portion of our earnings to the king, right?
Speaker 2:  Like that is borderline on American that that's how we have to do this.
Speaker 2:  And I feel like again, I think you're right, we're gonna get away from a
Speaker 2:  lot of the technicalities and like being in the courtroom for USV Google,
Speaker 2:  it is all about technicalities. Like all they talk about is deal structure
Speaker 2:  and revenue sharing and the like tiny little mechanical economic details
Speaker 2:  of how this stuff works. I would assume, and it's totally possible I end
Speaker 2:  up being wrong that this ends up being a much less technical trial because
Speaker 2:  what they have to do, like you were saying, is essentially tell a story to
Speaker 2:  a jury that is going to have to then apply it to a hundred year old precedent.
Speaker 2:  That arguably doesn't make any sense in the current context and
Speaker 2:  I assume whatever way this goes, it is going to be absolutely ripe for appeal
Speaker 2:  and everything's gonna get weird even more so than most of these cases because
Speaker 2:  it's a jury trial. But it just seems like we're gonna get much more
Speaker 2:  feelings and sort of grand storytelling as opposed to like a parade of
Speaker 2:  expert witnesses telling you how contracts work,
Speaker 6:  Right? I mean it makes the most sense. If I was Epic's attorney right now,
Speaker 6:  that would be my, my approach is focus
Speaker 6:  more on storytelling than like overwhelming people with
Speaker 6:  these ridiculous You know numbers and economic data and everything.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, it's gonna be really interesting to see, I'm sort of sad we're not
Speaker 2:  gonna get as much access to this one as we did Epic v Apple, which you
Speaker 2:  could like because it was covid, it was ironically more publicly available.
Speaker 2:  This one we we're back to much more closed down, but Sean Hollister is gonna
Speaker 2:  be in the courtroom store. We're gonna see a bunch of stuff we are you looking
Speaker 2:  for in in this one? Like is there is, are we looking to see
Speaker 2:  if Epic can get another version of kind of the small wins it got an Apple,
Speaker 2:  is this gonna be a much bigger win or lose? Like how would you sort of
Speaker 2:  handicap the odds here? Yeah,
Speaker 6:  I'd want to first hear the arguments on like you were bringing up earlier
Speaker 6:  about the Samsung store, the ability to load apps and stuff on
Speaker 6:  outside of the Play store. I'm curious how those arguments are made. What
Speaker 6:  we hear from the Judge You know and the You know the mind reading of the
Speaker 6:  jury on that of reporters in the room. And I think that will really
Speaker 6:  color what we can expect because if
Speaker 6:  we're right here and we're talking about You know something that is focused
Speaker 6:  more on storytelling than You know this like granular evidence,
Speaker 6:  I think that is where we are going to get the best idea of what
Speaker 6:  You know this end result will look like.
Speaker 2:  Alright. Sean Hollister is gonna be in the courtroom so we'll grab him on
Speaker 2:  this show at some point in the next, I think this supposed to be five weeks
Speaker 2:  is the plan for this one.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it's supposed to end right before
Speaker 2:  Christmas. Okay, well God help us all for the next five weeks. I know,
Speaker 2:  but yeah, we'll we'll check back in and, and keep it locked on the site.
Speaker 2:  Sean's gonna be covering it for us. Makena, thank you as always. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  No problem.
Speaker 2:  Alright, we gotta take a break and then we will be back to talk Sam. Bankman
Speaker 2:  free. We'll be right back.
Speaker 7:  Support for this show comes from Wix web agencies. You're gonna like this
Speaker 7:  one. Let me tell you about Wix Studio. The platform that gives agencies total
Speaker 7:  creative freedom to deliver complex client sites while still smashing
Speaker 7:  deadlines. How? First, let's talk about the advanced design capabilities.
Speaker 7:  With Wix Studio you can build unique layouts with a revolutionary grid
Speaker 7:  experience and watch those elements scale proportionally by default. No code
Speaker 7:  animations at sparks of delight while custom CSS gives total design
Speaker 7:  control, but it doesn't stop there. Bring ambitious client projects to life
Speaker 7:  in any industry with a fully integrated suite of business solutions
Speaker 7:  from e-comm to events bookings and more and extend the capabilities
Speaker 7:  even further with hundreds of APIs and integrations and You know what else
Speaker 7:  The workflows, they just make sense. There's the built-in AI
Speaker 7:  tools, the centralized workspace, the on canvas collaborating, the
Speaker 7:  reuse of assets across sites, the seamless client handover. And that's not
Speaker 7:  all. Find out more at Wix dot com slash studio
Speaker 7:  Support for The. Vergecast comes from IRLA new show from Mozilla. For
Speaker 7:  all the noise out there about ai, it's more than worth considering the real
Speaker 7:  people behind it. All policies and practices are taking shape right now.
Speaker 7:  They'll define how we talk about AI for the next generation. The podcast
Speaker 7:  IRL is all about that. It's hosted by Bridget Todd and their current season
Speaker 7:  is all about people over profit. Some questions they tackle. How do you
Speaker 7:  build a truly trustworthy and responsible ai? What does innovation look like
Speaker 7:  when a trillion dollar company and investors aren't calling all the shots
Speaker 7:  and the people come first? In one episode of IRL, you'll hear the stories
Speaker 7:  of people pushing back against companies that hired millions of quote unquote
Speaker 7:  invisible workers. Sometimes for as little as $2 an hour
Speaker 7:  to review toxic disturbing content in order to keep it off. Generative AI
Speaker 7:  like chat GPT, you'll hear about those people developing AI tools that
Speaker 7:  don't rely on putting laborers in those positions. Instead they try to empower
Speaker 7:  the folks working behind the scenes to make machine learning systems that
Speaker 7:  can work for the rest of us. Search for Mozilla IRL in your podcast
Speaker 7:  player or visit irl podcast.org.
Speaker 2:  All right, we're back last week after a truly wild
Speaker 2:  trial that lasted more than a month and a saga in general that lasted
Speaker 2:  almost exactly to the day a year. FTX founder
Speaker 2:  Sam Bankman Freed was found guilty on seven counts, which included wire
Speaker 2:  fraud conspiracy to commit wire fraud and conspiracy to commit money
Speaker 2:  laundering. The short version of a really long story is that SBF was accused
Speaker 2:  and convicted of using Ft X's customer deposits to shore up his crypto
Speaker 2:  trading firm called Alameda Research. Throughout the whole trial, his
Speaker 2:  former colleagues testified that FTX falsified numbers gave
Speaker 2:  Alameda special privileges including to lose billions of dollars and that
Speaker 2:  he lied to the public and users about where their money was.
Speaker 2:  Prosecutors said FTX was a fraud from the start and a jury
Speaker 2:  agreed in a certain sense the SBF story is now over
Speaker 2:  or at least almost over, given that he's set to be sentenced in March. And
Speaker 2:  the verges, Liz Lipato has watched it all go down. She was in the courtroom
Speaker 2:  for the entire trial watching the whole thing unravel So I brought
Speaker 2:  her in to see what she saw, how it felt. And what happens next. Liz.
Speaker 2:  Hello.
Speaker 6:  Hi David. How's it going?
Speaker 2:  You survived. I'm so proud of you.
Speaker 6:  I made it.
Speaker 2:  How do you, how is your like head space after what, six weeks of sitting
Speaker 2:  in a courtroom?
Speaker 6:  Oh man. Well I'm very ready to do something else.
Speaker 6:  Fair. But it was intense. I mean it was like a You know a I
Speaker 6:  wasn't just sitting in the courtroom, I was also standing outside the courtroom
Speaker 6:  at the wee hours of the morning. Many mornings. Yeah. So I.
Speaker 6:  I am excited to have a life again 'cause this was like sort of an aesthetic
Speaker 6:  experience for about a month.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I do actually wanna talk about the sort of spectacle of this. 'cause
Speaker 2:  I remember one of the things we talked about I think on the show before it
Speaker 2:  started was how much kind of
Speaker 2:  outside interest there was gonna be. Like we, it was obviously gonna be a
Speaker 2:  very high profile trial, but the question of like, are there gonna be crypto
Speaker 2:  fan boys outside the courtroom every morning or like are there gonna
Speaker 2:  be there, there were like the Elizabeth Holmes cosplay that the Theranos
Speaker 2:  trial. Are we gonna get some of that? The only bit of story that I heard
Speaker 2:  was that we literally had to hire a line sitter for you at one point because
Speaker 2:  the line for the Sam bits of testimony was so early
Speaker 2:  that it was like untenable for you to be there early
Speaker 2:  enough to get in line. So like was it like that the whole trial, how crazy
Speaker 2:  did it get?
Speaker 6:  So the Sam testimony was the peak, especially the Sam cross. And
Speaker 6:  the way that line sitter thing worked was like I got in line
Speaker 6:  on Sunday night for Monday. Like I got in line at like,
Speaker 6:  I don't know, 1145 on Sunday night. Good
Speaker 6:  Lord. Because I knew there was going to be a lot of interest and I was to
Speaker 6:  be clear like fourth. Wow. Yeah. So the
Speaker 6:  first person who had gotten there had gotten there around 10 30 and You know
Speaker 6:  the day ended. I was like so tired. I felt drunk and I still had a story
Speaker 6:  to write. Yeah. And I remember going in to
Speaker 6:  like, 'cause nobody's up yet. Like, we're going into the building, it's seven
Speaker 6:  30, the editors haven't logged on. And I was just texting them like, I
Speaker 6:  can't do this Tuesday. Like Tuesday You know I'm gonna, I'm gonna write.
Speaker 6:  And then I, I don't have enough time to like have dinner and sleep because
Speaker 2:  You would literally have to walk out of the courtroom, file your story and
Speaker 2:  then walk back to the courtroom.
Speaker 6:  That's right. So that's how we ended up with a line center on Tuesday. I,
Speaker 6:  I got like six hours of sleep and it was like the best six hours of sleep
Speaker 6:  I've ever had in my life. It was so rewarding. It felt amazing. That's
Speaker 2:  Very good. So it wasn't like that the whole time. That was just the, the
Speaker 2:  Sam
Speaker 6:  Bits. Oh yeah. I mean like You know Caroline Ellison was the other sort
Speaker 6:  of big draw and that was like, that was a much more reasonable 4:00 AM
Speaker 6:  time to get line super chill. There was just, there were a lot of people
Speaker 6:  there. It was, especially for the Sam testimony, there were a lot of people
Speaker 6:  who were You know they worked in tech or they worked in finance or they like
Speaker 6:  had an interest in crypto. A lot of reporters obviously. So
Speaker 6:  there was just a, it was a pretty big draw from the general public and there
Speaker 6:  were like a couple of people who were in town from
Speaker 6:  London or from Ireland who had stopped by the
Speaker 6:  trial. And so that was like pretty remarkable to me. It
Speaker 2:  Was like a tourist attraction. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  So there was absolutely, there was a certain amount of like spectacle.
Speaker 6:  There weren't any cos players like there were at the Holmes trial. We didn't
Speaker 6:  see like You know the art students who were setting up like
Speaker 6:  Theranos themed like gift shops or anything like that. But there was
Speaker 6:  some very, very intense interest from a lot of people who
Speaker 6:  had been following this. That's
Speaker 2:  Just nuts. So, and I'm, I'm particularly curious, we've obviously, we know
Speaker 2:  how the trial ended, which we're gonna get to in a minute, but I'm, I'm super
Speaker 2:  curious about the vibes in the courtroom, which I feel like is one of the
Speaker 2:  things you wrote a lot about was you spent a lot of time watching
Speaker 2:  one person's testimony while watching somebody else just sort of be in the
Speaker 2:  courtroom. That's right. And especially Sam and
Speaker 2:  Caroline for a chunk of it. And Sam's parents, I feel like were kind of your
Speaker 2:  main characters for obvious reasons throughout the whole trial. And I'm really
Speaker 2:  curious how the kind of vibes shifted from the beginning
Speaker 2:  of the trial to the end of the trial just as like a person in the room in
Speaker 2:  the courtroom.
Speaker 6:  So this is why I wanted to be in the courtroom is that there are things that
Speaker 6:  play really differently in the courtroom than they do even in the overflow
Speaker 6:  rooms or in the transcript or on Twitter. And I was really struck by
Speaker 6:  that throughout this trial. You know we had moments of levity that like people
Speaker 6:  didn't think were funny outside of the courtroom, for instance. So like the
Speaker 6:  best example was when Sam was testifying and his lawyer successfully
Speaker 6:  objected to a question and Sam responded anyway that he
Speaker 6:  thought You know embezzling money was not protecting customer assets. And
Speaker 6:  his lawyer was kinda like, Sam, you've been here for a couple weeks, You
Speaker 6:  know you don't have to answer that. And Sam was like, yeah, but I, I felt
Speaker 6:  like it was important. And that was like a big laugh line in the courtroom.
Speaker 6:  And the way that it seemed to play elsewhere was that he was getting scolded,
Speaker 6:  which like, it was like a little bit of a scolding, but it was, it was playful
Speaker 6:  You know. So there were these moments that I i, that's part of the
Speaker 6:  reason why I was getting up at those kind of insane hours was I wanted to
Speaker 6:  really sort of describe what was happening in the room because
Speaker 6:  the text only version of that doesn't give you how people are feeling.
Speaker 6:  And part of it was that I wanted to keep an eye on the jury and by the
Speaker 6:  end of the prosecution's case, the jury was really fed up with Sam
Speaker 6:  Bankman Fried. And this was before he took the stand. I wanna be clear. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Like You know we have, we have Caroline testifying to You
Speaker 6:  know the sort of arc of her, her time at Alameda and ending
Speaker 6:  with this all hands meeting where she essentially confesses to her staff
Speaker 6:  what has happened. And then immediately afterwards we have Christian
Speaker 6:  droppy getting up on the stand. He's a former
Speaker 6:  employee, he's got the recording of her You know doing it.
Speaker 6:  And the jury was really wrapped for that. I know that it played
Speaker 6:  a little differently again for other people who like was like, oh, she's
Speaker 6:  like giggling You know. But the jury was absolutely locked
Speaker 6:  in You know this was something that they took very seriously. And part of
Speaker 6:  the reason he had been called was to talk about the way that she was speaking
Speaker 6:  on the tape. He, he noted that she has a habit of giggling
Speaker 6:  nervously. Like when there are times of tension, she, she tends to laugh
Speaker 6:  uncomfortably and like, so that was part of the reason I think that he was
Speaker 6:  giving the ta that testimony was to to say like, she's not laughing like
Speaker 6:  out of joy or anything. Like this is a, a very uncomfortable moment for her.
Speaker 6:  Nice. Right. As that tape was playing, I was watching members of the jury
Speaker 6:  like shaking their heads Mm. Like no. And like
Speaker 6:  I saw them shake their heads again at the sort of towards the end of the
Speaker 6:  prosecution's case where can's son, who is one of
Speaker 6:  the FTX lawyers was testifying that Sam, Beckman Fried had come
Speaker 6:  to him and talked about wanting to find an excuse to give
Speaker 6:  Apollo the private equity group. He was trying to raise money from an
Speaker 6:  explanation legally for how all of this money had gone missing. And
Speaker 6:  Kane's Sun like ran through three explanations. It was like none of them,
Speaker 6:  none of them do it. Like, and then he quit. Oh boy. And
Speaker 6:  this, this is sort of a recurring theme. Yeah. You know. We immediately saw
Speaker 6:  Sam Bick Madre in a December interview with George Stephanopoulos
Speaker 6:  running through one of these explanations and saying, oh it was the margin
Speaker 6:  lending program, which Canson had been very clear with him. Like it was so
Speaker 6:  much more money than was in the margin lending program. There's no good explanation
Speaker 6:  for this. And again, during this video clip you could see members of the
Speaker 6:  jury like shaking their heads like, no, like this, this is,
Speaker 6:  this is ridiculous. So there was sort of You know this sense
Speaker 6:  of almost absurdity Hmm. By the end of the prosecution's
Speaker 6:  case because every day I would come in and then there would be like
Speaker 6:  a new crime. And like at one point I remember turning
Speaker 6:  to another reporter, like when we were standing in line and being like, look,
Speaker 6:  I knew he was guilty but didn didn't know. He was like guilty. Guilty. He
Speaker 6:  is like guiltier than I thought. The prosecution easily could have arrested
Speaker 6:  their case after the second week and we had two more weeks. So
Speaker 6:  it was, it was a lot of evidence. It was really like an overwhelming amount
Speaker 6:  of evidence. And You know by the end we had a pretty good idea of what
Speaker 6:  had happened. And then I guess the idea behind Sam testifying is
Speaker 6:  sort of something that you get in these white collar cases where intent really
Speaker 6:  matters. You may remember that Elizabeth Holmes testified in her own trial
Speaker 6:  too. Yep. And who can speak to the intent better than the person who
Speaker 6:  is is there
Speaker 2:  And the defense just a button on that the, the defense in that case
Speaker 2:  basically is either I didn't know or I
Speaker 2:  didn't mean to essentially Right. Because it, it kind of boils down to like,
Speaker 2:  did you do this on purpose or not? And if you can convincingly say you didn't
Speaker 2:  do it on purpose, you might get away with it.
Speaker 6:  That's right. Good intentions are a complete defense. Like it's not illegal
Speaker 6:  to be an idiot, which is lucky for me. The lying is the illegal part.
Speaker 6:  It's not that he lost all this money, it's that he lied to people. That's
Speaker 6:  the fraud piece of it. So if he had believed what he was saying,
Speaker 6:  if he hadn't known that it was untrue, that would be a complete
Speaker 6:  defense. That would be enough. And the problem with putting your defendant
Speaker 6:  on the stand in that way is you open them up to cross examination
Speaker 6:  and that can be really gnarly. And that was really gnarly. Like that was,
Speaker 6:  I've seen a lot of cross examinations and that was probably the nastiest
Speaker 6:  I think I've ever seen. Wow. Danielle Sassoon, who was the prosecutor, she
Speaker 6:  clearly knew just backwards and forwards everything Sam, begman,
Speaker 6:  Fried had ever said in public. Just like all indexed in her brain.
Speaker 2:  Which is a lot by the way that man has talked in public so much.
Speaker 6:  So much. Yeah. So we had, we had like a long section of her saying,
Speaker 6:  did you say this? And him being like, I don't recall. And then her playing
Speaker 6:  it and then her saying, did you say this? And him saying, I don't recall.
Speaker 6:  And her playing it, oh boy You know, it was like a couple hours of this
Speaker 6:  and it really established him as like an unreliable narrator. Particularly
Speaker 6:  because he wasn't saying something like, I don't remember saying that specifically,
Speaker 6:  but it sounds like something I would've said. It was just like, I don't recall.
Speaker 6:  I don't recall. I don't recall. And like after a certain point again you
Speaker 6:  see like the jury starting to make like prolonged eye contact with each other.
Speaker 6:  Like You know when somebody's misbehaving on the subway and you make eye
Speaker 6:  contact with a stranger. Like do you see the shit? Yeah. Like it was very
Speaker 6:  that so that was not great. No and it's
Speaker 6:  not what you want. It's not
Speaker 2:  Well and it also seems like that specific thing is part of the shift
Speaker 2:  I think that you covered in a lot of your stories is like at the beginning
Speaker 2:  of the trial, Sam thought and a big part of his whole
Speaker 2:  shtick had been that you can get an awfully long way with
Speaker 2:  this kind of moppy haired, slightly
Speaker 2:  spacey genius weirdo. And that that affectation ironically, like
Speaker 2:  you and I have been covering this space a long time, like there's no better
Speaker 2:  way to be a billionaire than to have that specific deal. People
Speaker 2:  will just throw money at you if you seem like you don't care how you dress
Speaker 2:  or what you look like or whatever. But then at some point over the course
Speaker 2:  of that trial that went from being like his greatest asset or at least what
Speaker 2:  he thought was his asset to like the thing that destroyed him in a
Speaker 2:  lot of ways
Speaker 6:  So, I wanna put a little button on that. It's not people that will give you
Speaker 6:  a lot of money, it's specifically VCs that will give you a lot of money.
Speaker 2:  That's a very good distinction. Yes.
Speaker 6:  VCs have like a specific model of what they think a genius looks like. And
Speaker 6:  he played very much into that. The problem is if you are
Speaker 6:  marketing yourself as a genius, if you're saying you're brilliant, if you
Speaker 6:  You know are putting yourself forth as like someone who is really, really
Speaker 6:  smart, you have a harder time showing
Speaker 6:  yourself to be stupid. Like, I mean that's like part of what's going on here,
Speaker 6:  right? Like he doesn't have ACFO at this company even though
Speaker 6:  it's a financial company. And that's like very important. He doesn't have
Speaker 6:  any risk management, which you're running a futures exchange risk
Speaker 6:  is what you do. Yeah. And trying to, to hold those two things
Speaker 6:  together in your mind that this guy's a genius and that there's no risk management,
Speaker 6:  there's no CFO, there are no no adults in the room that
Speaker 6:  starts to look damning, that starts to look like you did something on purpose.
Speaker 6:  It starts to look like you don't want risk management because you think risk
Speaker 6:  management won't approve of what you did. And so that's sort of,
Speaker 6:  I think one of the specific ways where this backfired. Like I
Speaker 6:  think that there could have been a lot more understanding
Speaker 6:  if he had been an ordinary person. Ironically
Speaker 6:  You know where it's like, oh yeah, ordinarily ordinary people like misplaced
Speaker 6:  things. Like they'd sometimes do dumb stuff. But You know if you're presenting
Speaker 6:  yourself as like this genius and he was You know, he was leaning very
Speaker 6:  heavily on like having gone to MIT having
Speaker 6:  worked at Jane Street, which is a pretty exclusive firm on Wall Street,
Speaker 6:  having been this like startup founder having done this incredible like
Speaker 6:  arbitrage trade to get his money. Like if your whole
Speaker 6:  story is that you're brilliant and then $8 billion
Speaker 6:  goes missing, people are not going to think you lost it.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And then a bunch of people get up on the stand and testify how you
Speaker 2:  did it.
Speaker 6:  In fact, you did not lose it. That's right.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And I think so much of what it seems
Speaker 2:  that he thought, and I, I am curious, like I generally am not
Speaker 2:  interested in trying to like psychoanalyze people in his
Speaker 2:  position, but like my guy just like got up on the stand for three days and
Speaker 2:  did it so we're gonna do it to him. You got the sense he felt like
Speaker 2:  through this whole process he could sort of smart guy his way out
Speaker 2:  of everything. And like, again, not to keep coming back to the Theranos thing,
Speaker 2:  but I think it's like there was this sense of if we can just get away with
Speaker 2:  it long enough, we'll eventually get where we're going and everything will
Speaker 2:  be fine and it'll be worth it. And like that's not even to bring in all of
Speaker 2:  the effective altruism, I'm gonna save the world stuff. Which like I'm just,
Speaker 2:  I'm done with that. Like I don't think, I don't care anymore that he was
Speaker 2:  an effective altruist. I'm no longer interested in that fact about him. But
Speaker 2:  I do think he thought he could just like smart guy his way through these
Speaker 2:  troubles and he was so smart that everything was gonna be fine and
Speaker 2:  that just, it just doesn't work. And I think even in this trial you
Speaker 2:  get the sense that he thought he could just get up there and smart guy his
Speaker 2:  way through it and that he would win in the end. And that was so
Speaker 2:  spectacularly the wrong call in this trial it seems.
Speaker 6:  I mean, watching his parents during the cross-examination was
Speaker 6:  sad
Speaker 2:  I'm sure.
Speaker 6:  And they, they left for the end of it. And I don't blame them
Speaker 6:  because it was, it was really nasty. It was
Speaker 6:  obvious what was happening. It was obvious what the outcome was going to
Speaker 6:  be and I wouldn't wanna watch that happen to my child either. But it
Speaker 6:  felt like throughout the course of the trial there was like
Speaker 6:  a delusion almost on at least Sam's part and maybe the part of his
Speaker 6:  parents as well that You know everything was going to be okay
Speaker 6:  because Sam was a really good guy and he never would've done anything wrong.
Speaker 6:  And that was, as far as I could tell, the entire defense
Speaker 6:  was like You know Sam talked about how he didn't drink when
Speaker 6:  he was in college and he You know, liked to play board
Speaker 6:  games and he was very wholesome and like
Speaker 6:  You know he was, he's a good boy. And I
Speaker 6:  think there was an understanding that Bateman Fried has of
Speaker 6:  himself and that his parents have of him that ran pretty much
Speaker 6:  headlong into the rest of the world and the way the rest of the world
Speaker 6:  understood him to be working. And certainly by the time of the
Speaker 6:  closing statements, I think everybody understood what was going to happen.
Speaker 2:  I was just about to ask that, like at what point did the whole room sort
Speaker 2:  of realize, oh, he's gonna be convicted. Was it closing arguments? I
Speaker 2:  kind of felt like reading your stories, it felt like it might've happened
Speaker 2:  before that.
Speaker 6:  It definitely happened before that for me. Okay. I think it happened before
Speaker 6:  that for several members of the jury, they weren't out very long. They were
Speaker 6:  out for four and a half hours. That's not a long time.
Speaker 2:  No, that's long enough to like have a coffee, look around the room and be
Speaker 2:  like, we good. And then go back in. Like that's not, that's not a group of
Speaker 2:  people who had a lot to talk about for four hours.
Speaker 6:  I mean they did, they did send in for like a couple of questions. They had
Speaker 6:  some questions around the investor testimony they wanted portions of that
Speaker 6:  sent in. But that was fast. You know something like this, a
Speaker 6:  complicated trial like this. I actually wasn't expecting a verdict until
Speaker 6:  the next week. I was expecting a verdict the following like Monday or Tuesday
Speaker 6:  and we just went right through and that was it. So 8:00 PM like
Speaker 6:  we had a verdict. But the reason I I come back to the, the closing
Speaker 6:  statements was that I was really struck by Sam
Speaker 6:  who had turned towards the jury and So I could see the side of his face
Speaker 6:  and he looked like he either had been crying or was about to cry.
Speaker 6:  You know his nose was red. He, he looked devastated basically.
Speaker 6:  And So I think, that's why I think he knew there was this very emotional
Speaker 6:  moment from him, of his attorney reading this closing
Speaker 6:  statement and him just looking terrified and
Speaker 6:  perhaps crying You know. And his parents throughout seemed
Speaker 6:  really horrified by the testimony. At
Speaker 6:  times You know, I could see his mother with her, her head and her hands.
Speaker 6:  It was rough and You know, one of the sort of recurring themes throughout
Speaker 6:  my cover like coverage is I just couldn't figure out why we were there. Like,
Speaker 6:  I don't know why you, you wouldn't just plead like that's the part that's
Speaker 6:  wild to me, right? Like, okay, maybe you're not gonna get a deal, but
Speaker 6:  if you plead guilty and you throw yourself on the mercy of the judge and
Speaker 6:  you say, I'm very very sorry, I heard a lot of people I did wrong, I wanna
Speaker 6:  be punished. Maybe you get a shorter sentence that way.
Speaker 6:  And even if you don't, you haven't dragged everybody you
Speaker 6:  love through this spectacle of a trial. Because if you think about it, like
Speaker 6:  the scale of destruction here is unusual. I mean,
Speaker 6:  there's obviously all of these customers who've lost money
Speaker 6:  and many of whom maybe don't wanna go public about how much money they've
Speaker 6:  lost because they feel silly about it. But like those people You know they
Speaker 6:  deserve our sympathy. I think the investors who've lost money,
Speaker 6:  the lenders who lost money, like one of them block fi ended
Speaker 6:  up going bankrupt. And it wasn't, this wasn't the only thing that pushed
Speaker 6:  them into bankruptcy, but it sure didn't help You know. And then on top of
Speaker 6:  sort of all of that, like destruction, You know a lot of the
Speaker 6:  FTX employees kept their money on the exchange. So they're the people
Speaker 6:  who are also wrapped up in this bankruptcy. Like they, they, they had no
Speaker 6:  idea most of them that anything was going wrong. That you think about Adam
Speaker 6:  ya DIA's testimony and like there was this horrible sort of
Speaker 6:  moment towards the end of it where one of the text messages he had read to
Speaker 6:  was read aloud. You know it was, he was telling Sam he loved him, he would
Speaker 6:  stand by him, he would try to like fix FTX. And then he found out what had
Speaker 6:  actually happened and he immediately quit. Wow. I want you to think about
Speaker 6:  this. This is like one of Sam's best friends from college. They were like
Speaker 6:  frat boys together. They shared a You know they were roommates in college,
Speaker 6:  they were roommates in The Bahamas. Like this is like one of his closest
Speaker 6:  friends. I want you to just hold that in your mind for a minute. Think about
Speaker 6:  your closest friend and how pissed off they would have to be at you, how
Speaker 6:  betrayed they would have to feel to testify against you at
Speaker 6:  trial.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And, and there was so much of that. I mean, I think the extent to
Speaker 2:  which, and, and you wrote about this at one point that like, I think you
Speaker 2:  called it like summer camp syndrome. Yeah. That it's just a group of friends
Speaker 2:  who all essentially turned all at once
Speaker 2:  on Sam at the end of this. I, I like, I think you're right. It it is
Speaker 2:  sort of unusual that everybody told the exact same story,
Speaker 2:  which I think in the end made it really easy in a lot of ways. Like
Speaker 2:  the prosecutor's story was so simple and so straightforward and so
Speaker 2:  corroborated by so many people. And then Sam's story was like
Speaker 2:  the Sam's story, but he just said he didn't know about any of it,
Speaker 6:  Right?
Speaker 2:  He, he clearly deserved to be convicted because all the evidence that so,
Speaker 2:  but the it it also just seemed like he was the, the weight of
Speaker 2:  the evidence against him was so sort of uniquely pointed and
Speaker 2:  strong in that sense.
Speaker 6:  Well and even assuming there hadn't been testimony
Speaker 6:  from his conspirators, You know his co-conspirators, all
Speaker 6:  of whom were like, yeah we worked together with Sam on this.
Speaker 6:  Just looking at where the money went and who benefited
Speaker 6:  from that money. Sam benefited more than anyone You know.
Speaker 6:  These were investments that he wanted to make. His parents got a home in
Speaker 6:  The Bahamas and that was traced back to FTX investor money. He got a
Speaker 6:  bunch of Robinhood shares and a personally owned vehicle like
Speaker 6:  just looking at You know who benefits like not even
Speaker 6:  thinking about like the blow by blow of how it happened. It's kind
Speaker 6:  of open and shut. And so to me You know there were all of these
Speaker 6:  moments where I kept being like, why are we here? Like literally why are
Speaker 6:  we here? You know like plead guilty and
Speaker 6:  spare You. know your family and friends this humiliation and maybe they'll
Speaker 6:  come visit you in jail.
Speaker 2:  So speaking of the, the ramifications of all of this, I feel like I've seen
Speaker 2:  two narratives over the last few days start to come out. One is that
Speaker 2:  Silicon Valley, as it does, will just move on. The VC
Speaker 2:  class is not going to do the self introspection that everybody always
Speaker 2:  wants them to do In moments like this. They didn't do it with Theranos, they're
Speaker 2:  not gonna do it now you just move on to the next thing. They're all pouring
Speaker 2:  money into AI stuff. And then on the flip side, there is this sense
Speaker 2:  that this is kind of a broader crypto reckoning. One
Speaker 2:  of the things we talked about at the beginning of the trial was how much
Speaker 2:  crypto industry dirt was gonna come out of this one way or the other about
Speaker 2:  how kind of unwatched and unmanaged a lot of this space is.
Speaker 2:  I have a hard time figuring out kind of what the macro
Speaker 2:  legacy of this trial is gonna be. Do you have a sense even just a few days
Speaker 2:  out? I
Speaker 6:  Think I do. And part of it is because there were crypto industry people who
Speaker 6:  were coming to the trial and so during Gary Wong's
Speaker 6:  testimony about the faked insurance fund,
Speaker 6:  'cause like this was just like Russian nesting dolls of crime.
Speaker 6:  But there, there was a random number generator that they had that was their
Speaker 6:  insurance fund. There was no insurance fund. Alameda was paying stuff out.
Speaker 6:  One of the people who I was talking to who was a crypto investor was like,
Speaker 6:  oh, Binance has an insurance fund. I wonder if that's
Speaker 6:  real too. Mm. Some things that are different, right? Like for instance there
Speaker 6:  are exchanges where You know which ones are the omnibus wallets. You
Speaker 6:  can watch them, you can sort of see on chain what's going on. But there
Speaker 6:  are going to be I think larger questions of who's telling the
Speaker 6:  truth. Because Sam said all the right things in terms of wanting
Speaker 6:  regulation, in terms of trying to be safe and trustworthy for
Speaker 6:  customers. And there is going to be because the scale
Speaker 6:  of this fraud was so enormous. I think there is going to be a question for
Speaker 6:  regulators, for customers, for everyone. The next time someone says
Speaker 6:  something like, oh yeah, we want regulation. Like is that true?
Speaker 6:  Sam said that, is that real? And So I think that that's
Speaker 6:  sort of going to be one of the lingering things from this trial more so than
Speaker 6:  anything else is this. This question of like how
Speaker 6:  trustworthy is the crypto industry? And You know this is an
Speaker 6:  industry that is like very, I think proudly full of pirates.
Speaker 6:  These are people who have been operating in sort of legal gray areas, many
Speaker 6:  of whom were excited about that. And that was like part of the joy
Speaker 6:  almost of the industry for a long time. And now it's cutting the other way
Speaker 6:  where it's like, okay, but like do you wanna give your money to pirates?
Speaker 6:  Right? So, I. I think that that's, that's certainly going to be a
Speaker 6:  long-term ramification. As for the VCs, I don't know. I
Speaker 6:  would like to say that I think it might be different. And part of the reason
Speaker 6:  I might say that is that interest rates have been going up
Speaker 6:  and that means that there's less money sloshing into VC than there
Speaker 6:  used to be. And there was this whole period where they had so much money
Speaker 6:  they had to figure out how to invest it somehow. And so like you had
Speaker 6:  mattress companies that were suddenly tech companies 'cause they were selling
Speaker 6:  stuff online, right? You had WeWork, which to Adam
Speaker 6:  Newman's credit, like that was not a fraud. He told everybody that he was
Speaker 6:  planning to benefit disproportionate from WeWork like that and they, they
Speaker 6:  funded it anyway. So there was this period where like the balance of
Speaker 6:  power had really shifted to founders. There was a real sense of FOMO in the
Speaker 6:  investing community. Then you could sort of pressure them into doing deals
Speaker 6:  without due diligence. And So I think as the money is
Speaker 6:  receding, which it has been and as the valuations are getting
Speaker 6:  cut and as like the tide is kind of going out, I think
Speaker 6:  that as well as the sort of profound embarrassments
Speaker 6:  of these major fraud trials may contribute to
Speaker 6:  more careful evaluation. Do I think that that's a guarantee?
Speaker 6:  No, I don't You know, I, I certainly have heard a lot of
Speaker 6:  wild VC talk about like how Elizabeth Holmes
Speaker 6:  wasn't really a product of Silicon Valley and they didn't really do
Speaker 6:  anything wrong and FGX was a standalone fraud and like
Speaker 6:  You know, I think there's a lot of denial, but I certainly think that
Speaker 6:  among the people who are using VC as an investment
Speaker 6:  vehicle You know whether those are family offices, retirement funds,
Speaker 6:  endowments, whatever. If they provide enough pressure
Speaker 6:  that will change things. And so the question is sort of You know who's upstream
Speaker 6:  from the VCs and how much pressure are they putting on, especially now that
Speaker 6:  we are out of this low interest rate environment and there are less risky
Speaker 6:  places for you to make money.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, my, my only worry about that outcome
Speaker 2:  would be that we've been through this in smaller
Speaker 2:  ways a bunch of times now, right? Like I think if you're still a crypto
Speaker 2:  believer, your tolerance for chaos and risk and fraud is so
Speaker 2:  high at this point that I wonder what would
Speaker 2:  possibly turn you off if you're a person who like earnestly believes that
Speaker 2:  crypto is the future of everything, what on earth is left to convince you?
Speaker 2:  This one's a pretty big one. And I think what it might do to your point
Speaker 2:  is it might instill worry in a lot of
Speaker 2:  people like two concentric circles out from the believers, the
Speaker 2:  kinds of people who were like setting up Coinbase accounts two years ago,
Speaker 2:  right? Who were like, what's this? I'm not like a diamond hands crypto
Speaker 2:  maniac, but I'm just like a person who wants to invest my money. And I think
Speaker 2:  you're definitely right that those people are going to remember FTX in a,
Speaker 2:  in a pretty real and pretty damning way for the crypto industry.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I think the true believers, I mean the true believers are the true
Speaker 6:  believers. They're still gonna be there. This is an internet subculture that
Speaker 6:  I think we're going to continue to see for a long time. You know they're
Speaker 6:  already talking about the next cycle.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. This is just crypto winter.
Speaker 6:  That's right. So You know, I don't, I don't know that crypto's gone forever.
Speaker 6:  I certainly don't think that's true. And I also think the approval of a Bitcoin
Speaker 6:  ETF, which is something that the crypto community has really been keeping
Speaker 6:  an eye on that might potentially be a help to them. Like that might be
Speaker 6:  something that gets institutional investors involved, You know your
Speaker 6:  BlackRocks and so on. Is that a guarantee? I don't know.
Speaker 6:  Again, we're in a different investing environment now where there are easier
Speaker 6:  ways, less risky ways to make money because part
Speaker 6:  of what really fueled the last boom was that
Speaker 6:  VCs were able to cash out much more quickly in crypto than they were in a
Speaker 6:  lot of other investments. And so that gave them a pretty quick return and
Speaker 6:  that gave them an incentive to work with a lot of crypto companies.
Speaker 6:  And I think that's less true now. So we'll
Speaker 6:  see. You know and I don't, and I don't necessarily mind weird internet subcultures.
Speaker 6:  I'm
Speaker 2:  Those are your people. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  I love the crypto True believers, they're a lot of fun to hang out with.
Speaker 6:  I don't necessarily agree with them, but they're a great time You know these
Speaker 6:  people. They're not stupid, they're not, they're smart and thoughtful and
Speaker 6:  they don't like the current financial system.
Speaker 2:  Totally All, right? We have to go and you have to go on vacation,
Speaker 2:  but thank you for coming on. You did truly ridiculous work over the last
Speaker 2:  four weeks, so thank you for all of that and for coming on the show. And
Speaker 2:  I have a feeling we're gonna be doing this again. What is it? In March when
Speaker 2:  sentencing happens, March
Speaker 6:  Is when sentencing happens. It's
Speaker 2:  Right. We are not done with this story just yet, so we'll, we'll we'll do
Speaker 2:  this again, but thanks Liz All,
Speaker 6:  Right? Thank you. David
Speaker 2:  All. right. We gotta take one more break and then we'll get to the Hotline.
Speaker 3:  This podcast is brought to you by Meta Quest three, the new mixed reality
Speaker 3:  headset from Meta. Now you can expand your world in ways you never thought
Speaker 3:  possible with the new Meta Quest three, put on the sleek most powerful
Speaker 3:  quest yet and jump into fully immersive games or blend virtual elements
Speaker 3:  into your physical surroundings with mixed reality. Instantly go from
Speaker 3:  watching to playing the part in your favorite show with Stranger Things vr,
Speaker 3:  live the action and really feel what it's like to step into the shoes of
Speaker 3:  an assassin, an Assassin's Creed nexus, even turn your couch
Speaker 3:  into court side seats with X stadium and watch your favorite NBA
Speaker 3:  team. With over 500 titles, it's easy to dive into whatever
Speaker 3:  you're into, expand your world with Meta Quest three, see child
Speaker 3:  safety guidance online accounts for 10 and up certain apps, games and experiences
Speaker 3:  may be suitable for a more mature audience. Learn more@meta.com.
Speaker 8:  Support for this episode comes from Justworks. Hey, small business
Speaker 8:  leaders, do you ever get tired of doing it all? Do you feel like you're too
Speaker 8:  busy cutting checks, filing forms and browsing benefits to even think
Speaker 8:  about the rest of your to-do list. Running a business takes a ton of work,
Speaker 8:  but you don't have to do it alone. Justworks can handle some of the administrative
Speaker 8:  work you don't love with their easy to use platform. You can manage
Speaker 8:  onboarding payroll and PTO all in one place. They specialize
Speaker 8:  in tackling tough tasks like filing tax documents, generating reports,
Speaker 8:  and sorting out state by state regulations to help ensure your business stays
Speaker 8:  compliant so you can focus on doing what you do best. Whether your teams
Speaker 8:  are remote in person or both, they'll help you find health insurance plans
Speaker 8:  that meet your needs and your budget. And if that's not enough, their expert
Speaker 8:  staff is standing by 24 7 to answer any questions.
Speaker 8:  So if you ever feel like your business is running, you visit
Speaker 8:  justworks.com/podcast to see how just works can
Speaker 8:  help you run your business
Speaker 2:  All, right? We're back. Let's get to The. Vergecast Hotline as always, the
Speaker 2:  number is eight six six Verge one, one call and ask us all of your weirdest,
Speaker 2:  deepest, darkest secrets and questions about technology. I don't know
Speaker 2:  how to ask us a secret, but you can do it if you want to. This week we have
Speaker 2:  a question about sports. So Richard Lawler is here to help me answer. Hi
Speaker 2:  Richard. Always
Speaker 3:  Love to talk sports.
Speaker 2:  Yeah man, we don't get to do it that often, so when it's just us we get to
Speaker 2:  talk about sports. This is gonna be a six hour long segment, it's gonna be
Speaker 2:  great. All, right? Let me just play the question, which I think is a very
Speaker 2:  fun one and then we're gonna get into it.
Speaker 9:  Hey David, this is Jeff from North Carolina. I recently listened to
Speaker 9:  your Friday episode where you were talking about the Hulu deal
Speaker 9:  with Disney and Comcast and I'm wondering, you mentioned that you think Disney
Speaker 9:  wants to sell ESPN and I'm curious if you
Speaker 9:  think that Disney would potentially not sell ESPN
Speaker 9:  and instead look for a strategic partnership like Apple
Speaker 9:  to run ESPN with them or do you think ESPN
Speaker 9:  would ever get sold to Apple altogether? Thanks so much the show.
Speaker 9:  Bye.
Speaker 2:  Okay, I love this question because A, it's about ESPN, which I very much
Speaker 2:  enjoy talking about, but B it brings up, I think a thing you and I have talked
Speaker 2:  a bunch about, which is why ESPN is kind of a harbinger of
Speaker 2:  the whole streaming universe. We talked about Disney and Hulu last
Speaker 2:  week. Disney is gonna be required to pay somewhere north of eight
Speaker 2:  and a half billion dollars to buy the rest of Hulu. That's very expensive.
Speaker 2:  Disney is not a company that is full of cash right now. But I'm curious hearing
Speaker 2:  this question, what if Disney doesn't sell ESPN? Could it sell to Apple?
Speaker 2:  Could it partner with Apple? What do you think
Speaker 10:  Apple is the always, oh they could buy it for every
Speaker 10:  question you ever have. They
Speaker 2:  Just have all the money
Speaker 10:  Because they have all of the money, every bit of money that there is
Speaker 10:  belongs to Apple. Tim Cook is just sitting on it presumably in a cave like
Speaker 10:  small I assume will they buy it? The answer is
Speaker 10:  almost always no. And I think for ESPN the answer is probably no.
Speaker 10:  You can never rule it out. But it's an interesting question. Okay, so like
Speaker 10:  what is Disney going to do? But I don't think they have an answer. That's
Speaker 10:  why we got these weird rumors about they wanna partner with different sports
Speaker 10:  leagues. Maybe because I, I don't know how that works with the sports
Speaker 10:  leagues owning part of the broadcaster that they sell broadcast to.
Speaker 10:  That seems strange and I don't know where the money comes from, but
Speaker 10:  Apple buying them is just one of those things where yes, it could technically
Speaker 10:  happen and yes, it would open up all of these things with Apple TVs that
Speaker 10:  they would love to do and it would give them something that everyone needs
Speaker 10:  to have, but they don't actually do those things. It's just, it's just generally
Speaker 10:  not the way that Apple operates for Disney, it would narrow the availability
Speaker 10:  of ESPN if it were suddenly somehow exclusive. Maybe even if they could
Speaker 10:  still sell it to cable operators, it would be weird. And
Speaker 10:  I think that what we've seen, like we saw with their, their deal with I
Speaker 10:  think Cable Vision, they kind of worked it out so that you have streaming
Speaker 10:  and you have cable and that's, it seems like that's the way that they're
Speaker 10:  going at least for the future. Because the other thing that we know now
Speaker 10:  is exactly how profitable ESPN is and that answer to that is a
Speaker 10:  lot. It makes a ton of money
Speaker 2:  So profitable. I think that's the thing that actually gets lost in a lot
Speaker 2:  of this because Disney has made fairly clear that it
Speaker 2:  would like to find some more money for ESPN, which people make
Speaker 2:  out to be because ESPN is not a good business. That's not true. ESPN
Speaker 2:  is such an unbelievably good business. They just started breaking
Speaker 2:  out how much money ESPN makes because it is so much money that like Disney
Speaker 2:  is trying to make the point
Speaker 10:  And that's now, that's now after everyone has cut the cord, after everyone
Speaker 10:  You know has stopped subscribing to cable, ESPN is still making just
Speaker 10:  absolute billions and billions and billions of dollars.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, and I do think it's true that if you cast out far enough,
Speaker 2:  you can see where ESPN gets harder because the, the rights deals that
Speaker 2:  ESPN is fighting for are getting more and more expensive. The number of
Speaker 2:  cable subscribers who are essentially paying for ESPN twice are going
Speaker 2:  down. So like you cast out another what, 10, 15 years
Speaker 2:  and ESPN is maybe a less good business right now. It's still an
Speaker 2:  unbelievably great business. I I'm with you. I don't think it would be
Speaker 2:  Apple because like I was thinking a lot about the the deal that Apple made
Speaker 2:  with the MLS and the deal that Apple didn't make to get Sunday ticket and
Speaker 2:  it seems like what Apple is all about and this makes sense given what Apple
Speaker 2:  is, is control, right? Apple wants a thing thing it can do itself.
Speaker 2:  So the idea of having a thing that is fundamentally about making a million
Speaker 2:  different partnerships with a million different people or being like a minority
Speaker 2:  owner in a thing, it doesn't actually control all of feels very
Speaker 2:  unapply to me. But like Amazon, I can absolutely imagine
Speaker 2:  making roughly that exact deal where Amazon is like, we're gonna put all
Speaker 2:  the sports on Prime. You can subscribe to ESPN through Prime, you get ESPN
Speaker 2:  if you're a prime subscriber, we're gonna make Prime $8 a month more expensive.
Speaker 2:  There's your cable difference right there. Like I can totally imagine a world
Speaker 2:  in which that happens. I don't think it would be Apple. I agree with you.
Speaker 2:  I think Apple's much more likely to like buy a sports league than it is
Speaker 2:  to buy ESPN.
Speaker 10:  Yeah. Something where they actually can control. And I think that's the,
Speaker 10:  the number one most important word for what Apple likes is control.
Speaker 10:  And the other part of ESPN is their deals with the different leagues
Speaker 10:  means that Apple would have no control because all of these arrangements
Speaker 10:  have are old and have been made in different ways and have a lot of compromises
Speaker 10:  and all the leagues have different things like people talk about Apple will
Speaker 10:  buy Formula One rights. It's one of those things that people say but I think
Speaker 10:  is unlikely Formula One broadcast itself, it does
Speaker 10:  all of it through its own broadcast center and sends it around the world.
Speaker 10:  Apple doesn't really want to deal with Formula One telling it what to do
Speaker 10:  and I think it's as you go down the line, that's just really what you run
Speaker 10:  into and that's what what makes it less and less and less likely. But yes,
Speaker 10:  like a company like Amazon, what if Microsoft is like You know what we should
Speaker 10:  combine ESPN and Game Pass. Let's do it. Yeah. ESPN game
Speaker 10:  pass Binging bundle. Done
Speaker 2:  The weirdest way to spend $20 a month that you've ever encountered. I love
Speaker 2:  it. The reason I continue to think ESPN is so interesting is because it is
Speaker 2:  right smack in the middle of this thing where what ESPN wants is to be
Speaker 2:  everywhere, right? Because the crazy part about this is ESPN
Speaker 2:  isn't gonna get the right deals that it wants if it doesn't have the
Speaker 2:  distribution that you get through cable. This is why CBS and Fox keep getting
Speaker 2:  deals because they're everywhere. Like no one but old
Speaker 2:  people watches CBS anymore. But CBS keeps getting football deals
Speaker 2:  because it's free over the air television that absolutely everybody
Speaker 2:  can get, which means you can charge more for ads, which means you get more
Speaker 2:  reach like everybody wins. So ESPN needs that, but it also
Speaker 2:  needs to figure out what a streaming only world looks
Speaker 2:  like because it's coming. But if ESPN in 10 years that world comes and
Speaker 2:  ESPN doesn't have any rights deals, ESPN is dead anyway. So it's caught in,
Speaker 2:  in this transition that we're in, nobody has a harder time of navigating
Speaker 2:  it than ESPN, even as it continues to just throw off billions of billions
Speaker 2:  of dollars for Disney. Yeah,
Speaker 10:  Being in the lead means that making a decision about changing something
Speaker 10:  is so much more difficult.
Speaker 2:  Totally. So, okay, real quick before we go, 12 months from now,
Speaker 2:  you have to answer, does Disney still own ESPN?
Speaker 10:  Yes, majority. Ah,
Speaker 2:  See that's good. That's good. I think I'm with you. I think if, if, if
Speaker 2:  I put the number at like five years, I think I'd have a hard time
Speaker 2:  answering the question. I think 12 months. It's just too big a thing
Speaker 2:  to change in that period of time and I think people really underrate
Speaker 2:  how messy sports deals are and just like the
Speaker 2:  paperwork involved in selling ESPN will, I think just like blow people's
Speaker 2:  minds
Speaker 10:  And I think the money that it brings in simply makes a lot of things that
Speaker 10:  Disney wants to do a lot easier. It is something that we know now that we
Speaker 10:  always suspected, but we know now like all those Marvel movies
Speaker 10:  are like ESPN paid for those you're welcome
Speaker 2:  In like a very real way. ESPN paid for all of that stuff
Speaker 2:  and now the question is gonna be can Disney find another
Speaker 2:  way to pay for all that stuff without ESPN and is it going to have to,
Speaker 2:  and all of that is so unknown, which is why it's very weird to be at Disney
Speaker 2:  right now because it's, it's dealing in like a thousand concurrent hypotheticals
Speaker 2:  that none of which are true now. Like right now Disney's fine. Wall Street
Speaker 2:  doesn't think so because they're terrified about like some future streaming
Speaker 2:  universe that doesn't actually exist yet. But like right now as a business,
Speaker 2:  Disney's doing great,
Speaker 10:  Bringing in just tons of money.
Speaker 2:  It's just hosed in so many ways. It doesn't yet understand, it
Speaker 2:  makes it very complicated.
Speaker 10:  What that future looks like is something that You know if, if you have an
Speaker 10:  answer, I'm sure Bob Iger will take your call. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Hit him up Bob at Disney dot com. I'm sure he'll take your email.
Speaker 2:  All, right? Richard, thank you as always. Appreciate it bud.
Speaker 2:  All, right. That's it for The Vergecast today. Thanks to everybody who was
Speaker 2:  on the show, and thank you as always for listening. There's lots more from
Speaker 2:  everything we talked about, all of Liz's SBF coverage is amazing. You should
Speaker 2:  go back and read it all. Everything Sean is doing from the courtroom for
Speaker 2:  Epic v Google has been great so far. We'll put some links in the show notes,
Speaker 2:  but also keep an eye on the website. There's all kinds of stuff still going
Speaker 2:  down and as always, if you have thoughts, questions, feelings, or
Speaker 2:  curiosities about the jury in these trials, let us know. You can always email
Speaker 2:  us at Vergecast at The Verge dot com or keep calling the Hotline 8 6 6
Speaker 2:  Verge one. One. Like I said before, I love hearing from you. It is one of
Speaker 2:  my favorite things we get to do on The Vergecast. This show is produced by
Speaker 2:  Andrew Marino and Liam James The. Vergecast is The Verge production and part
Speaker 2:  of the Vox Media podcast network. Neli. Alex and I will be back on Friday
Speaker 2:  to talk about everything happening at OpenAI, the new MacBook, the PS five
Speaker 2:  slim, and a whole bunch more. We'll see you then. Rock and roll. We,
Speaker 11:  From the moment Twitter was founded, no one knew what it was supposed to
Speaker 11:  be exactly, which was kind of great.
Speaker 12:  Some people would look at it and say, this is the future of communications.
Speaker 12:  Others would look at it and say, this is the public square.
Speaker 11:  Eventually it became not so great.
Speaker 13:  What we didn't foresee was that everybody having
Speaker 13:  a voice might produce a global
Speaker 13:  voracious mob, and there was only one place that that was happening.
Speaker 13:  It was Twitter
Speaker 11:  A year ago in what was essentially the world's most expensive impulse
Speaker 11:  purchase. Elon Musk bought Twitter that made him
Speaker 11:  Twitter's most important user, but he's certainly not the only
Speaker 11:  one to fall for. Its spell a spell that promises attention,
Speaker 11:  connection, and power.
Speaker 11:  I'm Peter Kafka and I'm hosting Land of the Giants, the Twitter fantasy.
Speaker 11:  It's from Vox on the Vox Media Podcast Network. This season is sponsored
Speaker 11:  by Mint Mobile to learn how Twitter got started, how it got
Speaker 11:  where it is today, and where it's going next. Follow land of the
Speaker 11:  Giants wherever you listen and get new episodes every Wednesday.
Speaker 3:  This podcast is brought to you by Meta Quest three, the new mixed reality
Speaker 3:  headset from Meta. Expand your World in ways you never thought Possible with
Speaker 3:  the new Meta Quest. Three, put on the most powerful quest yet and
Speaker 3:  jump into fully immersive games like Assassin's Creed Nexus, or
Speaker 3:  blend virtual elements into your surroundings in games like Stranger Things
Speaker 3:  vr. With over 500 titles, it's easy to dive into
Speaker 3:  whatever you're into. Expand your world with Meta Quest three. See child
Speaker 3:  safety guidance online accounts for 10 and up. Certain apps, games and experiences
Speaker 3:  may be suitable for a more mature audience. Learn more@meta.com.