# Transcript
ID: 33259450-bc80-11ed-b20c-27cb2c30cb78
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Apple glucose monitor rumors, Marvel fatigue, and podcast misinformation
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-4100765726586244134/-6345559613654286335/s93290-US-4418s-1678149427.mp3
Description: Today on the flagship podcast of hyper specific wearable sensors:
01:19 - Victoria Song joins Alex Cranz to talk about the latest rumors around Apple’s big progress in blood glucose monitoring.
Apple Makes Major Progress on No-Prick Blood Glucose Tracking for Its Watch
Continuous glucose monitor startups still have to prove their worth
Apple is looking at opportunities to do great things in health in India: Sumbul Desai
17:14 - Ariel Shapiro talks with Valerie Wirtschafter, a data analyst at the Brookings Institution, about how often podcasts spread political misinformation, and what that means for the medium.
Audible reckoning: How top political podcasters spread unsubstantiated and false claims
Policy recommendations for addressing content moderation in podcasts
43:57 - Alex and Charles Pulliam-Moore chat about the latest episode of The Last of Us and all the Marvel movie fatigue that has cropped up since Ant-Man and the Wasp: Quantumania came out. [Warning: Spoiler alert]
HBO’s The Last of Us is pushing all the right buttons by telling new stories
HBO’s The Last of Us is wisely skipping to the cutscenes
Ant-Man and the Wasp: Quantumania review: this is your brain on Kangs
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com, or call the Vergecast Hotline at 866-VERGE11
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Disabled
Speaker 2:  Welcome to the Vergecast, the flagship podcast of hyper
Speaker 2:  specific wearable sensors. Yeah, that's a, that's a thing and we're the,
Speaker 2:  we're the flagship for it. I'm your friend Alex Kranz and I'm super
Speaker 2:  excited about this week's episode because it's just a bunch of like really
Speaker 2:  neat conversations with coworkers and at least one
Speaker 2:  senior data analyst. Victoria's song is gonna be joining me
Speaker 2:  to talk about the latest rumors around Apple's, big progress in blood glucose
Speaker 2:  monitoring. This has been a very hot topic of conversation since Mark
Speaker 2:  Germond wrote a big piece in Bloomberg last week. In fact, this week,
Speaker 2:  Apple's VP of Health symbol Desai that in an interview with the
Speaker 2:  Hindu business line where the blood glucose monitoring work got name checked.
Speaker 2:  She didn't say much, but it definitely feels like we're like in a moment.
Speaker 2:  So Victoria and I are gonna talk about that moment and then Ariel Shapiro
Speaker 2:  is gonna come on to talk with the data analyst at the Brookings Institution
Speaker 2:  all about podcast misinformation, which is super interesting. And finally,
Speaker 2:  I gotta admit I got selfish and I brought back Charles plu Moore
Speaker 2:  because we absolutely had to talk about the latest episode of the last
Speaker 2:  of us and all of the Marvel fatigue that's cropped up around
Speaker 2:  Antman and the wash quantum mania. So we're gonna go all over the place
Speaker 2:  this episode, but it's a lot of super interesting conversations. Stay tuned.
Speaker 2:  This episode is sponsored by TurboTax. TurboTax has
Speaker 2:  experts who can help relieve you from the stress of taxes and follow for
Speaker 2:  you so you can do not taxes. With TurboTax, an expert
Speaker 2:  will do your taxes from start to finish, ensuring your taxes are done right
Speaker 2:  so you can relax. Feels good to be done with your taxes, right?
Speaker 2:  Come to TurboTax and don't do your taxes. You can visit
Speaker 2:  turbotax.com to learn more. Intuit TurboTax full service
Speaker 2:  products only video meeting while expert does your taxes required. See
Speaker 2:  guaranteed details at turbotax.com/guarantees.
Speaker 3:  Support for this podcast comes from Lenovo. Any team looking
Speaker 3:  to complete a difficult task needs access to the most powerful tools to
Speaker 3:  get the job done. And that's exactly what Lenovo specializes in
Speaker 3:  their think station. P six 20 workstation allows power users
Speaker 3:  like animators, engineers and geoscientists to harness
Speaker 3:  the incredible speed of the a MD rise in thread Ripper Pro
Speaker 3:  processor. And with Tgx remote workstation software,
Speaker 3:  realtime access to massive data sets and unparalleled
Speaker 3:  power is possible from anywhere in the world. To learn more,
Speaker 3:  visit lenovo.com/think station P six 20.
Speaker 2:  Okay, and we're back. Victoria Song. Hello. Hello, how are you?
Speaker 2:  I'm doing great Victoria. Thank you for asking. So Victoria, I wanna talk
Speaker 2:  about this rumor first reported by Bloomberg that Apple has been working
Speaker 2:  on a device that will let you test your blood sugar because that is like
Speaker 2:  really, really useful for people with diabetes. But it could also be useful
Speaker 2:  for people who don't know they should get tested for diabetes. Am I right?
Speaker 2:  Yeah,
Speaker 4:  There's actually a lot of reasons why anyone might wanna test their
Speaker 4:  blood sugar, including like hardcore athletes who are doing
Speaker 4:  endurance races who are just like, oh my God, do I need to
Speaker 4:  fuel? Do am I, how are my carbs doing? So you know, there was this
Speaker 4:  article in Bloomberg from Mark Gorman, the quote unquote
Speaker 4:  Apple Profit this past week that was saying that Apple had made
Speaker 4:  huge strides in their non-invasive
Speaker 4:  glucose monitoring tech. And you know, that sounds pretty cool.
Speaker 4:  All it means is that you can read your blood sugar without having to
Speaker 4:  prick your finger, which, you know, any person with diabetes would know that's,
Speaker 4:  it's not fun pricking your finger to get a little blood test all the time.
Speaker 4:  So that is what's kind of been causing a little buzz in
Speaker 4:  non-invasive blood glucose monitoring this past week at least. But
Speaker 4:  you know, it's actually been around for a while. Like the concept of it has
Speaker 4:  been around for quite some time, like over 10 years. I want to say,
Speaker 4:  oh
Speaker 2:  Wow, I didn't realize this that long. Cuz I think when we think about testing
Speaker 2:  for, for diabetes testing your glucose, it's generally
Speaker 2:  the the pin prick just taking blood. And then also, I know there was
Speaker 2:  the patch, Nicole Wetsman did this wonderful piece about testing
Speaker 2:  one of the patches and her blood sugar versus her friend who has
Speaker 2:  type one diabetes. So generally the idea is you have to take blood and some
Speaker 2:  people were working on, well what if you could actually get the, the blood
Speaker 2:  sugar level from sweat? Is that what Apple is doing?
Speaker 4:  No. So there's two types of non-invasive blood glucose monitoring. The first
Speaker 4:  type is optical and that's what Apple is working on. Optical is similar to,
Speaker 4:  you know how this Apple watch has a P P G sensor
Speaker 4:  and it reflects light into your skin and based on the
Speaker 4:  reflection that comes back, it can kind of estimate what your heart rate
Speaker 4:  is from that. So Apple is basically working on
Speaker 4:  a optical version using spectroscopy. Ah-huh. That
Speaker 4:  is basically going to, based on the article, shine light
Speaker 4:  into your interstitial fluid and based on that,
Speaker 4:  figure out how much blood sugar is in your body. So interstitial
Speaker 4:  fluid is the fluid that sits in the space
Speaker 4:  between your cells. It's basically how they get powered is
Speaker 4:  also where all the waste product goes out. There's glucose in
Speaker 2:  There. So it's not blood,
Speaker 4:  It's not blood, it is interstitial fluid, which is
Speaker 4:  the fluid between the spaces of your cells. Okay. And it,
Speaker 4:  it is a legitimate thing that they use to measure blood glucose. So it
Speaker 4:  sounds science fictiony, but it's, it's real. We all have it. It sits
Speaker 4:  right beneath the skin. That's what Bloomberg says that Apple is
Speaker 4:  approaching it from. But the other way is the way that you were mentioning
Speaker 4:  where you find blood glucose from a fluid, so that's
Speaker 4:  your urine, that's your tears. That's what a couple years back
Speaker 4:  Google was thinking of trying to make smart contacts that could read your
Speaker 4:  blood sugar from your, you know, your eyeballs. Yeah. The, the fluid there.
Speaker 4:  But this is very complicated. There's a lot of stuff that goes into this.
Speaker 4:  Well
Speaker 2:  It's complicated and also there's a lot of different body types and stuff.
Speaker 2:  And oftentimes these tests initially are for just one type of
Speaker 2:  body, for one just type of skin type. We see a
Speaker 2:  lot of different ways that it can kind of then mess up. I think we're seeing
Speaker 2:  that right now, right? With with blood oxygen and some of the other
Speaker 2:  optical sensors that Apple and other wearables are making
Speaker 2:  where they don't work on darker skin colors and they just flat out do not
Speaker 2:  work at all on tattoos.
Speaker 4:  Right. So you know, in the case of the PPG sensors, these are
Speaker 4:  the green lights that you see on the back of every wearable that measures
Speaker 4:  your heart rate. That color of light is very much impacted
Speaker 4:  by melanin and by tattoo. So that's why you have a lot
Speaker 4:  of tattoo users who have very dense tattoos on their wrists who cannot use
Speaker 4:  the Apple watch properly. You know, they have to like get epoxy stickers
Speaker 4:  and stick that on and somehow that makes it work. It's slightly different
Speaker 4:  in the case of blood glucose because if you're gonna do optical blood
Speaker 4:  glucose measurements, you're gonna be using a type of infrared wavelength
Speaker 4:  and ideally you'll be using more than one wavelength.
Speaker 4:  But that causes its own problems because
Speaker 4:  blood glucose has a lot more challenges than heart rate
Speaker 4:  does. Heart rate is relatively easy. You're measuring your pulse
Speaker 4:  is essentially what you're doing with the optical sensors and you know, you
Speaker 4:  can feed pulse into an algorithm and that's cool. But blood
Speaker 4:  glucose is about infinitely more complicated because
Speaker 4:  glucose is a very, very tiny molecule and there's a lot of other
Speaker 4:  molecules in interstitial fluid in other places. So there's a lot of signal
Speaker 4:  interference. So that's one of the big problems there.
Speaker 2:  This is even more complicated, but also it feels like it
Speaker 2:  has an even higher risk if you fail. You know, if my
Speaker 2:  heart rate skyrockets, I'd like to know, but it's not
Speaker 2:  necessarily the end of the world. It could be because I took the stairs
Speaker 2:  too fast. It could be because I got really exciting or really devastating
Speaker 2:  news. If my blood sugar is off and I have say
Speaker 2:  diabetes or something, well that could just mean I die.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It's actually gonna be something that requires F D A
Speaker 4:  regulation our, our very good friend the Food and Drug Administration,
Speaker 4:  but that the stakes are higher with blood glucose. Right. Because you cannot
Speaker 4:  get this wrong for diabetics. So you know, the image
Speaker 4:  that we have of what these smartwatch blood glucose monitors are gonna be
Speaker 4:  is just replacing the finger pricks, replacing the
Speaker 4:  continuous blood glucose monitors that they use needles.
Speaker 4:  So that's kind of the perception that we have for it. But if you
Speaker 4:  read closely into the Bloomberg piece, I really don't think that's where
Speaker 4:  apple's gonna go first. So, you know, they were saying that they were gonna
Speaker 4:  do it to screen pre-diabetes and there's multiple types of
Speaker 4:  pre-diabetes. You know, the human body is a wonderland that we'd know nothing
Speaker 4:  about. Basically the, the further you go into health tech, the more you realize
Speaker 4:  how much doctors have no idea how this bo how our bodies work. So
Speaker 4:  basically, you know, they're talking about you wear this like
Speaker 4:  device all the time and it can continuously monitor
Speaker 4:  your blood glucose and then give you a ping and say hey
Speaker 4:  you might have risk factors for pre-diabetes and that's very
Speaker 4:  different than monitoring your blood glucose for a diabetic.
Speaker 4:  So what we're gonna see at least first is something I
Speaker 4:  think, I think similar to what Apple did with heart rate and
Speaker 4:  ECG and AFib. So apple's not diagnosing anything for you,
Speaker 4:  right? They're just saying, hey, you show signs that kind of
Speaker 4:  indicate that you might have this issue. So go see a doctor. And
Speaker 4:  that's what I think that they're gonna do based on like that article,
Speaker 4:  the idea of pre-screening for diabetes. That's what I think
Speaker 4:  wearable version of this is gonna go towards first at least.
Speaker 4:  I don't think we're gonna go straight into a wearable monitor for people
Speaker 4:  with diabetes Precisely because if you fuck up people might die and
Speaker 4:  nobody wants that.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I was about to say like, so my, my mom has type two diabetes,
Speaker 2:  I am obviously at risk because family
Speaker 2:  factors and I wouldn't want my mom to rely on
Speaker 2:  solely an Apple watch unless it has really gone through the rigors and can
Speaker 2:  match that, that pin prick test. Whereas it might be nice for me to be able
Speaker 2:  to say, oh, I should have a conversation with my doctor and find out if I
Speaker 2:  just need to be less dumb about eating breakfast or
Speaker 2:  if I've got other issues.
Speaker 4:  I mean I, I have the same thing. My dad had diabetes, I have P C O S,
Speaker 4:  I am predisposed to being a diabetic. So you know, every single time I go
Speaker 4:  to the doctor they're like, oh, let's check your blood sugar levels.
Speaker 2:  Gotta know your a1c man. You gotta, you
Speaker 4:  Gotta, yeah, you gotta know your a1c. Yeah. So you know, the idea is to kind
Speaker 4:  of be like, Nicole put this a really great way,
Speaker 4:  a warning light for wearables to kind of go, Hey,
Speaker 4:  I think you should go talk to a medical professional
Speaker 4:  cuz you'll never get in trouble for saying, Hey, go talk
Speaker 4:  to a medical professional. We actually do not give you medical advice
Speaker 4:  and any wearable, you see, even the ones with FDA cleared features
Speaker 4:  are going to say this is not in lieu of medical advice and the
Speaker 4:  reason is liability. They don't wanna be in trouble for you not
Speaker 4:  listening to them, but they do want the credit for when it saves your life.
Speaker 2:  I, I do wonder if Apple does go down this route, and it's not a
Speaker 2:  diagnostic feature, but it is a feature, a warning feature. Does that
Speaker 2:  mean Apple's just kind of getting into the business of making us terrified
Speaker 2:  of our own bodies every time we put on an Apple watch?
Speaker 4:  I mean a little bit, I this is, this is the dark side of wearable
Speaker 4:  tech is that it can very much cause anxiety. And I wrote a thing
Speaker 4:  recently about, you know, how to use fitness truckers and smartwatches in
Speaker 4:  a less anxiety inducing way. And you know, I test these for a living,
Speaker 4:  I have anxiety because these things tell me certain, there was like
Speaker 4:  a woman who got one of the notifications on the Apple Watch and then took
Speaker 4:  like 900 ECGs over the course of the year because she was really
Speaker 4:  anxious and this was a study that they did and it does does induce this
Speaker 4:  level of anxiety within people. So that's the thing
Speaker 4:  that I don't think we as a society and at the medical community has really
Speaker 4:  come to grips with yet is the fact that this tech is very new.
Speaker 4:  You're putting monitoring in the hands of people, continuous
Speaker 4:  monitoring, passive monitoring, and then they go to their doctors with data
Speaker 4:  and the doctors are like, well I don't know what to do with this data. I
Speaker 4:  don't know how to help you with treatment. And in some cases it's very obvious
Speaker 4:  and okay, like, oh, we can see that you do have this issue
Speaker 4:  and in other cases doctors are just gonna be like, okay, so your
Speaker 4:  heart rate was high once and you're fine now. Right? Yeah. So the, the promise
Speaker 4:  is that, you know, remote patient monitoring, that's the real promise of
Speaker 4:  all of this. But when it comes to diabetes, I'm not even sure
Speaker 4:  how doctors would necessarily use it, but most
Speaker 4:  likely at first it'll follow the path that continuous
Speaker 4:  blood glucose monitors, this is like a, a tongue twister every single
Speaker 4:  time I have to say it like that they did, which is, you know, they were
Speaker 4:  not meant to be your primary form of testing blood sugar, they
Speaker 4:  were kind of a supplement. You were supposed to do the pinprick and then
Speaker 4:  that could be kind of a supplemental, you know, secondary type of
Speaker 4:  monitoring method. And it's most likely that if we do get this
Speaker 4:  technology in a wearable, that's probably what it's gonna be. But
Speaker 4:  getting it small enough to be an wearable, this is like a recurring theme
Speaker 4:  is very difficult to do because as I mentioned, the signal is gonna
Speaker 4:  be really small for glucose and it's just gonna be a lot of interference.
Speaker 4:  So the AI model, the algorithm has to be extremely precise. And then
Speaker 4:  on top of that, you know, there's, there's other issues with blood glucose
Speaker 4:  compared to heart rate that are a zillion times more complicated, not least
Speaker 4:  of which is that you and I can eat the same foods and our blood sugar
Speaker 4:  will decrease or spike at a different rate. It's not linear
Speaker 4:  per se. Yeah. So that's a lot. How are they gonna program
Speaker 4:  that? That's difficult. That requires a lot of testing, which
Speaker 2:  Right now it sounded like in Ingerman's article it sounded like it's
Speaker 2:  still very,
Speaker 4:  Very large.
Speaker 2:  Yes. This isn't even close to being on the wrist yet.
Speaker 4:  So, you know, the, the major milestone that Garmin was referring to is that
Speaker 4:  the first version of it was this giant thing that sat on a table and
Speaker 4:  now they're working on a prototype that's about the size of an iPhone that
Speaker 4:  you would wear on your bicep. So, you know, we
Speaker 4:  are years away. Like he does mention that in the article, right? He's not
Speaker 4:  saying that this is coming out next year. Yeah. It is a big milestone to
Speaker 4:  go from something that has to sit on a table to something that can be worn.
Speaker 4:  But going from an iPhone sized object to
Speaker 4:  a watch sized object is is a whole other ballpark. And that's
Speaker 4:  really the challenge that you have with wearable devices in
Speaker 4:  general.
Speaker 2:  So next time we hear somebody say a rumor that the next
Speaker 2:  Apple watch is gonna have continuous glucose monitoring.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, yeah, no, that's, that's I call bullshit on that because
Speaker 4:  it's not easy to do first off and you know, they're probably
Speaker 4:  already in regulatory talks because this kind of product
Speaker 4:  doesn't exist. It just doesn't, there were some failed versions
Speaker 4:  of like smart watchy prototype versions of this stuff, but
Speaker 4:  you know, the FDA's probably gonna have to sit there and be like, okay, how
Speaker 4:  do we even get you to test this thing in a way
Speaker 4:  that's not going to endanger human life? And you know, I've, I've been
Speaker 4:  talking to some scientists about how they do test this type of technology
Speaker 4:  and first off they, they test it with a glass of water
Speaker 4:  because if you cannot read blood sugar from water, you're screwed and you
Speaker 4:  have to go back to the drawing board. And then they have another, like
Speaker 4:  they call it a phantom, which is kind of like a mannequin that has
Speaker 4:  human-like stuff on it and you know, it's a proxy
Speaker 4:  for human testing but it's not the same thing. So this stuff is
Speaker 4:  very hard to test in a safe way. Like, you know, the
Speaker 4:  ethics of testing this tech is really tough with SPO two. You
Speaker 4:  basically have to make people go hypoxic for a certain period of time
Speaker 4:  in a controlled setting, which, you know, hypoxia is
Speaker 4:  when your blood oxygen level goes to points where you should be in a hospital.
Speaker 4:  So this is very difficult testing to do and that's only one portion
Speaker 4:  of FDA regulatory clearance. There's also stuff like making sure
Speaker 4:  that the way you store your data is HIPAA compliant. That's just
Speaker 4:  regulatory clearance. Just because something has regulatory clearance
Speaker 4:  does not mean it's an accurate device for that particular
Speaker 4:  purpose. Like the easy way for me to say it is that yes, this tech
Speaker 4:  is being developed, yes we are seeing progress in terms of
Speaker 4:  miniaturization and accuracy. AI is getting better, the sensors
Speaker 4:  are getting smaller, but there's so many issues like
Speaker 4:  because most of the optical methods are using infrared light. Did you
Speaker 4:  know that if it gets hot in the room, the sensors are gonna pick up on that
Speaker 4:  and they may say you have a spike in blood sugar even though it's
Speaker 4:  just hot. Like that's an actual problem that scientists are dealing with
Speaker 4:  and that, you know, they had a study that showed that. So it's very
Speaker 4:  challenging from an AI perspective, from the fact that the signal is so
Speaker 4:  small and just the fact that you have to have so many
Speaker 4:  different wavelengths of infrared light that it could get
Speaker 4:  hot.
Speaker 2:  So one last question for you. Which do you think we get first, the Apple
Speaker 2:  watch with continuous glucose monitoring
Speaker 2:  or smart glasses from Apple that you would wanna wear in public?
Speaker 4:  God if Apple has figured out how to
Speaker 4:  handle the ambient light problem like
Speaker 4:  relatively well I think that because that you could use as
Speaker 4:  a heads up display, you know, you see them in cars now and
Speaker 4:  directions, there's, there's a, there's a use case for everybody there
Speaker 4:  that everyone will want to use that likely will not burn your
Speaker 4:  eyeballs off and is not something that requires
Speaker 4:  super regulatory clearance with lots and lots of clinical testing.
Speaker 4:  So I'm gonna guess that
Speaker 2:  I was unaware that smart glasses could potentially burn my eyeballs
Speaker 4:  Off. Well the contacts might.
Speaker 2:  Victoria, thank you for coming on and popping all of the hype bubbles.
Speaker 2:  Appreciate it.
Speaker 4:  I live to pop everyone's health tech bubble just by being a
Speaker 4:  wet blanket saying actually we're gonna have to wait a really
Speaker 4:  long time for all the cool stuff.
Speaker 2:  Okay, we're gonna take a break and when we get back we're gonna move from
Speaker 2:  talking about blood glucose monitoring to podcast
Speaker 2:  misinformation with Ariel Shapiro. It is actually really exciting.
Speaker 2:  They're totally unrelated but it's gonna be a lot of fun More right after
Speaker 2:  this.
Speaker 5:  Mint Mobile offers premium wireless for just 15 bucks a month. That
Speaker 5:  means spending a little less money on your phone bill and a little more for
Speaker 5:  online shopping, probably on your phone. All plans come with
Speaker 5:  unlimited talk and text plus high-speed data. You can use your own phone
Speaker 5:  with any Mint mobile plan and switch easily in minutes with eim
Speaker 5:  to get your new wireless plan for just 15 bucks a month and get the
Speaker 5:  plan shipped to your door for free, go to mint
Speaker 5:  mobile.com/vox. That's mint
Speaker 5:  mobile.com/vox.
Speaker 6:  Running a business is stressful, but worrying about how to grow
Speaker 6:  your company in the digital space can make any ambitious person wanna give
Speaker 6:  up. Wouldn't it be nice to have a set of expertly designed tools to help
Speaker 6:  you create your own growth tailored exactly to your company's needs?
Speaker 6:  That's where uny comes in. Unisys is a global technology
Speaker 6:  solutions company dedicated to helping people and organizations reach
Speaker 6:  their next breakthrough. They offer tools to help you run your business more
Speaker 6:  efficiently, like systems integration, consulting services,
Speaker 6:  application management and device management software. Plus
Speaker 6:  Unisys applies specialized expertise to strengthen and transform
Speaker 6:  teams and processes by helping organizations act on new opportunities
Speaker 6:  through digital workplace cloud applications, enterprise computing
Speaker 6:  and business process solutions. To learn more, visit
Speaker 6:  uny.com, that's U N I S Y s.com.
Speaker 6:  Uny, keep breaking through.
Speaker 2:  Okay and we're back. And I'm here with Ariel Shapiro. Hey Ariel, how you
Speaker 2:  doing?
Speaker 7:  I'm doing well Alex, how are you doing?
Speaker 2:  I am doing fantastic. I hear you have been interviewing some people
Speaker 2:  about a very fun little segment for the show, all about
Speaker 2:  podcasting.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, A couple weeks ago I spoke with Valerie, who's a
Speaker 7:  senior data analyst at Brookings last year. She put together this tool
Speaker 7:  that I have been like obsessively playing with that tracks a
Speaker 7:  bunch of the most important political podcasts. Oh cool.
Speaker 7:  So it started out just looking at the frequency of
Speaker 7:  episodes in terms of conservative versus liberal versus moderate. But recently
Speaker 7:  they came out with a really extensive and troubling study
Speaker 7:  about misinformation in these podcasts and it really runs
Speaker 7:  the gamut. Some podcasts do pretty well in terms of fact
Speaker 7:  checking and then some one out of every five episodes will feature
Speaker 7:  either blatant misinformation or unverified
Speaker 7:  information. Oh
Speaker 2:  No, okay, so like what's the criteria here? Like does the Verge
Speaker 2:  cast count? Does Joe Rogan count what counts as a political podcast?
Speaker 7:  So neither Verge Cast nor Joe Rogan were part of this
Speaker 7:  study. Okay. They limited it to specifically
Speaker 7:  political podcasts that rank or have ranked in
Speaker 7:  Apple Podcast top 100. Okay. So Joe Rogan doesn't count because
Speaker 7:  he's only on Spotify, so, but if he was on Apple he would count
Speaker 7:  or podcasts that are recommended through those podcasts through
Speaker 7:  Apple's algorithm. It doesn't encompass the entire political podcast world,
Speaker 7:  but it does look at the podcasts with the most reach.
Speaker 7:  So that's, you know, Ben Shapiro's show, that's
Speaker 7:  Steve Bannon's show, which is actually only allowed on Apple podcasts
Speaker 7:  of the major platforms. They are banned from YouTube and from Spotify,
Speaker 7:  but also, you know, shows on the liberal end of the spectrum like Pod Save
Speaker 7:  America. So Valerie talks about the findings of the data, what it
Speaker 7:  means for podcasting and what it means for tech companies and what they can
Speaker 7:  do with the findings.
Speaker 2:  Okay. Well that sounds like a very interesting conversation. Let's go ahead
Speaker 2:  and listen to it.
Speaker 7:  Thank you so much for being here, Valerie. Your research really seems to
Speaker 7:  be the first of its kind that's looking this in depth
Speaker 7:  at podcasts and what kind of information or
Speaker 7:  misinformation gets shared on them. And so we hear a lot about misinformation
Speaker 7:  on cable news and on social media. Why did you choose to
Speaker 7:  look into podcasts in particular?
Speaker 8:  So at the Brookings Institution, my team is really interested in
Speaker 8:  exploring artificial intelligence, emerging technologies
Speaker 8:  and their broader societal implications. And so for me that
Speaker 8:  also includes especially the role of new media and the
Speaker 8:  internet in shaping this information ecosystem. And so the
Speaker 8:  reason I thought about focusing on podcasts is because, well, it really struck
Speaker 8:  me as increasingly important. People love their
Speaker 8:  podcasters really there's kind of a, a unique attachment that
Speaker 8:  we see two podcast hosts and it seems like, you know, anybody can really
Speaker 8:  start a podcast. Obviously having a successful podcast is a
Speaker 8:  another question, but anybody can be a host, sort of anybody
Speaker 8:  can have the microphone, anybody can be an expert on anything that they
Speaker 8:  decide they're an expert on in that day. And so those kinds of
Speaker 8:  elements seemed really interesting to me as kind of this new media
Speaker 8:  aspect, sort of the Twitter personalities or
Speaker 8:  YouTube personalities who kind of gain their platform seems really
Speaker 8:  applicable to podcasting. But at the same time, there isn't that
Speaker 8:  kind of dialogue element to it. It's very much more
Speaker 8:  in the vein of a, a traditional media space where the
Speaker 8:  podcaster is, is speaking to the audience and there's not
Speaker 8:  a ton of dialogue possibilities usually it's a much more kind of
Speaker 8:  top-down information provision. And so I thought that was really interesting
Speaker 8:  as a dyk as well.
Speaker 7:  So I get the sense that podcasts don't really get as much attention
Speaker 7:  as they might deserve in terms of the political influence they can have.
Speaker 7:  Aside from like Joe Rogan who absolutely dominates the new cycle,
Speaker 7:  but especially because it's so easy to develop these parasocial
Speaker 7:  relationships with podcast hosts, it seems like they can
Speaker 7:  actually have a lot of influence. Why do you think this is an area that's
Speaker 7:  gone so unexplored?
Speaker 8:  I mean, I would say probably the biggest reason for
Speaker 8:  me at least is the challenge of the medium, the
Speaker 8:  kind of actual audio-based function of the medium versus
Speaker 8:  something like text-based analysis. So we, we see a lot of
Speaker 8:  research on Twitter, which you know, it's very short snippets of text, very
Speaker 8:  available up until recently, at least with the API
Speaker 8:  interface. So academics, researchers could really access Twitter
Speaker 8:  data very quickly. Podcasting, you know, I kind of, I had to
Speaker 8:  sort of think about a whole strategy and design an approach
Speaker 8:  to be able to collect the audio files and then from there, get the audio
Speaker 8:  files into a space that was, you know, large enough to hold
Speaker 8:  36,000 MP three s and then from there
Speaker 8:  transform it into a text-based format. And then from
Speaker 8:  there continue along to actually find small
Speaker 8:  claims, small elements in, you know, some of these hosts like
Speaker 8:  Joe Rogan obviously was not in this report given this sort of Spotify
Speaker 8:  exclusive nature of his podcast and the data
Speaker 8:  collection process. They sort of didn't align. But a lot of
Speaker 8:  these hosts like Joe Rogan, you know, like Steve Bannon will have, you know,
Speaker 8:  four episodes a day, hour long episodes. And so it's a lot of
Speaker 8:  text. And so the methods alignment was a bit of a
Speaker 8:  challenge to figure out. And so I think that has maybe
Speaker 8:  pushed some people away from the medium potentially in terms of an
Speaker 8:  analysis side of it. And then on the other end of the spectrum, I don't know
Speaker 8:  if people actually sort of saw this space as highly
Speaker 8:  political or highly politically charged in terms of the
Speaker 8:  content that people were producing. We have great series like Radiolab
Speaker 8:  or this American Life or you know, true Crime podcast like cereal.
Speaker 8:  And so, you know, I think maybe that's kind of the perception of the
Speaker 8:  medium, but there is this entire world of political punditry
Speaker 8:  that is growing increasingly popular and increasingly prominent.
Speaker 7:  And one thing that is pretty shocking when you look at the tracker
Speaker 7:  in terms of the frequency of episodes published, you, you separated
Speaker 7:  into conservative episodes, moderate episodes and
Speaker 7:  liberal episodes. And based on your criteria of shows
Speaker 7:  that appear in Apple's top 100 and affiliated podcasts that
Speaker 7:  are recommended through the algorithm, it is, is so overwhelmingly
Speaker 7:  conservative. Why is that? It, it seems, it seems just completely out
Speaker 7:  of balance.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, I mean, so there's two elements to that. One is, so the series
Speaker 8:  is not necessarily as imbalanced as the number of
Speaker 8:  episodes. So I, I'm not remembering the exact numbers at the moment,
Speaker 8:  but I think it's something like one and a half to one ratio for
Speaker 8:  conservative series. So say we have 40 conservative series,
Speaker 8:  we're gonna have 30 liberal series or something like that
Speaker 8:  in terms of the imbalance from the selection process. But then
Speaker 8:  when you get at the episode level, it's something like triple the amount.
Speaker 8:  So conservative podcasters are producing many,
Speaker 8:  many more shows than liberal podcasters. And so
Speaker 8:  I think that that is really what that explosion is built around is just
Speaker 8:  the kind of, you know, and, and Steve Bannon has a
Speaker 8:  less than PC way of saying it, of like flooding the zone
Speaker 8:  with garbage is sort of some sort of his media strategy.
Speaker 8:  And so, you know, we do see this kind of, you know, whether whatever the
Speaker 8:  quality is, we do see this approach of like continuing to air episodes
Speaker 8:  daily, sometimes multiple episodes a day. And I think that's a
Speaker 8:  lot more of the conservative media ethos built around talk radio,
Speaker 8:  things like that. And so I think that's where a lot of that originates from.
Speaker 8:  And so that imbalance I think is particularly striking at the
Speaker 8:  episode level. It's, I'd say less, it's still an
Speaker 8:  imbalance but less dramatic at the series level.
Speaker 7:  What surprised you most when you were going through the data?
Speaker 8:  You know, I think that there were a few sort of specific
Speaker 8:  things. One, I think that what surprised me actually
Speaker 8:  is the kind of disparity in terms of some shows really
Speaker 8:  do kind of air a lot of these types of claims somewhat
Speaker 8:  frequently, like maybe one in 10 episodes, one in five episodes for
Speaker 8:  some of 'em. And then there are really, I think very high quality shows that
Speaker 8:  are just, you know, do a really excellent job. And so the kind
Speaker 8:  of distinction between those that shared quite a bit of content
Speaker 8:  that was maybe unsubstantiated or not backed by evidence
Speaker 8:  versus those that really didn't do it much at all. And so that
Speaker 8:  distinction I think was, was quite visible
Speaker 7:  In your report. You found that overall in this, among the shows you were
Speaker 7:  looking at, that it was about one in 20 episodes featured either
Speaker 7:  unsubstantiated or false claims, but the worst offenders
Speaker 7:  had rates of 15%, 20% of their
Speaker 7:  episodes with this sort of misinformation. So is this a
Speaker 7:  podcasting problem or is this maybe limited to
Speaker 7:  a group of particularly irresponsible podcasters?
Speaker 8:  That's a good question as well. I mean, I think that the nature
Speaker 8:  of the medium is such that, you know, this type of content
Speaker 8:  just naturally filters in, it's very conversational,
Speaker 8:  very extemporaneous, somewhat informal, you know, people are
Speaker 8:  bound to throw around and you know, I think I did it at the beginning of
Speaker 8:  the show, people are bound to throw around like estimates that they remember
Speaker 8:  off the top of their head that may or may not be accurate. And so I think
Speaker 8:  that, you know, it's just a natural function of the kind of back and
Speaker 8:  forth of the medium. But you know, I do think as the medium
Speaker 8:  becomes increasingly concentrated in terms
Speaker 8:  of political series and even since the data collection for this
Speaker 8:  report was completed, there's you know, dozens of new
Speaker 8:  shows that are really kind of highly politically charged.
Speaker 8:  And so I don't see this necessarily as something that will
Speaker 8:  be fading or that is concentrated amongst just a
Speaker 8:  few people. It's something that I think will continue to grow as I think
Speaker 8:  the medium continues to, to grow as well.
Speaker 7:  And in terms of the frequency of misinformation that you found,
Speaker 7:  how does it compare to other types of media, whether that's TV or social
Speaker 7:  or you know, terrestrial radio?
Speaker 8:  Yeah, I think that is, you know, it's hard to quantify
Speaker 8:  because the tools have been lacking. So
Speaker 8:  recent research up until, you know, maybe a couple years
Speaker 8:  ago really focused on domain based content. So
Speaker 8:  focused on what was perceived to be low quality domain sharing.
Speaker 8:  And even those, which is I think a very inclusive
Speaker 8:  definition and you're bound to grab a lot of content that
Speaker 8:  is, you know, it might be highly political, but it isn't necessarily
Speaker 8:  false. That was a very inclusive measurement tool
Speaker 8:  and even then it was very small in terms of the
Speaker 8:  repeated sharing especially was low. And then, you know, for users,
Speaker 8:  there's a few studies that look at users, I think it's, it's quite
Speaker 8:  low in terms of percentage that share information that links to
Speaker 8:  these sort of suspect websites or domains. And then other
Speaker 8:  research that's maybe gotten a little bit more complicated and look at at
Speaker 8:  like browsers and broader media habits really
Speaker 8:  gets into like, you know, I think the rate is maybe like one minute per day
Speaker 8:  or something is the exposure. And so that I think puts
Speaker 8:  into perspective the amount for podcasting. I
Speaker 8:  do think the fact that 70% of the series shared
Speaker 8:  something, and that's liberal podcasters, that's conservative podcasters,
Speaker 8:  that's moderate podcasters and those that I couldn't, you know, assign a
Speaker 8:  political ideology, 70% is very high, but based
Speaker 8:  on the nature of the medium, that doesn't necessarily surprise me. And
Speaker 8:  so I, you know, I would put this as like on the higher side, but
Speaker 8:  you know, it's obviously not every two episodes or every
Speaker 8:  side episodes. So I still think that it is comparatively
Speaker 8:  high, but not, not so, so high that we're entering
Speaker 8:  this like very troubling space.
Speaker 7:  Right? And some of these hosts that fall into the top
Speaker 7:  10 worst defenders are really prominent. So in addition to
Speaker 7:  Bannon who had the highest rate of one in five
Speaker 7:  episodes featuring this information, you had Charlie Kirk and Sean
Speaker 7:  Hannity very, very well known pundits, right? Is the issue that these claims
Speaker 7:  on the podcasting side just go unnoticed or that maybe
Speaker 7:  the audiences who are listening to them in the first place just agree with
Speaker 7:  them or that people who might look at media in a critical
Speaker 7:  sense just aren't really paying attention to these podcasts?
Speaker 8:  I think it's all three. You know, all three of those elements are
Speaker 8:  what makes this medium slightly different than television, which is much
Speaker 8:  more visible. You know, there's a fixed number of channels, there's a fixed
Speaker 8:  number of shows people are watching whether critically
Speaker 8:  or for confirmatory evidence. And there
Speaker 8:  are guardrails in place, right? Like after the election, Fox
Speaker 8:  News cracked down on what its pundits could say about the election,
Speaker 8:  especially after the safe harbor deadlines passed and when
Speaker 8:  there were kind of lawsuits flying around about voting machines.
Speaker 8:  And so, you know, there are sort of guardrails in place
Speaker 8:  a little bit, whereas in this space it's kind of, you know,
Speaker 8:  anything seems to go, it could be because it kind of flies under
Speaker 8:  the radar, this sort of sandbox of ideas where
Speaker 8:  you know, let's test out this possibility, see, see if it sticks,
Speaker 8:  see if it gets some traction, and then maybe expand it to a broader set of
Speaker 8:  conversations. And so I think that that's what makes
Speaker 8:  podcasting a bit different than those other spaces.
Speaker 7:  And so I know this is a complicated question, but what kind of steps
Speaker 7:  can the platforms take to mitigate these
Speaker 7:  misinformation issues?
Speaker 8:  I see a few ways to go about just
Speaker 8:  broadly even improving the medium. I mean the architecture is
Speaker 8:  so sparse for a lot of these apps that in in some
Speaker 8:  ways building that out a little bit, putting some investment into
Speaker 8:  a more collaborative medium potentially. You know, we
Speaker 8:  see on Twitter now with content moderation, it's kind of this wisdom of
Speaker 8:  the crowd approach. Wikipedia is a very wisdom of the crowd approach.
Speaker 8:  Reddit has moderators stack overflow, which is
Speaker 8:  more on the like data science side, maybe a bit of a niche
Speaker 8:  medium. But in any case, they all have these sort of
Speaker 8:  community based approaches. You know, podcasting could, could
Speaker 8:  experiment with something like that. Incorporating a little bit of an audience
Speaker 8:  check. You know, some apps have no potential even for
Speaker 8:  reporting series or reporting episodes or when they do
Speaker 8:  have that in place, it's so sparse and so lacking in detail
Speaker 8:  that you know, it's basically useless at that point. And so
Speaker 8:  reincorporating the audience, making it a little bit more of an interactive
Speaker 8:  medium potentially. Can users add transcripts? Maybe they wanna
Speaker 8:  add show notes. I know that some podcasters who have really kind of loyal
Speaker 8:  fan bases have this automatically, like now there's a
Speaker 8:  podcast about the Joe Rogan experience podcast,
Speaker 7:  Right? Like
Speaker 8:  Summarize it so like, you know, obviously some shows don't have
Speaker 8:  that loyal of a following or that kind of excited of a
Speaker 8:  following, but like building in some opportunity for that potential I think
Speaker 8:  would be really useful. Absent broader content moderation
Speaker 8:  practices, I think, you know, just transparency in general, like
Speaker 8:  what are your content moderation practices detailing those.
Speaker 8:  I think Apple has something that in their prac content moderation practices,
Speaker 8:  it's like mean-spirited content, but like what does that mean?
Speaker 7:  That could be anything,
Speaker 8:  Right? What does that mean? And then, you know, thinking about like
Speaker 8:  the algorithms that govern what serious people are exposed to
Speaker 8:  transparency around those, right? So I think that, you know,
Speaker 8:  other than word of mouth, those lists that are curated
Speaker 8:  are often ways that people find podcasts. And so,
Speaker 8:  you know, what goes into making those lists, obviously people are gonna then
Speaker 8:  try and game those lists and so, you know, being careful
Speaker 8:  but providing a little bit more transparency around that are their
Speaker 8:  series that, or lines where the content can stay up
Speaker 8:  but it won't be recommended or things like that. So just the broader
Speaker 8:  transparency space I think can be really greatly improved.
Speaker 8:  A little bit more effort into kind of the community
Speaker 8:  that's building around a lot of these podcasts, letting the audience
Speaker 8:  play a role, kind of removing that top down
Speaker 8:  information flow and adding like a bottom up conversation as
Speaker 8:  well I think could be really useful too. And then, you know, beyond
Speaker 8:  platforms, you know, I would love to see more researchers paying attention
Speaker 8:  to this medium. I hope that this research project has shown that
Speaker 8:  it's possible to explore this space systematically,
Speaker 8:  even though I only, you know, bit off 79
Speaker 8:  series out of, you know, the thousands that are out there and
Speaker 8:  36,000 episodes out of the millions that are out there. But it was
Speaker 8:  sort of strategic and systematic. And so it is possible to
Speaker 8:  explore this space in a way that is
Speaker 8:  productive as opposed to cherry picked here and there for the
Speaker 8:  worst offenders. And so hopefully I think that
Speaker 8:  galvanizes the research community a bit more because I do see this space
Speaker 8:  as, as growing and becoming increasingly prominent. Have
Speaker 7:  The platforms reached out at all saying, hey, maybe maybe we should change
Speaker 7:  our approach a little bit or be more specific in how we
Speaker 7:  define dangerous content.
Speaker 8:  I mean, I have seen even from past research,
Speaker 8:  so this is kind of the major report out of a lot
Speaker 8:  of, out of about two years of research into this space in
Speaker 8:  which various blog posts were published on the Brookings website. And so
Speaker 8:  even from those, I've seen shifts from the platforms a
Speaker 8:  bit. So Google has made it clear that they
Speaker 8:  aren't actually hosting content in like popups
Speaker 8:  on their website. So you know, I think that's a clear distinction between
Speaker 8:  like a Twitter and a Google podcast is the hosting element.
Speaker 8:  You know, apple has expanded, its sort of feedback
Speaker 8:  form to include specific categories that do align
Speaker 8:  with their content moderation practices. It's unclear if that's
Speaker 8:  wholly in response to this sort of line of research inquiry. But I have seen
Speaker 8:  some small changes. Another one that's an interesting one
Speaker 8:  actually is also Apple. You know, a lot of these shows
Speaker 8:  used to be classified as news and so
Speaker 8:  we would see, you know, the wrestling BA show or Pot Save
Speaker 8:  America or whatever being classified as news and you know,
Speaker 8:  there's now a new category that is news commentary. And so
Speaker 8:  I think that that is really important as well just to be able to
Speaker 8:  add in a layer of editorialization
Speaker 8:  because you know, it is news commentary, it's, it's not necessarily
Speaker 8:  news. And so I think that's also like a micro shift that
Speaker 8:  is meaningful in some respects, but there's way more to do in this space.
Speaker 8:  And I think that the apps have recognized it as a
Speaker 8:  space that will need to be dealt with, especially for places that
Speaker 8:  are thinking about more monetization, expanding sort of
Speaker 8:  these, you know, exclusive arrangements or
Speaker 8:  you know, like Apple Podcast plus or things like that where
Speaker 8:  they have additional content or things like that. So actually paying a bit
Speaker 8:  more attention to these things I think as the monetization grows
Speaker 8:  will definitely be something that I would see a lot of these places doing.
Speaker 7:  A lot of these platforms have very explicit policies on
Speaker 7:  overtly dangerous content, right? Violent content,
Speaker 7:  clear hate speech. And then when you get into misinformation that that's
Speaker 7:  just a little bit trickier, how far do you think they'll be willing to go
Speaker 7:  to tackle misinformation?
Speaker 8:  Yeah, I mean I, I think that that's a huge challenge when we saw it a ton
Speaker 8:  during the pandemic, right? Like especially as the pandemic
Speaker 8:  evolved, things that were obviously incorrect at a certain point
Speaker 8:  in time then became more accurate down the road. And so
Speaker 8:  while I think it's important to add sourcing
Speaker 8:  or notes or things like that, tags that say like, the claims
Speaker 8:  made in this are blah, blah blah or are the opinion of the
Speaker 8:  podcaster or here's your coronavirus
Speaker 8:  information center, or things like that, you know, I think all those things
Speaker 8:  are important and just giving people more context
Speaker 8:  and more ability to find the authoritative information
Speaker 8:  I think would be really useful as opposed to saying, you know, oh, you
Speaker 8:  shared this theory, like delete your episode, one more strike,
Speaker 8:  you're done. Because I do think what that has shown us is that
Speaker 8:  it's a really, like, especially in the midst of an
Speaker 8:  evolving health crisis, the information ecosystem is very
Speaker 8:  fluid, but it's also important to make sure people have access
Speaker 8:  to, you know, the latest medical guidelines or the,
Speaker 8:  the latest recommendations. And so, you know, incorporating that
Speaker 8:  into the architecture of the apps
Speaker 8:  I think would be really important as well.
Speaker 7:  Where do you think we are in terms of moderating
Speaker 7:  audio technologically, right? Like we, we've seen some improvements already.
Speaker 7:  You know, Spotify recently acquired a company that
Speaker 7:  uses AI to identify dangerous
Speaker 7:  information, they look for specific buzzwords, that kind of thing. How much
Speaker 7:  further does the technology have to improve before we can really
Speaker 7:  adequately moderate this kind of content?
Speaker 8:  I mean, there's two things I'll say to that. So one
Speaker 8:  is regardless of the machine learning
Speaker 8:  algorithm or whatever detection software is in
Speaker 8:  place, I think it's so important to still have a level of human
Speaker 8:  oversight. This report required at least two
Speaker 8:  coders for every episode that was flagged through
Speaker 8:  a text-based process. And so because of the
Speaker 8:  context around these claims, because of the nature
Speaker 8:  of the conversation, it's really important to be able to, to
Speaker 8:  have people to be able to actually get in there and, and look at the
Speaker 8:  surrounding content, which I think at this point is very much
Speaker 8:  still in the realm of human review. There are ways
Speaker 8:  to sort of look at like negating words or things like that or
Speaker 8:  to add that context in a little bit. But I do think that having that human
Speaker 8:  oversight is super important. And then even in terms of progress,
Speaker 8:  even in the span of this research project, we were using
Speaker 8:  sort of larger platform transcription tools that had a
Speaker 8:  cost associated with them. And so even in that span,
Speaker 8:  OpenAI has it's, it's called Whisper, which is a
Speaker 8:  free open source software for transcription and it
Speaker 8:  does a fairly good job. You know, even the AI
Speaker 8:  software that I use for speech to text recognition failed occasionally.
Speaker 8:  One of the funny ones that I came across was like Fauci s role, like
Speaker 8:  Anthony Fauci s role in all this sometimes transcribed
Speaker 8:  to like foul cheese roll.
Speaker 7:  Yeah.
Speaker 8:  And that was paid for, right? And so, right, there's still those issues in
Speaker 8:  that space as well, but Whisper has obviously some of those
Speaker 8:  challenges built into it still, even with the kind
Speaker 8:  of state-of-the-art softwares, we were still getting some of those bugs in
Speaker 8:  which obviously is par for the course, I think would
Speaker 8:  likely lead to an undercount as opposed to an overcount. But
Speaker 8:  even so, like now there are open source softwares that we can use
Speaker 8:  to make this a much more affordable process. Even
Speaker 8:  podcasters if they want to add free transcripts to their episodes, can
Speaker 8:  do it now using these softwares. And so I think that that
Speaker 8:  has been an evolution that has happened quite quickly. And so
Speaker 8:  it's kind of a, a mixed bag, right? Like there still has to be, I think
Speaker 8:  that level of manual oversight to make sure that sort of
Speaker 8:  the context of the claim, the intent of the claim or
Speaker 8:  whatever is being searched for are actually meaning what we think
Speaker 8:  they're meaning. And you know, while sort of automated processes can
Speaker 8:  help with that, the manual oversight is, I still think very important, but
Speaker 8:  then the tools are evolving and becoming more accessible as well.
Speaker 8:  And so I think it's, it's a bit of both,
Speaker 7:  You know, every election cycle it seems like there's a new
Speaker 7:  media narrative that emerges, right? Like cable news is
Speaker 7:  the problem or Facebook is the problem, or Twitter is the problem. And
Speaker 7:  we haven't really seen podcasting get much credit or
Speaker 7:  blame for how it's shaping political thought. Do you think that's
Speaker 7:  something that's gonna change in the 2024 cycle?
Speaker 8:  I mean, the thing about podcasting and a lot of the
Speaker 8:  kind of political hosts is that they have platforms everywhere. So
Speaker 8:  podcasting is just another tool in a broader
Speaker 8:  portfolio, right? Where they have a Twitter presence, maybe they're on a
Speaker 8:  cable news channel, also potentially on the radio also potentially on
Speaker 8:  podcasting. And so I think whether it is the,
Speaker 8:  the primary focus, I don't necessarily think so, but I think it only
Speaker 8:  can amplify. And by virtue of the challenges
Speaker 8:  inherent to analyzing the medium might be a space
Speaker 8:  where, you know, something that was maybe taken off of Twitter flies in
Speaker 8:  the podcasting world. You know, hopefully it can be incorporated
Speaker 8:  into a suite of kind of analysis processes that
Speaker 8:  explores all these different spaces as opposed to, you know, just
Speaker 8:  Twitter or just Facebook or just YouTube, you know, thinking
Speaker 8:  of them holistically is, is really important.
Speaker 7:  Valerie, thank you so, so much.
Speaker 8:  Of course.
Speaker 2:  Okay, we're gonna take one more break and then we're gonna be talking about
Speaker 2:  something that is really, really fun that I'm super excited about, entertainment
Speaker 2:  coverage. Charles Pullam Moore is gonna be talking with me all about the
Speaker 2:  last of us and Ant Man and the WASP Quantum mania. It's just a bunch
Speaker 2:  of nerds nerd now more right after this,
Speaker 9:  It's late, you're almost home after catching that concert you and your friend
Speaker 9:  snag tickets to with MX months ago. You're all speechless from the last
Speaker 9:  hour spent singing your hearts out. And the only thing playing in the car
Speaker 9:  is the last song of the night on a full blast in your head.
Speaker 9:  Admit it. You want it stuck there. The live version you can't get
Speaker 9:  anywhere else looks like you're getting goosebumps all over again.
Speaker 9:  When the night's a hit, that's when you're with amex. American Express.
Speaker 9:  Don't live life without it.
Speaker 10:  The world looks different behind the handle bars of a rat electric bike
Speaker 10:  grabbing takeout looks less like greasy styrofoam boxes and more like
Speaker 10:  a cross town adventure ride shares look less like piling into the back
Speaker 10:  of a car and more like grabbing fresh air with your friends and
Speaker 10:  commuting can even start to look like the best part of your day.
Speaker 10:  That's because with Rad the world is what you make of it, not what it makes
Speaker 10:  of you see for yourself with a 14 day free trial, find your
Speaker 10:  fun@radpowerbikes.com.
Speaker 2:  And we're back and I've got Charles Pulley Moore here to talk about the last
Speaker 2:  of us in and Marvel fatigue. Yeah, let's start with
Speaker 2:  our last of us because this was the first time we met Riley. They're doing
Speaker 2:  the adaptation of the DLC from the game and it was an
Speaker 2:  absolutely emotional downer of an episode. Ri,
Speaker 10:  Why
Speaker 2:  Have you been? I will tell you everything you have to come with me for a
Speaker 2:  few hours. You trust we're almost to the end of the first
Speaker 2:  season. This was the big episode where we did like
Speaker 2:  flashbacks to stuff that was in comic books and
Speaker 2:  stuff, right?
Speaker 11:  Yeah. Like Riley is mentioned in the first last of us, but it isn't
Speaker 11:  until the last of us comic that we really sort of start to see the full
Speaker 11:  story of what went down between Riley. Not just like how they
Speaker 11:  were friends and the qsy, but sort of like one of the most like
Speaker 11:  momentous parts of their relationship. Like takes place sort of like
Speaker 11:  right before the video game picks up. And so when we are meeting Ellie
Speaker 11:  as like a player, it's just sort of like, oh, who's this aloof kid
Speaker 11:  who's just kind of sort of out about, you know, in the wilderness, you
Speaker 11:  know, doing their own thing. And Ellie, you know, is truly like in
Speaker 11:  the thick of like some emotional distraughtness that
Speaker 11:  Joel is included into, and we're not clued into because you know, we're
Speaker 11:  seeing things from his perspective. But when you dig into the comic you
Speaker 11:  sort of see like, oh, like Ellie, she's not an asshole, right? Like she's
Speaker 11:  coping with everything. This episode just really just introduces us to Riley
Speaker 11:  with a fullness that was not the case in the video game and
Speaker 11:  in the same way that a lot of people were sort of like lit up by episode
Speaker 11:  three long, long time. And the way that it sort of brought Frank and Bill
Speaker 11:  into the picture. Yeah, I remember when I was watching the screeners, I
Speaker 11:  had that same feeling for this episode because like you said, it is
Speaker 11:  another flashback episode with some sort of sad moments, but
Speaker 11:  it's also sort of this bottle episode that uses its
Speaker 11:  being in the past to show you like what all these people have lost
Speaker 11:  and it just like really moves me.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I thought it was interesting we'd kind of been teased about Riley
Speaker 2:  on the show. There was this expectation because there had been this,
Speaker 2:  this D l C starring her. There had been this comic book featuring her,
Speaker 2:  so fans knew who Riley was and there was almost treated
Speaker 2:  like an Easter egg in early episodes where people would mention Riley and,
Speaker 2:  and Ellie would get all stone-faced and upset. But now we finally, we
Speaker 2:  finally see her and, and Storm Reeb really has to like live up to a lot of
Speaker 2:  hype,
Speaker 11:  Right? In the same way that we are supposed to really sort of have this
Speaker 11:  deeper understanding of the pain that Joel is carrying
Speaker 11:  with him after we sort of meet his daughter Sarah. The same sort of has
Speaker 11:  to happen here after we meet Riley. Obviously their dynamic is a little
Speaker 11:  different. So like in the context of the show, given that we've had another
Speaker 11:  bottle episode that was about Bill and Frank, I think that the, the challenge
Speaker 11:  that Storm Reed was really up against in
Speaker 11:  portraying Riley was like, you have all of sort of like the the
Speaker 11:  textual elements of the character that we have from the comic and the game,
Speaker 11:  but then within the context of the show, you also sort of have to nail,
Speaker 11:  I hate to put it this way, but like, surprise, you're another sad queer
Speaker 11:  character who exists wholly in the past. We need you to exist here
Speaker 11:  and stand out from the other sad gays that our show has had. Can you
Speaker 11:  do it?
Speaker 2:  No, but that's, that's true. Like,
Speaker 11:  Like you and I are two queers who watch a lot of media and we consume
Speaker 11:  a lot of queer like sad queer media in particular. And it's like
Speaker 2:  A hundred percent
Speaker 11:  You get like one in a show, it's like, all right, you've used your, your
Speaker 11:  ticket to sad queer town do something a little different. And for this show
Speaker 11:  to be like, oh, we're going back for another one.
Speaker 2:  What do we do now?
Speaker 2:  We're gonna figure it out.
Speaker 11:  I think that in focusing on like a young lesbian
Speaker 11:  romance between two teenage girls in the apocalypse, that in and of
Speaker 11:  itself already fundamentally shifts what kind of story is being told, right?
Speaker 11:  Like right. This episode was really sort of great because
Speaker 11:  it picks up at a, it's not really showing you the origins of their
Speaker 11:  friendship and their bond. We sort of meet them. Riley is essentially like
Speaker 11:  gone missing and everyone assumes that she's dead. Are
Speaker 12:  You okay? I'm fine. I just ran away for a bit. That's
Speaker 2:  All.
Speaker 11:  So many of these scenes kind of reinforce that the loneliness that Ellie
Speaker 11:  leads with that hard loneliness, that hardened loneliness that she leads
Speaker 11:  with, that was coming in fits and starts here when this
Speaker 11:  episode opens. You know, we're seeing that she's being bullied by these
Speaker 11:  other kids at school and she's, you know, she's whipping these bullies asses,
Speaker 11:  which is great, but she's also really sort of in pain in a
Speaker 11:  way that she thinks she's never really gonna be able to pull herself out
Speaker 11:  of until Riley shows back up
Speaker 12:  Tonight. I'm gonna show you the four wonders of them all.
Speaker 2:  I think what's interesting if we compare and contrast this with the Bill
Speaker 2:  and Frank episode, cause I think there's a lot to compare and contrast there,
Speaker 2:  right? Is that this episode is much more about highlighting that
Speaker 2:  loneliness. Mm. And so we really feel like
Speaker 2:  the stakes to her saving and protecting Joel in this episode and in
Speaker 2:  the episodes that are gonna follow has to hit a lot harder. And I think both
Speaker 2:  actresses just did a really, really fantastic job of, of nailing this
Speaker 2:  relationship and making us feel something so
Speaker 2:  that her, her loneliness and, and her, her
Speaker 2:  stakes are all kind of there for the rest of this, for this next big
Speaker 2:  arc that Ellie has to experience
Speaker 11:  Something that this episode really sort of highlights. And I think in a
Speaker 11:  really beautiful, subtle way, it does sort of get into how being
Speaker 11:  born into this fundamentally changes a person. And it's not a change
Speaker 11:  that any of those people themselves can perceive, but it is something
Speaker 11:  one imagines that adults like Joel and Tess could see in
Speaker 11:  kids like Ellie. Like, oh, you, you move through the world differently as
Speaker 11:  a child and we all know why and there's nothing that any of us can really
Speaker 11:  do to change it because there's no amount of like shielding
Speaker 11:  or coddling or making things relatively okay that can
Speaker 11:  really counterbalance growing up in the apocalypse. You know what I mean?
Speaker 11:  Right. Watching the show, it's difficult to understand like what the fireflies
Speaker 11:  are entirely, but this episode does a solid job of really conveying to you
Speaker 11:  how life is so shitty that working with the firefly seems like a
Speaker 11:  viable option for Riley.
Speaker 2:  And there's just enough hope, particularly in her relationship with Ellie.
Speaker 2:  There's just enough hope there that you, you can feel kind of the hope, but
Speaker 2:  always she comes back to this, this core wariness.
Speaker 11:  There's a wariness, but there's also this pragmatism, right? Yeah. Which
Speaker 11:  I really love. One of my least favorite tropes in post-apocalyptic fiction
Speaker 11:  is where kids wander outside of the zone. Like let's go do dangerous things.
Speaker 11:  Be a little dumbasses. Why? Why? Why would you do that? Like your existence
Speaker 11:  up until this point suggests to me that you don't do stupid things like
Speaker 11:  this. But apparently I'm wrong. But with this, because the show has really
Speaker 11:  established like, look, in order for the qsy to function the way they do,
Speaker 11:  runners have to be able to go outside regularly, right? Kids
Speaker 11:  like Ellie and Riley are growing up understanding that there are people
Speaker 11:  going in and out of the boundaries regularly and presumably they, you know,
Speaker 11:  some of them get jazzed up to do it themselves. And for it to be like, Hey,
Speaker 11:  do you wanna come to a, like, do you wanna come to the mall with me? Do
Speaker 11:  you wanna come to the mall and make the most noise possible? Again, not
Speaker 11:  smart, not smart at all. In the context of the episode, it does kind of
Speaker 11:  play like, look, I know you and I are really accustomed to being no
Speaker 11:  nonsense. Let's not do stupid shit, but do you just wanna do the tiniest
Speaker 11:  little bit of stupid shit together?
Speaker 2:  They just have so much fun and happiness that they accidentally wake up a
Speaker 2:  zombie and get bit, no,
Speaker 13:  No, no, no, no, no.
Speaker 11:  We don't have to see it. And that just sort of goes back to how this show
Speaker 11:  understands or rather, this show has really stuck to its commitment
Speaker 11:  to be about human emotions and not so much
Speaker 11:  the gore, the gruesomeness. I'm, I'm torn on that cuz I, I, I wrote this
Speaker 11:  in my review personally. I wanted to see more zombies, or rather I wanted
Speaker 11:  to see more fungus. They don't need to be fighting them. Like truly, if
Speaker 11:  I just saw Blo walking down the street cuz they get
Speaker 11:  around, right? They're not always fighting like, just show me chords. And
Speaker 11:  like a couple of them are specials zombies. But the show has
Speaker 11:  decided not to do that. I, I, I get it. But every time there is one
Speaker 11:  of these sort of like, ah, shit, I got bits. It does always hit really hard.
Speaker 11:  So I have to say like it's the show's doing a good job with them.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, it's nice. I think we've had probably what, two really graphic
Speaker 2:  death by zombies from characters that we actually like.
Speaker 2:  And, and that was Cass and then Sam. And otherwise it's
Speaker 2:  been like doing a real kindness to just going, yeah, you've seen all these
Speaker 2:  other ones. You don't need to see this, this teenage girl turn and her friend
Speaker 2:  like sobbing as she has to kill her. Like we can skip that.
Speaker 2:  You can, you can just imagine that
Speaker 11:  The casual Oh yeah, she got, got too. That quality to how
Speaker 11:  Kathleen got gotten in just like the, the, the chaos of the
Speaker 11:  zombies coming outta the ground. I love that the show's just like, here's
Speaker 11:  a big bad that you, you need to be worried about. And then by the end it's
Speaker 11:  like, yeah, and then, you know, a random zombie just jumps on or would not
Speaker 11:  talk about her anymore.
Speaker 2:  Well speaking of, of things coming out of the ground and then everybody talking
Speaker 2:  about it furiously, let's, let's talk about this. Is that my segue
Speaker 2:  for, for Marvel and Antman and, and Marvel Fatigue?
Speaker 15:  I used to ask myself a lot of questions. Scott, you're at Ex-Con,
Speaker 15:  how are you an Avenger?
Speaker 2:  That doesn't make sense because Antman Quantum Media, you and I both saw
Speaker 2:  it. I liked it more than you did. You were like, this is fine. And I was
Speaker 2:  like, this is solid like BB plus. And most people do not feel
Speaker 2:  that way about it.
Speaker 11:  You and I have been talking about this movie for the past week and every
Speaker 11:  time you've come talk to me, I'm like, crayons my goodness. You know, I,
Speaker 11:  you know, I, you know, I don't have any space in my mind for Quantum Mania
Speaker 11:  anymore. And it wasn't until this weekend that I looked and saw that like
Speaker 11:  it's not that it's being review bombed, people just do not care for this
Speaker 11:  movie.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. People
Speaker 11:  Are passionately against anti man in the wasp quantum
Speaker 11:  mania. I get it. I get it. To a certain extent, it is not my favorite film
Speaker 11:  from Marvel Studios by any stretch of the imagination. Even though I don't
Speaker 11:  think it's Marvel's worst film. I think it is a film that is suffering from
Speaker 11:  when it comes out in the grand scheme of things, like if we were to
Speaker 11:  anthropomorphize Marvel films, I think that Black Widow and Quantum Mania
Speaker 11:  would be sitting at a table by themselves saying, wow, look at how
Speaker 11:  they've done us dirty.
Speaker 2:  Just refusing to make eye contact with all the other movies around this
Speaker 11:  Truly, truly, you know, Antman in the, was Quantum Mania, it is the third
Speaker 11:  Ant Man film. I guess finally sort of making good on like the promise of
Speaker 11:  the quantum realm. I went into this thinking like this is gonna be the one
Speaker 11:  that finally kind of, sort of tries to explain what the quantum realm is.
Speaker 11:  Is it just a waystation for time travelers? Let's find out. And
Speaker 11:  Quantum Mania says not just that, it's essentially the micro verse, right?
Speaker 11:  Comic book fans, I'm not gonna get into what the micro verse is, but tldr,
Speaker 11:  it is an entire universe, but tiny, it's
Speaker 16:  A secret universe beneath ours.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, it gets, it like moves right past the science. There's like a
Speaker 2:  minute of science and then it's like, no, we're just gonna go do Journey
Speaker 2:  to the center of the Earth, but with tons more cgi.
Speaker 11:  You see Journey to the center of the Earth. I see Osmosis Jones,
Speaker 11:  it's your standard Marvel film, right? We get sucked into strange
Speaker 11:  place where there is a villainous type
Speaker 11:  character who has complicated motivations, who is terrorizing people.
Speaker 11:  In this case it's Jonathan Majors is hanging the conqueror who is, he's
Speaker 11:  conquered the quantum realm. And at one point he was very good friends with
Speaker 11:  Janet VanDyne, Michelle Pfeiffer, who you know from the second Aunt Manon
Speaker 11:  movie, aunt Man in the Wasp. She got outta the quantum realm in the second
Speaker 11:  movie and didn't tell anybody anything about it. And this movie is like,
Speaker 11:  yo, Janet, what was going on down there? And all of this is, again,
Speaker 11:  all of this is just your, this is all very standard Marvel Fair.
Speaker 2:  I would definitely say of all of the Marvel like trilogies little
Speaker 2:  sections, ant Man Pound for Pound is still the
Speaker 2:  strongest
Speaker 11:  No act
Speaker 2:  Because Iron Man Two I like, I think Iron Man two is significantly
Speaker 2:  worse.
Speaker 11:  Oh it is.
Speaker 2:  And so like it drags, it drags down the Iron Man franchise
Speaker 2:  more than Quantum Mania drags down the Antman franchise
Speaker 11:  And the promise of Quantum mania is like one Billy Quantum
Speaker 11:  Mania and Multiverse Madness or two of like the better names that that Marvel
Speaker 11:  has ever had. Like oh shit, what's going on? And they've both just
Speaker 11:  under-delivered in big ways. But that's what I was saying. So the confluence
Speaker 11:  of factors, right? It's the third movie in a franchise, which can go either
Speaker 11:  way. It can be a great, like we can, you can Ragner Rocket and be like,
Speaker 11:  oh shit, let's revitalize things and bring everybody in. Or you can Iron
Speaker 11:  Man three it and sort of just kind of wrap it up, right?
Speaker 11:  There's that going on for it. But there's also been a gradual shift
Speaker 11:  in the way that Marvel makes movies, right? If you go back and watch the
Speaker 11:  first Antman movie, it's set predominantly Aunt San Francisco, right? We
Speaker 11:  are moving through the real, the regular human world and playing
Speaker 11:  with perspective in size and ways that are comedic, right? Oh my god, Thomas
Speaker 11:  a tank engine is humongous. Look at that. So crazy Scott
Speaker 11:  Lang's going down a pipe. That's cool. We can all recognize what that
Speaker 11:  is. You know what I mean? We can recognize what a lot of those set pieces
Speaker 11:  were, sort of what the jokes are meant to be here in quantum mania.
Speaker 11:  Everything is set in the quantum realm. And while this could have been an
Speaker 11:  opportunity to explain sort of what the quantum realm is, what it does,
Speaker 11:  it's literally just a big CGI fest. My impression
Speaker 11:  watching this, everything looks as if it was shot on a sound stage, partially
Speaker 11:  because the lighting and
Speaker 2:  Also it was shot on a sound
Speaker 11:  Stage. Well you, but you know what I mean? Yeah. Everything is just a lit
Speaker 11:  so aggressively that it looks like it's a staged play, which it shouldn't,
Speaker 11:  right? When you're throwing this much expensive VFX at something,
Speaker 11:  right? This is a lesson that James Cameron understands very well when you're
Speaker 11:  going to be that expensive, it has to look real.
Speaker 11:  And the challenge is settling on a reality
Speaker 11:  to sort of shoot for, right? It's not what, when we go into
Speaker 11:  an avatar the way of water, we are not looking for shots
Speaker 11:  of reality that gel with our own experience of Pandora cuz we
Speaker 11:  haven't been there, right? We are looking for something that has
Speaker 11:  determined what its reality is going to be and then done everything in its
Speaker 11:  power to make that reality look organic and living in breathing
Speaker 11:  so much so that you are tricked into thinking, oh this looks
Speaker 11:  real. Right? When people say that the way water looks realistic,
Speaker 11:  I think to myself point to me in the movie where it was realistic, please
Speaker 11:  show me, show me, show me, show me. You may have an argument when it comes
Speaker 11:  to the way that the light is refracted through the water. Sure. But
Speaker 11:  everything else is sort of ridiculous. It's just that it's all working in
Speaker 11:  concert together to create an illusion. Quantum mania. There are many, so
Speaker 11:  this is not a spoiler cuz you've seen it in the trailer. Delaying family.
Speaker 11:  Everybody right? Everybody gets sucked in the quantum realm. It's
Speaker 11:  underwhelming. And part of it is because a lot of these things are difficult
Speaker 11:  to, to visualize. I was thinking this, watching one of the Latter Hunger
Speaker 11:  Games movies over the weekend where no one knew what they were acting
Speaker 11:  against. And it, it's, you can say that it's the actor's job to be able
Speaker 11:  to know, but it is hard to conjure the emotion of
Speaker 11:  being in to, of being chased by a wall of black liquid or
Speaker 11:  being in the quantum realm surrounded by ameba people. So everyone
Speaker 11:  is doing their best job at being like, wow, there's energy
Speaker 11:  spirals in the sky and yet it does not read on the screen. And I think that
Speaker 11:  a lot of the negative reaction to this film, it stems from
Speaker 11:  the fact that the creation of the illusion is just so subpar
Speaker 11:  in multiple ways throughout the film that you, well, rather that
Speaker 11:  audiences are just like, huh, this is the third Aunt Man movie,
Speaker 11:  isn't it? Huh? No one has talked about what's going on with that
Speaker 11:  eternal hand coming out the planet. Have they, I guess Marvel is kind of
Speaker 11:  sort of entering a weird spot and not fulfilling, you know, my expectations
Speaker 11:  and that's fine, but I don't think that it's fair
Speaker 11:  entirely to blame it solely on quantum mania.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I I think, I think the fatigue is separate
Speaker 2:  from, from this particular movie. I think like this movie, the, the
Speaker 2:  flaws of this movie highlight that fatigue because people are tired of
Speaker 2:  things with no stakes. And the stakes have gotten so
Speaker 2:  cosmic, they've gotten so big in the Marvel
Speaker 2:  universe that they've gone right back around to not having, not really having
Speaker 2:  steaks. Right. They're not grounding it enough. And so they try
Speaker 2:  to, they tried to give, like Michelle Pfeiffer, bless her heart, she is working,
Speaker 2:  she's great to give this film Steaks. Yeah.
Speaker 11:  Part of the issue with Quantum Man is that there are too many people in
Speaker 11:  it. We have Aunt Man and the Waz cool. We have Scott's daughter,
Speaker 11:  Cassie. Cool. We've also got the original aunt man, Hank Pam
Speaker 11:  and his wife Janet VanDyne, who have drama
Speaker 11:  with their daughter. Hope that is being addressed in this movie.
Speaker 11:  And I'm sure that there's a flow chart somewhere in Marm HQ being like,
Speaker 11:  here's how it's all gonna work together perfectly and synergize. And it
Speaker 11:  totally could've, it just didn't hear, do I wanna see cool old man
Speaker 11:  Michael Douglas commanding Army's events? Sure. But I also wanna see,
Speaker 11:  and I say this in the, the Marvel branding sense, I wanna see like old woman
Speaker 11:  Janet in the quantum realm, you know, shooting stuff with her blasters and
Speaker 11:  the film. You can tell that the film is trying to play in all of these faces,
Speaker 11:  but it can't commit to any one of them. And in doing so, a lot of the stories,
Speaker 11:  they are all addressed and touched upon to
Speaker 11:  equal levels of depth, I think, but not quite deep enough for
Speaker 11:  any of them to really hit or land, which would be
Speaker 11:  fine if this was like the second hit man movie, I kind of feel.
Speaker 11:  But for the, this is the one that kicks off the next phase and this is the
Speaker 11:  one where we're seeing King the conqueror in full action. It's like, all
Speaker 11:  right, well let's focus on that cuz that kind of seems to me like it's important.
Speaker 11:  No,
Speaker 2:  Yeah. It, it felt like the film got kind of dragged down by the
Speaker 2:  expectations of the o over the overarching plot. Hmm. So it felt
Speaker 2:  more like when you're watching, you're watching your little show, and I'm
Speaker 2:  gonna gonna refer to like the CW d c universe shows. You're watching your
Speaker 2:  little show, you're having a good time, and then suddenly everything shifts
Speaker 2:  because they've gotta go serve their purpose to the big crossover episode.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And it's that same feeling of like, okay, but like I was super
Speaker 2:  girls that got this whole thing going on and I'm really excited about this
Speaker 2:  plot, and now I gotta suddenly worry about the flash. And like, I didn't
Speaker 2:  ask for that,
Speaker 11:  And that's kind of how the movie's supposed to work. But it's like, at the
Speaker 11:  beginning I'm thinking to myself like, oh no, like I'm ant man and I'm super
Speaker 11:  famous and I don't know what to do with my life. And I kind of sort of don't
Speaker 11:  have a relationship with my daughter. I'm like, oh, Scott Lang just, I want
Speaker 11:  this. Like, give me, give me this. I, I imagine that Marvel,
Speaker 11:  Kevin Figes had many a conversation about this. How do you
Speaker 11:  start to see the universe with a new big bad, right? Because
Speaker 11:  pre Thanos, the, the Marvel movies were just like, oh, like Thor
Speaker 11:  got his hammer back. Oh, look at that Ironman, he is still alive. And then
Speaker 11:  at one point it was just, Thanos just showed up, truly a, a purple man just
Speaker 11:  showed up. It's not that he didn't make any sense, but there was no warning.
Speaker 11:  The purple man showed up, the nerds lost their minds and Marvel said, we
Speaker 11:  got 'em. Yeah. The difficulty with all these things, once you, you know,
Speaker 11:  pulling off a trick once does not ensure its success again. And now
Speaker 11:  Marvel has tried to do, Marvel has tried to do something similar by
Speaker 11:  having a Kang variant pop up at the end of Loki. But it
Speaker 11:  just hasn't quite stuck. It's like, all right, well, so what
Speaker 2:  I don't think making King the big bad is the problem, right? Like Jonathan
Speaker 2:  Majors is just killing it, but the, but they, they're trying to build, they're
Speaker 2:  trying to set up a multiverse. And the thing is, we've seen a lot of multiverses
Speaker 2:  at this point. Like we as audiences are familiar with them,
Speaker 2:  say what you will about the CW shows it did a really good multiverse and
Speaker 2:  it did it well, and it did a super entertaining job. Spider-Man into the
Speaker 2:  multiverse that does a really good job of doing multiverses. And we are seeing
Speaker 2:  all these, we've seen some other multiverses out there too, right? But the
Speaker 2:  Marvel one is just weird. It's not gelling. And I think
Speaker 2:  part of that is because we don't care about any of the other characters in
Speaker 2:  the multiverse. They're all just like, what Cannon fodder. And then it seems
Speaker 2:  to take like the impact of King diminish the impact of
Speaker 2:  Kane because there's a ton of kings. So it's like, okay, which is like the
Speaker 2:  big bad,
Speaker 11:  I have said this in public before, my interest, my
Speaker 11:  investment rather in the M C U started to diminish
Speaker 11:  one's characters I like started to disappear either because the actors who
Speaker 11:  played them died or because Wanda became bad and then she left
Speaker 11:  and then she died. And now I'm just kind of like, all right, well I don't
Speaker 11:  really know why I'm here anymore. I think part of the fatigue is people
Speaker 11:  don't like having to keep track of all of this. I think it's not that people
Speaker 11:  don't want to do the work, people aren't willing to do the work, rather
Speaker 11:  of watching a, a Disney plus show here seeing a movie there,
Speaker 11:  but the expectation is that that work is going to be rewarded
Speaker 11:  at some point or that there's going to be some sort of payoff to it.
Speaker 11:  And this phase in particular right now has definitely felt
Speaker 11:  like, I know that the official Marvel line is this is the multiverse saga.
Speaker 11:  This feels like the holding pattern saga. Yeah. More so than anything else,
Speaker 11:  right? This has felt like everybody's gotta have kids and then we're gonna
Speaker 11:  have the kids set up for the future and then we're gonna introduce the next
Speaker 11:  big bad and then everything can start coming together. And for like the
Speaker 11:  nerdiest of nerds. Sure. But for your average
Speaker 11:  casual fans who are just like, I wanna see the Avengers, right?
Speaker 11:  People who expect to see a team of superheroes, they wanna get their
Speaker 11:  money's worth. Like none of these solo projects, they wanna see sweeping
Speaker 11:  shots of people standing back to back saving the world. We haven't quite
Speaker 11:  gotten there.
Speaker 2:  We haven't, part of that is we're seeing the scaffolding of this. We're
Speaker 2:  seeing the structure of Disney creating this
Speaker 2:  new storyline, right? Like quantum mania. I think one of the
Speaker 2:  things that is probably most difficult for people is that they know they're
Speaker 2:  being set up. They know that this is a set up movie. There's emotional
Speaker 2:  payoff, right? We see that, that that relationship between Scott and
Speaker 2:  Cassie take a turn and he starts to trust her as being a superhero.
Speaker 2:  And we see hope, kind of fix things a little with her mom
Speaker 2:  kinda, but for the most part it feels like, no, we're in this holding pattern
Speaker 2:  and we know exactly why we're in this holding pattern because there's gonna
Speaker 2:  be more movies and they need to save some of the plot for those movies.
Speaker 2:  Whereas those first couple of phases in the Marvel universe, those
Speaker 2:  didn't feel like we're getting the band together. But hold up a second cuz
Speaker 2:  we gotta make sure everybody's contracts are signed and we're good to go.
Speaker 2:  Those first ones were just like, oh wow, look at all these characters and
Speaker 2:  now they're all coming together, this is crazy. And like the Guardians of
Speaker 2:  the Galaxy are here, what do they do? This is wild. And now it's like,
Speaker 2:  okay, most of these other ones, by the end of the film, people have not grown
Speaker 2:  or they've grown and then are abruptly murdered.
Speaker 11:  Right? Or they're pulled into space for space tribunal and
Speaker 11:  it's like, okay, sure. I guess we'll see that in seven years.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And, and it's just, it's, I, I get why people are fatigued,
Speaker 2:  especially if you didn't, if you haven't had to already do all of this reading
Speaker 2:  comic books, like a lot you, you and I were like, it's a little tiring, but
Speaker 2:  we've been doing this for years because we read comic books and this is how
Speaker 2:  comic books handle big stories and it's really irritating and we hate
Speaker 2:  it. And marvel's like, yeah, it is really irritating and you do hate it,
Speaker 2:  but it sells comics. So we're gonna do the exact same thing for films.
Speaker 11:  But you saying earlier about the scaffolding, I think that's so interesting
Speaker 11:  because you're right, like thinking back to I like what is the, the most
Speaker 11:  interesting thing that Marvel has put out recently or the thing that's like
Speaker 11:  lit me up the most? And I think the, when we're talking about the MCU
Speaker 11:  proper, I'm still kind of stuck on Miss Marvel, right? Because it
Speaker 11:  was, it just felt really fresh and sort of really new for the space. But
Speaker 11:  in that last episode, when you hear the theme
Speaker 11:  song from the X-Men playing, it's so interesting because at one point in
Speaker 11:  time that would've just been like a haha, the X-men are showing up, you
Speaker 11:  guys get excited
Speaker 2:  An Easter egg, and you're like, oh, nice.
Speaker 11:  Yeah. And now it's like Kamala's a mutant, what does this mean for everybody?
Speaker 11:  When are the X-men coming up? How is Kamala gonna become a part of them?
Speaker 11:  And part of that is it's our own fault, right? For
Speaker 11:  being the speculative rumor hungry nerds that we are. But
Speaker 11:  the studios play into it now, right? Like it's very much intentional
Speaker 11:  and it has the unintended consequence of making everything
Speaker 11:  sort of feel inconsent not inconsequential, but when
Speaker 11:  you have your focus so firmly fixed on the future, the present doesn't mean
Speaker 11:  quite as much, right? So thinking to myself, I'm still stuck on,
Speaker 11:  is Kamala a mutant? We have a poster for the marbles, they're all going
Speaker 11:  to space together and she's got a new costume. And I'm thinking to myself,
Speaker 11:  what's going on with your genetic makeup? Right? And I think,
Speaker 11:  I think on that, like that's, that's, that's, that's good synergy to a certain
Speaker 11:  extent, but I think that it's not always ideal
Speaker 11:  because you are sort of keeping your eye on the horizon. So the entire time
Speaker 11:  watching Quantum mania, to your point to set a movie, I'm thinking, well,
Speaker 11:  the Kang dynasty is competent. It's coming, right? No matter how this movie
Speaker 11:  ends, I know that Kang, one of them is going to succeed
Speaker 11:  in some way that necessitates the Avengers teaming up to
Speaker 11:  try to take him down. And that's definitely an exciting
Speaker 11:  prospect for me, Kang fan. But for me, person
Speaker 11:  who was trying to give Scott Lang another try, I'm like, all right, Scott Lang,
Speaker 11:  show me what you got. But I looked up my watch a couple of times while I
Speaker 11:  was watching the movie. I'm not gonna lie.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I, I did too. And I, I would give it a, I'd still
Speaker 2:  give the movie a solid beat, but that is because I just love whenever somebody
Speaker 2:  goes to brand a new planet and sees a MEbA people. Well,
Speaker 2:  thank you. Thank you Charles as always for Pop popping on and talking
Speaker 2:  to me about what's going on in the pop culture universe.
Speaker 11:  Of course.
Speaker 2:  Okay, that is it for the Ver Cast today. Thanks for listening. There's a
Speaker 2:  lot more stuff from all of these conversations@theverge.com
Speaker 2:  and we put a bunch of links in the show notes and you have any
Speaker 2:  thoughts, feedback, feelings, tips, you can always email
Speaker 2:  us@vergecasttheverge.com or you can call the hotline. It's
Speaker 2:  eight six six Verge 11, that's 8 66 Verge 11.
Speaker 2:  We may answer a question you have in a future episode. The show is
Speaker 2:  produced by Andrew Marino and Liam James Brooke Mentors is our editorial
Speaker 2:  director of Audio. The Vercast is a Verge production and part of the Vox
Speaker 2:  Media podcast network. Eli Richard and I are gonna be back on Friday with
Speaker 2:  more of the Verge crew to talk all about Mobile World Congress gadgets and
Speaker 2:  more. So we'll see you then.