# Transcript
ID: 1f9284a7-b147-456a-88dd-41d67f7ca70c
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Saying goodbye to Twitter
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/3082112407509788653/6135683490531024156/s93290-US-4430s-1702457908.mp3
Description: Today on the flagship podcast of good tweets:
03:40 - The Verge’s William Poor goes on a vintage tech odyssey in the hopes of future-proofing his family’s heirloom Mac Classic.
28:35 - David Pierce, Alex Cranz, and Nilay Patel discuss why they spent so much time on Twitter for so many years.
The year Twitter died: a special series from The Verge
How Twitter broke the news
Extremely softcore: the old Twitter was an idealist’s workplace and a naive business
The great tweet archive
Twitter was a harassment machine
It’s time for the Excel World Championships!
1:05:40 - David answers a question from the Vergecast Hotline about organizing your digital photos.
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we love hearing from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (2 ads detected)
Speaker 2:  Welcome To The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of Good Tweets. I'm your friend,
Speaker 2:  David Pierce, and I am currently standing on the casino floor of the
Speaker 2:  MGM Grand Casino in Las Vegas. I've been here for the last few days, not
Speaker 2:  for the National Rodeo Finals, which was this weekend, or for the NBA in
Speaker 2:  season tournament, which was this weekend or for the Raiders game, which
Speaker 2:  was this weekend, but for easily the biggest event of all the Microsoft
Speaker 2:  Excel World Championships. That's a real thing and it was
Speaker 2:  awesome. Basically the idea is a bunch of the world's best spreadsheets get
Speaker 2:  together and they spend a couple of days teaching each other how to use Excel
Speaker 2:  learning some of the app's, coolest new features, and then they compete.
Speaker 2:  They get these incredibly complicated puzzles and they spend hours
Speaker 2:  and hours trying to figure out the best, fastest, most
Speaker 2:  elaborate, most efficient way to solve these puzzles.
Speaker 2:  The competition was actually in the HyperX eSports arena at the Luxor
Speaker 2:  Casino. It was a big deal. This is the biggest one of these they've ever
Speaker 2:  done, and I have to say it was pretty dramatic, or at least as dramatic
Speaker 2:  as it can be when a bunch of people are sitting on stage doing spreadsheets
Speaker 2:  in ways that you absolutely do not understand and didn't even know people
Speaker 2:  could do spreadsheets, but you should watch this thing. It's a few hours
Speaker 2:  long, but you can kind of blow through it. The video on YouTube, it's streamed
Speaker 2:  on Twitch and on ESPN. I'll link it in the show notes. It was a ton of fun.
Speaker 2:  Cannot recommend it enough, and now I'm just basically wandering the casino
Speaker 2:  floor, looking for somewhere to lose $20 before I have to go get back on
Speaker 2:  the plane. Anyway, we have an awesome show coming up for you today. The verges
Speaker 2:  will pour is gonna take us through an adventure he had when he
Speaker 2:  rediscovered a 30-year-old computer and tried to figure out what to do with
Speaker 2:  it. Then we're gonna talk about Twitter because in a very real way,
Speaker 2:  2023 was the year that Twitter died and Diverge just did a big
Speaker 2:  package on what it meant and kind of mourning what Twitter once
Speaker 2:  was and for all the bad stuff about it, Twitter had some moments. So we're
Speaker 2:  gonna talk about what those moments were. It's gonna be a lot of fun. And
Speaker 2:  then of course, as we always do, we're gonna get to The Vergecast Hotline
Speaker 2:  Super fun show lot to get to. First I'm gonna go spin the wheel of Fortune
Speaker 2:  wheel. Wish me luck. This is The Vergecast. We'll be right back.
Speaker 3:  Nearly 24,000 kids had their identity stolen in 2022.
Speaker 3:  In the age of social media and phishing schemes, it's more important
Speaker 3:  than ever to protect your family's personal data. Microsoft
Speaker 3:  Defender helps keep your personal information safer online with
Speaker 3:  identity theft monitoring for the whole family, giving you real-time
Speaker 3:  alerts, expert guidance, and even hands-on restoration
Speaker 3:  support. When you need help, you get personal data plus
Speaker 3:  device protection all in one easy to use app.
Speaker 3:  Maximize your protection with Microsoft Defender. Available with a Microsoft
Speaker 3:  3, 6, 5 personal or family subscription.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back, All, right, made it home from Vegas for once.
Speaker 2:  I didn't get sick on the plane. It's very exciting. Let's get to the show.
Speaker 2:  The first thing we have today is a story about the life of vintage computers.
Speaker 2:  We talk a lot about right to repair and old gadgets and
Speaker 2:  how to extend the shelf life of the gadgets that we rely on, but
Speaker 2:  how do you think about that when instead of months and years, you're thinking
Speaker 2:  about decades. How much really can you do with
Speaker 2:  gadgets to keep them alive much, much longer than you might think?
Speaker 2:  That's the question that Verge producer will pour set out to answer. Can
Speaker 2:  a 30-year-old Macintosh live on for another 30 years with
Speaker 2:  the same parts? If not, what do you need to do to preserve it?
Speaker 2:  What does preserving it even mean and what do you lose along the way when
Speaker 2:  you do that? I'm gonna let will take over from here and then I'll be back
Speaker 2:  for the second half of the show. Here's Will.
Speaker 5:  The first computer my family ever owned is this Apple Mac Classic from
Speaker 5:  1991.
Speaker 5:  It's an updated riff on the original Macintosh from 1984.
Speaker 5:  A cute little all-in-One beige box with a nine inch black and white screen.
Speaker 5:  I spent a lot of time playing with this computer growing up.
Speaker 5:  I did my third grade homework on it. I drew for hours in Mac
Speaker 5:  Paint and I played glorious games like Rickles and Load
Speaker 5:  Runner and Dark Castle. I can still hear the drone of
Speaker 5:  the fan, the feel of the keys and the click,
Speaker 5:  click, click of the hard drive.
Speaker 5:  I asked my parents about the Classic recently and to my delight, they kept
Speaker 5:  it for posterity.
Speaker 5:  We pulled it out of their attic and miraculously, after 32 years,
Speaker 5:  it still works,
Speaker 5:  sort of. It doesn't always boot, and when it does, it makes a
Speaker 5:  scary pinging sound that makes me fear for the hard drive.
Speaker 5:  I wanted to revisit my homework and games and everything else, but
Speaker 5:  I was scared I'd break something and lose it all for good. So I
Speaker 5:  decided to see what it would take to restore an old computer like this one
Speaker 5:  to find out what fails in these machines and how to stop it from happening
Speaker 5:  so that this little time capsule could survive another 32 years.
Speaker 5:  That seems simple enough, but I should have recognized a rabbit hole
Speaker 5:  when I saw one. I went deep into the world of vintage computer
Speaker 5:  collectors. I learned to solder and I ended up
Speaker 5:  grappling with some big heady questions about the right or
Speaker 5:  wrong ways to preserve the past.
Speaker 5:  Mac Classic battery replacement.
Speaker 5:  The first thing I learned about vintage computer repair is machines of this
Speaker 5:  era are time bombs. Many have a little internal battery
Speaker 5:  that keeps track of the date and time and as the years roll by
Speaker 5:  those batteries love to leak all over the machine's. Innards. Everyone
Speaker 5:  I talked to told me to fish that little battery out like yesterday.
Speaker 5:  So armed with a bunch of YouTube tutorials, I plop the Mac down on a
Speaker 5:  workbench in my garage. Okay, tools,
Speaker 5:  this is amateur hour. Luckily the Classic is
Speaker 5:  constructed simply enough that I could work with what I had on hand. The
Speaker 5:  case is held together with just four standard torque screws.
Speaker 5:  Lefty Lucy.
Speaker 5:  There it goes. Okay. Once the screws were out, the whole case split
Speaker 5:  in half vertically though it took some encouraging. Ouch.
Speaker 5:  All, right? I am sliding
Speaker 5:  this whole back plastic plate away
Speaker 5:  from the computer. And
Speaker 5:  ah, inside the components are all jammed densely
Speaker 5:  together, which makes disassembly a little touchy. You can get a nasty
Speaker 5:  electrical shock off the monitor tube even when the computer is unplugged.
Speaker 5:  My flashlight with some effort, I managed to unplug all
Speaker 5:  the little cables connecting to the logic board. Oh, it's sticky and
Speaker 5:  slide it free. The logic board is the brains of the
Speaker 5:  computer. It's an unremarkable green rectangle full of circuitry,
Speaker 5:  and there sitting in one corner was the battery. It was easy to
Speaker 5:  spot and easier still to pop out of its little cradle and amazingly
Speaker 5:  it didn't look leaky at all. It's in good shape. Disaster
Speaker 5:  averted, but my work wasn't done. I also learned about the
Speaker 5:  handful of capacitors, soldered to the logic board. They're little
Speaker 5:  components that hold and release energy to different parts of the computer
Speaker 5:  and they can leak and ruin things too. This is where I get outta
Speaker 5:  my depth. I don't know what a capacitor looks like. Much less how to
Speaker 5:  replace one time to call in the experts.
Speaker 5:  I've been driving with this Matt Classic sitting on
Speaker 5:  a towel on the floor of the driver's side.
Speaker 5:  The expert I roped into. This is Jason Perkins. He's an
Speaker 5:  information security engineer who lives in a little town about an hour north
Speaker 5:  of Seattle. A few weeks ago I found myself pulling up to
Speaker 5:  his house with my Matt Classic riding shotgun old
Speaker 5:  Ford pickup truck parked next to a Tesla. There
Speaker 5:  is something fitting about that for this story.
Speaker 5:  Hey, how's going? Morning, how are ya? Good. Good to see ya. Good to see
Speaker 5:  you. I hope you don't mind. I'm recording my journey, trying to be a good
Speaker 5:  podcaster. It is an audio podcast, right? I met Jason while working on
Speaker 5:  another story about an Apple computer from the eighties called the Lisa.
Speaker 5:  He has an extensive collection of vintage tech and when I reached out to
Speaker 5:  him about my Mac, he immediately offered to help.
Speaker 7:  So this
Speaker 5:  Is the workshop plan,
Speaker 7:  Converting it into electronics shop. So
Speaker 5:  It's been, Jason moved recently, so his home workshop is a bit of a
Speaker 5:  mess. Picture a garagey space filled to the brimm with boxes,
Speaker 5:  monitors, wires and tools. But there's a method to the
Speaker 5:  madness in one corner. Huge vintage printers sit neatly on
Speaker 5:  metal shelves.
Speaker 8:  For now, that's printer land. You have to be careful when you put multiple
Speaker 8:  laser writers in one spot because the sheer weight can cause
Speaker 8:  a black hole.
Speaker 5:  I'll keep my distance. Yeah. Then there are the computers, an
Speaker 5:  assortment of diverse systems from the 1980s. There are a few more
Speaker 5:  recognizable machines. An Apple, Lisa, a Macintosh se that looks
Speaker 5:  a lot like my Classic, but also computers. I'd never heard of
Speaker 5:  an NCR PC four.
Speaker 8:  This was the first computer that I, that I ever personally had. Somebody
Speaker 8:  gave it to me
Speaker 5:  A funny little thing called a nabu.
Speaker 8:  The keyboard has like a 20 foot cable or something on it. So you'd hook this
Speaker 8:  up to your TV in the living room and you'll sit back on the couch.
Speaker 5:  A xerox daybreak.
Speaker 8:  It actually has an extra card in there with a
Speaker 8:  IBM 8 0 180 6 processor on it. So you can have a PC
Speaker 8:  emulation in a window with a hardware processor. So you can run PC
Speaker 8:  software and Xerox software on
Speaker 5:  Just a kaleidoscope of earth tone plastic boxes. You got,
Speaker 5:  you've got it up and running
Speaker 8:  It. This is up and running.
Speaker 5:  Then there's the telecom collection. A shelf of gleaming
Speaker 5:  gloriously analog phones and answering machines from the sixties.
Speaker 8:  In the sixties, it was actually a crime to
Speaker 8:  connect any equipment not provided by the phone company
Speaker 8:  to your telephone line. Oh, so this is an
Speaker 8:  answering machine which can pick up the phone, answer it,
Speaker 8:  play an announcement, record a message, and hang the phone up with no connection
Speaker 8:  to the phone line.
Speaker 5:  Jason is an irrepressible fountain of tech knowledge for
Speaker 5:  basically every device we looked at. He gave me the full backstory
Speaker 5:  on the product and company, the devices, components, construction,
Speaker 5:  hardware, and software quirk. He constantly interrupts himself and digs
Speaker 5:  up new pieces of tech to make a point.
Speaker 8:  And I remember actually, I happen to have one. So
Speaker 8:  there's no hard drive in this. And so plus development
Speaker 8:  developed this thing called the hard card, where it's an expansion
Speaker 8:  card with
Speaker 5:  A, it's worth noting that all of this machinery is functional.
Speaker 5:  The printer's print
Speaker 5:  the answering machines pick up and the computer's
Speaker 5:  word process. It took a lot of effort to fix this stuff
Speaker 5:  up. But for Jason, working devices are the whole point.
Speaker 8:  In oh three, the Smithsonian Institution was doing an
Speaker 8:  exhibit on history of technology, history of computing. I was so excited
Speaker 8:  to go see it and probably one of the most
Speaker 8:  disappointing things I've ever experienced in my life actually. 'cause
Speaker 8:  we got there and it's like, oh great, there's an original Macintosh
Speaker 8:  turned off behind a piece of plexiglass and oh look, there's a xerox
Speaker 8:  alto that isn't turned on. And the whole thing's behind flex and glass. It's
Speaker 8:  like you can only admire so many beige rectangles
Speaker 8:  before you're like, they just, it's kind of the same thing over and over
Speaker 8:  again. That's not what really makes it special. It's,
Speaker 8:  if you go to an art museum, You, don't sit and observe the frame.
Speaker 8:  You look at the art like you can, you can look at the art and experience
Speaker 8:  the art. If you have a record album, you don't just pick up the record album
Speaker 8:  and look at it. You listen to it. And with the technology,
Speaker 8:  it's the interaction that is, to me, the big, the big part of it.
Speaker 5:  That idea struck a chord with me. I'm here to
Speaker 5:  restore my Mac so that I can do stuff with it again. And remember all the
Speaker 5:  fun stuff I did 30 years ago. I'm not a collector, I'm
Speaker 5:  just nostalgic.
Speaker 5:  After the tour, we got down to business.
Speaker 8:  I'm generally pretty good at getting these apart by hand. You just
Speaker 8:  kind of tap on it a little bit.
Speaker 5:  Jason dug the logic board outta my Mac and took a closer look and
Speaker 5:  it turns out I'd missed some things.
Speaker 8:  So this, the capacitors on this have actually started to leak. Oh yeah. Okay.
Speaker 8:  Very slightly. So if you look at this, all these little silver
Speaker 8:  cans are the surface mount electrolytic capacitors. Okay.
Speaker 5:  Dotted across the surface of the board are these eight little cylindrical
Speaker 5:  objects smaller than an eraser head.
Speaker 8:  Do you notice on this chip, this VLSI chip, how there's this line going
Speaker 8:  diagonally across.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, it's like part of the chip is a little darker colored than the,
Speaker 8:  The gunk from this has wafted along and is halfway
Speaker 8:  across this chip. Oh no. Cabinets. And that's, you can see it in the dust.
Speaker 5:  Oh, I never would've noticed.
Speaker 8:  You also notice, see how this chip, all the little solders are nice
Speaker 8:  and kind of bright. Yes. And this one they look kind of fuzzy
Speaker 8:  and dark gray. Yep. The solders on this had been corroded by
Speaker 8:  the leaking capacitor stuff.
Speaker 5:  Luckily the damage to the board was minimal. It was just really
Speaker 5:  dirty. Jason walked me through the process of cleaning up the mess and installing
Speaker 5:  new capacitors. Step one, remove the old ones.
Speaker 8:  So we're gonna take a a sharp pair of
Speaker 8:  cutters. Okay. And we're just gonna cut this thing off.
Speaker 8:  And the danger here is it does go flying. Okay. So watch your eyes slightly,
Speaker 8:  but we'll just, you know, covering my
Speaker 5:  Eyes and, oops. Okay. We've just snipped,
Speaker 8:  Snipped it
Speaker 5:  Off. Step two, clean the logic board. I figured we'd
Speaker 5:  use some special solvent, but we just went to the kitchen and ran the whole
Speaker 5:  board under hot water. It turns out that water doesn't hurt circuit
Speaker 5:  boards at all. As long as they're not plugged in while they're wet.
Speaker 8:  Some regular dish soap. And I've got a toothbrush
Speaker 8:  and we're gonna scrubby, scrubby, scrubby.
Speaker 5:  Step three, blow dry the board to get all the moisture out.
Speaker 8:  So now I've just got a regular, just a little air compressor. I'm gonna blow
Speaker 8:  this off. So this'll be probably kind of loud
Speaker 5:  To the extra. Sure. The board was dry, we just left it in the sun and went
Speaker 5:  to lunch. After that we were finally ready to solder on the new
Speaker 5:  capacitors.
Speaker 8:  I'm gonna solder this guy right here. This thing. Oh, okay. So you
Speaker 8:  see we've got the two leads sticking out. Yep. I'm gonna clean the tip of
Speaker 8:  my iron first and the scrubby thing. That's nice and shiny. Now when I
Speaker 8:  put the solder on here, we'll see. Watch what happens. Do you see how it's
Speaker 8:  flowing all across the pad? It's not flowed onto the wire yet. There's
Speaker 8:  not enough solder. So as I continue to add now, do
Speaker 8:  you see how it's like flowed up the wire a little bit and
Speaker 5:  It makes that Yeah, it's being pulled up. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  That acid cleans the surface and it makes the solder
Speaker 8:  stick.
Speaker 5:  It's super fiddly work holding the new capacitor gently with
Speaker 5:  some forceps. I placed it as precisely as possible on
Speaker 5:  the little pad where the old one was.
Speaker 8:  Notice too, how each can, there's like a black
Speaker 8:  side. Yes. A little black stripe. That's the negative side. Okay.
Speaker 8:  Notice helpfully on the circuit board there's a plus Yes. On
Speaker 8:  each one of these. The orientation is very important. I see. If you install
Speaker 8:  them backwards, they explode. Gotcha.
Speaker 5:  Then I went in with the soldering iron and melted fresh solder around
Speaker 5:  the tiny little capacitor. Okay, so I'm gonna nudge this capacitor.
Speaker 5:  You're
Speaker 8:  Pretty
Speaker 5:  Close into as close a place as possible. Boop.
Speaker 8:  That looks good. You smell that fish fishy smell. I was
Speaker 5:  Gonna ask about that.
Speaker 8:  That is the capacitor oil. Okay. It smells like fishes.
Speaker 5:  Okay. I didn't trust myself. I was like, there's no way I smelled seafood
Speaker 5:  right
Speaker 8:  Now. You absolutely do that. That is the smell of
Speaker 8:  leaked capacitors. Leaked
Speaker 5:  Capacitors smell like fish. Yes. If I take nothing else away from this
Speaker 5:  entire project, I will have learned that it
Speaker 5:  was easy enough once I got the hang of it and a few minutes later we were
Speaker 5:  done. Eight new capacitors on a sparkly clean circuit board.
Speaker 5:  We slid the board back into the computer and put everything back together.
Speaker 8:  The next step is the smoke test. You plug it in and see if it smokes.
Speaker 8:  You think I'm joking?
Speaker 5:  Some of the capacitors we replaced help power the speaker. So we hope
Speaker 5:  we might get one of those iconic max startup chimes when we flip the switch
Speaker 5:  and moment of truth. A complete computer.
Speaker 8:  No bong.
Speaker 5:  No bong
Speaker 8:  Mwo but no smoke.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I'll take it. Mission largely
Speaker 5:  accomplished.
Speaker 8:  You'll notice this time it's gonna stay on this screen a little bit longer
Speaker 8:  'cause we have more memory. So this pattern is what it does while it's testing
Speaker 8:  the memory. Mm.
Speaker 5:  After all that work, I had a feeling of satisfaction that only
Speaker 5:  newbies get. I did a thing, it didn't break. I
Speaker 5:  felt like we did what I came to do. So this computer is immortal now. Right?
Speaker 5:  You can see where this is going.
Speaker 5:  So without messing with it anymore, now that we've fixed
Speaker 5:  the, the things that we know are problems, if you had to guess how
Speaker 5:  much longer this Classic would last for after
Speaker 5:  what is now what, 32 or so years,
Speaker 5:  what would you say?
Speaker 8:  The next thing to fail will be? The hard drive. I can show you
Speaker 8:  why and then we can describe it. I just happen to have
Speaker 8:  another quantum prodrive that I was monkeying with.
Speaker 8:  So this is gonna get a little bit into hard drive theory
Speaker 5:  Here. Jason gets very Jason again in a nutshell, some
Speaker 5:  rubber inside the drive will eventually turn to goo.
Speaker 5:  Also, the drive will slowly demagnetize degrading the data.
Speaker 5:  The point is, this hard drive could die at any moment
Speaker 5:  and when it does, it could take all my digital memories with it. So if
Speaker 5:  my goal is preservation, I've got more work to do.
Speaker 8:  Probably the best long-term method would be to they, they make hard drive
Speaker 8:  replacements now that use an SD card. Well you install the SSD card on this,
Speaker 8:  this special converter that to the computer looks like a scuzzy hard drive.
Speaker 8:  Okay. And so it's like within the SD card there's this enclave
Speaker 8:  that is pretending to be, you know, a scuzzy hard drive.
Speaker 5:  A hard drive from 1991. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. And the computer is essentially none the wiser.
Speaker 5:  That sounded intimidating technically, but there was something else.
Speaker 5:  Tripping me up.
Speaker 5:  If the whole point of this exercise is to recreate the experience
Speaker 5:  of using this computer in 1991, what
Speaker 5:  happens to that experience when you start making larger changes?
Speaker 5:  Part of what I remember about this computer is hearing the hard drive
Speaker 5:  spin up and were, if I replace it with a little SD card,
Speaker 5:  I'll have preserved most of that experience. But will I have
Speaker 5:  preserved the computer?
Speaker 5:  Jason unsurprisingly, has spent a lot of time with these questions.
Speaker 5:  When does preservation become enhancement? What counts as
Speaker 5:  authentic or original?
Speaker 8:  Well, I, I like having as much original
Speaker 8:  hardware as I can. Even if it's like, you know, maybe slightly newer
Speaker 8:  but still like an upgrade compared to what it was when it was new. I like
Speaker 8:  doing that. Some people like really into that. Like, oh, I'll get all these
Speaker 8:  new boards and like build the whole thing from scratch and it's, that's really
Speaker 8:  neat, you know? But it's not, I guess that's not what my personal thing is.
Speaker 8:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  What's different about that to you?
Speaker 8:  You know, one of my friends actually just built a new Lisa,
Speaker 8:  like new circuit boards 'cause people have come up with his
Speaker 8:  schematics and has made himself a a a Lisa from Ether. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  And it's really cool. Me personally, that's not the kind of project
Speaker 8:  that I would set out on.
Speaker 5:  Do you think for you it's the sort of like top down
Speaker 5:  taking something that exists and maintaining it and tweaking it
Speaker 5:  versus the bottom up?
Speaker 8:  I think it is, yeah. That I enjoy more of the top down of this
Speaker 8:  worked. At one point I should be able to make it work just like it did. Again,
Speaker 8:  let's say you take a car from the sixties and now you've like, you replace
Speaker 8:  all the suspension and the running gear and the engine and the transmission
Speaker 8:  with all brand new stuff. It's like, okay, it's really nice and some of this
Speaker 8:  stuff is just so expertly done. But do you, is it
Speaker 8:  really still the, is it the original car at that point? Like
Speaker 8:  if you've replaced everything that makes it function with something new,
Speaker 5:  There's that, what you're describing with it's the ship Ethe. It's ship
Speaker 5:  Ephesus. Right? Right.
Speaker 5:  The Ship SIUs is a paradox that philosophers have been arguing
Speaker 5:  about for 2000 years. Basically, there's this famous
Speaker 5:  ship once sailed by the Greek adventurer SIUs. His fans
Speaker 5:  pledged to preserve the ship forever by replacing any plank that
Speaker 5:  rots out, which is great. but it begs the question, when
Speaker 5:  all the planks eventually get replaced, is it the same ship
Speaker 5:  anymore? What exactly is being preserved? What makes the ship
Speaker 5:  the ship being a paradox? There's no clear
Speaker 5:  answer. And for my Mac Classic, the thought experiment only gets weirder.
Speaker 5:  Adding an SD card would be like fitting the ship of SS with an
Speaker 5:  outboard motor.
Speaker 5:  Adding modern components also starts to blur the line
Speaker 5:  between restoration and modding. And that's where things really
Speaker 5:  get wild.
Speaker 10:  Welcome To, the Mac Classic remodel build in which you'll witness the process
Speaker 10:  it took to convert an old Mac into a modernized pc.
Speaker 10:  This video has
Speaker 5:  Click around YouTube or Reddit and you'll find mods swapping vintage
Speaker 5:  and modern parts with abandon an
Speaker 11:  Obscenely upgraded Macintosh SE 30 in a clear case.
Speaker 5:  One listener reached out to show us their heavily moed first generation
Speaker 5:  Macintosh. It's got an iPad for a screen and
Speaker 5:  runs a vintage OSS alongside a doc and FaceTime
Speaker 5:  So
Speaker 12:  I built a custom system that brings the power of apple silicon to this
Speaker 12:  iconic design in a magical way.
Speaker 5:  And it is a long way from a Mac Classic with an SSD card in it.
Speaker 5:  Jason appreciates the more inventive creations as long as Moders
Speaker 5:  don't destroy working vintage hardware along the way.
Speaker 8:  I definitely don't have a problem with it. I think it's just a preference
Speaker 8:  of I've managed to accumulate enough crap over the years that Yeah,
Speaker 8:  or it's the challenge of finding the original one or getting the original
Speaker 8:  one going again. It's the fun of the search.
Speaker 5:  That said, he sees debates play out on forums all the time.
Speaker 8:  Oh you know, it's kind of the typical, geez, am I gonna date
Speaker 8:  myself if I use the term flame war? But
Speaker 5:  Yeah,
Speaker 8:  Yeah, yeah. Well people in technology tend to have strongly held opinions.
Speaker 5:  Ultimately, Jason's just glad that these computers are still out there for
Speaker 5:  people to play with and fix up and argue over. It shows in
Speaker 5:  the care he's put into his own collection and in the hours he was happy to
Speaker 5:  spend with me. It takes a lot to preserve the experience of
Speaker 5:  vintage computing and even then, this stuff is not gonna last
Speaker 5:  forever. But clearly Jason thinks it's worth the effort anyway,
Speaker 8:  All these things that we create reflect us as a society, as people,
Speaker 8:  and it's valuable. People put a lot of time and effort into
Speaker 8:  creating these things. You know it to conjure this thing
Speaker 8:  from nothing that does something now, like that's you, you had, you had to
Speaker 8:  picture that before it existed. That's, that's pretty cool. And
Speaker 8:  being able to continue to display or interact
Speaker 8:  with that creation gives it value. And if instead
Speaker 8:  it is locked away and forgotten about,
Speaker 8:  we lose that value. You know, it just like if you couldn't read
Speaker 8:  books that were 20 years old. I think it's a problem that historians in the
Speaker 8:  future are gonna be really ringing their hands about.
Speaker 5:  After chatting with Jason, a small irony occurred to me.
Speaker 5:  Those historians may have a much harder time preserving newer
Speaker 5:  computers. My old Mac Classic was a breeze to repair,
Speaker 5:  which enables a whole ecosystem of amateurs like me to learn
Speaker 5:  and tinker and keep these systems alive. Whereas my
Speaker 5:  2019 MacBook Pro is rocking a one out
Speaker 5:  of 10 on, I fix its repairability meter. It is a lot
Speaker 5:  more complex and miniaturized and openly hostile to
Speaker 5:  tinkering. I'd need to deal with glue and rivets
Speaker 5:  and a lot more solder to pull off any significant repair.
Speaker 5:  Also, I'd need something called a ger and I do not care to learn
Speaker 5:  what that is. The point is, whatever memories I have
Speaker 5:  that are tied to newer computers, those will probably die with the hardware
Speaker 5:  back at home. I fired up the Mac Classic,
Speaker 5:  it booted great. I used an external speaker for the sound and
Speaker 5:  I finally got to just sit down and explore.
Speaker 13:  There is a document that is just called The Cat,
Speaker 13:  and that is, it's just a drawing of a cat
Speaker 13:  with a title that says the cat gonna click
Speaker 13:  on octopus picture.
Speaker 13:  That was so patient as a 10-year-old. This computer is
Speaker 13:  so slow.
Speaker 5:  I found tons of drawings. It reminded me how much I used to love drawing
Speaker 5:  lots of homework too. There's this really sweet interview with my grandpa
Speaker 5:  that I did when I was 10 and the games
Speaker 13:  Load runner, my gosh, load runner is the best.
Speaker 13:  God. Somehow I remembered the controls
Speaker 13:  without having to think twice about it.
Speaker 13:  All, right? I just need to beat this level and then I'll finish this
Speaker 13:  podcast segment.
Speaker 5:  After spending all this time with the computer, I agree with Jason.
Speaker 5:  What makes this thing valuable is not the beige box or the
Speaker 5:  software or documents inside of it. It's everything working in concert
Speaker 5:  like it did 30 years ago. That's what makes it a time machine.
Speaker 5:  So I'm not gonna mess with it too much more. I'm gonna follow Jason's advice
Speaker 5:  and swap the hard drive out for an SD card that'll keep things running
Speaker 5:  for a little while. But that's it. I've replaced enough
Speaker 5:  planks on this ship for a few more voyages. After that,
Speaker 5:  the sea can reclaim it.
Speaker 13:  They're fun.
Speaker 13:  Shut down.
Speaker 2:  We gotta take a break and then we're gonna come back and we're gonna talk
Speaker 2:  about Twitter. We'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. This week, The Verge published a whole bunch of stories about
Speaker 2:  the fall of Twitter collected into a series we're calling The year.
Speaker 2:  Twitter died. You should go read all of them. They're really great
Speaker 2:  stories and the art to go along with them is like deranged
Speaker 2:  in the best possible way. It's one of the most fun things we've had on The
Speaker 2:  Verge all year. I really encourage you to go check it out. We'll link it
Speaker 2:  in the show notes. But today on the show I wanna talk more about what Twitter
Speaker 2:  was, which is a weird way to think about it. I know, but I think as
Speaker 2:  we get some hindsight from this weird website that we spent
Speaker 2:  so many hours staring at and talking about and that felt so central
Speaker 2:  to life and culture for so many people for so long. I think
Speaker 2:  we're getting a little closer to figuring it out. And as Twitter becomes
Speaker 2:  X, which becomes something else, I think now is a good time to talk about
Speaker 2:  what Twitter meant to us for so long. So Nila Patel and Alex
Speaker 2:  Cranz, my co-hosts are here to pour one out for the Twitter that used to
Speaker 2:  be Neli. Hello.
Speaker 17:  Hello.
Speaker 2:  Alex. Cranz not wearing glasses and squinting. I wish everyone could see
Speaker 2:  the face Alex is making right now.
Speaker 18:  Am I squinting really badly? Yes, it's blur. So
Speaker 2:  We're, we're here to talk about Twitter and I, I say Twitter very specifically
Speaker 2:  because Twitter ends at the day of a certain acquisition. We're not
Speaker 2:  gonna talk about that. We spent a lot of time over this last year talking
Speaker 2:  about like what Twitter was and what it meant. We had this big package and
Speaker 2:  Nila, you wrote a story, but I realized the first thing I wanna talk about
Speaker 2:  because I was thinking like, what is, when I think of Twitter, what's the
Speaker 2:  first thing that comes to mind? And I wanna know from both of you, what was
Speaker 2:  the closest you ever got to being the main character on Twitter? For good
Speaker 2:  reasons or bad reasons? Like what was the biggest moment you ever had on
Speaker 2:  Twitter? Neli? I wanna hear yours first.
Speaker 17:  All of mine are bad.
Speaker 18:  Okay.
Speaker 17:  Same. You know, I'm the editor of a thing, like anything goes wrong
Speaker 17:  and it's my fault. Which is fine. That's the job. That's what the money's
Speaker 17:  for. But when you're like, what is the closest you've come to being the
Speaker 17:  main character? It's like the Apple Watch review. Ooh,
Speaker 2:  Ooh. The original Apple Watch
Speaker 17:  People got really mad at me 'cause I said the, what was it? The Meese
Speaker 17:  loop. I was like, this shit's fussy for old people. And then everyone tweeted
Speaker 17:  pictures of my spiky bracelet and it's like, yeah dude, I'm that, I'm that
Speaker 17:  I'm that person, not your dad.
Speaker 17:  Go away, get in your Rolls Royce and drive away from my face.
Speaker 18:  Do you have a spiky bracelet? Apple Watch band?
Speaker 17:  I don't, no one's ever gotten me one. I would welcome one. Send me one without
Speaker 17:  any weird powders in the envelope and I'll happily wear it.
Speaker 18:  I'm just so excited to learn this. This just made my gift giving a lot easier.
Speaker 18:  Thank you
Speaker 17:  For, for the man who has everything.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 17:  There, I mean there's other ones like any minor scandal that we've
Speaker 17:  had. Like the thing that I will just take out of this without listing
Speaker 17:  every scandal, The Verge has ever had. You asked me that question and all
Speaker 17:  of my instincts were negative. Mm. There's a flip side
Speaker 17:  to this, right? When we were covering Apple versus Samsung,
Speaker 17:  we were in the center of that coverage of that trial. And I was writing
Speaker 17:  patent explainers with Matt McCarry, a patent lawyer that we'd put
Speaker 17:  on staff for the period of that trial. And we were the center of
Speaker 17:  that conver and that was a really positive experience that made our careers,
Speaker 17:  it made the early part of The Verge like a very real way. But when you ask
Speaker 17:  me a question, it's like, when were you the main character? My immediate
Speaker 17:  instinct is negative.
Speaker 2:  That's fair. Cranz, what about you? Do you have a happy story?
Speaker 18:  Hmm. No. Hmm. No. 'cause the, the the times I was a
Speaker 18:  main character, it was usually like the time I got in a fight with, oh no,
Speaker 18:  they didn't. And that was, that was fun.
Speaker 18:  Okay. In the time that like Tucker Carlson used one of my
Speaker 18:  tweets and put it in his thing being like the liberal journalist. Oh
Speaker 18:  that was, that was fun.
Speaker 2:  A true rite of passage on Twitter.
Speaker 17:  And Cranz was like, these Netflix prices are outta control. And Tucker Carlson
Speaker 17:  was like, these
Speaker 2:  Liberals, this is why millennials can't buy houses.
Speaker 18:  Don't tweet on vacation is what I learned. But there was one time I had
Speaker 18:  to make, like, when I left my last job, I made a big announcement on Twitter
Speaker 18:  and, and that was actually like really nice 'cause I got tons of people
Speaker 18:  I'd never even heard of. Like tons of like big folks in tech and everybody
Speaker 18:  just being like, you're awesome. And it was just like an enormous morale
Speaker 18:  boost and it was just instant. Like just that that dopamine hit was so fast.
Speaker 18:  I was like, oh, okay, Twitter is good. And then like, but that was like
Speaker 18:  2020 So I. I was like late to the party when it comes to having like really
Speaker 18:  good Twitter experiences like that.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Personal news Twitter I think was like consistently one of the best
Speaker 2:  things on Twitter. Yes. The like somebody gets a new job,
Speaker 2:  leaves a job, changes careers, whatever. And it was just like a random
Speaker 2:  outpouring of enthusiasm every single time. It was great. Yeah. I I
Speaker 2:  congratulated so many strangers on new jobs. Same. I loved it. You're
Speaker 17:  Gonna be great. Yeah. We launched the entire Verge in the back of Twitter
Speaker 17:  in like a real way. We had the End Gadget podcast and then we all quit a
Speaker 17:  OL in a moment for blogging that will probably never be recreated. Like
Speaker 17:  national news, bunch of gadget blockers leave a OL Yeah.
Speaker 17:  This was in the New York Times. Yeah. We took our audience with us
Speaker 17:  because we had the big podcast audience. It's now this show
Speaker 17:  and we communicated to all of them about what we were doing and where we
Speaker 17:  were going on Twitter and that, you know, that's a core
Speaker 17:  memory. That's a thing that we did that was not su no one could do
Speaker 17:  before these tools existed in that way. And so yeah, I I have
Speaker 17:  these happy memories like outpourings of affection.
Speaker 17:  But when you say main character, my mind leaps to the goal is to
Speaker 17:  not be the main character.
Speaker 2:  Yes.
Speaker 18:  Yeah. You never like main character in a romance novel. Cool.
Speaker 18:  Main character on Twitter Bad.
Speaker 2:  That's fair. The closest I ever got was in I think 2021.
Speaker 2:  Nicki Minaj tweeted angrily at me thinking she was tweeting angrily at Pi
Speaker 2:  Morgan.
Speaker 17:  That's pretty good.
Speaker 2:  I got don don't know 10,000 replies that day from
Speaker 2:  people who were mad at me. And then there was,
Speaker 2:  there was somebody who tweeted at Nikki that was like, leave this poor nerd
Speaker 2:  child alone. He didn't do this. And then Nikki apologized to
Speaker 2:  me again on Twitter and So I got a bunch more replies and, and it was just
Speaker 2:  like I became, I became one of the Barbs, which is Nikki's fans. And so it
Speaker 2:  was, it was, it was a lovely moment. They were very mad at me for like an
Speaker 2:  hour and then they were very nice to me after that. I still get dms from
Speaker 2:  people who are like, who are like, what did you do to Nicki? And I'm like,
Speaker 2:  I didn't do anything. I'm really sorry.
Speaker 17:  Being mistaken for Pierce Morgan. That's bad dude. It's
Speaker 18:  Like, that's just bad.
Speaker 2:  It's the worst. The single worst thing about Twitter has been like, I got
Speaker 2:  a very good Twitter handle. I was at Pierce on Twitter. So when you
Speaker 2:  type at PIER because you wanna be mad at Pierce Morgan,
Speaker 2:  there was a non-zero chance that my name would be the first thing that came
Speaker 2:  up. So like every few days somebody would get extremely
Speaker 2:  mad at Pi Morgan in my mentions. And I
Speaker 2:  do not miss that at all.
Speaker 17:  That's really funny.
Speaker 2:  The thing that I've been trying to reckon with over the course of the last
Speaker 2:  year or so, and like, I basically stopped tweeting when I went on
Speaker 2:  parental leave. So this is like almost exactly a year ago. I was
Speaker 2:  just like, gonna stop with social media for a while, gonna not post on
Speaker 2:  the internet, gonna go like be a dad on parental leave for a few months.
Speaker 2:  And I was like, I'll come back. It'll all be the same. Everything will be
Speaker 2:  fine. And I haven't tweeted since and I haven't missed it at all. And so
Speaker 2:  I've spent this year like trying to figure out why Twitter
Speaker 2:  was so central in my life and then what changed and why it went away. But
Speaker 2:  Neli, you wrote this piece this week reckoning with that at like the big
Speaker 2:  level, which is like we as reporters I think were the people like
Speaker 2:  most obsessed with Twitter as a single group of people.
Speaker 2:  And you asked around to talk to a hundred people. Do you have like a unified
Speaker 2:  theory of what Twitter did to us as journalists?
Speaker 17:  It gave us a direct connection to an audience in a way that no other platform
Speaker 17:  has ever done. Even the ones now that seem like they have a more direct
Speaker 17:  connection, like TikTok or whatever, there's still artifice there. Twitter
Speaker 17:  was you type, you hit the button, maybe some people will yell at you and
Speaker 17:  come back to you. You could work out an idea in public. A lot of reporters
Speaker 17:  built their brands by just firing half cocked ideas out
Speaker 17:  into the world and then working them out and then publishing
Speaker 17:  the, the fully cocked idea, which maybe nobody even ever read, but the process
Speaker 17:  of the journalism, like built a brand for people or the ability to
Speaker 17:  immediately synthesize and react built the brand for people. And
Speaker 17:  the more I think about what that did to our ability to think,
Speaker 17:  the more I think that we should stop it.
Speaker 17:  Like, and may, maybe that is me just being old and Crochety. But you know,
Speaker 17:  I talked to Ezra Klein who obviously founded Vox and is not the New York
Speaker 17:  Times. I talked to Ben Smith who founded Buzzfeed News and
Speaker 17:  now runs Semaphore. Previously the New York Times. I talked to Corey Zika
Speaker 17:  New York magazine previously the New York Times. I talked to Lydia Paul Green,
Speaker 17:  who was the editor-in-chief of Hogan Post now at the New York Times. I maybe
Speaker 17:  you can see a trend here.
Speaker 2:  It's also very funny by the way that all of those people are like big deal
Speaker 2:  media executives now. And I, all of them were like
Speaker 2:  OG Twitter stars. Exactly. Yeah. Like if you rewind 10 years ago, they were
Speaker 2:  like Twitter loving bloggers who became,
Speaker 17:  They were in it massive things. Yeah, yeah. They, they were in it and they
Speaker 17:  all started and blogging and they, you know, all of them owned an audience
Speaker 17:  on blogs and then they moved to Twitter, which is an interesting shift.
Speaker 17:  And then they, from there they were able to do all the amazing things they've
Speaker 17:  done since then. And all of them I think agree that
Speaker 17:  giving all of our best work to Twitter for free was
Speaker 17:  a mistake because all of the media institutions collapsed in the wake of
Speaker 17:  that decision. Let's give everything away for free and then we'll see what
Speaker 17:  happens. Maybe the platforms are thinking that we're important enough to
Speaker 17:  pay for the news. I don't know why anybody thought that this was true, because
Speaker 17:  the platforms are very happy to just move on to the next 20 something who
Speaker 17:  will burn out and that is the cycle they're on. But I think what
Speaker 17:  the other thing that happened there that Ezra talked about really specifically
Speaker 17:  is that we started making the content for Twitter and
Speaker 17:  he said this thing to me that I keep thinking about, which is you can feel
Speaker 17:  how it made you smaller, we increased the scale of our
Speaker 17:  communication, but we decrease the quality of it by fitting everything into
Speaker 17:  the same box. Hmm. And so that's just, to me,
Speaker 17:  I fe I felt that, but by the end of the Twitter moment, I
Speaker 17:  was communicating in tweets and we, that's like,
Speaker 17:  I have more to to say than 240 characters, you know, 280
Speaker 17:  characters. So that, that to me is like the, the core thing that I think
Speaker 17:  people are reacting to now, that if you get away from Twitter for just
Speaker 17:  a minute, David, you quit and you didn't look back. I know so many people
Speaker 17:  have quit over the last year and it's like, for a day or two
Speaker 17:  you're like, I had something happened to me, I must complain. And then
Speaker 17:  you stop doing that and your brain just like
Speaker 17:  bounces back so quickly and you're like, oh, I'm having
Speaker 17:  fuller richer thoughts. And that's pleasing to me
Speaker 17:  in that I know so many people who've had that exact experience
Speaker 17:  to be like, oh, it's more rewarding to think longer thoughts
Speaker 17:  and not seek the dopamine hit of instant feedback all the time.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I've actually discovered recently that I, I now have the opposite problem,
Speaker 2:  which is like, as somebody for whom it is like debatably, but potentially
Speaker 2:  professionally useful to like be present online and be a person who posts
Speaker 2:  a lot, the number of things that now don't get through my filter of I should
Speaker 2:  post this on the internet is like way too high. And, and I need to like,
Speaker 2:  I need to get back to saying dumb shit on the internet because that's like
Speaker 2:  what we all do all day. And it's way I now have
Speaker 2:  just like complaints that stay in my head and then they just go away. And
Speaker 2:  like, that's not, that's not what the internet is for. Like I'm doing this
Speaker 2:  wrong. Yeah.
Speaker 18:  I think, I think it's okay to, to sometimes sit on your, your complaints
Speaker 18:  and things, right? Like that's, that's why Twitter sucked a lot of the times.
Speaker 18:  I like, I didn't use it as much as you guys did. I I came to it kind of
Speaker 18:  late, like I think I heard about it in 2007 from the PVP web comic.
Speaker 18:  And then was like, what? That's stupid. I'm not gonna use that. That's
Speaker 2:  Pretty early by the way. I think you're you're still good on that front.
Speaker 2:  Yeah,
Speaker 18:  I'm still, but I didn't join until like 2009 and I was like, everybody's
Speaker 18:  joining and then I didn't, I didn't hit like, I didn't post really
Speaker 18:  until I started working I think at Gawker because that was a place that
Speaker 18:  was very digital media and was very like everybody was online. Right. And,
Speaker 18:  and So I just had a very, I think, I feel like I had a different relationship
Speaker 18:  with it than, than you guys to some extent because I, I did, the few times
Speaker 18:  I did complain, like Tucker Carlson was like, okay, cool, let me just put
Speaker 18:  that out for everybody else to see too. And I'm like, I don't, I don't need
Speaker 18:  that.
Speaker 2:  Do you think you had a healthier relationship with it? Like, do you look
Speaker 2:  back and think like, oh, I I spent an appropriate amount of time using and
Speaker 2:  thinking about Twitter?
Speaker 17:  Mm,
Speaker 18:  For the first half, yes. Okay. For the second half, no. Like, as your
Speaker 18:  followers would go up, you, you just, like, you start doing it more 'cause
Speaker 18:  you want more followers, you wanna see more, you want the engagement and
Speaker 18:  like you get into that cycle and once you're in that cycle, you can't escape
Speaker 18:  it. And you do like, start to be do dumber and dumber things and
Speaker 18:  then Tucker Carlson is, is retweeting you or putting you up on the, on his
Speaker 18:  show. So yeah, like I, I definitely felt like ISI watched it all
Speaker 18:  happen, but I think the thing that really sticks out to me was to your point,
Speaker 18:  NELI, how it changed relationships between creators and, and their
Speaker 18:  audiences. And it wasn't, it was like journalism was a big one, but the
Speaker 18:  one that I always go back to was, and like you guys are both gonna roll
Speaker 18:  your eyes, was Glee. Do you get, you remember Glee the horrible TV show?
Speaker 2:  Don Don't remember the horrible TV show Glee? I remember the wonderful TV
Speaker 2:  show Glee. Oh,
Speaker 18:  Oh, we're in different places, David. We're in different places. But, but
Speaker 18:  when Glee came out, it was a very online show. It was like that and Shonda
Speaker 18:  Rhimes doing stuff with Scandal. Those, those two shows were really all
Speaker 18:  about using Twitter and everything. But with Glee, the audience was a lot
Speaker 18:  younger and that audience learned that they could like, because they had
Speaker 18:  the direct relationship with the, the creators and the, the the
Speaker 18:  actors and everything. They had that direct relationship and then they
Speaker 18:  started to demand things and they started to make demands. And then sometimes
Speaker 18:  the show would like be like, okay, you guys want these two characters to
Speaker 18:  make out, we're gonna do it. Yeah. And then it was like, oh no, that's actually
Speaker 18:  terrible. Like actually you shouldn't have that relationship between creators
Speaker 18:  and, and the people and taking it in because like,
Speaker 18:  can you imagine like, it, it was just bad just led to bad tv. And then a
Speaker 18:  lot of TV shows and a lot of movies and stuff started chasing that started
Speaker 18:  chasing like, well, what will the fans think? And it was like, actually
Speaker 18:  there's only four fans and they're very vocal and they have a bunch of sock
Speaker 18:  puppet accounts. Maybe don't chase that.
Speaker 17:  It's just Zack Snyder being like, make it darker.
Speaker 17:  Just can you grit this up? I'm looking for Glee, but there's a
Speaker 17:  murder. Come on.
Speaker 18:  That was every episode
Speaker 17:  Glee on these streets, the Zach Snyder story,
Speaker 2:  To be fair, I would watch that. I was
Speaker 18:  Like, I would a hundred percent watch that. That's,
Speaker 2:  That's like, that's an objectively better idea than any other Zack Snyder.
Speaker 2:  Cut. So Zach, if you're listening and I know that you are,
Speaker 17:  By the way, Alex is right by the way, Zach, if you're listening Glee on
Speaker 17:  these streets, you can have it.
Speaker 18:  I want that.
Speaker 17:  But to Alex's point, this actually did happen a lot. Like this joke
Speaker 17:  about Zach Snyder there, he did run a coordinated harassment campaign
Speaker 17:  against a bunch of Warner Media executives on Twitter. Yeah. Yep. It's a
Speaker 17:  real thing. And no one could parse the difference between the
Speaker 17:  real fans who are spending money and just the volume
Speaker 17:  of noise that existed in the world. And really, the thing I have
Speaker 17:  come to think about Twitter the most is everyone is so desperate
Speaker 17:  for feedback. They're so desperate to complete the
Speaker 17:  loop between cause and effect in their lives. And Twitter just
Speaker 17:  slotted neatly into that hole in everyone's brain. Oh,
Speaker 17:  I can just get some feedback here. Oh, I can just see what's going on. Oh,
Speaker 17:  I can just, I can put my finger on whatever the pulse of this group of people
Speaker 17:  is. And that felt enough like feedback, even if it was
Speaker 17:  wrong, even if it was lies, even if it was coordinated bot activity from
Speaker 17:  Glee fans
Speaker 18:  Led to bad things.
Speaker 17:  Is the world shaped more or less by coordinated bot activity by Glee
Speaker 17:  fans? It's more than you think. Yeah. But it's, and it's because everyone
Speaker 17:  just wants the feedback and Twitter was there to provide it.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And I feel like we also never figured out how
Speaker 2:  to put it in context, which I think is still true of a lot of social stuff
Speaker 2:  right now. Right. Like, I remember so many perceived
Speaker 2:  scandals or bad things that happened were just like four people being mad
Speaker 2:  on Twitter. And we got to the point, like there was a whole genre of story
Speaker 2:  on the internet that was like, the internet is mad about X, Y, and Z and
Speaker 2:  it just would embed four tweets as like evidence of the internet being mad
Speaker 2:  about something. And that's so not reflective
Speaker 2:  of anything except like I could find four people who believe anything,
Speaker 2:  literally anything at any time.
Speaker 17:  Especially an ex. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  Exactly. And So I, I think part of what has been
Speaker 2:  so strange is that like I, we have not solved that problem in any way. Right?
Speaker 2:  And I think so much of Twitter was that everything felt big
Speaker 2:  and fast and vibrant and chaotic. And it was like, I think there were
Speaker 2:  people who used Twitter in a like group chatty kind of way where you
Speaker 2:  just like find your handful of people and you have sort of a public messaging
Speaker 2:  service to each other on there. And that's a totally valid use of Twitter
Speaker 2:  that I think is not being replaced really anywhere. And I think
Speaker 2:  that's really interesting. But this thing that it was just like, it, it just
Speaker 2:  felt lively and whatever you cared about it felt like other people cared
Speaker 2:  about it too. And you could tell any story you wanted with it. And we just
Speaker 2:  like never figured out how to put any of that in context. Like, I think it
Speaker 2:  was, I think it was Charlie Wartell who's now at the Atlantic at one point,
Speaker 2:  who said to me like, anytime I read the internet, on the internet, I
Speaker 2:  read 12 people on Twitter. And it changes the context of how you think about
Speaker 2:  everything. And I still think about that all the time. That's
Speaker 17:  How I think about TikTok too. It's like, people say people on TikTok and
Speaker 17:  it's like, not really, it's like four
Speaker 2:  People. It's a, a video
Speaker 17:  And you can't even find, at least on Twitter, you could go find the four
Speaker 17:  people on, on TikTok. Yeah. It's, it's, it's totally segmented away.
Speaker 17:  The thing that I, I I just want to bring some balance back to this.
Speaker 17:  It's very easy now to look back on Twitter. It's this very negative force,
Speaker 17:  especially 'cause of what it has become and all of us have gotten away from
Speaker 17:  it. But I, I think on the show I've compared Twitter to smoking like
Speaker 17:  a million times. Yes. I can't smoke a cigarette anymore. Like
Speaker 17:  I'm an old man and I haven't smoked in a long time. And every now and again
Speaker 17:  I see someone doing it and I take a drag and the next day I'm like, why
Speaker 17:  my, I'm still coughing. When I smoked, it ruled like
Speaker 17:  it was the best. And I like organized my days
Speaker 17:  around this activity and then I quit and it was really hard to quit.
Speaker 17:  But there's no part of me that looks back on that and is like, huh, you
Speaker 17:  know, like all of my whole life would've been better or different. It's
Speaker 17:  like, that is the thing that happened. For better or worse, lots of people
Speaker 17:  enjoyed smoking and now maybe we're gonna quit.
Speaker 17:  but it made everyone's life exciting. I can't tell if I'm talking about
Speaker 17:  cigarettes or Twitter right now. Twitter made everyone's life exciting.
Speaker 17:  Like most people's lives are not inherently exciting.
Speaker 17:  I'll, I'll give you this one example. I think about this all the time. I
Speaker 17:  love watching like cooking tiktoks. There's all this movement in foods like
Speaker 17:  make everything from scratch or like do things the hard way or be natural.
Speaker 17:  And you're like, if you weren't doing this on camera to an audience,
Speaker 17:  this would be so boring if you had to wake up and make bread
Speaker 17:  every day to feed your family. It's no wonder the industrial
Speaker 17:  revolution happened,
Speaker 17:  right? Like, this is actually not a rewarding task unless you have an audience
Speaker 17:  or it's a special occasion if this, if your life is just like this mundane
Speaker 17:  every single day, like of course you're gonna go look
Speaker 17:  for some outside validation. And what phones generally have brought people
Speaker 17:  is like an enormous way to go gain the outside
Speaker 17:  validation. And so if Twitter did that for people, I think you can look
Speaker 17:  at all the negatives that came along with it. But I think you can also look
Speaker 17:  at the idea that a random kid in the middle
Speaker 17:  of the country or around the world could go find not only
Speaker 17:  external validation for whoever they wish to become, but also
Speaker 17:  a sense of excitement that they too could like reach the audience. And that
Speaker 17:  changed the nature of how we think about a lot of things, positive and negative.
Speaker 17:  Totally. There's something to mind there. There's something to take out
Speaker 17:  of there that says, oh, we can actually make our lives like
Speaker 17:  meaningfully different and better if we are just careful to not
Speaker 17:  bring the baggage of the noise along with us. I don't know that we're gonna
Speaker 17:  be careful. I think we're probably just gonna start smoking again.
Speaker 2:  Well, and I do think all that stuff is totally inseparable, right? Which
Speaker 2:  is like why Twitter is fascinating because I think what it did was basically
Speaker 2:  like lean into this sort of feeling of
Speaker 2:  liveliness and like there's always something going on to like the
Speaker 2:  100th degree and it made everything feel chaotic and
Speaker 2:  problematic and everything moved too quickly. but it also had that like,
Speaker 2:  it it vibed in a way that nothing else like it has. And we're seeing this
Speaker 2:  on threads now too, where they've like very deliberately turned that dial
Speaker 2:  down from a 10 to like a four and it feels way less
Speaker 2:  fun. Yeah. It's like you can still find some of that. There's still community,
Speaker 2:  there's still interesting people, all that stuff. But this sense of like,
Speaker 2:  something is happening, I have to go on Twitter or
Speaker 2:  just this feeling like my pocket is buzzing because something is always
Speaker 2:  happening underneath that Twitter icon. Like, wait,
Speaker 17:  Did you have notifications turned on Twitter until the very end? No.
Speaker 2:  Dear God, no. Oh
Speaker 17:  My God. I turned off notifications on Twitter like the second year. I was
Speaker 17:  like, I no, thank you. All the
Speaker 2:  People who had notifications on from Donald Trump when
Speaker 2:  he was president during that presidency is like oof. I have, yeah. Anyone
Speaker 2:  who had Twitter notifications on after about 2014 was like a glutton for
Speaker 2:  punishment. Yeah. But there was, I just mean like that that feeling of like,
Speaker 2:  if I hit the Twitter icon on my phone, something is going to be happening.
Speaker 2:  Like is that a problematic drug In a very
Speaker 2:  real way, yes. but it was also the thing that made it so fun and
Speaker 2:  made it so lively and meant that everyone was there. So there were all these
Speaker 2:  opportunities and like you, we talk a lot about how badly run Twitter was
Speaker 2:  for all of its existence. And I think that there's an interesting
Speaker 2:  sort of parallel universe in which it's much better run. And I actually don't
Speaker 2:  think the outcome ends up being all that different. 'cause I just, it just
Speaker 2:  seems to me you can't have one side of that without the other. Yeah.
Speaker 18:  I did actually, the early part of Twitter, I was really into
Speaker 18:  different communities. Like I was really into to film Twitter and, and,
Speaker 18:  and all of those folks. And yet there was this ability to find a group and
Speaker 18:  find, find your people, so to speak. But that wasn't just inherent
Speaker 18:  to Twitter. That's, that's like, look, those communities form everywhere.
Speaker 18:  And in fact the Twitter ones were probably the most disparate because it
Speaker 18:  did move so fast because it was like just, you'd get tons of noise
Speaker 18:  in there, you'd be like, oh, I really like this movie too. And then somebody
Speaker 18:  just blast in and say like, a horrible cuss, right?
Speaker 18:  Like chanting, you're like, oh, get out. And, and I thought, I thought Sarah
Speaker 18:  Jung's piece in the Twitter package was, was really good about, was talking
Speaker 18:  about this and, and specifically that moderation because like, you know,
Speaker 18:  if you do that on a forum or live journal or Tumblr or, or Reddit, even
Speaker 18:  somebody's gonna come in and be like, no, you can't do that. You're, you're
Speaker 18:  out and kick you out. And and Twitter was always like, no, everybody's voice
Speaker 18:  matters. And it's like, we learned that actually some people are
Speaker 18:  just jerks and their voice. Like, we don't actually need to hear
Speaker 18:  a bunch of cusses in a row after like an interesting conversation. Speak
Speaker 17:  For yourself.
Speaker 2:  Well, and I think the, the other part of that Alex is like if you went on
Speaker 2:  letterbox and just like started cussing at people, like they would either
Speaker 2:  kick you out of letterbox or just be like, we don't talk about that here.
Speaker 2:  Right? And like Reddit would do that too. They have moderators, they do that
Speaker 2:  stuff, but Twitter was just like, it was everything everywhere all the time.
Speaker 2:  So it's like, as long as you're not breaking the rules, you can talk about
Speaker 2:  whatever you want. So like, you might follow me for tech stuff, but you're
Speaker 2:  also gonna get me yelling at Delta when my flight is delayed. And then you're
Speaker 2:  gonna get mad that your flight is delayed. And now we've gone down a whole
Speaker 2:  crazy rabbit hole way away from what we are like ostensibly here to talk
Speaker 2:  about or why you followed me in the first place. And it just, it's like that
Speaker 2:  pull is so intense that I feel like even like Film Twitter eventually
Speaker 2:  became politics Twitter because it was just the thing it felt like everybody
Speaker 2:  was talking about. And it's so you have to be like personally disciplined
Speaker 2:  to not do that. And I think if Twitter taught us anything, it's that we're
Speaker 2:  not personally disciplined enough to not do that.
Speaker 18:  I'm trying, I tried for a very long time.
Speaker 17:  There's something in there too that is very important that there was total
Speaker 17:  collapse in form on Twitter. So if you watch a TikTok and you don't like
Speaker 17:  the TikTok, it is perhaps likely that you'll make a duet or a stitch
Speaker 17:  or something. It's much more likely that you're just gonna leave a text
Speaker 17:  comment. And that means you have sort of down ranked yourself in the
Speaker 17:  experience, right? The video is the, the primary element, and then your
Speaker 17:  comment is next to it. And maybe people will never see it. And even if you
Speaker 17:  make a duet video, you're, no one's gonna see it unless they find your video.
Speaker 17:  Right? It's not in line on Twitter, it's all the same, right? Someone
Speaker 17:  tweets and someone replies and it's all the hierarchy. That information
Speaker 17:  is the same, which meant drive by cuss
Speaker 17:  words were elevated to the same level as the main thing
Speaker 17:  all the time and could quickly become the point, right? Like
Speaker 17:  a bad tweet with 10,000 people below it saying ratio.
Speaker 17:  The point of that was the word ratio. Yep. That's like fascinating.
Speaker 17:  Like that's probably media studies, PhD. Like that's the only platform I
Speaker 17:  can think of that truly works like that. Even text posts on Facebook
Speaker 17:  don't truly work like that. Twitter, the absolute collapse, I think just
Speaker 17:  led to radically different dynamics.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. One a again, like the, the threads example there is really interesting
Speaker 2:  is like Adam Messer even talked about that in the very early days of threads
Speaker 2:  that like the thing that worked about Twitter was that sort of evening of
Speaker 2:  all the content where it's not like a thing and then comments on the thing.
Speaker 2:  Everything is the same, but Threads has not actually panned out that way.
Speaker 2:  And you can see it like, everybody kind of knows that if you reply to your
Speaker 2:  own post on threads, your, your second post gets down ranked in
Speaker 2:  the algorithm. And just because everything is algorithmic, like you, you
Speaker 2:  just end up playing a different game. Whereas Twitter, even that it was
Speaker 2:  algorithmic was so much less carefully curated for your interest
Speaker 2:  that there was just this sense of like, you could just tweet the word ratio
Speaker 2:  and there was a really good chance it was gonna show up in somebody's
Speaker 17:  Timeline
Speaker 2:  And like, yeah. And again, I feel like, and you talk about this in your piece
Speaker 2:  Neli, that like the upside of that was it, it brought in new voices who never
Speaker 2:  would've had a chance otherwise. It gave everybody what amounts to like one-to-one
Speaker 2:  access to everybody else, which is terrifying and like
Speaker 2:  exhilarating all at the same time. but it just, it did, it, it it sort of
Speaker 2:  broke every barrier, like up and down and left and right of
Speaker 2:  how we talk to each other. And it, it feels like, I almost wish we had gotten
Speaker 2:  like 50 more years of Twitter and we could see if we ever got good at it.
Speaker 2:  And I'm not sure we would have, but it would've been an interesting thing
Speaker 2:  to play out. And it's like, would Gen Z have figured it out
Speaker 2:  and have like healthier relationships on Twitter? You don't think so?
Speaker 17:  No. I think in one very important way, gen Z is much worse
Speaker 17:  at technology than anyone caress to admit. Like this is a generation that
Speaker 17:  does not know about file systems. We've written that story. We just link
Speaker 17:  that story in the show notes, right? Like they are worse at the
Speaker 17:  technical aspects of computing Yeah. In
Speaker 17:  some meaningfully measurable ways. And then they are much
Speaker 17:  better at media literacy in other meaningful, measurable ways.
Speaker 17:  Like an entire generation of millennials were
Speaker 17:  like experienced the I did bad tweets problem and like
Speaker 17:  just loudly stuck their finger in the outlet for all the world to see over
Speaker 17:  and over again. Yeah. And all of, all of Gen Z just watched that
Speaker 17:  happen.
Speaker 19:  I would just like to interrupt quickly to let our Gen Z audience know that
Speaker 19:  Eli's email address is neli at the
Speaker 17:  This is no, I'm, this is a, this is a, you can email me and that's fine.
Speaker 17:  I'm Gen X So I am outside of this. I, I, I cast no
Speaker 17:  aspersions on anyone. I think all of you should get off my lawn. Get back
Speaker 17:  to work.
Speaker 19:  We don't remember your generation. It's fine.
Speaker 17:  I raised myself Alex, but I think that the media literacy of,
Speaker 17:  oh, I need to curate this persona for the world. My social media
Speaker 17:  presence is something that I need to be in control of that that was the
Speaker 17:  water, right? Like that, that's very native. That's not a new idea. And
Speaker 17:  So I, I, I don't know if Gen Z would've figured it out as much as they would've
Speaker 17:  stopped using the tool in a way that made it as vibrant as this is. So
Speaker 2:  To that point, actually, one of the things I'm curious what you guys think
Speaker 2:  is if we are ever going to get something like this again, 'cause I think
Speaker 2:  on the one hand nobody would've predicted Twitter to turn out the
Speaker 2:  way that it did. Right? It, it grew in weird, unusual, surprising ways.
Speaker 2:  And I think it did a lot of things really well. And it was like culturally
Speaker 2:  vibrant in ways that very few tech products have ever been culturally
Speaker 2:  vibrant to the point where Tucker Carlson is reading Alex's tweets on
Speaker 2:  television, which like, if you just think about it, is objectively insane.
Speaker 2:  Like nothing about that makes any sense. Not just you Cranz, but like Yeah,
Speaker 18:  Yeah. No, no, no, I agree. I was like,
Speaker 2:  We talk about a decade of cable news is just like news anchors reading tweets
Speaker 2:  to each other. Yes. And like it was, it really, really
Speaker 17:  Was. It was just the worst podcast of all time
Speaker 17:  for four years. CNN was just very expensive. Haircuts,
Speaker 17:  reading tweets.
Speaker 2:  But I also think like, to your point, NELI, the people coming up
Speaker 2:  are likely not going to go down the same road of like how
Speaker 2:  they exist online as we did in, you know,
Speaker 2:  2007. So like Threads kind of wants to tweet Twitter, but it kind of doesn't
Speaker 2:  wanna be Twitter X kind of wants to be Twitter but doesn't wanna be Twitter.
Speaker 2:  Like, are we ever gonna get another thing that feels the
Speaker 2:  way that Twitter did in 2015?
Speaker 18:  I totally don't think so. Okay. And, and my, my rationale for this is
Speaker 18:  that essentially the internet happened and, and everybody could suddenly
Speaker 18:  communicate and then Twitter and, and Facebook and all these things were
Speaker 18:  like, okay, what if everybody could communicate? What if Tucker Carlson,
Speaker 18:  Alex Cranz, David Pierce and Nicki Minaj were all in Pierce Morgan over
Speaker 18:  in the corner, we're all in the same coffee shop. Wouldn't that be great?
Speaker 17:  I would go to that coffee shop so quickly just to see
Speaker 17:  Nick mistake David for Pierce and then turn on in person
Speaker 17:  Pierce mortgage. Like Yeah.
Speaker 18:  And it sounds really compelling, right? It sounds like a cool ass coffee
Speaker 18:  shop, but we're all talking at the same volume and also there's a hundred
Speaker 18:  thousand other people all talking at the same volume in the same coffee
Speaker 18:  shop. And we realized, wait a minute, that's actually too much. Actually
Speaker 18:  we do. And and we've seen that, right? We've seen like the decentralization
Speaker 18:  of social media and it's happening a lot faster. And so those, those
Speaker 18:  communities are cropping up in smaller places where they can close themselves
Speaker 18:  off, where they can say, actually we don't want the person who just jumps
Speaker 18:  in and says Cusses or Pi Morgan just accidentally like Nicki
Speaker 18:  Minaj tweeting at David instead of Pierce Morgan. That's actually bad. We
Speaker 18:  don't want that. And So I think like, it was a moment where we had the internet
Speaker 18:  and we had this really great moment in the internet where we said, what
Speaker 18:  if everybody could talk at the same time? And then we went, wait, no, that's
Speaker 18:  bad. And I think collectively and just both like
Speaker 18:  collectively us and in kind of what our package was about and what we've
Speaker 18:  been talking about here, and also everybody out in the world who didn't
Speaker 18:  use Twitter because it wasn't actually one of the most popular social media
Speaker 18:  apps all realized together, no, this isn't actually something we want. Like
Speaker 18:  I think the hu the market spoke and the market was all of humanity
Speaker 18:  coming together and saying, nevermind
Speaker 17:  Ezra raises this point in the piece that I wrote. He
Speaker 17:  said, I, he thinks that Twitter reached its peak at
Speaker 17:  sort of 2020 with Covid and the Black Lives Matter
Speaker 17:  protests and that whole reckoning that occurred and that
Speaker 17:  sort of tearing down of institutions. And he says that was its peak. And
Speaker 17:  after that, a bunch of large institutions, the government, big
Speaker 17:  companies, they all said, do we want Twitter to have this much influence
Speaker 17:  over us? And they sort of collectively decided no. And then that
Speaker 17:  barrels straight into January 6th, that barrell straight into
Speaker 17:  Elon buying Twitter. And you see that his point was, even if
Speaker 17:  Elon hadn't bought Twitter and turned it into X and sort of dismantled it,
Speaker 17:  the institutions were pushing back on it. They were saying this is
Speaker 17:  too much. And people like Ezra were saying, this is too much and I need
Speaker 17:  to get away from it. And so there would've been a natural pendulum swing
Speaker 17:  based on how intense 2020 was, but then Elon
Speaker 17:  showed up and he
Speaker 18:  Just accelerated. Yeah. He put a little rocket on the pendulum.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Right.
Speaker 17:  He's like, here's a falcon that doesn't work. Kaboom.
Speaker 18:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  No, I I think that's right. I think it's like if, if we've learned anything
Speaker 2:  from the last couple of years, it's that everything changes and we
Speaker 2:  are very in so, so, so many ways at the end of like a very
Speaker 2:  specific era of technology. And I think it's definitely
Speaker 2:  true that the pandemic sped a lot of that up. It's definitely true that Elon
Speaker 2:  Musk sp a lot of that up, but I think this was all kind of coming
Speaker 2:  anyway. And I do think, I think you're right, Cranz, that like at some point
Speaker 2:  in the last five years everybody kind of looked around and was like, this
Speaker 2:  is all a mess. And like this thing where we just all
Speaker 2:  hang out together in one place is bad. Like I know
Speaker 2:  my family's political opinions in a way that I'm not in interested in knowing
Speaker 2:  and this is not helpful or good or making me feel better
Speaker 2:  and it was gonna happen eventually. But that said, I will look
Speaker 2:  back on this whole era as like pure chaos,
Speaker 2:  but there were good times. I'm friends with Nicki Minaj now.
Speaker 18:  I mean, I think it was a really important era and I think, I think
Speaker 18:  we still haven't fully grasped just how big an impact it
Speaker 18:  had on us culturally and like as a society. Like I, I do
Speaker 18:  think that it was a big deal and, and it's gonna, we're gonna keep thinking
Speaker 18:  about it later on and we're gonna keep learning those lessons and thinking
Speaker 18:  about the lessons we learned from it.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I do think we're still in the like Nicorette gum phase
Speaker 2:  yo Yeah. Of quitting smoking here. Like we're, we're definitely not out of
Speaker 2:  whatever brain space we've been in for a long time.
Speaker 18:  Yeah. Threads is just like a vape.
Speaker 17:  Yeah. I mean, is is Threads gonna be Nicorette or is
Speaker 17:  it gonna be a Juul or it's gonna be those weird off-brand
Speaker 17:  nicotine mints you can buy at the CVS? I've gone through it. I'm
Speaker 17:  just saying ideally we have none of them. We are not reliant on
Speaker 17:  a even weaker, diluted, centralized social media experience.
Speaker 17:  What we are gonna do is we're gonna build some distributed
Speaker 17:  platforms that let people own their audiences. And don't put all of
Speaker 17:  our, like the story of Twitter. I I was talking to a former Virgin
Speaker 17:  reporter now platform managing editors, Zoe Scheffer about this. And we
Speaker 17:  sort of landed on the idea that Twitter is defined, the story of Twitter
Speaker 17:  is defined by two power users, Donald Trump and Elon Musk.
Speaker 17:  And like, that, that's, that's a, it's, that's a fun thing to think through.
Speaker 17:  And Zoe is on decoder and you can listen to that episode and we, we, we
Speaker 17:  thought it through together and that was good. But you take a step back,
Speaker 17:  you're like, should that be how the world works? Like, should that be
Speaker 17:  how media works? Like two people who get really good at getting likes
Speaker 17:  on a platform suddenly like warp the world around.
Speaker 17:  Like that shouldn't be how that works. You should be able to find your own
Speaker 17:  little network. So I'm, I'm hopeful, I'm hopeful that Threads is successful
Speaker 17:  because I, they're gonna federate and you know, everyone knows how I feel
Speaker 17:  about that, but I'm also, I'm much more hopeful that people seek
Speaker 17:  out smaller pockets of the internet and that is actually what we
Speaker 17:  aim for as opposed to just mindlessly centralizing once again.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I think that's right. I I certainly hope that's true. I have a cynical
Speaker 2:  piece of my brain that wonders if we've now spent so long teaching people
Speaker 2:  how good it feels to chase giant audiences that telling them
Speaker 2:  to chase smaller audiences is gonna be hard to do.
Speaker 18:  I think it's okay. And, and I'm gonna point back to fandom because my, my
Speaker 18:  big theory of the universe is fandom is where all online like
Speaker 18:  behavior incubates. And so in fandom,
Speaker 18:  they've all gotten really upset. They're all actually, they're like, the
Speaker 18:  big discourse right now is that everybody's doing it for the likes on a
Speaker 18:  O three and Wattpad. And that's just inherently hysterical to, to do that
Speaker 18:  anyway. But, but you're seeing younger people, it's particularly younger
Speaker 18:  people like younger Gen Z and Gen A being like, we don't like that. And
Speaker 18:  then like all the old millennials and, and Gen Xers being like, we also
Speaker 18:  don't like that. And so you're you're seeing people reject it in a
Speaker 18:  way that feels like heartening, not totally. It's still happening.
Speaker 17:  Gen X, gen Z alignment. It's right there. Yeah.
Speaker 18:  Just, but like, like young millennials and older Gen
Speaker 18:  Z are still like, I just do it. Like I have AI right by
Speaker 18:  One Direction fanfic and it's like, think about what you've just said
Speaker 18:  and do you really want that to be your legacy online?
Speaker 17:  Alex's email is Alex Cranz.
Speaker 18:  If you use an AI to write your f your Bad
Speaker 2:  Send Alex links to all of your favorite AI generated Fanfic please.
Speaker 18:  I do actually wanna read that
Speaker 2:  All, right? We need to go. I will Miss Twitter. Yeah, I,
Speaker 2:  I'll just say it. It was good. We had a good run. I miss when I could just
Speaker 2:  dmm random strangers who happened to follow me on the internet accidentally.
Speaker 2:  Those were good days.
Speaker 17:  My entire personality wa was like Miller Light and Marro Lights.
Speaker 17:  Yeah, it was good. I had a good time in my twenties
Speaker 2:  And now you have to figure out a new thing. Yeah, it's time.
Speaker 2:  It's time for all of us to figure out a new thing. That's our 2024 goal at
Speaker 2:  the end of 2024. We're gonna come back, we're gonna do this and we're gonna
Speaker 2:  say what's our new thing? It's gonna be great. All, right? Thank you both.
Speaker 2:  Yeah,
Speaker 20:  No, that was good. Twitter. Yeah, that's good. I loved it.
Speaker 2:  All right. We gotta take one more break and then we're gonna get to the Birch
Speaker 2:  cast. Hotline. We'll be right
Speaker 2:  All. right. We're back. Let's do a question from The Vergecast Hotline. As
Speaker 2:  a reminder, you can always email Vergecast at The Verge dot com or call
Speaker 2:  8 6 6 Verge one one to reach us. We try and answer at least one
Speaker 2:  question every week. Thank you as always. To everybody who calls and emails,
Speaker 2:  we've gotten tons of stuff about the USBC episode in particular.
Speaker 2:  Very excited. Thank you to everybody who has reached out today. We have a
Speaker 2:  question about organizing photos, which is a thing I care very deeply about.
Speaker 2:  Here's that.
Speaker 21:  Hey, Virg was just calling through my
Speaker 21:  iPhone photo library. My most recent number
Speaker 21:  in my iPhone photo library is
Speaker 21:  74,224 photos. We can all be
Speaker 21:  real about the fact that these are not all photos that I need to have in
Speaker 21:  my life and I am wondering if there's any app,
Speaker 21:  website, any kind of tool that any of you have used that
Speaker 21:  has been helpful in terms of curating your photo
Speaker 21:  library in mass, especially one that that's that big. Hope you can help
Speaker 21:  me out. Thanks. Bye.
Speaker 2:  Okay, I have a bunch of thoughts on this subject. The first thing I would
Speaker 2:  say is take all of those photos, all
Speaker 2:  74,000, however many it was, and put them all
Speaker 2:  somewhere before you start organizing. Before you start putting things in
Speaker 2:  the places that they deserve to go, just take the whole batch and
Speaker 2:  put them don Don't know in Amazon Photos, which you might have if you have
Speaker 2:  a Prime subscription or in Google Photos or put them on a hard drive
Speaker 2:  somewhere or back them up to another computer, like put all of your photos
Speaker 2:  somewhere. Because at least in my experience, there's always been a time
Speaker 2:  where I delete something 'cause I didn't think I'd want it and then I want
Speaker 2:  it or I'm going through stuff later and I accidentally should have kept
Speaker 2:  something that I didn't just take the whole number and shove 'em somewhere.
Speaker 2:  Then I have three organization tips. The first thing
Speaker 2:  is on your phone, open up photos and then go to albums
Speaker 2:  and then scroll down and you get to the list of media types.
Speaker 2:  And that's actually an incredibly good way to organize some of your photos,
Speaker 2:  really just to delete a lot of them. Like for me, I have hundreds and hundreds
Speaker 2:  and hundreds and hundreds of screenshots saved here and I don't need any
Speaker 2:  of them. So if you just open up screenshots, you can select all really easily,
Speaker 2:  delete them, that's a huge portion of them gone. You can do the same with
Speaker 2:  videos, with selfies, with live photos, with panoramas.
Speaker 2:  It's not a perfect way to weed stuff out, but it's actually a pretty good
Speaker 2:  one in my experience. So that's where I would start. The second thing is
Speaker 2:  to go to duplicates, which is down at the very bottom of that album's page
Speaker 2:  and merge all the duplicates you can. This is less of an issue if you do
Speaker 2:  most of your photography actually on your iPhone, but if you do a lot of
Speaker 2:  importing from other cameras or moving stuff around between devices, odds
Speaker 2:  are you're going to get duplicate photos. And the iPhone does a pretty good
Speaker 2:  job of managing that and knowing when two photos are
Speaker 2:  identical. So I've just been able to go through select all, merge all,
Speaker 2:  and boom, there go hundreds of my different photos all into
Speaker 2:  the correct number of photos. So that's what I would do. And then there are
Speaker 2:  two apps that I have to recommend. One is called Slide Box and one is
Speaker 2:  called Swipe Wipe. Personally I have mostly used Swipe Wipe,
Speaker 2:  but both Slide Box and Swipe Wipe. These are ridiculous things to say out
Speaker 2:  loud are on iPhone and Android and they're basically like Tinder
Speaker 2:  for your photos. You just open the apps up, swipe through, and
Speaker 2:  you quickly just choose basically keeper, toss Keeper, toss Keeper, toss.
Speaker 2:  Slide Box I think has more organization. You can put them into
Speaker 2:  albums and stuff like that, but for me it's just like right and left
Speaker 2:  Keep Don't Keep is a surprisingly quick way to get through a
Speaker 2:  ton of photos. They both cost some money, but if I'm remembering correctly,
Speaker 2:  slide box I think is $10 once for the premium
Speaker 2:  account, then you get it forever and Swipe Wipe I think is more
Speaker 2:  expensive. It's like six bucks a week, but you get three days for free.
Speaker 2:  So if you just want to do it once and just like spend a couple of hours going
Speaker 2:  through all of your photos, you can do it without having to pay any money.
Speaker 2:  And that's actually what I would do. My favorite way to do this is to go
Speaker 2:  through all my photos. Basically on the largest screen you have like the
Speaker 2:  iPad's a good one, phone works fine, Mac Works fine, doesn't
Speaker 2:  have the apps, but is like a bigger screen you can look at it on. I usually
Speaker 2:  do this on my iPad personally. Download the apps, start looking at your photos.
Speaker 2:  I tend to like put on a podcast or watch a movie and just swipe
Speaker 2:  through photos, just swipe, swipe, swipe, swipe, swipe. And you'll be amazed
Speaker 2:  how quickly you get through stuff. 74,000 photos is a lot of photos, but
Speaker 2:  also you don't have to go through every single one of them in order to have
Speaker 2:  a much better handle on your camera roll. So that's what I would do.
Speaker 2:  I am sure there are other apps. If you have one that you really like for
Speaker 2:  organizing and cleaning up your camera roll, let me know. Again, Vergecast
Speaker 2:  to The Verge dot com. 8, 6, 6. Verge one, one is the Hotline
Speaker 2:  number, but again, back 'em All Up somewhere. And then Slide Box and Swipe
Speaker 2:  Wipe are the two that I've found that I really like. They're very helpful.
Speaker 2:  I hope that helps. And if you get through, I want to know how many
Speaker 2:  of those 74,000 actually stick around. So keep me posted.
Speaker 2:  Alright, that is it for The Vergecast today. Thank you to everybody who was
Speaker 2:  on the show, and thank you as always for listening. There's lots more on
Speaker 2:  everything we talked about at The Verge dot com. The Twitter package is fantastic.
Speaker 2:  Sean Hollister has been doing amazing coverage of the Epic
Speaker 2:  versus Google trial. That one we're gonna talk a bunch more about on Friday,
Speaker 2:  but there's a ton of news going on there. The site's been really great even
Speaker 2:  as we wind towards the holidays. So come check out the homepage, but also
Speaker 2:  we'll put some links in the show notes, find our bylines. Good stuff everywhere.
Speaker 2:  If you have thoughts, questions, feelings, favorite tweets or
Speaker 2:  anything else you wanna talk about, again, you can always email us Vergecast
Speaker 2:  at The Verge dot com or call the Hotline eight six six Verge one one.
Speaker 2:  We do a Hotline question at least once every week, so keep 'em coming. This
Speaker 2:  show is produced by Andrew Marino, Liam James, and William Poor Vergecast
Speaker 2:  is VERGE production and part of the Vox Media podcast network. Neli, Alex.
Speaker 2:  And I'll be back on Friday to talk about, like I said, epic versus Google.
Speaker 2:  All the stuff going on with beeper and Apple and lots more. We'll see you
Speaker 2:  then. Rock and roll.
Speaker 3:  Having your identity stolen can be devastating financially
Speaker 3:  and emotionally, and it feels like identity thieves are constantly
Speaker 3:  embedding new ways to take advantage of unsuspecting people. Now you
Speaker 3:  can stay one step ahead with Microsoft Defender. Microsoft Defender
Speaker 3:  helps keep your personal information safer online with continuous
Speaker 3:  monitoring of threats to your identity and credit. Get timely
Speaker 3:  alerts, monthly credit reports, expert guidance, and even hands-on
Speaker 3:  restoration support. When you need help, all in one easy to use
Speaker 3:  security dashboard. Maximize your protection with Microsoft Defender.
Speaker 3:  Available with a Microsoft 3, 6, 5 personal or family
Speaker 3:  subscription.