# Transcript
ID: 1a3808a0-5e02-4119-876a-ac434bb822a2
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: An impossible journey into self-hosting
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/143721901078483274/4388882343512830295/s93290-US-3288s-1698660033.mp3
Description: Today on the flagship podcast of network-attached storage:
This is the fourth in our four-part series all about connectivity. This week we're talking about software: how software connects us, how we connect to software, and how software connects to other software.
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we love hearing from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Disabled
Speaker 1:  Support for this episode comes from Amazon Web Services. The
Speaker 1:  strength of your organization has everything to do with your applications,
Speaker 1:  from your back office operations to the applications that connect you to
Speaker 1:  your customers and partners. AWS continually innovates their
Speaker 1:  infrastructure and services so you can build, run and scale
Speaker 1:  applications in the cloud on premises and at the edge. That's
Speaker 1:  why millions of organizations trust AWS for every
Speaker 1:  application, wanna develop and deploy secure applications faster
Speaker 1:  so you can optimize costs and free up time to innovate for your customers.
Speaker 1:  Choose AWS and Power virtually any application
Speaker 1:  you can imagine.
Speaker 3:  Welcome To, The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of Network attached storage.
Speaker 3:  I'm your friend David Pierce and This is the fourth in our four part series
Speaker 3:  all about connectivity. Over the last few weeks we've dug into the ways we
Speaker 3:  connect to content, to each other and to audiences. And
Speaker 3:  this week I wanna talk about something a little different. I wanna talk about
Speaker 3:  software, how software connects us, how we connect to software,
Speaker 3:  and how software connects to other software. And that story, at least
Speaker 3:  for our purposes today, starts with the computer I bought a little while
Speaker 3:  ago. I bought it on Amazon with essentially no research but I bought it.
Speaker 3:  It's called the B Link mini pc. It has 12th generation Intel chips,
Speaker 3:  16 gigs of Ram, 500 gigs of SSD storage. It's a fine little
Speaker 3:  computer and it's just this little box of a thing about the size of
Speaker 3:  like two of the boxes. The iPhone comes in, it's pretty small and I just
Speaker 3:  hit it immediately off in the corner of my desk. I bought this thing because
Speaker 3:  I wanted to test a theory. That theory is that maybe self-hosting is
Speaker 3:  the future of technology. Over the last two decades really we've been
Speaker 3:  on this race toward cloud software in which all of the apps and
Speaker 3:  platforms and data you use are stored not on your computer but on a
Speaker 3:  server somewhere in a Google or Amazon or Microsoft warehouse.
Speaker 3:  There are a lot of good reasons for that shift. There are a lot of good things
Speaker 3:  about cloud software and there are also a lot of reasons to think cloud
Speaker 3:  software is not going anywhere anytime soon. Here is Peter Van Hardenberg
Speaker 3:  who works at a research lab called Ink and Switch explaining the upsides.
Speaker 3:  I think pretty well.
Speaker 4:  The idea of the cloud was that hey, it turns out that actually shipping software
Speaker 4:  onto people's computers is a huge pain in the neck. It's out of date,
Speaker 4:  you can't fix it if it breaks, you have no idea what's happening.
Speaker 4:  There's all these problems and I think the biggest thing just from like a,
Speaker 4:  like a brass test tax perspective, it's not a technical problem. It was like
Speaker 4:  a, an onboarding problem. Cloud software gets users easier.
Speaker 3:  We're gonna come back to Peter in a minute I promise. But cloud software
Speaker 3:  for all the things, it makes easier and more useful also has lots of
Speaker 3:  downsides. It doesn't work offline for one thing because it's not really
Speaker 3:  on your device at all. Also, if that software's developer
Speaker 3:  goes away or pivots to something else or just decides not to deal
Speaker 3:  with you anymore, the software you rely on can just disappear.
Speaker 3:  The cloud software world is convenient and great, but it's just
Speaker 3:  fragile and it is so fundamentally not yours. So
Speaker 3:  like I said, I had this theory that self-hosting might be the answer at least
Speaker 3:  for important stuff. I figured maybe I should stop relying on cloud services
Speaker 3:  and instead build a system that lets me access my own stuff from anywhere
Speaker 3:  through tools that I control. So, I bought this B link and started
Speaker 3:  setting stuff up. It went poorly. The main thing I discovered
Speaker 3:  is that self-hosting is hard. I'm not the world's most technically
Speaker 3:  capable person, but I know my way around a computer and still I could
Speaker 3:  barely get things up and running. If you wanna like set up a Plex server
Speaker 3:  so you can get at your movie collection from anywhere, that's pretty easy.
Speaker 3:  But at least in my experience so far, there's essentially nothing else out
Speaker 3:  there that is that easy. One great guide I found is from an author and
Speaker 3:  entrepreneur named Derek Sives who created a really handy step-by-step system
Speaker 3:  for registering a domain, setting up your own cloud storage and
Speaker 3:  routing everything from files to email to your calendar, all to that
Speaker 3:  system. He calls this guy Tech Independence, which I really like and it is
Speaker 3:  really useful. You can get through it without knowing a ton going in, but
Speaker 3:  it is so much work and it requires a lot of
Speaker 3:  technical sophistication just in the sense of you have to know what
Speaker 3:  terminal is and how to open it, And what to type in and just time and
Speaker 3:  energy. It's just a lot. I won't lie to you. I built about halfway
Speaker 3:  through the process, I ran into a thing with the FTP server and just gave
Speaker 3:  up. One tool I did manage to set up is called Image. It's a
Speaker 3:  self-hosted alternative to Google Photos. I was thinking about it at the
Speaker 3:  beginning of this process and realized that if all my cloud stuff were to
Speaker 3:  disappear tomorrow, the photos I lost would be the worst part. So
Speaker 3:  I wanted to switch them over to something that wouldn't go away and
Speaker 3:  image is actually a great tool. It has a nice mobile app, it has lots of
Speaker 3:  features, it's a pretty passable Google Photos replacement. But by the
Speaker 3:  time I downloaded Docker and was worrying about virtual machines and
Speaker 3:  containers, it was eating all the memory on my computer. I was just back
Speaker 3:  to feeling totally over my head. I did eventually get it working, but
Speaker 3:  I can't imagine most people are gonna wanna do all of that work. Image was
Speaker 3:  created by this guy named Alex Tran and I kept wondering how he felt
Speaker 3:  about the setup process. So I called him up and asked him. He told me that
Speaker 3:  he started working on Image in the first place because his wife wanted a
Speaker 3:  tool like Google Photos but didn't wanna pay for Google Photos, which as
Speaker 3:  far as I'm concerned is like an extremely universal opinion on the internet.
Speaker 3:  So he set out to build something that was self-hosted and easy
Speaker 3:  and he found nothing.
Speaker 5:  So when I first started Image, I used image as the
Speaker 5:  opportunity for me to learn about You, know how to build nice
Speaker 5:  software, how to build good soft software. So I structured it in a way of
Speaker 5:  using Docker. Using Docker is actually coming from the idea
Speaker 5:  from the community on the self-hosted subreddit that everything should
Speaker 5:  be running from Docker because of the ease of
Speaker 5:  development and maintenance. At the time I didn't have a lot, lot of
Speaker 5:  experience with Docker, so it's nice, it's perfect for for me to learn how
Speaker 5:  to build a Docker image, how to put that into a deployable way.
Speaker 5:  So I put everything into Docker Compose and at first
Speaker 5:  there were a bunch of setting that you have to do before
Speaker 5:  running the docker compose up com command to bring up
Speaker 5:  the whole application. And over time that has been
Speaker 5:  simplified and now we basically move all of the, anything that you can
Speaker 5:  configure through the command, through the environment variable.
Speaker 5:  Now you can do it directly inside image. So it's cut out that
Speaker 5:  initial configuration to the point now that the only thing that you need
Speaker 5:  to change when you're setting up a new MS server is the
Speaker 5:  location where you want to sort a file and then you just do docker, compose
Speaker 5:  up and then it would run.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, I found the, the, the install package on your website even, which was
Speaker 3:  surprisingly simple. I was, I was impressed with how quickly I got
Speaker 3:  up and running.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, this has gone through a lot of improvement and for
Speaker 5:  sure this is coming from the team that has experience with a lot of
Speaker 5:  deployment, so I'm really thankful for, for them to help me learn.
Speaker 5:  Yeah,
Speaker 3:  That's awesome. But do you think just the fact that it requires
Speaker 3:  Docker kind of immediately rules out most people,
Speaker 3:  like I, I don't think I'm gonna convince my wife to like even
Speaker 3:  know what Docker is in order to set up a photo server, right? Is
Speaker 3:  that just kind of the, the cost of doing software this
Speaker 3:  way? Like is there, is there a world in which all of this can be made
Speaker 3:  simpler and easier over time and start to feel like
Speaker 3:  You know you can install and set up a a server just like installing and
Speaker 3:  setting up another app?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, there are a lot of re requests for for that. But from
Speaker 5:  my point of view, when when you are doing something, especially for
Speaker 5:  self-hosting, right, and now when it come to your really important
Speaker 5:  data like photo, the person who managed the server
Speaker 5:  should have some technical knowledge about managing
Speaker 5:  the server. I think it is a, something that
Speaker 5:  self-hosting person should learn is to
Speaker 5:  how to use Docker. Because now when you go into the
Speaker 5:  the awesome self-hosted GitHub repository,
Speaker 5:  most of the application you see can be run from Docker
Speaker 5:  because it's just make the development easier, more mainstream
Speaker 5:  and also the deployment easier and more mainstream.
Speaker 5:  For example, you can deploy it on Dian,
Speaker 5:  Ubuntu or Fedora the same way
Speaker 5:  without worry about which package should be
Speaker 5:  compatible with my digital or with this version.
Speaker 5:  Everything is just, just work from the containerization
Speaker 5:  standpoint.
Speaker 3:  What's your sense of kind of the, the state of the self-hosting movement
Speaker 3:  in general now that you're in it now you've been talking to people. I feel
Speaker 3:  like there's been this little crowd of people who really believe in
Speaker 3:  self-hosting and they're, they're mostly very technical and they understand
Speaker 3:  how to make it work and they know all of the different sort of underlying
Speaker 3:  systems and they spend a lot of time in terminal. But I don't feel like the
Speaker 3:  self-hosting world has ever quite gotten out of that. But part of me thinks
Speaker 3:  it might be starting to happen. Being able to kind of have your stuff
Speaker 3:  on your device but access it from anywhere is starting to be a slightly more
Speaker 3:  mainstream thing. What are you seeing, do you think like
Speaker 3:  self-hosting is about to hit the big time?
Speaker 5:  The reason sentiment is that a lot more people
Speaker 5:  are starting to concern more about their privacy with all the story
Speaker 5:  that about the third party or the services
Speaker 5:  that you use can access your data. So more and more people are starting
Speaker 5:  to be noticing that and I, I think
Speaker 5:  the more people are starting noticing that, then they will start to find
Speaker 5:  a way to get back that control of the data
Speaker 5:  and it would be a good drive to get
Speaker 5:  people to look into self-hosting more. But of course this is a
Speaker 5:  very technical field, right? You would need to have some
Speaker 5:  IT knowledge, some computer knowledge as well as
Speaker 5:  networking et cetera. So that's why it's
Speaker 5:  not that easy for other people to get into but someone to
Speaker 5:  really be interested in this So I still feel
Speaker 5:  like there's some maybe a long way to go in order to get more and more
Speaker 5:  people to get into self-hosting, but with the trend
Speaker 5:  of You know high paying CS degree,
Speaker 5:  high paying CSS jobs so more people get into computer
Speaker 5:  science so it's exposed them more to these things.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, it's gonna be interesting to see if the trend is that more
Speaker 3:  people gain these skills or if that these
Speaker 3:  tools and systems become simpler and it'll probably be a little of
Speaker 3:  both, right? Like do you think there is a path for You know the people
Speaker 3:  who just don't have the interest or expertise to care about Docker
Speaker 3:  to maybe in a few years be able to make use of a tool like this? It seems
Speaker 3:  like we're we're kind of one really great user interface
Speaker 3:  invention away from this stuff being easier. Do you think there's a way to
Speaker 3:  get there?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, we always looking for a way to make it simpler, but as
Speaker 5:  of right now, I think with the limitation of the tool that we have and the
Speaker 5:  tool that we have access to in order to serve, to
Speaker 5:  fulfill the purpose of high performance, easy to
Speaker 5:  maintain right now I don't see a tool better than Docker unless
Speaker 5:  we have some invention down the road in this space that compete with
Speaker 5:  Docker and to make thing even more streamlined and easier. That
Speaker 5:  would be really cool thing to have. But as of right
Speaker 5:  now I don't see the al alternative. If you do know
Speaker 5:  anything, please let me know.
Speaker 3:  By the time I'd finished talking to Alex, I'd sort of given up on the idea
Speaker 3:  that self-hosting can be a mainstream solution for people who want
Speaker 3:  more ownership and control of their stuff seriously. Just the fact that
Speaker 3:  Docker an app that's all about containerized application development might
Speaker 3:  become a mainstream thing that people know how to use just seems
Speaker 3:  wrong to me. I just don't think that's gonna happen. I don't think it's necessarily
Speaker 3:  impossible to make self-hosted systems that are user-friendly and simple.
Speaker 3:  I think Plex is actually a really good example of how to do it right, but
Speaker 3:  there's just not much else out there that qualifies right now. But as I was
Speaker 3:  asking around trying to figure out what might work if self-hosting doesn't,
Speaker 3:  I heard about this concept that a few people mentioned to me. It's called
Speaker 3:  Local First software and when we come back from a quick break, we're gonna
Speaker 3:  talk about why local first software might just be the best of both worlds.
Speaker 3:  We'll be right back.
Speaker 1:  Thank you to Amazon Web Services for sponsoring Vergecast
Speaker 1:  AWS has been innovating infrastructure for over 15 years
Speaker 1:  so you can build and run secure performance applications faster and
Speaker 1:  more economically. That's why AWS pioneered serverless technology
Speaker 1:  in 2014 with the launch of AWS Lambda.
Speaker 6:  Lambda allows developers to supply snippets of code in
Speaker 6:  various languages like Java or Python or otherwise and we
Speaker 6:  run it on their behalf using AWS's power of
Speaker 6:  infrastructure.
Speaker 1:  AJ NIR is Lambda's general manager with AWS Serverless services
Speaker 1:  customers can offload most operational responsibilities to AWS
Speaker 1:  and get built-in high availability, scalability and security best
Speaker 1:  practices by default
Speaker 6:  And, what that means is they can get a, what we would call a production grade
Speaker 6:  application up and running in factors of time that are three to five
Speaker 6:  times shorter than it used to be in the past.
Speaker 1:  AJ will be back later in the show to tell you more about how AWS
Speaker 1:  serverless technologies make it easy to scale and manage cloud applications.
Speaker 1:  Reimagine your applications with AWS
Speaker 3:  All, right? We're back. Okay, local first software, let's go back 40
Speaker 3:  years or so to the early days of the computer era. Computers were
Speaker 3:  huge and boxes and beige and made by a bunch of companies that mostly
Speaker 3:  don't exist anymore. Back then cloud services weren't a thing. Nobody was
Speaker 3:  running all their software on servers anywhere because none of that existed.
Speaker 3:  People acquired software by like going to a store and buying
Speaker 3:  a box that had a disc of some kind in it that you plugged into your computer
Speaker 3:  to install a program. That all sounds sort of quaint now. Like can you
Speaker 3:  imagine getting in the car and driving to Target every time you wanted to
Speaker 3:  get a new app on your phone? Hard pass. It's all much better now. But that
Speaker 3:  approach did have one really nice side effect. Your software was
Speaker 3:  yours, it was installed on your computer locally.
Speaker 3:  If the company that made your game went out of business, you might not get
Speaker 3:  updates but your game would still run fine on your computer. If the
Speaker 3:  developer of your productivity app made some horrible UI change you hate,
Speaker 3:  no problem, just don't buy the next version. That's how software worked for
Speaker 3:  a long, long time. One way to think about it is that our computers used to
Speaker 3:  be the home for our software and now they're just the way that we access
Speaker 3:  software that lives somewhere else. That difference feels small but it
Speaker 3:  actually totally changes the way we think about what our devices actually
Speaker 3:  do. Which brings us back to Peter from before. Remember the cloud services
Speaker 3:  guy from Ink and Switch, he is a big believer and promoter of the idea
Speaker 3:  of local first software, which he thinks can combine the best of all
Speaker 3:  of the last four decades of software. Basically in a local first
Speaker 3:  world, your apps live on your device just like they did 40 years ago.
Speaker 3:  They are yours. Your software belongs to you and you can access them
Speaker 3:  offline or without worrying that they'll still be around tomorrow. But you
Speaker 3:  can also connect that software to the cloud and get all of the collaboration
Speaker 3:  and multi-device sync and in general the convenience benefits
Speaker 3:  of having it in the cloud. This sounds like the best of both worlds, right?
Speaker 3:  This is how it should all work. I think So I called up Peter to ask him
Speaker 3:  how It works, why he's such a big believer in the idea and why
Speaker 3:  software didn't turn out that way in the first place. He started by telling
Speaker 3:  me a story about a music app that I certainly had not thought about in
Speaker 3:  a long time and I bet you haven't either. It's called R-D-O-R-D-O
Speaker 4:  Was a great piece of software but the offline mode for the RDO
Speaker 4:  app was like a whole other program from the main app. It had
Speaker 4:  different features, it behaved in different ways, it had different bugs.
Speaker 4:  And I just remember this feeling of like why
Speaker 4:  was the song I just listened to and the playlist I was just looking
Speaker 4:  at where did they go when I went into offline mode
Speaker 4:  because I had them here. And so in a sense what was happening is that this
Speaker 4:  app was deleting my data, right? And like there's a more sophistic like I'm
Speaker 4:  a developer, these are my friends who built this app, I've worked on this
Speaker 4:  stuff. I know the real answer is more complicated, which is that like You
Speaker 4:  know the kind of normal way of building apps in this era is that
Speaker 4:  you have a server which is where the software really lives and the
Speaker 4:  thing that you hold on your, in your hand or the thing that you have on your
Speaker 4:  computer in front of you, that's not really the program that's just like
Speaker 4:  a mask in front of the program and it talks to the program on your behalf
Speaker 4:  and it presents like a pretend version of the program. That's what you use.
Speaker 4:  And I had this feeling of like especially though if you have an offline mode
Speaker 4:  then you need to have the program. 'cause you can't talk to the program when
Speaker 4:  there's no internet, right? But it's crazy 'cause everybody's building like
Speaker 4:  this sophisticated program that running it in the cloud and then on
Speaker 4:  the mobile app in the device for offline mode, they run smaller worse
Speaker 4:  versions of it that don't actually work the same way. And I was just like,
Speaker 4:  how about this? How about we write the program, we run it on our computers
Speaker 4:  and then we talk to the cloud to get the data and then we have the data in
Speaker 4:  our computers whether they're in our pockets or on our laptops or
Speaker 4:  whatever. 'cause like when you go in an airplane or in a taxi
Speaker 4:  or take Muni and your computer just turns into a paperweight, that
Speaker 4:  sucks. And not only that but like I was a huge fan of RDO. I know
Speaker 4:  a lot of people who loved RDO. You can't use it anymore, right? You can't
Speaker 4:  use it anymore because you never had it. I can still run winamp,
Speaker 4:  I can go and download winamp and I can run winamp today. I can find
Speaker 4:  all those sweet skins from the 1990s. I can use Winamp but r d's gone
Speaker 4:  forever. And as I got deeper into this stuff, the more I started to think
Speaker 4:  about that and the more I realized that like not only is this just
Speaker 4:  an inconvenience for me it's it's a disappointment, right? Like RIP Google
Speaker 4:  Reader or whatever your favorite cloud software that's gone. But like
Speaker 4:  we are in a dark age of software. And I mean that not in like the
Speaker 4:  sense that the software is bad. What I mean is that every piece of
Speaker 4:  software that runs today that's built the way we build software, everything
Speaker 4:  we built on Heroku where we used You know I used to work, all that stuff
Speaker 4:  is going to disappear irrevocably soon. And
Speaker 4:  everything that we've built and everything that we've done in this era, all
Speaker 4:  of our collective communal work will be lost.
Speaker 3:  The thing you're describing though, where it sort of matches
Speaker 3:  the best of those two things, this idea of local first software, how did
Speaker 3:  we not get to that sooner that that seems like anyone sort of looking
Speaker 3:  at this for a long time should have thought what if I had the app on my device?
Speaker 3:  Like RDO is such an interesting example, right? Like the people at RDO did
Speaker 3:  they just not think someday this will all be gone. Wouldn't it be nice like
Speaker 3:  this is one of the things I go back and forth with with all this software
Speaker 3:  is I understand all the reasons it's easier to build cloud first software
Speaker 3:  and that it's more you make more money doing it. That that all makes sense
Speaker 3:  but but part of me wonders like is the reason just that people don't care
Speaker 3:  about the flip side?
Speaker 4:  I don't think that's it. I think there are a few elements here but
Speaker 4:  a lot of it comes, there's two things. There's a technical challenge and
Speaker 4:  there's a narrative dimension. Okay? The narrative dimension is
Speaker 4:  that You know everybody wants to build the next big
Speaker 4:  startup and make a billion dollars venture capitalists are
Speaker 4:  telling everybody that's how to build software. Everybody thinks that
Speaker 4:  they have to build for Google scale, they're gonna need
Speaker 4:  Cassandra, they're gonna have a billion users, they're gonna be You know
Speaker 4:  it, this ends the rocket ship, You know just hop on. And like
Speaker 4:  when you approach building software with this mindset,
Speaker 4:  then you reach for the tools that other people who have done this task have
Speaker 4:  used. And so a big part of it as well is that like You know
Speaker 4:  there's like a, the term is path dependence, right? Like we started
Speaker 4:  making cloud software and we're like oh this is great. And then we just kept
Speaker 4:  piling more and more energy onto that trying to solve the problems of it.
Speaker 4:  And there was very little investment on this other axis.
Speaker 4:  You know there was like the offline first movement, which I think You know
Speaker 4:  is a closely related precursor but like the narrative has
Speaker 4:  been like well why do you want that? The cloud solves all our problems, right?
Speaker 4:  Like internet is everywhere. You've got wifi at home, you've got wifi, you
Speaker 4:  make a hotspot with your phone, everyone's got internet all the time. What's
Speaker 4:  the big deal? Just wait. It'll be there. And so first that's not true. I
Speaker 4:  mean there is internet more and more places. But the other thing is this
Speaker 4:  kind of like the consequences of the cloud took a long time to become clear.
Speaker 4:  Hmm. Right? When we started working on Heroku You know
Speaker 4:  and back in the day there wasn't killed by
Speaker 4:  google.com right? We didn't have a history of apps that had come and
Speaker 4:  gone and now we're lost because we hadn't had time to go through that sort
Speaker 4:  of generational cycle. So I think a lot of the problems have
Speaker 4:  You know as so often as the case have emerged over time, right? If you look
Speaker 4:  at the oil era, nobody was like hey this awesome energy source might
Speaker 4:  turn out to have some consequences someday. People are like this is amazing.
Speaker 4:  I can go see my aunt and I don't have to like feed a horse to get there.
Speaker 4:  That's
Speaker 3:  Very fair. And it does seem like You know, you mentioned the narrative side
Speaker 3:  and the technological side and it does seem like with sort of the,
Speaker 3:  I don't know, manifesto of local first software, you did try to get at
Speaker 3:  both of those. 'cause I think one of the questions I came into this with
Speaker 3:  was like to what extent is the kind of heady case
Speaker 3:  for data ownership and
Speaker 3:  longevity and the idea of like having a space on the
Speaker 3:  internet that's mine. How far does that really get you? And I feel like you
Speaker 3:  do make some of that case and I'm curious how broadly effective you think
Speaker 3:  that case can be. But then there is also like at some point you just have
Speaker 3:  to build better products And I feel like one thing I'd liked about the way
Speaker 3:  you guys approached it is you also make the case that this is a way to make
Speaker 3:  better products.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I think these kinds of philosophical perspectives
Speaker 4:  will motivate a certain audience but I think that when you
Speaker 4:  make the right thing, the easy thing people will do it. It's as simple as
Speaker 4:  that. If it's cheaper and easier to build software local
Speaker 4:  first, then people will do it. And so what we do is we just
Speaker 4:  focus on that problem which is You know we care about some of these things
Speaker 4:  and we know there are people who care about some of these things and that's
Speaker 4:  great and there are like people with privacy concerns like activists and
Speaker 4:  so on. But like I think when you look at those narrow
Speaker 4:  niche markets, those those audiences, they're great people with real problems
Speaker 4:  and it's great to be able to help people who have those problems. But like
Speaker 4:  we all want software that works. We all hate when the thing doesn't
Speaker 4:  go, when the keystrokes are too slow and you hit submit and you get a
Speaker 4:  spinner. Like, and if we can just make it easier to build software in a way
Speaker 4:  where that just doesn't happen or happens less, then I think
Speaker 4:  everybody will be happy. So just make the right thing the easy thing you
Speaker 4:  were saying, oh earlier like is it harder to build software this way? It's
Speaker 4:  impossible to build software the way we build software. It's
Speaker 4:  costs a fortune to build software the way we build software. You need to
Speaker 4:  learn Kubernetes. There's like literally like
Speaker 4:  203 letter acronym services that constitute Amazon
Speaker 4:  web services. And then on top of that you have to learn go multi-cloud and
Speaker 4:  learn how to do it on Google and Microsoft as well. It's
Speaker 4:  impossible to build software today the way we build software, it's like
Speaker 4:  you wanna like go to the grocery store and you gotta use
Speaker 4:  all the technology to build an aircraft carrier to get there. What
Speaker 4:  we need is bicycles, right? But all we're building is aircraft carriers and
Speaker 4:  this is like the Jonathan Edwards line, right? We were promised bicycles
Speaker 4:  for the mine but we got aircraft carriers instead. Yeah. Like it's so
Speaker 4:  complicated to build anything in the cloud. And then on top of that, once
Speaker 4:  you do, you figure out your GraphQL and whether you use Postgres or
Speaker 4:  Mongo and like what front end framework and node or
Speaker 4:  go on the backend and do you need to use auth zero? Do you need to use this?
Speaker 4:  Do you need like all these cloud services, you put it all together, you get
Speaker 4:  the damn thing running and now you gotta pay every month to keep the thing
Speaker 4:  online and when anything falls over, you get paged in the middle of the night,
Speaker 4:  woken up, it's impossible to build software and if you do you're gonna regret
Speaker 4:  it 'cause it's gonna cost you a fortune and wake you up.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. And most of the pieces of that equation you have absolutely no
Speaker 3:  control over. Like I, I'm reminded of this every time AWS goes down
Speaker 3:  and it's like oh the internet dies whenever a Wix has an issue. Like
Speaker 3:  fundamentally we rely on Amazon to keep its data centers up
Speaker 3:  to like live our lives and that's bonkers.
Speaker 4:  Yeah And also hilarious is just that like we've so totally
Speaker 4:  broken the internet as this like mesh network
Speaker 4:  that literally if you and I were in the same room recording this call,
Speaker 4:  all of our data would probably be bouncing off of US East one in Ashburn,
Speaker 4:  Virginia and back to each other's laptops just so that we could collaborate.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, it's wild. I think there's a bunch of other interesting problems.
Speaker 4:  I mean like there's interesting challenges around like You know the
Speaker 4:  networking stuff, right? It's called a browser not a keeper.
Speaker 4:  All this app that I'm looking at right now as we're talking, when I close
Speaker 4:  and open the tab, it's not gonna be saved. I can't come back to this work.
Speaker 4:  And the browser really assumes that you're just kind of grazing as you use
Speaker 4:  your computer but it's become the main platform for software. And so then
Speaker 4:  there's Electron which is like a wrapper around a browser with a bunch of
Speaker 4:  bells and whistles. But like all this stuff feels kind of unsatisfying and
Speaker 4:  I think You know it's tough when like the incentives
Speaker 4:  of the organization that builds the most important piece of software on your
Speaker 4:  computer are to sell you ads. Like the platform
Speaker 4:  we all live every day in is run by an ad company
Speaker 4:  and You know lots of great people at Google, they care about these problems
Speaker 4:  but like there's just an incentive structure here that's not
Speaker 4:  favorable for solving these problems. Yeah. And so there's, there's some
Speaker 4:  of that dimension. But I think in terms of like value and
Speaker 4:  priority, I think one thing that we are really interested in at
Speaker 4:  in Can switch is what we call malleable software after Philip S's
Speaker 4:  PhD. And this is this idea that like we live in this weird
Speaker 4:  world where like computers again are meant to be this like very powerful
Speaker 4:  compositional informational environment but increasingly like
Speaker 4:  all of the software we use are these like closed boxes
Speaker 4:  that are given to you by somebody else and you can't do anything with You
Speaker 4:  know and So I like to think of the ideal computing
Speaker 4:  environment as being like a wood shop or a kitchen. Like in my
Speaker 4:  kitchen I can make Indian food or Japanese food. I can go and like
Speaker 4:  reheat some leftovers and like I have not too many kitchen
Speaker 4:  gadgets but like you can go a long way with a chef's knife and a cutting
Speaker 4:  board and like You know a stand mixer. Yeah You know to measuring
Speaker 4:  screens like you, you can do a lot with like a few good elements
Speaker 4:  but like the software world is very much like You know, oh this note taking
Speaker 4:  app. Can't open the notes from that note taking app And So I think a lot
Speaker 4:  about like once we have local first software for us this is really just the
Speaker 4:  first step, right? If the software is local first and you have the software,
Speaker 4:  then just like if you bring shelving home from Ikea, You know you can decide
Speaker 4:  whether or not you wanna put all the shelves in or if you wanna set it up
Speaker 4:  on its side or upright if you want to cut the legs off the chairs
Speaker 4:  'cause you're short You know you wanna paint it a different color to match
Speaker 4:  your space. We're really interested in this problem of like once
Speaker 4:  we have the software, can we start to actually use it? Can we make it our
Speaker 4:  own? As we see the local first movement start to build steam, we see
Speaker 4:  so many people getting involved. Our vision is starting to look forward
Speaker 4:  to like the next frontier which is actually empowering users to
Speaker 4:  not have to care about these things but to be able to care about these
Speaker 4:  things, right? And in your home, if you have a challenge you might go to
Speaker 4:  the hardware store and buy the things and fix it for yourself or you might
Speaker 4:  hire a handyman or maybe you live in an apartment and you call your super
Speaker 4:  sure right? But whatever that relationship you have to that space is,
Speaker 4:  it's something that you can have agency and make choices about. And we think
Speaker 4:  that all computing environments should have those properties and we wanna
Speaker 4:  start figuring out how to bring that next to the broader world and and that's
Speaker 4:  kind of where we think about where this goes after we start to see local
Speaker 4:  first software take off.
Speaker 3:  This is all kind of heady I know, but the app that I was thinking about
Speaker 3:  that helped me understand the idea is this note taking app called Obsidian.
Speaker 3:  You might have used it, it's pretty popular. It's a great app. Big fan Obsidian
Speaker 3:  is above all just an app you download to your computer that reads and writes
Speaker 3:  text files. If you boil it all the way down, that's what it's the company
Speaker 3:  offers a service for syncing your files. But that's a separate thing. And
Speaker 3:  if obsidian goes outta business, you can always sync through Google Drive
Speaker 3:  or Dropbox or lots of other things. And Obsidian is built on a
Speaker 3:  plugin system. So the main app is really basic but you can add all kinds
Speaker 3:  of functionality just by downloading a bit of code or even writing some yourself.
Speaker 3:  If obsidian ever goes away, you'll still have the app. If a plugin ever
Speaker 3:  disappears, you'll still have the version that you installed. And if for
Speaker 3:  some reason way down the road the app ever stops working entirely,
Speaker 3:  you'll still have your folder of text files because that's all it is anyway
Speaker 3:  and you can just take them somewhere else. Obsidian the company is building
Speaker 3:  new tools for sharing and publishing and lots of other stuff because again,
Speaker 3:  the cloud is a good thing. There are lots of upsides but you don't have to
Speaker 3:  use any of them. And if obsidian goes away you'll still have obsidian
Speaker 3:  that is local first software right there. I love it. All, right? We have
Speaker 3:  to take one more break and then we have one more big idea about software
Speaker 3:  to talk about. We'll be right back.
Speaker 7:  Fox Creative,
Speaker 1:  This is advertiser content brought to you by Amazon Web Services.
Speaker 1:  AJ Nir from AWS says there's an easy way to understand the
Speaker 1:  benefits of serverless app development.
Speaker 6:  So, I. Think about serverless closer to the concept of wireless,
Speaker 1:  Meaning the servers are there, you just don't have to think about it.
Speaker 6:  They become our problem to worry about.
Speaker 1:  That means no infrastructure to provision or manage no operating
Speaker 1:  systems to install, upgrade or patch AWS takes care of it all
Speaker 1:  for you.
Speaker 6:  A lot of the innovation we see in the market today I don't believe would
Speaker 6:  have been possible if something like cloud services did not exist as the
Speaker 6:  accelerant.
Speaker 1:  That's because serverless technologies from Amazon help customers
Speaker 1:  across industries do two very important things. First,
Speaker 1:  serverless technologies eliminate operational overhead so your teams
Speaker 1:  can release quickly, get feedback and iterate to get to market faster.
Speaker 6:  The customer is always gonna pick the one who meets their needs faster.
Speaker 1:  Second, AWS serverless solutions reduce total
Speaker 1:  cost of ownership with a pay for value billing model. So you never
Speaker 1:  pay for resources, you don't need
Speaker 6:  The total cost of ownership and infrastructure costs are lower than what
Speaker 6:  they would do if they were building on their own. I continue to marvel that
Speaker 6:  when we see companies that are built by one and two people that are serving
Speaker 6:  millions of customers and helping millions of people around the world do
Speaker 6:  things better. And those are the kind of accelerations that happen when customers
Speaker 6:  use cloud services.
Speaker 1:  Learn how a Wix serverless technologies can help you
Speaker 1:  accelerate innovation and lower TCO if your
Speaker 1:  applications@go.aws slash every
Speaker 1:  app
Speaker 3:  All, right? We're back as I was working on this episode and trying to figure
Speaker 3:  out what it means to take back some control of our software and our
Speaker 3:  devices. I was also reading a new book called The Internet Con by Cory
Speaker 3:  Dro. If you've never heard of Cory, he's an activist and author and blogger
Speaker 3:  and he's been thinking about the way that the internet should work for a
Speaker 3:  really long time. And this book is basically a step-by-step guide
Speaker 3:  for how to take down the tech giants. He argues, as he often does,
Speaker 3:  that the internet is run by a few huge companies. That's a problem and
Speaker 3:  we should stop it. Most of that is a conversation for another day. And
Speaker 3:  I don't agree with all of Corey's thoughts on the subject, but it's a really
Speaker 3:  good book. It's really interesting and worth reading. The thing that jumped
Speaker 3:  out at me most about it was Corey's specific idea for how to
Speaker 3:  improve our tech situation. He doesn't argue for breaking up the tech giants
Speaker 3:  or reinventing capitalism altogether, though I suspect he'd be cool with
Speaker 3:  both of those things. He actually makes the case that interoperability different
Speaker 3:  apps and platforms being compatible with one another is pretty close
Speaker 3:  to a one stop fix for everything. Ever since I read the book, I
Speaker 3:  haven't been able to stop thinking about that idea that maybe instead of
Speaker 3:  going back to having all my data only on my device or
Speaker 3:  only using software that works offline, the solution is just to make it so
Speaker 3:  easy to move between services that a few of them going away wouldn't
Speaker 3:  make a difference. I guess like if the whole internet goes down, you're still
Speaker 3:  in trouble, but we're in big trouble anyway if the internet goes down. Anyway,
Speaker 3:  I wanted to understand why Corey thought interop was the answer. Like
Speaker 3:  the answer So I called him up to figure it out. The biggest picture thing
Speaker 3:  you talk about is interoperability and the idea that what we should do is
Speaker 3:  by hook or by crook, open all these platforms to each other
Speaker 3:  and to others. And then I think if I'm not misunderstanding, this
Speaker 3:  web standards are the fastest way to get there, right? Like I, I've, I feel
Speaker 3:  like I've spent the last year or so talking to people and betting on the
Speaker 3:  idea that like the open web can be the solution to a lot of our
Speaker 3:  platform problems. If only we allowed it to be you're, you're making a face.
Speaker 3:  Tell me what you think
Speaker 8:  So I would say. It's not quite web standards are how we get there. 'cause
Speaker 8:  first of all, web standards are mandatory. So we've all seen ver
Speaker 8:  versions of embrace and extend So. I would say that there has to be a
Speaker 8:  two-pronged approach. One is rules about what you must do.
Speaker 8:  So we might say to Facebook, you have to open up a gateway and that might
Speaker 8:  be through legislation but it might be through a settlement, right? Like
Speaker 8:  Facebook and Twitter and all these other companies, they're just incapable
Speaker 8:  of coloring within the lines. They're just like pathological cheaters. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  And so they're all already under multiple FTC consent
Speaker 8:  decrees and European Commission consent decrees and whatever. And they're
Speaker 8:  all violating them and they're all eventually going to be
Speaker 8:  dragged into a situation where they're gonna seek a settlement. And so we
Speaker 8:  might as a settlement say, oh you have to stand up these gateways.
Speaker 3:  But like in theory the the eus legislation about interoperability between
Speaker 3:  messaging apps, that's the kind of thing you're talking about, right? Yeah.
Speaker 3:  And
Speaker 8:  The digital markets act, it's not just messaging apps, it's a whole bunch
Speaker 8:  of different platforms. They're just starting with messaging, which sure
Speaker 8:  we can talk about this later, I think is a mistake. They should be starting
Speaker 8:  with social media messaging if they screw it up is gonna like expose
Speaker 8:  dissidents and other people to leaks in their messaging. And yeah, it's like
Speaker 8:  the next Jamal Khashoggi who's murdered the way Jamal Khashoggi was
Speaker 8:  by someone exploiting a defect in the instant messaging tools that he
Speaker 8:  uses to lu him to his death is gonna discredit this whole project. I, it's
Speaker 8:  a huge mistake, but it's not just those mandates, right? Like 'cause that's
Speaker 8:  gonna roll out over 10 years. In the in parallel there's like Facebook violating
Speaker 8:  its consent decree. Google does violating consent decree, Twitter violating
Speaker 8:  all of these other rules. You know and they're gonna in
Speaker 8:  parallel with this. Someone might just say like, okay, well if you wanna
Speaker 8:  not be fined 10 x your market cap and
Speaker 8:  live to fight another day, you're gonna have to consent to standing up this
Speaker 8:  interoperable gateway. Twitter is gonna have to offer a activity pub gateway
Speaker 8:  or something. Right? And the problem with that is it's very hard to
Speaker 8:  administer that remedy. And we're getting into some wonky sort of
Speaker 8:  public administration stuff here. But like say we say to Facebook,
Speaker 8:  you have to stand up a gateway to activity pub so people can leave, go to
Speaker 8:  a masto on server, but still be connected to the people that matter to them
Speaker 8:  and the customers and the communities and all the things that they're sort
Speaker 8:  of glued to Facebook by. But then Facebook shuts down that gateway
Speaker 8:  and says, we shut it down. 'cause we thought there was another Cambridge
Speaker 8:  Analytica that was stealing a billion users data, which is a thing that actual
Speaker 8:  future Cambridge Analytica are gonna try to do, right? Sure. They're gonna
Speaker 8:  try to exploit this APO, we just saw You know 23 and me get scraped for
Speaker 8:  however many million ashkenazis genetic records. And it is
Speaker 8:  just like a, as an Ashkenazi person, a very creepy sentence to say You know.
Speaker 8:  And so we are gonna want them to like have an intrusion detection system
Speaker 8:  in a firewall and security engineers. But how do you distinguish the pretext
Speaker 8:  from the reality, right? When, when, when Facebook says, oh we're shutting
Speaker 8:  this down once a week because we're worried about VULs
Speaker 8:  and act of attacks when everybody understands Facebook's
Speaker 8:  infrastructure is to a first approximation of Facebook employee and
Speaker 8:  you're like deposing these people and spending like years arguing about whether
Speaker 8:  this was a pretext or not. In the meantime, the new market
Speaker 8:  entrance, these Mastodon servers or whatever it is that have stood up to
Speaker 8:  like welcome in Facebook refugees that were evacuating from Facebook,
Speaker 8:  those users are learning that they can't rely on them. The
Speaker 8:  financiers, the banks or the individuals who funded them are learning that
Speaker 8:  you shouldn't fund these projects. And the people who started them are learning
Speaker 8:  that it's not a, it's not a fruitful thing to do with their time. It's a
Speaker 8:  waste of their time. So you also need to
Speaker 8:  legalize the stuff that Facebook did to MySpace. So when Facebook started,
Speaker 8:  everybody was MySpace user and they didn't just say, Hey come
Speaker 8:  hang out on Facebook. We have a better user interface. Eventually your
Speaker 8:  friends might show up and in the meantime you could admire our great color
Speaker 8:  choices. They said like, here's a bot, give it your login,
Speaker 8:  give it your password, it'll go to MySpace several times a day.
Speaker 8:  Impersonate you log in, scrape your inbox, put it in your Facebook inbox
Speaker 8:  and let you autopilot your responses back out to Facebook. So you to MySpace
Speaker 8:  so you can eat your cake and have it too. So what if we re legalize that
Speaker 8:  conduct? 'cause You know when people try to do that to Facebook like Power
Speaker 8:  Ventures did or OG app or other other tools that have popped
Speaker 8:  up to do this to Facebook. Facebook just soos them into like radioactive
Speaker 8:  rubble, right? Computer fraud abuse Act, DMC 1201
Speaker 8:  tortious interference with contract, patent, trademark, copyright, all these
Speaker 8:  other kind of this thicket of what we call ip, but which is like the
Speaker 8:  right to control the conduct of your customer's critics and and competitors.
Speaker 8:  And so You know if we re legalize that conduct, then
Speaker 8:  those new market entrants who Facebook locks out of their API
Speaker 8:  could fall back to scraping bots, reverse engineering and other tools.
Speaker 8:  Now that's gorilla warfare with Facebook in general. I think
Speaker 8:  Facebook will lose that over the long run because for Facebook to
Speaker 8:  just successfully defend this, they need to make zero mistakes
Speaker 8:  and to successfully attack their defenses, you need to find one mistake.
Speaker 8:  And so that will privilege them. But I also think Facebook
Speaker 8:  would all other things being equal prefer a managed
Speaker 8:  solution where the API is reliable to a situation where they cannot
Speaker 8:  use the law to stop these adversarial inter operators because
Speaker 8:  Gorilla warfare represents an unquantifiable risk to Facebook
Speaker 8:  and shareholders do not like surprises. And we saw Facebook
Speaker 8:  lose a quarter of a trillion dollars after their first
Speaker 8:  report of 2022 to their shareholders when they revealed that
Speaker 8:  they, it wasn't even contraction, it was less growth than they'd anticipated
Speaker 8:  among US users. And the people who bore the brunt of that
Speaker 8:  stock crash were the managers who made the decisions
Speaker 8:  that led to the reduction in users, right? Because they're the ones whose
Speaker 8:  portfolios are primarily stuffed with Facebook stock, right? More than anyone
Speaker 8:  else. They're the least diverse shareholders, right? And so
Speaker 8:  if we say to Facebook to the decision makers at Facebook,
Speaker 8:  if you break your API you will have to contend with Gorilla warfare and
Speaker 8:  that Gorilla Warfare will produce the surprises that will make you personally
Speaker 8:  significantly poorer. Then I think we align their incentives. But of
Speaker 8:  course no one ever lost money by betting on the hubris of
Speaker 8:  tech executives. Yeah. So if they do go ahead and do this, then we
Speaker 8:  have a fallback. That's what I mean by like an administrative remedy,
Speaker 8:  right? A an actual plan that looks at what Facebook is doing that
Speaker 8:  harms people, what stops people from getting out of harm's way, what will
Speaker 8:  moderate those harms? And what we'll do when Facebook takes a
Speaker 8:  countermeasure to recover its super normal profits
Speaker 8:  at the expense of everyday users. And how we will counter that
Speaker 3:  One, like much lower stakes thing you're making me think about is like I'm,
Speaker 3:  I'm an obsessive user of note taking apps and I switch between them constantly.
Speaker 8:  Are you an Evernote casualty? Oh
Speaker 3:  Yes. And this is kind of, this is actually where I was going is one of the
Speaker 3:  first things you do if you build a note taking app is you build an Evernote
Speaker 3:  importer because there are a lot of people who have hated Evernote because
Speaker 3:  it's been very bad for 10 years who are stuck there because they have thousands
Speaker 3:  of notes and they wanna leave. And Evernote makes you, makes you export in
Speaker 3:  this like EN ex file that is proprietary,
Speaker 3:  but also everyone else has figured out how to manage it. And So
Speaker 3:  I can now with two clicks pull all of my Evernote notes into some other app
Speaker 3:  which has made it possible to leave Evernote for tons and tons of people
Speaker 3:  who otherwise would not have been allowed out. And what it is in social is
Speaker 3:  like I'm stuck in Evernote for the rest of my life because it is so
Speaker 3:  hard to switch that I will put up with whatever nonsense there is
Speaker 3:  just to be here. And like the note taking is such a smaller version of it
Speaker 3:  but is like that's how it should work.
Speaker 8:  That's a great example because one of the reasons that that's true is that
Speaker 8:  Evernote started late or started early if Evernote started later when
Speaker 8:  they were, when there were better developed, more reliable and
Speaker 8:  more widely understood strategies for blocking that reverse engineering
Speaker 8:  You know if they, if they were encrypting those databases, then bypassing
Speaker 8:  the encryption would be unlawful. If you could only access
Speaker 8:  those databases through an app that blocked scraping and
Speaker 8:  autopiloting, then they could use terms of service violations to stop you
Speaker 8:  from running something locally that just iterated through every note you
Speaker 8:  had and then spit it out. Right? So like it shows you that while
Speaker 8:  mandates are important, right? We, we, we we could, if Evernote were large
Speaker 8:  enough and, and enough of a hazard, you could imagine a future in which Evernote
Speaker 8:  was legally required to offer you an export tool, but
Speaker 8:  you don't actually need it. Some of the time, some of the time rival firms
Speaker 8:  can just work this out. And that's what Apple did with, with
Speaker 8:  Microsoft Office. You know, they, they, I was, I tell the story in the book,
Speaker 8:  I was a, a freelance CIO running You know the
Speaker 8:  networks for all these small and medium companies and a typical company would
Speaker 8:  have a 20 people with Windows PCs and a designer with a Mac.
Speaker 8:  And if you tried to send that designer a Word file, an Excel file or an office
Speaker 8:  file and they tried to open it to my Mac office, it would either not work
Speaker 8:  or then after they made changes and saved it, it would be corrupt or You
Speaker 8:  know some variation. All you had to do is like wave the Mac office floppy
Speaker 8:  around and files would spontaneously corrupt. And I just started, like first
Speaker 8:  I put PCs on those designer's desks that they used as dedicated office works
Speaker 8:  stations. And then when that became unwieldy, I put big graphics cards in
Speaker 8:  their PCs and got them Quirk and Adobe for, for their PC
Speaker 8:  and threw away their Mac and Apple figured out this was happening. And so
Speaker 8:  they just got engineers to reverse engineer office. And so we
Speaker 8:  get iWork suite pages numbers in Keynote that reads and writes the
Speaker 8:  Microsoft office files. And then the really interesting thing is what Microsoft
Speaker 8:  did because after a few rounds of aggressively
Speaker 8:  changing those file formats and incurring their own engineering expenses,
Speaker 8:  because then they have to update all their own Windows software, they sued
Speaker 8:  for peace and they standardized the office file formats, which
Speaker 8:  is why we have the X at the end of the XLSX and PPTX and Doc X,
Speaker 8:  which stands for XML. And this is why you can now past
Speaker 8:  style text between Word Google Docs,
Speaker 8:  web forms, You know Medium has a parser for it, right? Like if
Speaker 8:  you're composing on medium, I bet your CMS does, I know The
Speaker 8:  Verge has got its own CMS that you guys built from scratch, but you probably
Speaker 8:  just imported a, like a reference library for parsing out those things. So
Speaker 8:  you can compose in Word or docs and it just works. Yep. And so like at
Speaker 8:  a certain point when you have to use engineers to block
Speaker 8:  interoperability instead of lawyers, then you just give
Speaker 8:  up because lawyers solve the problem forever, right? Lawyers teach every
Speaker 8:  financier, every entrepreneur and every user don't trust
Speaker 8:  interoperable solutions engineers. They have to fight and
Speaker 8:  fight and fight and eventually they lose in these wars of attrition.
Speaker 8:  And so once you take away the lawyers, the company's sue for
Speaker 8:  peace,
Speaker 3:  At least as far as I can tell, like Mastodon and sort of what the
Speaker 3:  whole activity Pub world represents is like the closest ex
Speaker 3:  extent thing to the kind of interoperability that you're talking
Speaker 3:  about.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. And Activity Pub came out of the W three C at the same time as
Speaker 8:  all this bad standardization was happening. And it, the reason
Speaker 8:  that this good standard emerged without being interfered with
Speaker 8:  I think is that the big tech companies didn't believe it would
Speaker 8:  matter enough to sabotage it. It wasn't like they couldn't, it's just that
Speaker 8:  they chose not to and they could have submarined all kinds of
Speaker 8:  proprietary advantages and so on into it and they just didn't. And as a
Speaker 8:  result, we got this thing that just kind of snuck in under the radar. 'cause
Speaker 8:  no one thought it was important. It's a bit like what happened with the web
Speaker 8:  itself, right? Where like nobody took the web seriously enough when the web
Speaker 8:  came along. The fight was between AOL and CompuServe and
Speaker 8:  just like nobody took it seriously enough. So Tim Burners Lee was able
Speaker 8:  to make a thing that Microsoft didn't extinguish the way they were going
Speaker 8:  after Rival online services. And then by the time the web took off
Speaker 8:  enough, they tried afterwards, right? It became a success. And
Speaker 8:  Microsoft tried all these variations that You know, if you remember, there
Speaker 8:  was a time when MSN meant something new every six months. Yeah. 'cause they
Speaker 8:  would relaunch MSN as some proprietary thing that was like
Speaker 8:  the web, but not the web. It was Blackbird at one time. All this stuff. They
Speaker 8:  were just trying to lure people into locking into a proprietary technology
Speaker 8:  stack to extinguish the web. And like it just snuck in under
Speaker 8:  the radar. Nobody was paying attention to it. And then all of a sudden it
Speaker 8:  was there and it was like too big to kill. And
Speaker 8:  You know, I think that activity pub kind of fits that, that window, it just
Speaker 8:  snuck in when no one was looking.
Speaker 3:  What do you make of the fact that like Adam er is constantly
Speaker 3:  saying that Threads, which is not currently federated, very much a closed
Speaker 3:  platform is going to be part of, like, is that a, is that a company c change
Speaker 3:  or is that just a guy saying the right thing at the right moment?
Speaker 8:  Well, I, I think that even people of Goodwill can
Speaker 8:  talk themselves into doing bad things. Like let's
Speaker 8:  stipulate that Messer is completely sincere, right? But in
Speaker 8:  two years there's 400 million daily
Speaker 8:  users of threads and they just rationalize
Speaker 8:  that, opening those users up to federation would expose them
Speaker 8:  to risks that Facebook is currently able to defend them from, that
Speaker 8:  they have the You know moderation tools and the other things
Speaker 8:  that are needed to prevent disinformation harassment and so on. And that
Speaker 8:  federating will expose new risks to those users. And it's just
Speaker 8:  unfair to those users,
Speaker 3:  Which to some extent is not untrue. Sure.
Speaker 8:  Particularly if you have a bunch of users who become accustomed to
Speaker 8:  certain practices that don't take account of the
Speaker 8:  risks, but also the benefits of federation. And so you just drop them into
Speaker 8:  the deep end. And so the way that you protect your future
Speaker 8:  weak self is for your present day strong self to do something
Speaker 8:  that is irrevocable in that service. So like we call these
Speaker 8:  Ulysses pacs, right? Ulysses in the, in the tail, he's a hacker.
Speaker 8:  He doesn't wanna fill his ears with wax when they sail through the sea of
Speaker 8:  the sirens to prevent their calls from luring him to his death in the sea.
Speaker 8:  He wants to hear them. So in this moment of strength, before he is hearing
Speaker 8:  the sirens call, he has the sailors lash him to the mast and says, whatever
Speaker 8:  I do don't untie me so that I can live through this. I can experience the
Speaker 8:  benefits of my strength even in a moment of weakness. And we've all done
Speaker 8:  versions of this, right? You throw away the Oreos the night you go on a diet,
Speaker 8:  right? That's a form of Ulysses Pact. Open source licenses are a form of
Speaker 8:  Ulysses Pact. 'cause they're all irrevocable, right? Every time an IP lawyer
Speaker 8:  who hasn't, who isn't familiar with open source first encounters
Speaker 8:  on open or a free license like the GPL or even the BSD license or whatever,
Speaker 8:  they go like, oh, this is, this is dumb. They everyone must have missed this.
Speaker 8:  This should have a way for you to revoke the license later. And if you change
Speaker 8:  your mind, and that is not a bug, it's a feature.
Speaker 8:  Because when your investors come to you and say, well
Speaker 8:  this was cute, but if you want the 150 people you convinced to quit
Speaker 8:  their jobs and put their kids' college funds on the line to come work for
Speaker 8:  you to have a job next week, you're gonna make this open source proprietary
Speaker 8:  next week. And you can just say like, you're the boss, but I can't,
Speaker 8:  like, I just can't. And so you're for Facebook to say, well
Speaker 8:  someday this will be open. Trust us given the company's track
Speaker 8:  record as bananas, right? 'cause Facebook in 2006,
Speaker 8:  their pitch to MySpace users was like, you love
Speaker 8:  your friends, but did You know that the evil, crappy and Australian billionaire
Speaker 8:  who owns MySpace, Rupert Murdoch spies on you with every hour that God sends
Speaker 8:  Facebook is the service that will never spy on you. That was their pitch
Speaker 8:  in 2006, right? We are the surveillance free social media
Speaker 8:  platform and we always will be. And in 2008, they pulled their users
Speaker 8:  and said, we're gonna start spying on you. Is this okay with you? And they
Speaker 8:  said no, and they did it anyway. Right? So like, as
Speaker 8:  George Bush taught us, right? Fool me once, shame on me, fool me twice. We
Speaker 8:  don't get fooled again. Right? And, and You know what would be a more
Speaker 8:  compelling thing than promising to federate federating.
Speaker 8:  Right? And if they're not federated, then all it is is a
Speaker 8:  latent capability. And like computers are touring complete universal Von
Speaker 8:  Neumann machines. So every capability is latent in every
Speaker 8:  service, right? Like, unless there's some means by which
Speaker 8:  users can discipline executives who take bad choices,
Speaker 8:  then we should expect those executives to fall prey to the same folly
Speaker 8:  and rationalization that all of us are capable of.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. And I think it, it sounds like you're of the mind of there are sort
Speaker 3:  of two approaches. One is to essentially mandate that threads federates
Speaker 3:  like put into law that if you, you have to have activity pub. The other one
Speaker 3:  is blow open enough holes or make it legal for people to
Speaker 3:  blow open holes in such a way that someone else will do
Speaker 3:  it for them. And there's nothing that threads can do about it.
Speaker 8:  I think this is more like two part epoxy, right? Adversarial interoperability,
Speaker 8:  the right to reverse engineer and stuff. The the at EFF we call this
Speaker 8:  ComCom competitive compatibility. 'cause adversarial interoperability is
Speaker 8:  so hard to say.
Speaker 3:  ComCom is very good. Yeah,
Speaker 8:  ComCom is great. So ComCom is great but it is unstable,
Speaker 8:  right? Because you are finding a blind spot in the intrusion
Speaker 8:  detection system or the anti automation stuff and you're exploiting it and
Speaker 8:  you're making it work.
Speaker 3:  You're playing a cat and mouse game with thousands of engineers designed
Speaker 3:  to stop you.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, I mean they have to make no mistakes. You have to find one mistake.
Speaker 8:  You can stockpile 20 vulnerabilities and roll them out one after another
Speaker 8:  as they plug one and then the other. There are lots of ways that this will
Speaker 8:  be advantageous, but it is unstable. You know in the days when mints
Speaker 8:  started, You know they were scraping like 6,000 different bank websites
Speaker 8:  and if the bank took active countermeasures to block them that they couldn't
Speaker 8:  overcome, what they would do is if you were a mint user, they would just
Speaker 8:  pop up a message that says like, sorry Bank of America customer, we are no
Speaker 8:  longer capable of scraping this account. Here is the phone number of the
Speaker 8:  lawyer who sent us the c and d for Bank of America. Call them up
Speaker 8:  and tell them you're a Bank of America customer who wants to access your
Speaker 8:  own financial data, right? So there are lots of ways around this and
Speaker 8:  mandates. On the other hand, You know formal, formal requirements. As we
Speaker 8:  said, they're hard to enforce or administer, but they are very strong, right?
Speaker 8:  If firms actually huge to a standard, the standard works You know you
Speaker 8:  never buy AUSB cigarette lighter adapter
Speaker 8:  at a, in a fishbowl at a gas station only to find that it doesn't work in
Speaker 8:  your cigarette lighter receptacle in your car. It just standards really work
Speaker 8:  but they're brittle. So you have something that is very flexible but
Speaker 8:  but also doesn't hold very well. And then you have something that
Speaker 8:  is very strong but is easy to break and you combine the
Speaker 8:  two and you get two part epoxy. Something that is
Speaker 8:  resilient but strong. And that's, that's why I think we need to combine
Speaker 8:  both of these approaches and that's why we need to understand that what tech
Speaker 8:  has done through its regulatory capture is on the one hand get broad
Speaker 8:  latitude to abuse us and on the other hand create broad prohibitions on
Speaker 8:  self-help. And we need to reverse that circumstance so that we have broad
Speaker 8:  prohibitions on abusive conduct by tech firms, whether they're large or small.
Speaker 8:  And we have broad latitude as users to take measures to help ourselves.
Speaker 3:  After all this time and effort and Amazon purchases and docker
Speaker 3:  downloads, I've now built a couple of things that stick. I have a Plex server
Speaker 3:  which rules and I now use it all the time. I also now have all my notes in
Speaker 3:  a collection of text files and I'll never use another note taking app that
Speaker 3:  doesn't read and write to that folder of text files stored on my computer.
Speaker 3:  The two apps I'm switching between right now, if you're curious are note
Speaker 3:  plan and obsidian. Obsidian like we were talking about is super powerful.
Speaker 3:  But note plan's just really pretty So I just keep coming back to it. I also
Speaker 3:  still have image running, but Docker takes up too much memory on my computer
Speaker 3:  most of the time. So I mostly don't use it. I did rig up a way to use
Speaker 3:  my B Link mini PC as a universal file backup for all my stuff,
Speaker 3:  but I also still have everything in Google Drive too because cloud services
Speaker 3:  are great. It's much easier to get at my stuff in Google Drive. I just like
Speaker 3:  having options and I like that my stuff works now even when
Speaker 3:  AWS or Google Cloud doesn't or when I'm on the train and don't have any wifi
Speaker 3:  at all. I'm not really doing all this for big moral reasons
Speaker 3:  or because I'm afraid the cloud is going to get sentient and rule us all
Speaker 3:  or because I think we should destroy the tech giants. I just like my stuff
Speaker 3:  being my stuff and I don't think that's too much to to ask.
Speaker 3:  Alright, that's it for The Vergecast today. Thanks so much to everyone who
Speaker 3:  is on the show, and thank you as always for listening. This is the last episode
Speaker 3:  in our connectivity series. The whole series has been super fun. If you miss
Speaker 3:  the earlier episodes, go check 'em out. And we have another Fun Minis series
Speaker 3:  coming up starting next week, so stay tuned. This show's produced by Andrew
Speaker 3:  Marino and Liam James The. Vergecast is a Verge production and part of the
Speaker 3:  Vox Media podcast network. We'll be back with episodes on Wednesday and Friday
Speaker 3:  talking about antitrust trials and video games and lots of other stuff.
Speaker 3:  See you then. Rock and roll.
Speaker 1:  Thank you to Amazon Web Services for supporting Vergecast.
Speaker 1:  According to Deloitte, customers who choose AWS serverless
Speaker 1:  services can reduce their total cost of ownership by up to 57%
Speaker 1:  and reduce their development time by 68%.
Speaker 6:  The more you can leverage the capabilities that are already out there, the
Speaker 6:  faster you're gonna be able to innovate on behalf of customers and absorb
Speaker 6:  all the great trends that are happening in the market today. And that's where
Speaker 6:  a lot of the million plus customers we have on Lambda today see the value
Speaker 6:  and continue to users today.
Speaker 1:  AWS Serverless can help you get your applications to market faster
Speaker 1:  while reducing your total cost of ownership. Learn more at
Speaker 1:  Goss.