# Transcript
ID: 4e00e1e0-9501-11ed-8c7a-c317cd3b6bf2
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: CES is back! Sony announces a car, everything has Matter, and Lenovo puts screens on top of screens
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-412412238235871177/104212888187870652/s93290-US-4972s-1673806832.mp3
Description: CES 2023 is in full swing! The Verge's Nilay Patel, Alex Cranz, and Richard Lawler parse the vapor ware from the cool new tech we hope to see ship this year.
Speaker 1:  Today on the Vergecast, get excited at CES 2023.
Speaker 1:  Sony announces a car while everybody else updates their TVs and
Speaker 1:  Lenovo out of nowhere with the craziest laptop we've ever seen all
Speaker 1:  that. So much more. Coming up right after this.
Speaker 3:  Support for this episode comes from the Moen Smartwater Network.
Speaker 3:  Trillions of gallons of water flow through our faucets, shower heads and
Speaker 3:  sprinklers every year in the US alone. Moan is bringing a new level of intelligence
Speaker 3:  to every drop. Their Smartwater networks give you a complete control of the
Speaker 3:  water you use both inside and outside your home. Powered by a
Speaker 3:  new wave of smart technology. Their network protects against leaks, waters
Speaker 3:  your lawn with precision, and allows you to use your kitchen faucet with
Speaker 3:  just a wave. Learn more about the Moen Smartwater
Speaker 3:  network@moen.com. That's m o e
Speaker 3:  n.com.
Speaker 4:  Hello and welcome to Bridge Cast, the flagship podcast with
Speaker 4:  2023. The whole year.
Speaker 3:  The whole year.
Speaker 4:  Every morning when you wake up, think of me, Eli Patel,
Speaker 4:  editor, inchi of the Verge and your friend or Alex Kranz who is here.
Speaker 4:  Yeah,
Speaker 3:  I like, think of me or Richard.
Speaker 5:  Do you think of fake Eli? Like is fake Eli coming back? Because I hear that
Speaker 5:  those Twitter accounts are actually pretty easy to make.
Speaker 3:  Still fake Ne Eli could come back.
Speaker 5:  It's, it's just $8.
Speaker 4:  It's true. Jeffrey Fowler made another fake senator on
Speaker 4:  Twitter. Another fake verified Senator.
Speaker 3:  I need to make a new fake ne Eli using my work email address again
Speaker 3:  and my, my home phone number. It'll be fine.
Speaker 5:  Nothing bad could come of that.
Speaker 4:  If you have a Twitter account that's over 90 days old, but you want to donate
Speaker 4:  to Alex's situation, by all means ambitious. Reach out
Speaker 4:  to Alex. That's it. That's where the three of us are on the show. Welcome
Speaker 4:  back to 2023. We've been off for a couple weeks. We gotta see if we remember
Speaker 4:  how to do the show that we've been doing for years.
Speaker 4:  Fine. It's also c s the consumer electronic show's happening in Las
Speaker 4:  Vegas. We've got a big Verge team down there. I am not there for like the
Speaker 4:  first time in 12 years. I feel like the, the covid years that didn't go don't
Speaker 4:  count.
Speaker 3:  They don't. Absolutely not. So
Speaker 4:  I have like a 12 to 13 year run, many of which were memorably
Speaker 4:  spent with Richard Lawler as babies.
Speaker 5:  Memorably is probably not the correct word. No one can say for
Speaker 5:  certain,
Speaker 4:  What's the word for something you remember? Because you don't remember it.
Speaker 5:  There's a, there's a gap, but No, it's weird being at home. I, I found out
Speaker 5:  that people do things in the first week of the year that I had no idea about.
Speaker 5:  Oh yeah. Wild. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  There's all kinds of action. Like time does not stop and get Vortex into
Speaker 4:  Las Vegas. I will say, and Richard, I don't know if you feel this way,
Speaker 4:  I miss it and I kind of, there's a part of me that wishes I was
Speaker 4:  in Vegas. That part is very small and I am beating in
Speaker 4:  submission on the daily, but there's like stuff happening at CES this
Speaker 4:  year.
Speaker 5:  There's a person inside of me who only exists when I wake up in the, the,
Speaker 5:  the Marriott in Las Vegas. Yeah. And, and they are
Speaker 5:  dormant the entire rest of the year and just for one week they run free and
Speaker 5:  I'm not
Speaker 4:  Really sure it's like activated by 0% humidity. Like the air is so
Speaker 4:  dry that a different version of you comes out and it's like, what I need
Speaker 4:  is a vodka soda and some swirly carpets and
Speaker 4:  at least three full memory cards, SD
Speaker 4:  cards of photos of laptops. And that's who I really am. And
Speaker 4:  there's a part of me that's jealous. The other reason I'm jealous that I'm
Speaker 4:  not there is, this is de Bones first year at CES as a Google
Speaker 4:  executive. And I just, I just want to go to those
Speaker 4:  meetings. De I I miss you buddy. I mean I talk to
Speaker 4:  you all the time with his friends. I'm just saying I can't wait to be in
Speaker 4:  that position where I'm, where he's got like flax. Yeah. Like, you know,
Speaker 4:  like press handlers and there's
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Follow him around.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Oh my god. Ah, I'm missing it. And
Speaker 3:  They're like, no, no, you can't talk to him.
Speaker 5:  Just waving at him to stop talking every time he says anything. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I get, I can't. That's the one thing I really miss. So you just
Speaker 4:  texted, there is a lot of stuff coming out at ts. There's like a two year
Speaker 4:  pandemic hangover that appears to be breaking in terms of gadgets. A hundred
Speaker 4:  percent. It is the usual level of gadget announcements. Will the
Speaker 4:  stuff ever come out? Will it be any good? Will any of us remember this
Speaker 4:  a year from now? Who knows? But for this week of the year,
Speaker 3:  You'll remember the car. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  We got some kind of cars for, for this week of the year. If you're
Speaker 4:  into gadgets, this is like some of the most gadget fun you can have. It's
Speaker 4:  CS and there's just a wild array of gadgets happening
Speaker 4:  because this is matters first year. So there's a whole bunch of weird smart
Speaker 4:  home gadgets. Sony's like, we made a car. We'll get
Speaker 4:  to the car in a minute. Cars fully ridiculous. BMW is like,
Speaker 4:  we also made a car with tomato of ein and it talks just,
Speaker 4:  just like a fully ridiculous yess. And there's obviously TV news and there's
Speaker 4:  obviously other laptop news. I the Lenovo yoga
Speaker 4:  book nine i that's a two screen. It's beautiful and it
Speaker 4:  comes with a stand to make it super tall. I it's like, just like
Speaker 3:  What have you glued two iPads together. We'll get
Speaker 5:  To it. This is what happens when engineers stay at home for two years. They
Speaker 5:  have like crazy
Speaker 3:  IPads and nobody's there to be like, stop
Speaker 4:  A super gad Cs. We gotta talk about all this stuff. Real quick before we
Speaker 4:  start here is one piece of exciting Vercast 2023 news.
Speaker 4:  This is our first episode that we're gonna publish on YouTube
Speaker 4:  is audio only. We've got some cool graphics, some ideas.
Speaker 4:  We'll be publishing some clips if you've been on our YouTube channel or
Speaker 4:  our TikTok channel. You've seen, we've been doing clips and shorts of
Speaker 4:  the Vercast video. We'll be doing more of that. We're building towards more
Speaker 4:  video things, but we're actually just publishing the podcast on the
Speaker 4:  VER YouTube channel first. This is our first public one. There have been
Speaker 4:  some secret ones as tests over the past few weeks. This is our first public
Speaker 4:  post. We're really excited about it. We want your feedback. We know a lot
Speaker 4:  of people listen to podcasts on YouTube. So we're, we're coming to you. Let
Speaker 4:  us know how it goes and then let us know what you think of the, the clips
Speaker 4:  and how those are working. We've got, we've got big ideas to expand the show
Speaker 4:  into video and onto YouTube in particular. So some exciting news to start
Speaker 4:  the year. All right, let's start with this car. So Sony a
Speaker 4:  couple years ago announced a car at CS and it was the most
Speaker 4:  vaporware car that has ever existed. Like I don't think it even had motors
Speaker 4:  in it. There were just like, there were Sony, handful of PlayStation announcements.
Speaker 4:  Do you like Spider-Man? Here's our car. Sony at cs.
Speaker 3:  Was it, there wasn't even a physical thing. Was there?
Speaker 4:  There was a, there was a model of a car car. I don't know if it moved.
Speaker 3:  The idea of a car. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  There was, they showed videos of cars, of things that were supposedly cars
Speaker 5:  driving around.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And they were like, this was at the time when like the vaporware car
Speaker 4:  explosion was like fully happening. Yeah. So Sony asked this car, everyone's
Speaker 4:  like, this is vapor, it's never going anywhere. Then they announced a partnership
Speaker 4:  with Honda to make cars. And the name of the partnership is Sony Honda Mobility.
Speaker 4:  So you see this is just a very literal situation. Yeah. Sony wants to make
Speaker 4:  a car. Honda makes cars. Let's start a new joint venture. It's called Sony
Speaker 4:  Honda Mobility. Cool. This year at CS Sony holds
Speaker 4:  a press conference. Press conference is all over the place. I encourage you
Speaker 4:  to go watch it. It's like Sony decided not to announce TVs at cs,
Speaker 4:  which if you are an avid CS watcher, you know this is a big
Speaker 4:  deal cuz this is where all the TVs get announced. Sony's like, nope, screw
Speaker 4:  it. Opting out. We'll do TVs later. Here's the new PSVR two.
Speaker 4:  Here's some movie stuff. Here's a Grand Theresa movie. Oh and by the way,
Speaker 4:  we made it. Here's our car. And so the Sony Honda
Speaker 4:  Mobility car will be a new brand. I can't
Speaker 4:  even say it.
Speaker 3:  I feel ya.
Speaker 4:  I'm so mad at you.
Speaker 4:  It's called Aila, A F E E L
Speaker 4:  a and they shut off their first car, which you know,
Speaker 4:  looks like a shoe as all modern EVs do. Like a,
Speaker 4:  a cross between a Honda Accord and a Lucid Air.
Speaker 4:  Like all cars now have the same like light bar vibes. It's like a
Speaker 4:  low slung sedan. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  They don't look, they all look like Tom Cruise and Steven Spielberg designed
Speaker 3:  them in 2002.
Speaker 4:  What do cars of the future look like? This it, you know, like when you're
Speaker 4:  a kid and you like are learning how to draw a car and you draw like
Speaker 3:  This
Speaker 4:  Two wheels and a bubble. Yep.
Speaker 3:  This is what you draw
Speaker 5:  Because I could not actually draw different parts. So I just drew one
Speaker 5:  arc and then wheels.
Speaker 4:  So it's, it's called again, I wanna come back to the name a Aila, which if
Speaker 4:  you go and watch the video, you the poor man.
Speaker 4:  He's, you know, he's like excited and he is like our new brand and then he
Speaker 4:  is like aila and there's, there's just not applause because
Speaker 4:  no one believes that he said
Speaker 3:  It. No one applauses that Dave.
Speaker 4:  And the idea here is that Honda bill a car and
Speaker 4:  Sony will stuff it full of screens that run Sony software
Speaker 4:  and play Sony movies. That that's the idea. It's like very
Speaker 4:  clearly the idea.
Speaker 3:  I like one of
Speaker 4:  Those things. But then there's one screen
Speaker 5:  Who doesn't wanna pay $60,000 for a psp. Yes.
Speaker 4:  The front of the car. The middle of of the light bar. This is the thing that
Speaker 4:  I am absolutely obsessed with and I really encourage you to go watch
Speaker 4:  our super cut of this event. So there's the two headlights and then there's
Speaker 4:  the light bar in the middle of the headlights. Almost all cars EVs especially
Speaker 4:  have this like light bar element in the middle of the headlights now, right?
Speaker 4:  Yeah,
Speaker 3:  It's electronic.
Speaker 4:  Okay. That is Sony's like what if that was a screen, a straight
Speaker 4:  up screen in the middle of the headlights charging screen and then in the
Speaker 4:  presentation they show you the things a screen could be used for and
Speaker 4:  one of them is just straight up advertising for Spider-Man. No way. Home.
Speaker 4:  So you're driving around and you're a Fila and you've got
Speaker 4:  Spider-Man. No way home on the front of your car. You can also
Speaker 4:  display the weather, which I think is amazing to display the
Speaker 4:  weather to other
Speaker 3:  People. It's helpful for the people you like, just run on the
Speaker 3:  ass of other people on the highway. You're like, I need you
Speaker 4:  To know the weather backwards. So you would just be showing the weather to
Speaker 4:  people backwards in their mirrors. I mean it's, it's perfect example of,
Speaker 4:  look,
Speaker 5:  Viju V didn't happen. We had to make it, we had to do something. And this
Speaker 4:  Sony doesn't know why it's building a car. It's, it's just very obvious
Speaker 4:  that Sony has not yet figured out why it's doing this.
Speaker 4:  Honda knows why it's building an ev. Honda's got that part
Speaker 4:  locked down. They're Honda Sony's like what we're gonna add to it is
Speaker 4:  Spider-Man and screens. Where are some places we can put those things?
Speaker 4:  And one of the places they settled on was the front of the car.
Speaker 4:  It's very good. Yes.
Speaker 3:  Aila. Yes. Perfect. No notes.
Speaker 4:  Aila. Now my personal aila theory is that again during one
Speaker 4:  one, what is the word for this? When you have a memory that is defined
Speaker 4:  by the absence of the memory
Speaker 3:  A blackout. Like
Speaker 4:  You, I know I was in Vegas with Richard. I I know, I
Speaker 4:  know that. And then I know I was at home there,
Speaker 5:  There are expense receipts, but what happened? Who can say
Speaker 3:  What does the memory taste like? Does it taste like vodka
Speaker 3:  whiskeys regret? Yes.
Speaker 4:  All of all of the above. All of them. It, it, it, and, and I know that Richard
Speaker 4:  and I are friends for life because of this memory, but it, I got nothing
Speaker 4:  else.
Speaker 5:  And somehow in the middle of this, that's when someone said
Speaker 5:  Aila
Speaker 4:  No.
Speaker 5:  Or they, they wrote it down and then they found it later
Speaker 4:  Down. Everyone. No the what is the ultimate Vegas c
Speaker 4:  e s song in every presentation? It's, I got a feeling by the black
Speaker 4:  eye peas, You cannot be, you cannot be
Speaker 4:  in that environment without hearing that song. For there was at least two
Speaker 4:  years where like the words of Mazeltov rang out of every
Speaker 4:  CS presentation cuz they were just playing. I got a feeling by the Black
Speaker 4:  Eyed Peas and now we have a feel like, I swear to God this is
Speaker 4:  what happened. Like they, Sony and Honda were up in the club and
Speaker 4:  that song was playing and they're like, I know what it's called. And now
Speaker 4:  we have, now we have to talk about this seriously for months to come. Years,
Speaker 5:  Years. It's not coming out until 2026.
Speaker 3:  They cried a lot that night though. Like they hugged coming out.
Speaker 3:  It's not allegedly
Speaker 4:  They're gonna take start taking orders in 2024
Speaker 4:  and they claim that they will ship the first ones in North America. And
Speaker 4:  they said the second half of 2025,
Speaker 3:  Who are the people that are gonna order this?
Speaker 4:  I mean this is a pretty huge risk. I think what you, it's de-risked by the
Speaker 4:  fact that it's more or less a Honda, right? Yeah. Okay. So you you know that
Speaker 4:  they know how to make
Speaker 3:  A call. Yeah, Honda exists. They make cars, we drive them.
Speaker 4:  But then you've got this like Bonker Sony
Speaker 4:  integration where they're, and oh by the way the, the whole car runs Qualcomm
Speaker 4:  tech and so it's Qualcomm chip set, Qualcom,
Speaker 4:  Qualcomm autonomous driving Qualcom interfaces like
Speaker 4:  everything. So
Speaker 3:  How much battery life is it gonna get versus the Apple car? Like 30%
Speaker 4:  Less. It runs really hot. The camera though in, in
Speaker 4:  some situations is better. I love that there's a charging the screen on the
Speaker 4:  front. You can, it could be a charging indicator. They're throwing out the
Speaker 4:  idea of fully integrating at PS five.
Speaker 3:  That's what I've always wanted in my
Speaker 4:  Car. This is the single silliest CS announcement that I've ever covered.
Speaker 4:  And if you've been listening to me at CS for a long time,
Speaker 4:  you know that that is a high bar. We have covered some truly
Speaker 4:  bonkers CS products. One year Qualcomm hired the
Speaker 4:  cast of Billy Madison to jump around in,
Speaker 4:  in furry suits claiming to be the next generation of technology.
Speaker 4:  This is a real thing that happened. And this is by
Speaker 4:  far the silliest thing that I've ever seen because the entire point of it
Speaker 4:  Dish
Speaker 5:  Brought, brought a real kangaroo
Speaker 4:  Ones. That's true
Speaker 5:  For
Speaker 4:  Whatever. It's the entire point of this car is to get you to subscribe to
Speaker 4:  Sony software inside the car. I don't think this car's ever gonna ship.
Speaker 4:  That's just my, I'm just, I'm calling it. I do not think the will ever ship.
Speaker 3:  You don't think a car with an integrated PS five
Speaker 3:  and the ability to play Spider-Man on the grill
Speaker 4:  A will attempt to embody three main themes, autonomy, augmentation,
Speaker 4:  and affinity. It's bad, it's bad. I'm just telling it's bad.
Speaker 5:  Okay, wait. If there's anything that Sony's good at, it's launching subscription
Speaker 5:  service that's never, let's never fail. And so I
Speaker 5:  I'm yeah I'm taking, I'm taking the highest out on this for sure.
Speaker 3:  So you think people are just gonna subscribe to own the car?
Speaker 5:  You just like a Yeah. PlayStation Cloud and game
Speaker 4:  All. I cannot believe it's called dfc. I can't believe that we all
Speaker 4:  have to say it. I can't believe it. They said it. I can't believe they paid
Speaker 4:  some consulting company like millions of dollars for this name.
Speaker 4:  But
Speaker 3:  I can't believe we've only done one pun about it. I think like that's
Speaker 3:  very impressive.
Speaker 4:  It's just the beginning of the year. We'll we'll come back to it.
Speaker 3:  It's true.
Speaker 4:  So that's like, I would say this is the news outta CS is this
Speaker 4:  Sony Honda Mobility new brand of a car. It's what everyone is talking about.
Speaker 4:  I'm just calling it right now. This thing is pure vapor and we'll never ship.
Speaker 5:  Do you think they'll ever ship any kind of Sony car or just not this?
Speaker 4:  It's not this. And if you, even if you think about, we talked about this
Speaker 4:  show so many times, like this is not the kind of car that people
Speaker 4:  are buying. People buy mid-size crossover SUVs. So showing
Speaker 4:  up with your weirdo sedan, like you can't even get the tax credits for this
Speaker 4:  right now in the United States the tax credits are all for SUVs. Do you know
Speaker 4:  the Tesla model Y and the Mustang Machi aren't getting a tax credit cuz they're
Speaker 4:  classified as sedans. So good. I mean it's just fully silly.
Speaker 3:  Just put a lift kit on it, they'll be fine.
Speaker 4:  You like roll up to the IRS with your lifted model Y.
Speaker 3:  This is the SUV now.
Speaker 4:  All right. Other car stuff at cs. I'm just calling it if you believe that
Speaker 4:  Aila will ship, let us know if you work at Sony and you can
Speaker 4:  show us a working production unit of the I will,
Speaker 4:  we'll talk about it but it's, I mean it's called the Aila. Okay, here's my
Speaker 4:  other question. Will they change the name if it ever ships?
Speaker 3:  No, they have to keep
Speaker 4:  It. They're committed to it now.
Speaker 3:  I mean they will absolutely change the name but I think even now
Speaker 3:  we need to say you cannot change the name. You made your choice. You got
Speaker 3:  drunk at the club a couple of years ago. You bonded,
Speaker 3:  you agreed you can't no takebacks. It's a feel
Speaker 3:  will
Speaker 4:  I am outside of the trunk. He's like here I,
Speaker 4:  you promised me
Speaker 4:  all where
Speaker 5:  Is will I am? How is he not, how is he not involved in this after all the
Speaker 5:  tech stuff that he wanted? This is the most, somehow this launched and he's
Speaker 5:  nowhere to be found. That's suspicious. That is very suspicious.
Speaker 3:  Did they name the execs who worked on it?
Speaker 4:  No. If will I am worked on this, he would've been named a creative director
Speaker 4:  of a Fila
Speaker 3:  Theoretically,
Speaker 4:  Which is his title with all the things he works on. Obviously we once did
Speaker 4:  an article and I think the headline as Will I am is the Kiss of Death
Speaker 4:  because every tech product that he has ever launched as a creative director
Speaker 4:  has been a spectacular flop. Dan Sievert once published the headline
Speaker 4:  like Will I AM's bracelet? Like I don't want it to touch my body.
Speaker 4:  It's Dan Have you, you've encountered Dan Sievert before. He is not
Speaker 4:  prone to bursts of hyperbole. No. And he is like, I don't want this
Speaker 4:  thing near my body.
Speaker 3:  Like don't even wanna look at it. Touched his hair, he's upset.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It's been a couple years since we've covered a bad William Gadget.
Speaker 4:  This is his moment. All right, we should talking about bmw, the iVision
Speaker 4:  d it it talks
Speaker 3:  It's your friend because this was the one that had the Arnold Schwarzenegger
Speaker 3:  commercial attached to it, right? Yeah. Where he spends the whole time
Speaker 3:  talking about how they're gonna be best friends and then he like helps a
Speaker 3:  lady hook up with some dude and they never show the most interesting part
Speaker 3:  of
Speaker 4:  The car. Yeah. That that's CS in a nutshell is they have a celebrity. That's
Speaker 4:  right. They did a skit. They don't show you the product. Let me just give
Speaker 4:  you, so the iVision D is a kind of like a retro futuristic bmw,
Speaker 4:  right? It's got some like Camaro vibes in the front end,
Speaker 4:  like sixties Camaro vibes in the front end. But
Speaker 3:  It's got the ugly, everybody's doing these ugly hubcaps
Speaker 4:  That's that's just like, that means EVs.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, they're bad.
Speaker 4:  So iVision D stands for digital emotional experience. D e e
Speaker 4:  let me just read this word to you. The headlights and the closed
Speaker 4:  B M W kidney grill also form a
Speaker 4:  common fidget to dole icon on a
Speaker 4:  uniform surface allowing the vehicle to produce different facial
Speaker 4:  expressions. And what they mean by fidgital is
Speaker 4:  the combination of the word physical and digital.
Speaker 5:  They were supposed to launch an NFT with this, but then they canceled it
Speaker 5:  when the prices crashed and they couldn't get fidgital out of the press release.
Speaker 5:  That's what happened here because that's the only place where they use this
Speaker 5:  work.
Speaker 4:  It's, it's very bad. The whole point of this is that it
Speaker 4:  has this assistant and then, and the inside of this car, we don't really
Speaker 4:  know what the car is gonna look like or if it really exists because all the
Speaker 4:  pictures are renders. But the whole point of this is that it will
Speaker 4:  talk back to you and that your driver, you can create like
Speaker 4:  a metaverse avatar which can be projected onto the side window of the car.
Speaker 3:  Like those are all things I do not want in my life.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, this was the N F T card. This was supposed to have your, your ape on
Speaker 5:  the outside and then they realized they couldn't do that and they just, they
Speaker 5:  still had the car renders laying around and they had to do something with
Speaker 5:  it. They're like oops. They had, they had already mocked those up.
Speaker 4:  Wait, is that real? This was an N F T
Speaker 3:  Car so they just dropped it.
Speaker 5:  I mean that must be the truth because every single thing about it matches
Speaker 5:  with n ft reality mixed reality. You put your
Speaker 5:  avatar on the outside, this is a tokenized vehicle. This is
Speaker 5:  a metaverse experience from bmw. Right?
Speaker 4:  Like and then they just didn't say the N F T parts because that's
Speaker 4:  anathema right now.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Does it have the BMW logo on it?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Yeah. It's got the round on the front.
Speaker 3:  Okay. There it is. Very tiny. It
Speaker 4:  Is truly one of the strangest, strangest cars I've ever seen.
Speaker 4:  It's, you just gotta go look at the pictures. It's all renders. This is
Speaker 4:  the most vaporware car we have ever covered. Like it does,
Speaker 4:  even the prototype doesn't exist. It's great. I love it.
Speaker 3:  It's so goofy.
Speaker 4:  Anyway, BMW is a company that charging subscriptions for heated seats. So
Speaker 4:  we'll see if they're weird non nft N F T car succeeds.
Speaker 3:  But what's annoying about it is that there's one
Speaker 3:  part of it that is real and they, they did last year
Speaker 3:  and they, they they showed off in this giant render that kind
Speaker 3:  of like destroyed all of my hope in humanity. And that's that it has the
Speaker 3:  e ink panels that we saw last year but in color, I
Speaker 4:  Mean because
Speaker 3:  Like we saw the cars last year, they had real cars driving around
Speaker 3:  CES last year with real e ink panels in it. And this year they
Speaker 3:  have real fake cars driving around in real fake
Speaker 3:  reality with actual real e ink panels, which is this
Speaker 3:  new like tech called Prism three from ein. And that's
Speaker 3:  really, really cool and I'm really annoyed because that's actually really,
Speaker 3:  really cool. Real technology paired with like the
Speaker 3:  cartoon car with your N F T on the face.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I will say that the fact that there are no actual pictures of the
Speaker 4:  eye vision D makes me wonder.
Speaker 3:  It's just all in motion. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  It's
Speaker 3:  And there's no real person driving it. It's always a cartoon lady driving
Speaker 3:  it
Speaker 4:  Or it's like really far away. Yeah, I guess there's one picture of
Speaker 4:  a guy, but then like in this picture, the car is all white.
Speaker 4:  So again,
Speaker 5:  I'm watching this video and it's blowing my
Speaker 4:  Mind. Why is that?
Speaker 5:  I, I don't know why Al, I I don't know why, why the Terminator is here.
Speaker 5:  I don't know why.
Speaker 4:  Oh yeah, no you have to to go watch this video. This is what Alex talking
Speaker 4:  about. This is what saying at the start like this, the video is the most
Speaker 4:  CS thing you can watch.
Speaker 3:  The video is so
Speaker 4:  Good like Arnold Schwarzenegger's in it. But
Speaker 3:  They don't show the panels.
Speaker 4:  They don't show the panels and the, and except for the last shot where they're
Speaker 4:  like helicopter overing, they're helicoptering over the car
Speaker 4:  and then it's like rendering. Yeah I don't, I'm just saying
Speaker 3:  It's, it's not a real car
Speaker 4:  Two of the most but
Speaker 3:  The e ink tech is real.
Speaker 4:  The e ink tech is real but is it mounted on a B BMW that
Speaker 4:  exists?
Speaker 3:  So E no, but it's like
Speaker 3:  E Ink sent me, they sent me a whole thing talking about it. It's
Speaker 3:  their four particle ASEP system
Speaker 3:  and ASAP has two branches and one is what you get, which
Speaker 3:  is like E-readers. The new gallery, three color E ink
Speaker 3:  that's coming out later this year. And then the other side is
Speaker 3:  prism three, which is what is on this and it's
Speaker 3:  more like a mesh. It's not like actual panels. It's
Speaker 3:  really weird. And I was like, oh this is so exciting. Oh it's on a
Speaker 3:  fake car that will never exist and is all a cartoon.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I'm
Speaker 3:  Deeply disappointed.
Speaker 4:  I love it because I think the audacity of launching in
Speaker 4:  intensely vaporware cars at CS the, for a long time
Speaker 4:  the way CS worked was we would see the insides of cars at cs. Yeah
Speaker 4:  because that's where the screens were. And we would hear about like whatever
Speaker 4:  q and X software upgrade was coming to like Jeeps next year
Speaker 4:  and then a week later at the Detroit Auto show we would see the outsides
Speaker 4:  of cars.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And now we're just going for broke on What about what we just showed you
Speaker 4:  entire fake cars.
Speaker 3:  What did we just showed you? A lot of really cool renders at CES with our
Speaker 3:  big
Speaker 4:  Screens. That's a lot. Alright. Some other car news at cs. Some
Speaker 4:  good stuff here in Mercedes installing thousands of ev fast
Speaker 4:  chargers across the United States. You're gonna spend a billion dollars on
Speaker 4:  it in conjunction with ChargePoint. They're gonna install 400 of
Speaker 4:  these hubs each with approximately six charging stations. Key cities,
Speaker 4:  major highways. This is good, this is good news. They needed to do this a
Speaker 4:  long time ago.
Speaker 3:  Did you see the part of the, the press release where they're like, well we're
Speaker 3:  not gonna put it in like some weird by the weird dumpster in like a shady
Speaker 3:  area. These are gonna be nice charging points in nice areas.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I was like, oh is is that a problem now?
Speaker 4:  It's a huge problem now. Like
Speaker 3:  Are they just did like where are, where are the charge I I always assumed
Speaker 3:  the chargers were always in the nice areas cuz everybody drives Teslas.
Speaker 4:  Yeah the Tesla chargers are generally a nicer experience. Ian Some of those
Speaker 4:  are weird. Yeah but like your average Electrify America single
Speaker 4:  charger is like broken. They might be anywhere. Right? There's like
Speaker 4:  coyotes howling in the distance. Even if you go watch our,
Speaker 4:  our Ford Lightning review video, we went to the charger on
Speaker 4:  the highway and it was nice. I remember that dumpster.
Speaker 3:  That's
Speaker 4:  True. And you know I, I've talked to many car CEOs and
Speaker 4:  I always ask 'em about this and they've, they've been punting and I think
Speaker 4:  them admitting that the chargers are by dumpsters is an important sign of
Speaker 4:  progress. Like step one, admit the chargers are currently by dumpsters.
Speaker 4:  Step two spend a billion dollars putting them somewhere else.
Speaker 4:  So that's good news. A good bit of CS news for Mercedes there
Speaker 4:  other little stuff car-wise ring car cam. Wait, who
Speaker 4:  knows why anybody wants this? The little ring dash cam
Speaker 5:  People were really interested in this story and people
Speaker 4:  Love it. People love dash cams. Most dash cams are made up by weirdo brands.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. They love a dash cam and they're like oh I recognize this brand but
Speaker 3:  you don't want this brand Go get like your weird never heard of before
Speaker 3:  company
Speaker 4:  The
Speaker 3:  One better dash cams
Speaker 4:  One that isn't deeply embedded with the police already. Yeah
Speaker 3:  Great. Don't get the police one.
Speaker 4:  Anyway, it's finally shipping for 200 bucks. The rings dash cam 200 bucks
Speaker 4:  and then two little bits of Google
Speaker 4:  Android Auto News. I mean the first one is just hilarious.
Speaker 4:  They have Google put out a split screen version of
Speaker 4:  Android Auto for cars with wide screen displays a little bit ago and now
Speaker 4:  it's really not to everyone. And they made a little video. They're it? Yes.
Speaker 4:  Nice bit of Google News. It looks exactly like CarPlay, like
Speaker 3:  Just identical
Speaker 5:  CarPlay from like three years ago. Yeah. Like Apple figured this out a
Speaker 5:  while ago.
Speaker 4:  Yeah it's like, it's fairly funny that Apple and Google are in the cycle
Speaker 4:  of just fully copying each other and neither one of these things.
Speaker 4:  Is that good? Just put it out there. They're both
Speaker 4:  fine. That's it. They're, you cannot claim that they're anything
Speaker 4:  better than fine. Which is a a a meaningful step
Speaker 4:  over what most car manufacturers could do.
Speaker 3:  I was have to say they're better than what the car manufacturers do. Cuz
Speaker 3:  if I have to do Mazda's built-in system or
Speaker 3:  Apple CarPlay, I'm going Apple CarPlay every time the Mazda system's
Speaker 5:  Horrible. What you don't like Honda's 2011 Android tablet.
Speaker 5:  You're right.
Speaker 4:  This is like the curse of low expectations, right? You're like
Speaker 4:  our bar that we have to beat is Ford Sync
Speaker 4:  actively torturing you.
Speaker 3:  Just kicking
Speaker 4:  You the bar. We have to clear. Yeah. Is Mazda
Speaker 4:  deleting all the money in your bank account when you try to put in a navigation
Speaker 4:  way pointer like whatever it is.
Speaker 3:  Yeah,
Speaker 4:  It's a low bar.
Speaker 3:  They cleared it
Speaker 4:  And the fact and now that they're converging on the same sort of mediocre
Speaker 4:  like eh, that said Google has
Speaker 4:  new high res maps that it's putting out first in the Volvo X 90, the new
Speaker 4:  EV and in the Polestar three. And so you can see Google's
Speaker 4:  and you know the Volvo and Polestar both use like Android as the
Speaker 4:  infotainment.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Stack. So you can see Google's pushing harder into cars like they're
Speaker 4:  owning more and more acquires they're doing Google built-in. Did we talk
Speaker 4:  about Google built-in on the VER test yet and how deeply confusing it is?
Speaker 5:  Well it's funny because they're redoing the same thing that happened with
Speaker 5:  Android where you have Android and you also have Android with Google
Speaker 5:  services where you can get like Gmail or, or in this case Google Maps and
Speaker 5:  YouTube maybe in the future someday. Yeah. But everybody uses Android
Speaker 5:  but usually it's without Google apps.
Speaker 4:  Right? So like Lanis uses Android but without
Speaker 4:  any Google services. Then Honda just announced a new accord with
Speaker 4:  Google built in, which is something, I
Speaker 3:  Can't believe they're betraying Sony already,
Speaker 4:  But it's something they're running something. But with Google
Speaker 4:  services like Google Maps.
Speaker 3:  Yeah,
Speaker 4:  I think GM also has Google Builtin, which is something but with
Speaker 4:  Google Maps but un unclear whether it's Android automotive
Speaker 4:  and then Volvo and Pulse are run Android automotive, which is just Android
Speaker 4:  and plus Google stuff. So now there's just these tiers of like Google
Speaker 4:  being in your car and you can see Google's strategy is basically whatever
Speaker 4:  you want as long as it's us. Whereas Apple's strategy
Speaker 4:  is nothing.
Speaker 3:  Do they have a strategy? Remember we got to see the whole car play
Speaker 3:  just the way you, the exhaustion appeared on your face just then thinking
Speaker 3:  about it that split second of, no I don't want to and
Speaker 4:  Then it's gonna happen. Strategy of what if the front grill of
Speaker 4:  your car showed up to people the weather, which is good. It's
Speaker 4:  not, I mean it's it's a service.
Speaker 3:  It's helpful
Speaker 4:  For cars.
Speaker 5:  Where's the Samsung car? Why, why don't we have the Samsung car? Where's
Speaker 4:  That is strange that Samsung has
Speaker 3:  With Bixby in it.
Speaker 4:  Well I mean the the the, you know the the Hyundai group is there with Hyundai
Speaker 4:  and Kia and all the rest. Yeah that that's who was supposed to be making
Speaker 4:  the Apple car. You could see Samsung just to walk down the street. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  right there.
Speaker 3:  Well they were, they were busy.
Speaker 4:  Damn. They were busy. There's stuff going on providing the
Speaker 4:  chips to the Sony car that doesn't exist. Okay. That's car stuff. I
Speaker 4:  gotta say we started with the feel just cuz I wanted to get it out of the
Speaker 4:  way. I feel ya. I'm not so much on Twitter anymore but the number of people
Speaker 4:  who tweeted me that we had to talk about AF feel was very high, higher than
Speaker 4:  anything else. But CS a TV show, that's what it's really for.
Speaker 4:  This is, this is where the action happens in the TV world, right.
Speaker 4:  One memory I do have of Cs with Richard is the H T D V D versus
Speaker 4:  Blu-ray c e s, which was incredible where
Speaker 4:  the, this was gonna be the format war year at cs and then before the show
Speaker 4:  started, Toshiba just caved and they tore down the HT D V
Speaker 4:  D booth.
Speaker 5:  Wait you could actually see that. You could actually see HT D V D fall apart
Speaker 5:  in real time. In real life in front of I've I've never experienced something
Speaker 5:  like that before Because it was like you, it was like watching a dream die
Speaker 5:  except the dream actually existed.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It was truly bizarre. But this year CS a little calmer, A
Speaker 4:  lot of TV upgrades, some interesting ideas about picture
Speaker 4:  modes. Like we're in a mature part of a TV cycle, right?
Speaker 4:  We're not insisting Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Like HDR has come. Yeah, they got it. They figured it out.
Speaker 3:  Have
Speaker 5:  They figured it
Speaker 3:  Out? We're done. Like they're like okay we know we know what to sell you.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, I mean they, they figured out like they know that their new thing
Speaker 3:  is they can't just force you to buy a new TV because of 4k. So they
Speaker 3:  pivoted to H D R and they've now realized that's not exactly great.
Speaker 3:  So they're just gonna like kind of hang out and and improve the
Speaker 3:  TVs until they figure out some reason to really force you to upgrade
Speaker 3:  again. Like they're all really missing,
Speaker 4:  Which will be 3D again. It's gonna be Avatar two way of water is gonna hit
Speaker 4:  absolutely on streaming and it's gonna be 3D again. I promise you for
Speaker 3:  Like a week,
Speaker 4:  If you go back and read some of James Cameron's quotes about Avatar coming
Speaker 4:  out on Blu-ray in 3D and he was like, this shit's the future
Speaker 4:  from back then. Yes he got distracted. Yes, it's been like four decades
Speaker 4:  since that movie came out. But his heart is still pure. He thinks
Speaker 4:  home 3D is gonna happen and Avatar is gonna make it happen again. But it's
Speaker 4:  true, like Alex is saying, we are in a mature part part of the TV cycle.
Speaker 4:  Yeah hdr like I think Richard, the way I would say it is when
Speaker 4:  Apple caved and added HDR 10 plus to the Apple TV
Speaker 4:  because Samsung wasn't gonna break and add Dolby vision like then you
Speaker 4:  know like all the fights are over, there are no more fights, it's just
Speaker 4:  incremental. But there's still some stuff. Alex ATSC
Speaker 4:  3.0 news your favorite,
Speaker 3:  Very, very exciting news.
Speaker 4:  Can you just tell people what it is?
Speaker 3:  So ATSC 3.0 is the next like broadcasting
Speaker 3:  standard for the four of you and my mom who still watch broadcast tv.
Speaker 3:  I'm surprised she's not watching it in another room right now at her house.
Speaker 3:  It just, it's supposed to be better because you can not only get it
Speaker 3:  through like an antenna but you can get it through 5g.
Speaker 3:  So like you and somebody else can both be sitting together on your
Speaker 3:  couch watching live TV on your phone without having to go through
Speaker 3:  Spectrum or charter or whoever your provider is. Just watching
Speaker 3:  it over the air through 5g. So like theoretically really, really,
Speaker 3:  really, really cool right? But nobody's actually adopting it. There's
Speaker 3:  very few markets that have it. New York City doesn't have it and it's a whole
Speaker 3:  weird complex problem. We'll hopefully talk about more
Speaker 3:  on a future episode of this show. But like I'm in Dallas Fort Worth right
Speaker 3:  now, one of the largest markets in the United States. I think we've got like
Speaker 3:  one station that has it. And it's crazy cuz at T S C 3.0 is like
Speaker 3:  could solve so many problems but everybody's kind of figured out, no we don't
Speaker 3:  wanna do broadcast, we all wanna have our little fems that you pay a subscription
Speaker 3:  for. Yeah. So we're just gonna do that. Suck it. Broadcast slowly die
Speaker 3:  and broadcast is like, okay, ATSC 3.0 we're on 5G now.
Speaker 3:  And so that was the big news. They did a test a couple of weeks ago and they
Speaker 3:  announced it this week that they had like successfully shown off like
Speaker 3:  5G over the air broadcasting in a moving car.
Speaker 3:  Which is like kind of hard to do, right? Like if you've ever had to
Speaker 3:  mess with antennas in your house to watch broadcast tv, now imagine
Speaker 3:  doing that while driving 60 miles per hour down the highway. That's like
Speaker 3:  not easy to do. So it is kind of impressive technology but
Speaker 3:  the fact that none of the markets are adopting it is bad.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, well because all those local news stations are getting sucked up into
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I mean there's an entire like media ownership crisis.
Speaker 3:  Well it was interesting cuz one of the biggest ones was Sinclair. And Sinclair
Speaker 3:  was actually part of this big announcement. So they like Sinclair who's who
Speaker 3:  kind of has bought a lot of these broadcast stations, they're very committed
Speaker 3:  to like ATSC 3.0 but also it's Sinclair
Speaker 3:  who has a lot of issues.
Speaker 4:  They're yeah, they're also committed to not spending money.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. So we'll see. Come on it guys, you can do it.
Speaker 4:  I'm pretty sure there's one ATSC 3.0 broadcaster by my,
Speaker 4:  my house up in the woods and they have chosen to use the additional bandwidth
Speaker 4:  not for higher picture quality, but to shove more infomercials.
Speaker 4:  Yes. In like sub-channel of infomercials. It's very good.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, that was, that was part of it. They were like, oh yeah, we can do so
Speaker 3:  many more channels on a channel so you can get a lot more advertising. And
Speaker 3:  I was like, is that a good thing? And they're like, oh
Speaker 4:  Yeah, it's not a good thing. All right, let's talk about some actual TVs.
Speaker 4:  LG had a bunch of TVs. I actually wanna start not with their weird wireless
Speaker 4:  TV we can talk about for a minute, but with this picture modes thing. So
Speaker 4:  if you'll remember LG owns web os I feel like every year at CS is just
Speaker 4:  me recapitulating the last 20 years of tech history. So there was,
Speaker 4:  there was some
Speaker 5:  Webs isn't dead, it's still here like that. That we should celebrate that.
Speaker 5:  We should celebrate that effort. It should be a holiday, a national
Speaker 4:  Holiday. It's true. So the Palm Prix was announced
Speaker 4:  at, what am I doing?
Speaker 4:  In 2008 the Palm Prix was announced ats Mattias
Speaker 4:  Duarte who is now works at Google, is out of design of
Speaker 4:  of Android and Google. He announced the Palm Prix along with this
Speaker 4:  new system called Web os. You might have heard of it if you have ever listened
Speaker 4:  to this show before many things happened, including the complete collapse
Speaker 4:  of Hewlett Packard
Speaker 4:  And Web Os somehow ended up in the hands of lg,
Speaker 4:  which used it not to make phones but to put on their
Speaker 4:  TVs. And their whole thing was they needed their own. Basically TV
Speaker 4:  apps are all HTML five apps. Yeah. So they needed their own stack to run
Speaker 4:  HTML five apps. TV world by the way, is still the most fragmented technology
Speaker 4:  landscape in the entire like ecosystem. Like phones, like
Speaker 4:  Android and iOS laptops are like Mac Os,
Speaker 4:  windows and little Linux TVs are, Samsung has ties
Speaker 4:  in, LG has web os, a bunch of people have Android
Speaker 4:  from Google. A bunch of people have Android without Google. A bunch of people
Speaker 4:  have Roku and then there's like yet more infinity
Speaker 4:  craziness. VIO runs its own weird thing. So TVs are totally all
Speaker 4:  over the place. They all run basically HTML five apps. LG buys
Speaker 4:  Web West. Their big thing is they introduced a character. This is a true
Speaker 4:  story. Etsy S called Bean Bird.
Speaker 3:  No,
Speaker 4:  Who is gonna help you? This is true. This is real. Who's gonna help you set
Speaker 4:  up your tv? And the idea was that your TV was too hard to use and Bean
Speaker 4:  bird would help you. They've held on to this idea.
Speaker 4:  Bean bird may have disappeared, but the idea that the TV should be more
Speaker 4:  helpful and LG can help you set it up and then target more advertising to
Speaker 4:  you has persisted. Thank you lg. So now they've got this thing where instead
Speaker 4:  of doing picture modes, when you turn on your LG tv, it's gonna
Speaker 4:  show you images on the screen and then you then you can like click through
Speaker 4:  them and tell 'em which ones you like and then that will adjust your picture
Speaker 4:  settings and this is gonna result.
Speaker 5:  So it's like going to the eye doctor.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, it's the eye doctor. Which one do you like better? This one or the,
Speaker 4:  like you go look at the pictures on our, our side, you can see it. And this
Speaker 4:  is gonna result in the most bonkers, insane
Speaker 4:  picture settings on grandparents TVs of all time.
Speaker 4:  Like it's gonna be so bad, fully blown out hall highlights, massive contrast,
Speaker 4:  brightness, crank to oblivion.
Speaker 3:  It's gonna be the worst thing in the world. Like right now,
Speaker 3:  I'm, I'm watching a show I can't talk about yet on a, it's coming out on
Speaker 3:  H B O, it's beautiful touching story of a, a dad and
Speaker 3:  his surrogate daughter. And it is so damn
Speaker 3:  dark and every day my mom's watching it with me and she's like, this is dark.
Speaker 3:  I can't see anything. Can we turn the brightness up? And I refuse to allow
Speaker 3:  it because I've already calibrated her TV and I'm like, no, this is what
Speaker 3:  they intended and this is just gonna ruin the creator's intent. It's super
Speaker 3:  sad. Wow. But it's also, I guess it'll make people happier
Speaker 3:  with their sets. I know that our, our producer Liam was talking about
Speaker 5:  Will any of the automatic settings turn off the soap opera quick? Because
Speaker 5:  I feel like the answer is no. The, the TV manufacturers are just decided
Speaker 5:  that's how you're going to live unless you go in and
Speaker 4:  Change this. No, no. They have, they have film mode now. They gave Tom cruiser
Speaker 4:  mode.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, I hope it shows them a clip when they're having to
Speaker 3:  select. They're like, which one looks nicer to you? Minions
Speaker 3:  two in superfast soap opera mode or not.
Speaker 3:  And I hope they all choose the soap opera mode.
Speaker 4:  I think we're about to learn that one. LG is collecting a
Speaker 4:  ton of data with this feature. I mean LG is the worst offender when it comes
Speaker 4:  to running ads in their TVs. By far the worst. They're gonna have the da,
Speaker 4:  they're gonna be armed in the next meeting with like Tom Cruise and Christopher Nolan
Speaker 4:  that people like the Snow opera effect. And two, I think we're gonna learn
Speaker 4:  that people have just bonkers taste when it comes to picture quality.
Speaker 4:  So yeah, they need the reference modes, which they, they're starting to add,
Speaker 4:  but then they're, they're doing this new thing where people get, I mean you
Speaker 4:  should just pick, it's called the personalized picture wizard and it's gonna
Speaker 4:  show you six images and like step you through eight times
Speaker 4:  and you pick the one you like and there's AI involved and
Speaker 4:  a lot of TVs are gonna look completely insane.
Speaker 3:  What I don't get is why they don't just set everything in like
Speaker 3:  cinema mode, which is calibrated to, to be
Speaker 3:  exactly like what the calibration specs for all the people making it do and
Speaker 3:  then just change the brightness
Speaker 4:  Because people have bad taste.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, but like don't let them have taste.
Speaker 4:  All right
Speaker 3:  Steve Trucks remove options. Just be like, no
Speaker 4:  You're, I want you to do, I want you to charge your mouse on the bottom.
Speaker 4:  I know what's best for you.
Speaker 3:  I'm not asking that. I'm just saying, you know what, it's supposed
Speaker 3:  to look a little yellow.
Speaker 4:  All right. We should talk about other TVs. It is supposed to look a little
Speaker 4:  you. You're correct. Yeah. People want bright and blue.
Speaker 3:  I hate them.
Speaker 5:  It's exactly what we're talking about. So, and exactly what Alex is talking
Speaker 5:  about, Samsung with their new TVs, they've got luminal mode now.
Speaker 5:  Now we like we've talked about the settings, but this is like a, a technology
Speaker 5:  that they're building that it translates from Latin to return the light
Speaker 5:  that uses Samsung AI of course to dynamically outline the
Speaker 5:  edges of onscreen elements and rebalance colors. It's supposed to be supposed
Speaker 5:  to help people with low vision, but as you said, you're going to come to
Speaker 5:  your parents' house and you're gonna find out that they have this thing on
Speaker 5:  and you are going to see something that you have never even imagined could
Speaker 5:  exist on a display luminal mode. You're
Speaker 4:  Welcome. This is because we're all home from the holidays. We're all dealing
Speaker 4:  with it. But it's there. It never stops. It never goes away. I turned off
Speaker 4:  motion smoothing on a TV that I personally turned off motion smoothing two
Speaker 4:  years ago and it just came back and they denied it. They
Speaker 4:  said, we don't even watch this tv. And I said, now it's back and Lumino mode
Speaker 4:  is coming. We should talk about this wireless LG tv.
Speaker 4:  This makes no sense to me. So it's super expensive. It has
Speaker 4:  a breakout HTMI box. So you mount TV in your wall, it's got a super thin
Speaker 4:  power cord and then somewhere else in your room
Speaker 4:  you plug everything into this box which then transmits
Speaker 4:  wirelessly to this tv.
Speaker 3:  It's for the aesthetic.
Speaker 4:  I mean it's a 97 inch screen. We're assuming it will be
Speaker 4:  extremely expensive. The last time LG showed off a concept ago, this TV itself
Speaker 4:  was like a hundred thousand dollars In the end. I'm just saying if you have
Speaker 4:  the money for the intense concept, 97 inch
Speaker 4:  tv, that still needs power. You still have to hide
Speaker 4:  the power cable. Do you not have the money to hide another cable?
Speaker 3:  I think this is like they're just doing a really nice service for installers
Speaker 3:  who are realistically the people setting these TVs
Speaker 3:  up. Right? Like if you're spending the money to buy a 97 inch TV for
Speaker 3:  however much, this is gonna be thousands and thousands of dollars, you're
Speaker 3:  probably paying an installer to come in and install it and make it all look
Speaker 3:  pretty in your house. And this is just nice for those installers because
Speaker 3:  instead of having to like hide a whole bunch of cords, they have to hide
Speaker 3:  a cord,
Speaker 4:  One cord,
Speaker 3:  One cord, one
Speaker 4:  One cord
Speaker 3:  And it's, that's one less than Samsung on their old high-end
Speaker 3:  TVs which had the breakout box and like the fiber optic cord.
Speaker 5:  I'm just confused because didn't we do this already with like all those wide
Speaker 5:  eye demos we went to 10 years ago?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, but this is bad. I mean this is, they're sending 4K 1 20, 30
Speaker 4:  feet wirelessly, which is insane. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  The video would've been compressed then. This is uncompressed pure, it's
Speaker 5:  processed in the box. The only thing on the screen is the display and no
Speaker 5:  electronics or whatever. It's paper thin. Right?
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I can't wait to see what happens when your kid is like microwaving
Speaker 3:  some hot wings while you're watching a football game and it just craps
Speaker 3:  out.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I don't trust anything wireless as I think our readers know.
Speaker 3:  But I, I think it's, I think it's cool. Like I think if you can bring
Speaker 3:  this, we've started to see Samsung slowly bring this like breakout box
Speaker 3:  idea down into more affordable products. I say more
Speaker 3:  affordable. I mean like, what was it, the $3,000,
Speaker 4:  The frame TV was on sale for 800 bucks. This, this last
Speaker 3:  Black credit. Yeah, they, they they've, they brought those prices down and
Speaker 3:  if you could do that, the same with this, I personally would never do it
Speaker 3:  because I love wires, but for a lot of people, those people who like, like
Speaker 3:  to put their TV over their fireplace, even though you should never ever do
Speaker 3:  that. This is like a dream come true.
Speaker 4:  But you still have to run power. If you have to run a power cable, you
Speaker 4:  can run one H D M I cable.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, but what about their Xbox and their PS five
Speaker 4:  But that cable just, you run it into the breakout box, like the frame tv,
Speaker 4:  you connect everything.
Speaker 3:  So you're just saying we should just have the breakout box.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I mean that's what most TVs, they've just eliminated the cable from
Speaker 4:  the tv, the panel to the breakout box.
Speaker 3:  I know, but like there was a long time where people were like, why do I need
Speaker 3:  cordless headphones? They're bad and stupid and they still are and
Speaker 3:  people still love it.
Speaker 4:  We just did an entire episode on Bluetooth, Alex.
Speaker 3:  I know. And as everyone, everyone listening knows I know nothing about
Speaker 3:  Bluetooth. Nothing.
Speaker 4:  No, I'm just saying like the, the limitations I I just don't get it.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. If you have a hundred thousand dollars to put this TV
Speaker 4:  on your wall and you've gotta run power, what does
Speaker 4:  the breakout box get you?
Speaker 3:  One less wire.
Speaker 4:  One less wire.
Speaker 5:  You can play physical games without getting off the couch. You can
Speaker 5:  have everything, everything you've ever wanted. You can have your, your physical
Speaker 5:  media archives but you don't have to get off the couch to change the movie
Speaker 5:  of the game. It's, it's perfect. What could be better?
Speaker 3:  So you just have a big like tower next to your couch. It's gonna be great.
Speaker 3:  The future
Speaker 5:  When we're all still using this.
Speaker 4:  That said, we dunno what the input lag, they won't say what the input lag
Speaker 4:  is. Other, we'll just quickly go through some other stuff. Roku
Speaker 4:  announced its own TV line. The only thing I wanna point out here, this makes
Speaker 4:  sense. Roku's been making TVs in partnership with TCL for years now. They're
Speaker 4:  just putting their own branding on TVs. TVs seem like they're gonna be one
Speaker 4:  step down from TCLs TVs and just like the, they, they
Speaker 4:  won't talk about specs and that usually means the specs aren't gonna be top
Speaker 4:  of the line specs, right?
Speaker 3:  Yeah. They'll be cheap.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, they will be cheap. Chris Waltz wrote this up for us. He noted that
Speaker 4:  the person in charge of Roku's TV efforts, former TCL
Speaker 4:  executive Chris Larson. So they're just keeping that in the family. This
Speaker 4:  feels like gm, like some things are a Buick and some things are a Chevy
Speaker 4:  but they're all the same car. It seems like what's happening with, because
Speaker 4:  Roku's not making the TVs. They're definitely rebranding something. So it's
Speaker 4:  TCL or Hiene or whatever, who knows? But my guess is
Speaker 3:  Insignia,
Speaker 4:  Insignia is also rebranded, whatever.
Speaker 3:  Damn
Speaker 4:  It. Yeah. Insignias is the best Buy house brand I think
Speaker 3:  Whatever, whatever the insignia, what whoever they go to, that's who Roku
Speaker 3:  went
Speaker 4:  To. That's who Roku went to. Speaking of tcl, they've got new
Speaker 4:  branding. They're, they have much higher specs and they're
Speaker 4:  totally, they have decided that gamers are their market, which I think
Speaker 4:  is pretty interesting actually because we, I think we've, we have people
Speaker 4:  on this on our staff. We definitely, people like this on Polyon staff. The
Speaker 4:  number of people who in the pandemic now have like multiple TVs in their
Speaker 4:  living room. So they can game side by side is fascinating to me.
Speaker 4:  Richard just gave a very knowing look after the side of this room,
Speaker 5:  I, there are two TVs behind me for no.
Speaker 4:  So I think that's fascinating. And then Razor made a sound bar
Speaker 4:  that tracks your head in the room for, I mean this is gonna sound horrible,
Speaker 4:  but they've made a sound bar with IR trackers like a connect to figure out
Speaker 4:  where your head is and then do surround sound based on where your head is
Speaker 4:  in the room. N neither do you sound convinced by this?
Speaker 3:  I, I had, I had the original Leviathan and then I broke the,
Speaker 3:  one of the cords on it and they couldn't, they were like, no, we don't sell,
Speaker 3:  we don't have replacements for that. I even went to like the PR guy. I did
Speaker 3:  like the thing that you should never do as a journalist. And I was like,
Speaker 3:  do you know if, if you guys make these replacement cords because I personally
Speaker 3:  want one. And he's like, no we don't. I can get you one. And I was like,
Speaker 3:  no, I I'm not gonna take one that you like just go and take out of another
Speaker 3:  box. You should just make these. So I, I'm, I'm I'm over
Speaker 3:  razor soundbars.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Well this one is looking for your head with infrared. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Even more over this particular
Speaker 4:  One and it will find you. We actually didn't talk about Samsung. Samsung
Speaker 4:  as always announced a ton of TVs and Chris Welch
Speaker 4:  I think dropped this story into Slack when he was done writing. He was like,
Speaker 4:  this is Eli's nightmare. Samsung is like all in
Speaker 4:  on AI picture tricks all in on remapping
Speaker 4:  SDR to H D R content. All in on more
Speaker 4:  processing enhancements just in general.
Speaker 4:  We've like hit the point where the panels are all pretty good and so
Speaker 4:  now all the effort to differentiate the panels is happening on the backend
Speaker 4:  and software and yeah, I would say well it's just correct. This feels like
Speaker 4:  my nightmare cuz it's all just weird processing tricks across the board.
Speaker 4:  Turn it off. All I really want is just show me the movie
Speaker 4:  as it was intended to be seen.
Speaker 3:  Please.
Speaker 5:  What if we didn't do that?
Speaker 4:  Auto HD R Remastering uses AI deep learning technology to analyze
Speaker 4:  and apply realtime HDR effects on standard dynamic range content on a scene
Speaker 4:  by scene basis. It's like
Speaker 3:  I don't want that,
Speaker 4:  I really don't want you to do that. But people love really bright pictures.
Speaker 4:  We'll see how it goes. See you know Samsung now is like everywhere,
Speaker 4:  right? They're making standard LCDs. They're making micro LEDs and they're
Speaker 4:  making ods.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, they're like just a full stack. Yeah. Are they good?
Speaker 3:  Do you wanna own one for more than a year remains to be seen.
Speaker 4:  Here's my question. Is this final, like I have a
Speaker 4:  early, I think a B seven  six lg
Speaker 4:  It's totally fine.
Speaker 3:  This the year,
Speaker 4:  You think this is the year?
Speaker 3:  This is the year because I have a B seven and I don't wanna be alone when
Speaker 3:  I go and upgrade mine. So do it. Eli
Speaker 5:  Welch gave you the, the reason the he, he gave you the reason to get the,
Speaker 5:  the new one this year. The one thing that we haven't talked about. What if,
Speaker 5:  what if they had had a software upgrade that was good? There's something
Speaker 5:  that changed in Web West that he does. Like the way the notifications pop
Speaker 5:  up. Oh so it they not
Speaker 5:  everything is bad or the worst and some of the H D M I 2.1 features.
Speaker 5:  Maybe they'll even work this year. Yeah, we'll have hope.
Speaker 4:  I have hope. You gotta at least wait for QD OED to
Speaker 4:  like
Speaker 1:  Actually spread out. Like so far it's just Sony with their highest end model,
Speaker 1:  which I know they bought from LG display but like not even
Speaker 1:  LG is making a TV with QD O lead yet. I would, I would wait for
Speaker 1:  that.
Speaker 3:  I'm just gonna get a reference monitor.
Speaker 4:  Yeah it's just like this TV's definitely good enough and I mostly watch like
Speaker 4:  ultra compressed streaming content like you know
Speaker 4:  it's
Speaker 3:  Fine.
Speaker 4:  All right. Alex put together a plex server of only the finest
Speaker 4:  uncompressed blue hair rips.
Speaker 3:  I got
Speaker 5:  You. We're gonna be watching Big Bunny for hours
Speaker 3:  All will they all be from the 1930s Probably.
Speaker 4:  We the public domain with Alex Grant.
Speaker 4:  Very good. There were look there was a bunch of other CS display stuff. Samsung
Speaker 4:  had a bunch of Rolly Foldy displays, lots of prototypes.
Speaker 4:  Hard to talk
Speaker 5:  Dell six K.
Speaker 4:  Oh yeah, there actually a bunch of people came at the pro display. Xdr,
Speaker 4:  Dell and Samsung. Samsung K
Speaker 4:  5K display. Dell had the 32 inch 6k. That's pretty cool.
Speaker 4:  It's neat to see a little competition in there. Like I said, CS is display
Speaker 4:  show, so go look on the site. It's hard to talk about displays especially
Speaker 4:  go look at all the Samsung prototypes cause they're cool as hell. They're
Speaker 4:  just not products and I think the TV market is super mature. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  like the answer is like if you want a tv, they're, you're not waiting for
Speaker 4:  anything better right now, like you might as well, which is how I justify
Speaker 4:  all multi-thousand dollars purchases. It's
Speaker 3:  Gonna be a huge game changer. Next year
Speaker 5:  We need the new TV because it will have the NFT app store. We're going crypto
Speaker 5:  this year. That's my, that's my goal. I'm going to sell all of you
Speaker 5:  tokens. We're going to do this together. We're not going to let crypto, we're
Speaker 5:  not going to let
Speaker 3:  The fire sale on FTX tokens. Go stock up, Richard.
Speaker 5:  Well, once the marketplace is reopened in, we can access thing. Yes, we
Speaker 5:  we're having a little problem, but it'll be fine.
Speaker 4:  Alright. Like I said, see has a display show lots of TV news. Chris
Speaker 4:  Welcher's done an amazing job. If you want all the details on the stuff,
Speaker 4:  go read his coverage. Go look at the tos of displays folding.
Speaker 4:  We gotta take a break. We can come back. There's still more. There's desktop,
Speaker 4:  there's laptops. I'm sure Richard will find a way to make that about crypto
Speaker 4:  too. We'll be right back.
Speaker 3:  Support for this episode comes from the Moen Smartwater network. MO
Speaker 3:  is ushering in the next wave of water technology with their smartwater network.
Speaker 3:  It gives you total control of water inside and outside your home with smart
Speaker 3:  technology that helps you get more out of every drop, create cooking and
Speaker 3:  shower presets, prevent plumbing disasters, and now never worry about over
Speaker 3:  or underwater in your lawn. The latest addition to the Smartwater network,
Speaker 3:  moan smart sprinkler controller, takes the guesswork outta lawn care set
Speaker 3:  custom water schedules that account for weather and seasonal information
Speaker 3:  so your system won't flood the lawn on a rainy day. Let the smart wireless
Speaker 3:  soil sensors determine which zones of your lawn need water and which ones
Speaker 3:  don't control it all in the palm of your hand with Moens powerful app,
Speaker 3:  part of the Moen Smartwater network. Learn more about the Moen Smartwater
Speaker 3:  network@moen.com. That's m O E
Speaker 3:  n.com.
Speaker 4:  All right, we're back. There's still more CS stuff to talk about.
Speaker 4:  It does feel like I'm a little drunk, you know, I'm not, get a little
Speaker 4:  but just
Speaker 3:  Little vodka
Speaker 4:  Talking about gadgets in Vegas for long enough. You get a little, takes you
Speaker 4:  to
Speaker 3:  A place, get a little tipsy,
Speaker 4:  Get a little out there.
Speaker 3:  Suddenly you're just smelling cigarette smoke and you don't know why you're
Speaker 3:  having a great time.
Speaker 4:  I got a, a text from an unnamed former colleague
Speaker 4:  and all it said was, I'm jonesing for a Juul.
Speaker 4:  And I realize that I was, and I have it in years
Speaker 4:  and it's just, I think my body expects nicotine in early
Speaker 4:  January. Yeah. Because of cs.
Speaker 3:  It's just gotten used
Speaker 4:  To it. It's just, this is when you smoke, bro. Like
Speaker 4:  where are we at,
Speaker 3:  Liam? What are you doing? Just vaping furiously.
Speaker 4:  That's horrible. Don't vape kids. Don't listen to us. Turn this off.
Speaker 4:  Get out of your car and run away from us a md Announce
Speaker 4:  a bunch of stuff. Alex, take us through it.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, they announced a lot of stuff amd this is kind of a big show for them
Speaker 3:  and they usually save some really big stuff for it. One of the big things
Speaker 3:  they announced is like a really fast mobile gpu.
Speaker 3:  The RX 7,600 M it's expected this
Speaker 3:  year in 2023. And they're promising basically
Speaker 3:  Nvidia 30 60 desktop performance
Speaker 3:  in a laptop, which is like really, really nice.
Speaker 3:  We're, we're not right quite at like 4K a hundred frames per
Speaker 3:  second, but we're definitely at that for 10 80 p So, which is
Speaker 3:  what a lot of laptops are at right now. So this is like
Speaker 3:  gonna be pretty fast. It's a nice bonus, but we don't know
Speaker 3:  what that power consumption is gonna look like and just how
Speaker 3:  much battery life these things are gonna crush. I predict
Speaker 3:  a lot. Yeah. AMD's gotten a lot better at this, but they're still
Speaker 3:  not like, they're not Apple. Apple is just schooling everybody when it
Speaker 3:  comes to power and, and performance. But,
Speaker 4:  But not necessarily on the GPU side.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, but I mean kind of even in the GPU side, right? Like
Speaker 3:  it's not at the same level and, and Apple GPU is not gonna
Speaker 3:  ever give you the same performance or an Apple chip isn't gonna give you
Speaker 3:  the same performance as one of these discreet graphics chips, but
Speaker 3:  it's still like the, the power consumption is still gonna be problem. This
Speaker 3:  is still probably not gonna be a 10 hour laptop, right? I mean,
Speaker 3:  I hope it is, but I I highly doubt it. And then the other, the
Speaker 3:  other big news was new CPUs all
Speaker 3:  Yeah. New mobile processors. This is, they've got including one that's
Speaker 3:  got a 16 core chip, which isn't quite as many
Speaker 3:  as one of the newer Intel mobile processors, which has a 24
Speaker 3:  core chip. And it's very, but it is very funny because these guys are still
Speaker 3:  talking about cores and apples over here being like, no, we don't even
Speaker 3:  have to talk about that anymore. We've moved beyond that. Like, sorry, I'm
Speaker 3:  just, I'm using a MD time to stand about Apple and I feel really bad about
Speaker 3:  it. But the Apple,
Speaker 4:  You're gonna get called out for this.
Speaker 3:  I, I am, but the processors are good.
Speaker 5:  Well, I mean it's, it's interesting what they're doing here because it, it's
Speaker 5:  only 16 cores, but it's not like Intel's kind of big little
Speaker 5:  arm star arm style approach they're using on the new chips. Like they're
Speaker 5:  all 16 are are all big cores I guess, or like two, it's like
Speaker 5:  two full eight core chips squeezed into one is, is what is described
Speaker 5:  as.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Yeah. I think we're starting to, I think what we're gonna, we're
Speaker 3:  we're starting to see and we're gonna continue to see is that a m d
Speaker 3:  has gotten a lot of work out of infinity
Speaker 3:  fabric, right? Like they've gotten a lot of play over the last six years
Speaker 3:  out of infinity fabric, which has let them to just bolt GPUs and CPUs
Speaker 3:  together just bolt core after core after core onto these processors and
Speaker 3:  get a lot of power. And everybody else has
Speaker 3:  really started to pivot in this other direction, this big little core. And
Speaker 3:  AMD is doing a little bit of that too across the board, but they're a little
Speaker 3:  behind. I'm, I'm kind of worried. I, I know they've talked a number of people
Speaker 3:  have talked to Lisa Sue, the CEO being like, are you guys
Speaker 3:  falling behind again? Are we about to see, are we gonna get another bulldozer
Speaker 3:  in a year or two? And obviously she's saying no, they're not going
Speaker 3:  to drop the ball catastrophically. And we're seeing
Speaker 3:  a lot of work like good work in that mobile space, right? Like this steam
Speaker 3:  deck uses an AMD processor and their
Speaker 3:  laptops have gotten a lot better, but they still get a lot of catching up
Speaker 3:  to do. I would say they're still better than Intel for the most part. Like
Speaker 3:  these processors are still gonna be faster if you can find them in a product
Speaker 3:  than the Intel processors. But a lot of people are really going, no,
Speaker 3:  I want something that is fast and has really good battery life. I don't necessarily
Speaker 3:  care about having the fastest thing in the world in a mobile
Speaker 5:  Check. And how will they find it with these names? Yeah, because I feel like
Speaker 5:  we haven't got enough credit. They changed the naming scheme for the processors
Speaker 5:  this year. Oh
Speaker 3:  My god. You, you don't like the names.
Speaker 5:  So everything is a 7,000 series this year and then the
Speaker 5:  the third number tells you how good it is and not the first
Speaker 5:  number like it used to be.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Like you have, you have to read a chart to figure out what the numbers mean
Speaker 5:  now. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Everything is a, I'll just read from Monica's post here.
Speaker 4:  The potential star of the show is the quote dragon range Zen four
Speaker 4:  risen 9 79 45 HX
Speaker 4:  rolls
Speaker 5:  Right off the, their new naming scheme. I
Speaker 3:  Mean change, that's the way they've always done it though. No, I, yes.
Speaker 4:  This is what
Speaker 3:  They've changed. Make sure this is the same naming scheme, right? They've
Speaker 3:  always had the first numbers, the generation,
Speaker 5:  They changed the, it's always been numbers like this, but they changed the
Speaker 5:  way that the numbers go. It's still four letters and then it's still four
Speaker 5:  numbers and then a letter. But the, it's the first number is the portfolio
Speaker 5:  year. So it's seven this year for 2023. The second number is market
Speaker 5:  segment. So like the most powerful ones are nine. One is
Speaker 5:  the one that you shouldn't buy. The third number is the Zen architecture.
Speaker 5:  So like one, two, or three. And then the fourth number is, I, I
Speaker 5:  don't know what that fourth number is. I, I don't know. Feature isolation.
Speaker 5:  You I I'm done. I I've got nothing.
Speaker 3:  It's a five.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It's deeply confusing. And the good news is
Speaker 4:  the people who buy the chips directly to install
Speaker 4:  in PCs directly will figure it out. Right? If you're, if you're out there
Speaker 4:  just like buying bare CPUs, you're gonna, you're gonna figure this out.
Speaker 5:  Maybe AMD had some problems with the wrong names on their
Speaker 5:  CPUs during the press conference. As Tom Warren noted, they repeatedly
Speaker 5:  called them the wrong thing. So what's driven laptop you get no
Speaker 4:  Assurances. So AMD it's, but by, hopefully by the time they arrive on
Speaker 4:  store shelves or your favorite online retailer, they'll figure it out. They'll
Speaker 4:  be charts, whatever. It's the companies, it's the
Speaker 4:  OEMs need to figure this out and then market the chips appropriately. At
Speaker 4:  the same time, I think, is this a MD chip faster than that Intel chip?
Speaker 4:  Impossible for the regular person to know at this moment in time. Especially
Speaker 4:  TAs explain
Speaker 3:  About that. Well, impossible to even test. Yeah. Like for the mobile chips,
Speaker 3:  it's kind of, it's a tossup cuz you can't do just an apple
Speaker 3:  to apples. Nobody's gonna be making the exact same laptop and just
Speaker 3:  switching out processors anymore.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. That said, enough of the laptops at CS are basically using the same
Speaker 4:  chips and the same that like the features that we're
Speaker 4:  competing on it, which it very much echoes the, the TV conversation.
Speaker 4:  Like everything has gotten to a place of like being good enough for Sammy
Speaker 4:  enough that we're now differentiating on absolutely bonkers features.
Speaker 4:  Which brings me, sorry, I just, I I can't be talking about
Speaker 4:  rising chips. When Lenovo was out there, Lenovo
Speaker 4:  has a bunch of stuff. Lenovo has a new think book which with modular accessories
Speaker 4:  like an LTE module, webcam, light, all this other stuff. A cool new all in
Speaker 4:  one with like a really neat stand looks. They made a, a phone, the
Speaker 4:  ThinkPad phone, which, well, none of this matters. The only reason that we're
Speaker 4:  doing this show today, the yoga book,
Speaker 3:  Eating
Speaker 4:  Tablet, not the ING tablet. They're weird Kindle scribe that no one will
Speaker 4:  like except for Alex. It's the yoga book nine I, which is a
Speaker 4:  dual screen laptop that has a stand that lets you
Speaker 4:  stand both screens up in portrait configuration.
Speaker 4:  Oh yeah. And then like a removable keyboard that comes with it.
Speaker 4:  And then just, you gotta watch this video. Go watch the video. Monica's like
Speaker 4:  over the moon about this thing. It looks so cool.
Speaker 3:  It looks like they've done this before. iPads.
Speaker 4:  Yeah,
Speaker 3:  Like this. I like, I'm really excited cuz we've been seeing this
Speaker 3:  exact like concept for years.
Speaker 3:  For a while you couldn't go to a single meeting with AMD or
Speaker 3:  Intel without them showing off a concept like this and being like, dual
Speaker 3:  screens are coming. Microsoft was doing it too. Everybody would have these
Speaker 3:  big meetings and they would show off this exact concept, but janky as
Speaker 3:  hell. And this is like slightly less janky,
Speaker 4:  Dual 13.3 inch ed touchscreens coming
Speaker 4:  aboard
Speaker 3:  Coming. It's, you can actually buy it.
Speaker 4:  Extremely weird vertical stand. This thing is
Speaker 4:  so like, I'm just like, watch this video, watch this video. A slight remove.
Speaker 4:  You've all seen Monica, you've watched her review video, video. She's been
Speaker 4:  on the show. She's so captivated though by this thing that she's like,
Speaker 4:  check out this easy 10 finger swipe.
Speaker 4:  It's like, I dunno about that.
Speaker 4:  It's great. The thing looks amazing. This is like what? Why CS
Speaker 4:  exists is this laptop. It's so, I can't wait to buy one. I'm
Speaker 4:  100% gonna buy one and then realize that I have no need for this at all and
Speaker 4:  not use it, but just look at the configurations.
Speaker 3:  Are you gonna return it like, like do we need to just time how long it takes
Speaker 3:  you to to return it?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I mean I'm gonna have it, I just,
Speaker 4:  just like look at it. You can put the, you can open it and then have both
Speaker 4:  screens in portrait. So you like turn it sideways
Speaker 3:  So you can read like a magazine.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Or like one full screen slack and one full screen doc and the keyboard's
Speaker 4:  in front. You can swipe the, you can. And when the bottom screen is the,
Speaker 4:  the keyboard, you can swipe the keyboard down to have keyboard in the front.
Speaker 4:  And then you get a variety of status indicators that Lenovo thinks are important,
Speaker 4:  but which are not important. It's so good. It has
Speaker 5:  Haptic. So it feels like you're typing when you're
Speaker 4:  Typing. Yeah. There's no way that a laptop size touching keyboard is going
Speaker 4:  feel good with its haptics.
Speaker 4:  $2,100 13th of Jan Intel core. I said
Speaker 4:  blah 16, 16 gigs of rando and it's come,
Speaker 4:  it's gonna ship in June as a pen. This is the future. You whatever
Speaker 4:  ein nonsense. You think you love it.
Speaker 3:  I think the most exciting thing about it is that the case and the
Speaker 3:  pin and the keyboard are included.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  That like, that was the part I was like, Doug,
Speaker 4:  It's it's a steal. How can you afford not to buy a Lenovo
Speaker 3:  Book? Yeah. Instead of 2,500, it's 2000 for everything. Beautiful.
Speaker 4:  I can't even get the name right. I'm so excited about it. How could you not
Speaker 4:  buy a Lenovo yoga book Night Eye in the market for a Bluetooth
Speaker 4:  keyboard? Have you considered the Lenovo yoga book Night Eye, which comes
Speaker 4:  with a full laptop with dual 13.3 inch os. I want it so badly.
Speaker 4:  It's like when I'm like, I kind of miss not being Cs like
Speaker 4:  the sensation of walking into a hotel suite that has been arranged
Speaker 4:  to display hundreds of laptops and like weird breakout boxes for tv.
Speaker 4:  Is it? No. Like I can smell that room. You
Speaker 3:  Can smell that.
Speaker 4:  The crackle of old coffee. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Yes. Mm. That one like coffee
Speaker 3:  fruit salad in the corner kind of getting a little old. It's beautiful.
Speaker 4:  No one ever. It's the fruit salad. I
Speaker 5:  Just, I'm, I'm envisioning getting on a plane with this and, and pulling
Speaker 5:  out my dual stack oles in front of me that that reach
Speaker 5:  above my head. Yeah. And
Speaker 4:  I'm not, no, first what you do is you wa you walk up and down the aisle of
Speaker 4:  that plane finding the one dude with the Samsung Galaxy fold
Speaker 4:  who's hot shit. Cuz that person is on every plane. Now. There's one dude
Speaker 4:  with a stylist in a Galaxy fold who's like, hmm, ho, ho ho, right? And
Speaker 4:  then you, then you pull out your yoga book just full
Speaker 4:  vertical unfold. You throw your keyboard in his lap, you start typing with
Speaker 4:  your foot while you hold that thing up like a scroll.
Speaker 3:  Don't even sit down
Speaker 4:  If I'm ever gonna get kicked off a plane. That's how I'm going out. I'm not
Speaker 4:  doing any of this like comfort animal stuff I'm
Speaker 4:  doing.
Speaker 4:  I'm doing old time navigator. One foot in the air on a keyboard
Speaker 4:  holding up a double stack ole display. All right.
Speaker 4:  That's enough. Other, do you wanna talk about this
Speaker 4:  Kindle scribe?
Speaker 3:  I mean it's, it's better than the Kindle scribe because it can, it actually
Speaker 3:  lets you do more note taking stuff. But it's also worse
Speaker 3:  in that it doesn't have an app store. It has, it runs Android but it
Speaker 3:  doesn't have an app store. You can't side load a lot of image types, a lot
Speaker 3:  of book types. It's very, very hamstrung. It's very
Speaker 3:  clearly meant less for people who wanna read and
Speaker 3:  more for like people who used to buy the Sony ePaper tablets
Speaker 3:  where it just lets you do markups of PDFs. That's who
Speaker 3:  this is for. And so like, cool. Maybe it'll bring the price down on these
Speaker 3:  notetaking devices. Lenovo's been playing around with E Ink for a really
Speaker 3:  long time. I love that they're doing like an all e Ink device, but
Speaker 3:  I probably won't buy one. I'd love to review one Lenovo
Speaker 3:  call me.
Speaker 4:  Are you gonna look at the Think Whip plus which has a color E screen on the
Speaker 4:  back of a regular display and you can swivel it around.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, well they've been doing that for a while, but now it's just color.
Speaker 3:  This is the year for Color E Ink.
Speaker 4:  No, but now you can spin it around. It's on a swivel screen
Speaker 3:  Before. Yeah, they had one with a swivel. I'm pretty sure.
Speaker 3:  Because they had the original ones, which was like the, the the like it was
Speaker 3:  a dual screen and you opened it up and one side was E ink and the other was
Speaker 3:  color. But then they, at one point they were like, okay, we're just gonna
Speaker 3:  have a swivel and you can just decide which screen you want to use.
Speaker 4:  If the next time I see you, you're not trying to operate the verge on an
Speaker 4:  e color E Ink think pad. I'm be very disappointed.
Speaker 3:  I got, I got some work to do. I'll call you guys later.
Speaker 4:  Bye. I love the HPE Dragonfly Pro
Speaker 4:  Chromebook because it is a Chromebook with our G Keys.
Speaker 4:  I am 1000% buy one of these from my parents.
Speaker 3:  I love Monica's gonna have game like the why.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. She, Monica refused to count this. It's like the difference between
Speaker 4:  her excitement over the yoga book where she's like, you just gotta watch
Speaker 4:  that video. She's, it's gleeful. She is gleeful to be looking at that laptop.
Speaker 4:  It's so happy. It's infectious. And then she's like, why do these keys let
Speaker 4:  up and no one can answer.
Speaker 4:  She also pointed out that the HP's elite
Speaker 4:  line is for professionals and the pro line is for
Speaker 4:  consumers. We're just like through like words have no meaning for Hewlett
Speaker 4:  Packard at this point. So HP Elites
Speaker 3:  I love you can only be elite enterprise
Speaker 4:  Professional products. HP Pro for consumers.
Speaker 4:  Very good. Buy buying a computer with your own money. Yeah. Not
Speaker 4:  elite. Not elite.
Speaker 3:  Not
Speaker 4:  Elite, but pro
Speaker 3:  Thrill, pro move.
Speaker 4:  I'm super into this. I'm, I brought my parents a Chrome famously
Speaker 4:  brought my parents a Chromebook years ago. It was the Chromebook Pixel, the
Speaker 4:  thousand dollars first Chromebook and it, it is now end of life. They got
Speaker 4:  a message while I was home saying that it would receive no more software
Speaker 4:  updates. Which is hilarious cuz it's just Chrome.
Speaker 3:  So you gotta get the new one.
Speaker 4:  It's years. So I gotta get the new one. They, I can't get 'em in Pixel book.
Speaker 4:  That's a way step down from a Chromebook pixel
Speaker 5:  And and now you can buy them to HP Dragonfly. Proletariat.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I'll be like, you're a gamer now, mom.
Speaker 4:  It's like, rainbow Keys going. It's gonna be great. Any other
Speaker 4:  laptop we should talk about? Should we talk about the Razor edge?
Speaker 3:  It's, it's cool. Like, I mean this is, Razor's
Speaker 3:  been doing a lot of work over the years with making mobile phones and
Speaker 3:  they've been doing a lot of work over the years with making
Speaker 3:  controllers that you can plug into mobile phones. And then they said, what
Speaker 3:  if it's all one thing and we work with Verizon to sell it. Yeah. And it's
Speaker 3:  got 5g.
Speaker 4:  Who doesn't like 5g? And
Speaker 5:  That's exactly what I was missing from the steam deck was the ability to
Speaker 5:  buy it on contract from Verizon.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  360 bucks wifi only is 3 99. Think about that.
Speaker 3:  Just, I mean, what a deal. I I I'll go with the steam deck.
Speaker 3:  I'm gonna stick with the steam deck for right now. Especially with Stadia
Speaker 3:  dying in a couple of weeks.
Speaker 4:  I just think it's very funny that the pricing here is like old school phone
Speaker 4:  contract pricing. Yeah. So the wifi only model costs 3 99
Speaker 4:  5G model without a contract 5 99. But
Speaker 4:  if you sign the Verizon contract 3 59, like see
Speaker 4:  the math is like, this is how much Verizon is soaking you for. It's $200.
Speaker 3:  So good.
Speaker 4:  It's pretty good. I don't know. It kinda looks like a Nexus seven.
Speaker 4:  It's, every time I look at it, I'm like, it's an XUS seven.
Speaker 3:  It's a fab, like the FTE is back and razor razor
Speaker 3:  resurrected the fab and said, what if it, you stuck it in
Speaker 3:  between two sides of controllers and it's had something for all of your
Speaker 3:  cloud gaming. So if you don't already have a steam deck and you don't already
Speaker 3:  have one of the other mini like mobile PC handhelds right now,
Speaker 3:  this is, this is a cool, this is an interesting option.
Speaker 4:  I think the big test here is really Verizons network can actually do cloud
Speaker 4:  gaming like this and we'll see. All right, we gotta take a
Speaker 4:  break. We'll come back. We got a little bit of a CS lightning round. It's
Speaker 4:  not over yet. You're still in Vegas with us. We'll be right back.
Speaker 3:  Support for this episode comes from the Moen Smartwater network. Nothing.
Speaker 3:  Waste watering creates serious damage faster than a burst pipe.
Speaker 3:  Plumbing mishaps like that can flood basements, destroy furniture and generally
Speaker 3:  wreak havoc inside your home. Moens flow, Smartwater monitor
Speaker 3:  and shutoff can help you avoid that potential disaster. Moens
Speaker 3:  flow, Smartwater monitor and shutoff keeps tabs on your entire
Speaker 3:  water system, checking for the leaks and other vulnerabilities.
Speaker 3:  24 7. When it detects irregular pressure in your pipes or
Speaker 3:  senses water flowing somewhere it shouldn't be flowing. Moen warns you
Speaker 3:  instantly avoid disaster and stop worrying about the damaged water
Speaker 3:  could do to your home. The Flow Smartwater Monitor is part of the Moen
Speaker 3:  Smartwater network, which offers an advanced holistic approach to
Speaker 3:  managing your water system both inside and outside of your home.
Speaker 3:  Learn more about the Moen Smartwater network@moen.com com. That's
Speaker 3:  m o E n.com.
Speaker 4:  All right, we're back lightning round. You ready? Yes. Let's
Speaker 3:  Go. Let's
Speaker 4:  Go. All right. Delta and T-Mobile making in-flight. Wifi free. If you have
Speaker 4:  sky miles sounds great. Also, if you just knew anybody with a
Speaker 4:  T-Mobile phone number, you could have typed in that number for years, which
Speaker 4:  is, I now feel comfortable disclosing.
Speaker 5:  But it was weird before, it was like some flights, it was like that and in
Speaker 5:  some flights it would not have that. So now it's just gonna be all flights
Speaker 5:  free, whatever if
Speaker 4:  You, but there's this thing called Delta Sync. They're not giving
Speaker 4:  you this thing for free. They are gonna target ads at you on this network.
Speaker 4:  Somehow. They've, they're talking about
Speaker 4:  personalization, which is a code for targeted ads. And as
Speaker 4:  we know, like ISPs, mobile caries in particular,
Speaker 4:  love to do weird ad targeting stuff. Love to collect data in weird ways.
Speaker 4:  I just wanna read these terms of service before this thing goes live. That's
Speaker 4:  all I'm saying. Do
Speaker 3:  They say how fast it'll
Speaker 4:  Be? It's supposed to be fast enough for streaming cuz it's ViaSat. It's not
Speaker 4:  the old Go-Go stuff.
Speaker 3:  Okay.
Speaker 4:  So we'll see. Delta's also doing a test with starlink. I think a bunch of
Speaker 4:  airlines are testing starlink on the side, but I, I'm just, I'm
Speaker 4:  flagging this one cuz free in-flight wifi is great. Cool, whatever.
Speaker 4:  When you add the, when you just like throw the word personalization in the
Speaker 4:  mix, I'm like, oh, they're gonna do some weird ad targeting.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Think about what you're, what you're using that wifi for. Don't, don't,
Speaker 3:  don't, don't go to certain places with this wifi also because kids are around.
Speaker 3:  But like,
Speaker 4:  Also because you're on a plane, Alex,
Speaker 3:  I've seen it happen. I've seen it happen. I've watched people
Speaker 3:  just like load up on their phone and I'm like, okay,
Speaker 4:  We were flying home from Chicago and Becky was like, oh, don't worry Darling
Speaker 4:  is on the plane. I might watch that. I'm like, no, you should not watch that
Speaker 4:  on this plane right now.
Speaker 3:  Not the planes.
Speaker 4:  There's a new version of chi, the wireless charging protocol
Speaker 4:  chi. It's called
Speaker 3:  Chichi. Our reviews editor, Nathan Edwards is so excited about
Speaker 4:  This. Sean Holster ridiculous. Excited about this. Basically what's happened
Speaker 4:  here, unsurprisingly, there was chi, the wireless standing, the
Speaker 4:  wireless charging protocol. Apple took it, forked
Speaker 4:  it into MagSafe,
Speaker 3:  Put some magnets on it,
Speaker 4:  Put some magnets on it, redid the coils, did some authentication
Speaker 4:  stuff to charge at a faster rate, but still back compatible chi. And now
Speaker 4:  Apple says we're gonna give the magnet stuff to chi. That's gonna form the
Speaker 4:  basis of chi two. It'll allow for non-fat
Speaker 4:  connectors. I e a watch. Very exciting all the way around.
Speaker 4:  The magnets still will not be strong enough to hold up a phone, which is
Speaker 4:  a huge miss. Just a huge miss For those of you
Speaker 4:  like me who are addicted to buying car chargers for your phone and
Speaker 4:  unclear whether Chetu will be back compatible with MagSafe as it
Speaker 4:  currently exists. So some bits and bobs here,
Speaker 4:  but it looks like Apple decided that MagSafe, which is like
Speaker 4:  more or less not a success. It's, it's a success in
Speaker 4:  that it exists in the Apple ecosystem
Speaker 3:  And nobody adopted it.
Speaker 4:  And people like you can buy accessories for it, but the magnets are too weak
Speaker 4:  to do anything particularly interesting. It's just a, it's weird.
Speaker 4:  Like my favorite MagSafe accessory is a little puck that I bought
Speaker 4:  to mount by my bathroom mirror so I can watch TV
Speaker 4:  in the morning while brushing my teeth.
Speaker 3:  Does it work?
Speaker 4:  It's awesome. It rules. I highly recommend you spend $15
Speaker 4:  on a MagSafe puck to mount next to your bathroom mirror so you can open YouTube
Speaker 4:  in the morning. You're YouTube tv in my case. It's great. Just do it
Speaker 4:  like Richard
Speaker 3:  Doesn't look excited. I'm
Speaker 5:  Confused. I I guess I'll find it use now because now on Android
Speaker 5:  we'll we'll have, we'll find out. It's like, it's one of those things where,
Speaker 5:  because it's only been on on iPhone, like I've heard about it, I'm like,
Speaker 5:  oh that sounds cool, but I've never actually used it to find out what it
Speaker 5:  doesn't do and like where the shortcomings are.
Speaker 4:  It just doesn't do a lot. It's a wireless charging thing with weak magnets.
Speaker 4:  But what is true is that every iPhone now has magnets
Speaker 4:  built into the back of it. So other companies can make
Speaker 4:  stronger magnets for things like mounts and cases, which are neat.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. But the but the combination of I want strong magnets,
Speaker 4:  15 wat wireless charging in something that doesn't look totally ugly
Speaker 4:  has alluded every and you need to be certified by Apple that you
Speaker 4:  can't, you can't.
Speaker 3:  Nobody's under. Nobody's cracked that
Speaker 4:  One. Nobody's pulled it off. So we're getting there. We'll I think the big
Speaker 4:  question here is whether Q2 with magnets will be back
Speaker 4:  compatible with MagSafe. Cuz I think the answer might be no.
Speaker 3:  Hmm.
Speaker 4:  There's some shadiness there. Bunch of smart home stuff. It's a big year
Speaker 4:  for matter.
Speaker 3:  It's the year for matter. It's
Speaker 4:  The year for matter. It's, I would say matter has not gotten off to
Speaker 4:  a raging start. Apple had to pull it, right? Remember they did the update
Speaker 4:  for iOS, it's in Go well and they pulled it.
Speaker 4:  But there's new bridges. There's New Eve.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I mean gin. So Jen's at the show, we're gonna talk to her a bunch
Speaker 3:  next week about this next Wednesday. But she says she's just
Speaker 3:  seeing Matter everywhere. She's seeing everybody's like, Hey, I have a new
Speaker 3:  refrigerator with Matter in it, a new TV
Speaker 3:  with Matter. Like everybody that's, that's how they announce it.
Speaker 3:  They announce all this stuff and they're like, and Matter. So she's seeing
Speaker 3:  just everywhere on the show floor right now. So the thing I'm really
Speaker 3:  about excited about is there's this new Phillips Hue app
Speaker 3:  that you can get on Samsung TVs
Speaker 3:  and it will let you sync all of the lights on the back of your tv.
Speaker 3:  If you put Phillips Hue lights on the back of your tv, it'll let you sync
Speaker 3:  it with all the content without having to go through a breakout box. But
Speaker 3:  because they still want money, you have to pay $130
Speaker 3:  for the app.
Speaker 4:  That's pretty good.
Speaker 3:  You don't know if you can take that app with you when you, if your TV dies
Speaker 3:  and you get a new tv, well you have to pay another $130. There's a bunch
Speaker 3:  of questions about this also. Like why not just
Speaker 3:  make Samsung pay for the, the technology
Speaker 3:  and be like, hey look, if you plug your Phillips HU lights into the new
Speaker 3:  Samsung TVs, you can automatically sync. Yeah
Speaker 3:  there's just like a bunch of kitchen
Speaker 4:  Or you can go by any number of gov kits on Amazon for like 50
Speaker 4:  bucks and accomplish this song.
Speaker 3:  The gov tip kits, you have to have like a camera pointed at your tv. This,
Speaker 3:  you don't have to have anything pointed at it. You don't have to worry about
Speaker 3:  like, oh I really need this to go through H D M I
Speaker 3:  2.1 so that I can get the, and the box only does H D M
Speaker 3:  I 2.0. You don't have to worry about any of that. You can just be like go.
Speaker 3:  It works for all the different apps on your TV and everything. So any like
Speaker 3:  input to your tv, it does it.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, but it's
Speaker 3:  $130 app,
Speaker 4:  Right? That's where you lose me. I I for your tv. I understand the points
Speaker 4:  you're making. I'm like the gov kit's like 50 bucks. You point of camera
Speaker 4:  at your TV call today.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  No more computers required.
Speaker 3:  It's very exciting and very stupid.
Speaker 4:  I love it. Jen also covered the weird wooden plank matter
Speaker 4:  controller. This is the thing I'm most excited about with matter at, at the
Speaker 4:  end of the day is now you can make different kinds of smart home controllers
Speaker 4:  cuz they can talk to everything. She was like, here's a cutting board you
Speaker 4:  can mount on the wall to turn your lights on and off. And I was like, yeah,
Speaker 4:  I'm in it. Like this is what we need. It's gonna be great. Exactly
Speaker 3:  What we need.
Speaker 4:  And lastly, we should talk about this Withings P sensor. You just stick it
Speaker 4:  in your toilet and pee on it and it tells you what your metabolism is doing.
Speaker 3:  It's, it's, it's great. People really care about the P sensor.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I will say that the p sensor did remarkable traffic. Here's
Speaker 4:  a line from the story written by Victoria. It sounds
Speaker 4:  relatively simple, but with things is very serious about p
Speaker 4:  it took four years and 13 patents. But you don't have to do anything until
Speaker 4:  it's time to recharge the reader or switch out cartridges. The reader, the
Speaker 4:  P reader that you put in your toilet. U S P C my friends.
Speaker 3:  Oh yeah, that's the, that we had a, we had a really long conversation about
Speaker 3:  this in the editing process because I just had all the questions. I was like,
Speaker 3:  well, like do you have to touch it all the time? Like are you having to like
Speaker 3:  reach down there and touch the pock before to, to test it
Speaker 3:  and no you don't. You stick it in there. There's some cartridges, it comes
Speaker 3:  with some gloves. So if you wanna hold on those glove,
Speaker 4:  Do you have to saves the gloves between don't cartridge
Speaker 3:  Changes? I don't think. That's just like a polite thing. And the idea
Speaker 3:  is anytime you pee on it, it'll detect it and
Speaker 3:  do a test. So sometimes you may have to like do
Speaker 3:  some, some shifting to make sure you're not peeing on it if you don't want
Speaker 3:  test. Cuz it has like a hundred cartridges. All right.
Speaker 3:  It's like a hundred days of P tests. Well,
Speaker 5:  We're not gonna talk about the number one smart home story that at least
Speaker 5:  surprise me. The shower pods,
Speaker 4:  The colder. Wait, before we go on the shower pods, can I just read you this
Speaker 4:  quote about data collection in the GDPR compliance of the
Speaker 4:  P sensor? Yes. And this is a quote, it's our company guideline
Speaker 4:  not to allow anyone to look at that data. We still need to look at the
Speaker 4:  details regarding law enforcement. Just
Speaker 4:  don't let the cops look at my t dude,
Speaker 3:  Don't show them my urine, please.
Speaker 4:  Very good. All right. Richard, what was your number one?
Speaker 5:  The nu number one surprise people could not get enough of this story. The
Speaker 5:  shower pods are here to turn your bathrooms in into a pod. They've got aromatherapy,
Speaker 5:  shower infusion system. Apparently more, more than MagSafe. When, when you're
Speaker 5:  brushing your teeth, this is what the people need. I, I don't know. I didn't
Speaker 5:  quite get it, but the girls will get it. Get it. This is
Speaker 3:  For all the people who can still smell things.
Speaker 4:  Yes. Kohler loves doing gadgets at cs. Like love, loves,
Speaker 4:  loves it. I think last year they did like a $10,000 toilet
Speaker 3:  For a plumbing company. They got big tech ambitions.
Speaker 4:  They do. I mean this is just a, they're pods, you know, it's like a
Speaker 4:  Kerik. Yeah. Aromatherapy pods and like a shower that takes P pods.
Speaker 4:  There's not a lot
Speaker 5:  Of, there's probably a subscription package for your, for your shower. Like
Speaker 5:  I, I I see the, I see the meth now.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Yeah. They, they're gonna sell you more pods. Here's a quote from their
Speaker 4:  press release. Kohler says the pods are safe to use on your entire body,
Speaker 4:  which it's a shower.
Speaker 5:  Has a lot of people asking questions that should be answered by my teacher.
Speaker 5:  You
Speaker 3:  Can watch, watch every bit. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Like if, if there was something that I assumed from the jump it
Speaker 4:  was, is the shower safe for my entire body?
Speaker 4:  Very good. Who's
Speaker 3:  Making the pods that aren't safe for your entire body is what I want to know.
Speaker 4:  That's what, yeah. Right. The illegal pods.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Don't buy those illegal pods. People
Speaker 5:  Get into the discord with somebody just making bootle pods on their own.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, these pods burn me. Here's your business model, Richard.
Speaker 4:  The design of the Sprigg shower pods are Kohler specific. We'll see if
Speaker 4:  there's actual software D rm. But right now, right, the pods are shaped.
Speaker 4:  They have to fit in a thing. $21 for a six pack of single
Speaker 4:  use pods. Wow. $24 for a
Speaker 4:  single multi-use pod with eight uses, a
Speaker 4:  multi-use pod with eight uses. Gonna do the math there.
Speaker 3:  How many, how many what? What constitutes a use?
Speaker 4:  All I'm saying is they're gonna charge you about $3 per shower no matter
Speaker 4:  which way you're going. $21 for six single use pods,
Speaker 4:  $24 for multi-use pod that can be used eight times. Do
Speaker 3:  You think the showerhead stops working if you don't have a pod in there,
Speaker 3:  like you just aren't allowed to be clean.
Speaker 4:  That's when it starts burning you, Alex?
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Or if there's a software update, because some, because someone's hacked the
Speaker 4:  Pod system. It's like warning, this is no longer safe for your entire body,
Speaker 4:  but we're not telling you where it's the problem. Enjoy the caller corporation.
Speaker 4:  It's true that this is one of our top stories from this entire Cs, and I
Speaker 4:  appreciate all of you for reading about the shower pods. One of my
Speaker 4:  favorite headlines of all time was a Paul Miller. Ashley Carmen joint.
Speaker 4:  I think Paul had the vibe line, but I think Ashley actually came up with
Speaker 4:  the headline. It was just the word tortilla pods in all capital letters.
Speaker 4:  And it was the whole story, like no further explanation.
Speaker 4:  And it was like a startup selling a pod system to make
Speaker 4:  tortillas.
Speaker 3:  It's a very good headline.
Speaker 4:  And all of the comments were like, you can just make tortillas.
Speaker 4:  This is a deeply solved problem. Very good. Well, pods
Speaker 4:  are back. Everyone. CS is rocking. And Roland, there's tons of news
Speaker 4:  on the site. I'm like I said, I'm feeling I got, I have the
Speaker 4:  fomo. There's a part of me that's for my own health. I'm happy I'm not
Speaker 4:  there. It's, it's bad to be there. It's bad to be in lo it's bad for
Speaker 4:  you. But I'm, I miss, I miss our team. I miss Skats. I miss
Speaker 4:  hotel rooms and the coffee smell.
Speaker 3:  I, I still got the c e s funk despite not
Speaker 4:  Being there. I miss walking outta Lenovo briefing, believing in my heart
Speaker 4:  that eight and 10 finger gestures on a dual screen, 13.3 inch
Speaker 4:  od laptop is like the future of all computing. Like I,
Speaker 4:  I feel that, but don't worry, there's more CS to
Speaker 4:  come. They're on the show floor today. Tomorrow. They're wrapping up through
Speaker 4:  the weekend. Alex, you said we've got more show to come, especially with
Speaker 4:  Jen about Matter.
Speaker 3:  Yes. Jen and Chris and Andy. We're gonna be chatting a bunch next week.
Speaker 3:  It's gonna be great.
Speaker 4:  Very good. All right. I gotta go keep reading CS coverage.
Speaker 4:  I can't, I can't stop. It's all on the site. I'm in the comments cuz I'm,
Speaker 4:  you know, I'm off Twitter, so you just find me in the comments of random
Speaker 4:  Verge articles, which I think is terrifying. Our reporters. Cause I like
Speaker 4:  getting into fights in the comments articles.
Speaker 3:  They're
Speaker 4:  A great time. I should stop it, but I'm here for you. Find me. You can tweet
Speaker 4:  at us. You can tweet at me. I'm at Reckless. Alex's Alex j Cranz. Richard
Speaker 4:  is at RJ ccc. I am. I do check the replies every
Speaker 4:  couple days, so I might, I'll throw you a, like if you hit me on Twitter
Speaker 4:  and you can find us on the Verge. We'll be back on Wednesday with more CES
Speaker 4:  coverage. That's it. That's for Chas.
Speaker 1:  And that's a wrap for Verge this week. Thanks for listening. If you enjoy
Speaker 1:  the show, subscribe in the podcast app of your choice or tell a friend, you
Speaker 1:  can send us feedback at vergecast@theverge.com. This show is produced
Speaker 1:  by me, Liam James, and our senior audio director, Andrew Marino. This
Speaker 1:  episode was edited and mixed by Amanda Rose Smith. Our editorial
Speaker 1:  director is Brooke Min and our executive producer is Eleanor Donovan.
Speaker 1:  The Vergecast is a production of the Verge and Box Media Podcast network.
Speaker 1:  And that's it. We'll see you next week.
Speaker 3:  Support for this episode comes from the new Moen Smartwater network.
Speaker 3:  Did you know that the average person unknowingly wastes up to 30
Speaker 3:  gallons of water every day? Moen is helping homeowners keep their water from
Speaker 3:  going down the drain. Their smartwater network helps you get the most out
Speaker 3:  of every drop. Moen gives you complete control of the water you use
Speaker 3:  both inside and outside your home. Powered by a new wave
Speaker 3:  of smart technology. Their network protects against leaks, waters
Speaker 3:  your lawn with precision, and allows you to use your kitchen faucet with
Speaker 3:  just a wave. See what else the Moen smartwater network can
Speaker 3:  do@moen.com. That's m O E
Speaker 3:  n.com.