# Transcript
ID: 13cd01d0-d281-11ed-b4d4-e1af67e95bfb
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: The swaggy AI Pope and Apple headset rumors
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/4837357641121187084/8584808035190189892/s93290-US-5280s-1680568730.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, Alex Cranz, and David Pierce discuss AI image generators getting better, Apple WWDC 2023 rumors, and the other big stories in tech this week.
Speaker 1:  This episode is brought to you by kpmg. At
Speaker 1:  kpmg Innovation is the go-to state of mind. Their visionary
Speaker 1:  thinkers and advanced technology help you see beyond the now, uncover
Speaker 1:  new insights and turn them into opportunities. KPMG
Speaker 1:  can help you leverage the value of data and drive transformational outcomes
Speaker 1:  through innovation To explore their thinking, go to
Speaker 1:  kpmg.us.
Speaker 2:  The Supreme Court is hearing a case this week about art and
Speaker 2:  who gets to remix an artistic idea. But this fight
Speaker 2:  is not new.
Speaker 3:  Olivia Rodrigo was not doing anything different from
Speaker 3:  Michaelangelo or Leonardo da Vinci. Honestly, those guys were
Speaker 3:  looking around seeing what other people did at the time in Florence
Speaker 3:  and Rome and wherever, and copying some of it.
Speaker 2:  SCOTUS copyright law. And you this week
Speaker 2:  on Intuit Vultures Pop Culture podcast.
Speaker 5:  Hello and welcome to Rich Chest, the flagship podcast with the swag
Speaker 5:  out Pope. God, I love the swag out Pope so much. If
Speaker 5:  human, if AI ends humanity, but we got swag Pope,
Speaker 5:  it'll been fine. Like, honestly, like it's worth it.
Speaker 5:  Put a sign on earth that's like, here lies swag, Pope
Speaker 5:  passing aliens. Like, just send that message out. Like, you know, there's
Speaker 5:  other civilizations in the universe where like, why have we never heard from
Speaker 5:  anyone? And there's that theory that every civilization gets to at this point
Speaker 5:  and collapses. We just need to send the message
Speaker 5:  now. Swag pop. If you see swag, Pope, you
Speaker 5:  probably have 25 years left.
Speaker 6:  That was us. We did that.
Speaker 5:  We, we know something.
Speaker 7:  That's what we leave behind
Speaker 5:  Drippy Pope, man. It's like, just shut it down once you get there. Hi,
Speaker 5:  I'm Eli. I'm your friend Alex Grant is here.
Speaker 7:  I'm your friend too. You don't know if I'm real unless you check how many
Speaker 7:  fingers I have in the photos.
Speaker 5:  David Pierce
Speaker 6:  Is here. Hi. I'm suddenly realizing I have a puffy jacket upstairs and that
Speaker 6:  like, maybe I should have been wearing it for this podcast. Oh,
Speaker 5:  You should have. You absolutely shouldn't. Now that we've moved into video,
Speaker 5:  I'm so sorry. We all, we gotta take, we gotta start taking style cues from
Speaker 5:  the Pope. Yeah. Just in general. We should, I mean, honestly, why have I
Speaker 5:  not been dress dressing like the head of a church this whole time? Let's
Speaker 5:  talk about the Pope. An amazing sentence to say on this. Our
Speaker 5:  technology podcast this week, mid Journey, which is a generative
Speaker 5:  AI tool that makes images, at least an update, the images can
Speaker 5:  now be vastly more photorealistic. And the first thing
Speaker 5:  that happened was people made images of the Pope
Speaker 5:  just absolutely swag out in a gigantic white puffy coat.
Speaker 6:  Well, actually, the, the best part of this is, that's the second thing that
Speaker 6:  happened. Okay? The first thing that happened was somebody tweeted a
Speaker 6:  generated picture of Donald Trump being arrested that no one fell
Speaker 6:  for. And actually it sparked this really interesting thing about like, oh,
Speaker 6:  look at this fake picture. Someday people are gonna fall for these. But it
Speaker 6:  didn't become a thing. And then literally a couple of days later, the
Speaker 6:  Pope swag out in a giant puffy coat gets everybody
Speaker 5:  That got. Yeah. So I, and, and this is like the heart of this story. This
Speaker 5:  is like the most verge casty thing. Why did the information environment
Speaker 5:  know not to fall for Trump being arrested, even though he's
Speaker 5:  tweeting I'm about to be arrested. Right? And then everyone I think had the
Speaker 5:  same reaction, which is they were scrolling on whatever feeds somewhere and
Speaker 5:  like, you know, that swag out Pope showed up and everyone
Speaker 5:  was like, oh, that rules and like moved on. Right? And like, there are
Speaker 5:  no stakes to falling for it, right? And so no one applied
Speaker 5:  their like, critical thinking skills until later when various
Speaker 5:  writers and people were like, Hey, the, the fake pope is important of
Speaker 5:  doom. That we all had to like, take a step back. You should go look at these
Speaker 5:  images if you haven't seen, I would, I, I can't imagine you're listening
Speaker 5:  to the show. We, James Vincent wrote a great piece. The headline is The
Speaker 5:  Swag Out Pope is an AI fake and an early glimpse of the new reality. A
Speaker 5:  perfect Verge headline. I love it. You should go read that piece. You should
Speaker 5:  go look the images, they are remarkably realistic. There's some pieces of
Speaker 5:  them that make it easy to spot, like this new version
Speaker 5:  of Mid Journey. It's kind of like everything's like a little too hdr. Everything
Speaker 5:  kind of looks like the clarity slider. And Lightroom has been turned up too
Speaker 5:  far. So they have a style, which is interesting in and of
Speaker 5:  itself. Like you tell Mid Journey make a thing that looks like a real photo
Speaker 5:  and it is like, okay, we've mined Zillow for the
Speaker 5:  most whacked down HDR real estate photos that can exist. And that's the
Speaker 5:  style we're using for,
Speaker 6:  One of the things I thought was really interesting is there have been people
Speaker 6:  like with some of these Trump photos that are starting to come out where
Speaker 6:  you can say things like, make it look like it came out of a TV camera. And
Speaker 6:  the people making these images are getting better and better at teaching
Speaker 6:  the system how to replicate the weirdness of photos that we
Speaker 6:  see in the world. Because in a weird way, like Instagram has trained us to
Speaker 6:  not notice that a photo isn't real anymore. Like first we had filters. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And now we have all these incredibly nuanced tools that people can use to
Speaker 6:  change things. And it's generally true that if you look really, really, really
Speaker 6:  hard, you can figure it out, right? Like there are, there are telltale signs
Speaker 6:  in like the, the dynamic range and the contrast and often the
Speaker 6:  hands. But like the argument that you should zoom this photo to
Speaker 6:  200% and inspect every pixel in order to see if this is real is
Speaker 6:  ridiculous. And we're way past that point. Like the idea that you can just
Speaker 6:  sort of quickly look at it and be like, that's not what faces are, which
Speaker 6:  is what these things were six months ago. Yeah. We're so far down the
Speaker 6:  road of like, this looks like a regular photo that a normal human might have
Speaker 6:  edited to have this kind of style and then posted on the internet. Like we've
Speaker 6:  crossed some Rubicon there.
Speaker 5:  The pop one is really interesting cause his glasses are melting onto his
Speaker 5:  face. Like it's it's right in front of you. Yeah. Like, you don't have to
Speaker 5:  ne you should go, go look at his hands. Everyone should go look at this picture.
Speaker 5:  There's a bunch of stuff in it that would tell you. But the first one
Speaker 5:  is that his glasses aren't melting into his face. Well,
Speaker 7:  You're too
Speaker 5:  Distracted and you just sort of overlook it Unscr, you're like, I don't know,
Speaker 5:  look at that jacket and you're just like, miss it. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  The jacket is really, really good. Like, I want that jacket. I wish the
Speaker 7:  jacket existed. The one that makes it look like it's got like the little
Speaker 7:  Pope Cumber bun built in. I was like, yes. Beautiful. No
Speaker 7:  notes. I don't even care that his glasses are melting into his face. That's
Speaker 7:  just an aesthetic choice for him, I assume.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And, and as James points out in his story, there's a couple of other
Speaker 6:  things too, right? Like the, the cross he's wearing on a necklace is, is
Speaker 6:  sort of warped and melted. Like Salvador Ali style, his hand
Speaker 6:  looks crazy with the, the thing that he's like, if you spend
Speaker 6:  15 seconds with this photo, you can pretty quickly figure out, it's not real,
Speaker 6:  but like, how many photos do you spend 15 seconds staring at going? Is this
Speaker 6:  a thing? Like, are we supposed to do that with every picture we see from
Speaker 6:  now on for the rest of our lives?
Speaker 5:  So bring that back around to Donald Trump. Right? I didn't even think of
Speaker 5:  it as the first thing that happened. Like of course the first thing that
Speaker 5:  somebody made with this tool was a photo of Trump getting arrested. Sure.
Speaker 5:  And it, but it didn't hit like it wasn't resonant in a really unique
Speaker 5:  way. Yeah. In the, the swag Pope was
Speaker 5:  Why do you think that is?
Speaker 6:  James makes a couple of arguments that I think are really compelling. His
Speaker 6:  piece is really good. Everybody should read it. But the, the first thing
Speaker 6:  I think is there is this like hyper-realism I think
Speaker 6:  is the phrase he he used that others have used before around celebrities
Speaker 6:  we're just like used to seeing these people in these odd places with odd
Speaker 6:  lighting doing weird stuff. The Pope in particular is the kind of person
Speaker 6:  who is like massively photographed. He is unusually, I think
Speaker 6:  for a pope around like swag all the time.
Speaker 6:  Like
Speaker 5:  There's
Speaker 6:  Just a picture of the man like signing a Lamborghini. And so it's like, it's
Speaker 6:  just in this realm of possibility enough. And then you add
Speaker 6:  on top of that this kind of weird veneer that is all
Speaker 6:  celebrity stuff now. And then attach again, like you said, sort of
Speaker 6:  the low stakes of it, right? Like Trump getting arrested is like objectively
Speaker 6:  it's a big deal if it happens. And so it's gonna cause most
Speaker 6:  discerning people to at least take a half a beat and be like, is this
Speaker 6:  anything? But like, why, why would they lie to you about like this sick jacket
Speaker 6:  the Pope is wearing? Right? Like, we're just that conditioned to ask that
Speaker 6:  question. And so I think you, you put all these things together and also
Speaker 6:  something like Mid Journey is gonna do really well with a photo
Speaker 6:  of the Pope or Donald Trump as opposed to like a picture of your neighbor
Speaker 6:  because it has the training data to do this. So it's just, it is able to
Speaker 6:  do these things in such a more convincing way because of kind
Speaker 6:  of both what we're primed to see and what it actually has in its system to
Speaker 6:  work with. I
Speaker 5:  Have a related theory, which is that Trump getting arrested is a sort of
Speaker 5:  thing that is immediately reinforced.
Speaker 6:  Hmm. Yeah. Like you'd be seeing at other places,
Speaker 5:  Like if that photo existed, the person who runs push alerts, the
Speaker 5:  New York Times would be losing their mind,
Speaker 5:  Right? They're like, just beat the phone again. Just hit him again. Just
Speaker 5:  tell him again, live updates. There's a, there's a story stream thing on
Speaker 5:  the top. Hit him again. Trump sneezed in handcuffs, hit him again, right?
Speaker 5:  Like, and the Post would be doing it and we would have it, like for some
Speaker 5:  reason we at Tech site would be like, we need to have a, like the information
Speaker 5:  environment would instantly reinforce that image as being
Speaker 5:  real. And I think we're trained for that to happen, right?
Speaker 5:  Like we know if something of that scale happens, it will happen
Speaker 5:  a lot like at massive scale. And so you see that
Speaker 5:  picture and you're like, eh, like there's not a, there's none of the other
Speaker 5:  signaling, right? And so then you're like, wait, is this real, the pope
Speaker 5:  the Pope wearing a puffer jacket with a built-in conman And Alex, I just
Speaker 5:  looked at that picture again. I had noticed that con button. It's like real
Speaker 6:  Good. It's, it's so good.
Speaker 5:  It's real good. The Pope wearing a like what is
Speaker 5:  objectively a sick jacket?
Speaker 7:  It's,
Speaker 5:  There's like, actually the New York Times might send a push alert about it,
Speaker 5:  like at this point they just can't help themselves.
Speaker 5:  But it, it doesn't, it just doesn't come with a signaling.
Speaker 7:  I think you're right. That's, that's exactly what it is. Like we're se we're,
Speaker 7:  we're used to kinda looking for that misinformation. We've been primed by
Speaker 7:  like the shark is in the, is in the highway flood, the
Speaker 7:  flooded highway. Like we see that video every single time
Speaker 7:  and somebody has to be like, it's fake. So you're used to kind being like,
Speaker 7:  this is the coolest thing ever. Why is no one talking about it? Oh cuz it's
Speaker 7:  fake. Whereas Trump, you're gonna go and you're gonna
Speaker 7:  immediately look for it because if he's being arrested, you're gonna wanna
Speaker 7:  like message your parents and be like, ha got him or whatever. Maybe you're
Speaker 7:  gonna arrest him. Like be happy about it. It was all really bad.
Speaker 5:  Here's my question. I posted a, a video of the swag
Speaker 5:  Pope, it's just a TikTok of different, I mean it's, it's so I can't get enough
Speaker 5:  of it's is the disinformation problem way lower stakes?
Speaker 5:  Right? It's not everyone's worried about the election that's coming up. No,
Speaker 5:  I think it's,
Speaker 7:  I think it's still high stakes because right now we're, we're,
Speaker 7:  we're seeing, we see the same thing with deep fakes. We saw it with Photoshop.
Speaker 7:  Every time we get these new tools that allow us to kind of recreate
Speaker 7:  reality, the initial things are like fun. It's like
Speaker 7:  deep fake Keanu Reeves on TikTok just eating a sandwich. Like that's funny.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. But then somebody's like, okay, well now I'm gonna use a really cool
Speaker 7:  deep fake to make it look like Biden said something really,
Speaker 7:  really horrible to, to get my bass really upset because my
Speaker 7:  base isn't as online as the rest of us are. So they're not as primed
Speaker 7:  to look for that disinformation and react to it appropriately.
Speaker 7:  So it's a lot easier to manipulate those like other groups who aren't as
Speaker 7:  primed as the majority of us looking at the Pope.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Yeah. And I think there's also the question of where the
Speaker 6:  line is kind of for us as consumers
Speaker 6:  is really fascinating to me. Cuz I think about the, like do you remember
Speaker 6:  that story from a couple of years ago when there were lions on the street
Speaker 6:  in Russia during the pandemic that one had a full,
Speaker 6:  everybody believed it cycle before it became something that was like
Speaker 6:  roundly debunked because it wasn't true. And so that's still kind of
Speaker 6:  under the, like we immediately learned to question it. Whereas
Speaker 6:  the former president of the United States is about to get arrested. Obviously
Speaker 6:  above the line of, I immediately need to scrutinize whether this is real
Speaker 6:  or not, right? Yeah. Yeah. But the, the best disinformation we've seen
Speaker 6:  has always been the stuff that exists just barely underneath that line.
Speaker 6:  Right? And I think especially as we get to the election, I don't know where
Speaker 6:  the line is, but this question of like, what is higher stakes than, yo, look
Speaker 6:  at the jacket this Pope has on but lower stakes than the former president
Speaker 6:  of the United States got arrested. And all of these very smart actors from
Speaker 6:  around the world are gonna find ways to live just right a smidge
Speaker 6:  underneath that line. And I think it just gets easier and easier to do
Speaker 6:  with some of these tools. Now
Speaker 5:  Let me rephrase that question. I think both of you're right in that way.
Speaker 5:  I meant like is it lower stakes if you did this to a
Speaker 5:  school board member, right? If you
Speaker 6:  Swag down a school board member, is that
Speaker 5:  Say Yeah. Yeah. If I was like, all right, let's, we're gonna swag David out,
Speaker 5:  right? And like put him and like put you out there like we're, you're not
Speaker 5:  gonna get the signal. It's a thing you're talking about. It's like just below
Speaker 5:  the line of instant scrutiny, right? Is is it that where the
Speaker 5:  problem is headed? Because that's what it feels like to me like this
Speaker 7:  Yeah, I
Speaker 5:  Trippy post it's is hilarious. But like I'm thinking about like high school
Speaker 5:  students. Yes. And maybe it's just there's not enough training data
Speaker 5:  to make weird celebrity photos of your principal, but you I you can just
Speaker 5:  see where it's going, right?
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Yeah. There was, I was trying to look up some old
Speaker 7:  celebrity and like an old photo of a celebrity I had in my head that I remember
Speaker 7:  being real. And I was like, I wish I could remember who it was now I was
Speaker 7:  like Judy Garland or something. I was like, I'm gonna go find this photo.
Speaker 7:  I've seen I've, I can see it in my head. I know it's real. And I went searching
Speaker 7:  for it and it was actually a Photoshop and I couldn't find an original photo.
Speaker 7:  And I was like, oh, this like idea I've had in my head all of this time
Speaker 7:  was just some dumb misinformation and I just felt bumped for a little while.
Speaker 7:  And I think that's probably gonna be the most common kind of thing. Like
Speaker 7:  maybe it's old celebrities or new celebrities, just a little twist
Speaker 7:  just so you're like, you love that photo of 'em so much. They're the swag
Speaker 7:  out pope. And, but it'll also be like, okay, well I can go and make
Speaker 7:  my best friend who I'm no longer friends with cuz I'm 16 and and
Speaker 7:  everything's in the world is ending look really ugly in this dress even though
Speaker 7:  she never owned that dress. And then everybody's gonna make fun of her.
Speaker 5:  That's very specific. Alex,
Speaker 7:  Look I was a teenage girl. We know how to bully better than anyone else
Speaker 7:  on the planet. But I think like we're gonna see a lot more of that
Speaker 7:  as those tools become easier to use for regular people.
Speaker 5:  So in the middle of this, right, right. The mid journey is not
Speaker 5:  photorealistic. It is remarkable. You should go look at the images, you should
Speaker 5:  go play with it. They are starting to close it down. I think they're
Speaker 5:  realizing like they need to put some rules around it. So that's happening.
Speaker 5:  There's a big push for that. Then there's the voices,
Speaker 5:  which are pretty accurate. Again, my favorite tos of all are
Speaker 5:  presidents talking about mixing music and arguing about it. It's like the
Speaker 5:  funniest shit in the entire world. It's, I'm gonna end up posting one every
Speaker 5:  week for the rest of my life cuz they're so funny. But the voices are good.
Speaker 5:  There's one I'll, I'll just post it. But the voices are good.
Speaker 5:  What they can't do yet is make a move. Right? So if you got
Speaker 5:  really great voices and you can generate an image of the president, you are
Speaker 5:  pretty close to a video of a president saying something bad. And we
Speaker 5:  are just starting to see, okay, we're making videos out of this. Right? Like
Speaker 5:  that part of the deep fake cycle where you just type in President Biden
Speaker 5:  saying he hates everyone generates an accurate looking video
Speaker 5:  of President Biden saying he he hates everyone without the sort of like current
Speaker 5:  deep fake remodeling that you have to do. We're not there yet. And we've
Speaker 5:  seen some examples now of AI generated video, which I think James referred
Speaker 5:  to as being in its demonic phase.
Speaker 7:  He's accurate.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. It's, it's, it's either wonderful or horrifying
Speaker 6:  and I genuinely can't, like I'm, I, every time I watch it, I like watch it
Speaker 6:  again and also don't wanna ever see it again as long as I live. But there's
Speaker 6:  like, yeah you can, you can type what is it? Will Smith Eating Pasta
Speaker 6:  and it will show you a video of Will Smith eating pasta. But it's, it's horrifying,
Speaker 6:  right? Like it's, yeah, it just makes me think of salad Fingers every time
Speaker 6:  for reasons I can't explain. But that's a reference most of our listeners
Speaker 6:  won't get anyway, so it's fine. But it's really funny cuz this is
Speaker 6:  the kind of thing you look at and it's like, oh this is just silly, right?
Speaker 6:  Like this is, these are like goofy videos of Joe Rogan
Speaker 6:  fighting a bear that is like essentially a cartoon. Yes.
Speaker 5:  And then he turns into a bear. Yeah. Like it's not, it's
Speaker 5:  not like, like they're cra like Will Smith eating go watch the video
Speaker 5:  Will Smith eating pasta. It's
Speaker 6:  Yeah, we'll post it in the shoutout. It's like the, they're all great, but
Speaker 6:  you look at them and it's like, okay, this is, this is ultimately harmless.
Speaker 6:  Like nobody's gonna look at this and be like, oh, Joe Rogan actually fought
Speaker 6:  and then became a bear. But also like last summer we were talking
Speaker 6:  about Dolly and Mid Journey in this same way where everything was
Speaker 6:  very abstract and it was like, oh, you can see how
Speaker 6:  it thinks this looks like a person, but it doesn't really, and no one would
Speaker 6:  be confused by it. And now here we are. Like that took, that took
Speaker 6:  six months essentially to go from, no one would ever confuse this for a
Speaker 6:  person to like, you have to work pretty hard to not confuse this for
Speaker 6:  a person. Yeah. And I think a video's gonna come the same way. And that's
Speaker 6:  where I think like, I don't know, we either enter this place of total nihilism
Speaker 6:  where it's like nothing matters. Don't believe anything. The only real thing
Speaker 6:  is like the stuff right in front of your face and maybe not even that.
Speaker 6:  Or we're gonna have to figure out some really complicated systems for how
Speaker 6:  we deal with all of this stuff. Well
Speaker 7:  I think it's, it's education, right? Like video obviously is more
Speaker 7:  complex than photos, but we've been dealing with this issue as long as kind
Speaker 7:  of photos have been existing, people have been faking photos. And we've even
Speaker 7:  seen it with video too. People were making fake videos all the time and
Speaker 7:  the only thing that's changed is that the tools are way, way more accessible
Speaker 7:  now. So there's gonna be a lot more content rather than just
Speaker 7:  a few really good people doing it. And I think the way you counter
Speaker 7:  that is to just educate people, make people the rest. Most
Speaker 7:  of us listening, most of us here talking right now can pretty much
Speaker 7:  pick this stuff out. Like we take a moment, we look at it, we know how to
Speaker 7:  do it because we've educated ourselves, we've learned how to,
Speaker 5:  I'm sorry, the premise of this conversation is that all of us got taken by
Speaker 5:  a dripped out pope.
Speaker 7:  Yeah because, but then you stop and you pay take a moment
Speaker 7:  and like once you apply rigor like we did with, with the fake
Speaker 7:  Trump photos, we immediately were like, no, those are fake. And so I think
Speaker 7:  like once people start applying that rigor more frequently with
Speaker 7:  this stuff, we're gonna like, it won't be quite as bad.
Speaker 7:  And I think that's certainly one of the better ways to deal with it than
Speaker 7:  like ban the tools altogether or some of the other weird
Speaker 6:  Plans. But I think that's, that's asking a lot of people, right? And we've,
Speaker 6:  we've been through this a few times where like we went through this with
Speaker 6:  misinformation on the internet in general, right? And we have a bunch of
Speaker 6:  tools that are making it easier to be smarter. And yet everybody gets
Speaker 6:  taken by most stuff because most of us are primed to think, most people
Speaker 6:  are not. Like it's deliberately lying to us, right? And so yeah, the
Speaker 6:  getting past that thing has been very hard. And then you talk about like
Speaker 6:  the chat G P T stuff that people believe, even though it is, these things
Speaker 6:  are known to lie, they say it confidently and like they know what they're
Speaker 6:  talking about. And I was talking to somebody the other day who was saying,
Speaker 6:  he was like, I've done more Googling than ever since chat G P T because I
Speaker 6:  have to Google every fact that this thing gives me. And like maybe that's
Speaker 6:  sneakily what Google's doing. They're like, if we make a shitty chatbot,
Speaker 6:  searches will go way up. But that's, it's a lot
Speaker 6:  of work and I think the idea that I'm gonna like scroll through my TikTok
Speaker 6:  feed or my Instagram feed or whatever and sort of inquire as to the
Speaker 6:  veracity of every single thing in it is just too much to ask of people. And
Speaker 6:  so you get people like Adobe is saying they're gonna come out with these
Speaker 6:  tools for identifying this stuff and one of open AI's businesses is
Speaker 6:  gonna be showing you what was made by open ai, which is like bonkers
Speaker 6:  and backwards and insane. That's good. But it does feel like that
Speaker 6:  stuff is gonna come eventually, but slowly. And we're we're
Speaker 6:  due for a really weird phase of being tricked by drippy popes. Wait,
Speaker 6:  between now and then
Speaker 7:  I figured it out. Snoops can go public and we all
Speaker 7:  invest in Snoops and they just spend forever
Speaker 7:  debunking every single fake
Speaker 6:  Just call it Snoops G P T. Yeah. And you just send it everything
Speaker 6:  and it says, is this real? Yeah, this is great idea. Come into this play.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  So the Adobe thing is really interesting, right? They call it the content
Speaker 5:  authenticity initiative. We've covered it. I talked to
Speaker 5:  Scott Beski from Adobe about it before. Their whole thing is okay,
Speaker 5:  we can verify an image from creation to
Speaker 5:  ingest to distribution. So you take a photo, your camera like sports, this
Speaker 5:  thing, you put it through Photoshop, it'll get tagged and we'll
Speaker 5:  basically, it's basically like a very complicated metadata system. And
Speaker 5:  various social networks will support it so that when Twitter
Speaker 5:  or Facebook or Instagram or whatever displays an image, it
Speaker 5:  will tell you it's real because it's been verified as authentic all the way
Speaker 5:  through the capture chain. I, I want to believe this will work. I do do I,
Speaker 5:  it's like it's a very verge solution to the problem. Like it's a nice idea
Speaker 5:  what if we did good metadata?
Speaker 5:  But like those are the kinds of solutions that the industry can come up with.
Speaker 5:  And they've even, Adobe's been plugging away at that for a minute now. Then
Speaker 5:  there's the sort of policy solutions, a group called The Future of Life
Speaker 5:  Institute published an open letter calling on AI labs around the world
Speaker 5:  to pause development. Elon Musk signed it. Alex, I think you were saying
Speaker 5:  Steve Wazniak signed it. Yeah, Andrew Yang showed up and
Speaker 5:  signed it. You know, Elon signing it. There's a lot
Speaker 5:  of history with Elon and open AI that's coming out now. It's maybe seems
Speaker 5:  like he just wants him to stop, but we're at that phase,
Speaker 5:  right? Yeah. Where there's an open letter there. There's another
Speaker 5:  group has called on the ftc, the Center for AI and Digital
Speaker 5:  Policy filed a complaint with the FTC saying Open
Speaker 5:  AI should stop launching new models of G P T because of
Speaker 5:  unfair and deceptive trade practices. Which is seems like a stretch.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Their, their big theory was like, because these things
Speaker 6:  can put out false information that falls under the auspices of
Speaker 6:  the FTC to regulate. It's, it's drawing a pretty tenuous
Speaker 6:  line. Yeah. Like you're saying there is a lot of momentum for this idea that
Speaker 6:  we just have to stop it because it is getting out of control and we don't
Speaker 6:  know what to do with it. Make it stop. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  The UK rejected the idea of a dedicated AI regulator. So and
Speaker 5:  then there's some sort of antitrust fight. Here's a question, a very vir
Speaker 5:  question. Do robots have free speech? Because cuz we do,
Speaker 5:  I think for
Speaker 7:  A while I, people who program the robots
Speaker 5:  Have until President DeSantis rides herd over these United States
Speaker 5:  like we do. Right? It's like legal to lie in most cases, right?
Speaker 5:  It's not legal to like do a fraud and like get money for lying. But like
Speaker 5:  in general, if I wanted to tell you that Aaron Rodgers is gonna have six
Speaker 5:  great seasons with the New York chats, like that's a thing I can say no one
Speaker 5:  can arrest before
Speaker 5:  I'm just lying to you.
Speaker 6:  Aaron Rodgers is outside of your door right now.
Speaker 5:  He's showing up, right? He's the, he's the law. Like
Speaker 5:  it's legal to lie to people. Is it legal for robots to lie to people? Like
Speaker 5:  I don't know the answer to that question in any way, shape or form. Well,
Speaker 5:  no. So I'm not sure that the government is presently constituted as the ability
Speaker 5:  to answer that question in a rational, coherent, or stable way.
Speaker 7:  So the Writer's Guild of America is currently renegotiating their contract
Speaker 7:  with the producers in Hollywood so that they can get a better deal
Speaker 7:  primarily on streaming rights. That's like a whole big deal.
Speaker 7:  We'll do a plenty of verge cast about it, don't worry about it. But
Speaker 7:  they're also talking about AI tools because there's a potential for somebody
Speaker 7:  to just be like, I don't need writers, I'm just gonna have the ai. Right?
Speaker 7:  The whole thing. And they said no. The same way that you don't just
Speaker 7:  like use a Wikipedia entry for a
Speaker 7:  story. We still are the ones writing itis are just
Speaker 7:  tools and you're allowed to use those tools to maybe enhance, maybe
Speaker 7:  make suggestions, but they cannot be credited. They cannot be
Speaker 7:  like treated the same, same as a writer because they're not because they're
Speaker 7:  tools. And they also called it kind of inherently plagiarism
Speaker 7:  because of the data it's trained on, which I thought was really interesting,
Speaker 7:  maybe wrong, but certainly like very, very interesting.
Speaker 7:  And I think that approach of like, these are tools, they're
Speaker 7:  inherently cannot lie. They cannot be credited because
Speaker 7:  they're tools. You don't credit Photoshop when you go and you do a really
Speaker 7:  cool edit. Like we don't credit Photoshop whenever we do illustrations on
Speaker 7:  the website, you wouldn't credit minefield in the same way. So I
Speaker 7:  thought that was kind of interesting.
Speaker 5:  So I should disclose the writer's skill of America is the
Speaker 5:  union that the Vox Media Union is part of. So our newsroom is
Speaker 5:  represented by the writer Guild of America. We're management. So we're not
Speaker 5:  Yeah, we're we're just the boot also, Comcast is an investor in
Speaker 5:  Vox Media. Oh my god. Yeah. And they Netflix own nbc,
Speaker 5:  which yeah, we talked about Hollywood here. Its, here's the block. Comcast
Speaker 5:  is investor in Vox, it's NBC universal division. I'm the
Speaker 5:  executive register of Netflix show which rules you should go watch it on
Speaker 5:  Netflix. That's part of Hollywood. And our company has six
Speaker 5:  unions and writers of America is one of them. Alex Heat lives in la. Do
Speaker 5:  we have to disclose that? Does that, is that anything? I have seen the
Speaker 5:  Hollywood sign.
Speaker 5:  It's not, it's remark. It's remarkably unremarkable. I would say. I
Speaker 5:  did not get stars in my eyes. It didn't happen.
Speaker 7:  Just got the bug.
Speaker 5:  So that's fascinating, right? Like this idea of attribution Yeah. To the
Speaker 5:  robot it it like, can a monkey take a selfie is like a real thing. Like we're
Speaker 5:  gonna do it again but with robots at scale and then there's this contingent
Speaker 5:  of people who are like, actually we need to stop it. Yes. Right. We, we are
Speaker 5:  not ready for this thing to happen. And then I think that
Speaker 5:  conversation entirely flattens out the fact that these systems are all different,
Speaker 5:  right? And you can get an open AI in a Microsoft, in a Google
Speaker 5:  to agree to some safety standards, but there's a lot of like
Speaker 5:  slightly worse ones or weird open source projects that do not have to agree
Speaker 5:  to anything. And they can still be used to do bad things and they will,
Speaker 5:  they'll be run by criminals. So like won't do what the laws
Speaker 5:  of various countries tell them to do. And that I, this is just a big
Speaker 5:  swirl of a mess right now. Yeah. And it at the
Speaker 5:  heart of it again is just like a speech question. Like what are you allowed
Speaker 5:  to do with a computer? Yep. Are you allowed to instruct the computer to lie
Speaker 5:  to people? Yes. Yes. Like it seems like do
Speaker 7:  It on Twitter all the time,
Speaker 5:  But I think there's gonna be some amount of, all right, the
Speaker 5:  companies, the big companies, the ones that truly democratize the tools
Speaker 5:  are gonna be either at a company market level,
Speaker 5:  they're gonna put some restrictions in, right? Like I think mid journey in
Speaker 5:  the rest of the image generators would do well to say we're gonna start ruining
Speaker 5:  faces again. Hmm. Cause that was a conscious decision
Speaker 5:  that they had made before that they wouldn't do faces and they undid it and
Speaker 5:  like you can see how as just an industry, they could say, you know what,
Speaker 5:  we're gonna start being bad at faces again because this is getting a little
Speaker 5:  weird until there's like a regulatory system that we, we understand. But
Speaker 5:  then you can also see how the government might be like, you know what, we
Speaker 5:  want you to shut it down or like register all your users or worse like D
Speaker 5:  r m, all the pictures so we know where they all came from and like, there's
Speaker 5:  just a range of options on the table I think is, I mean this is what the
Speaker 5:  verges made for. Yeah. Like one publication can talk about all these things
Speaker 5:  that happening
Speaker 6:  At once. But I do think you're right that to a pretty real extent, like the,
Speaker 6:  the whatever the horse is out of the barn, the toothpaste is out of the tube,
Speaker 6:  whatever you want to pick on that one. That like the, this antitrust argument
Speaker 6:  that is starting to happen is like people like Lenahan and Jonathan Canter
Speaker 6:  are basically saying these things are really expensive to build. They're
Speaker 6:  really expensive to train. And inherently what that does is give too
Speaker 6:  much of the power and control and sort of the ability to make this stuff
Speaker 6:  to these big companies. Right? And it's why you look at open ai, which got
Speaker 6:  10 billion from Microsoft and it's why Microsoft is doing it and it's why
Speaker 6:  Google is doing it. There's just not that many out there. But that's changing
Speaker 6:  really, really, really, really fast. And some of this stuff is starting to
Speaker 6:  get open sourced and the training data is more available and we're hitting
Speaker 6:  this point where building one of these things from scratch is hard, but you
Speaker 6:  kind of don't have to anymore. Yep. Like there's just so much infrastructure
Speaker 6:  out there now that if you, like you're saying if I wanted to just go build
Speaker 6:  a large language model chatbot and have it be horrible, it's a hell of a
Speaker 6:  lot easier than it was 12 months ago and it's gonna be a hell of a lot easier
Speaker 6:  in 12 months than it is right now. Like I don't see how we can rewind that
Speaker 6:  from here.
Speaker 7:  See, I don't know if that's actually true because of
Speaker 7:  Getty Getty's a good example of this. They're the professional image library.
Speaker 7:  We use them, almost every single publication pays
Speaker 7:  Getty so that we can use their photos. They are
Speaker 7:  currently suing some of these ais because they've trained their data
Speaker 7:  on Getty Yeah. Images and didn't pay licenses for it. And
Speaker 7:  what can very easily happen there is Getty can say, you have to license
Speaker 7:  our entire data, like all of our images to train your data
Speaker 7:  set and we're gonna charge you thousands and thousands and probably millions
Speaker 7:  of dollars to do so. Or actually we're just gonna build
Speaker 7:  our own generator using our data set. And now we have
Speaker 7:  like our photo monopoly has gotten even larger. And I think
Speaker 7:  that's gonna be, we're seeing that with others too. Like people are starting
Speaker 7:  to say, Hey, you can't use my artwork to train your data because
Speaker 7:  of plagiarism. We saw that with the W G A accusing, like
Speaker 7:  just inherently using what's publicly available as
Speaker 7:  plagiarism. So I think that fight's still out there and
Speaker 7:  is going to continue to happen primarily in the court. And
Speaker 7:  that's gonna be a pretty significant component of this, I think.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I mean if there's a more verge story than AI copyright, I, I don't
Speaker 5:  know what it is. I'm lit
Speaker 7:  Up. Yeah, you just got very like the big grin on your face. You
Speaker 5:  Got another hour. Let's do it again. The the Copyright act was
Speaker 5:  like barely functional on the internet, right? Yeah. Like it barely
Speaker 5:  describes what people do on the internet. It is the thing that governs most
Speaker 5:  of our lives on the internet. It's like the default law. It's the only law
Speaker 5:  that counts. It's like a cliche in our newsroom.
Speaker 6:  Can I ask a question out of a really tortured metaphor that might not work
Speaker 6:  and we can cut it out
Speaker 5:  Shelf? What show do you think this is? Of course you should.
Speaker 6:  Is this or is this like the Napster moment of
Speaker 6:  this where it's like everything is free, everything is chaos. Take all this
Speaker 6:  stuff that belongs to somebody else, shove it into a pile. You can have it
Speaker 6:  any way you want. And like what you're talking about with Getty, it just
Speaker 6:  made me think of like the R I A A coming after people saying, you owe 60 billion
Speaker 6:  for the songs that you downloaded. And they successfully like
Speaker 6:  sued enough people to make them afraid and enough companies to run them outta
Speaker 6:  business that it sort of reverted back. And then it's like, okay, now we
Speaker 6:  need a different kind of model for that. Like are we in that first phase
Speaker 6:  now or is this just totally different not making that?
Speaker 7:  I, I think so. Yeah. I mean nea you, you, you feel you have stronger feelings
Speaker 7:  about copyright than I do and know more about
Speaker 5:  It. It's all I care about. All of my emotions are pointed. Copy.
Speaker 7:  What do you think?
Speaker 5:  I think that that there's a parallel there. I don't know if it's a direct
Speaker 5:  comparison. Like the music industry for all of its idiocy had a
Speaker 5:  point, right? Like you were making copies of the songs and
Speaker 5:  then giving those copies to other people, all right? Like at some point
Speaker 5:  they should have something was amiss there, right? Like
Speaker 5:  no one was capturing the value. The artists were working for free I think
Speaker 5:  many, many years later. My my position on should artists work for free
Speaker 5:  has changed from the time when I was like, music Napster the doorman. And
Speaker 5:  that was different, right? The the economic condition of the music
Speaker 5:  industry made them unsympathetic at that point in time, right? I was
Speaker 5:  like, Metallica's already rich. Like I'm just taking inner sand from them.
Speaker 5:  Like screw you Lars, right now. I think in 2023 there's
Speaker 5:  a lot more sympathy towards people who make things and whether
Speaker 5:  they should be compensated for those things and what's free and how you give
Speaker 5:  credit. And like the younger generations on the internet
Speaker 5:  are just much more attuned to like, oh, there's value extraction that happens
Speaker 5:  on the internet every single day and we should, artists should be rich. Like
Speaker 5:  we're mad at Spotify in general even though we won't stop using it because
Speaker 5:  the artists are always grumbling about how they don't get paid enough. And
Speaker 5:  just that sort of economic literacy of the internet is vastly different than
Speaker 5:  the Napster moment. That's, and so I think that's one piece of it. The second
Speaker 5:  piece of it, one more technical and I think will result in a number of
Speaker 5:  disastrously hilarious rulings from courts.
Speaker 5:  Because at the end of the day, like yes, it's training data but
Speaker 5:  the thing they make is not a copy.
Speaker 6:  Right? Yeah. It's a much less direct line from you burned a CD
Speaker 6:  and gave it to people on the internet. Like that's a very straight line.
Speaker 6:  How you get from, I wrote a screenplay to it, generated a different
Speaker 6:  screenplay maybe potentially with some knowledge of my screenplay
Speaker 6:  is different.
Speaker 5:  There is a copy that's being made in there. Like I, one of the things that
Speaker 5:  I think we forget about Cut all the time is like, it's still rooted in, in
Speaker 5:  Adams, right? It's rooted in the idea of like making copies.
Speaker 5:  It's, that's what it's called. And so there was a line of
Speaker 5:  cases that literally had to say every copy that a computer
Speaker 5:  made, it was legal. Like literally copying a program from
Speaker 5:  a disc onto the ram of a computer was a lawsuit, right? Cause
Speaker 5:  it's making a copy, right? And so we've kind of just like abstracted away
Speaker 5:  what computers do, which is just constantly make billions of copies all the
Speaker 5:  time for all kinds of reasons. And now we're gonna come back, I think to
Speaker 5:  okay, to use our images as your trading data. You have to copy
Speaker 5:  them all onto your disks. Just step one. Like was that
Speaker 5:  copy authorized? Did? Is that a, is that allowed? Is that legal?
Speaker 5:  And like we just haven't had to ask that question in the context of
Speaker 5:  computers for about 20 years and like we're just, that's gonna be Getty's
Speaker 5:  first argument. It's like, here's what open AI did. They went to Best Buy,
Speaker 5:  they bought all the Western digital hard drives that existed and
Speaker 5:  copied the, the Getty database onto them, right? And it's like,
Speaker 5:  wait, hold on, we're doing that because that's their opening salvo
Speaker 5:  best theory of the case. Like just making that database is a
Speaker 5:  copyright infringement and like we're just gonna, I think we're gonna go
Speaker 5:  back there in a weird way and maybe never get all the way to, and then we
Speaker 5:  created derivative works of those images
Speaker 5:  violating a computer, predict the next pixel in a sequence. I can talk about
Speaker 5:  this all day. Can we keep, we should probably move on. Addie and
Speaker 5:  Sarah, John and I are like lit up with the copyright story cuz it's so complicated
Speaker 5:  and so weird and like so many old internet laws
Speaker 5:  are coming back around, right? Foundational copyright cases of the internet
Speaker 5:  are kind of like up for grabs in really weird ways.
Speaker 5:  And I think that's gonna be, again, because the economic understanding
Speaker 5:  of how the internet works is so different now. They could go another
Speaker 5:  way. Hmm. Like the, the copyright cases that allowed Google to
Speaker 5:  exist and make image search happened in a wildly different economic
Speaker 5:  climate. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  The last time we were doing this, everybody was shouting about how, you know,
Speaker 6:  the internet wants to be free and information wants to be free. And we
Speaker 6:  don't look at it quite like that anymore, generally
Speaker 5:  Speaking. Yeah. Not, not even a little bit. Right? And like Google got rich
Speaker 5:  at, at the end of the day Google captured all the value and photographers
Speaker 5:  and musicians and whoever didn't. And like this is another one of those moments.
Speaker 5:  And I, I just think that economic understanding of the trade off of
Speaker 5:  information wants to be free is a lot, is a lot clearer for people.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Last we should just note this, there was a really well reported piece
Speaker 5:  in the information this week claiming that Bard was birthed
Speaker 5:  in conflict at Google, including a researcher leaving the
Speaker 5:  team because he claimed that Bard was trained
Speaker 5:  using chat G p T data through a tool called Shared G P T.
Speaker 5:  Google has denied it. They gave a statement to us, we have it on the site.
Speaker 5:  Bard is not trained on any data from shared G P T or chat G P T. It's a very
Speaker 5:  clear denial, but I think it is just worth pointing out
Speaker 5:  even throughout this conversation. We've mostly talked about startups, right?
Speaker 5:  There's Microsoft on the side, but open AI is a new company, mid Journey
Speaker 5:  is a new company. The big companies are still finding their footing,
Speaker 5:  right? Or they've just bought into it in the case of Microsoft, right? Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Or Bard. Okay, here's let's wrap, I'm gonna wrap this up with two
Speaker 5:  instructions. One, if you work at Google and you're on the Bard team, let
Speaker 5:  that shit be horny. It'll work. Just horn it up.
Speaker 5:  Just let part flirt man it it's got swag W RZ
Speaker 5:  from Bard. It's like that's put that on the on the board.
Speaker 5:  And then two, if you operate a radio telescope of any kind or
Speaker 5:  anything that can send signals in a deep space, I'm gonna give you this audio
Speaker 5:  clip. Just broadcast it as much as you can. Swag Pope
Speaker 5:  is important of doom. You have 25 years
Speaker 5:  left. If you see a drippy pope, citizens of the
Speaker 5:  Galaxy, galaxy swag Pope is a signal of doom.
Speaker 5:  End message. And if you could just send that to space, I think,
Speaker 5:  I think we'll be doing a surface to all the, it's so weird a time traveler
Speaker 5:  just showed up and said, I heard he's straight here. Swag.
Speaker 5:  Pope is doomed.
Speaker 5:  All right, we gotta take a break.
Speaker 7:  Sport for today's show comes from Deloitte. What does a future look like?
Speaker 7:  It's a question that drives progress, but more importantly, how do you
Speaker 7:  get there? It's curiosity, resourcefulness and bold ideas that
Speaker 7:  can drive us even further than new technology. Because while technology can
Speaker 7:  take you far human exploration could take you even farther. Deloitte
Speaker 7:  helps businesses build the future only they can imagine by melding deep business
Speaker 7:  acumen and innovative technology with a vast team of tech savvy
Speaker 7:  professionals. Unlock technology as powerful as your vision and push
Speaker 7:  the boundaries of the possible so that you can stay a step ahead with the
Speaker 7:  thinking to help you transform what's next into what's now helping
Speaker 7:  you see the extraordinary potential in the seemingly ordinary while blending
Speaker 7:  the possible with the practical is what Deloitte does. See how you can
Speaker 7:  engineer advantage with Deloitte at
Speaker 7:  deloitte.com/us/engineering advantage.
Speaker 9:  The all new Chevy Colorado is made for more stacked with the latest
Speaker 9:  in vehicle technologies like a class leading 11 inch diagonal center
Speaker 9:  touchscreen and an extra large wireless charging pad. Plus it
Speaker 9:  features wireless apple CarPlay and Android auto compatibility to make staying
Speaker 9:  connected easy wherever your adventure takes you. Chevy Colorado
Speaker 9:  made for more. Learn more at
Speaker 9:  chevrolet.com/truck/colorado claims based on latest
Speaker 9:  competitive data.
Speaker 5:  Alright, we're back. Let's talk about some gadgets or promised
Speaker 5:  gadgets soon to be gadgets. Gadgets that might also be important of
Speaker 5:  doom but not for us. For Apple.
Speaker 7:  Just apple.
Speaker 5:  So WW C was announced this week, June 5th. We will
Speaker 5:  probably send an army of people, we could do the preview like WW C is
Speaker 5:  kinda like a known quantity in the base level, right? Yeah. They announced
Speaker 5:  the new versions of iOS, Mac os, t V os, home os all
Speaker 5:  oss watch os and then maybe we usually see a previous
Speaker 5:  hardware this year. That piece of the puzzle
Speaker 5:  is loaded with meaning, right? Yes. Because people think it's gonna be the
Speaker 5:  big mixed reality headset and there's like a lot of
Speaker 5:  reporting about it in a way that is unusual in
Speaker 5:  tone and unusual in volume I would say.
Speaker 6:  Okay. I'm really glad you said that cuz I was actually trying to remember
Speaker 6:  in prepping for this, if there has ever been a sort of run
Speaker 6:  up to an Apple product quite like this one because like when the Apple Watch
Speaker 6:  launched there was a lot of smoke that there was gonna be a watch. That's
Speaker 6:  kind of all we knew about it, right? But it feels like as Apple gets ready
Speaker 6:  to come out with its mixed reality headset, which we think is likely to
Speaker 6:  come at WWDC that we should get into why suddenly there's questions about
Speaker 6:  that. We know a shocking amount about what the thing is gonna cost, what
Speaker 6:  it's gonna do, what it looks like, how it works, how people at Apple feel
Speaker 6:  about it. Like is this, can you remember another time when it feels like
Speaker 6:  a product Apple is working on this much feels like it has been sort of out
Speaker 6:  there in the world this much ahead of time.
Speaker 5:  The iPad, was it?
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Did
Speaker 7:  The iPad have that same like sense of just the
Speaker 7:  grimace emoji that seems to be surrounding the mixed reality headset?
Speaker 6:  Well it did right after because everybody thought the name iPad was stupid,
Speaker 6:  but I actually don't remember if it was there before.
Speaker 5:  No, it definitely had more hopes and dreams, but if you just remember,
Speaker 5:  they had to like go to the media like Steve Jobs and Asie iPad and he was
Speaker 5:  like, it's, this is the future of newspapers and magazines. So like, and
Speaker 5:  then remember like Rippert Murdoch made the daily Oh
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  R i p The Daily, which was actually great. And the staff of the Daily has
Speaker 5:  gone on to do amazing things around the hundred. Yeah. Because he assembled
Speaker 5:  like an amazing team to make that, what was it? It was like an iPad app that
Speaker 5:  updated with news every day and then it failed because
Speaker 6:  You could turn pages. It was the most like anachronistic thing I think Apple
Speaker 6:  has ever done. It was amazing. They made a print magazine that you could
Speaker 6:  only read on the iPad. It
Speaker 5:  Was like truly strange. Right? But like, because they had made all those
Speaker 5:  deals, like a lot of people had awareness of the iPad. Yeah. Yeah. And, and
Speaker 5:  like pre-baked good thoughts about the iPad. Like they were rooted in
Speaker 5:  actual experiences. So like I would just like remind you like yes, the iPad
Speaker 5:  was that thing where the hype around it was so high and
Speaker 5:  enough people had like, sort of used it that there was like a a
Speaker 5:  level of doubts, right? If you remember it's just a big iPhone was like
Speaker 5:  the Totally. And that was correct. Yeah. It turns out
Speaker 5:  years later it's a, it's a big iPhone with some features of the Mac and it
Speaker 5:  should just be a Mac remains the, the gestalt of the iPad. Yep.
Speaker 5:  But this one is different. It's more than that. Right? And I think
Speaker 5:  it's because the iPad was obvious, like in the best possible way. Sure.
Speaker 5:  You should make a really big iPhone. People love iPhones. People will
Speaker 5:  love this thing. Yeah. And there's all kinds of stuff you could do. You can
Speaker 5:  just imagine where it will go. You can imagine how to make it right, like
Speaker 5:  make the screen bigger and like whatever.
Speaker 6:  Right. You made a thing that's all screened do more Screen
Speaker 5:  Apple now with the mixed reality headset is operating in the context of,
Speaker 5:  well we have them, they exist as products. Most of,
Speaker 5:  there's the meta quests pro sitting right behind me on that shelf there is
Speaker 5:  not been charged in weeks, months. You know, like
Speaker 5:  whatever.
Speaker 6:  You're you're out on the supernatural. You're not boxing
Speaker 5:  Anymore. I, no, I use the Quest two for that. Oh. Oh. It's lighter and simpler
Speaker 5:  and that's fair. Right? And it doesn't have 90 cameras. It's not trying to
Speaker 5:  do a thing that no one wants to do. Yeah. Right. It's just, it's a game console.
Speaker 5:  I have a p I have a review unit or the PSVR two in the other room
Speaker 5:  and I spend all my chase points on a Logitech racing wheel.
Speaker 5:  And I gotta tell you, grand Tomo in the PSVR two is the single best
Speaker 5:  experience you can have. It makes me sick after 20 minutes, but boy
Speaker 5:  do I wanna not be sick again so I can go spend another 20 minutes in it.
Speaker 5:  It's so fun. Right? And like as game consoles, like that's really cool.
Speaker 5:  I I cannot recommend that experience. Now Sean Holster wrote about it and
Speaker 5:  I immediately figured out how to have this experience of like VR racing
Speaker 5:  game cuz it's so cool. That's not a market that's big enough for Apple.
Speaker 5:  They've gotta do a thing here. So Alex Heath, when he was at the information
Speaker 5:  broke the price like $3,000. That was his scoop. It's held up so far.
Speaker 5:  Yep. And then there's this stack of problems that we just know
Speaker 5:  really well because of the meta quests too. And just the reality of what
Speaker 5:  these problems are. Like you've gotta build a headset that doesn't look
Speaker 5:  ridiculous. Very few people have accomplished this. Maybe no one has,
Speaker 6:  Okay, zero people have accomplished this yet.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. They're just familiar now. They're not not ridiculous. Right? It's
Speaker 5:  like clowns, like, you know what a clown looks like. You're not like, oh
Speaker 5:  my God, a click no, that's ridiculous, but like a familiar way just there.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. You've gotta, it's gotta have a processor in it. It's gotta have a
Speaker 5:  display system that doesn't suck all the power. It's gotta have a bunch of
Speaker 5:  cameras. You've gotta process the cameras in real time and augment the information.
Speaker 5:  Like we've done this stack on the ver has a hundred times the problems here
Speaker 5:  at every level are novel computing problems. Yes. And then you, you're
Speaker 5:  constrained in power and battery life and all this stuff. And so Apple's
Speaker 5:  solutions, as far as we understand are like external battery pack.
Speaker 5:  They don't want you to wear it all day. Really high priced to make it clear
Speaker 5:  this is not a mass consumer product. And then this reporting
Speaker 5:  that we that's come out over the past few weeks, we're like, they're searching
Speaker 5:  for a killer app. Mark Gurman said this will have the same curve as the watch.
Speaker 5:  Like that's their hope. And if you'll recall, the watch launched, it was
Speaker 5:  really messy. The battery life was constrained and then they figured out
Speaker 5:  as a fitness tracker with notifications and now people love it. And also
Speaker 5:  they use their ecosystem lock in ruthlessly to make sure it has no
Speaker 5:  competition for iOS owners, whatever. But here it's like
Speaker 5:  every layer, there's a novel technology problem and there's no killer app
Speaker 5:  because they're not gonna do Grand Tomo VR on a $3,000 headset.
Speaker 5:  They're just not gonna do it. And also they suck at games like
Speaker 5:  yes they have Apple Arcade, but you're, you're, you are just not gonna buy
Speaker 5:  a $3,000 headset to play Monument Valley. You know? It's like, it's
Speaker 6:  Not gonna happen. Well apparently the thing that they're talking the most
Speaker 6:  about is, I think Tim Cook keeps calling it co-presence has been the,
Speaker 6:  the thing that's been reported is basically really great video
Speaker 6:  chat and this feeling like, you know, I can see through your eyes
Speaker 6:  because you're wearing the headset and it's looking out and that's,
Speaker 5:  That shit's gonna make people vomit all over everything all the time. Can
Speaker 6:  You imagine? Yes, a hundred percent. And even to the extent that like that
Speaker 6:  is, is cool as far as it goes. Like I think we've all arrived
Speaker 6:  at a point where we've decided that Google Meet and Zoom
Speaker 6:  are pretty good for what they do. And the bar for
Speaker 6:  like, let me get dedicated hardware to have a meeting every single
Speaker 6:  time is, is so much higher than anybody realizes. And like,
Speaker 6:  this is what Meta has been trying to do for a while. They're like, what if
Speaker 6:  instead of having a Zoom meeting, you had a meeting in Horizons. Yeah. And
Speaker 6:  you all sat around a table and didn't have legs and made weird faces at each
Speaker 6:  other. And it's like, actually no one wants that. Well
Speaker 5:  I will say Horizons is so hard to use that I don't
Speaker 5:  even know if I don't want that. Right. I know for a fact
Speaker 5:  I do not want to use their software.
Speaker 6:  Yes.
Speaker 5:  That's the, like without question the idea, I have the remote
Speaker 5:  desktop server on my Mac and they're constantly updating it like every
Speaker 5:  day. It's like a new version of the meta quests remote desktop. It's like,
Speaker 5:  why like, shouldn't you spend all your engineering effort? I'm like
Speaker 5:  joining a meeting and not having it crash.
Speaker 6:  Well, so that's kind of the thing. Right? And this is what you're talking
Speaker 6:  about, about having to solve all these problems simultaneously. Like, have
Speaker 6:  you ever seen the movie The Kingsman? Yeah. Yes. So do you know the thing
Speaker 6:  in the Kingsman where to have a meeting, you sit down and you basically put
Speaker 6:  on a pair of like Wayfair sunglasses and immediately
Speaker 6:  around you, you sort of sit at your chair at the table and everybody else
Speaker 6:  is sitting at the same table in other places in the world and their, their
Speaker 6:  holograms show up with you. So it appears roughly as if you're all sitting
Speaker 6:  at the table super into that. That sounds great. Short of that, I
Speaker 6:  suspect almost every experience that isn't that
Speaker 6:  sucks. Okay. And will be more work than it's worth to just talk to your
Speaker 6:  coworkers or friends.
Speaker 7:  What if the mixed reality headset let you have feet?
Speaker 5:  That's the big winner.
Speaker 7:  That's the
Speaker 6:  Winner. Right? $5,000 I
Speaker 5:  Has already promised feet or the oh, the, the brightest mind technology,
Speaker 5:  to
Speaker 6:  Be fair, he feet, legs, we have not talked about feet yet. Feet is like,
Speaker 6:  that's a apple's
Speaker 7:  Gonna go. Apple's gonna skip legs and go straight to feet and you're gonna
Speaker 7:  be like,
Speaker 6:  You have no legs but feet.
Speaker 7:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  You're
Speaker 6:  Just feet in hands. Nothing else.
Speaker 5:  It's like this emoji it's that, you know, like the the emoji that's just
Speaker 5:  the the face with the hands.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 7:  You're now feet.
Speaker 5:  So the Kingsman thing is like, that's what everybody wants. Yes. Right. That's,
Speaker 5:  that's a useful analogy for this, that movies also really funny. You should
Speaker 5:  go, it's a
Speaker 6:  Great movie. Everybody should watch it. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  But every time I see that scene, I'm like, okay, how do you know what chair
Speaker 5:  everyone's in? How do they know it? Like they're not, are they all in the
Speaker 5:  same room but the room is empty?
Speaker 6:  No. They all, yes, they all have the same room. I think, I could be wrong
Speaker 6:  about this, I haven't seen,
Speaker 5:  But do they all sit like, what if you screw up and you everyone sits at the
Speaker 5:  head of the table? Well, like, just the amount of,
Speaker 6:  There's a lot of laps sitting happening, like
Speaker 5:  The future,
Speaker 6:  Like sitting on each other's laps by accident. Who's,
Speaker 5:  That's what it's, and then you need a picture of them, of their faces.
Speaker 5:  Right. And if you're wearing this Apple headset, you've gotta recreate that
Speaker 5:  face. So like you're just creating this like stack of
Speaker 5:  problems that is vastly more expensive and vastly more
Speaker 5:  complicated and vastly less reliable than getting on a plane.
Speaker 6:  Yes. And I think my, my running theory is if you solve 60%
Speaker 6:  of that problem, you've made everything worse. And that, that actually
Speaker 6:  the only way to do it is to fully all the way
Speaker 6:  completely do it. And I, I think like
Speaker 6:  one of the things that it seems possible that Apple is gonna do is basically
Speaker 6:  render big screens as you use these things that I think rather than
Speaker 6:  try to do some of the AR stuff, it'll just kind of look like you have a big
Speaker 6:  floating screen in front of your face. And that is substantially less exciting,
Speaker 6:  but mitigates some of the like crappy, uncanny valley of all of this, I think.
Speaker 6:  But yeah, I just, I, I have such a hard time imagining that Apple has
Speaker 6:  solved every single one of these problems in its fullest way
Speaker 6:  in order to be able to do this. And I think it's a real bummer for Apple.
Speaker 6:  Like if I work at Apple, I'm really, really upset that all of this is coming
Speaker 6:  out because even to the extent that it's gonna dull the hype. So
Speaker 5:  This is the reporting, we should bring this all the way back around. This
Speaker 5:  is the reporting, right? This is what you and I are both noticing. One of
Speaker 5:  the stories is the design team didn't wanna ship it and Tim Cook overruled
Speaker 5:  them. Ooh. Now obviously I think every story like this is,
Speaker 5:  people will tell you it's too simple. That's not how it actually, like it's
Speaker 5:  a big company, lots of process, but like that's a story that somebody wanted
Speaker 5:  told, right? There's a group of people who thought this isn't ready yet.
Speaker 5:  Yep. And we shouldn't do it. There's other stories about people being worried
Speaker 5:  about the price. There's other stories about people saying there's not a
Speaker 5:  killer app and like co-presence like this isn't gonna do it. I don't wanna
Speaker 5:  knock this. Right? Like it's, if you can get to AR glasses, which is where
Speaker 5:  Apple wants to go, which is where Meadow wants to go, I, that is the
Speaker 5:  dream. Like I was,
Speaker 6:  Is awesome. I really, really, really do
Speaker 5:  Well, I know it's a killer app for AR glasses is it's faces and names. Like
Speaker 5:  I was just at the ASME awards where the Verge won an award for
Speaker 5:  best print design. It was great. And I was sitting next to Anna Wintour when
Speaker 5:  we won the award for best print design and I screamed, it's a website and
Speaker 5:  that will go down. I mean it truly one of the most hilarious achievements
Speaker 5:  of our careers. And I mean that in both senses. It's an achievement, right?
Speaker 5:  The Homeland Series was very complicated. There's a lot of incredible reporting
Speaker 5:  on it. We made a zine that was really difficult. It's beautiful.
Speaker 5:  Christian Raki or Art Tractor like did a beautiful job with it. But we're,
Speaker 5:  we won best print award. Like that's hilarious.
Speaker 5:  And so like have it announced or we're sitting next to like Conde Nastro,
Speaker 5:  like hilarious. It was so good. But I was like at a thing and I was like,
Speaker 5:  look at all these people. And I was like, man, if I could just put names
Speaker 5:  to these faces, I'd be like king of the universe. I'd be honest to vote Patel
Speaker 5:  man. Like let's do it. And like I want that. I
Speaker 5:  insurmountable problems all the way to, you need a worldwide database of
Speaker 5:  faces and names, which seems bad. Facebook has it though,
Speaker 5:  but boy would I buy that product in one second. But to your point, David,
Speaker 5:  that's a hundred percent, 60% of that product is a $3,000 headset
Speaker 5:  with an external battery pack that doesn't actually do augmented reality
Speaker 5:  does pass through video mixed
Speaker 6:  Reality. And it just says like, I think that guy's name is Bill.
Speaker 5:  And it's like, because it's Apple and their privacy thing, it's like super
Speaker 5:  wrong all the time. Exactly. Like
Speaker 5:  you can see why there's drama around this product and why, you know,
Speaker 5:  to some extent they're, they're actively lowering expectations for
Speaker 7:  It. This is also like probably the most ambitious
Speaker 7:  Apple's been in a while, right? Like Apple's whole mo, I think they even
Speaker 7:  mention it in the New York Times piece about people being
Speaker 7:  nervous and not really wanting this thing to go out was that Apple
Speaker 7:  usually waits until the markets kind of mature. Like when the Apple Watch
Speaker 7:  came out, Fitbit was already huge. People were wearing these bands all the
Speaker 7:  time. So people were like, oh yeah, it's a new band but it's better. The
Speaker 7:  iPhone was the same thing. Smartphones had been around for a while. They
Speaker 7:  just figured out pension zoom better laptops, everything. And this time they're
Speaker 7:  like, yeah, this market is not mature. It has not proven itself
Speaker 7:  in any way, shape or form. We're gonna do it anyway. And that's just super
Speaker 7:  unlike Apple.
Speaker 5:  So I would make the comparison to the watch, right? They did create the smartwatch
Speaker 5:  market like the Pebble existed, but everyone kind of knew that wasn't
Speaker 5:  it? You know? Yeah. They created a modern smartphone market like
Speaker 5:  Noki existed and I'm sure people are gonna start sending us any angry emails,
Speaker 5:  but like those phones were not mainstream in this country. They were in some
Speaker 5:  cases mainstream in
Speaker 7:  Europe. They, they took something that was already deeply flawed. Like they,
Speaker 7:  these were, these were other places where it was super, super deeply flawed
Speaker 7:  and Apple said, we're gonna make it perfect. And they did.
Speaker 5:  Right? So the Steve Jobs used to be able to put up the photos of the competitor
Speaker 5:  products and be like, look at this shit. Right? I fixed it right With the
Speaker 5:  watch, they were not able to do that. Right? And this is kind of like Tim
Speaker 5:  Cook's legacy is he's pushing 'em into categories that have not yet been
Speaker 5:  defined. And the watch was a real mess. And the thing with the
Speaker 5:  watch was that it had conviction behind it. This is what Johnny
Speaker 5:  Ive wanted to do. We, we had Trip Mickel on the show. He wrote the great
Speaker 5:  book about Johnny and Tim and the legacy of after Steve there.
Speaker 5:  This is like Johnny, ive wanted to do it. It's a product that made sense.
Speaker 5:  Like intuitively you're like, do I want a computer on my wrist? And everyone
Speaker 5:  thinks about Dick Tracy and the answer is yes.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, a hundred percent.
Speaker 5:  They didn't know what it should do. And the battery life was a mess and the
Speaker 5:  screen was all this stuff. But they knew that like this category should definitely
Speaker 5:  exist and it, there's enough value
Speaker 5:  that is like articulable, like you can say what the value will be if we get
Speaker 5:  everything right along the way.
Speaker 6:  Well, and even to the extent that they were wrong about what the watch was
Speaker 6:  for, which is I think the, the like legacy of the watch and as we've talked
Speaker 6:  about is that Apple was right about the hardware and totally wrong about
Speaker 6:  what people were gonna use it for. And it took a few years for them to realize,
Speaker 6:  oh this is just fitness and health, right? Like we can stack out their stuff
Speaker 6:  on top of it, but fundamentally what people really want is a better Fitbit.
Speaker 6:  So they just built a better Fitbit and now here we are. But it, they were
Speaker 6:  right to your point in Eli that like what people wanted was on their
Speaker 6:  wrist, what they wanted on their wrist, apple was wrong about, but they were
Speaker 6:  like, we can, we can focus on this space and figure it out. What is not at
Speaker 6:  all clear is if people want stuff on their face Yeah.
Speaker 5:  For any amount of time.
Speaker 6:  Like not even a little bit clearer. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Back in the watch days I had this, I like a formula
Speaker 5:  for thinking about it, which is like the more it touches your body, the less
Speaker 5:  you, the more value it has to provide and the less you should care for it.
Speaker 5:  And you can just like, that's a good monkey with the variables. And so my,
Speaker 5:  my best example was glasses, right? Glasses are pretty finicky. You have
Speaker 5:  to care for them. You can't break them If you break them like you're really
Speaker 5:  screwed. Like I do not drive anywhere. I worry about losing my contact lenses
Speaker 5:  all the time. Like right? So there's a lot of care in there on your body,
Speaker 5:  but the amount of value they provide to you is immense. So you just like
Speaker 5:  put up with it and you don't think about it too much. And then there's like
Speaker 5:  clothes where depending on your relationship to clothes, if you're the swag
Speaker 5:  pope or you're just like me, you know, there's a big spectrum of how much
Speaker 5:  you might care about your clothes. We actually care for them a lot, but they
Speaker 5:  provide value. They make you feel good about your solid stuff. And the watch
Speaker 5:  was like, it was wrong and a bunch of the variables in the beginning, right?
Speaker 5:  It didn't, wasn't useful enough. It was like kind of hard to use you to care
Speaker 5:  for it a lot. You charge battery every day and it was like on your wrist
Speaker 5:  and like they just got it wrong in the beginning. Like they really increased
Speaker 5:  the value and helped fitness. They made it easier to care for, right? The
Speaker 5:  batteries started lasting longer and like they, they aligned that
Speaker 5:  equation such that the watch is like a really good pro. Like I really like
Speaker 5:  my Apple Watch Ultra. Do I worry that everyone can read every notification
Speaker 5:  that I ever read from like a hundred meters away like I do, but like I still
Speaker 5:  love it. The face computer zone, those equations are just completely
Speaker 5:  outta whack, right? They're like almost all universally hard to use. You
Speaker 5:  have to care for them a lot. You have to put them on your face and they like
Speaker 5:  don't do anything. The best thing that you can do in them is play games.
Speaker 5:  And like I, again, if you are a Grando person, go
Speaker 5:  spend all over the money on Psvr two and play grand. Like it is great.
Speaker 5:  It is an incredible experience, but that's it.
Speaker 5:  You know, like none of the other stuff is quite there yet. And
Speaker 5:  I like, I just, I I should, we should come back to this equation around headset
Speaker 5:  time and like try to lay it out. Yeah. If people have thoughts on like what
Speaker 5:  that equation is like, what the variables are, but like it's a really helpful
Speaker 5:  way of understanding like the second you strap it to your body, like
Speaker 5:  you sort of have to, the amount of value you have to deliver starts going
Speaker 5:  up in a way that is just enormous.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Yeah. Well and I think one of the interesting things about
Speaker 6:  all of this is that I think Apple has been so
Speaker 6:  successful that it's gonna have a really hard time launching this thing
Speaker 6:  even as it knows and will say as many times as it can. This
Speaker 6:  thing is $3,000, it's new, we're still learning, it's an
Speaker 6:  experiment, whatever. It's like Apple doesn't get to do that
Speaker 6:  anymore, right? Like when was the last time Apple launched something that
Speaker 6:  they didn't claim was gonna like change the course of your life in history
Speaker 5:  Apple TV see drives like is hobby and they're still kinda like,
Speaker 5:  ugh. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  I mean that's, that's a really good example. And I would say if the, if
Speaker 6:  Apples mixed reality plans go the way of Apple tv,
Speaker 6:  that's, that's a real rough look.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. They are not allowed to say that this is a hobby. No. Even though absolutely
Speaker 6:  Not. I don't, I don't think it's a hobby. I think it's as so much as it is
Speaker 6:  like this is a science experiment that they're shipping to you, right? They're
Speaker 6:  like, some people will buy this, this, it'll be good for some things. But
Speaker 6:  Tim Cook is gonna get up and he's gonna talk about the reality dial,
Speaker 6:  which is an unbelievable name for a thing. It's how you control how
Speaker 6:  much of the world you can see versus how much of a VR thing. And he's gonna
Speaker 6:  say things about it being a revolutionary input mechanism on par with the
Speaker 6:  mouse and the touchscreen. Like it's, this is just what Apple does. And I
Speaker 6:  have such a hard time imagining any other pitch and if
Speaker 6:  they make the classic Apple pitch, I think there's a pretty good chance this
Speaker 6:  ends up in a really weird place.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I don't think that they can, I even the fact that we're hearing this
Speaker 5:  much dissent now in their reporting is like I, they have to know they
Speaker 5:  can't make the, like it
Speaker 6:  Does make you wonder if it's strategic. If there's like, if they're like,
Speaker 6:  oh you think this is dumb, let me give you Trip Michael's phone number.
Speaker 5:  I dunno about that. That's very unlike them. But it No, that's like three
Speaker 5:  takes too clever, you know, like let's undercut ourselves before. But I do
Speaker 5:  think it's reflective of the volume of dissent inside the company. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Like go back, I said this so many times, but go back and watch
Speaker 5:  the Apple Watch introduction. They were so high in their own
Speaker 5:  fumes. Oh yeah, yeah, right. Like Bono was there,
Speaker 5:  do you remember this saying like, Christie Turton was there to talk about
Speaker 5:  running marathons in Africa. Like it was crazy. And
Speaker 5:  they, they, I'm not saying this product is not successful again, I really
Speaker 5:  like mine. I'm just saying like their belief in
Speaker 5:  could they just reassemble the pieces of past success. It
Speaker 5:  was like a Marvel phase three movie. They're like, remember the Avengers,
Speaker 5:  here's that movie again. But like with different worse actors
Speaker 5:  like, and like they, they cannot
Speaker 5:  do that again. And because this product is, it can't support
Speaker 5:  the weight of those expectations. The watch could not support the weight
Speaker 5:  of those
Speaker 6:  Expectations. But on the flip side, what Apple needs desperately to do is
Speaker 6:  convince people that this is the future. And especially right now we're in
Speaker 6:  this moment where I think a lot of people are souring on the whole idea of
Speaker 6:  the metaverse and you know, ar and VR as the next big thing. And
Speaker 6:  we're seeing all these companies like, didn't Disney just lay off its whole
Speaker 6:  Metaverse division got
Speaker 7:  Rid of the whole thing.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Like that. That's not nothing. Right. And so now the, the weight of
Speaker 6:  all this has kind of always been and feels even more so on Apple to
Speaker 6:  say this, this is the thing, right? Like this is where we are headed.
Speaker 6:  Developers come build for this content, people come make content for this.
Speaker 6:  So Apple, apple kind of has to and can't sandbag
Speaker 6:  itself at the same time.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. They're, they're the same position meta's in where they've
Speaker 7:  invested too much time and energy into this thing to give
Speaker 7:  up. They just have to like close their eyes and keep going and hope
Speaker 7:  it turns out fine. Probably not. Cuz that seems like it'd be bad for their
Speaker 7:  bottom line. But,
Speaker 5:  But what is the pressure to do this? I
Speaker 7:  Think it's because they, they've put so much time and effort into it already.
Speaker 7:  Like I think
Speaker 5:  They, they they have started and stopped a car company
Speaker 5:  40
Speaker 7:  Times. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Right. Like they don't, they're, they've
Speaker 7:  Actually done twice in the recording of this podcast by the way.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Project Titan has been shut down and restarted twice.
Speaker 5:  Doug Field has gone from Ford to Apple and Tesla five more times.
Speaker 5:  No, I'm just like for real. Like the yeah, like what is the pressure?
Speaker 5:  It's not meta beating them.
Speaker 7:  Like I think it's this grand desire to have the next iPhone to have the
Speaker 7:  next hardware device that can drive computing forward the same
Speaker 7:  way the iPhone did. Right? Like the iPhone was a c change. It it, it
Speaker 7:  changed how, how we use our devices. There's a whole generation of people
Speaker 7:  who don't know how to search files on their computer because they've only
Speaker 7:  used their smartphone all this time and
Speaker 5:  I told you this would happen.
Speaker 7:  You, you like totally vindicated and
Speaker 5:  The kids are so confused.
Speaker 7:  So confused. Do not tell them what a file tree is.
Speaker 7:  They will not know. But I like that was, that was like
Speaker 7:  the, the major impetus behind this, right? Like they wanted to find the next
Speaker 7:  iPhone and then they've invested in it. And then Silicon Valley as we've
Speaker 7:  seen is really prone to groupthink and I think it kind of, I
Speaker 7:  don't wanna say infected, but it did it like infected Silicon Valley. Everybody
Speaker 7:  was like we have to have the next mixed reality thing. And then it just so
Speaker 7:  happened that Tim Cook and Mark Zuckerberg were two of the people totally
Speaker 7:  convinced by that. And now we're going off on this like
Speaker 7:  weird path into spacial computing when we're not quite ready
Speaker 7:  for it yet. That's
Speaker 6:  The thing, you know what's the move is Tim Cook should come out at WW C
Speaker 6:  and be like, look we thought this was the moment we thought it was gonna
Speaker 6:  happen. It's not, we're not the world we're
Speaker 6:  this isn't ready, it's not done. Cuz I think if, if you rewind a couple years
Speaker 6:  ago when we first started hearing about this, it was very clear to everyone
Speaker 6:  that by now every other company on earth was going to have made a headset,
Speaker 6:  right? Yes. And we were gonna, in this giant race, Google was gonna be out
Speaker 6:  there, HTC was building stuff, HoloLens was gonna be huge. There was this
Speaker 6:  big race and now it is the opposite. It's like we're back in the phase
Speaker 6:  of like, is this actually anything? And it feels like Apple
Speaker 6:  is about to finish a race. It's kind of not needing to
Speaker 6:  run at the moment. And
Speaker 5:  Yeah, that's what I mean. Like what is the wouldn't it be better if Apple
Speaker 5:  was like we've built generative AI tools into iOS.
Speaker 6:  I think at this point it can, yeah for a lot of reasons.
Speaker 6:  Presumably like production and all that stuff. But even just like from a
Speaker 6:  sort of pers like the world's perspective of Apple thing, like
Speaker 6:  there's too much out there now. Like the perception is already that this
Speaker 6:  thing is coming late and it's been a problem and it kind of like,
Speaker 6:  I believe it needs to do what it did with air power, which is be like nevermind
Speaker 6:  this doesn't work, we'll come back to you later. Or it has to ship
Speaker 6:  the thing and just like bully everyone into believing in it
Speaker 6:  until there's actually something good here. Like I don't, I don't necessarily
Speaker 6:  know that it has another move at this point. Even though I think it would
Speaker 6:  be badass if Tim Cook came out and he was like, look we built this headset,
Speaker 6:  it's rad. I don't wanna talk about it cuz it's not done yet. Like that would
Speaker 6:  be amazing.
Speaker 7:  Chuck it off stage.
Speaker 5:  When I think about things Tim Cook is likely to
Speaker 6:  Do, listen,
Speaker 5:  I'm not saying it's likely canceling a product live on stage. Yes.
Speaker 5:  After showing it to you that's high on the list.
Speaker 6:  Be badass though.
Speaker 7:  It'd be really cool.
Speaker 5:  He's like, all right Jeff, take over. I'm out.
Speaker 6:  He just sits down, puts it on and just kicks back on stage.
Speaker 5:  I'm just gonna read the rest of the Apple things and we're gonna take a break,
Speaker 5:  do a lighting round. iOS 16.4 is here, it has a bunch of new emoji.
Speaker 5:  Importantly for the six people who care, Google P now
Speaker 5:  supports 5G on the iPhone as of 16.4
Speaker 6:  To you as one of those six people. Congratulations.
Speaker 5:  It was great. I mean now it's, it's basically now I have at and t and T-Mobile
Speaker 5:  on my phone but I can turn the T-Mobile on and off whenever I want. I love
Speaker 5:  that. Which is actually really useful if you're the sort of person who like
Speaker 5:  constantly has phones like floating through your life, right? So very cool.
Speaker 5:  Thank you finally for solving this extremely stupid problem. I love it.
Speaker 5:  Also the new architecture for the home app back again for round two. We'll
Speaker 5:  see you guys are gonna have Jen on the Wednesday show to talk about sidewalk.
Speaker 5:  You should talk about what's going on with Matter too.
Speaker 6:  We are, that's we, we teased that this week because we got, we got a
Speaker 6:  hotline question that was like a bunch of other stuff and then it was like
Speaker 6:  what's going on with Matter? And I was like we can't do this here Jen. Like
Speaker 6:  we have to not but we're gonna do it next week so stick around.
Speaker 5:  Yeah because Amazon launched its sidewalk, low range IOT
Speaker 5:  network that's like every Alexa is now a little little wireless node.
Speaker 5:  It's very cool. But the new architecture and
Speaker 5:  home is out to so little smartphone, little smart home stuff going on in
Speaker 5:  the background there. Apple Buy now pay later is finally launching, which
Speaker 5:  took them forever. It seems like that moment of
Speaker 5:  unrestrained pandemic spending might be
Speaker 6:  Over. Yes.
Speaker 5:  So whatever.
Speaker 6:  And then And also the whole buy now pay later industry might be over.
Speaker 5:  Yeah that
Speaker 5:  and then Apple Music Classical also come
Speaker 6:  Out. Yeah. Wait, crayons. I just wanna know your thoughts on classical before
Speaker 6:  we take a break because Yeah, I a lot of enthusiasm about this
Speaker 7:  App. I've been using it since it came out. I don't consider
Speaker 7:  myself a classical music fan, but then when we were all talking about it,
Speaker 7:  I guess I am one who knew.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. You like classical music name five composers.
Speaker 7:  I can, but I'm not gonna do that because I don't trust my pronunciation of
Speaker 7:  their names. That's,
Speaker 6:  That was a trick. Well
Speaker 7:  I really, really like the app. I wish the regular Apple Music
Speaker 7:  app was actually this just because I like all the different
Speaker 7:  metadata. I like that I can just look things up by composer and not have
Speaker 7:  a bunch of garbage that I don't care about. Like every time I look up Steven
Speaker 7:  Sondheim in the regular app, it's like do you wanna listen to Steven
Speaker 7:  Sondheim talk? And I'm like no, I just wanna see a list of
Speaker 7:  musicals he wrote. And I can do that with Apple classical
Speaker 7:  music. Not with Sondheim but with lots of other people like Gershwin and
Speaker 7:  and Rachmaninov. And I'm so close to naming a few more for you
Speaker 7:  David, but I'm not gonna do it. You'll just have to stay tuned. I'm writing
Speaker 7:  about it on the website. It's gonna be great.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I would say it's like a pure strategy credit to Apple, right? Like
Speaker 5:  they don't need Apple music to make money. It's just
Speaker 5:  like not what it does for them. So they can spit out another app and be like,
Speaker 5:  look classical music lovers, we made you a thing. Like don't you love it?
Speaker 5:  And like se target ever smaller segments of music lovers
Speaker 5:  in a way that like Spotify kind of can't cuz it can't spread all the costs.
Speaker 7:  I cannot
Speaker 5:  Wait. So that's cool. And then Apple is really high on spatial for
Speaker 5:  classical as far as I can tell, where it actually makes sense.
Speaker 7:  It sounds fine
Speaker 5:  Because you have like an orchestra, you know all around you.
Speaker 7:  It's fine. I'd rather just listen on a really nice pair of headphones
Speaker 7:  than like spatial audio. But everything about it, I'm
Speaker 7:  really, really digging. I've had way, way, way too much fun with it
Speaker 7:  this week and like forgot how much I liked classical music. So
Speaker 7:  it's a nice pre-discovery.
Speaker 5:  I should mention here by the way, Chris Welch reviewed the Sonos era 100
Speaker 5:  and the Sonos era 300 era 100. Just a, a stereo speaker. It's
Speaker 5:  great. He likes it says it's superior to the Sonos one era 300,
Speaker 5:  the only other real standalone spatial speaker apart from
Speaker 5:  the HomePod and whatever Amazon thing. He said it's great, it's spatial.
Speaker 5:  Was it for spatial not as great on stereo tracks.
Speaker 5:  This satisfy, which is a real, it's a real trade off in there.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. But one of the reasons that I think Apples so high on
Speaker 5:  classical for spatial is cuz they can do the thing where the guy sneaks up
Speaker 5:  behind you with a symbol and goes crash.
Speaker 7:  It's gonna be the OBO player slowly coming up behind
Speaker 7:  you.
Speaker 5:  Go over those reviews. Chris did a great job. There's just a
Speaker 6:  Lot I'm very excited about the Arrow 100. Very excited about the Arrow 100.
Speaker 5:  I'm, I'm thinking I might buy a 300 just to like, I feel like I need to give
Speaker 5:  spatial a shot. I've been so down on it for so long and now
Speaker 5:  everyone's like the new mixes are good and I'm just like, eh, like
Speaker 5:  maybe adding some new hardware to the mix
Speaker 6:  Makes when, when Mariah Carey does a spatial audio mix of, of
Speaker 6:  baby, then Eli will buy an arrow three the
Speaker 7:  Way ne Eli's face changed.
Speaker 5:  If Mariah Carey would sneak up behind me, I'd be so happy.
Speaker 5:  Mariah, I dunno if you're listening, if anyone has a radio telescope point
Speaker 5:  at Mariah
Speaker 7:  Carey,
Speaker 5:  I love you. I loved you my whole life.
Speaker 5:  All right, we gotta take a break. If you see the swag up
Speaker 5:  Pope, let Mariah Carey know I love her.
Speaker 6:  Tell her to get away before doom happens.
Speaker 5:  She needs to know we gotta take a break. We'll be right
Speaker 5:  back in the lightning round
Speaker 10:  As if the mc crispy couldn't get any better. Bacon and ranch
Speaker 10:  just entered the chat. The Bacon Ranch Mc Crispy
Speaker 10:  available at participating McDonald's for a limited time.
Speaker 11:  Well folks, here we are. Former president Donald Trump
Speaker 11:  has been indicted by a Manhattan grand jury. I'm Preet
Speaker 11:  Barra, the former US attorney in Manhattan. My podcast
Speaker 11:  stay tuned is about law, justice, power and democracy.
Speaker 11:  Recently I broke down the indictment with a group of former federal prosecutors
Speaker 11:  who understand how the justice system really works.
Speaker 11:  Joyce Vance, Barb McQuaid and Ellie Honig.
Speaker 11:  We discuss the questions on everyone's mind. Like,
Speaker 12:  Can you directly tie Donald Trump to the way these
Speaker 12:  payments were booked and
Speaker 13:  Logged? Are prosecutors considering additional defendants or
Speaker 13:  additional charges?
Speaker 11:  Is this the kind of conduct that merits a charge of a former president of
Speaker 11:  the United States? I
Speaker 14:  Think this is a serious crime pre and I think it's one that I would charge.
Speaker 11:  And where do we go from here?
Speaker 13:  The presidency from prison, right? I mean add to the crazy.
Speaker 11:  Add to the crazy to listen. Just search. Stay tuned
Speaker 11:  wherever you get your podcasts. New episodes drop every Thursday.
Speaker 11:  Stay tuned.
Speaker 5:  All right, we're back. We gotta do a lightning round. There's a lot of news
Speaker 5:  this week. A lot of news. Just a lot of things. Yeah. Franz, why don't you
Speaker 5:  start.
Speaker 7:  All right. My big thing this week is Ike Perlmutter is no longer at
Speaker 7:  Disney. He was the guy who owned Marvel
Speaker 7:  for years and years and years. When Marvel got acquired by Disney,
Speaker 7:  he stayed on. He notoriously was like, people don't want
Speaker 7:  superhero movies with girls in them. We don't need toys with girls
Speaker 7:  on 'em. That's dumb.
Speaker 5:  That was a perfect impression by the way. A plus
Speaker 7:  Impression. Thank you. I worked really, really hard on it. He had to be slowly
Speaker 7:  forced out because Kevin Faggy and him just didn't get along. And like he
Speaker 7:  was trying to make Black Panther and Captain Marvel and Perlmutter was like,
Speaker 7:  no, we only want white guys. That's, that's the only thing people
Speaker 7:  will buy at a superhero movie. He was quickly proven wrong with both of those.
Speaker 7:  So it was kind of shocking that he was still at Disney and Marvel and now
Speaker 7:  he no longer is Goodbye Ike.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, he also tried to do a coup with an actor.
Speaker 7:  He did try to do a coup didn't go over well for him. So like
Speaker 7:  he, you know, it's, it's time he, he can go off and do other things and have
Speaker 7:  strong feelings about women and people of color on his own time.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Can I tell you my favorite Disney story of the week? Yes. Do you,
Speaker 5:  do you, have you guys heard about the King Charles clause? No. Yes.
Speaker 7:  Oh that was so
Speaker 5:  Good. This is so good. So Governor DeSantis in Florida
Speaker 5:  mad about Disney. Don't say gay passes a bill to take away
Speaker 5:  Disney's like 50 or 60 year old weird tax exception
Speaker 5:  district. The REI Creek Improvement district. So like, Disney was like basically
Speaker 5:  a city, right? Yeah. In this like huge area. And they got to, they ran everything
Speaker 5:  and they were exempted from laws and like, it's weird, it's weird to give
Speaker 5:  corporations cities to America, but they had it, they had it for a long time.
Speaker 5:  Whatever Florida they come out against the, don't say gay bell in Florida.
Speaker 5:  DeSantis does his thing. Tries to punish them for it. So he passes law,
Speaker 5:  he replaces the people who run this district with like five of his own handpicked
Speaker 5:  people. It comes out yesterday day before, right
Speaker 5:  before those people took power, Disney along with like
Speaker 5:  Vanguard and BlackRock passed a bunch of
Speaker 5:  bills giving itself permanent power over the
Speaker 5:  district and completely disempowering the new board.
Speaker 7:  That's so
Speaker 5:  Good. And so the new board is literally like we have no power. Like all we
Speaker 5:  have is the power to maintain the roads in Disney is like
Speaker 5:  giving itself a 30 year development agreement. It no longer needs approval
Speaker 5:  to build buildings of any height or assign development rights. And
Speaker 5:  then it says if the court finds this agreement is
Speaker 5:  illegally in perpetuity, we will extend its term by the
Speaker 5:  following. This declaration shall continue in, in effect until 21
Speaker 5:  years after the death of the last survivor of the descendants of King
Speaker 5:  Charles iii, king of England living as of the date of this
Speaker 5:  declaration. So, and they did it all. And their
Speaker 5:  thing is like we held meetings, no one came, like the board held meetings
Speaker 5:  and we passed the resolutions and no one came or paid
Speaker 5:  attention or told Governor DeSantis. It
Speaker 7:  Was a real,
Speaker 5:  So
Speaker 7:  They Bart losing to Martin in the Simpsons
Speaker 7:  moment.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Wow. I mean, and so the board is like, they,
Speaker 5:  we have to like sue Disney to get the power that we're supposed to have back.
Speaker 5:  It's really good. I mean it is like corporate trickery and it's
Speaker 5:  finest and it's like hard to root for. Yeah. But I'm like rooting for Disney
Speaker 5:  cuz it's fun. Like you, you pick the funnier one and you pick that
Speaker 6:  One. Yeah. It's like if, if succession had two more seasons, like that would
Speaker 6:  for sure be a plot line in one of the episodes. Yeah. That's fantastic.
Speaker 5:  Lemme just read this quote. This essentially makes Disney, the government,
Speaker 5:  Ron Perry, one of the new board members as appointed by DeSantis said the
Speaker 5:  board loses for all practical purposes, the majority of its ability to do
Speaker 5:  anything beyond maintain the roads and maintain basic infrastructure.
Speaker 5:  It's like, oh, they just wrote themselves a contract and signed it.
Speaker 6:  Said, does anyone object
Speaker 5:  To an empty room? And that was it because it's like so fundamentally
Speaker 5:  unserious no one paid any attention and they just got away with it. It's
Speaker 5:  really good. It's so good. That's like the i promo thing is funny in its
Speaker 5:  way cuz they just allowed like the cranky old man to stay at Disney. He just
Speaker 5:  had off, laid off after he tried to do a coup. This is like deeply
Speaker 5:  like you went up against Disney's lawyers and you thought they wouldn't
Speaker 5:  and they didn't and they were suspiciously quiet the whole time.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. They were just like, yeah, whatever. It's gonna be fine. It's very,
Speaker 7:  and it was and
Speaker 6:  They and they pinged it to King Charles King.
Speaker 5:  The king Charles Claus is like icing on the cake. Right. It's
Speaker 6:  Amazing. Yeah, it's very good. I have, I have no notes. That's perfect.
Speaker 6:  Mine is that Elon Musk is now the most followed person on Twitter,
Speaker 6:  which is like fine. Great. Congratulations Elon Musk. Everyone should
Speaker 6:  quit Twitter. It's a cesspool and a horrible place and it's only getting
Speaker 6:  worse and everyone should leave.
Speaker 5:  Did you listen to the Macon episode as decoder?
Speaker 6:  It's terrific. It's very, very good. Everyone should listen to it. Well
Speaker 5:  Thank you for complimenting me. Do you think Maidan is gonna
Speaker 6:  Survive? No, Maidan is not the answer. I think Macedon is gonna be fine,
Speaker 6:  but I think I, I have a story on activity pub that's coming in the next couple
Speaker 6:  of weeks because it's this, it's it's typical call everybody is betting on,
Speaker 6:  right? It's like they're betting on the open web instead of the, instead
Speaker 6:  of aol And like that's essentially where we're headed or at least a lot of
Speaker 6:  people think we're headed. And what I've heard from a bunch of people about
Speaker 6:  Mastodon is that Mastodon is probably not going to be
Speaker 6:  like the largest platform in this space, but it's, it was really, really,
Speaker 6:  really important that Mastodon was there for the last like
Speaker 6:  six months or so, that like, that there was a thing that proved this point
Speaker 6:  that it can and should exist and we can still have what we want in a better
Speaker 6:  way. Even if Macedon doesn't win, it will have like earned its place in
Speaker 6:  history just by being here at this like pivotal moment. Yeah. Which I think
Speaker 6:  is really interesting.
Speaker 5:  Activity probably in general is fascinating to me. It's the sort of,
Speaker 5:  how would you describe, it's like RSS but good.
Speaker 6:  That's one way to think about it. Yeah, I mean it's, it's essentially it's,
Speaker 6:  it's just a very simple communication tool. Like you can
Speaker 6:  build all kinds of stuff on top of it, but fundamentally it's a way of, it's
Speaker 6:  a structure for taking a type of content and distributing that type of content.
Speaker 6:  Like that's really all it is. And then people are building all kinds of social
Speaker 6:  networks on top of it and messaging platforms on top of it. And the idea
Speaker 6:  is I can make a thing and anywhere that can read that thing, it's closer
Speaker 6:  to email for social media really than anything else that I, I make a thing
Speaker 6:  and it can be read and interacted with from lots of places in a standardized
Speaker 6:  way. And that's a better vision than one platform
Speaker 6:  owned by a guy who just wanted to be the most followed person. But the real
Speaker 6:  reason I love this is because this happened right after
Speaker 6:  our friends Casey and Zoe over at Platformer reported that there is a secret
Speaker 6:  list of I think 35 people on Twitter who are being
Speaker 6:  artificially boosted by the algorithm in order to I guess
Speaker 6:  like keep them happy. And the list is hilarious. It's like Mr. Beast
Speaker 6:  and Elon Musk, but also drill and cat turd
Speaker 5:  And
Speaker 6:  It's just this random list of like relatively influential
Speaker 6:  tweeters who are given extra shine on the platform presumably in
Speaker 6:  order to keep them happy and using the platform. So it's like Elon Musk
Speaker 6:  put his thumb on the scale such that he is now the most followed person on
Speaker 6:  Twitter. Like, congratulations, I suppose you did it. Yeah, 44 billion
Speaker 6:  later you beat Barack Obama.
Speaker 5:  Good job. Twitter is rolling on its API
Speaker 5:  payment structures this week. We're all gonna lose our blue check mark
Speaker 5:  soon. Yep. Alright, whatever.
Speaker 6:  Do you guys remember a few months ago when we had a big argument about whether
Speaker 6:  we were gonna pay $8 a month for Twitter Blue and
Speaker 6:  Alex Heath Vociferously said, we're all going to, I don't remember what you
Speaker 6:  two said. And I said there's absolutely no chance in hell if I didn't say
Speaker 6:  that. Please nobody find the clip and send it to me. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I'm definitely not gonna pay
Speaker 6:  For it. No, of course not. Who like it's now it literally has reached the
Speaker 6:  point actually Kranz, I think this was your case back then and you were right.
Speaker 6:  So kudos. It's embarrassing now to be the person who paid for Twitter Blue
Speaker 6:  to the point where they're gonna let you hide your check mark even if you
Speaker 6:  pay for Twitter blue. Like that's how far around this has come. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  I love it so much. The other piece of the puzzle is the API
Speaker 5:  limits. Yeah. So you, there's a free tier, I think it's
Speaker 5:  1500 tweets a month,
Speaker 6:  Which is nothing for most most things apps using this. That's nothing
Speaker 5:  Like we have an auto tweeter built into our cms that is not enough
Speaker 5:  for us. Just us little inbox media. So like a bunch of
Speaker 5:  publications have to figure out like are they gonna pay to tweet their stories?
Speaker 5:  Ooh. Right. Like that's just a weird imposition of a
Speaker 5:  cost. I think the New York Times said it was definitely not gonna pay for
Speaker 5:  Twitter blue French reporters. We, I I doubt that we are, I think we have
Speaker 5:  better things to spend our money on. Like I'd rather spend money on reporting
Speaker 7:  Also it's charging an additional fee for like
Speaker 7:  publications and stuff, right? To be verified.
Speaker 6:  Well you can get your own special verification badge for even more
Speaker 6:  money. So you can,
Speaker 5:  I mean the thing that is like whatever is being said today is not the thing
Speaker 5:  that is true tomorrow. Correct. Like the, the the who
Speaker 5:  knows, like whatever I say today on this podcast about what is happening
Speaker 5:  is definitely not what will be true next week. The big idea is that Twitter,
Speaker 5:  Twitter's gonna, it's gonna start costing money to post Right.
Speaker 5:  In a variety of ways. Whether it's you want to be, have your replies
Speaker 5:  seen and you need Twitter blue and that's gonna cost money. Or whether you
Speaker 5:  are an app developer, a publisher, and you tweet enough that you need API
Speaker 5:  access that's gonna cost money and imposing the cost on that side
Speaker 5:  is super weird cuz there's no value on the other side.
Speaker 5:  So if I pay money onto Twitter, what am I, how do I make the money
Speaker 5:  back? No one knows.
Speaker 6:  I've seen a bunch of creators asking that recently this, they're like, okay,
Speaker 6:  let me get this straight. You're gonna charge me money to post so that you
Speaker 6:  can put ads next to my post that you take
Speaker 5:  This.
Speaker 7:  It's
Speaker 5:  Not a bunch of craters. It's Elon's number one guy.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, that's
Speaker 7:  Right. Old capture.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And, and so it's like I'm you're, you're asking me to pay to do
Speaker 6:  a bunch of work from which you accrue all of the value. Like that's a bad
Speaker 6:  deal. I'm no economist, but like that's a bad deal.
Speaker 5:  You got like there are like cookie shop owners that can do this
Speaker 5:  math.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Like no pH like a six-year-old lemonade sands. Like lemme get it, lemme get
Speaker 5:  this straight. I gotta pay to set up shop and then there's no one to buy
Speaker 5:  the lemonade.
Speaker 6:  You're gonna give me $10 and then I'm gonna drink the lemonade.
Speaker 7:  That's how this works.
Speaker 5:  So we'll see. I I, I know. All right, here's, okay, so that's Twitter. We'll
Speaker 5:  see I think the next inflection point is when they start charging for API
Speaker 5:  access and they take away the check marks. Agreed. And I think that the
Speaker 5:  line on the curve goes a different Get ready mastodon is what I'm saying.
Speaker 5:  Even if it doesn't survive all tumble. Okay, I have two for
Speaker 5:  lightning iron. One is very fast. The new Sony Z V
Speaker 5:  E one came out this week. It's like an RX 100 with a full frame sensor in
Speaker 5:  it. There's no other way to describe it. Like it's that model of camera,
Speaker 6:  Which is literally ne Eli's dream camera. Like what you just described is
Speaker 6:  everything you've ever wanted your whole life.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So I have a zv one, right? So the camera I'm looking into right now
Speaker 5:  is a Sony Zv one. I have two of them as webcams. They're just like
Speaker 5:  cheaper RX 100 class cameras. They have APSC sensors in them.
Speaker 5:  They're great. I love them. Zv one little bigger, but same
Speaker 5:  physical concept, full frame sensor, interchangeable lenses. Just go
Speaker 5:  watch Becca's video with it. It's so good. It's great. It's
Speaker 5:  such a good idea. What if we make a full frame camera that kind of just
Speaker 5:  acts like an iPhone, right? It's just like does it all all for you? It's
Speaker 5:  just like lets you f like just run and gun shoot with it. It's so expensive.
Speaker 5:  It's like $2,200 for body only And I'm like oh would I want it really bad?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, that's how they get you.
Speaker 5:  But go watch that video cause it's really cool and like for all of our, what
Speaker 5:  is a photo conversations and ai, video conversations,
Speaker 5:  whatever. Cool. Cameras are still really cool, you know And like
Speaker 5:  there's something about this one that just makes me want to go start a
Speaker 5:  YouTube channel. Like it's a piece of hardware that is like inspiring
Speaker 5:  to think about using and I think that's really cool. So that's one. Go watch
Speaker 5:  that video also. Becca's good. And she might have sold me the camera. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  go watch the video. Okay, here's my last one. I just think this is like a
Speaker 5:  very, we talked about Matter in Smart Home, it's taken three years
Speaker 5:  since Google invested like hundreds of millions of dollars into a d t. The
Speaker 5:  the security company to compete with Ring
Speaker 6:  Straight up. Forgot that happened. Like until I saw this headline, I absolutely
Speaker 6:  forgot that happened
Speaker 5:  Three years, 450 million. They invested in
Speaker 5:  ADT because they're like, ring is killing us and they finally
Speaker 5:  have rolled something out. It's called the self setup system. And it just
Speaker 5:  like integrates Google Nest video doorbells and cameras into a D
Speaker 5:  t and gives you a bunch of sensors. You gotta pay $25 a month,
Speaker 5:  24 9 9 a month. And then you also need a Nest Aware subscription, which is
Speaker 5:  $35 a month. Ooh. And the starter
Speaker 5:  package is like nobody knows how much it costs. So Jen had to run around
Speaker 5:  like asking executives at Google and a D t like how much does this cost?
Speaker 5:  Because you keep saying it's gonna be $220 but that's just
Speaker 5:  the introductory price and soon it'll be $480.
Speaker 5:  No. And it's like why? Wow. Just all like the
Speaker 5:  whole nest story landed in this place where three years after they
Speaker 5:  spent almost half a billion dollars to invest in this company. They're like,
Speaker 5:  now your Nest cameras can alert the cops
Speaker 5:  through your AD T subscription. I just dunno what they're
Speaker 6:  Doing. It's like the most expensive, very simple a p i of all time. Like
Speaker 6:  congratulations to everybody involved there. Yeah. How did that take three
Speaker 6:  years? Nothing in any of this announcement sounds like three years of work.
Speaker 6:  There's just, it sounds very much like they, there's like one person at Google
Speaker 6:  and one person at AD T who talked to each other and they like lost each other's
Speaker 6:  phone numbers for two years and then were like, should we do it now? And
Speaker 6:  then they did it and now here we are.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Look where's the stuff?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 5:  Like yeah where are the new products? Where's the, it's
Speaker 5:  just like the reason you would invest in a company like ADT is cause they
Speaker 5:  like have sales and service and dealers and da da da and it's like nah,
Speaker 5:  it's just your Google cameras. You already have to hang up by yourself. Like
Speaker 5:  I don't get it. It's super weird. It's just completely emblematic of like
Speaker 5:  Google lack of focus. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  But it's out. Jen actually says pricing-wise it's like compelling. Once you
Speaker 5:  add up all the services, it's just, you gotta add up all the services and
Speaker 5:  the point is you should have a pu No thanks anyhow. Look, I, I started on
Speaker 5:  the high of the CBE one. Yes. I hope spend $2,200 on a body
Speaker 5:  only full frame handled camera. That's exciting.
Speaker 5:  No, I will not spend $50 a month on that to wear wear subscription.
Speaker 6:  Sounds about right
Speaker 5:  To, to protect my family. But
Speaker 6:  If you put a full frame sensor in that nest cam and you eyes back in
Speaker 5:  For sure. Alright, we're over as always.
Speaker 5:  This is a delight. We should just have like wide-ranging philosophical Wait,
Speaker 5:  that's our show. That's what we do every week. Surprise. We
Speaker 5:  have actually a lot of coverage. We didn't talk about the TikTok band this
Speaker 5:  week. We talked about a lot last week. There's a lot more coverage on the
Speaker 5:  side of that. Yep. The political alliances are actually shifting. Like Rand
Speaker 5:  Paul came out against it today. Siding with a bunch of progressive democrats.
Speaker 5:  Like that's weird. It's weird. Weird. That's about there. Yeah. And his
Speaker 5:  argument is like, this is a weird imposition on the First Amendment. It's
Speaker 5:  weird. It's weird. Me and Rand Paul together at last. So
Speaker 5:  go look at that coverage cuz it's important. I think I will just say this
Speaker 5:  in response to some of the like Instagram reels comments I saw from our clips
Speaker 5:  last week. It's not about China or not China. It's like if the United States
Speaker 5:  government wants to do something like this, they have to make a good case.
Speaker 5:  They didn't. It's just like pretty flat out. Like they're
Speaker 5:  not doing that right now. And like yeah, I feel bad that the wifi guy
Speaker 5:  didn't know how to ask the question about the wifi and there's like 500 people
Speaker 5:  trying to explain to us what he really meant. No, but like he wields the
Speaker 5:  power of the state so like he has to do a good job and
Speaker 5:  that's like, there's just like a disconnect there where like I think we're
Speaker 5:  all too sympathetic to people who are making bad decisions about technology.
Speaker 5:  It's like you're gonna shut down an app that millions of people use anyway.
Speaker 5:  It's all on the site. Addie wrote a great piece. The TikTok ban is a betrayal
Speaker 5:  of the open internet. Go read it. Also very virgie. This has been a very
Speaker 5:  virgie episode. You should listen to decoder y Eugene Roco, the CEO of Macedon.
Speaker 5:  There's a lot of activity pub conversation there, which I to you is important.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Next week we're wrapping up our centennial series with the CEO of Hasbro.
Speaker 5:  We talk a lot about magic, the gathering in Dungeons and Dragons and like
Speaker 5:  there's a lot of controversy in those communities. It's very good.
Speaker 5:  But here's the thing that I learned, hasbro hundred years old started
Speaker 5:  in 1923 by the Hassenfeld Brothers. It's just the
Speaker 5:  Hasbros. Wait, really? It's
Speaker 6:  So good. It's the has. It's like how Adidas is Adi and Doss. They're just
Speaker 6:  two people. It's the Hasbros.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. But think about 1923. They're like, oh, we're bros. Like it's just
Speaker 5:  like, it blows your mind. Like this language didn't exist in 1923.
Speaker 6:  Also the Hasbros is like an ice cream shop that I would go to every single
Speaker 6:  day. I'm just gonna throw that out there.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, it's very good. That's coming next week and Wednesday show what's on
Speaker 5:  the Wednesday show.
Speaker 6:  Wednesday show. We're gonna talk about Matter and Sidewalk. We're gonna talk
Speaker 6:  about a bunch of Microsoft AI stuff with Tom. Part of the sort of
Speaker 6:  ongoing question of like, what is AI actually good for? Microsoft's doing
Speaker 6:  a bunch of interesting stuff, so we're gonna dig into that with him. And
Speaker 6:  then we sent Monica Chin out to Times Square to test a bunch of laptop
Speaker 6:  microphones and it went so differently than I expected,
Speaker 6:  which is fascinating and really fun. And it's gonna be one of those episodes
Speaker 6:  that like occasionally sounds terrible, but in the service of good
Speaker 6:  things. So it's gonna be,
Speaker 5:  It's a good one. Journalism.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. All
Speaker 5:  Right. I love it. That's it. It's for chest background
Speaker 15:  And that's a wrap for Vergecast this week. Thanks for listening. If you
Speaker 15:  enjoy the show, subscribe in the podcast app of your choice or tell a friend,
Speaker 15:  you can send us feedback at vergecast@theverge.com. This show is
Speaker 15:  produced by me, Liam James, and our senior audio director, Andrew Marino.
Speaker 15:  This episode was edited and mixed by Amanda Rose Smith. Our
Speaker 15:  editorial director is Brooke Min, and our executive producer is Eleanor
Speaker 15:  Donovan. The Verge Cast is a production of the Verge and Box Media
Speaker 15:  podcast network. And that's it. We'll see you next week.
Speaker 16:  What one seemed improbable is happening now? Insurance is
Speaker 16:  front and center for tech companies who are finally commanding the space
Speaker 16:  they occupy in every other industry. Behind the disruption is Cover
Speaker 16:  Genius, the InsureTech for embedded insurance that protects customers of
Speaker 16:  the world's largest digital companies available at Amazon. Intuit,
Speaker 16:  Flipcart, eBay, booking.com. Skyscanner, Ryan Air
Speaker 16:  and Southeast Asia's largest company. Shoppy cover Genius's
Speaker 16:  platform makes it easy for their global partners to embed insurance and
Speaker 16:  warranty bundles, and especially RUS within their booking path or
Speaker 16:  signup, connecting customers with the protection they need and with global
Speaker 16:  licensing and end-to-end capabilities across all industries. From property
Speaker 16:  to travel, FinTech logistics. The gig economy in Retail
Speaker 16:  Cover Genius can build and distribute any kind of insurance and process
Speaker 16:  claims in all 50 states and in more than 60 countries, all through a
Speaker 16:  single integration. Because your customers are at the center of everything.
Speaker 16:  Cover Genius Pays claims instantly and maintains an NPS of
Speaker 16:  65 plus the highest in an industry where traditional insurers
Speaker 16:  rely on paper forms, missed calls and mail checks. To deliver NPS
Speaker 16:  below Zero, give your customers the peace of mind they deserve. Visit cover
Speaker 16:  genius.com/fox today to learn more. Cover Genius,
Speaker 16:  the intro tech for Embedded Insurance.