# Transcript
ID: 49643840-a7d9-11ed-93bd-6f1da73038a2
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: “The Hidden Hand Behind Your Swipes” from Land of the Giants
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-3595905313148058800/665739084805395242/s93290-US-2347s-1675878715.mp3
Description: We are sharing an episode of Land of the Giants: Dating. Big tech is transforming every aspect of our world. But how? And at what cost? In this season of Land of the Giants: Dating Games, The Verge and New York Magazine's The Cut trace the evolution of the multi-billion dollar dating app industry. Hosts Sangeeta Singh Kurtz and Lakshmi Rengarajan explore the modern dating landscape forged by companies like Tinder, Bumble, and Hinge, and their impact on our hopes for connection. They answer the question – are the business goals of dating app companies aligned with users' romantic aspirations?
Follow Land of the Giants to hear new episodes every Wednesday.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Disabled
Speaker 1:  Hey y'all. This is Josh Muci, host of the Pitch a
Speaker 1:  Vox Media podcast where real entrepreneurs pitch real tech
Speaker 1:  investors for real money. In this season, we're letting listeners
Speaker 1:  like you invest in the startups on our show, hear
Speaker 1:  the next billion dollar idea way before anyone else.
Speaker 2:  That's kind of sexy.
Speaker 1:  Go make the money, honey. Follow the pitch. For our best season yet,
Speaker 1:  new episodes start dropping weekly on February 8th.
Speaker 4:  Hey, it's your friend Eli. I just wanna tell you about our new newsletter.
Speaker 4:  It's called Command Line. It's written by the verges, Alex Heath, and it's
Speaker 4:  all about the tech industry's inside conversation with scoops, interviews
Speaker 4:  and analysis you won't get anywhere else. Here's Alex.
Speaker 5:  Each week you'll get scoops about what's coming next from tech giants like
Speaker 5:  Apple and Meta and hear about the product and people moves that matter. And
Speaker 5:  I want you to be part of the conversation. So I'll be answering questions
Speaker 5:  and featuring what you have
Speaker 4:  To say. Head on over to the verge.com/command line to subscribe today. That's
Speaker 4:  the verge.com/command line.
Speaker 6:  Hello, and you're listening to the Vergecast, the flagship podcast of
Speaker 6:  building your own lightsaber. I'm your friend Alex Cranz and I gotta
Speaker 6:  confess, I just lied. There is not an episode of the Vergecast today because
Speaker 6:  I am in Disney World having a great time on vacation, but don't worry,
Speaker 6:  we've got an episode of Land of the Giants playing for you. This season is
Speaker 6:  all about dating apps and it's really, really interesting. I think you're
Speaker 6:  gonna like it On Friday, Eli and I will be back to talk about everything
Speaker 6:  going on in the news this week with lots of other people from the Verge.
Speaker 6:  Stay tuned. Until then, have a great day. Rock and Roll.
Speaker 7:  Lakshmi, I wanna tell you about this guy, a dating app guy,
Speaker 7:  sort of. He's been using dating apps for nearly a decade,
Speaker 7:  but a few years ago he discovered something about them that made him feel
Speaker 7:  a little cheated. His name is Eve Gilbert.
Speaker 7:  He's an attorney in Midtown Manhattan. It's sick that you're a lawyer.
Speaker 2:  Oh, thank you. It does surprise a lot of people.
Speaker 7:  When I met him, he was wearing these heart shaped Lolita glasses
Speaker 7:  and leather pants. You're definitely the most stylish lawyer that
Speaker 7:  I've come
Speaker 2:  Across. Thank you. That is what I aim for.
Speaker 7:  And when it comes to the apps, he's seen it all. He told me he started using
Speaker 7:  them when he was pretty young,
Speaker 2:  Like most little gay kids I was using like Grindr when I
Speaker 2:  first started. Cause that's like really the only way to like meet other
Speaker 2:  gay people.
Speaker 7:  Grindr was enough when he was living in the suburbs, but he moved to New York
Speaker 7:  in 2016 and had a new city new me moment and so we decided
Speaker 7:  to try some new dating apps. Okay, Cupid was first.
Speaker 7:  It had these quirky, queer friendly ads on the subway that caught his eye.
Speaker 2:  I do fall for ads very easily.
Speaker 7:  Then he got on Tinder.
Speaker 2:  When I started, Tinder was like, oh, this is the fancy one.
Speaker 2:  This is the one that you go go to to meet like a more long-term partner.
Speaker 7:  At the time, Tinder was already building a reputation as a hookup app,
Speaker 7:  but when Gilbert compared it to Grindr it actually felt more serious.
Speaker 7:  So he was on these apps for years and went on so many bad dates. You know,
Speaker 7:  he wanted to be done.
Speaker 8:  I mean dating burnout is real.
Speaker 7:  Totally. And then in 2018 he thought he saw the light
Speaker 7:  at the end of the tunnel hinge. It was supposed to have
Speaker 7:  this sophisticated algorithm, you know, high quality matches. The app
Speaker 7:  pitched itself as designed to be deleted
Speaker 2:  And then I, I think the first five or six profiles I've seen
Speaker 2:  were people I had already talked to and some of them I had already like been
Speaker 2:  on dates with like the same dates. That precipitated me switching
Speaker 2:  to a new app.
Speaker 8:  Okay, so I think I know where this story is going.
Speaker 7:  Did you proceed to match with them or did you like throw your
Speaker 7:  phone away in frustration?
Speaker 2:  It just made me sit there for a bit. I was like, this is
Speaker 2:  New York. It's one of the biggest cities in the world. These
Speaker 2:  cannot be the only options here.
Speaker 7:  He did not throw his phone, but he was left with a
Speaker 7:  rage induced curiosity. Okay, Cupid, Tinder
Speaker 7:  Hinge, these apps were all marketed differently. They
Speaker 7:  were supposed to provide distinct experiences, so why
Speaker 7:  did using them feel so similar? After doing a bit of
Speaker 7:  research, he realized that all of the apps he'd been using over the years
Speaker 7:  besides Grindr were under the same corporate umbrella.
Speaker 2:  Honestly, I felt kind of like cheated in a
Speaker 2:  way. It's like, okay, Tinder has been treating me badly, so lemme try
Speaker 2:  Hinge. You know, kind of like the same way like if you have a bad product,
Speaker 2:  you're like, oh, I'm gonna buy like that competitor's product instead
Speaker 7:  Dozens of dating apps and websites all owned by the same company.
Speaker 7:  That company is Match Group.
Speaker 2:  I'm like, how? How is this possible?
Speaker 8:  This is Land of the Giants Match Group owns nearly
Speaker 8:  all of the top dating apps in the United States, which means
Speaker 8:  it controls the way dating works for millions of people.
Speaker 7:  That's a lot of power for one company to hold and it got
Speaker 7:  all of that power through a long campaign of buying up the competition
Speaker 8:  And steering our romantic lives. It's been a lucrative business
Speaker 8:  for Match Group. It knows our most intimate preferences and
Speaker 8:  behaviors and Match uses that data to better sell
Speaker 8:  itself to build new features that make more money
Speaker 8:  from our desire to connect.
Speaker 7:  But what about users as Match Group perfects the
Speaker 7:  business model of dating? Are people seeing better results?
Speaker 8:  That is a great question. Sangita, since I used to
Speaker 8:  work at Match Group, we thought it'd be a good idea to hear your fresh take
Speaker 8:  on Matches story. I can't wait to hear what you find out.
Speaker 7:  Thanks Lakshmi.
Speaker 7:  the.com boom in the nineties was a bit of a wild west and a young
Speaker 7:  computer scientist named Gary Kremin wanted to try his luck.
Speaker 7:  He had an B from Stanford, but his big business idea was pretty simple.
Speaker 7:  He bought up a bunch of catchy domain names,
Speaker 7:  jobs.com, housing.com,
Speaker 7:  autos.com. He also owned sex.com and
Speaker 7:  match.com. In 1995, the first version
Speaker 7:  of match.com would've looked familiar.
Speaker 9:  I've seen old mockups and like they literally looked like the
Speaker 9:  classified section in a newspaper, which probably don't even exist anymore.
Speaker 7:  That's Amna Tomb Bray. He's the CEO of Match Group
Speaker 7:  Americas and that was exactly the idea
Speaker 7:  that Match and all of those other domains would function as a
Speaker 7:  sort of online classified space. Kremen created
Speaker 7:  a company called Electric classified to houses his domains
Speaker 7:  named himself the c o and set out to conquer the
Speaker 7:  digital classified business and what respectable classified
Speaker 7:  section didn't have personal ads. The only thing was that
Speaker 7:  personal ads weren't always that respectable.
Speaker 10:  In the mid nineties, a lot of the media was
Speaker 10:  talking about the dangers of the internet. Not only that
Speaker 10:  personals, which were mostly newspaper 900 numbers
Speaker 10:  had a very bad reputation.
Speaker 7:  Fran Meyer was a classmate of Cremins from Stanford
Speaker 7:  When she joined Electric classifieds, Kremen put her in charge of
Speaker 7:  match.com. Personals had an image problem.
Speaker 7:  Meyer says that the personal ads sections of local weekly
Speaker 7:  newspapers often featured fake ads that were
Speaker 7:  basically scams
Speaker 10:  Ads like I'm interested in a gang bang, really
Speaker 10:  disgusting that would though generate lots
Speaker 10:  of phone calls to the 900 number. Okay, so this
Speaker 10:  is the reason why personals were were considered fairly
Speaker 10:  sleazy.
Speaker 7:  Beyond that the internet was new for most people and for
Speaker 7:  those who were already online meeting someone often meant anonymous
Speaker 7:  conversations in occasionally sketchy chat rooms.
Speaker 7:  So Match and Meyer had to figure out how to clean up the SL factor
Speaker 7:  and begin to build trust. She said that they started
Speaker 7:  with the idea that men would follow women and the way to get women on Match
Speaker 7:  was to make sure the men were serious. A great way to do so, make
Speaker 7:  them pay to use the service subscriptions.
Speaker 10:  Once we started charging, the percentage of women went up
Speaker 10:  almost immediately and I think it's because it sort of
Speaker 10:  qualified the guides that were on the service. There were a lot of other
Speaker 10:  online personals, but there was none that was really taking
Speaker 10:  a brand focused, target focused approach and I
Speaker 10:  think that's why we emerged as the winner from really
Speaker 10:  for the very beginning.
Speaker 11:  Today we adapt our regular weekly feature computer line
Speaker 11:  to Valentine's Day. The search for True Romance as you probably
Speaker 11:  know can begin just about anywhere but these days many of those seeking
Speaker 11:  soulmates are turning to the internet
Speaker 7:  Online. Dating's rebrand got the Good Morning America's seal of approval
Speaker 7:  in the late nineties. By then a lot had changed.
Speaker 7:  For one thing, more people were using the internet and culturally
Speaker 7:  things were shifting too. Conversations about
Speaker 7:  cybersex in shows like Sex in the City and films like You've Got
Speaker 7:  Male were helping to eradicate the online dating is
Speaker 7:  dangerous and weird stigma. It wasn't enough for the owners of
Speaker 7:  Electric classifieds. Kremen was already gone. He'd bounced in
Speaker 7:  96 after butting heads with Investors. A parade of
Speaker 7:  new CEOs did not see a future for online dating
Speaker 7:  in 1997. Electric classifieds sold
Speaker 7:  match.com.
Speaker 7:  This is where Media mogul Barry Diller comes in. His
Speaker 7:  company bought match.com in 1999 for 50 million.
Speaker 7:  Diller was an entertainment executive who'd been the chairman at
Speaker 7:  Paramount Pictures and launched the Fox Network in
Speaker 7:  1995. He made his last big play in TV and bought a bunch of
Speaker 7:  regional stations.
Speaker 12:  Then along came the internet and essentially we followed our curiosity,
Speaker 12:  right? We're not deal junkies in a sense, but there was a lot of curiosity
Speaker 12:  and a ton of opportunity and so
Speaker 12:  we just followed the opportunity
Speaker 7:  That Stiller speaking to Fortune Magazine. Opportunity to
Speaker 7:  him meant gathering his acquisitions under one corporate umbrella.
Speaker 7:  The name of his behemoth was InterActiveCorp IAC for
Speaker 7:  short. When IAC bought match.com, the
Speaker 7:  website had 500,000 users. That's roughly the
Speaker 7:  population of Minneapolis, but Diller wanted match to dominate the
Speaker 7:  whole country and then the world.
Speaker 7:  He did what he did best and went on a deal making spree. He bought
Speaker 7:  exclusive rights to the personal section of New York Mag and b e t.
Speaker 7:  He partnered with M S N and A O L to increase matches membership
Speaker 7:  base. Then there was the Marketing National
Speaker 7:  radio and TV spots inviting people to come and get your love.
Speaker 7:  A very 2006 partnership with Dr. Phil
Speaker 13:  Jodi. Whoa, Jodi,
Speaker 7:  Sorry.
Speaker 13:  You still daydreaming about Mr. Wright? Yeah, you've got
Speaker 13:  personality Looks iq, you just need little guy
Speaker 13:  Q. That's all.
Speaker 14:  Visit match.com today.
Speaker 7:  A campaign for people who still felt like online dating was for losers.
Speaker 7:  It featured real match users
Speaker 7:  in this ad from 2007. Danish Beauty
Speaker 7:  22 is wearing an evening gown. She's gorgeous and
Speaker 7:  glamorous. The tagline for the campaign, it's okay to
Speaker 7:  look whether it was matches aggressive marketing,
Speaker 7:  greater internet usage, a shift in pop culture or
Speaker 7:  all of these things. At some point online dating became a
Speaker 7:  thing and match.com was leading the pack.
Speaker 7:  Here's Diller again, speaking to Fortune in 2009, about
Speaker 7:  10 years after first buying match
Speaker 12:  Million, 500,000 people pay 25 bucks a month or so
Speaker 12:  to do this thing now and that's a very
Speaker 12:  good margin. Really remarkably solid
Speaker 12:  business
Speaker 7:  With a solid business, a good margin and cash flow
Speaker 7:  IAC could use. Its for chest to level up match.com into something
Speaker 7:  entirely new.
Speaker 16:  IAC is a holding company, meaning they have stakes in
Speaker 16:  a variety of other businesses and so it's like
Speaker 16:  a conglomerate. They don't just have one type of business.
Speaker 7:  David Marcus runs Evermore Global Advisors, an
Speaker 7:  investment firm that specializes in holding companies like iac.
Speaker 7:  Marcus is a big fan of the Diller way.
Speaker 16:  I think of IAC as a compounding machine. They just do this.
Speaker 16:  They put in these tiny things, spend years developing them.
Speaker 16:  Then what comes out the other side is a great business that can
Speaker 16:  live and stand and thrive on its own. Put it even
Speaker 16:  more simply. Think about a magician's hat. IAC itself is
Speaker 16:  the magician's hat and over the years he's been pulling all these rabbits
Speaker 16:  out, but these are rabbits that are multi-billion dollar opportunities.
Speaker 7:  It wasn't enough that match.com was growing and making money.
Speaker 7:  Diller still wanted to forge a company that would dominate online dating
Speaker 7:  entirely.
Speaker 7:  In 2009, match.com became Match Group
Speaker 7:  its strategy to eat the competition. That
Speaker 7:  same year Match Group made its first acquisition People Media
Speaker 7:  for 80 million. A little over a year later
Speaker 7:  it acquired Metech. Each of these sites brought
Speaker 7:  something unique to the business people. Media had niche brands,
Speaker 7:  specifically social connection websites that included our
Speaker 7:  time.com and black people meet.com. Meic was
Speaker 7:  really popular in France and let Match get its tentacles into the
Speaker 7:  European market. But the most important thing was that these
Speaker 7:  acquisitions brought millions more people under the Match group
Speaker 7:  umbrella. So Match Group was growing but it was also wary of the
Speaker 7:  competition. Its biggest problem in 2011 was
Speaker 7:  OkCupid.
Speaker 7:  The site was reaching younger Gen Xers and millennials who were curious
Speaker 7:  about online dating but reluctant to Fort Co for $30 a month
Speaker 7:  for a match.com subscription and OkCupid was free.
Speaker 7:  It liked to rub that in matches face. In fact, in those days
Speaker 7:  it cast a lot of aspersions on match matches. Marketing
Speaker 7:  claimed that 12 couples got engaged today thanks to match.com.
Speaker 7:  OkCupid took aim at this brag with a snarky blog post suggesting that
Speaker 7:  given matches scale, this was kind of a rip off.
Speaker 7:  What's more compared to OkCupid Match was old school.
Speaker 7:  Its users were still building and browsing elaborate profiles.
Speaker 7:  OkCupid did things a little differently. It had a user's
Speaker 7:  answer tons of personality questions to get a compatibility percentage
Speaker 7:  with other users. It felt scientific but fun.
Speaker 9:  So in the case of OkCupid, it was clearly attracting
Speaker 9:  like a more coastal, progressive,
Speaker 9:  geeky data-oriented person.
Speaker 7:  Ana Torey, c e o of Match Americas.
Speaker 9:  So it was a very unique passionate user base that like to answer questions
Speaker 9:  and like it was a very different way of analyzing and matching
Speaker 9:  people as well as assessing people.
Speaker 7:  So instead of competing with OkCupid Match just bought it
Speaker 7:  Match's. Next major Target was Plenty of Phish, a free dating site that
Speaker 7:  was wildly popular in the mid 2010s. It was
Speaker 7:  launched by Marcus friend, a computer scientist back in
Speaker 7:  2003 and it became so successful because friend
Speaker 7:  mastered the s e o game. When people searched for dating in LA
Speaker 7:  or dating in New York, they would see plenty of Phish at the top of
Speaker 7:  the results. Kim Kaplan joined the company in 2009.
Speaker 18:  So my first week at Plenty of Fish, we went to an online dating
Speaker 18:  conference in Miami and Marcus got up on stage and
Speaker 18:  was presented with a Darth Vader helmet and it was basically
Speaker 18:  them saying you're going to kill everybody in the industry.
Speaker 7:  In a 2009 profile in Ink Magazine friend talked
Speaker 7:  about how he worked one hour a day and made 10 million each year
Speaker 7:  running the site from his apartment.
Speaker 18:  Marcus said he would never sell he he reiterated that
Speaker 18:  number of times to everybody, I'm never selling, I'm never selling, I'm
Speaker 18:  never selling.
Speaker 7:  Why would he? He was making millions and he owned 100%
Speaker 7:  of Plenty of fish, which by the way was true to its name.
Speaker 7:  It had 3.6 million daily active users. In
Speaker 7:  2015 Amna Tre again,
Speaker 9:  I think it was number two in the country.
Speaker 9:  So that was like, obviously it was huge and extremely popular
Speaker 9:  in like the smaller towns or small town America.
Speaker 7:  This was obviously a problem for Match Group, a rival dating
Speaker 7:  platform with huge reach that refused to be bought,
Speaker 7:  but at some point friend's position on selling had
Speaker 7:  evolved. He went to dinner with Match
Speaker 7:  Sam Yagan and by the end of it, match owned Plenty of Fish
Speaker 7:  Friend left with over half a billion dollars in his pocket.
Speaker 7:  It was Match group's largest acquisition to date with plenty of
Speaker 7:  fish in its portfolio. Match group now owned four of the five
Speaker 7:  top dating brands in North America This
Speaker 19:  Morning the biggest dating websites are getting ready to Woo. Wall Street.
Speaker 19:  Barry Diller's
Speaker 7:  Company in November, 2015, match Group went public.
Speaker 7:  It was the moment when Barry Diller pulled the rabbit out of his magician's
Speaker 7:  hat and showed Wall Street just how much online dating was worth.
Speaker 7:  IAC had spent nearly 1.3 billion to acquire 25
Speaker 7:  brands for its dating portfolio match group's. Market Cap
Speaker 7:  at I P O was nearly $3 billion.
Speaker 7:  More and more daters were turning to mobile apps to meet people. While
Speaker 7:  Match owned the most popular mobile dating app out there, it wasn't
Speaker 7:  bringing in much money that was about to change.
Speaker 7:  In 2013, about a third of Match groups users were
Speaker 7:  signing up for its products on mobile devices. By 2015,
Speaker 7:  that number was closer to 70%. Part of this was thanks
Speaker 7:  to Tinder, which was created in an incubator owned by iac.
Speaker 7:  That relationship eventually evolved into Match Group owning the app.
Speaker 7:  Tinder still had something of a startup spirit, though it
Speaker 7:  spent the first couple of years focused on growth, not revenue.
Speaker 7:  That all changed when Match Group was preparing to go public.
Speaker 20:  I do remember, you know finding out like, oh hey, we have to monetize, but
Speaker 20:  I think based upon an earnings call
Speaker 7:  That's Jonathan Badin, one of the co-founders of Tinder
Speaker 20:  And I was like, wait, we're we're what? I was like, okay,
Speaker 7:  Tinder had followed a common playbook, make the app free
Speaker 7:  and figure out how to make money later. Well it was later
Speaker 7:  and Match Group wanted Tinder users to start paying up
Speaker 7:  Tinder just had to find out what users would actually shell out for.
Speaker 7:  Jess Caro was one of the people tasked with figuring that out.
Speaker 7:  In 2014 she was studying sociology at UCLA and
Speaker 7:  writing about online dating for her dissertation. She was
Speaker 7:  also using dating apps. Caro had recently matched with
Speaker 7:  Sean Rad, another one of Tinder's co-founders. She took it as a
Speaker 7:  sign when he started to message her while she was on a boring date a few
Speaker 7:  days later
Speaker 21:  I was literally like back and forth while all this was happening in the
Speaker 21:  bathroom live messaging Sean, the guy either thought I had a urinary tract
Speaker 21:  infection or a Cohan habit or I was just woefully uninterested. It
Speaker 21:  was obviously the third option here.
Speaker 7:  She pitched her research and herself and soon enough she was working
Speaker 7:  at Tinder's offices in West Hollywood.
Speaker 7:  One of her tasks she says, was to dig through the data from Tinder's user
Speaker 7:  surveys.
Speaker 21:  I helped them monetize. I helped them figure out, you know what people were
Speaker 21:  willing to pay for.
Speaker 7:  She wanted to know would members drop money on a tool that would
Speaker 7:  help them stand out from the crowd?
Speaker 21:  How often were they going to use it? Under what
Speaker 21:  circumstances would they use it? Were men more likely to use it than women?
Speaker 21:  These were all questions that I was trying to answer in the back of my mind
Speaker 21:  to understand the motivation for whether or not we should be investing in
Speaker 21:  it.
Speaker 7:  Her research was fed to teams that developed special features.
Speaker 7:  What Tinder calls superpowers. There was the boost
Speaker 7:  which got your profile seen by more people for a limited period and the
Speaker 7:  super like, but you could send someone to show them that you really liked
Speaker 7:  them, but these features were not free. Ana
Speaker 7:  tore again,
Speaker 9:  We are constantly looking at various ways to
Speaker 9:  say give users a way to enhance their chance at succeeding
Speaker 9:  on the app and that's something that users always willing to pay for
Speaker 7:  And users did. They spent millions seeking an advantage
Speaker 7:  on the app and on subscriptions, which Tinder added next
Speaker 7:  in 2016 it brought in 169 million
Speaker 7:  in revenue and still match wasn't finished.
Speaker 7:  There were plenty of other dating apps that could pose a threat to Tinder's
Speaker 7:  dominance. So Match Group went back to its
Speaker 7:  old playbook competition, no problem,
Speaker 7:  we'll just buy it in the mid 2010s. Dating
Speaker 7:  apps were mostly the same.
Speaker 2:  All the dating apps were Tinder except for what's your One Little Wrinkle?
Speaker 7:  That's Tim. Matt Duggan, a former executive at Hinge.
Speaker 7:  In the early years, hinge was pretty much just like Tinder,
Speaker 7:  but it used social media to connect users to friends of friends.
Speaker 2:  We were chasing their tails. We had a swiping experience very much like theirs.
Speaker 2:  We had profiles very much like theirs. We had a couple little things that
Speaker 2:  made it a little bit different and we had a little bit of a different ethos
Speaker 2:  and all that was well and good, but ultimately people saw us as the same
Speaker 2:  kind of product and they used us in the same way as a numbers scheme,
Speaker 7:  But Hinch didn't want to be Tinder. It wanted to beat Tinder
Speaker 22:  Internally we were like at war against Tinder. We were like, we need our
Speaker 22:  product to be better than Tinders. They're all about gamification. We're
Speaker 22:  all about like really like human design.
Speaker 7:  Lucy Mort was a product designer at Hinge in late 2015
Speaker 7:  when that war against Tinder took shape.
Speaker 7:  A Vanity Fair piece on Tinder's role in the rise of hookup culture had gone
Speaker 7:  mega viral. Tinder it said was Patient zero
Speaker 7:  in the quote dating Apocalypse Romance as we
Speaker 7:  knew it had been destroyed, Tinder had reduced it to swiping and bad
Speaker 7:  sex and anyone who was serious about finding a partner was out of luck.
Speaker 7:  This is music from an animated video that was part of Hinges anti
Speaker 7:  Tinder campaign in it, a man who looks a lot like
Speaker 7:  Hinge ceo Justin McLeod wanders through a kind of
Speaker 7:  dating hellscape with signs to attractions like eye candy
Speaker 7:  and one nighter.
Speaker 7:  Then he walks through a door that says Hinge and finds a bright paradise
Speaker 7:  of happy couples. The campaign was called the Dating
Speaker 7:  Apocalypse, the same name as that Vanity Fair piece.
Speaker 7:  It was not exactly subtle
Speaker 7:  if most other apps were just Tinder with a twist hinges new
Speaker 7:  plan was to be everything that Tinder wasn't to be the anti
Speaker 7:  Tinder.
Speaker 22:  We knew that if you can really like get to the core of what a
Speaker 22:  young single woman's problem is and solve that,
Speaker 22:  then you were going to like have a successful dating product
Speaker 22:  and at the time it was like single millennial women. They were just like
Speaker 22:  so tired of hookup culture, tired of like not really
Speaker 22:  knowing a man's intentions and that was the problem that we really said
Speaker 22:  about solving.
Speaker 7:  Mort led a redesign of Hinge to make it feel less hindery.
Speaker 7:  It started with dropping the swipe.
Speaker 2:  The traditional swiping app experience was a numbers
Speaker 2:  game.
Speaker 22:  It did lead to this like culture where people
Speaker 22:  weren't coming into using a dating app with intention of really like
Speaker 22:  dating and getting to know someone and getting into a relationship.
Speaker 2:  What we wanted to do was to create a
Speaker 2:  environment where actions meant what they were
Speaker 2:  supposed to mean.
Speaker 22:  So we knew we had to like slow people down to make sure they're really
Speaker 22:  measured with their decisions and to like help get the conversation started.
Speaker 7:  While Tinder liked to brag about its billions of swipes and
Speaker 7:  introductions, hinge used different metrics, good
Speaker 7:  dates per user became the app's North Star. According to Tim,
Speaker 7:  Matt Gin,
Speaker 2:  If we were the best at creating dates for our users, we would win.
Speaker 7:  In 2017, hinges strategy had started to work.
Speaker 7:  It was gaining users and venture capitalists were getting curious.
Speaker 7:  They weren't the only ones.
Speaker 9:  I'm always looking for like what's missing, right? Like is there a
Speaker 9:  need user need out there that's that is not being served.
Speaker 7:  Ana Tre again,
Speaker 9:  Tinder was like fun and fast and easy
Speaker 9:  and like everyone loved it but there was a certain
Speaker 9:  kind of user, which I think I I call it like more
Speaker 9:  intentional like millennial who wanted like to spend
Speaker 9:  more time on each profile, be a little more intentional about who they wanna
Speaker 9:  meet, learn more about that person. They wanted something
Speaker 9:  cool and fun and modern as Tinder but a little like
Speaker 9:  slow and intentional.
Speaker 7:  In theory, acquiring Hinge would help match Group remain a
Speaker 7:  one-stop shop for any online dating experience a user could
Speaker 7:  want. You know if you hate Tinder, we've got the anti Tinder.
Speaker 7:  So in 2017 Match made an initial investment in
Speaker 7:  Hinge. Two years later it bought the whole thing.
Speaker 7:  Hinge hadn't beaten Tinder, it had joined it but
Speaker 7:  that was good enough for Matt Gin.
Speaker 2:  It was a strong sense of validation that what we were doing was working and
Speaker 2:  that we had a a promising future
Speaker 7:  And Hinge maintained its image as the anti Tinder. After
Speaker 7:  joining Match Group
Speaker 23:  Hinge wants you to meet someone great
Speaker 23:  even if it kills us.
Speaker 23:  Hinge, the dating app designed to be deleted
Speaker 7:  But Match didn't buy Hinge just to fill out a place in its portfolio.
Speaker 7:  It expected the app to bring in cash too.
Speaker 2:  We needed to make money and so
Speaker 2:  we needed to show a return on investment. So 2020 was the year when
Speaker 2:  we needed to monetize.
Speaker 7:  Good thing there was already a playbook for that. Tinder's business
Speaker 7:  model was a proven success. It had made hundreds of millions
Speaker 7:  of dollars selling superpowers a la carte and bundling them
Speaker 7:  into premium subscriptions. In 2019, Tinder
Speaker 7:  bought in 1.2 billion in direct revenue. It
Speaker 7:  made sense for Hinge to go down the same path.
Speaker 2:  What you can pay for is a more effective
Speaker 2:  or accelerated experience of finding your next date,
Speaker 2:  engaging with more people at once, getting more attention.
Speaker 7:  Hinge debuted a new feature called the Rose in 2020.
Speaker 7:  If you saw someone you really liked, you could send them a rose.
Speaker 7:  Every user got a free rose each week. The idea was that
Speaker 7:  if you were willing to part with your precious rose for someone, they'd be
Speaker 7:  more likely to hit you back. The Rose also bumped you to the top of
Speaker 7:  their list of people who had liked them. You might be buried otherwise
Speaker 7:  and a Rose could also get you access to people who are the most
Speaker 7:  desirable on the app, so-called standouts.
Speaker 7:  You could buy more roses for 3 99 a pop and of
Speaker 7:  course they're cheaper by the dozen. If all of this
Speaker 7:  sounds familiar. That's because the Rose is just Tinder's super like in
Speaker 7:  cellophane packaging. The reception to some of these new features,
Speaker 7:  which were after all ripped from Tinder was a little bit
Speaker 7:  frosty. Lucy Mort again,
Speaker 22:  Yeah, it's like withholding pieces of the experience
Speaker 22:  and like dangling a carrot in front of a user but being like, mm,
Speaker 22:  pay us to get it. And I think that can feel like kind of shitty
Speaker 22:  as a user,
Speaker 24:  But it seems like these apps are improving on taking
Speaker 24:  our money and making us spend more time on their apps than
Speaker 24:  they are in, in actuality matching us with people that
Speaker 24:  we're more interested in. Right.
Speaker 7:  That's Jeremy. We're only using his first name because he works
Speaker 7:  as an app developer and wants to keep his job anyway.
Speaker 7:  Jeremy is one of the dozens of dating app users we talked to for this series.
Speaker 7:  He's skeptical of the effectiveness of Roses and the other
Speaker 7:  superpowers the app asks users to pay for.
Speaker 24:  I would never pay to send a rose to someone on Hinge and if I
Speaker 24:  did I, I wouldn't think that they'd be motivated to
Speaker 24:  match with me over someone else.
Speaker 7:  But Jeremy does pay for a Hinge subscription. It
Speaker 7:  lets him see people who have already liked him and that he says makes
Speaker 7:  things more efficient. But he's not sure. Efficiency has
Speaker 7:  helped him find what he's really looking for A partner
Speaker 7:  for Jeremy and many other users. It's not clear if buying all of
Speaker 7:  this extra stuff is working or if it's just throwing money into the void.
Speaker 7:  Sarah Satir is another dater. She diligently
Speaker 7:  uses her free rose every week.
Speaker 25:  I mean upwards for sure. If it's been
Speaker 25:  a year then I've given out 50,
Speaker 25:  but I do it every week. So however long it's existed, I've been doing it
Speaker 25:  once a week.
Speaker 7:  One person has responded to a Rose, she has sent
Speaker 7:  a guy who is thinking about moving to her city. They talked for months before
Speaker 7:  he arrived, but in person, the chemistry was non-existent.
Speaker 25:  I think I kept going out with him cuz I was like on paper, he is so perfect
Speaker 25:  and there's gotta be something here that I'm missing. I've gotta be able
Speaker 25:  to unlock the connection here and there just wasn't and I think that's the
Speaker 25:  thing you can't, you can't account for and you can't
Speaker 25:  app optimize for the connection. You just can't make that
Speaker 25:  a feature.
Speaker 7:  Edison Wilkinson also hasn't had luck with Roses.
Speaker 26:  Hinge does that like, oh my goodness, we know you'll be attracted to these
Speaker 26:  women and you have to like, you give them the one rose you get or pay
Speaker 26:  five bucks for a rose. Yes, absolutely. They do that for sure.
Speaker 7:  Have you paid to interact with those women?
Speaker 26:  Absolutely. For sure.
Speaker 26:  Absolutely, and nothing has come from it at all.
Speaker 26:  Fool me. One, shame on you, fool me twice. I need to get off this
Speaker 26:  app.
Speaker 7:  But that's not what's happening. People are staying on the app
Speaker 7:  and they're paying on the app. In 2020, hinge brought in
Speaker 7:  90 million in revenue. It nearly doubled the
Speaker 7:  following year. Hinge was making more from each paying user
Speaker 7:  too. In 2019, that was around $5 per month.
Speaker 7:  In 2022 it was 25. The value
Speaker 7:  proposition of these premium features is more efficiency, more
Speaker 7:  visibility, more likes, more, more,
Speaker 7:  more. But do they allow users to achieve their
Speaker 7:  romantic goals to find partners? I put the
Speaker 7:  question to Amna tore the Match Group executive. Do you
Speaker 7:  think those other features do
Speaker 7:  give people more success on the app?
Speaker 9:  Yes, they do. I mean like the obvious proof of that is that they're willing
Speaker 9:  to continue to pay for it because they see when they use it, they see
Speaker 9:  results and when they see more results, they want to buy it. Again,
Speaker 7:  Obvious proof is a stretch of the dozens of users
Speaker 7:  we spoke to, it seemed that what people were paying for was the
Speaker 7:  promise of results. Like spend enough and
Speaker 7:  surely they'll meet the right person eventually. I
Speaker 7:  wonder are the roses helping people find love? Is that what the data
Speaker 7:  is showing?
Speaker 9:  It is, it is. I mean, I think there's a stat on the app itself that like
Speaker 9:  once, if you send a Rose, you have a far higher chance of getting
Speaker 9:  a response and getting into a conversation. Then you don't,
Speaker 7:  That's not really what I asked, but former HIN
Speaker 7:  exec Tim, Matt Gin says matches moneymaking strategy.
Speaker 7:  While not perfect is a win for everyone, users
Speaker 2:  Want to go on dates. That's what the product is there to deliver. People
Speaker 2:  who pay for these things are getting incremental value, otherwise they wouldn't
Speaker 2:  pay for them. The roses that they're buying are working, the boosts they're
Speaker 2:  buying are working. The subscriptions that they're buying are working, they're
Speaker 2:  having a better experience and more dates. And if you want those things then
Speaker 2:  you can pay for them. You, you don't. Great. Functionally, I
Speaker 2:  can know that we took nothing away from the free experience when we introduced
Speaker 2:  them
Speaker 2:  and you know, a listener might believe me
Speaker 2:  or they might not. I don't know. It's a hard thing to prove. And
Speaker 2:  who trusts big corporations? You know,
Speaker 2:  if you assume that they're well-meaning and good, they wanna find
Speaker 2:  you, you're perfect match so that the more they know about you,
Speaker 2:  the more perfect partner they can show you.
Speaker 7:  Ev Gilbert, the lawyer we heard from earlier, doesn't think that
Speaker 7:  paying more for the apps means more success.
Speaker 2:  The less benevolent interpretation is that they're trying to find
Speaker 2:  a way to make more money off of you. So maybe
Speaker 2:  if they know who exactly you're attracted to, they're gonna give
Speaker 2:  you something that's the store brand diversion. So
Speaker 2:  you're like, okay, so the real one is out there. It's like
Speaker 2:  nibbling at the edges, but never getting the core.
Speaker 7:  We are sold on the idea that it's just a matter of time until that
Speaker 7:  special person sees our profile and swipes right
Speaker 7:  and paying for special features will supposedly shorten the process.
Speaker 2:  It felt like someone was trying to figure out what I liked, but it didn't
Speaker 2:  feel like they were trying to do that to help me in any way.
Speaker 7:  What did you do in terms of that? Like did that change your relationship
Speaker 7:  to the apps? Did you stop using them and you were pissed about it?
Speaker 2:  I I kept using them because what's the
Speaker 2:  alternative?
Speaker 7:  Lakshmi, welcome back. What did you think?
Speaker 8:  I take it that AV Gilbert does not pay for dating apps.
Speaker 7:  I don't think so. In his final year of law school, he actually wrote a
Speaker 7:  paper calling Match Group a monopoly.
Speaker 8:  It's like that moment when you realize Proctor and Gamble makes all of your
Speaker 8:  household products or that Rupert Murdoch is the hand behind a
Speaker 8:  lot of the news, but then you stop and think about dating apps,
Speaker 8:  you're hoping they'll help you find other humans to connect with, and then
Speaker 8:  you think they're run by a multi-billion dollar
Speaker 8:  corporation trying to keep its shareholders happy. That can be
Speaker 8:  concerning
Speaker 7:  Is this late stage capitalism at its finest?
Speaker 7:  Anything and truly everything has a price.
Speaker 8:  The thing that strikes me is our love lives are being steered by match
Speaker 8:  group's business objectives. So people are paying for all of these
Speaker 8:  features and they don't really know if the money's getting them anywhere.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, being a part of Match Group seems to flatten these dating
Speaker 7:  services into machines, but a lot of people feel
Speaker 7:  like there aren't many alternatives to this world that match Group rules
Speaker 8:  And Match Group truly has its tentacles in every niche of the market.
Speaker 8:  From black singles to single parents to folks over
Speaker 8:  50, no matter where you turn year in the Match, vortex,
Speaker 7:  So many different cars. But when you lift the hood and take a look at
Speaker 7:  the engine, it's still Match Group.
Speaker 8:  In our next episode, we're gonna go one layer deeper into the system
Speaker 8:  and look at the algorithms that are literally shaping our romantic futures,
Speaker 7:  How daters are noticing the patterns in how the apps work, and
Speaker 7:  trying to figure out ways to make them work a little better for themselves.
Speaker 7:  Special thanks to Dr. Helen Fisher, Mark Brooks and Jim
Speaker 7:  Osman. Archival clips in this episode are from CBS. This Morning
Speaker 8:  Land of the Giants Dating Games is a production of The Cut
Speaker 8:  the Verge and the Vox Media podcast network. Owa
Speaker 8:  Kemi, ALA Desu is the show's producer. Cynthia
Speaker 8:  Beza is our production assistant, Charlotte Silver Fact. Check
Speaker 8:  this episode. Jolie Myers is our editor.
Speaker 8:  Brandon McFarland is our engineer and also compose the show's theme.
Speaker 7:  Nicole Hill is our showrunner. Additional support from
Speaker 7:  Art Chung. Jake Kanakas is Deputy Editor of the
Speaker 7:  Verge. Nasha Kwa is our executive producer.
Speaker 7:  I'm Sangita Sing Kurtz
Speaker 8:  And I am Lakshmi Renin. If you liked this episode,
Speaker 8:  please share it and follow the show by clicking the plus sign in your
Speaker 8:  podcast app.