# Transcript
ID: 6921748f-dad0-4471-aebd-97bde79be9ad
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: iPhone and watches and wallpapers, oh my
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-4290211756264018645/-8963137978197215062/s93290-US-6171s-1695217256.mp3
Description: Today on the flagship podcast of the Action Button:
03:34 - The Verge's David Pierce chats with Allison Johnson and Dan Seifert about their reviews of the iPhone 15 and iPhone 15 Pro.
41:02 - Victoria Song joins the show to talk about her review of the Apple Watch Series 9 and Apple Watch Ultra 2.
1:07:58 - David chats with Isaac Mosna and Widgetsmith's David Smith about customizing your iPhone wallpaper and widgets.
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we love hearing from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Disabled
Speaker 2:  Welcome to The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of the action button. I'm
Speaker 2:  your friend David Pierce and I'm having one of those days, I assume everybody
Speaker 2:  has days like this where you wake up at some outrageously early hour
Speaker 2:  and you look at the clock and you're like, ah, cool, I have five more hours
Speaker 2:  to sleep. But then something in your brain is just like, no,
Speaker 2:  we are awake now. Anyway, that's the kind of day I'm having. I've been up
Speaker 2:  since like two o'clock this morning. I read a bunch of news, I
Speaker 2:  read a book. I looked at TikTok for a while. I saw every
Speaker 2:  single thing that has like ever been posted to Reddit in history. I
Speaker 2:  did all the New York Times games and somehow it's still like first thing
Speaker 2:  in the morning. It's a very confusing way to start the day 'cause I kind
Speaker 2:  of feel like it's lunchtime now. Now I'm out just like aimlessly
Speaker 2:  wandering the neighborhood because I don't know what else to do with myself
Speaker 2:  because the sun just came up and I've been awake for what feels like a
Speaker 2:  hundred hours. Anyway, it's gonna be a very confusing day. I'm gonna get
Speaker 2:  to 2:00 PM and be like, well time for dinner. Time to go to bed. Wish me
Speaker 2:  luck. Anyway, we have an awesome show coming up for you today we're gonna
Speaker 2:  talk mostly about the iPhones because it's iPhone season. We have
Speaker 2:  reviews of the iPhone 15 and iPhone 15 Pro to talk about. We're also gonna
Speaker 2:  talk about our reviews of the Apple Watch and the Apple Watch Ultra, but
Speaker 2:  we're also gonna talk about software stuff. There's obviously new stuff in
Speaker 2:  iOS 17 interactive widgets and all kinds of cool things going on. But
Speaker 2:  more broadly, thinking about all this stuff over the last few months has
Speaker 2:  really led me down this rabbit hole of phone personalization. I think the
Speaker 2:  work people are willing to do to make their phone feel like
Speaker 2:  an extension of themselves, whether it's a case or the wallpaper or the
Speaker 2:  app icons or the look and feel of the whole phone in
Speaker 2:  general, people are willing to do a lot so that when you turn on the screen
Speaker 2:  it makes you feel something. It makes you feel like you. And I think that's
Speaker 2:  really cool. So I called up a couple of smart people to talk about how we
Speaker 2:  do that and how that works and how Apple thinks about that. So we're gonna
Speaker 2:  dig into that too. All of that is coming up in just a second, but first
Speaker 2:  it is finally time that I can go home and like reasonably make breakfast
Speaker 2:  and have coffee and start the day and also probably take a
Speaker 2:  several hour nap and see how we do. So I'm gonna go do all of that
Speaker 2:  and then we'll be right back. This is The Vergecast. We'll see you in a sec.
Speaker 3:  Support for this show comes from Intel. Where do world changing
Speaker 3:  ideas get their start at Intel. It starts with real
Speaker 3:  solutions and real solutions. Start with exceptional
Speaker 3:  engineering. The quantum computing revolution. The next
Speaker 3:  generation of AI experts, the renewable energy grid
Speaker 3:  early diagnosis for cancer. The examples are
Speaker 3:  countless, the impacts are endless, but the foundation is
Speaker 3:  always the same. It starts with Intel. Learn
Speaker 3:  more at Intel dot com slash stories.
Speaker 4:  Support for this show comes from American, Express, Business If. you
Speaker 4:  are a small business owner. you wanna partner with someone that can help
Speaker 4:  make your day to day a rewarding experience. That's where American
Speaker 4:  Express can come in. American Express business cards are built
Speaker 4:  for your business with features and benefits like the ability to earn membership
Speaker 4:  rewards, points on select cards, the power to pay for big business
Speaker 4:  purchases and 24 7 support from a business specialist
Speaker 4:  built for your business. Amex business terms apply.
Speaker 4:  learn more at American Express dot com slash business cards.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. All right, I've had coffee, I've had Cheerios,
Speaker 2:  I kind of know what time it is. I'm ready. Let's do this.
Speaker 2:  The new iPhones go on sale this Friday and our reviews of the
Speaker 2:  iPhone 1515 plus 15 Pro and 15 Pro
Speaker 2:  Max are all live on The Verge dot com. You should read them all. They're
Speaker 2:  all really great. I don't know if this is the most interesting phone
Speaker 2:  of the year exactly. In fact, it's definitely not the most interesting
Speaker 2:  phone of the year. If you define interesting as just like the one trying
Speaker 2:  to do the most new cool stuff. But it's almost certainly the
Speaker 2:  one the most people are thinking about buying. But should you
Speaker 2:  and which one? Who better to answer that question than the people who reviewed
Speaker 2:  the phones? The Verge is Allison Johnson and Dan Seaford. They're both here.
Speaker 2:  Let's get into it. Allison. Hello. Hello Dan? Hello.
Speaker 5:  Hello.
Speaker 2:  You both have used two of the four phones. You've done
Speaker 2:  big reviews. I have a million like specific questions, but let's
Speaker 2:  just kind of like top line takeaways from your reviews.
Speaker 2:  Like are these phones any good? Yes or no? Who cares?
Speaker 2:  Dan, you go first. iPhone 15 and 15 plus. What's the verdict?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. In a shocking turn of events, apple released a turd of a device. No,
Speaker 5:  I'm kidding. This is the 15th. iPhone like it's, it's like they've been
Speaker 5:  doing this a long time. They know how to make iPhones. Yes, they are good
Speaker 5:  devices. In fact, you could probably say they are great devices and I think
Speaker 5:  that I review the 15 and the 15 plus. I think if people buy them, they're
Speaker 5:  gonna be really happy with them. The type of person that buys this phone
Speaker 5:  typically is coming from a much older iPhone and so
Speaker 5:  they're not coming from an iPhone 14, probably not a 13, so we're talking
Speaker 5:  like a 12 or an 11 or maybe even a 10 Ss. And they are
Speaker 5:  going to get a lot of new features and new experiences plus better
Speaker 5:  camera, better battery life, better performance, better display, all that
Speaker 5:  stuff. So I think it is like a meaningful upgrade for the type of person
Speaker 5:  that is buying this are the 15 and 15 plus all that exciting to
Speaker 5:  us, like enthusiasts and maybe our audience, probably not.
Speaker 5:  Like we've seen all of these things before. They are,
Speaker 5:  I've been calling them a repackaging of the 14 pro. They've got
Speaker 5:  most of the same features as the 14 pro, but not all of the
Speaker 5:  features. Notably they have, they don't have high refresh free screens and
Speaker 5:  they don't have always on displays, which is like two things that I think
Speaker 5:  would make a better experience on these devices. And
Speaker 2:  We're gonna come back to both those, those things.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. But like otherwise you get the dynamic island, you get a high
Speaker 5:  resolution camera. Apple's changes to the design this year by just kind of
Speaker 5:  softening the edges and the matte glass and stuff do make them nicer
Speaker 5:  to hold, which you'll never experience 'cause you're gonna put a case on
Speaker 5:  it anyways, but it's there and then they come in
Speaker 5:  five very boring colors.
Speaker 2:  The rage you feel about the colors really like it, it, it's just like it,
Speaker 2:  it fills me up in a lovely way,
Speaker 5:  Don't, I don't get it. Like why bother with colors if you're gonna, if this
Speaker 5:  is what you're gonna do and, and we know apple's done good colors in the
Speaker 5:  past,
Speaker 2:  So yeah, apple is perfectly capable of making cool colors. It just chose
Speaker 2:  not to this year for some reason. Like if you find yourself making a color
Speaker 2:  that you call natural, like you've done it wrong, you've just, you blew it.
Speaker 2:  All right. Allison the pro and pro Max, what's the, what's the kind of top
Speaker 2:  line verdict here?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it's kind of along similar lines. I mean they're good
Speaker 6:  in the ways that we are used to pro iPhone
Speaker 6:  being good. I think the new things here this year are
Speaker 6:  like certainly not breakthroughs. And anyone
Speaker 6:  on Android who's hearing me talk about U S B C in like
Speaker 6:  a five times Zoom lens is, you know, like cackling. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  We should just say right up top like Android users. Like we know.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. The number of things we're going to say that Android phones have had
Speaker 2:  since like 2004, like we get it. We're we're with you
Speaker 2:  we're on the same page. The SS 23 Ultra is a terrific phone. Yes.
Speaker 2:  Just let Apple people have this one just, just for today. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  Just today
Speaker 2:  Apple people have this like
Speaker 6:  A blanket statement of like I get it. I know. Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 6:  But yeah, it is the first time these things have all come together
Speaker 6:  on an iPhone and I think they're, they're smart in the pro.
Speaker 6:  They're things that, you know, being able to to hook up like
Speaker 6:  an SSD card reader that isn't a special lightning
Speaker 6:  dongle situation is cool. And like I appreciate that
Speaker 6:  someone who is maybe just, just wants a phone, just
Speaker 6:  wants it to work is don't really care so much but it's there. The
Speaker 6:  five times zoom, you know, is, is neat for people who wanna get
Speaker 6:  in there a little more and who are a little more picky about their photography.
Speaker 6:  And the action button is just nice. Like you
Speaker 6:  want a button that does whatever you want on your iPhone, you can have
Speaker 6:  it now like that's super sweet.
Speaker 2:  Okay. I have a bunch of specific things in there I wanna talk about. I think
Speaker 2:  U S B C is a, is a big one and I, I wanna spend a bunch of time talking about
Speaker 2:  that 'cause that surprised me a lot from both of your reviews. But the
Speaker 2:  first thing that jumped out at me that you both said, which I thought was
Speaker 2:  surprising was that the new phones feel
Speaker 2:  different like to hold in your hands than the other ones do.
Speaker 2:  Like I feel like I'm used to Apple saying every year, like we've developed
Speaker 2:  an all new way to make these phones that will change everything. And then
Speaker 2:  you pick it up and it's like, yep, this is still that one. It's an iPhone.
Speaker 2:  But both of you had the experience of kind of picking up the new one and
Speaker 2:  being like, this feels, this feels better. Walk me through
Speaker 2:  that. What, what's actually better about it when you hold it?
Speaker 6:  So I live the life you guys know where I have like 10 phones on my desk at
Speaker 6:  once and I will reach for the 15
Speaker 6:  Pro and pick it up and I just have that moment of like, Ooh, this is
Speaker 6:  a little nicer than I was expecting. Like it's the brushed
Speaker 6:  finish on the sides of the phone. It's, they're a little more rounded
Speaker 6:  the edges so they're, they're just like a tiny bit more comfortable to hold.
Speaker 6:  And really the major thing is on the pro models,
Speaker 6:  especially just being noticeably lighter.
Speaker 6:  Like they're not light phones but if you ever
Speaker 6:  hauled a 14 pro Max then you know the experience of
Speaker 6:  like holding a paper weight in your hand.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, it's a, it's a big phone.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, this, this feels like holding a normal phone. It doesn't feel like
Speaker 6:  holding a super heavy phone. Okay.
Speaker 2:  And so how much of that is like the, the titanium and all this stuff
Speaker 2:  they talked about in the pro versus just kind of the, the
Speaker 2:  way they've reshaped it? 'cause Dan you had a very similar experience in
Speaker 2:  kind of how the lower end phones feel, right?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, yeah. No the, the lower end phones I guess the, the 15 to the 15 plus
Speaker 5:  they're technically the same weights or within very small minute
Speaker 5:  differences of last year's models. But if you're coming from like
Speaker 5:  an iPhone 11 and iPhone 15 is like noticeably
Speaker 5:  lighter, like the order of more than 20 grams which is is absolutely
Speaker 5:  noticeable. I've been, my personal phone's an iPhone 13 pro and that just
Speaker 5:  feels like a lead weight to me. The 15 plus which has a much larger
Speaker 5:  screen is actually technically lighter than my 13 pro.
Speaker 5:  And so you know, you you may say like oh 10 20 grams here,
Speaker 5:  it doesn't really matter. Like when you're holding these things all day long
Speaker 5:  and you're putting 'em in and in your pocket or whatever, like I feel every
Speaker 5:  single gram that gets added and it's like my biggest complaint with the iPhone
Speaker 5:  for the past few years, the pro models at least is how heavy they've become
Speaker 5:  because Apple is stuck with the stainless steel frame and the
Speaker 5:  polished and the premium, all that jazz. So I'm really excited that the
Speaker 5:  pro models move to titanium but I also appreciate that the
Speaker 5:  standard model also benefits from the softer edges on the frame
Speaker 5:  so that it doesn't cut into your pinky or your your palm as much when you're
Speaker 5:  holding it. The back glass is now a frosted or matte finish
Speaker 5:  which is like nicer to hold. I think that makes it a little bit more slippery.
Speaker 5:  Anyone who's owned a pro foam for the past few years kind of knows what that
Speaker 5:  back glass feels like. It's a kind of a slippery experience. Again, most
Speaker 5:  people are gonna put cases on these and all kind of doesn't matter, but they
Speaker 5:  just feel like nicer objects and that's like befitting of what the prices
Speaker 5:  are because really even the less expensive phones are starting at
Speaker 5:  $800 and at this point like that is like purely in premium phone
Speaker 5:  territory. You can get really like advanced devices for this much.
Speaker 5:  I mean if you find a good deal you'll find a flip phone from Samsung for
Speaker 5:  that much money. So like, you know, you have to like kind of justify
Speaker 5:  what the cost is that you're paying for and there's a lot of reasons for
Speaker 5:  it. But you know, part of it is the experience of the tactile device and,
Speaker 5:  and I think that these are very well made, it's very obvious that Apple's
Speaker 5:  been making iPhones for a very long time and they've continued to like kind
Speaker 5:  of iterate and polish them to, to make them a nicer experience.
Speaker 2:  Okay. Yeah that makes sense. Allison, this one's just for you and then we're
Speaker 2:  gonna go back to things Dan's allowed to talk about Action button. What did
Speaker 2:  you do? Well I don't care about anything else about the iPhone 15. I care
Speaker 2:  so much about the action button
Speaker 6:  Button. There's a new button I, so I put it to
Speaker 6:  open the camera, which I thought I would really like. 'cause I, I struggle
Speaker 6:  with a swiping on the screen to open. I don't know why
Speaker 2:  The number of people I have heard say that in the last seven days is so fascinating.
Speaker 2:  Yeah I feel like there are a hundred thousand ways to open the camera
Speaker 2:  iOS like another button to do it is the last thing I need. oh my gosh. But
Speaker 2:  it seems like so many people ha struggle with that same thing
Speaker 2:  you're describing. It's really interesting.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it's always when someone else is looking at me using the phone too,
Speaker 2:  They're like, take this picture and you're like, ah,
Speaker 6:  I don't know, I'm sorry. Yeah, so I I,
Speaker 6:  that's like the first thing I did. I was super excited about it but then
Speaker 6:  I noticed I just wasn't really using it for that. I think it's just
Speaker 6:  like I used the pro Max a little more and I think having it just like, like
Speaker 6:  it's that much taller and the action button is that much farther away. It
Speaker 6:  just felt like a pain to it just like kind of awkward to be like
Speaker 6:  reaching around the back of the phone to you know, push the button. But
Speaker 6:  so I have other ideas for it, I'm gonna, I'm gonna do the shortcuts like
Speaker 6:  y'all think I'm kidding about making it order me a pumpkin spice latte.
Speaker 6:  But I am a hundred percent doing that. Yeah, I'm back in my
Speaker 6:  back of my natural environment so I can go wild with it
Speaker 6:  now.
Speaker 2:  I love that. Dan you're not allowed to answer 'cause you reviewed the loser
Speaker 2:  phones. I'm just kidding. Someday when you're allowed to have an action button
Speaker 2:  many years from now, what are you gonna do with it?
Speaker 5:  I hate to be really boring but I, I think I would probably use it for the
Speaker 5:  ringer switch maybe. But like I was thinking yesterday,
Speaker 5:  there's a feature on Android that I really like that if you flip the phone
Speaker 5:  face down it turns into do not disturb mode. And there isn't a way to do
Speaker 5:  that on the iPhone, but I could set the action button to do not disturb.
Speaker 5:  So like I could just like hold it for a second put in do not disturb face
Speaker 5:  down. It's more than like I want, do I wanna just flip it over and have it
Speaker 5:  down? So I don't know, that's like my first initial idea. I, you know, Allison
Speaker 5:  mentioned we the camera, I think that what a lot of
Speaker 5:  enthusiasts will do is set it up to open third party camera apps, which
Speaker 5:  right now is a pain no matter which way you do it on the
Speaker 5:  iPhone, whether it's for the lock screen or control center or whatever, opening
Speaker 5:  a third party camera app is kind of annoying. I think maybe you could set
Speaker 5:  a widget on the lock screen now to do it, which is a workaround. But
Speaker 5:  I've already seen the developers of Haylight are like adding a toggle in
Speaker 5:  their app to like let you do it from the action button. And so I'm sure a
Speaker 5:  lot of people are gonna do that.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, that's a good one. It's funny you mentioned Do Not Disturb because
Speaker 2:  that was, that was my thought too. Like somebody sent me a thing the other
Speaker 2:  day where they had built a shortcut where whenever they plug their phone
Speaker 2:  in, if it's after 10:00 PM it automatically switches it to sleep mode.
Speaker 2:  And I was like, that's genius. But then this came out and I was just like,
Speaker 2:  oh it's the same thing. Like I, I can just punch on Do not disturb, which
Speaker 2:  is the kind of thing that I'd like to like do often when I even just wanna
Speaker 2:  pay attention for a few minutes or whatever. And having a button that can
Speaker 2:  do it seems very nice. I'm very into that but okay, that's enough of that.
Speaker 2:  I could also talk to you about interactive widgets for several hours, but
Speaker 2:  we'll do that on another podcast. Let's talk about U U S P C because
Speaker 2:  the thing that I think a bunch of us have discovered over the last
Speaker 2:  eight days since this iPhone launched is that Apple
Speaker 2:  made a much more open port than any of us expected.
Speaker 2:  And I'm just assuming, knowing the two of you that you've spent a lot of
Speaker 2:  time over the last week plugging random things into the iPhone to see what
Speaker 2:  would happen. Allison what, what have you been plugging into the iPhone and
Speaker 2:  what has happened?
Speaker 6:  Well, when we were shooting the video, you know, we had access to like
Speaker 6:  an ethernet cable and SD card and all this stuff
Speaker 6:  and yeah, it, it truly is like kind of mind blowing that you
Speaker 6:  plug it in and it, it doesn't, it doesn't complain, it doesn't,
Speaker 6:  you know, make you jump through a bunch of hoops. Like it just does
Speaker 6:  whatever you're trying to do. And like we plugged in that ethernet cable
Speaker 6:  and turned off the wifi and the cell data and
Speaker 6:  it just had internet. It just had internet from a cable. It was like
Speaker 6:  who, who saw that coming? What
Speaker 2:  A world I
Speaker 6:  Know.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I think we've been so conditioned for like, especially with the iPhone
Speaker 5:  for Apple to get in the way of what we want to do with it. That it's, it
Speaker 5:  is like, it's a si it's, it feels a little silly to say that like I plugged
Speaker 5:  in an ethernet cable and it worked or like I plugged in an SD card and I
Speaker 5:  could see the files on it. Like, but we are just so conditioned
Speaker 5:  to the iPhone's kind of like guard walled garden
Speaker 5:  experience where you wouldn't think that you can normally do these things
Speaker 5:  and in the past they required special hardware adapters and even
Speaker 5:  then it was still limited. So like it was kind of fun to just
Speaker 5:  jam something into the U S B port, watch what happens and then be like, oh
Speaker 5:  that's the thing you would've expected to happen. And like I don't know how
Speaker 5:  often you're going to use ethernet on your iPhone, probably never, but
Speaker 5:  photographers might use SD card, videographers can shoot directly to an SS
Speaker 5:  S S D, stuff like that. Like all those things just kind of work. It's almost
Speaker 5:  like it's a computer.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. What a crazy idea. It does seem like storage is
Speaker 2:  probably the most likely real use case for people. Right.
Speaker 2:  In part because it's a way to like get stuff off of your phone in a way that
Speaker 2:  is not always easy. But also because like I, I
Speaker 2:  feel like a thing I have surprisingly often is I have something on a hard
Speaker 2:  drive or somewhere else that I would like to be on my phone so that I can
Speaker 2:  do something with and you can just plug in external storage and it just opens
Speaker 2:  up in the files app. Right? Like that's pretty meaningful and new and
Speaker 2:  it's nuts that I'm saying that like it's an exciting new feature but, but
Speaker 2:  like here we are. Yeah. Are there, are there other things that you feel like
Speaker 2:  rise to that level of like things people might actually
Speaker 2:  use this port for other than charging?
Speaker 5:  I think that some people might wanna use use it for video out You can, yeah
Speaker 5:  you can plug a U S B C cable to H D M I or to display port. It supports
Speaker 5:  display port out at four K 60 resolution. So if you want
Speaker 5:  to plug the phone into a TV and watch a video
Speaker 5:  on the tv, you get, you get screen mirroring basically. But the, the, if
Speaker 5:  you're watching a video you can make the video go whole scr full screen.
Speaker 5:  That might be a a use case for some folks. But again, yeah, I think you're
Speaker 5:  probably right in that it is either U S B hubs that allow you
Speaker 5:  to plug in like U S B A accessories or storage
Speaker 5:  are really going to be the main type of accessories outside of
Speaker 5:  charging that you would use the U S B C port for.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I just, I just wanna say Allison, kudos for getting the sentence Dex
Speaker 2:  remains undefeated into the 15 pro review because you
Speaker 2:  Thank you. You would think you could plug it into something and you might
Speaker 2:  get a full blown, you know, desktop environment on a screen. But
Speaker 2:  we, we got a little, we got a little Dex win in the 15 pro review and that
Speaker 2:  made me very happy
Speaker 6:  And and they're so intense about like how good this
Speaker 6:  processor is that you would think like, okay so let me do
Speaker 6:  something with it. No, you can play resonant Evo.
Speaker 2:  I will not lie. I have had the thought that stage manager
Speaker 2:  feels like something that might appear when you plug your
Speaker 2:  iPhone into a larger display sometime in the near future. I don't think
Speaker 5:  It's ever gonna happen.
Speaker 2:  I will do that once if that exists. And then never, ever, ever again
Speaker 2:  because it's stage manager. Okay, so the, the other thing we should talk
Speaker 2:  about is the cameras and I think especially on the pro Allison and
Speaker 2:  there are a bunch of new things, there's a bunch of new like
Speaker 2:  underlying tech, but in terms of like features for people, there's the new
Speaker 2:  telephoto lens, the which is five x zoom, which I think is a big deal. There
Speaker 2:  are the new focal lengths on the default camera, which you can move around
Speaker 2:  and pick between. It shoots 24 megapixels by default. Now
Speaker 2:  am I missing anything? Like have those jumped out to you as like really making
Speaker 2:  a difference in how you use your phone's camera every day?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, they're all things that I'm really appreciating and
Speaker 6:  having that, you know, you could always like pinch and zoom a little bit
Speaker 6:  if you feel like the standard camera lens is too wide.
Speaker 6:  But there's something different about, especially having those little like
Speaker 6:  millimeter focal length equivalents in there. It just kind of warms your
Speaker 6:  heart and makes you feel like, oh I'm take, I'm doing photography,
Speaker 2:  I'm real photography.
Speaker 6:  Yeah I'm taking a picture at 35 millimeters, not
Speaker 6:  1.5 x. It like switches back to 1.5 x.
Speaker 2:  As soon as you do it, you get to be the person who says, I make photos, I
Speaker 2:  don't take photos. Yeah. That's like, that's, that's what happens. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  I've been saying that all week and everyone's so tired of me, I'm
Speaker 6:  like, shh, I'm making photographs. Yeah, no I,
Speaker 6:  I've like just very eagerly like incorporated them
Speaker 6:  into how I think about taking pictures with an iPhone and it's great.
Speaker 6:  I'm, I'm happy with, you know, all the flexibility we get this year.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Dan you, I remember when it first launched were very excited about
Speaker 2:  the idea of the, of the 24 megapixel default photos. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  My worry was file size, right? And there's always the thing where it's like,
Speaker 2:  it depends on where you put it, how much resolution you actually need and
Speaker 2:  on and on. And we can debate that forever, but how good
Speaker 2:  a photo do you want versus how many can you store on your phone is kind of
Speaker 2:  a forever question. Like did Apple find the right middle there?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I think with the 24 it's not as big of
Speaker 5:  a file size compromise as, as some people might have expected if you're
Speaker 5:  using the default heath mode, which I'm gonna say heath,
Speaker 2:  Which either is or is not pronounced heath but we'll leave it alone for this
Speaker 2:  heath
Speaker 5:  I noticed that it's about like, you know, if a jpeg is
Speaker 5:  or or if a 12 megapixel image is two megabytes, A 24 is about three
Speaker 5:  that can vary some, you know, photos if they've got more detail
Speaker 5:  in them and stuff like that can be larger and so then the 24 megapixel will
Speaker 5:  be larger but when you go to 48 megapixel it's double the 24.
Speaker 5:  So that is like a significant difference and that will eat up your storage
Speaker 5:  and I don't think you actually gain much in terms of detail with the side-by-side
Speaker 5:  comparisons I did between the 24 and the full size 48,
Speaker 5:  you're not getting a lot there in terms of extra detail because these are
Speaker 5:  such small sensors. But with 24 megapixels you're moving past the
Speaker 5:  12 which we had been at since the iPhone success and you are getting a
Speaker 5:  little bit more room to crop, maybe a little bit more room to digital Zoom
Speaker 5:  as Allison mentioned and a little bit more flexibility. But ultimately,
Speaker 5:  you know, apple likes to talk about how oh you could blow it up to a 20 inch
Speaker 5:  by 30 inch poster and do all this stuff and it's like, yeah no you're not
Speaker 5:  gonna do that. It's a phone photo, it's still gonna look like it comes from
Speaker 5:  a phone but it gives you a little bit more cropping ability
Speaker 5:  after the fact without really compromising storage that much.
Speaker 5:  These phones all started 128 gigabytes now, which is not a
Speaker 5:  terrible starting point especially if you're coming from an older one that
Speaker 5:  had 64 gigs or getting twice as much storage so you got more room for the
Speaker 5:  photos and Apple would love to sell you iCloud plus storage, which it will
Speaker 5:  do up to 12 terabytes a month now. It
Speaker 2:  Would love, it would, I mean it would love to like, like so much it would
Speaker 2:  make Tim Cook personally thrilled to sell you 12 terabytes of iCloud
Speaker 2:  storage. Allison, you and I are both long term
Speaker 2:  anti digital Zoom zealots. I would say, I
Speaker 2:  believe it is criminal to just stand there and pinch and zoom on the
Speaker 2:  screen to make your photos worse. But you in the process of reviewing
Speaker 2:  the 15 Pro and Promax seem to have found some kind of zen
Speaker 2:  with the way that Apple is approaching this. Can you, can you explain this
Speaker 2:  to me? How did you, why does it feel like this works for you?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I, I think part of it is in my head when you're,
Speaker 6:  when you're going to like a specific focal length and Apple
Speaker 6:  is doing a little bit extra in the background with the
Speaker 6:  processing, you know it's not just, it's not just upraising the
Speaker 6:  image and calling it a day. There's
Speaker 6:  a fair amount going on with like deep fusion and then incorporating
Speaker 6:  some detail from a higher resolution frame, which is
Speaker 6:  either the 48 or 24 megapixel if you're in the
Speaker 6:  35 millimeter crop, how much of that makes a big
Speaker 6:  difference? I don't know, but it makes me feel better.
Speaker 6:  I feel like at ease with the picture that I'm taking and
Speaker 6:  I think that's something that we're all gonna have to get more comfy with
Speaker 6:  going forward because even walking, you know, comparing it with the
Speaker 6:  Samsung S 23 Ultra which has that 10 x lens,
Speaker 6:  you know, I'm going to five x to compare it to the
Speaker 6:  iPhone and that's not a native focal length that it has,
Speaker 6:  it's still looks better than the iPhone image,
Speaker 6:  which is funny. So it just kind of changes how you have to think about like,
Speaker 6:  like letting the, trusting the camera a little more and not
Speaker 6:  being quite so picky about focal length.
Speaker 2:  It is a weird thing. I mean all of the process now is digital, like
Speaker 2:  every step of the way computers are doing computer
Speaker 2:  things. So I think I'm, I'm also slowly learning to let go of the
Speaker 2:  idea that if I do it at one x it is capturing a photo as
Speaker 2:  photos were meant to be captured and everything else is like some
Speaker 2:  computery lie, like it's all kind of a computery lie. Yeah. At this point,
Speaker 2:  right? Yeah it's
Speaker 6:  An illusion. We we've,
Speaker 5:  We've heard this from, I know Google when it introduced
Speaker 5:  its super res zoom feature it, it kind of said similar things that
Speaker 5:  like if you were to use super res zoom before you take the photo,
Speaker 5:  you will get a better image than if you just took the photo at the wide angle
Speaker 5:  and digitally cropped it afterwards because they're, they're taking input
Speaker 5:  from multiple frames and averaging them together and things like that. Whereas
Speaker 5:  if you crop later it is just a single frame that you have to work with and
Speaker 5:  Apple's doing a very similar type of thing here where it is averaging multiple
Speaker 5:  frames, stacking them together. That's what D Fusion has been doing for a
Speaker 5:  few years now. I think Allison, they're on like generation three or five
Speaker 5:  of D Fusion, something like that and then now they have the larger sensor
Speaker 5:  that they can also pair higher resolution data from for detail. So I know
Speaker 5:  that like when I go get an iPhone 15 pro and start using it, I'm gonna
Speaker 5:  lock it on 35 millimeter and never look back.
Speaker 2:  That was actually gonna be my next question is like what's the right default
Speaker 2:  setup here? 'cause the other part
Speaker 5:  Is 35 millimeter is the only correct focal
Speaker 2:  Light. Okay. So, we, we shoot 24 megapixel heath images,
Speaker 2:  35 millimeter camera victory forever
Speaker 6:  ProRes log video.
Speaker 2:  You can fit four photos on your phone and it's all over.
Speaker 5:  If you want to be the cool street photographer, you shoot a 35 millimeter.
Speaker 5:  There
Speaker 2:  We go.
Speaker 6:  That's true. That is proven. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Asked and answered. Alright, so let's, let's do some like straightforward
Speaker 2:  buying advice here. So Dan, last year it seems very clear
Speaker 2:  that the people who wanted a 14 picked a 14 over a
Speaker 2:  14 plus. Is there any reason to believe that's not gonna be the case again
Speaker 2:  of the like entry phones? Do we think the 14 is probably
Speaker 2:  the one for most people, the 15 Jesus Christ.
Speaker 5:  So I, you know, I think last year with the 14 and the 14 plus, it was kind
Speaker 5:  of a weird scenario. One the 14 plus didn't come out for quite a few months
Speaker 5:  afterwards so it, it didn't, wasn't the variable at the same time. That's
Speaker 5:  true. And then the 14 plus was like if you want a big screen and a
Speaker 5:  big battery and, and Allison's review last year, like she made the point
Speaker 5:  like this delivers on both of those things but it was doing it at $900
Speaker 5:  and if you wanted a 14 pro Max it was only 200 bucks more
Speaker 5:  this year. The not only is the 15 to 15 plus available
Speaker 5:  at the same time, so you will be able to take advantage of all the same carrier
Speaker 5:  promotions or whatever you'll be in the store. You'll look at it, it's like
Speaker 5:  oh wow, this one actually is bigger but it's also, it's still
Speaker 5:  $900. But the bigger pro phone, the pro Max has
Speaker 5:  gone up in starting price a hundred dollars so now there's a
Speaker 5:  $300 jump And I think that starts to make it like,
Speaker 5:  do I really need to go that much if I just want a big screen and a big battery?
Speaker 5:  And I, I think that people will be making that calculus more and and maybe
Speaker 5:  it'll do better for the plus model. I, I could tell you that the plus model
Speaker 5:  this year absolutely delivers on battery life. I had a horrific travel
Speaker 5:  day coming back from WW D c I was staring at the 15 plus
Speaker 5:  all day long. I had like something like eight, nine hours of screen time
Speaker 5:  and I got home at like 11 or 12 and midnight
Speaker 5:  and I still had like 35% battery left flat on it. It was like that's pretty
Speaker 5:  good. Like this thing just goes. And so for a lot of people big screen, big
Speaker 5:  battery is exactly what they want and 15 plus delivers. I think if you are
Speaker 5:  coming from a mini, which if you have a 12 mini, maybe you're getting
Speaker 5:  around time, they're like needing a new phone, the iPhone 15 is obviously
Speaker 5:  gonna be much more attractive to you. It's smaller, it's lighter, it fits
Speaker 5:  in your hand easier. It's stuff like that. I think that is really the only
Speaker 5:  practical option for anyone who wants a small iPhone at this point. And then
Speaker 5:  the last point of consideration is as usual, apple is selling last
Speaker 5:  year's 14 and 14 plus for a hundred dollars less than the 15 and 15 plus
Speaker 5:  this year. I think that this year the things you
Speaker 5:  get for the a hundred dollars more make it worthwhile to get the 15. Last
Speaker 5:  year we had the opposite conclusion, the 14 was not that much better than
Speaker 5:  the 13 and you can still buy the 13 for a hundred bucks less go save your
Speaker 5:  money. But this year you get U S B C, which is more convenient,
Speaker 5:  flexible way to charge, you get the dynamic island which is you know, a
Speaker 5:  more pleasant, fun user interface and it's going to continue to get more
Speaker 5:  utilized as we go forward. And you do get meaningful improvements on the
Speaker 5:  camera. We didn't really talk too much about it, but I think that the automatic
Speaker 5:  portrait mode is a thing that people will actually really
Speaker 5:  like and use and get a lot of value out of. Especially the average
Speaker 5:  custom consumer buying the iPhone 15 or 15 plus. So all of those things add
Speaker 5:  up. I think they make it worthwhile to buy the 15 over the 14 this year.
Speaker 5:  But if you have a 14, there's no reason to upgrade. There's need, there's
Speaker 5:  probably not much of a reason to upgrade. But if you are on a 12 or 11 or
Speaker 5:  older then I think you, you get a lot here this year. The
Speaker 2:  Portrait mode thing is a good one. I knew there was something in the cool
Speaker 2:  things in the camera list I was forgetting and that's one that's a big deal.
Speaker 2:  Yeah,
Speaker 5:  I I I think that like, you know, I observe my spouse taking pictures of our
Speaker 5:  kids all the time and she never switches to portrait mode or anything like
Speaker 5:  that that she just snaps with the default camera and now if she had an
Speaker 5:  iPhone 15 or a 15 Pro, she can just do that and then
Speaker 5:  after the fact I can go in the photo set and be like, oh portrait mode cool
Speaker 5:  and I can play with it and whatever and make it pop more. And I think that
Speaker 5:  there's probably a lot of people who a, never realize that they could
Speaker 5:  switch to portrait mode because it was a entirely different setting or B
Speaker 5:  didn't remember how or didn't remember to do it in the moment when they're
Speaker 5:  trying to capture the image which is happening quickly in front of them
Speaker 2:  Because like Allison, they couldn't figure out how to get the button to work.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, just stuck on that home screen, on the lock screen. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Okay. And then Allison for you the, the pro versus the pro Max
Speaker 2:  again screen and battery differences, am I right in thinking that the
Speaker 2:  five x telephoto zoom is only on the pro Max?
Speaker 6:  That's right.
Speaker 2:  Okay, so that's a big difference too. Like what, how would you rank between
Speaker 2:  the two? Like how, how should people choose which one to buy?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it kind of throws all my usual like buying a
Speaker 6:  new phone thinking out the window because I, I think there, you know there
Speaker 6:  is kind of a different customer for the pro and the pro Max and
Speaker 6:  whether whether or not your current phone is working well is like
Speaker 6:  less part of the equation. But I think
Speaker 6:  yeah the five times Zoom is nice. I, I get why it's only
Speaker 6:  on the bigger phone. Google only puts it on its bigger phone,
Speaker 6:  it's something I would consider going up to the bigger phone for,
Speaker 6:  especially since it's a little bit lighter weight this year and it doesn't
Speaker 6:  feel like such a burden carrying it around. But
Speaker 6:  there's a lot to consider and I think some people are just gonna jump on,
Speaker 6:  you know, the new pro iPhone and I think like as silly as
Speaker 6:  the word pro is and kind of meaningless now,
Speaker 6:  I think there is a a certain kind of person who like if, if your phone
Speaker 6:  is kind of a big part of like how you work
Speaker 6:  when you travel and you've got chargers for other things or if you,
Speaker 6:  if you're a video creator and you can see
Speaker 6:  yourself really, you know, using it more in your workflow, I think
Speaker 6:  it does make sense for a, I don't think pros are the
Speaker 6:  word I would use but it makes sense for a certain kind of person.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, it's like the iPhone 15 videographer. Yeah it's like
Speaker 2:  if you, if you shoot a lot of big files you're the, this might work
Speaker 2:  extras pretty good. I like that. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  We kind of like have these discussions every year like who is a person to
Speaker 5:  buy a pro over a standard iPhone and like ultimately
Speaker 5:  at the end of the day Apple sells a ton of pro phones. I think the reports
Speaker 5:  from the 14 generation was like the iPhone 14 was like
Speaker 5:  single digit percentage more than the iPhone 14 pro in terms of like numbers
Speaker 5:  of people that bought it. So like people will buy the more expensive phone
Speaker 5:  I think 'cause it's more expensive but also because it's nicer. I think a
Speaker 5:  lot of people see the three lenses on the back where they're just three X
Speaker 5:  or five x and they see that like hey this does more and and their
Speaker 5:  carrier's willing to subsidize half the price anyways. So you know,
Speaker 5:  I think we'll see a lot of people buying the pro models this year and then
Speaker 5:  the 15 and the 15 plus will be, you know, a much
Speaker 5:  slower ramp up in terms of like interest in buying and people will buy them
Speaker 5:  as their old phones break, but like the early adopter, the person who's upgrading
Speaker 5:  every single year, they're, they're gonna gravitate to the pro always. It's
Speaker 5:  the exciting one. That's what I wrote in my review is like the regular 15
Speaker 5:  is never going to be exciting. It's never going to be like the platform for
Speaker 5:  new ideas or technologies. The pro is always going to be that. So if you
Speaker 5:  want that, if you wanna experience that, you're always gonna go with the
Speaker 5:  pro.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I, I totally agree. I think that's right. Alright, I'm gonna let you
Speaker 2:  guys go here in a minute but before I do, will you guys hang out and do a
Speaker 2:  hotline question with me really fast? Yeah, just I think you're the right
Speaker 2:  two people to help me answer this question. As a reminder, the hotline number
Speaker 2:  is 8 6 6 Verge one one call. Ask us all your tech questions and
Speaker 2:  you can email Vergecast at The Verge dot com if you don't wanna call. But
Speaker 2:  frankly it's super fun when you call, it's nice to hear your voices. Okay,
Speaker 2:  let's hear Dan, I have been pestering you about this all day so I expect
Speaker 2:  good things from you but here we go. Let me just play the question we have
Speaker 2:  for you right now.
Speaker 7:  Hey there guys, my name is Jordan. I had a question about the new
Speaker 7:  iPhone fifteens specifically how you could
Speaker 7:  charge other iPhones by plugging in A U S B C cable.
Speaker 7:  I know that if you do a U SS B C to lightning it will always charge
Speaker 7:  the lightning phone and if you the iPhone it will kind of
Speaker 7:  do like a handshake action and charge the lesser charge
Speaker 7:  of the two. My question is, you know, it'll, it'll do like a
Speaker 7:  51% versus 50% and then the 51% will start charging
Speaker 7:  that one or whatever. But what if you take like an iPhone plus
Speaker 7:  and you plug in say U S B C cable to another like standard
Speaker 7:  iPhone 15 and they're both at like, you know, let's say the the iPhone plus
Speaker 7:  is at like 45% whereas the other one is at like
Speaker 7:  50%, right? So like the plus technically has less battery
Speaker 7:  percentage but it has a bigger battery. What
Speaker 7:  happens? Who wins that exchange? Does the plus charge because it
Speaker 7:  technically has more battery with which to charge or
Speaker 7:  does the phone with the higher percentage win every time?
Speaker 7:  Thanks and love the show.
Speaker 2:  Okay, so this is maybe the most Verge casty hotline question we have ever
Speaker 2:  received. I was gonna say I love it so much. I have
Speaker 5:  An answer
Speaker 2:  Dan, I have been making you plug things into other things all day. I've been
Speaker 2:  also
Speaker 5:  Running down batteries to try and get the levels right or whatever.
Speaker 2:  So tell me what you know so far. So
Speaker 5:  What I know so far is he's correct that if you plug in
Speaker 5:  a lightning iPhone to A U SS B C iPhone, the U S B C
Speaker 5:  one will always send power to the lightning iPhone. The lightning does not
Speaker 5:  work the other direction.
Speaker 2:  And also AirPods and watches, which is like the thing it's ostensibly meant
Speaker 2:  for is to charge your small devices. Yeah
Speaker 5:  Air POS and watches it will charge those devices. They will not reverse charge
Speaker 5:  the phone. But right now I've got the iPhone 15 plus which is at
Speaker 5:  75% battery and I've got the iPhone 15, which is
Speaker 5:  a 96% battery and I plug them in together with my u S BBC cable
Speaker 5:  and the iPhone 15 is charging the 15 plus.
Speaker 5:  Whoa. So the theory is which everyone has the lowest
Speaker 5:  amount of battery percentage on its meter, even if the real life capacity
Speaker 5:  is still more than the 15 seems to be the way that the power
Speaker 5:  goes. U S B C is kind of weird. You can kind of like sometimes
Speaker 5:  unplug them and replug them and it will do its handshake again
Speaker 5:  and like switch rolls with other U S B C devices. But with the iPhones at
Speaker 5:  least it seems to be consistently happening that the one with the larger
Speaker 5:  battery percentage charges the one with a lower battery percentage. So
Speaker 5:  if you want it to be a real mensch with your iPhone 15 and you've got
Speaker 5:  a buddy who's got an iPhone 15 plus or pro Max or whatever and
Speaker 5:  and, and you wanna give them your battery and and and give them some juice
Speaker 5:  and they will just suck all the life out of your phone No
Speaker 5:  to power up their big battery cells. You can do that. But it does do this
Speaker 5:  at a pretty slow wattage. It's 4.5 watch, which is slower than
Speaker 5:  slow wireless charging. So you're not gonna be charging all that quickly.
Speaker 5:  But I guess if you, you know, really are in a pinch, you can do it.
Speaker 5:  I tried some other devices, the MacBook will always charge the
Speaker 5:  phone. The MacBook could have like no power and it will still try to charge
Speaker 5:  the phone. I plugged the iPhone 15 plus into a
Speaker 5:  lightning iPad and what happened was the lightning
Speaker 5:  iPad would start charging for a second and then it would say not charging.
Speaker 5:  'cause I think it's just not enough wattage. I plugged the 15 plus
Speaker 5:  into a Windows tablet thing and it would give
Speaker 5:  enough juice to wake the Windows tablet up and then it would try to
Speaker 5:  charge the iPhone. So for the most part you're not really charging
Speaker 5:  larger devices with this, aside from the fact that you can charge the bigger
Speaker 5:  iPhone with the smaller iPhone, which is kind of hilarious. If
Speaker 6:  Your friend with a 15 plus asks you to charge up
Speaker 6:  their phone, that's not a good friend.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Walk away. I mean where the big wrong in their, in their manage life
Speaker 5:  management where they need, they didn't charge their phone. That gets massive
Speaker 5:  battery life. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  Real friends charge their own phone, is that what you're saying?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, that's their problem.
Speaker 2:  I don't know. Good friends charge their own phone but best friends charge
Speaker 2:  everybody's phone. That's what I always say.
Speaker 6:  Maybe
Speaker 5:  The other weird thing you can do while we're on the topic is let me just
Speaker 5:  see if this actually works. I've got a a, a MagSafe charger here. I'm gonna
Speaker 5:  put the phone on the MagSafe charger and watch it start
Speaker 5:  charging and then I'm gonna plug it into another phone through U S B C cable
Speaker 5:  and everybody charges so you can
Speaker 5:  daisy chain.
Speaker 6:  Oh.
Speaker 2:  Oh that's it. That's kind of rad. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  I mean I assume this is gonna stop charging when it like overheats but yeah,
Speaker 5:  all
Speaker 2:  Of these things are like use cases that don't exist, but I think
Speaker 2:  it's delightful. Nonetheless, this is the,
Speaker 5:  The potential of U S B C, the power of U S B C that we've been missing with
Speaker 5:  the iPhone for however many years that's
Speaker 6:  It's here.
Speaker 2:  I love it. All right, well listen, I hope that helps. U S P C is very confusing
Speaker 2:  and if we figure out the actual logic behind all of this, we'll be sure to
Speaker 2:  let you know. But for now, go charge your friend's iPhones, be a good friend.
Speaker 2:  Alright, thank you both. We gotta take a break and then we're gonna come
Speaker 2:  back and talk about the Apple Watch.
Speaker 3:  Support for this show comes from Intel. Where do world
Speaker 3:  changing ideas get their start at Intel? It starts with
Speaker 3:  real solutions and real solutions Start with
Speaker 3:  exceptional engineering. Empowering those with disabilities
Speaker 3:  starts with assistive AI and discovering new galaxies
Speaker 3:  starts with supercomputing. The intelligent factory
Speaker 3:  starts with edge analytics while the sustainable supply chain
Speaker 3:  starts with open manufacturing. And that's just the start.
Speaker 3:  The quantum computing revolution. The next generation of AI experts,
Speaker 3:  the renewable energy grid, liquid cooling data centers,
Speaker 3:  early diagnosis for cancer, water restoration,
Speaker 3:  farmland protection. They all start with Intel.
Speaker 3:  The examples are countless, the impacts are endless but the
Speaker 3:  foundation is always the same. It starts with
Speaker 3:  Intel. Learn more at Intel dot com slash
Speaker 3:  stories.
Speaker 8:  Support for this show comes from Wix. So you've probably heard about Wix,
Speaker 8:  right? The website builder with templates designs, SS e o tools, you name
Speaker 8:  it. But have you heard of Wix Studio? It's their new end-to-end
Speaker 8:  platform designed exclusively for agencies and professionals. With
Speaker 8:  Wix Studio, you have total creative freedom to deliver your most ambitious
Speaker 8:  web visions while still smashing your deadline. You can create
Speaker 8:  intuitively on canvas with smart features like no-code animations or you
Speaker 8:  can take more control with custom c s s and backend coding.
Speaker 8:  Plus their most complex layouts can adapt for every screen size.
Speaker 8:  From a centralized workspace to on canvas collaborating to
Speaker 8:  reusing assets across sites. The workflows just make sense.
Speaker 8:  Wix Studios can help make your ideas come to life. And with advanced
Speaker 8:  native business solutions from e-comm to events bookings and
Speaker 8:  more you can cater to every industry. This is just a glimpse
Speaker 8:  of what's possible. Wix Studio, find out more at
Speaker 8:  wix.com/studio.
Speaker 1:  Welcome
Speaker 2:  Back. The iPhones aren't the only new Apple devices coming out
Speaker 2:  this week. There's also the new Apple Watch series nine and the Apple Watch
Speaker 2:  Ultra two. The Verges Victoria song are resident wearer of many
Speaker 2:  fitness watches. Simultaneously reviewed them both and she's been using
Speaker 2:  the new watchOS 10 software for a while as well. V and I haven't talked about
Speaker 2:  this yet, but I have a feeling the software is actually the real
Speaker 2:  story of the Apple Watch this year. But let's see if I'm right or not. V's.
Speaker 2:  With me here now. Hi Vee. Hello, Dan Seaford still here. Hi Dan. How
Speaker 2:  you doing? Just can't get rid of you this week. No,
Speaker 5:  I'm a cockroach.
Speaker 2:  Okay, so my overarching thesis via about
Speaker 2:  these new watches, and I am curious to hear if I'm right, is that the
Speaker 2:  software this year is significantly more interesting than the hardware this
Speaker 2:  year.
Speaker 9:  100000%. Okay. Like the, well, okay
Speaker 9:  100 maybe like 999,000. Okay. Like that
Speaker 9:  1% is so like if we're talking about hardware,
Speaker 9:  the one little tiny stumble in your
Speaker 9:  theory is the S nine sip that enables all the
Speaker 9:  interesting software updates. So it's still software.
Speaker 2:  Explain what that, what that actually means in practice.
Speaker 9:  So the SS nine sip is the first, let's say major
Speaker 9:  in scare quotes, major processor update that the Apple Watch has
Speaker 9:  had in a very long time because so far it, the last few years
Speaker 9:  it's been a rebadged version of the processor from the year before.
Speaker 9:  No real meaningful changes in terms of like features
Speaker 9:  that it enables, but this year it's actually got a 30% faster
Speaker 9:  C P U and a four chord neural engine that
Speaker 9:  you know, that enables the double tap feature. It enables
Speaker 9:  a smarter series smarter in the sense that it works offline
Speaker 9:  now and it's supposedly 25% more
Speaker 9:  accurate at dictation and the screens are brighter,
Speaker 9:  yay. 'cause better power efficiency. But they're not gonna give you better
Speaker 9:  battery life for that power efficiency. They're gonna reinvest it into
Speaker 9:  brighter screens.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, this is the thing I wish Apple would stop doing. Like I, I
Speaker 2:  actually think on most of Apple's devices it's the right call, especially
Speaker 2:  with the MacBooks. I think we've reached a point where like the battery life
Speaker 2:  is terrific sacrificing a bunch of stuff to get me like a few more hours.
Speaker 2:  I'm not sure is all that meaningful. I think especially with the entry level
Speaker 2:  watch in this case the series nine I would take small
Speaker 2:  trade-offs to get like six more hours of battery life out of the thing.
Speaker 2:  It's the only DI device of mine that reliably, consistently dies at this
Speaker 2:  point.
Speaker 9:  Oh god David, you just opened the can of worms, which is to say
Speaker 9:  that there are two camps with regards to the Apple watch. Okay.
Speaker 9:  And their battery life. There's the camp that's like, don't even
Speaker 9:  look at me in the face until this Apple watch can last a week.
Speaker 9:  How dare you come back to me after yet another year with
Speaker 9:  18 hours of battery life. I spit, I spit on your gr
Speaker 9:  petie. There's that crowd and then there's the other crowd, which
Speaker 9:  I think Dan belongs to this crowd, which is like I have my little charging
Speaker 9:  routine. My Apple watch is never out of battery.
Speaker 9:  You charge your phone every night. It's not that hard to just
Speaker 9:  plop your Apple watch on a charger at like a time when you're not using it
Speaker 9:  like the shower or 10 minutes before bed. Why are you complaining so
Speaker 9:  hard?
Speaker 5:  I will just state in my own defense, I would love to not have to have
Speaker 5:  the routine. I just happen to have the routine outta necessity.
Speaker 2:  Can I tell you my problem with this routine? The the correct time
Speaker 2:  you just said it V to charge your watch is while you're in the shower? Yeah
Speaker 2:  and there's something about having a charger in the bathroom that I just
Speaker 2:  can't, I can't do it. Maybe it's the specifics of my bathroom. I don't, we
Speaker 2:  don't have to talk a lot about what my bathroom looks like, but the idea
Speaker 2:  of just like having a cable dangling in my bathroom waiting for
Speaker 2:  my Apple watch is just like a bridge too far for me. I can't do it. You,
Speaker 9:  You could just put it in your bedroom and just go back to your bedroom after
Speaker 9:  your shower. But I mean
Speaker 5:  See David, David is in a mansion, his bedroom in his bathroom
Speaker 5:  or like four football fields apart, they're in separate wing. He's gonna
Speaker 5:  miss all those steps.
Speaker 2:  Who has the time? I know. No, my real problem is I forget to take it off
Speaker 2:  until I'm already in the shower and then I just kind of like huck it over
Speaker 2:  to the sink and that's my charging strategy. But the actual features here,
Speaker 2:  you basically named the three things I wanna talk about and it seems like
Speaker 2:  from a pure hardware perspective they're so similar that you couldn't
Speaker 2:  tell which watch was which, right? Like you had the Ultra and the
Speaker 2:  Ultra two and they're the same damn thing as far as like what the actual
Speaker 2:  thing looks and feels like, right?
Speaker 9:  Yeah. And I like, I've told this story before, but when I was at
Speaker 9:  Apple Park and I had my Ultra out and I was you know, taking
Speaker 9:  comparison photos like this representative very well-meaning comes
Speaker 9:  up to me, she's like, can you put your Ultra away? We
Speaker 9:  wouldn't want you to lose it. And that's because it looks
Speaker 9:  exactly the same. I've actually had to have a code this week when I'm
Speaker 9:  switching straps. I'm where I say out loud
Speaker 9:  the Ultra is the one with the gray strap, the Ultra two is
Speaker 9:  the one with the pink strap. Like I've, I've basically been keeping
Speaker 9:  the new ones in pink because pink is what's new. Love it. And
Speaker 9:  I had to do that because even the back crystal doesn't say Ultra two, it
Speaker 9:  says Ultra. So there's really no
Speaker 9:  way to tell unless I like I have terrible eyesight if you
Speaker 9:  read my reviews, you know, I complain about readability all the time, but
Speaker 9:  I basically have to take the original Ultra straight up to my face and
Speaker 9:  go, which one has that minuscule nick that I got one time that
Speaker 9:  only I know where it is. And that's how I tell the Ultra and
Speaker 9:  the Ultra two apart as far as my review units go.
Speaker 2:  Okay, good. So, we can just leave the hardware aside because it is what it
Speaker 2:  is. The double tap seems like the thing, right? Like it's the thing Apple
Speaker 2:  talked the most about. This feature has like been around for a while
Speaker 2:  in some accessibility ways. Like just walk me through kind of how this thing
Speaker 2:  like fits into your life as a watch wearer.
Speaker 9:  So I actually think this is potentially one of the most
Speaker 9:  significant updates just that Apple's ever put out. But
Speaker 9:  it's just not flashy, right? First of all, it's in some capacity. It's been
Speaker 9:  around since watchOS eight and assistive touch right now that
Speaker 9:  tech is just being repurposed in a more general use capacity.
Speaker 9:  It's supposedly, it's built into the system. So it's more
Speaker 9:  contextual. You don't have to do anything. Whereas with assistive touch,
Speaker 9:  you have to go into the accessibility settings, you have to enable it and
Speaker 9:  you have to program it because for some people with limb differences, this
Speaker 9:  is the only possible way for them to control the watch. It's how they're
Speaker 9:  gonna navigate menus, it's how they're gonna operate the digital crown. If
Speaker 9:  they have an alter, it's how they're gonna press the action button.
Speaker 9:  So it's, it's much more comprehensive and there's more gestures involved.
Speaker 9:  There's a clench gesture, there's a single tap gesture. It there's,
Speaker 9:  there's a, there's four actual gestures that you do with assistive touch.
Speaker 9:  But double tap is just the double tap or more accurately the pinchy
Speaker 9:  pinch. The pinchy pinch or the pinching motion.
Speaker 9:  And you basically use it to control the primary
Speaker 9:  function of an app. And what that means is, say you get a phone call,
Speaker 9:  you pinchy pinch, it's gonna answer the phone call when you're like, I'm
Speaker 9:  done with you. I'm gonna hang up in a rage. Then you pinchy pinch again and
Speaker 9:  then it hangs up.
Speaker 2:  Can you rage pinchy, pinch? I'm not sure you could rage pinchy, pinch you
Speaker 2:  rage. That doesn't skip rage. You can rage pinchy, pinch.
Speaker 9:  You just do it really aggressively. Like you're an angry lobster. You just
Speaker 9:  go, ah,
Speaker 2:  I like it. And that's,
Speaker 9:  That's,
Speaker 5:  I can't wait to see the Wall Street rows in, out on the street
Speaker 5:  just screaming at their assistant and then really violently pinching
Speaker 5:  to hang up at them.
Speaker 2:  I feel like you need to wear like castanets so that it like makes a loud
Speaker 2:  noise when you pinchy pinch. That's how you really get your feelings across.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, so that, that thing you just described actually is one of the questions
Speaker 2:  I have about Watch West 10. 'cause that that idea that it's like the primary
Speaker 2:  thing makes obvious sense to me in some ways, right? Like it's a, it,
Speaker 2:  it should pause my music if my music is playing. But there are other ways
Speaker 2:  where, what is the primary thing I'm supposed to do with the tap here
Speaker 2:  is substantially less obvious. And you're, you're nodding like that has been
Speaker 2:  true in practice. Has that been true in practice?
Speaker 9:  Yes. Okay. Yes, it absolutely has. And you know, apple acknowledges this
Speaker 9:  to an extent because there are two circumstances where you can
Speaker 9:  customize what the pinch does. So that first is, as you mentioned,
Speaker 9:  music playback. So you can do it and it can pause
Speaker 9:  or it can play your, your music. But I actually, that's not
Speaker 9:  intuitively what I would want it to do. What I would want it to do is
Speaker 9:  skip a track and you can, you know, edit it so that it skips a
Speaker 9:  track. So I was just in the car the other day driving and I was like, Nope,
Speaker 9:  not this. Nope, not this. Nope, not this. I'm just pinching while I'm driving.
Speaker 9:  And that's kind of actually safer than me
Speaker 9:  reaching over to the car in infotainment and just trying to
Speaker 9:  flip through that way. So that's, that's one way you can customize
Speaker 9:  it. The other way you can customize it and it has to do with Apple intuiting.
Speaker 9:  What you want is the smart stack. So the smart stack is new with
Speaker 9:  watch OSS 10 'cause it's widgets just everywhere in watch OSS 10
Speaker 9:  and the smart stack, you can either double pinch to scroll
Speaker 9:  through your smart stack or you can double pinch to
Speaker 9:  select the first stack and only the first stack.
Speaker 9:  And you know, apple's like if they do their job right and if they
Speaker 9:  anticipate which widget you need at the right time of day so that whenever
Speaker 9:  you bring up your widgets, you just wanna pick the first one there,
Speaker 9:  you can pinch and select it. Which to me I'm like wow, that's,
Speaker 9:  that's almost never gonna
Speaker 5:  But don't, in order to bring up the widgets, you have to scroll the digital
Speaker 5:  crown or swipe up on the screen. So you're already, you
Speaker 9:  Can, you can pinch so you just wake it up, pinch brings up
Speaker 9:  the widgets and then the second pinch will either scroll through, ah,
Speaker 9:  or select that first top one. So for me, testing
Speaker 9:  that's been a nightmare because the first one that pops up has been the tips
Speaker 9:  thing that I just can't get to go away, which goes away after
Speaker 9:  a while. But it's like I don't need these tips so I can't actually use
Speaker 9:  that particular function. But those are the only two ways you can customize
Speaker 9:  it. And for me with messages, like say I get a text,
Speaker 9:  you pinchy pinch and it'll bring up the voice message reply.
Speaker 9:  Makes sense. That makes total sense. If you're just trying to keep things
Speaker 9:  hands free or single handed. For me though, I wanna
Speaker 9:  scroll through my quick replies and select one. I would love
Speaker 9:  to do that but that's kind of hard because pinching to scroll through your
Speaker 9:  quick replies and then pausing and then pinching again to select it
Speaker 9:  kind of is something that has to be a lot more intuitive. You can do that
Speaker 9:  in assistive touch but you can't really do that with the double
Speaker 9:  tap. But that is what I wish I could do with it.
Speaker 2:  Dan, you and I are both sickos for customization. I would
Speaker 2:  say as a, as a general rule, this strikes me as the kind of thing I would
Speaker 2:  want tons of control over. Like I should be able to decide in every single
Speaker 2:  app what the double tap does. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Well I think we should, we should clarify that it does nothing in third party
Speaker 5:  apps.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Wait, is that, oh okay. So developers can do it, they just haven't
Speaker 2:  yet. Okay.
Speaker 5:  No, they, they actually can't. What v correct me if I get
Speaker 5:  this wrong. Developers can interact with double tap through
Speaker 5:  notification. So basically if you get a notification in and you double tap
Speaker 5:  it will do what is like the default action on that notification. And developers
Speaker 5:  can define that default action. So if you've got a notification that's like
Speaker 5:  an email and the default action is a delete, you can double tap to delete
Speaker 5:  it or you can double tap to reply to a message if it's in WhatsApp or something
Speaker 5:  outside of Apple's messages. But if you are in a third party app, double
Speaker 5:  tap doesn't do anything. Is that correct? V
Speaker 9:  Oh so far I think, I think you're right. I haven't been able to use it with
Speaker 9:  any third party, third party app right now. But this is also just like the
Speaker 9:  first implementation of it. I imagine there's gonna be a lot of
Speaker 9:  trial and error as people use this for the first time. And I could see,
Speaker 9:  I could see ways, ways down that third party apps
Speaker 9:  will eventually get some ability to do it. But the problem
Speaker 9:  really is that this is supposed to be contextual and intuitive.
Speaker 9:  So you're having people, you're basically trying to mind read what
Speaker 9:  people are gonna try and pinch for. And it's funny
Speaker 9:  because you know, I have a beta version with this enabled,
Speaker 9:  there's no explanation on my version. I imagine there will be some
Speaker 9:  short walkthrough in like the Tips app when Apple releases this
Speaker 9:  to the public. But there's no real explanation of what apps
Speaker 9:  this works with and what it'll do within those apps. You just kind of have
Speaker 9:  to go into the app and start like pinching like a weirdo and
Speaker 9:  seeing what it does. And there's a little glyph or an icon that
Speaker 9:  appears that shows you that you've just done it. And when you can't
Speaker 9:  have any double tap gesture, it'll just like do a little
Speaker 9:  shake that's like, nuh, can't do it. So I've just been like this
Speaker 9:  past few days just sitting there just going like, oh does this, does this
Speaker 9:  work? Pinch, pinch, oh no, okay, can't do that. Does this work? Pinch,
Speaker 9:  pinch? Oh no, can't do that. So it can be
Speaker 9:  really intuitive and also weirdly frustrating 'cause
Speaker 9:  you don't know when you're gonna run up against the wall of the, the pinch
Speaker 9:  not working like timers is the other example I'm gonna use. If
Speaker 9:  you have talked to Siri and you have a, and you have a timer going and
Speaker 9:  that timer app is front and center, when you do the
Speaker 9:  the double tap, it'll pause the timer and then you can, you know, restart
Speaker 9:  the timer and when it ends you can close the timer. I want what if I want
Speaker 9:  a timer to restart? I, I have several like Pomodoro
Speaker 9:  method nonsense where I just want to restart a timer as soon as it's done.
Speaker 9:  Can't do that. I actually have to go and figure out whether I'm gonna ask
Speaker 9:  Siri to set another timer or whether I'm gonna go in manually and set that
Speaker 9:  timer. So that's annoying. And then also if the, the, the
Speaker 9:  timer app goes away, it's not front and center then no amount
Speaker 9:  of pinching you're gonna do is really gonna change anything until it goes
Speaker 9:  off. So if you wanna pause the, the timer, while the timer app is not front
Speaker 9:  and center, you can't do anything. So it's sort of like, that's
Speaker 9:  weirdly annoying for me. I don't know if it'll be weirdly annoying for everyone.
Speaker 9:  It
Speaker 2:  Just strikes me as a classic Apple kind of being too clever by half
Speaker 2:  thing and like the thing it got really right with the action button was
Speaker 2:  it was just like, just do just do whatever you want. Like here's some options.
Speaker 2:  We have some ideas. Just do just action
Speaker 5:  Action button on the phone. Yes. Let's, let's clarify.
Speaker 2:  No, you're, that's absolutely right. But the action button and the iPhone
Speaker 2:  15, which we were just talking about that you have some control over and
Speaker 2:  there's a cool interface for it and they're like, this will work. This is
Speaker 2:  the equivalent of if they had taken the action button on the phone and been
Speaker 2:  like in every app it will do the thing we think it should do. It's like Apple.
Speaker 2:  Like sometimes that thing is obvious. If I open the camera app on my
Speaker 2:  iPhone, it should be the shutter button and it is and that kicks ass sometimes
Speaker 2:  I want it to do something and I should be able to make it do that thing.
Speaker 2:  And I feel like so many times with the watch Apple is like, this is a small
Speaker 2:  screen, people don't wanna spend too much time on it. We have to do all the
Speaker 2:  work magically for them. And sometimes it works and way too
Speaker 2:  often I feel like it doesn't, and speaking of things that way too often
Speaker 2:  don't work. Siri is the other thing I was curious about because Apple made
Speaker 2:  a bunch of noise about Siri being offline and working on device,
Speaker 2:  which if it is successful, it's a huge deal for the watch, right? Like it,
Speaker 2:  it opens, opens up all kinds of things you can do if you don't have a cellular
Speaker 2:  device, if you're out in the world doing stuff like potentially a big deal.
Speaker 2:  What have you seen so far?
Speaker 9:  Yeah, it works. It just works like, okay wait, hold
Speaker 2:  On, hold on. Do you want to be on the record saying Siri works? I just like,
Speaker 2:  I just wanna be so clear about what you just, I'm
Speaker 9:  Getting into caveats. Just, just gimme a second to get into the
Speaker 9:  of this here. Okay. So you know, it does now work
Speaker 9:  if you don't have your phone and you're not in any kind of internet
Speaker 9:  connection. So like your laundry room is in your basement, you
Speaker 9:  left your phone upstairs, your hands are tied up and you wanna
Speaker 9:  set the stupid laundry timer so that you know when to go get your laundry.
Speaker 9:  Now you can say like, hey set this timer and it'll do it.
Speaker 9:  Which feels like a thing that it should have been able to do already.
Speaker 2:  This happened to me by the way, literally this morning I was doing daycare
Speaker 2:  drop off with my kid, needed to remind myself to do something
Speaker 2:  had I had left my phone at home and my watch just was useless to me. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  like this very simple basic thing that it ought to be able to do it couldn't
Speaker 2:  do. Yeah,
Speaker 9:  It can do that now. That's very, it's pretty reliably. I turned
Speaker 9:  airplane mode on my phone and the watch on and made sure
Speaker 9:  that there was no wifi connection still and it was, it was able to do
Speaker 9:  stuff. It was even able to pull weather updates because it had pulled that
Speaker 9:  already. It may not have been the most accurate weather update at that point
Speaker 9:  in time, but it was able to like give me an update which I
Speaker 9:  had not been expecting because as I understand it, if it needs to pull some
Speaker 9:  sort of data from the internet, it still needs the internet connection.
Speaker 9:  It's more so that you can do tasks like, oh, set a
Speaker 9:  timer or I guess in my case, set a workout like I
Speaker 9:  don't know if you're in the trails of, of like Missouri somewhere where
Speaker 9:  there's no any kind of internet connection and your phone doesn't even have
Speaker 9:  an internet connection. Well now you can hands-free set a workout,
Speaker 9:  which there is a use case for that, but I think for most people that's not
Speaker 9:  a thing that they've necessarily thought to do, but it can do it now.
Speaker 9:  So yay za
Speaker 5:  I've had the opportunity to test the new Siri as well. I, I haven't, my demo
Speaker 5:  unit doesn't have the double tap, but I do have the new Siri and I think
Speaker 5:  the thing that is actually impactful is for me at least when I'm outside
Speaker 5:  on the grill, I set timers for how long to keep leave the burgers on before
Speaker 5:  I need to flip 'em or whatever. And because I'm like on the edge of my wifi
Speaker 5:  network, it like I will watch the, I will do the, the command
Speaker 5:  and watch the watch figure itself out. And so, but with the series
Speaker 5:  nine I was able to just say, set a timer for five minutes and it just did
Speaker 5:  it. And so like I think those are like more practical use cases for where
Speaker 5:  this better improved on-device Siri is going to make an impact.
Speaker 5:  I will add that this new Siri doesn't do anything that the old
Speaker 5:  Siri couldn't do. So it's not like Siri gets smarter or more capable,
Speaker 5:  it's just, it works better at the things that it could already do because
Speaker 5:  it doesn't have to send your voice command out to the internet,
Speaker 5:  transcribe it and bring it back down to the watch.
Speaker 2:  My biggest issue with Siri on the watch has always been that it, it seems
Speaker 2:  to just fail completely a lot more often than Siri
Speaker 2:  elsewhere with really basic things like trying to set a reminder
Speaker 2:  or add something to my calendar or set a timer even it much
Speaker 2:  more often does the thing where it thinks and then it still thinks and then
Speaker 2:  nothing happens. And my assumption has always been that's because of this
Speaker 2:  sort of like daisy chain of connections it's having to do in order to get
Speaker 2:  the information back to the watch. Have you noticed that being any better
Speaker 2:  on the watch because it's able to run locally? I would think it would just
Speaker 2:  be able to do more things more reliably.
Speaker 9:  Yeah, it has been more reliable for me except with
Speaker 9:  understanding me that is just the same level of,
Speaker 9:  you know, like it, it's better like it can finally understand
Speaker 9:  Mahershala Ali's name, which I've been using for years as a litmus test
Speaker 9:  progress,
Speaker 2:  Whether
Speaker 9:  It can understand me and you know, it's gotten better over the years like
Speaker 9:  four or five years ago it was just like Herschel Walker and it's like, no
Speaker 9:  that's, that's not what I said.
Speaker 2:  It's a different guy. Yeah,
Speaker 9:  Completely different name. But you know, I, I live in a
Speaker 9:  community where it's mixed language. I have to communicate with people
Speaker 9:  with names that are not English. And with that respect
Speaker 9:  it is still not great. Like I was, I was
Speaker 9:  messaging my friend and I was like, oh New K-pop album come out, do
Speaker 9:  we love him? And it's like Joe Fang Fu or something like that
Speaker 9:  and it was like, no that's not his name. Oh boy, that's
Speaker 9:  not how it works. Okay. We, we still have to do the thing where when I am
Speaker 9:  messaging my friends and with like Korean lone words
Speaker 9:  where I have to go like bull gogi for it to understand
Speaker 9:  me and it for it to be clear and not to be ridiculous And we had a lot of
Speaker 9:  fun testing the dictation, our video producer had me
Speaker 9:  rap alphabet aerobics and that was certainly
Speaker 9:  a time I did a bunch of tongue twisters about Betty and her
Speaker 9:  bitter butter and her better butter and buying them. And for
Speaker 9:  the most part I wanna say both my S eight powered
Speaker 9:  Ultra and the S nine powered series nine kind
Speaker 9:  of overall did about the same in terms of accuracy. Okay.
Speaker 9:  So I don't know if that's just me and the way I pronounce and
Speaker 9:  as Owen says, wow you talk fast. So I'm not sure
Speaker 9:  if I am like having issues because I'm in an edge case of people
Speaker 9:  who talk at the speed of New York, but it's, it's, it's
Speaker 9:  better just not so much better that if you upgraded now
Speaker 9:  you'd be like, oh my god they finally fixed Siri. That kind of thing.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, that tracks so full takeaway here. Like it seems to
Speaker 2:  me that if you bought a watch in the last couple of years, you're gonna get
Speaker 2:  watchOS 10. Is double tap coming to these other devices or is that only in
Speaker 2:  the new stuff? Okay, that
Speaker 9:  Is only on the new watches along with the precision finding,
Speaker 9:  right? Those are only on the new watches and as far as I understand it,
Speaker 9:  it's because, you know, some people have been like why Assistive Touch works
Speaker 9:  on the older watches, why won't double touch work on those watches? And it's
Speaker 9:  because Assistive Touch is powered on the C P U directly. It's very
Speaker 9:  power intensive. Double tap is powered by the neural engine
Speaker 9:  so it can be offloaded a bit and is a lot more power efficient and can run
Speaker 9:  in the background. That's, that's the line they're giving all of us. So
Speaker 9:  I I like my interpretation is if they were to put double tap on the older
Speaker 9:  watches, your battery life would be even more in the toilet than it currently
Speaker 9:  is. So basically in my review I say if you have a series
Speaker 9:  seven, eight or an original Ultra cool jets
Speaker 9:  contribute to apple's carbon neutral plans and don't buy yourself a new box
Speaker 9:  there.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, it seems like even if double tap is like really meaningful to you,
Speaker 2:  waiting a year for like developers to figure it out and the feature will
Speaker 2:  get better. Seems like the move Dan, you're nodding like you,
Speaker 2:  you agree with me.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I think in a year double tap will be more useful. Maybe
Speaker 5:  Apple will have opened it up to third party developers in a more meaningful
Speaker 5:  way. Maybe we'll have other gestures arriving that like
Speaker 5:  use the same kind of concept and logic that allows you to do this thing
Speaker 5:  for now. If you have the new watches, if you get the new watches, it's neat.
Speaker 5:  But I think V would agree that it's not a like absolute must have feature.
Speaker 9:  No, and you can, you can experiment if you have a, a seven or eight
Speaker 9:  with assistive touch to see whether just your control is something you
Speaker 9:  even like. 'cause if you're like, oh this whatever, I'm not passionate about
Speaker 9:  this, then you really don't need, you have like empirical evidence that you
Speaker 9:  don't need to update just for double tap. I will say that going forward,
Speaker 9:  I think the combination of rearranging the watch to be very
Speaker 9:  widget centric and double tap kind of is like
Speaker 9:  a fundamental groundwork that they're laying to change the way that we
Speaker 9:  interact with the device. Yeah, so it's weird because on that one hand I'm
Speaker 9:  seeing that and I'm, and I I like, I'm like, oh I see what you're doing,
Speaker 9:  I see what you're doing. You are changing how we
Speaker 9:  fundamentally interact with these devices. But you're doing it in a
Speaker 9:  way where it's like, oh, what if I left this book of secrets out
Speaker 9:  on this table who is curious enough to come and read this book of
Speaker 9:  secrets and let's see what they do with that. And they're in the bushes somewhere
Speaker 9:  in the bag with their little binoculars going, what are they doing?
Speaker 9:  That's kind of what this is. They're, they're laying some very important
Speaker 9:  groundwork to change the Apple watch to be a single handed device.
Speaker 9:  Much in the way that, you know, Dan pointed this out to be more like the
Speaker 9:  iPhone, which is a, you know, if you get it in the right size, everyone will
Speaker 9:  agree that that it's a single handed device and you're
Speaker 9:  making it so that it's much more different. It's not just a mini
Speaker 9:  phone on your wrist because the way that these new apps have been redesigned
Speaker 9:  and that the way the widget stack works on the Apple Watch, you don't
Speaker 9:  need quite as much of your phone because there is a lot of
Speaker 9:  information that's glanceable and a lot of information that you can operate
Speaker 9:  with one hand now and that's not something that you've really been able to
Speaker 9:  do before. So I think once this gets refined going forward,
Speaker 9:  maybe, I don't wanna say for the 10, but maybe the 11 or the 12,
Speaker 9:  I don't think we'll be using these watches in the same way that we currently
Speaker 9:  do.
Speaker 2:  I like it. Alright, thank you both. We gotta take one more break and then
Speaker 2:  we're gonna switch things up a little bit and talk about how we take these
Speaker 2:  devices, which millions or tens of millions or billions of people
Speaker 2:  buy and make them feel a lot more like ours.
Speaker 2:  We'll be right back.
Speaker 8:  Support for this show comes from the podcast Business Wars from Wondery
Speaker 8:  Business Wars Delves deep into some of the biggest corporate rivalries of
Speaker 8:  all time and the award-winning podcast is coming back with a new season and
Speaker 8:  this time they're telling the real stories behind the rise of ai. Starting
Speaker 8:  in the 2010s, the dream of artificial intelligence became a real
Speaker 8:  possibility that companies like Google and Meta knew they'd have to harness
Speaker 8:  it if they were going to win the AI race. In fact, some companies saw it
Speaker 8:  as key to their very survival, but researchers within each company
Speaker 8:  sounded the alarm that if they move too fast, the consequences
Speaker 8:  could be devastating. It's the newest season of business Wars, the
Speaker 8:  rise of AI where tech behemoths fight to dominate the artificial
Speaker 8:  intelligence space and reckoned with the costs hosted by
Speaker 8:  veteran public radio journalist David Brown. You can listen to the real stories
Speaker 8:  that are shaping the business landscape today. Follow Business Wars
Speaker 8:  wherever you get your podcasts, you can listen ad free on the Amazon Music
Speaker 8:  or Wonder App
Speaker 3:  Support for this show comes from Global Citizen. On
Speaker 3:  September 23rd, the Global Citizen Festival will gather thousands of people
Speaker 3:  who took action to end extreme poverty. Watch the Red Hot Chili
Speaker 3:  Peppers, Ms. Lauren Hill, ook and Anita as they
Speaker 3:  take the stage with world leaders and activists to demand action for
Speaker 3:  equity for the planet, for food and for jobs.
Speaker 3:  Download the Global Citizen app to watch live, learn more at Global Citizen
Speaker 3:  dot org slash vox.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. One of the things I like about this time of year is that it
Speaker 2:  ends up being phone cleaning time. It's like spring cleaning in the spring
Speaker 2:  phone cleaning in the fall. Particularly if you're an
Speaker 2:  iPhone user, this is the time of year you probably get some new software
Speaker 2:  with some new features, some new widgets, a bunch of weird new
Speaker 2:  gestures and interaction ideas and it's just a fun moment
Speaker 2:  to kind of take stock of how you use your phone, which apps get a
Speaker 2:  spot on your home screen, all that good stuff. This year's iOS,
Speaker 2:  iOS 17 brings one of the biggest changes in a while, which is one
Speaker 2:  we've already been talking about in this episode. Interactive widgets instead
Speaker 2:  of widgets just being things you look at, they're now things you
Speaker 2:  can do. And widgets are actually a big feature of pretty much all
Speaker 2:  of Apple's new software. This year the Apple Watch got a redesign with watchOS
Speaker 2:  10. So it's basically now just a clock and a bunch of widgets. macOS is
Speaker 2:  getting widgets with Sonoma. The iPad got widgets on the lock screen. It's
Speaker 2:  just widgets all the way down y'all. It's great. Oh, and I should say
Speaker 2:  before we get too far into this, if you're yelling at your podcast player
Speaker 2:  right now, Android did it first. Please know that I know
Speaker 2:  and I'm with you. And Android widgets have been way better than iOS widgets
Speaker 2:  for years. That is absolutely true, but this is new for the
Speaker 2:  iPhone users so you know, let them have this one. Anyway, as all
Speaker 2:  of this has been coming out, I've been trying to figure out not just wi widgets
Speaker 2:  I want to use, but how to think about widgets and how widgets work
Speaker 2:  across all of these devices. Just on the iPhone you have home
Speaker 2:  screen widgets and lock screen widgets. There's the dynamic island, there's
Speaker 2:  live activities, there's just a lot of different ways that information
Speaker 2:  moves around the iPhone and it can be kind of confusing. So to
Speaker 2:  figure it out, I decided to call up the expert David Smith.
Speaker 10:  Apple added widgets and it was great and they worked and it didn't have
Speaker 10:  any negative impacts, it was only positive ones.
Speaker 2:  David makes an app called Widget Smith that is probably the most
Speaker 2:  powerful and most successful widget making app on the planet. It was a
Speaker 2:  massive hit when it first came out in 2020, which you might remember was
Speaker 2:  iOS 14, which was when Home Screen Widgets came to the iPhone for the first
Speaker 2:  time this year for iOS 17, he's got a big update to
Speaker 2:  Widgetsmith with a bunch of really cool interactive widgets. You
Speaker 2:  can now scroll the weather on your home screen. There's a way to flip through
Speaker 2:  your music, like the cover flow thing that used to be in the iPod. It's just
Speaker 2:  delightful. David knows how widgets work better than just about anybody and
Speaker 2:  I think he understands how Apple thinks about them too, which is really helpful.
Speaker 2:  So I called him up and asked him all of my questions starting with the most
Speaker 2:  burning one, oddly enough. Is it as surprising to you as it is to me
Speaker 2:  that people love widgets this much?
Speaker 10:  Yes, I, I mean, I think, I mean I, I don't know if I really expected widgets
Speaker 10:  to be as big as they were when I started getting into the widget business.
Speaker 10:  Like Widget Smith was not something that I expected it to ever be. This
Speaker 10:  massive app that kind of had a viral moment and like took over the world
Speaker 10:  for a few weeks and like it was that, like I did not expect that at all.
Speaker 10:  I, I, I think I was excited about widgets when they first came out, but
Speaker 10:  it was, that definitely had no expectation for just how much like pent up
Speaker 10:  demand there is for that kind of thing that people really want that kind
Speaker 10:  of interaction and that kind of experience. And so yeah, I mean it definitely
Speaker 10:  feels like, oh and it just keeps coming like this year I think other than
Speaker 10:  Apple TV widgets are everywhere on Apple's platforms now. It's
Speaker 10:  really true. So it was definitely like, okay, well I guess next year I know
Speaker 10:  what to expect at the, you know, somehow it's gonna be widgets on Apple
Speaker 10:  TV 'cause they just, you know, complete the set. But yeah, it's a little
Speaker 10:  wild.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I have to say I did not expect Widgetsmith to get as big as it did
Speaker 2:  either. I, I sort of put it in the like shortcuts bucket at first
Speaker 2:  where it's like, this is a cool thing, it's a little, you know,
Speaker 2:  fiddly and finicky and there's a lot of people who like that, but this is
Speaker 2:  not necessarily going to be sort of a mainstream thing. But the
Speaker 2:  number of people who even in the early days were
Speaker 2:  like willing to do the work to make a photo widget that looked
Speaker 2:  nice on their home screen was just like orders of magnitude bigger
Speaker 2:  than I would've expected. It was wild the customization people started doing,
Speaker 2:  it's the minute they were able to do it and the amount of work that they
Speaker 2:  would put in to do it just kind of blew my mind from the very beginning and
Speaker 2:  I've like not really forgotten that lesson since then.
Speaker 10:  I mean it certainly helped that it launched in 2020 when I think there was
Speaker 10:  a lot of people with a lot of time on their hands just sort of to, to work
Speaker 10:  on that level. But yeah, like it, it, the amount that people care about
Speaker 10:  how what their home screen looks like is dramatic. Like there's a
Speaker 10:  meaningful thing that people really care about, you know, how what exactly
Speaker 10:  what their home screen looks like. Whether what colors it is, what fonts
Speaker 10:  it is, the layout of it and they're willing to put in the effort to,
Speaker 10:  to make that happen. And so yeah, it's like I definitely, when I launched
Speaker 10:  Widgetsmith, I think very much shortcut, this is a great analogy that I
Speaker 10:  was like, oh this is a cool niche feature for like, you know, sort of power
Speaker 10:  usy kind of people who enjoy really, you know, sort of tweaking and fiddling
Speaker 10:  with things. And it turned out actually no, it's everyone and you know,
Speaker 10:  it's like middle school kids through like, you know, retirees who
Speaker 10:  are all just, they, they just want to have, you know, the this device that
Speaker 10:  they spend so much of their day looking at, they just want it to be exactly
Speaker 10:  the way they want it. And you know, wood Smith was like turned out to be
Speaker 10:  the tool that helps 'em accomplish that.
Speaker 2:  I am curious how you've like over the last three years I've even had trouble
Speaker 2:  thinking about where information kind of lives on your phone.
Speaker 2:  First it was just widgets and then it was lock screen widgets and then it
Speaker 2:  was live activities and then it was the dynamic island. And we've gotten
Speaker 2:  to this point where it's like how I define a widget gets more
Speaker 2:  complicated over time and you've kind of tentacle out into some of those
Speaker 2:  things too. Like do you have a really good sort of mental
Speaker 2:  picture of how all of that stuff works and fits together
Speaker 2:  and makes sense?
Speaker 10:  Sure. I mean I think at, at its core widgets are about
Speaker 10:  taking little bits of an app and exporting
Speaker 10:  them outside of the app itself. Okay. And I think depending on
Speaker 10:  what kind of experience you're trying to pull out of the app, those different
Speaker 10:  locations, whether it's a home screen widget, a lock screen widget, whether
Speaker 10:  it's a live activity or a live activity in the dynamic island, but what
Speaker 10:  makes sense in each of those places is going to be very different. If it's
Speaker 10:  something that is like just showing the temperature, for example is a great
Speaker 10:  lock screen widget, it's something that's small, concise, useful,
Speaker 10:  and very glanceable. It's not something that you need, you know, it's just,
Speaker 10:  you just wanna know how hot it is outside in the same way that we put the
Speaker 10:  time on our lock screen and we all got rid of our watches. And so
Speaker 10:  like that kind of data was great on the lock screen. But I think home screen
Speaker 10:  is, it gets into this, you start to get into a place where it's like, well,
Speaker 10:  do I want a bit more? Can I, you know, have a lot more space I can be like,
Speaker 10:  have a bit more there and is it allowing me to get the data that I want
Speaker 10:  out of an app without having to go into that app? Hmm. And then
Speaker 10:  live activities and the dynamic island, it tends to be much more of the
Speaker 10:  sense of is there data that is ac that is changing in a
Speaker 10:  very real time way, which doesn't really lend itself to the
Speaker 10:  other forms because of the performance limitations that Apple puts on
Speaker 10:  the other types of widget, those widgets, you know, the home screen and
Speaker 10:  lock screen widgets are static essentially. I mean there's interactivity
Speaker 10:  we have this year, but fundamentally they are showing a snapshot of data
Speaker 10:  and so it, if it's updating in real time, they are not the right place for
Speaker 10:  that. And so instead Apple made this other place where you have these temporary
Speaker 10:  experiences that are widgets that are given special permission to update
Speaker 10:  very regularly. You know, you're updating a few times, you know, it's like
Speaker 10:  every few seconds rather than every few minutes. And that I think is sort
Speaker 10:  of generally the way that I think about these sort of this hierarchy of
Speaker 10:  different widget experiences we have now that they, they sort of go
Speaker 10:  from the small to the large and then from the kind of real
Speaker 10:  time to the just sort of static and where you are on the sort of
Speaker 10:  on those, on those axes determines which one of those widget types you're
Speaker 10:  gonna be in. But there's definitely more and more places that were sort
Speaker 10:  of our widgets are being put because they're catering to different needs
Speaker 10:  or to different sort of user desires.
Speaker 2:  That's really helpful perspective actually, because I will say as a, as a
Speaker 2:  user who does not understand the sort of performance capabilities of
Speaker 2:  each one, the distinction between kind of what's allowed to refresh constantly
Speaker 2:  and what isn't never really made a lot of sense to me. And I think the, the
Speaker 2:  thing that has been the hardest for me is to figure out the difference between
Speaker 2:  like a very good home screen widget and let's say a live
Speaker 2:  activity. Sure. Because to me those should, those should just be the same
Speaker 2:  thing. And I get that they're not, and I get that there are sort of artificial
Speaker 2:  reasons that they can't be, but the idea of having something that is
Speaker 2:  like, why can't I run a, I don't know, FaceTime
Speaker 2:  call from a widget on my home screen? Like that seems like a thing that
Speaker 2:  maybe should exist in the world. I don't dunno if that's a good idea or not,
Speaker 2:  but it, it's just interesting that there are those kind of artificial limitations
Speaker 2:  put on each one to make that hierarchy. And when you understand it like that,
Speaker 2:  that hierarchy does kind of make sense even though as a user I'm kind of
Speaker 2:  like just, just like, let me, I just wanna be able to hit a thing and just
Speaker 2:  say, update this. Like, like the thing you can do with your email inbox where
Speaker 2:  you decide how often it pulls or just have it push whenever there's new stuff.
Speaker 2:  Like I kind of want that in all my widgets too, even if it crushes my battery
Speaker 2:  life. I dunno. Sure.
Speaker 10:  And I mean I think, and this is an area that I think is very, it is been
Speaker 10:  a fascinating sort of timeline with Apple because Widgets originally, the
Speaker 10:  first version of widgets was the Today view screen that they added
Speaker 10:  back in, I can't remember much older versions of, of iOS.
Speaker 10:  And that was actually something more akin to a fully
Speaker 10:  running app that was running, like when you looked at your Today
Speaker 10:  view, that app was running and it could do all kinds of real time things
Speaker 10:  and could be That's true, yeah. Much more lively and interactive and you
Speaker 10:  could have buttons and you could do all these things, but it, in order to
Speaker 10:  do that, apple had to like put it somewhere to the side so that it
Speaker 10:  wasn't running all the time, that it was only running if you swiped over
Speaker 10:  to, you know, to the left of your home screen. But that also meant that
Speaker 10:  it wasn't nearly as useful because you had to go and find it in order to
Speaker 10:  do it. And you know, the reason they did that is of course is you know,
Speaker 10:  it's performance and battery that it's whenever, if you allow an app to
Speaker 10:  run all the time, inevitably bad things are gonna happen in terms of there's
Speaker 10:  security issues, there's battery life issues, there's, is it
Speaker 10:  interacting with other, you know, other apps that are running on the, on
Speaker 10:  your phone issues. And so I think very wisely in many ways what Apple instead
Speaker 10:  did is they built the, you know, the standard widgets that you see are just
Speaker 10:  a, they're a very clever snapshot, but almost just like a picture that my
Speaker 10:  app will generate and send over to, to, to iOS
Speaker 10:  and then iOS can show that that picture and it doesn't cost them anything.
Speaker 10:  There's no performance hit, you know, I, I can display a widget on your
Speaker 10:  home screen all day and it isn't costing you any more battery life than
Speaker 10:  if you've just had a collection of apps app icons there. And I think that
Speaker 10:  sort of is the cleverness that behind what they did, they've done by doing
Speaker 10:  that. But yeah, it creates this weird tension between, it's like, well,
Speaker 10:  why isn't it an app? Well it's like if we gave you what you want and let
Speaker 10:  you run a full app inside of a widget, then your overall
Speaker 10:  experience of your phone will be worse because inevitably it's going to
Speaker 10:  be draining on your device in a way that isn't actually getting
Speaker 10:  you, you now you're not getting enough utility to justify the battery drain
Speaker 10:  and performance hit that you're getting. And so instead they're taking this
Speaker 10:  very incremental approach and saying it's like, well we're gonna do this
Speaker 10:  snapshot approach, you know, we're gonna do live activities where it's like
Speaker 10:  they're special and time bound and they're live in a special place. And
Speaker 10:  even there, the technology that they're using to do those is similarly
Speaker 10:  based on snapshots and clever things that a live activity isn't a live app
Speaker 10:  that's running all the time, it's just an app that's given permission to
Speaker 10:  refresh itself very regularly.
Speaker 2:  I see, okay.
Speaker 10:  Rather than something that is actually like if a window into
Speaker 10:  the application itself. And then similarly with interactivity, they did
Speaker 10:  the same exact thing where instead they're just saying if a user pushes
Speaker 10:  on a particular part of a widget, you get a, a guaranteed refresh
Speaker 10:  instantly so you can respond to the user's
Speaker 10:  interaction and it feels like you're interacting with an app, but actually
Speaker 10:  you're, it's just a very special way to say, gimme the next snapshot, gimme
Speaker 10:  the next snapshot. And as a result it's super performant because the last
Speaker 10:  time you hit that button, the last time it generates that snapshot, it's
Speaker 10:  done and all the work is done and it'll be go back to immediately using
Speaker 10:  Zero Battery and impacting your, you know, your device at all from that
Speaker 10:  point on goes immediately to zero. And so I think it's a very clever approach
Speaker 10:  in that regard technically, and it's just a very, it means that there's
Speaker 10:  these weird distinctions users have to sort of navigate, but overall it
Speaker 10:  means that I think widgets can be used everywhere and the story wasn't Apple
Speaker 10:  added widgets and then my battery was toast. Right. It's like Apple
Speaker 10:  added widgets and it was great and they worked and it didn't have any negative
Speaker 10:  impacts. It was only positive ones.
Speaker 2:  That makes sense. So yeah. Is you've been goofing around with interactivity,
Speaker 2:  I've been using some of the stuff you found in Widget Smith. What do you
Speaker 2:  make of it so far? Like did they, does that balance feel right?
Speaker 10:  Yeah, I mean I think the, the balance that've struck right now with interactivity
Speaker 10:  I think is very, is very strong in the sense of it's,
Speaker 10:  it's amazing what you can get done with just a, you know, getting
Speaker 10:  a guaranteed refresh based on a user action. Like it is
Speaker 10:  surprisingly powerful for what the interactions and the inter the experiences
Speaker 10:  that you can build with that. You know, the WC keynote was just like checking
Speaker 10:  an item off a to-do list, which seems a bit basic and it's like you can
Speaker 10:  totally do that. It's like, or you can, you know, scroll through
Speaker 10:  your calendar in, you know, sort of dynamically or look at a weather forecast
Speaker 10:  and say, you know, it's an hourly forecast and you wanna see the next six
Speaker 10:  hours after that, well you can tap and it'll slide over and they can
Speaker 10:  do things there where they can make these rich. It can make the experience
Speaker 10:  that much richer and creates that many fewer places and reasons why you
Speaker 10:  have to actually get into the app in the first place. And I think that's
Speaker 10:  what interactivity mostly is allowing at this point is that it reminds me
Speaker 10:  a lot of watchOS apps where like a really good
Speaker 10:  watchOS app is an app that it typically is something that you're only gonna
Speaker 10:  experience for a few seconds. That it's, you're going in to get something
Speaker 10:  and then coming out and it's not an app that you're expecting to just like
Speaker 10:  be sitting tapping on your wrist for five minutes. It's something that you're
Speaker 10:  gonna be in in seconds. And similarly I think Interactive Widgets allow
Speaker 10:  you to have those same kinds of interactions on your home screen where
Speaker 10:  rather than having to open the app to do something, maybe you can just,
Speaker 10:  you know, tap two or three times on the widget to get to the exact date
Speaker 10:  of view that you're interested in or the exact, you know, behavior you want
Speaker 10:  and then you're done. And you never actually had to launch the app to do
Speaker 10:  that. And so I think they've struck a really interesting balance. I think,
Speaker 10:  I doubt this is the final form of it, like my suspicion is that there will
Speaker 10:  be more things that will come over time as they've kind of
Speaker 10:  explore how we, you know, how users respond to interactivity, but it feels
Speaker 10:  like they've been taking this incrementally growing out the widgets story
Speaker 10:  over the last, you know, since 2020 and it, I doubt they're done at this
Speaker 10:  point. I think it's a, this seems like a very meaningful step forward to
Speaker 10:  make them not just static things, but to have the user expectation of being
Speaker 10:  able to interact with them in the first place.
Speaker 2:  Got it. Okay. So yeah, I, I guess part of me is trying to figure out how
Speaker 2:  far I want that to go because it's like a, the checkoff that to do list example's
Speaker 2:  a good one, right? That's, that's an easy obvious thing that it's always
Speaker 2:  been sort of ridiculous. You have to open an app for, but then it's like,
Speaker 2:  okay, I want to edit a task. Should it open up a text
Speaker 2:  box on top of the widget? That seems like probably not,
Speaker 2:  I don't know. It's, it's there, there's finding out where that middle ground
Speaker 2:  sort of eventually ought to be with all of this is really interesting. And
Speaker 2:  I think that like refresh the snapshot thing makes me think that
Speaker 2:  if that's the paradigm, it's always gonna be just kind of, you can do
Speaker 2:  one thing at a time and this is not meant to be like a multi-step
Speaker 2:  tool. It's a look at this thing and then look at this thing. Yes. And that
Speaker 2:  that maybe that's enough.
Speaker 10:  Yeah. And I think if we got further things, I think they would be in that
Speaker 10:  same model. And it reminds me a bit of how in notifications when you get
Speaker 10:  a notification and it's like you can respond to the, like someone sends
Speaker 10:  you a text, you can respond to that text without opening the messages app
Speaker 10:  in terms of you can respond inside the notification is a thing that they've
Speaker 10:  allowed you to do for, for a while now. And I think I could imagine
Speaker 10:  a similar thing in widgets where it's like you have the ability to,
Speaker 10:  you know, prompt the user for text. And so if you wanted to
Speaker 10:  have a to-do list app where you are able to add items directly from your
Speaker 10:  home screen, it would be through some kind of, you know, system managed
Speaker 10:  process where you would tap a button and the keyboard would pop up with
Speaker 10:  a little text view, you type in whatever it is you want, you hit return
Speaker 10:  that gets sent to the app and then it refle refreshes the
Speaker 10:  widget. So you're not launching like the, the app is not,
Speaker 10:  is only ever getting the text. It's not, I'm, I'm not responsible for the
Speaker 10:  keyboard, it's not an interactive experience in the same way, but it's a
Speaker 10:  way of kind of pushing that next step forward because I think anything they
Speaker 10:  do is going to be through this kind of very regimented
Speaker 10:  approach where your widgets are locked down in a way that is very performant
Speaker 10:  and clever. But it's like if they added text entry in iOS 18, like
Speaker 10:  that would seem like a very logical next step to do. And there's expands
Speaker 10:  the range of activities that would be potentially useful that, you know,
Speaker 10:  you could imagine a notes app or to do app or any kind of thing that you're
Speaker 10:  collect regularly collecting little bits of information that seems great
Speaker 10:  to not have to, to open an app in order to do that.
Speaker 2:  Has interactivity opened up your brain on stuff you wanna
Speaker 2:  put into Widgetsmith? I think most of the stuff I've seen so far is kind
Speaker 2:  of extensions on the things you've already been doing. The one I've been
Speaker 2:  using constantly is being able to scroll the hourly forecast. I love that.
Speaker 2:  Sure. Like it's, it's one of those little things I didn't expect to like
Speaker 2:  really care about, but it loves, it's, it's delightful. But are there things
Speaker 2:  you've been either building or looking at that are sort of totally
Speaker 2:  new and different because of interactivity? Sure.
Speaker 10:  I mean, I think, I mean the, the, the most like silly example of that is
Speaker 10:  like being able to put games into your widgets, which doesn't, it's like,
Speaker 10:  it's a, it is a complete silly thing in many ways, but like sometimes the
Speaker 10:  silly things are the best things and like that's an example of something
Speaker 10:  that just wasn't possible before. And now you can, and obviously there's
Speaker 10:  limitations on a game 'cause it has to be a game that you can play only
Speaker 10:  by sort of intermittent tapping that is not in a
Speaker 10:  timely way. So like
Speaker 2:  Tic-tac-toe in a widget would totally work.
Speaker 10:  Yes, exactly. Okay. Like something in any kind of game where there's, you're
Speaker 10:  taking turns or that kind of behavior is definitely something that's possible.
Speaker 10:  But you know, you know, you're not gonna be able to make Flappy Bird for
Speaker 10:  the widget because there's no sense of timeliness to the, the, you know,
Speaker 10:  when you tap and how it responds. But I think that's a kind of thing that's,
Speaker 10:  I don't think the game itself necessarily is the end state of that,
Speaker 10:  but I think that's an example of the kind of thing that you can start to
Speaker 10:  do where just having the ability to respond to a button tap
Speaker 10:  opens up a variety of things that you could come up with and you could think
Speaker 10:  of that allow you to do. And like, I mean, so I've done a bunch of things
Speaker 10:  with, related to music. It was actually a widget that I found
Speaker 10:  super helpful for me is I've made a little like a co cover flow widget.
Speaker 10:  So, you know, so you can put, put your albums into a, a medium
Speaker 10:  widget and you can, you know, sort of you tap on the edges and you can scroll
Speaker 10:  through them and then you can tap on the one in the middle and it'll start
Speaker 10:  to play. And because it's interactive, I don't, you don't have to launch
Speaker 10:  the app for it to play, you know, it's, it's, it's not needing
Speaker 10:  you to even do an app launch. It can just start. And then, because the now
Speaker 10:  playing experience goes up into the, you know, the dynamic island, you just
Speaker 10:  see that the album started playing and you can, you know, move on. And I
Speaker 10:  think that kind of thing is just really just different
Speaker 10:  that it, it feels very interesting to not even have to duck in and out of
Speaker 10:  an app. Like previously if I'd done music widgets, like, well you have to
Speaker 10:  launch Widgetsmith, it'll start to play and then you have to quit it because
Speaker 10:  that you always had to have this weird round trip to the app even if the
Speaker 10:  app was doing hardly anything, you know, or similarly you can start workouts
Speaker 10:  is another thing with interactivity where you could, you know, you can say
Speaker 10:  you're going for a run and you tap it and your phone just starts striking
Speaker 10:  your run without having to open an app necessarily and you can just jump
Speaker 10:  into the, the live activity or the dynamic island and you
Speaker 10:  can tap the widget and then you can lock your phone and then off you go
Speaker 10:  and it's, your progress would show up on your home, you know, on your lock
Speaker 10:  screen in the live activity. And it's not like that one step
Speaker 10:  is huge, but I feel like taking the number of times that you can take out
Speaker 10:  that one step will add up over time in terms of its value
Speaker 10:  and utility.
Speaker 2:  After David and I talked naturally, I put a thousand new widgets on my iPhone,
Speaker 2:  but while I'm in the middle of this personalization craze, I started
Speaker 2:  thinking about changing my wallpaper and my app icons too, both
Speaker 2:  of which are also really good ways to personalize your phone and make it
Speaker 2:  work the way that you want it to. I ended up buying a wallpaper from a guy
Speaker 2:  named Isaac Mosna, who you might know as Kasie from YouTube and elsewhere
Speaker 2:  on the internet
Speaker 11:  Today I'll be showing you how I've set up my phone, some of the apps I use
Speaker 11:  and generally how I've customized it to match my style and how I
Speaker 11:  use my device.
Speaker 2:  I like the wallpaper, it looks great, but it kind of made me wonder what
Speaker 2:  is it like being in the iPhone personalization business?
Speaker 2:  There are countless free iPhone wallpapers online, so how
Speaker 2:  do you make some that people will pay for? What makes them pay for it and
Speaker 2:  what makes a great wallpaper? Great. Anyway,
Speaker 2:  so I called up Isaac and asked him, and I asked him just to start at the
Speaker 2:  very beginning, how do you become a person who makes wallpapers?
Speaker 12:  It was kind of for myself originally, because I'm making YouTube videos,
Speaker 12:  I can never find the, the wallpaper I wanted to like showcase any YouTube
Speaker 12:  video because you don't
Speaker 2:  Wanna just have the same like stock wallpapers everybody has, right?
Speaker 12:  No, no, I, I couldn't do that. I'm like, I used to do that. But then like
Speaker 12:  making videos, everybody has like a really nice vibrant eye catching
Speaker 12:  wallpaper in the thumbnail and I used like a lot of
Speaker 12:  'em and then I just kinda got sick of hunting and searching and being like,
Speaker 12:  okay, this is okay. But like, I wish it was a bit more orange or a bit more
Speaker 12:  blue because the thumbnail idea I have doesn't really work or you know,
Speaker 12:  in the video it doesn't really match the, the scheme of like my set
Speaker 12:  design. So I'm like, what if I just made them? And it was during Covid
Speaker 12:  so I had so much time, like I was home and I'm like, I'm gonna get my iPad
Speaker 12:  out, I'm gonna start drawing, I'm gonna start making some wallpapers. And
Speaker 12:  I thought I was pretty happy with my original designs and I thought that
Speaker 12:  they looked, they looked great and matched my style of like minimal designs
Speaker 12:  and matched sort of my thumbnail style and my video style. It was all a
Speaker 12:  nice cohesive experience. You know, being a YouTube video, people
Speaker 12:  would ask immediately like, where'd you get your wallpaper from? It's the
Speaker 12:  most common question in any tech video on a phone or a tablet or a laptop.
Speaker 12:  It's like, where's the wallpaper from? For me, I, I just made them all.
Speaker 12:  So eventually I was able to launch a Shopify store with my zero
Speaker 12:  knowledge of web design. Nice. I was able to figure it out and
Speaker 12:  Shopify makes it really easy to do all that stuff. And you know, Shopify
Speaker 12:  makes the whole sales process very easy too. Yeah. Lets me sell
Speaker 12:  to whoever I want. There's apps to have digital downloads,
Speaker 12:  all that fun stuff. And next thing you know, I'm dropping a wallpaper
Speaker 12:  pack every few weeks and wallpaper packs for me just consist of
Speaker 12:  different designs that kind of go together in a specific theme.
Speaker 12:  I like to have fun with it. I like to like think of really cool names for
Speaker 12:  all the wallpaper names for all the different wallpapers in a pack have
Speaker 12:  like a very themed design for like the mockup photos.
Speaker 12:  Pretty much every pack would have like new photos with little quirks and
Speaker 12:  little fun things here and there and I didn't really know
Speaker 12:  how well it would do, but then it just started blowing up.
Speaker 12:  Like it was just nonstop. It almost became a full business. I almost had
Speaker 12:  to hire somebody to manage like customer service. Wow. And manage
Speaker 12:  hosting the website. I'm thankful that I, I had just finished
Speaker 12:  university so I was like ready to go. I was ready to work and my whole focus
Speaker 12:  was dedicated to YouTube, Instagram, other content production and, and now
Speaker 12:  my website with these wallpaper.
Speaker 2:  Why do you think it worked so well? I mean, wallpapers are a funny thing
Speaker 2:  in that there are a billion of them out there, right? Like if you just google
Speaker 2:  like iPhone wallpaper, like you can, you can look through the options until
Speaker 2:  the day you die and you'll never run out. Like I wonder if there is something
Speaker 2:  to just like, you have a style that fits and people just like understand
Speaker 2:  your style and like your style and that goes a long way. I don't know like
Speaker 2:  why do you think it took off the way it did?
Speaker 12:  It's a mix of different things. It's a mix of people seeing the wallpaper
Speaker 12:  in action on my channel. People who know my style, they know
Speaker 12:  I like these sort of designs. People seeing it in use, it's great. I think
Speaker 12:  also Apple's customization push was also a good thing. It came at the right
Speaker 12:  time. People like to make their phone personal and
Speaker 12:  they like to make it something that is uniquely them because one thing that
Speaker 12:  I also envision too, or I at least thought of when designing these is like,
Speaker 12:  we don't really hang that many things up in our homes anymore, like art
Speaker 12:  or designs. But our phone is like a canvas that we see
Speaker 12:  every single day. It's like we turn it on, we see a wallpaper or a new
Speaker 12:  wallpaper that cycles. And to be able to see like a little bit of art
Speaker 12:  or a nice design, it has the same effect as art in your home. Whether
Speaker 12:  when you come home and you see it, you have like this nice feeling of
Speaker 12:  this is familiar or this makes me feel a certain way. If something is dynamic
Speaker 12:  and bold and bright, it kinda like wakes you up a little bit. It makes you
Speaker 12:  feel a bit more energetic. And obviously I'm just talking about a image
Speaker 12:  or a jpeg, but it's like it, it does have that feeling whenever
Speaker 12:  I turn my phone on, like I get hit with like a bold, textured,
Speaker 12:  vibrant piece and makes me happy. So it's a mix of different
Speaker 12:  things.
Speaker 2:  No, I, I think, I think you're totally right. So take me through the process
Speaker 2:  a little bit. Like you, you sit down and you're like, okay, I want to, I
Speaker 2:  want to do a new pack, a new collection. Where do you start?
Speaker 12:  So pretty much I like to start with colors. I think colors
Speaker 12:  are the best place to start for me personally and the way I work. Let's
Speaker 12:  say I wanna do like a very cool toned palette, maybe it's like a purple
Speaker 12:  and a pink and a blue. I start to just mess with things I usually use per
Speaker 12:  crate. I've done some stuff in illustrators and stuff in Photoshop, but
Speaker 12:  usually procreate is the most consistent best way I work. I know
Speaker 12:  how it works to a T now I know how all the brushes work, how everything
Speaker 12:  kind of flows. And I think Procreate is so great because it's
Speaker 12:  very natural and organic versus a computer you're like typing and you're
Speaker 12:  clicking things. It's not as natural as like a pen or your finger.
Speaker 12:  So I'll start by like mixing around different colors and trying different
Speaker 12:  gradients or trying different shapes. And then usually
Speaker 12:  I'm able to just think of the pack right there. Like let's say it's like
Speaker 12:  a two D shape based pack. I start drawing some flowing shapes, I start adding
Speaker 12:  different colors, you know, things aren't really in the right place. I tweak
Speaker 12:  them a little bit. Maybe I'll warp a shape a little bit until I really get
Speaker 12:  that exact shape and form I want. If it's a more abstract, like
Speaker 12:  gradient based or like a really flowing designed pack, I'll just
Speaker 12:  mess with it until I think it looks right and I think it has like the feeling
Speaker 12:  I want. Then I do things like add a little bit of noise, add a bit of sharpness
Speaker 12:  to things, tweak the colors a little bit, and then I throw them onto most
Speaker 12:  of my devices to test them out. So I have it on my phone. Looks good. Okay,
Speaker 12:  that's, that's solid. Put it on the desktop. I don't really know how that
Speaker 12:  looks on the desktop. Maybe I have to tweak this one area a little bit.
Speaker 12:  Maybe I have to blow this part up a little bit. Pull it back on the iPad,
Speaker 12:  tweak that, send it to the desktop, try it on the iPad as well. And
Speaker 12:  then once it's all shit, once it's all like in a, in a state that I like,
Speaker 12:  I'm ready to ship it onto my website. I do all the mockup photos, I shoot
Speaker 12:  everything, you know, name everything as well based on how I feel, what
Speaker 12:  the pack conveys in terms of the overall collection name
Speaker 12:  and all the different names of all the different pieces. And then load it
Speaker 12:  all up, write a nice little description and then that's it.
Speaker 2:  So talk to me about the icon pack before I forget to ask about the icon pack.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I find icons so fascinating because yeah, like
Speaker 2:  you only have one wallpaper, there are a million apps out there
Speaker 2:  in the world. So I would think trying to make an icon pack that like is both
Speaker 2:  sort of cohesive and looks nice, but also like exists
Speaker 2:  in a world where everybody has a mountain of different apps on their phone.
Speaker 2:  Strikes me as very hard. So like, what made you wanna do this in the first
Speaker 2:  place? Like you just saw everybody customizing and you're like, I wanna,
Speaker 2:  I want to see how I can be part of this too
Speaker 12:  In some regards. But also like when I started designing the wallpapers,
Speaker 12:  I felt like from my phone personally, the icons, like icons are all
Speaker 12:  over the place these days. You know, there's like, like so many different
Speaker 12:  colors. Some of them are all black, some of them are all white. And I just
Speaker 12:  couldn't really think of a way to make it look cohesive. So I'll have the
Speaker 12:  wallpaper that I'm really happy with, but then I'm like, okay. But the icons
Speaker 12:  are just, they kind of mess with the color scheme. And you know, I like
Speaker 12:  to keep things simple. Usually I like to keep things pretty minimal with
Speaker 12:  design. So I just wanted to have like a set that is, you
Speaker 12:  can either choose just, you can choose all black or all white and
Speaker 12:  that's it. So with the, with my icon pack, like it's obviously a
Speaker 12:  very specific taste. Like I hand drew every single icon. I
Speaker 12:  don't remember exactly how icons, how many icons there are at this point.
Speaker 12:  That's
Speaker 2:  So many icons.
Speaker 12:  I know I just, it was all like stock apps and then also a bunch of the popular
Speaker 12:  apps that people use every single day. And I just wanted to make something
Speaker 12:  that was very different than what everybody else did. 'cause I think a lot
Speaker 12:  of people just shipped literally the same icons and
Speaker 12:  like different, different packs. Like everybody was dropping contacts and
Speaker 12:  a lot of them were just the same icons. And I just thought like what?
Speaker 2:  There was so much like very basic like clip art looking
Speaker 2:  stuff in all those icon packs. Yes. Yeah.
Speaker 12:  And the reason why is because it was the easiest way to make a lot of money.
Speaker 12:  Like there was all these stories about some developer making a hundred thousand
Speaker 12:  in a month off of a minimal icon pack and everybody wants to make a hundred
Speaker 12:  thousand in a month. Yeah. But it's like, I can't do stuff like that. Like
Speaker 12:  I just couldn't just ship out a random pack and then use my channels to
Speaker 12:  promote it. 'cause I would feel bad. And also like I probably wouldn't have
Speaker 12:  designed all of those icons, like where are they coming from? But obviously
Speaker 12:  I don't mean to trash talk that designer. I think he was one of the first
Speaker 12:  people to see the potential of custom icons. And I think he did it all
Speaker 12:  by himself, which is great. I love that. I love seeing successes like that.
Speaker 12:  Yeah. So for my collection, I want to have things that would fit my style,
Speaker 12:  be a little bit unique, be a little bit different. It's not obviously for
Speaker 12:  everyone, but the people who do like it are always sharing
Speaker 12:  screenshots on Twitter or Instagram. Tell me how much they like it and
Speaker 12:  request icons that they want to add. And obviously I can't do every single
Speaker 12:  icon. I'm not physically capable of doing that, but I
Speaker 12:  like to be able to have icons for most of the popular apps and all the stock
Speaker 12:  apps. And now with the new iPhones that have dynamic
Speaker 12:  islands, it hides that really annoying shortcut notification
Speaker 12:  that drops down every single time you open a shortcut, as I'm sure you're
Speaker 12:  familiar with. That's one of the biggest things that prevented me from even
Speaker 12:  doing this in the first place. Like even wanting to use icons. 'cause when
Speaker 12:  you know this ability first came out, it was okay. Like it was
Speaker 12:  like, you know that dropdown, you forget it's there. You get used to it.
Speaker 12:  Either decide do I wanna see that notification every single time or
Speaker 12:  do I have a nice beautiful custom home screen? And obviously a
Speaker 12:  lot of people have chosen the ladder because it's worth the trade-off to
Speaker 12:  sometimes have that customization in place. But now with the new dynamic
Speaker 12:  island functionality, you don't see that notification at all. It hides it.
Speaker 12:  In the island, it's very, very subtle. And now even with things like the
Speaker 12:  camera before, if you used a shortcut with a custom
Speaker 12:  icon to open up the camera app, it would take an extra full second for
Speaker 12:  the camera. Oh geez. To like be ready to go canceled dealbreaker. I can't
Speaker 12:  deal deal with that. But now you can do it. And if you're willing
Speaker 12:  to go through the process, which isn't super terrible these days and there
Speaker 12:  are very cohesive guides and I think even shortcuts you can download.
Speaker 12:  It's pretty easy to do. But for me personally, my home screen is very clean
Speaker 12:  and I like to have just a couple icons. Everything else is in the app
Speaker 12:  library and that's how I like it. So
Speaker 2:  I like that. Are you just a one home screen guy?
Speaker 12:  Yeah, yeah. I have. I
Speaker 2:  Admire that. I aspire to be that. It's
Speaker 12:  All that works for me at this point. I like to have four apps in the doc
Speaker 12:  and then four apps on my home screen. A little square
Speaker 12:  arrangement using the Clear Spaces app. 'cause I don't really wanna see
Speaker 12:  too much when I turn my phone on. I want to be able to see my wallpaper
Speaker 12:  and also be able to just see the core apps I need and any distracting things
Speaker 12:  like Instagram and Twitter. All those are on in the app library,
Speaker 12:  so they're not like the first thing I see when I turn my phone on.
Speaker 2:  After I talked to Isaac, I blew up my whole phone again. I got rid of a bunch
Speaker 2:  of the widgets, I changed my wallpaper again and I changed a few icons.
Speaker 2:  I didn't change all of my icons, just the four in my doc,
Speaker 2:  which tend to be the ones that never really move around and they're all a
Speaker 2:  single style now. I really like how it looks. Plus I now have just two home
Speaker 2:  screens. One is apps and one is widgets. And I think Isaac's right that
Speaker 2:  less is more there. The app library or the app drawer on Android
Speaker 2:  do the job. Great.
Speaker 2:  After all this, suffice to say my phone looks really different than it did
Speaker 2:  a few weeks ago and it was a really fun exercise actually. I wound up not
Speaker 2:  just changing the look of my phone, but really thinking about where I want
Speaker 2:  things to be and what I want to have easy access to and maybe just as
Speaker 2:  important what I don't wanna have easy access to, plus what my home
Speaker 2:  screen and wallpaper and icons and widgets should not just
Speaker 2:  do, but make me feel every time I turn my phone on.
Speaker 2:  Not everyone is gonna want to go down this unbelievable rabbit hole of
Speaker 2:  personalization and shortcuts and widgets and all kinds of different stuff
Speaker 2:  and that's okay. But I think it's worth at least spending a few minutes to
Speaker 2:  make sure that when you turn your phone on, as we all do a million times
Speaker 2:  a day, it feels the way you want it to because I think that's important.
Speaker 2:  Alright, that's enough Apple talk. That is it for The Vergecast today. Thanks
Speaker 2:  to everybody who came on the show, and thank you as always for listening.
Speaker 2:  There's lots more from everything we talked about on The Verge dot com.
Speaker 2:  We'll put some links to all our reviews in the show notes. But also, you
Speaker 2:  know, read The Verge dot com. There's so much gadget news this week.
Speaker 2:  There's Xbox Leaks, there's a Microsoft event, there's an Amazon event, there's
Speaker 2:  a ton happening. All of it is on The Verge dot com. If you have thoughts,
Speaker 2:  questions, feelings, or other phones you think people should buy instead
Speaker 2:  of the iPhone 15, you can always email us at Vergecast at The Verge dot
Speaker 2:  com or keep calling the hotline. 8 6 6 Verge one one. Send us all of your
Speaker 2:  thoughts and questions. And again, this is probably the last call for this.
Speaker 2:  If you have questions about The Verge or The Vergecast, send them in. The
Speaker 2:  meta episode is coming really soon. This show is produced by
Speaker 2:  Andrew Moreno and Liam James. Brooke Miners is our editorial director of
Speaker 2:  Audio The. Vergecast is a Verge production and part of the Vox Media podcast
Speaker 2:  network. Neli, Alex, and I'll be back on Friday to talk about
Speaker 2:  Amazon, Microsoft y, Amazon and Microsoft are suddenly kind of
Speaker 2:  at odds about gadgets, Xbox, and all the other stuff going on this week.
Speaker 2:  See you then. Rock and roll
Speaker 13:  Support for this episode comes from Zelle. You'd
Speaker 13:  never fall for an online scam. Right? You use
Speaker 13:  two factor authentication. Ignore calls from everyone named
Speaker 13:  spam risk and never use the password. Password.
Speaker 13:  But scammers are getting more sophisticated and more active,
Speaker 13:  which means they're finding millions of new victims every single
Speaker 13:  year. The good news is that there's a lot you can do to protect yourself
Speaker 13:  on the wild, wild web For starters. Zelle wants
Speaker 13:  to remind you only send money to people You know and trust.
Speaker 13:  Zelle is available to United States Bank account holders only terms and
Speaker 13:  conditions apply.
Speaker 3:  Support for this show comes from Global Citizen. On
Speaker 3:  September 23rd, the Global Citizen Festival will gather thousands of people
Speaker 3:  who took action to end extreme poverty. Watch the red Hot
Speaker 3:  Chili peppers, Ms. Lauren Hill, Jean and Anita
Speaker 3:  as they take the stage with world leaders and activists to demand
Speaker 3:  action for equity, for the planet, for food and for jobs.
Speaker 3:  Download the Global Citizen app to watch live. Learn more at Global Citizen
Speaker 3:  dot org slash vox.