# Transcript
ID: 4e752780-9501-11ed-b69d-65cd7ca9468f
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Apple might make a touchscreen Mac / Samsung S23 images leak
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/1284717545890167436/7771977918361877487/s93290-US-3926s-1673806833.mp3
Description: The Verge's Alex Cranz, Richard Lawler, and Dan Seifert discuss the numerous Apple rumors we heard about this week, a Samsung Unpacked preview, and the latest gadget news.
Speaker 1:  Hey, it's your friend Eli. I just wanna tell you about our new newsletter.
Speaker 1:  It's called Command Line. It's written by the verges, Alex Heath, and it's
Speaker 1:  all about the tech industry's inside conversation with scoops, interviews
Speaker 1:  and analysis you won't get anywhere else. Here's Alex.
Speaker 2:  Each week you'll get scoops about what's coming next from tech giants like
Speaker 2:  Apple and Meta and hear about the product and people moves that matter. And
Speaker 2:  I want you to be part of the conversation. So I'll be answering questions
Speaker 2:  and featuring what you have
Speaker 1:  To say. Head on over to the verge.com/command line to subscribe today. That's
Speaker 1:  the verge.com/command line.
Speaker 4:  Hello and welcome to the Vergecast, the flagship podcast
Speaker 4:  of Fleetwood Max 1977. Incredible
Speaker 4:  album Rumors cuz we're, we're, we're gonna talk about rumors.
Speaker 5:  Tusk is better.
Speaker 4:  Wow. I've been told that we cannot actually play any songs from rumors over
Speaker 4:  this. Otherwise Fleetwood Mac will come to the Vergecast
Speaker 4:  studio and beat up Andrew. So sorry Andrew, we'll protect you.
Speaker 4:  Please don't play any other music, even though it's great. But joining me
Speaker 4:  in the studio today, not in the studio. Joining me today is Dan
Speaker 4:  Seifert. Hello Dan.
Speaker 5:  Hello
Speaker 4:  And the incredible Richard Lawler. Hello Richard.
Speaker 6:  Hello. I would like everyone to know that I did not steal funds and if you'd
Speaker 6:  like to know more about that, you can subscribe to my CK there's a feature.
Speaker 6:  Thank you.
Speaker 4:  Thank you. Richard. As you know, NELA is not here. He disappeared.
Speaker 4:  I think he's somewhere upstate, unclear where, unclear what's
Speaker 4:  happening. I think he's okay. He's probably okay. Send
Speaker 4:  him all your love and all of your pictures of Mariah Carey to keep him through
Speaker 4:  these cold long winter nights. But we've got a lot of things
Speaker 4:  going on on the Verge cast today. We've got a ton of Apple rumors,
Speaker 4:  we've got a ton of Samsung rumors. We have no Fleetwood Mac rumors
Speaker 4:  because again, we don't want Andrew to die, but we, we've just got, there's
Speaker 4:  a whole bunch of things happening today, so we're gonna get right into it.
Speaker 4:  Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Let's
Speaker 6:  Do it. And, and let's get started. Started with the biggest rumor that we've
Speaker 6:  all been waiting for. At least some of us have been waiting for or someone
Speaker 6:  has been waiting for that Apple might finally make a touchscreen Mac.
Speaker 4:  Yes. This is Dan's favorite thing Dan, you were so excited about this.
Speaker 4:  I've never seen someone glow with joy at a rumor
Speaker 4:  before. Yeah. You like, I notice like a, a
Speaker 4:  legendary desire for all Verge cast listeners, for all people
Speaker 4:  at the Verge to have a touch MacBook Pro, a touch Mac.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. At
Speaker 5:  All. Yeah. So there's rumors coming from Bloomberg
Speaker 4:  You said really enthusiastic.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. You know, well, I mean look, it'll be good. It'll be
Speaker 5:  fine to have it. I think that there's like, let me just like say
Speaker 5:  what this rumor is. So Mark Derman at Bloomberg has reported
Speaker 5:  that in 2025 Apple will release its first
Speaker 5:  touchscreen Mac, or at least that's what they're aiming for now, which is
Speaker 5:  two years away at least. And it might use an Olet screen, but the big deal
Speaker 5:  is it would be a touchscreen, which would be first for the Mac. So
Speaker 5:  the way that he's framed this rumor is that this is not
Speaker 5:  iPad hardware running Mac os It is. Okay. Kind
Speaker 5:  of framed as like this is a, a MacBook style laptop
Speaker 5:  with a touchscreen on it. Which is, you know, very similar to
Speaker 5:  countless windows running devices that have been on the market for many years
Speaker 5:  that have touchscreens and people like them and they enjoy them and stuff
Speaker 5:  like that for like a decade. But what it doesn't seem like it is, what's
Speaker 5:  that?
Speaker 4:  It's like a decade. We've had touchscreen windows machines for over a decade.
Speaker 5:  Yes. Very long time. But a lot of those touchscreen
Speaker 5:  devices and those Windows machines have been like convertibles. Either they
Speaker 5:  like flip the screen around behind the keyboard or you could
Speaker 5:  do the surface style and rip the keyboard off becomes a tablet, stuff like
Speaker 5:  that. This is like at least how it's framed now in the reporting it,
Speaker 5:  I am not reading that. I am reading that this is a laptop with a touchscreen
Speaker 5:  and a fixed hinge that extends to a certain opening degrees and then it's
Speaker 5:  just st always a laptop. You never turn this into a tablet. And so then the
Speaker 5:  question becomes, well what benefit does that bring? Right. And I think that
Speaker 5:  if it pans out that way, it would just be like your main
Speaker 5:  input devices are still the keyboard and the track pad, which have
Speaker 5:  been always, well at least the track pad's always been excellent on max and
Speaker 5:  the recent keyboards have been very good. Yeah. And then the touchscreen
Speaker 5:  is just there and you can like poke at it to like scroll
Speaker 5:  a, a webpage or pinch zoom on something or tap a button or something
Speaker 5:  like that. Which is exactly how I use a touchscreen windows laptop. And that'll
Speaker 5:  be nice
Speaker 6:  And it's fine.
Speaker 4:  So it's basically like for those of us who have stupid fingers,
Speaker 4:  cuz I have very stupid fingers and I'll use my iPad all the time and then
Speaker 4:  I'll go to my MacBook and then I'll be like, oh, I wanna make Richard bigger
Speaker 4:  on the screen and just reach out and touch Richard's face and nothing
Speaker 4:  happens because it's just a normal computer. And I'm like, oh yeah,
Speaker 4:  that's not how those work. It's for me. Right. Like it's, it's for those
Speaker 4:  of us who are just like, forget.
Speaker 6:  Well I think it's also for people who are much younger than us Yeah. Who
Speaker 6:  have had touchscreens surrounding them their whole lives. Partially due to
Speaker 6:  Apple's success with the iPhone, with the iPad, they are used to being able
Speaker 6:  to reach out and touch things that is,
Speaker 5:  Or you know, they have Chromebooks that have touchscreens and that's what
Speaker 5:  they're using in school. And so like that's what you know they are, they
Speaker 5:  are accustomed to it. It is a very natural interaction. Wanna touch a screen?
Speaker 5:  I can tell you from years of reviewing laptops, many of those Windows
Speaker 5:  laptops that head touchscreens and every time I would like review a laptop
Speaker 5:  for a couple of weeks or whatever and go back to using my work Mac, I would
Speaker 5:  hit the stupid screen, punch a screen by reflex cuz it became so
Speaker 5:  natural and normal to be able to like click an okay button
Speaker 5:  or you know, close a window by just having the screen. It's not
Speaker 5:  the primary interaction model, it's just another
Speaker 5:  convenient way to use the device in a natural way. That makes sense.
Speaker 5:  I think the people that like really kind of like are
Speaker 5:  against this idea are the people who are of the mind
Speaker 5:  that like my fingers never leave the home row. I know all the keyboard shortcuts
Speaker 5:  and I have perfect typing form and I know how to navigate the whole os without
Speaker 5:  ever lifting my fingers off the keyboard. And like that's great for you.
Speaker 5:  You don't ever have to touch the screen if you don't want to. Like I'm sure
Speaker 5:  Mac os will still
Speaker 6:  Work. Davis Bacon is very proud. It's
Speaker 5:  Just Richard exactly the way. But like the rest of the world doesn't work.
Speaker 5:  Have you ever watched someone use a computer? Their hands are like all over
Speaker 5:  the place and like they, they got their hand down on the track pad or they
Speaker 5:  are like, you know, have poor typing for 'em like myself. Like
Speaker 5:  so it's, it's a natural way. It makes sense. The fact that they didn't do
Speaker 5:  it for so long I think is kind of like silly. I
Speaker 4:  Don't think it's silly
Speaker 6:  Though that they went with the touch bar at all that that ever happened.
Speaker 4:  The touch bar was incredible. Shut your dirty mouth. It was in, it was
Speaker 4:  wonderful. I loved it so much.
Speaker 5:  I mean if you still want it, you could still get it on a MacBook Pro 13 inch
Speaker 5:  M two if you love
Speaker 4:  It that much. The other day I was going and I have a stream deck at home
Speaker 4:  and it has a button on it that I just press and it opens a quick post and
Speaker 4:  I can immediately pop off a quick post and now instead I have to like do
Speaker 4:  more things. And I was like, man, I wish this MacBook Air had
Speaker 4:  a touch bar with a quick post button on it and I could just go, boop, like
Speaker 4:  I miss i I dream about a touch bar that's
Speaker 4:  works perfectly. It never existed but it could have. Okay. My
Speaker 4:  heart.
Speaker 6:  And that was what struck me cuz I went, I went back and looked at Jake's
Speaker 6:  review of the first MacBook PR that had a touch bar. Yeah. And that
Speaker 6:  was kind of what he said was that the idea was decent and that he could see
Speaker 6:  where, where there were opportunities for it but the software didn't exist.
Speaker 6:  And now years later we know that the software never existed. It never exist.
Speaker 6:  The use case it, it just never really came about.
Speaker 5:  It never, it never got the buy-in. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  There was like three developers who were like, those three developers were
Speaker 4:  working so hard and they're we're doing so much cool stuff and then you'll
Speaker 4:  be like, wow, I can't do anything else but like mute.
Speaker 4:  But I can mute real fast and it's great and I don't have to think about it.
Speaker 4:  I guess I could also do that with physical buttons and
Speaker 5:  Changing the volume takes three taps I believe it took as opposed to just,
Speaker 5:  you know, one Yeah. Rude. The other, the other way to look
Speaker 5:  at this I think is you could argue that Apple has already
Speaker 5:  made a touchscreen laptop and it's called the iPad with the magic keyboard
Speaker 5:  or now even more so the magic keyboard folio. And I think the magic keyboard
Speaker 5:  folio is the more instructive use case here. The one that came out for the
Speaker 5:  10th gen iPad because the magic keyboard for the
Speaker 5:  iPad Pro kind of is designed to bring that screen forward
Speaker 5:  toward you so it's closer to you so that when you do touch it, it's not like
Speaker 5:  you're reaching as far, but the magic keyboard folio is the opposite. It's
Speaker 5:  design is like pretty far away for you to be reaching up and touching the
Speaker 5:  screen much like it is with a laptop. And the screen is like kind of a
Speaker 5:  distance for you to touch. And so your primary interactions when you're using
Speaker 5:  the magic keyboard folio with the iPad is you're using the keyboard and the
Speaker 5:  track pad and then occasionally you're tapping the screen to select a box
Speaker 5:  or hit okay. Or close a window or scroll or just zoom
Speaker 5:  whatever it is convenient for you. But again it's, it's like this extra interaction.
Speaker 5:  So
Speaker 4:  This is what I wanted to talk about cuz like, okay, they say we're gonna
Speaker 4:  do a touch, it's gonna be gonna be a MacBook, it's gonna look like an app
Speaker 4:  MacBook, it's gonna act like a MacBook and it'll just have a touch thing
Speaker 4:  on it. And like you could go and do that for years now. You could go and
Speaker 4:  like hack one, put a, there are these cool little like weird screen overlays
Speaker 4:  you could do, don't do it. They were terrible. But you could theoretically
Speaker 4:  do it. It's like the worst experience in the world. But the
Speaker 4:  problem is like iPad exists and iPad is built for touch and all the buttons
Speaker 4:  are big for touch. Everything is intended for touch. The MacBook is not
Speaker 4:  intended for touch and I don't think anybody wants the buttons to suddenly
Speaker 4:  get huge and all of those touch, have
Speaker 5:  You seen Control Center on recent Mac Os? Like
Speaker 4:  I am looking at my little, my little, you know the
Speaker 4:  little dots that make your windows get big and small. Those are still small.
Speaker 4:  Sure. But I would imagine on like on if it was a touch, I'd want them big
Speaker 4:  so that I don't,
Speaker 6:  And those are annoying to hit with the mouse. They should be big.
Speaker 4:  So you're, you're a pro big button. You're I see
Speaker 5:  How, I mean look with, so this is this Rumor's two years out, right? So that
Speaker 5:  is two versions of Makos that they can tweak and adjust and
Speaker 5:  continue to bring Makos closer to this touch experience. Like
Speaker 5:  we're already, we've, we, I think if you look back like two Mac os
Speaker 5:  reviews ago, the story was about how they're making it more like an
Speaker 5:  iPad with the control center updates, right. And some other interaction things.
Speaker 5:  This year they brought Stage Manager, which is very obviously an
Speaker 5:  iPad first designed feature that you can also run on the Mac but
Speaker 5:  it works like it does on the iPad. And so like you could
Speaker 5:  see that these next steps are gonna come, they'll figure out some way to
Speaker 5:  do window management in a nice more toucher friendly way. But again,
Speaker 5:  I don't know if touch is ever going to be the primary
Speaker 5:  interaction this
Speaker 4:  Often figured out how to do Windows management on an iPad though. Like just
Speaker 4:  last, this was like two years ago that they were like, we're doing Windows
Speaker 6:  Or on a Mac in opinion,
Speaker 5:  But Right. But that, that's like, that's, that's not because it, it's not
Speaker 5:  touchable, it's because of the iPad's os structure
Speaker 5:  and the way that they are trying to
Speaker 4:  Reinvent everything.
Speaker 5:  But if the, but like the iPad comes
Speaker 4:  From
Speaker 5:  Everything as a touch first experience and this
Speaker 5:  in a, in a, in a laptop, the touch layer is not the first primary
Speaker 5:  way of interacting with it. It is like a tertiary interaction level.
Speaker 5:  And so like you don't need everything to be touch friendly like on
Speaker 5:  Windows. Not everything is touch friendly. Like there's lots of little fiddly
Speaker 5:  things on Windows that when you're using touchscreen on a Windows device,
Speaker 5:  like are still fiddly. Microsoft has changed it a little bit. They, they
Speaker 5:  get the, the task bar a little bigger. The buttons get a little bit larger
Speaker 5:  when you switch into tablet mode and stuff like that. But there's still a
Speaker 5:  lot of fiddly check boxes. It's still Windows. And I don't think that really
Speaker 5:  needs to change because it's not like this would be the primary interaction.
Speaker 5:  It's just like certain things you would wanna touch or you would reflexively
Speaker 5:  touch. I think the thing that I always end up doing is on the lock screen
Speaker 5:  when you log in, you type in your password and you wanna click okay and you
Speaker 5:  wanna touch the button to hit Okay. Which is already, it's
Speaker 4:  So satisfying. Just
Speaker 5:  Boop. Exactly. And so like things like that is
Speaker 6:  Where you will touch and that's what we've seen on, on Windows. Like those
Speaker 6:  like three buttons to manage the windows. They, they're not a lot bigger
Speaker 6:  than they used to be, but they've gotten more touch friendly. They, they
Speaker 6:  figured it out. If mi if Microsoft can figure out how to make the UI touch
Speaker 6:  friendly between Windows eight and Windows 11 and it mostly is now
Speaker 6:  Mo mostly most of the time.
Speaker 4:  Mostly
Speaker 6:  I'm pretty sure Apple can can do something there.
Speaker 5:  The other point here is that you can run iPad
Speaker 5:  apps on the Mac now. Like if you open the home app on the Mac,
Speaker 5:  it is essentially the iPad app running on the Mac with the same interaction,
Speaker 5:  the same ui, and the same interface. And that goes on for like a number of
Speaker 5:  other apps. So like it's not weird to run those, it'd actually be better
Speaker 5:  to use those with touch because they were designed touch first. So a lot
Speaker 5:  of the things are like, I would like to be able to touch this screen, but
Speaker 5:  then if I'm using, I don't know, I, I'm looking at GarageBand and my web
Speaker 5:  browser right now, I probably would not interact with those with Touch primarily
Speaker 5:  I would use my mouse and keyboard like I always have. Ooh,
Speaker 4:  Are we gonna get to a point? They always say every time these rumors start
Speaker 4:  flying and we start hearing about like the touchscreen MacBooks and
Speaker 4:  the, the continued fusion of iPad OS and Mac Os, we start
Speaker 4:  talking about walled gardens. How like if we had to do,
Speaker 4:  there's, there's the Go 90 scale, which is all about streaming
Speaker 4:  services, but I think there should be like a walled garden scale from like
Speaker 4:  no wall to wall. That's a terrible scale, but that's what it is.
Speaker 4:  How in danger do you think the un walled Garden of Mac OS
Speaker 4:  is with a touch Mac and that that like iPad energy
Speaker 4:  getting more infused into the Mac? Cause I'm a little nervous. I'm
Speaker 4:  not gonna lie.
Speaker 5:  I mean, I mean the optimist in me, which is a rare person who comes
Speaker 5:  out, you don't see the optimism.
Speaker 4:  Who is, this is not, this is not Dan.
Speaker 5:  I don't, I don't think it like, again, I don't think because I don't see
Speaker 5:  them making touch the primary interaction level, which would
Speaker 5:  mean that like you would design an app that runs in the app store so it can
Speaker 5:  be installed on Mac, iOS and iPad all at the same
Speaker 5:  time. It has to run through the app store to do that. Right. Right. That's
Speaker 5:  if the touch is the first primary interaction level. But if you're still
Speaker 5:  able to make Mac apps that use a keyboard and mouse and have
Speaker 5:  all their keyboard shortcuts, support and things like that, or keyboard and
Speaker 5:  track pad, what have you, as long as you're still able to do that and those
Speaker 5:  are still able to run because it's still Mac os they didn't, don't change
Speaker 5:  it that drastically then like you'll still be able to download apps
Speaker 5:  from websites and from, you know, stuff like that and run them already.
Speaker 5:  Right now that's kind of an annoying thing to do because you have to like
Speaker 5:  jump through a bunch of check boxes to get the thing to install. Yeah. But
Speaker 5:  I don't see how adding touch changes that, especially if touch
Speaker 5:  is not the primary interaction
Speaker 6:  Level. I I have one question for, for Dan that I, I wanna ask you, are
Speaker 6:  we glossing over the ole rumor? Like how, how big of a change would it be
Speaker 6:  to have ole screens on MacBook Pros from, from the screens that we have now?
Speaker 6:  The,
Speaker 5:  You know, it's, it's kinda interesting. We're gonna probably talk about the
Speaker 5:  micro L e d rumor later on in the show. But like many
Speaker 5:  micro, micro led micro led. Yes. Micro, micro, no
Speaker 4:  We say no micro L E d We're not saying micro led.
Speaker 4:  Absolutely not. Richard. No, do not nobody normalize
Speaker 4:  that. Everybody listening, you're not allowed to normalize that.
Speaker 5:  Please normalize it. Tweeta tweeta, Alex
Speaker 5:  recordings of you saying it.
Speaker 5:  So there's like the, in the span of like, or the, the progression of display
Speaker 5:  technology for computers, right? It's like L C D and then mini l
Speaker 5:  e d, which apple's already at with the MacBook Pro 14 and 16
Speaker 5:  and then O led and then micro L e D and O
Speaker 5:  would have, you know, slightly better blacks
Speaker 5:  than the current crop of mini L e d. But I gotta tell you the mini l
Speaker 5:  e d screens on the 14 and the 16 MacBook Pro look phenomenal. Like
Speaker 5:  I I, I don't know how much I would appreciate having olet instead of
Speaker 5:  them like maybe it would be a little bit more efficient. Maybe it'd be using
Speaker 5:  less power, I don't know. But they get way brighter than
Speaker 5:  any OD laptop I've ever seen and they get way brighter than most OED
Speaker 5:  screens that we're familiar with. So like if you go from mini l e D to od,
Speaker 5:  that's kind of like a small step in certain respects, but maybe a
Speaker 5:  sidestep in others. And then when you get to micro l e d that is
Speaker 5:  supposed to bring the, all the benefits of OD and all the benefits of mini
Speaker 5:  L e d without the drawbacks of either of them, the drawbacks of ole being,
Speaker 5:  the fact that it's organic and can have burn and can degrade
Speaker 5:  over time. And then mini l e d being not quite as
Speaker 5:  black blacks or high levels of contrast as ole
Speaker 5:  offers, but micro L e D is able to offer that. So like it's a stepping
Speaker 5:  towards it.
Speaker 4:  I I I feel like the ola you're like if you're, they're on,
Speaker 4:  they're on mini l e D right now, right? Yes. And then the plan is micro L
Speaker 4:  e d but primarily for watches first, even though that's like the weirdest
Speaker 4:  place to put it.
Speaker 5:  Well yeah, I mean if we wanna just jump to that report. I mean like the other
Speaker 5:  thing, there's been so many like Apple rumors this week. So the other thing
Speaker 5:  from No, no,
Speaker 4:  No, I wanna talk about my thing first. I wanna talk about my free thing first.
Speaker 4:  Everybody get excited? These rumors are coming. I told you this is a rumors
Speaker 4:  episode, we're all talking rumors. But I was just gonna say like it doesn't
Speaker 4:  make sense to go to O ad if you're at mini l e d because the reason that
Speaker 4:  O ad is so captivating on a TV is you don't get all that bloom
Speaker 4:  that you get with edge lighting or that you get with mini l
Speaker 4:  e d that's, that makes it like you get a lot of bloom in a 55
Speaker 4:  inch tv. You don't get a lot of bloom very often in
Speaker 4:  a high quality laptop display like you see in a Mac. So it doesn't make sense
Speaker 4:  to look like ola, I mean such a minor
Speaker 5:  Upgrade if you had a high quality OLA display and compared it side by side
Speaker 5:  though, you would notice like we can, we can see a difference between the
Speaker 5:  mini l e d in the pro display xcr,
Speaker 5:  which was like the first mini l e d kind of technology that Apple came out
Speaker 5:  with and then it went into the iPad Pro 12.9
Speaker 5:  and it got better in the iPad PRO 12.9 and then it went into
Speaker 5:  the MacBook Pro 14 and 16 and it did get noticeably better when you put them
Speaker 5:  them side by side, there's less blooming because there are more mini
Speaker 5:  LEDs in those laptops than there was on the iPad or
Speaker 5:  the pro display xdr,
Speaker 4:  Right?
Speaker 5:  Maybe if you put the Olet S next to a mini L E d, you would see that
Speaker 5:  kind of same step forward. Okay. Where it's like, okay, now now that blooming
Speaker 5:  I didn't notice before. Oh, I see it now. And I don't see it on
Speaker 5:  the od my thought is that the OD just won't get the same brightness,
Speaker 5:  it just won't hit the same levels of brightness.
Speaker 6:  Well I I think my, my question or my thought for the about why they might
Speaker 6:  do this, if we assume that all the rumors we've heard this week are true,
Speaker 6:  every single thing is going to come true. Exactly. Everything's
Speaker 4:  Gonna happen.
Speaker 5:  Nothing will change
Speaker 6:  That. That some micro l e d is coming from
Speaker 6:  Apple, that they're going to do OED laptops. That the reason why you would
Speaker 6:  have this design target for these 2025 macro pros as OED screens
Speaker 6:  is because you don't think that the micro l e d technology will be ready
Speaker 6:  for a laptop by then. Right? Right. And it may not be ready for several years
Speaker 6:  even after that. Even if they get it in the watch, it could take years to
Speaker 6:  scale up, but
Speaker 4:  It sounds like it's gonna be expensive. Right.
Speaker 5:  Right. So like then the question is do they stick with the mini l e D
Speaker 5:  for until micro l e d is ready in a laptop size?
Speaker 5:  Or do they do this kind of like half step forward with an OED before
Speaker 5:  going the full step to micro? I
Speaker 4:  Guess we did see a lot of ods at CES this year. We saw a lot of OD laptops.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, there's a ton of OD laptops on the market. Like there's,
Speaker 5:  Monica's reviewed a bunch of them. There's, they range in prices now.
Speaker 5:  You can get OED laptops running Windows for about a thousand dollars now.
Speaker 5:  And they do look really good, but they don't hit nearly the brightness of
Speaker 5:  the MacBook Crows like Right. They don't hit the, the regular everyday
Speaker 5:  brightness and they certainly don't hit the HDR brightness. So that's like
Speaker 5:  what mini l e d brings that ole as we've seen it so far,
Speaker 5:  does not. So in two years maybe Ole will have gotten
Speaker 5:  to a point, they, it gets a little bit brighter every year, right? Like the
Speaker 5:  TVs have gotten a little bit brighter every single year. Maybe they'll get
Speaker 5:  a little bit brighter enough to to, to get up to the point of where many
Speaker 5:  l e D is at.
Speaker 6:  The, the last thing that, that I wanted to get on on this particular thing
Speaker 6:  is that it's a turn from Apple. They, they've like, like we've said kind
Speaker 6:  of at the beginning, that they, they were not doing touchscreen laptops.
Speaker 6:  They said they wouldn't do touchscreen laptops now if they would, but
Speaker 6:  if you think about Apple, isn't it kind of, that's their thing is to say
Speaker 6:  that they won't do something and then they later say that they did it and
Speaker 6:  did it better than anyone else.
Speaker 5:  I mean that's, yeah, that's totally Apple's mo. I think what's interesting
Speaker 5:  about the touchscreen though is that it's taken so long for them to make
Speaker 5:  that turn like
Speaker 4:  10 years. 10 years
Speaker 5:  Or more. Even longer. Like even longer. It's probably closer to 15
Speaker 5:  years. And like
Speaker 4:  When Steve was saying absolutely not to touchscreen laptops
Speaker 4:  when he was alive and he'd passed away in what, 20,
Speaker 5:  11,009 or 2010 when they launched the iPad, right?
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  He never see this.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. His argument was that like your arm gets tired and it's
Speaker 5:  clumsy trying to use as touch and like that is true if touch is the only
Speaker 5:  way that you interact with it, but guess what, you also have a keyboard and
Speaker 5:  a track pad in front of it. So like, that's why I'm saying like touch is
Speaker 5:  like this third level of interaction. It's not your primary way of using
Speaker 5:  it. But you, we did see Apple, you know, Steve Jobs
Speaker 5:  also said that they would never do a stylist because it would be like, you
Speaker 5:  know, filing down your fingers or something like that. And lo and behold
Speaker 5:  the Apple pencil came out and the apple pencils really good and stuff like
Speaker 5:  that. So like, yes, Apple's done this. Like we will say it's bad or deny
Speaker 5:  it until it happens and then when we do it, it's the best thing ever. It's
Speaker 5:  just what's interesting is how long the Mac has gone without a touch
Speaker 5:  screen and how they've done these kind of like half steps, like the touch
Speaker 5:  bar that didn't really work or take off instead, instead of just doing the
Speaker 5:  thing that everybody wanted was just put a touchscreen on it.
Speaker 4:  All right. We gotta talk about the micro, we've talked about the many
Speaker 4:  LEDs. We've talked about the O LEDs. Oh, I called 'em O LEDs.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, that's right. We, we, we've talked about the touchscreens. We gotta
Speaker 4:  talk about the micro LEDs because those are only,
Speaker 4:  the rumor is that's only for the watch, right? Dan,
Speaker 4:  walk me through it. Walk us through it.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, so here's another, another report from Mark Ena Bloomberg.
Speaker 5:  But this one is backed by some other reporting that we, that Apple
Speaker 5:  is working on micro e d screens, which you've been talking about for a few
Speaker 5:  minutes. The report is that like the Apple is designing its own
Speaker 5:  displays that it would then work with manufacturers to build, as opposed
Speaker 5:  to buying already design displays off the shelf and integrating 'em in it's
Speaker 5:  products. And that it will start with
Speaker 5:  making these micro LED screens for the Apple watch, which is currently using
Speaker 5:  OED screens and has since launched. And so this would be like
Speaker 5:  kind of the first major screen technology shift for the Apple
Speaker 5:  Watch. And that is, it's also rumored around the timeline of 24 or
Speaker 5:  25. So we're a little bit ways out. And then once it's in the Apple watch,
Speaker 5:  maybe it would be in a high-end version, like whatever the version of the
Speaker 5:  ultra is at that year, it would show up in there. So it's a little bit lower
Speaker 5:  yield or smaller number of devices out there. And then as Apple
Speaker 5:  figures out, the manufacturing is able to bring the cost down, stuff like
Speaker 5:  that, it would trickled out to the phones and then the tablets and then eventually
Speaker 5:  probably the, the laptops and the desktop displays. So it's, it's like their
Speaker 5:  next level of display technology. Yeah, and I think as we've just
Speaker 5:  discussed, we can find a really great argument for micro l e d
Speaker 5:  in a tv, in a desktop display, in a laptop display. But
Speaker 5:  once you get down to a smaller handheld size device and once you get down
Speaker 5:  to an Apple watch, especially I I, it's hard for me
Speaker 5:  to see what micro l e d brings to that technology
Speaker 5:  because if you look at the ultra, the watch ultras screen right now, it's
Speaker 5:  bright, it's 2000 nets, it's got incredible viewing angles.
Speaker 5:  It's incredibly vibrant and color rich and it looks like it's
Speaker 5:  painted on the glass already. And all of those things are what Mark Irman
Speaker 5:  is saying, micro l e d brings. And it's like we already had that,
Speaker 4:  That was what, so Chris Welch wrote this really rarely great
Speaker 4:  explainer about the micro L e D watch and the two things he was like, so
Speaker 4:  here are like the big things. It's supposed to do better. It's supposed to
Speaker 4:  have better like, I guess power control because it's LEDs instead of
Speaker 4:  OLEDs and they won't burn, burn in, but they'll do basically the same kind
Speaker 4:  of power control but better somehow and it'll look like it's painted on
Speaker 4:  the screen. And I'm just What does that
Speaker 4:  mean?
Speaker 6:  Well, one of the things I wonder is that maybe the, the impulses a
Speaker 6:  if this is the screen size that they think they can make first also. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Something that I've heard people talk about with micro l e d and we've, we've
Speaker 6:  heard it being talked about to go in virtual reality and augment reality
Speaker 6:  headsets, that kind of tech technology, if you can make the screen a different
Speaker 6:  shape, if you can change maybe the bezel or something like that. If, if it
Speaker 6:  gives them some advantages there maybe that that's a reason for them to put
Speaker 6:  in the watch initially.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So it's like
Speaker 4:  There's,
Speaker 5:  There's probably things that I'm not aware of or not thinking of that
Speaker 5:  it does bring benefits, but at least as in the report that we have about
Speaker 5:  it in the article that Mark wrote and Bloomberg, he said it
Speaker 5:  does these things better color reproduction, better brightness,
Speaker 5:  and better viewing angles. And I'm like, none of those things are a problem
Speaker 5:  on the watch ultra. Like have you, like nobody's complained about any of
Speaker 5:  those things.
Speaker 4:  Dan, you've got an Apple watch. Richard, do you also have an Apple watch?
Speaker 4:  No, I do not. I assume, yeah. What what do you do? You have a smartwatch?
Speaker 6:  I I have a Fitbit somewhere that I I are you free? Yeah. I,
Speaker 6:  I'm untethered.
Speaker 4:  You're free. Oh my gosh. What's
Speaker 6:  That like? I don't know how long I've been standing or if or if I ever did.
Speaker 6:  Yeah,
Speaker 4:  I don't think you like never You just sat and float with
Speaker 4:  your computers all around you. Yes. Three
Speaker 6:  Laptops surrounded by screens.
Speaker 4:  That's newsfeed on all three of them. Yeah, but I've,
Speaker 4:  I don't think I've ever looked at my Apple watch and been like, man that
Speaker 4:  red just doesn't pop the way I wish it did with a micro l e d screen. Like
Speaker 4:  I, I do that with my TV all the time. Yeah. But not my watch.
Speaker 5:  Here's a optimist take, I'm full of them
Speaker 5:  today.
Speaker 4:  You are. You are just pro Apple today.
Speaker 5:  If you look at the Apple Watches user interface,
Speaker 4:  Okay.
Speaker 5:  The design of it is entirely in dark mode. It is designed
Speaker 5:  to take advantage of an OED screen. All the menus are black, all the backgrounds
Speaker 5:  are black. Many of the watch faces have black backgrounds, so on and so forth.
Speaker 5:  There's, I mean Apple's been adding more colorful ones over the years and
Speaker 5:  yes you can do a light watch face or whatever, but the interface that when
Speaker 5:  you jump into menus and stuff like that is all black and that all of that
Speaker 5:  is stemming from power management on the first Apple watches
Speaker 5:  that came out and they used OED screens and OED screens consume
Speaker 5:  less power with black backgrounds because they turn on fewer pixels or whatever.
Speaker 4:  Well they're just not on like those pixels are just off
Speaker 5:  If micro l e d they're just off so they're not using as much power. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  yeah. Or any power when they're off. If micro l e d is
Speaker 5:  able to allow Apple to have the same level of power consumption as
Speaker 5:  the ole and have more interface flexibility, maybe
Speaker 5:  we'll see a revamp of the Apple watches design UI design, which
Speaker 5:  we haven't seen in since basically since it came out.
Speaker 4:  But how does that
Speaker 5:  Work? Oh, maybe we'll see a refresh there. Because this technology allows
Speaker 5:  them to do more flexibility with what the interface looks like and what is
Speaker 5:  displayed on the screen without consuming more power. That could be a thing.
Speaker 4:  But how does it make it more flexible? I just don't
Speaker 5:  That's Well like you could have a white background instead of black,
Speaker 4:  But you're still gonna have the same power draw issues you'd have on an olet.
Speaker 4:  You just wouldn't have to worry about burning.
Speaker 5:  I mean not necessarily.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, because Bo, both micro LEDs and in in OLEDs there, they're whole,
Speaker 4:  the whole idea is that if it's black, that means there's just nothing on
Speaker 4:  Right. It's completely tho those pixels are turned off. So like
Speaker 4:  those power draw issues, I don't know. It's one of those things where one,
Speaker 4:  I'm like the micro l e D thing just doesn't make that much sense. It seems
Speaker 4:  like a weird hill for, for the design wonks that Apple to die
Speaker 4:  on to be like, yes, we're going to pivot so many resources
Speaker 4:  towards a micro L e D screen, the smallest we can make
Speaker 4:  on our wrist instead of these other places where there's genuine use case.
Speaker 4:  Especially well now hold on, hold on. Especially
Speaker 4:  when E Ink exists and has even less power draw.
Speaker 5:  You
Speaker 6:  Walked
Speaker 4:  Right into that one. It's not like you're out here. Yeah, y'all were like,
Speaker 4:  you thought you were getting away with it. Have you
Speaker 5:  Seen ink? I mean come on Alex.
Speaker 4:  Gallery three's
Speaker 5:  Coming. You know what Pebble used Ein? Where's Pebble
Speaker 6:  Today? A legend.
Speaker 4:  It wasn't EIN's fault. Pebble's love
Speaker 5:  The pessimist take on this is that Apple is doing this transition
Speaker 5:  and move to get away from having to rely
Speaker 5:  on other companies as much. It can design its own screens and design its
Speaker 5:  own things and design its own margins and et cetera, et cetera. So it's not
Speaker 5:  relying on LG display or Samsung display or Sharp or whoever's, you know,
Speaker 5:  making and designing the screens. That is probably
Speaker 5:  what's driving a lot of this. Unless the technology, which we haven't seen,
Speaker 5:  cuz admittedly I've never seen a micro l e d screen in person. They are only
Speaker 5:  available on like $800,000 TVs that you only get to see if you go to
Speaker 5:  ces. And I didn't go to ces. So exactly
Speaker 4:  The wall, the Samsung wall really
Speaker 6:  Cool. I've, I've seen the Samsung wall, it looked
Speaker 5:  Fun, but like we've never seen it on a phone size device. We'd never seen
Speaker 5:  it on a watch size device. We've never seen it on a laptop size device. We
Speaker 5:  don't, we don't really know how much better it could look in those use
Speaker 5:  cases. So if un unless like if, if it
Speaker 5:  turns out that it's not that much different than OED that we have or the
Speaker 5:  mini l e d that we have, then this reads to me more like a business move
Speaker 5:  in that it allows Apple more control over its pipeline and more control over
Speaker 5:  the profit margins and things like that. It's probably the reality is going
Speaker 5:  to land somewhere in the middle, right? There's, it's going to bring some
Speaker 5:  better technology, better user experience and better display
Speaker 5:  technology to the devices that makes using them easier or better
Speaker 5:  or more enjoyable. But it will also help Apple's business
Speaker 5:  case.
Speaker 6:  Hmm. We can settle this easily. We, we can just call our good personal friend
Speaker 6:  Dan Cook. He's got one of the like three the wall displays that have ever
Speaker 6:  been installed and we'll, we'll sit down and watch some stuff and figure
Speaker 6:  out what's good for Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Do we have, do we have
Speaker 4:  To talk to him? Richard? I I would watch you ideally know hang out with
Speaker 4:  Dane Cook. What would you guys talk about? You're just
Speaker 4:  on your phone the whole time. Just like I I don't wanna talk to you or look
Speaker 4:  at the wall. I'm just here because my bosses told me to come.
Speaker 4:  All right. Right. We're gonna take a break and when we come back we're gonna
Speaker 4:  talk more rumors this time, not Apple. We're gonna talk about some Samsung
Speaker 4:  rumors. Big event coming up. Stay tuned
Speaker 4:  and we're back. Dan, I feel like you, you are on rumor
Speaker 4:  patrol today. You are Fleetwood Mac. What's going on with Samsung?
Speaker 4:  That was a big, that was a big claim. You've got a lot to live up to. You're
Speaker 4:  Fleetwood Mac
Speaker 5:  Now. Not a rumor. This is actual real news. They are
Speaker 5:  having an event on February 1st. It is the first Samsung event of the year
Speaker 5:  and we're expecting to see the next generation of the Galaxy S line, which
Speaker 5:  would be the S 23. This is a little bit earlier than Samsung usually has
Speaker 5:  an event. Typically we see it later in February closer to when
Speaker 5:  MWC happens
Speaker 4:  Because they do like Mobile World Congress.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. They usually try to beat MWC by like a week or two, but now they're
Speaker 5:  beating it by like a whole month. And it feels like it's coming up really
Speaker 5:  fast after CES for all of us. Such as kind of slogged through Cs, but whatever.
Speaker 5:  It's happening February 1st and today actually
Speaker 5:  we got rumors that of the first like images of the
Speaker 5:  S 23 that we've really seen in terms of renders have leaked and you know,
Speaker 5:  they look like phones.
Speaker 5:  What can we say
Speaker 4:  That? Sure. Is there a phone? The
Speaker 5:  Thing, the thing with the S 23 launch is that like, this is not like the,
Speaker 5:  the, the area that Samsung really like pushes boundaries, right? That happens
Speaker 5:  with the folding phones later in the year. This is like the mainstream galaxy
Speaker 5:  phones that most people, at least here in the US if you're buying an Android
Speaker 5:  phone, you're probably buying a Galaxy S phone. And this is like when
Speaker 5:  the, these look
Speaker 4:  Like iPhones,
Speaker 5:  They look well they, I mean they look like Galaxy S phones. They really haven't
Speaker 5:  changed the design on these front of a couple
Speaker 4:  Years. These photos? No, the camera modules. Yes.
Speaker 5:  So
Speaker 4:  It looks like the camera modules look Samsung, but everything else looks,
Speaker 4:  it
Speaker 5:  Looks like they've iPhone eliminated the camera bump, which would be a change
Speaker 5:  in that. Like it's slightly thinner now. It's not as wobbly when you put
Speaker 5:  it on a table and things like that. But these are slab smartphones. That's
Speaker 5:  not a bump. They're not like breaking the, the mold here with what this
Speaker 5:  design looks like and stuff like that. You can expect it to have the latest
Speaker 5:  Qualcomm chip inside of it. That's a pretty much a given. It will probably
Speaker 5:  have upgraded cameras, it might have a slightly better, slightly brighter
Speaker 5:  display. It's likely that there will be the S 23, the S 23
Speaker 5:  plus the S 23 ultra, just like the S 22 models that preceded it.
Speaker 5:  And so, you know, there will be the S 23 ultra
Speaker 5:  would be the top of the line that's probably gonna have a stylist and the
Speaker 5:  most cameras and the latest technology and stuff like that. And then the
Speaker 5:  other models will have some features stripped out or just smaller size screens.
Speaker 6:  Can we expect a sprint exclusive Galaxy S 23 Epic
Speaker 6:  to 5G with a hardware keyboard? Is that, is that likely that Sprint
Speaker 5:  Yes. Still existed? I'm sure you could have
Speaker 4:  Where's gonna be our Army green one with like the plastic case
Speaker 4:  so that you can check it outta your car, it'll survive. That's always my
Speaker 4:  favorite like variation on the s the Galaxy
Speaker 5:  S six. Yeah, they haven't done like the, the active models in a couple of
Speaker 5:  years. I don't think. Those were always like the ones that like were super
Speaker 5:  chunky and rugged and could like take a beating, but they, it's been a while
Speaker 5:  since I've seen one of those release. They should just do that with the regular
Speaker 5:  line. Just make it more rugged. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  Just gimme some chunky phones. Yeah. But like the thing that's really throwing
Speaker 4:  me on looking at these renders is the wallpaper on these things just looks
Speaker 4:  ripped straight from Apple a couple of years ago when they first did the
Speaker 4:  notch and they tried to hide the notch, you know, by the, by doing like all
Speaker 4:  the color but curved on one side, just barely missing the notch. All of these
Speaker 4:  have the exact same wallpaper.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I mean I would say that's not a new move for Samsung. When they first
Speaker 5:  launched phones with the whole punch camera, they did the same thing with
Speaker 5:  their, their wallpaper. They, they like hit it. It just like with the way
Speaker 5:  the wallpaper promo wallpaper worked.
Speaker 4:  That's wild. Do you think is, is this one gonna have a notch or is it gonna
Speaker 4:  be a hole punch?
Speaker 5:  Oh, it's almost definitely a hole punch based on these rumors or based on
Speaker 5:  these images.
Speaker 4:  It is just the most iPhone looking Samsung device I've seen
Speaker 4:  in a very long time. Like they usually don't ape Apple
Speaker 4:  to this extent. And this looks real iPhoney.
Speaker 5:  Well if you look at the S 22 and the S 21 before it, it kind of had
Speaker 5:  some more distinctive like design traits around, especially particularly
Speaker 5:  around the camera. Like you had that like metal housing that like bent
Speaker 5:  into the metal frame of the phone and stuff like that. And that was kind
Speaker 5:  of pretty distinctive design tree. And now it's like
Speaker 5:  they seem to be removing that. They seem to be going with, it's hard to tell
Speaker 5:  exactly, but maybe the sides are a little bit more square, which is giving
Speaker 5:  you that iPhone as type of look to the modern iPhones and stuff like that.
Speaker 5:  The can, the back is very plain. It's just three, three holes.
Speaker 5:  There's no like adornment to it and things like that. So I,
Speaker 4:  What's seven?
Speaker 5:  I don't know. I mean like obviously we have not seen these things in person.
Speaker 5:  We are working off of like the very first kind of image leaks that we've
Speaker 5:  seen so far. But yeah, I'm with you that like these aren't super exciting
Speaker 5:  looking,
Speaker 6:  Perhaps they just don't care anymore. Look, you've got how many engineers
Speaker 6:  devoted to making the Galaxy folks hinge work in the screen?
Speaker 6:  Notre. So
Speaker 4:  Just the guy being like, oh yes, I
Speaker 5:  I I
Speaker 6:  Have a feeling they don't have that much time.
Speaker 5:  We sell way more S 20 threes or
Speaker 6:  S and also everyone else's phones look like this too. So maybe you're not
Speaker 6:  so worried about saying, oh, we're copying Apple. You say look at a phone.
Speaker 6:  It is what phones, this is what phones look like.
Speaker 5:  Yes. For better or worse,
Speaker 4:  Do you think this is gonna be the year? Samsung's just like, thems are phones.
Speaker 4:  Here's your phones. Take 'em. All right, see you next year. Like do you think
Speaker 4:  they're gonna put a lot of effort into
Speaker 5:  The Sun Pack? That's not Sam Sex. Yes. Well, so the, oh I, I didn't
Speaker 5:  even mention this is their first in-person unpacked event in like three years.
Speaker 5:  I think they're gonna go all out. I think they're like the last
Speaker 4:  Big speech.
Speaker 5:  I don't remember the last in-person unpacked event. I went to
Speaker 5:  myself but up until the pandemic they were like
Speaker 5:  doing these like really tech-heavy
Speaker 5:  presentations. Like the
Speaker 4:  Super elaborate
Speaker 5:  Oh super elaborate. They had like stages with screens underneath the presenters
Speaker 5:  and curved up behind them and all of like orchestral music and everything
Speaker 5:  was like this big production and stuff like that. And I think they might
Speaker 5:  be really excited to go do that again cuz they haven't been able to really
Speaker 5:  do that because you don't really get that same impression through a virtual
Speaker 5:  presentation.
Speaker 4:  So we're gonna get something besides these phones then, right? Because it's
Speaker 4:  gonna be really sad if they're like, look at this incredible stage and here's
Speaker 4:  the phone. Richard said we don't really care about an he's correct
Speaker 4:  enjoy. Like they can't, there's gonna be other cool stuff they're gonna have
Speaker 4:  at it. Like head we, there were some headphone rumors this week, right? Did
Speaker 4:  I read that right?
Speaker 5:  Well they've, they've released a new feature for the existing Galaxy Buds
Speaker 5:  two Pro, which just came out last August. So you can now record 3D
Speaker 5:  audio with them. So that's kind of cool. I don't know, I haven't
Speaker 5:  seen any rumors for headphones and I haven't seen any rumors for wearables.
Speaker 5:  Samsung had a really big fall for wearables.
Speaker 5:  They launched the Galaxy Watch five, they will launch the Watch five Pro
Speaker 5:  and they've been pretty well received and pretty popular. So I'd be surprised
Speaker 5:  if we see any wearables that's not typically happen at, at this year's or
Speaker 5:  this time of year event. It's really, they focus on the S line because the
Speaker 5:  S line is their moneymaker.
Speaker 4:  Okay. And no, no note the note's dead, right?
Speaker 5:  No, the s the S 22 essentially embodied the note last
Speaker 5:  year and it's pretty reasonable to expect that the S 23
Speaker 5:  Ultra will embody the note. It'll have the stylus and
Speaker 5:  the more squared off design that works well with the stylus for running
Speaker 4:  On the screen. Well it's coming February 1st. You guys get excited. We'll
Speaker 4:  absolutely have, we'll probably see more rumors not far away before then.
Speaker 4:  We'll, we'll have a big breakdown of it beforehand. It's gonna be great.
Speaker 4:  Richard. There's also, there was some news with H B O Max. There's a
Speaker 4:  bunch of news this this week I feel like for H B O Max, the Minx. This was,
Speaker 4:  this is something I personally was very excited about, Minx was the show
Speaker 4:  that nobody watched. Look at your faces. You've ne do you even know what
Speaker 5:  Minx is? I watched Minx. I thought they canceled it.
Speaker 4:  They did. They canceled it.
Speaker 6:  HBO o I only heard of it when you said that they canceled it.
Speaker 4:  You're like, oh bummer. But so Minx was this show about
Speaker 4:  like seventies Feminist Porno Magazine. It was on H B O max.
Speaker 4:  It got canceled. Stars has now picked it up Oh. And
Speaker 4:  is gonna be airing the second season cuz they filmed a whole second season
Speaker 4:  and then H B o Max was like, no, we don't wanna pay for it. Take it. We don't
Speaker 4:  want it. And so it's going on Stars, which happens to be owned by
Speaker 4:  Legendary, which also produced banks. But it's like, it's good, it's kind
Speaker 4:  of good news cuz we had so many weeks of stuff getting canceled and just
Speaker 4:  disappearing and getting yanked from the service. So it's nice to know that
Speaker 4:  some of this stuff is gonna find a home. I hope. I really wanna see what
Speaker 4:  happens in that back half of the nevers.
Speaker 6:  And meanwhile on HBO Max where you're getting less than you used to get,
Speaker 6:  you will now be paying more on, at least on the app pre-plan. It's
Speaker 6:  getting $1 more expensive effective today if you're a new subscriber, I think
Speaker 6:  kicking in like next month, if you already subscribed
Speaker 6:  15 99 0
Speaker 5:  Warning, how much more will I have to pay to mooch my father-in-law's
Speaker 5:  cable account that gives me access to H B O Max? Well
Speaker 6:  You you've seen it with Netflix. It starts with with price hikes all the
Speaker 6:  time. And then suddenly they're like, you know what? We're not so into password
Speaker 6:  sharing.
Speaker 5:  Yeah,
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It's gonna be a sad
Speaker 6:  Day. Like, so, so I think you're gonna see kind of all, all the streamers
Speaker 6:  go down the same path. And that's something that Emma Roth wrote, wrote about
Speaker 6:  recently about why streaming all of these plans is getting more expensive.
Speaker 6:  We, we know that Netflix has had price hikes every year,
Speaker 4:  Right?
Speaker 6:  Just about for several years now.
Speaker 5:  Apple TV raised its price a month or two ago. Yep.
Speaker 6:  The price of Disney Plus is going up now there's, they're bringing in ad
Speaker 6:  packages. HBO already had the a, the ad package so
Speaker 6:  that you kind of had that option. But they started at 15 bucks essentially
Speaker 6:  two years ago, you know, years ago now we, or almost three years ago. Wow.
Speaker 6:  2020.
Speaker 4:  Woo.
Speaker 6:  It has been a pandemic, but they, they had not raised the price, but
Speaker 6:  they started high at that, at that time it was a, it was a bit more expensive
Speaker 6:  than, than Netflix and everything else because, because it was hbo o but
Speaker 6:  now HBO Max is the, the primary HBO o and, and
Speaker 6:  I don't know, I'm, I'm not sure how people feel about this. I feel like if
Speaker 6:  if you were enjoying paying for HBO Max, you're not necessarily worried about
Speaker 6:  it at a dollar more, but you might miss some of the content that they've
Speaker 6:  pulled. And I, I wonder how it's gonna go when they, when they blend together
Speaker 6:  the HBO O max and discovery apps
Speaker 5:  And, and
Speaker 4:  Then this is just, this is just the ad free version
Speaker 4:  of HBO O max. Yes. Which is, which was historically the
Speaker 4:  same price as what you would pay to subscribe to HBO Max. Right.
Speaker 4:  Through your cable network. But nobody has cable anymore except for Dan's
Speaker 4:  father-in-law. So
Speaker 5:  I hope he never cuts the cord.
Speaker 6:  It, it's, it's just me. I'm, I'm the only person who still has
Speaker 4:  Cable. Those people are still gonna be paying $15 a month. The rest of us
Speaker 4:  are gonna be paying $16 a month.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And
Speaker 4:  So everybody,
Speaker 5:  I don't, I mean, like, to Rich's point, I don't think that's a trick. This
Speaker 5:  is not the price hike that causes people to cancel. Yeah. But it
Speaker 5:  is just telling of like where this is going. So like then like in a couple
Speaker 5:  years, it eventually it'll be another $2 price hike or whatever. They're
Speaker 5:  going to get to that $20 price point where Netflix is already at for its
Speaker 5:  4K plan. And then you combine that with they
Speaker 5:  are removing things, they're removing old shows, they are removing
Speaker 5:  canceling new shows and stuff like that. And now it's just like, I don't
Speaker 5:  know. It, it ain't great. I
Speaker 4:  Mean, you know, if, if if, if, if my best friend David
Speaker 4:  Zaslav was here with us today, he would say, well look, we, we added
Speaker 4:  Fixer Upper, we added some other TLC shows that only
Speaker 4:  my mom and my sister watch. I love you both, but you have trash taste in
Speaker 4:  TV and film and you're not listening to this cuz you have trash taste. So
Speaker 4:  you're not even listening to the best show on, on, on podcast networks ever.
Speaker 4:  Rude. But like, like they, they have
Speaker 4:  added stuff. They've pulled a lot out. They pulled a lot out that we, that
Speaker 4:  most of us can considered kind of core H B O stuff.
Speaker 4:  Really high quality cartoons, really high quality TV shows. They pulled that
Speaker 4:  Westworld, I think is probably the most notable example of a show that just
Speaker 4:  got like, just gone like, oh, you didn't catch up on season
Speaker 4:  four.
Speaker 6:  I I, I was shocked. Like I knew that they had pulled it, it, but when I actually
Speaker 6:  went to HBO O Max and I searched for it and it wasn't there, I I I just,
Speaker 6:  I didn't even know how to feel.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, you're just
Speaker 5:  Like, I mean
Speaker 6:  Honestly didn't watch and I haven't watched since the first season. So it
Speaker 6:  was, it was a vest.
Speaker 5:  I mean I, I think that was in the interest of
Speaker 5:  public health to remove Westworld and so nobody
Speaker 5:  fell down that, that rabbit hole of watching Westworld.
Speaker 4:  The, like this is the only reason Eli is, that's actually probably what NEI
Speaker 4:  is doing. He found some old copies of Westworld. Somebody, somebody sent
Speaker 4:  him some, that's where he is right now, furiously watching that season
Speaker 4:  four. He's the only one. It was just him and David Zaslav who then
Speaker 4:  said absolutely not kill it, kick it off the network. But
Speaker 4:  yeah, I'm like, I think he, Zov would say we we're adding a bunch of content,
Speaker 4:  we're gonna be adding more with this, with this new
Speaker 4:  product that they haven't, that may be called Max just
Speaker 4:  Simply Max, which is a terrible name, great name for a kid,
Speaker 4:  terrible name for a streaming network. And my question
Speaker 4:  is, are they gonna increase the price again? Are we gonna see Max rollout
Speaker 4:  in six months and then have to pay even more money?
Speaker 5:  No, I don't, I don't think they'll increase it in six months. When, when,
Speaker 5:  when they roll out Max, they'll keep the price the same and they will say,
Speaker 6:  And that's why they raised it now. Like that's,
Speaker 5:  That's the reason. Yeah. They raise it now. So, so they, they will be able
Speaker 5:  to keep it the same and then a year later, six months after that or whatever,
Speaker 5:  okay, then you'll, you'll get the price hike for that and then they'll, it's
Speaker 5:  just like a a, a frog in boiling water. It's, they just keep little turning
Speaker 5:  up the heat over time and then you just keep paying it until you realize
Speaker 5:  like, wait a minute, Netflix isn't worth $20 a month and you cancel it like
Speaker 5:  I do.
Speaker 4:  I mean I still pay for all of them. I have no money
Speaker 4:  for anything. Someone helped me figure out how to budget. Can't
Speaker 4:  pay my rent. But I can pay for HBO Max, but I won't pay for Max. I
Speaker 6:  Told you about cryptocurrency.
Speaker 4:  Richard. Richard, no, I I can't lose any more money to you, sir.
Speaker 4:  I have to, I have to like, I have to have a retirement at some point. Living
Speaker 4:  in your house. The, I guess the other kind of
Speaker 4:  news for me that was really surprising this week was John Deere
Speaker 4:  saying, we're gonna allow you to repair tractors, which is
Speaker 4:  a big moment for Right to repair advocates. I mean, nobody here
Speaker 4:  has a tractor to my knowledge. Unclear. Dan, you do you have a tractor?
Speaker 5:  No,
Speaker 4:  Richard, Richard lost his tractor in the cryptocurrency.
Speaker 6:  It was unfortunate I took some lost on Ethereum.
Speaker 5:  Stop. Yeah, I mean, to be fair, these, these, these we're talking about like
Speaker 5:  tractors, commercial level tractors.
Speaker 4:  No, no, no. We're talking about
Speaker 6:  Stuff like that. No, there's, you
Speaker 4:  Gotta move that hay. You gotta, you gotta feed the
Speaker 6:  Cows. Not that far from where I live. They have a John Deere like facility
Speaker 6:  where you can see these huge tractors and combines driving around on the
Speaker 6:  streets all the time. It's, it's a amazing, like seeing them in person
Speaker 6:  is really isn't so inspiring. It's just like, I can't believe something is
Speaker 6:  that big.
Speaker 4:  They're fun to sit in.
Speaker 5:  So is it, isn't there a huge catch with this John Deere news though? Yes.
Speaker 6:  It's been kind of a flashpoint over the last few years in, in the Right to
Speaker 6:  repair thing because farmers have a lot of kind of cultural
Speaker 6:  cache, political economic importance, you know, to to everything
Speaker 6:  that we do. And they've been saying that we have a problem. The trucks,
Speaker 6:  the, the tractors and, and all of this farm equipment is getting more technology
Speaker 6:  based. They have to repair things on the farm. They're, they're not near
Speaker 6:  some, like they can't go to the Apple store when, when their tractor breaks
Speaker 6:  down. Right. If they wanna fix apart, if they need to make, if they need
Speaker 6:  to tweak something because it's not working for, for what they're doing,
Speaker 6:  they wanna be able to do it. They wanna be able to get in there. Some, some
Speaker 6:  of these people who are on farms have computer experience are, you know,
Speaker 6:  kind of hacking them and doing their own thing. Making them run doom if they
Speaker 6:  want to. Yeah. And John Deere doesn't like that or hasn't liked that
Speaker 6:  and, and has pushed back. But now, yes, with, with this agreement,
Speaker 6:  they sort of said that farmers should be able to repair
Speaker 6:  their own tractors, but there are some loopholes that kind of allow them
Speaker 6:  to get out of this deal if they want to. So, so it's not because it
Speaker 4:  Wasn't with the government, it's with this agreement isn't with the government,
Speaker 4:  it's just with like a group of, it is like an organized group of very
Speaker 4:  passionate farmers. Also, if you call those organized groups where they all
Speaker 4:  collectively come together to make bargaining agreements and stuff. A union
Speaker 4:  don't, doesn't go Well I did it one time,
Speaker 4:  do not recommend, but, but this was with the what? The
Speaker 4:  American
Speaker 6:  American Farm Bureau Federation.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, the American Farm, bureau of Federation, not a federal organization,
Speaker 4:  just a group closely tied with the federal government, closely tied with
Speaker 4:  farmers, technically an independent group as far as I know. And, and they
Speaker 4:  just, they, they, the agreement was, yeah, we agree to let you
Speaker 4:  do it up until a point. And also we reserve the right to
Speaker 4:  rescind it at any point, if any right. To repair law at the
Speaker 4:  state or federal level comes out that we don't like. Yeah. So basically
Speaker 4:  do it our way or
Speaker 6:  Else they've turned this group in into an ally for them and
Speaker 6:  an enemy against people trying to pass these right to repair laws potentially.
Speaker 6:  And
Speaker 5:  You might remember New York just passed a right to repair law the end
Speaker 5:  of this year, which is like pretty groundbreaking and, and, and was a
Speaker 5:  new level for it. However, at the last minute, just before it went live,
Speaker 5:  there was a huge change to it that, you know, it doesn't apply to
Speaker 5:  farm equipment and it doesn't kind of apply to the things that people want
Speaker 5:  from John, from John Deere. So, so that already is on the books,
Speaker 5:  but I guess John Deere's happy with that one. And I guess if one came out
Speaker 5:  where it did apply to their equipment, then they would say, all right, well
Speaker 5:  we're, we're out of this agreement.
Speaker 4:  Now it gives me, it gives me the wikis,
Speaker 5:  But I mean, if it's a law, they're forced to comply. So like whatever, right?
Speaker 5:  Like if, if a law comes out, they have to comply, right?
Speaker 4:  But right now they basically are pitting, they're basically saying, okay,
Speaker 4:  farmers, you can either put your weight behind this law and
Speaker 4:  get your right to your little fancy right to repair laws that you think will
Speaker 4:  solve everything passed. Or you can join with us
Speaker 4:  and we'll let you do most of what you want without having to worry about
Speaker 4:  laws, without having to worry about going and talk, writing your congressman.
Speaker 4:  That's so boring. Just work with us. Like it's a very
Speaker 4:  seductive routine going on here. Not a romantically
Speaker 4:  seductive. Just seductive.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I don't, I
Speaker 4:  Don't trust them. No, don't trust them. This always, always makes me think
Speaker 4:  of like how 1930s people were getting very,
Speaker 4:  I'm going back in time, y'all, I'm sorry. 1930s people were getting super
Speaker 4:  upset about film. They felt there was, there was too much titillation in
Speaker 4:  film. They felt too much was happening. So they said, we're gonna start passing
Speaker 4:  a bunch of censorship laws to censor how films and TV are being made, or
Speaker 4:  TV didn't exist, how films are being made. And all of the, the film companies
Speaker 4:  got together and said, no, we're gonna figure our own thing out with absolutely
Speaker 4:  no oversight from the government. Theoretically. Good thing that then created
Speaker 4:  the Hayes code, which is made by like this guy who was like a
Speaker 4:  preacher and had very strong feelings and a lot of them were really racist
Speaker 4:  and sexist and homophobic. And then they made the MP a,
Speaker 4:  which has continued in, perpetuated a lot of that racist and sexist at
Speaker 4:  homophobic stuff when like maybe just some little regulation
Speaker 4:  of like, Hey, if it's got certain titillating things going on,
Speaker 4:  maybe reconsider having kids go and see that without permission from their
Speaker 5:  Parents. A similar thing happened with, with music too.
Speaker 4:  I don't know, maybe, am I calling for more regulation? A similar thing. I
Speaker 4:  feel like I'm calling for sensitive regulation ever. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Politically, this is, it's a industry trying to come up with
Speaker 5:  to a self-regulation to prevent government interference for sure. Because
Speaker 5:  government interference might do things that they don't agree or like,
Speaker 5:  and sometimes it's been effective and sometimes it works. I don't know how
Speaker 5:  effective parental advisory stickers were when I was a kid, cause that just
Speaker 5:  made me want to buy it more. But you know. Ooh, when
Speaker 4:  You say that Emma on there, you're like, I need that. That's the am I allowed
Speaker 4:  to have it? I don't care. That's the one I want. Yeah. I just murdered
Speaker 4:  so many people. I'm now I have nightmares, but, all right,
Speaker 4:  well, we're gonna take a break for a second. It's got really dark. We're
Speaker 4:  gonna say, okay. I know it got really dark. Somebody say something funny
Speaker 4:  quick. No, no. Funny. All right. Okay. I love those, those mature
Speaker 4:  rated games, but we should probably move on. So we're gonna take a break
Speaker 4:  and when we come back, we're gonna try to have a lightning round. Some really
Speaker 4:  fun gadgets this week. Did I select all the gadgets this week? You
Speaker 4:  be the judge.
Speaker 5:  I, I wonder how you'll be able to tell.
Speaker 4:  All right, we'll be back.
Speaker 8:  Support for our show comes from click up. One key to managing a productive
Speaker 8:  team is efficiency and also great office snacks, but mostly
Speaker 8:  efficiency. And whether you're leading a group of 10 or 110,
Speaker 8:  it's important to get the most out of every hour in the workday. That's where
Speaker 8:  Click Up can help. Click up is a productivity platform designed to save you
Speaker 8:  a full day every week. That means more time for clients, for meetings,
Speaker 8:  and for eating great office snacks, basically all of the important stuff.
Speaker 8:  Here's how it works. Click up houses, all of your projects, docs, goals,
Speaker 8:  spreadsheets, and anything else you need for work all in one place. Forget
Speaker 8:  wasting precious times. Switching from app to app or using a multitude
Speaker 8:  of tools to finish a single task. Click up Redefines Productivity by collecting
Speaker 8:  all of your mission critical tools into one fully customizable app.
Speaker 8:  Work the way you work best with Click Up. You can help your team of 10
Speaker 8:  plus be more efficient and productive with Click Up. Use Code Verge
Speaker 8:  to get 15% off click ups, massive unlimited plan for a year,
Speaker 8:  meaning you can start reclaiming your time for under $5 a month. You can
Speaker 8:  sign up today@clickup.com and use Code Verge. Take your
Speaker 8:  productivity to the next level with click up today
Speaker 4:  And we're back. I think the thing I really wanna talk about
Speaker 4:  was somebody over last week sent me a video
Speaker 4:  of a guy wearing glasses that had E ink built into it. And I got so
Speaker 4:  mad. I was furious. And then Sheena today saw the exact same video
Speaker 4:  in her own like work throughout the day and was like, I have to blog
Speaker 4:  about this with the exact same amount of fury I had. And it was a
Speaker 4:  beautiful, beautiful moment. So thank you Sheena for that. But these things
Speaker 4:  are called, hold on. This is from a startup called Soul
Speaker 4:  Reader. It's an, they, they're claiming it's gonna be about
Speaker 4:  $350. They're working with Palmer Lucky who, who made the, the
Speaker 4:  ocu who founded Oculus and then went off to do a bunch of like,
Speaker 4:  he's like in satellites now or something, right? Like he's, he was making,
Speaker 4:  he's in government surveillance. Yeah, he's building like weapons and surveillance
Speaker 4:  systems and stuff, but I guess he took a break from building weapons and
Speaker 4:  surveillance systems to work with this company called Soul Reader on these
Speaker 4:  $350 E Ink glasses.
Speaker 4:  They're just a hands-free display, but instead of like a
Speaker 4:  color display in there, it's E ink. Totally opaque e
Speaker 4:  ink. Okay. I don't understand why it exists,
Speaker 4:  but I'm really like, like part of me is delighted by it.
Speaker 4:  Cause I want new uses of E ink, but the other part of me is horrified by
Speaker 4:  it because who needs this? What
Speaker 5:  Does this delight you as much as BMW's car that's covered in ein
Speaker 5:  panels?
Speaker 4:  No, because that's cool. I want a car that has color chaining panels
Speaker 4:  on it. I wanna like go through a tunnel and come out the other side and be
Speaker 4:  like, ah, I'm a whole new person. It's red now. That's neat. This is like,
Speaker 4:  I wanna put some glasses on and I guess just hang out
Speaker 4:  and, and read that way. I think there, there's probably definitely a use
Speaker 4:  case for people who don't have as much mobility, but I'm
Speaker 4:  still a little confused by their existence
Speaker 6:  As a person who spent an ungodly amount of money to buy an item in a video
Speaker 6:  game that doesn't make me any better at the game. And, and then bought a
Speaker 6:  version of that in real life to represent the useless item in the game that
Speaker 6:  is also useless in real life.
Speaker 6:  I think the problem with this is that it's a little too useful. It's too
Speaker 6:  close to being useful. Like, like you said, like they're, they're kind of
Speaker 6:  use cases for it, but still it's, it's glasses that you would put
Speaker 6:  on to read something and you'd pay $350 for
Speaker 6:  that experience. And then the only thing you would be able to do is read
Speaker 6:  something,
Speaker 4:  Right?
Speaker 6:  First of all, words are evil and bad and written. The written word
Speaker 6:  shouldn't exist.
Speaker 6:  Second, rich. Rich,
Speaker 5:  Do you, you know what your job is,
Speaker 9:  My dude.
Speaker 5:  Do you know what we do here?
Speaker 6:  Look
Speaker 4:  What you do. Richard does something very different
Speaker 6:  The, with the way I do it
Speaker 9:  Just
Speaker 5:  With, with such utter hate and distaste for each word that comes out of
Speaker 5:  the keyboard,
Speaker 6:  Ev every day
Speaker 4:  Just mercilessly killing all that copy
Speaker 6:  Re regretfully. But I, I, I certainly wouldn't want just the
Speaker 6:  written word to be my entire experience and interaction with the world. It
Speaker 6:  just, I, I just can't do it. And, and, and I can see how it's useful that
Speaker 6:  that's, I think that's the problem is that it's too close to being something
Speaker 6:  that's u useful. If it were completely useless, I'd be into it.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Do you guys remember a few years ago there was a trend of gadgets that
Speaker 5:  were like visors that you put on that were like video screens
Speaker 5:  and they had headphones attached? Yes. And it was supposed to be like this
Speaker 5:  like personal theater experience. I think de had
Speaker 5:  reviewed one. They're
Speaker 6:  Still getting promoted on YouTube. Like, like people still see them. We,
Speaker 6:  we,
Speaker 9:  It
Speaker 5:  That's like what this is except for reading.
Speaker 4:  It's an Instagram commercial. Yeah. So you can read all of
Speaker 5:  Your stuff. I I have never seen anyone outside of ces. See
Speaker 6:  It was that la See, was that last word that you said that that was I was
Speaker 6:  into it until you said reading.
Speaker 4:  I said nope. It did video. Richard might be into it, but otherwise, nope.
Speaker 4:  All right. Richard, what, what's your, what's your gadget of the week? What's,
Speaker 4:  what's, what's got you excited?
Speaker 6:  Chris person brought the Pine seal into everyone's life.
Speaker 4:  He did. People got excited in, in at the Verge
Speaker 6:  About this. I, I don't fully understand what it is. And, and again, that
Speaker 6:  is the key to making it interesting is it's $25. It plugs into U S b. I don't
Speaker 6:  know what it does, but I want one, I need it right now.
Speaker 9:  So
Speaker 9:  Richard read the first line of the article
Speaker 5:  And then just stopped Cause words bad.
Speaker 9:  Yeah, so he doesn't know what it does, but he got his 25 bucks,
Speaker 4:  He's got four of them now.
Speaker 6:  I'm just saying it's a better way to live.
Speaker 4:  So the pine cell is a soldering iron and you can dial in
Speaker 4:  the, the heat you want and it doesn't, you usually you
Speaker 4:  have to like plug a soldering iron in and it's got a big golf cable and all
Speaker 4:  this stuff and it can be kind of annoying and and awkward and it takes a
Speaker 4:  while to heat up and you will burn the crap out of yourself repeatedly. And
Speaker 4:  Chris guarantees you will burn yourself less with this. Chris
Speaker 4:  doesn't know how bad I am at soldering.
Speaker 5:  So yeah, this, this is powered by u s bbc, which is kind of like very
Speaker 5:  convenient. You can run it off a Wall war or you can run it off a u s BBC
Speaker 5:  battery according to Chris in the article. But the, the key thing here is
Speaker 5:  this is like $25 and it heats up super quickly and then
Speaker 5:  cools down really quickly. So maybe you'll burn yourself less with this one
Speaker 5:  because it cools down so quickly and it's just not as like Yankee and bulky
Speaker 5:  as like the old school soldering irons that have not really changed in 50
Speaker 5:  years.
Speaker 6:  That's $25 in this translucent I'm in, I'll, I'll, I'll pick
Speaker 4:  People and, and was Wild was like everybody in
Speaker 4:  chat at here at the Verge when when he dropped this thing he was like, does
Speaker 4:  anybody know what the pine cell is? Like? Two people knew and we're like,
Speaker 4:  yes, I love it. And everybody else was like, no, I need it. Like just
Speaker 4:  reflexively. It was like, it was like the Sharper Image, sharper Image
Speaker 4:  catalog. You just opened it and everybody's like, I want it right now. Like
Speaker 4:  so and then all, a lot of readers, our readers seem to really, really like
Speaker 4:  it too. Apparently it's better for the tips don't melt it.
Speaker 4:  Like don't get all messy and gross as often. So very exciting
Speaker 4:  if you're in need of a soldering iron.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And it's easy to replace the tips and stuff like that.
Speaker 4:  This pine cell has a terrible name and it's also open source. I don't
Speaker 4:  know what an like, he's explained it to me multiple times. What an open
Speaker 4:  source soldering iron is and I still don't understand and I'm okay with
Speaker 4:  that. I'm like Richard right now. No, actually
Speaker 5:  If you get the pine si you can go build your ploy.
Speaker 4:  I've got, I got to, don't need to bring up the fact that my ploys
Speaker 4:  been sitting in a Ziploc bag for six months. I was sanding. Well,
Speaker 5:  I you just need a pine sill and then you can build your plo.
Speaker 4:  I know. I just need the pine si to finish. Yeah, it's gonna be great. Okay.
Speaker 4:  Dan, what's your gadget of the week? Is it this week or are you gonna be
Speaker 4:  cheating and say something from ces?
Speaker 5:  I'm gonna cheat and say something from ces. I knew it but
Speaker 5:  the, the reason I'm saying this is because this was actually our
Speaker 5:  like best like smart home gadget that we saw at ces
Speaker 5:  and that article didn't come out until after last week's v
Speaker 5:  episode. So this is the aca,
Speaker 5:  present sensor is like my gadget of the week. I'm super excited for this
Speaker 5:  thing and I know Jen is really excited about it. Basically this is
Speaker 5:  a device that can detect, it uses millimeter wave technology, not
Speaker 5:  like millimeter way 5g, but like it, it emits millimeter waves
Speaker 5:  from it and it can detect a person in a room or a space
Speaker 5:  really accurately and really down to like minute movement. So
Speaker 5:  it knows that you're breathing. And what it can do then is you can say like,
Speaker 5:  if I'm in this room, don't turn off the lights. Which is like a problem with
Speaker 5:  motion sensors in smart homes is that like when you
Speaker 5:  have, it's really great for motion sensors to turn on lights when you're
Speaker 5:  come into a room. But then if you don't have your automation set up properly
Speaker 5:  or they don't detect motion, say you're reading a book or you're watching
Speaker 5:  a movie or whatever it is and you're not moving enough for the current ones
Speaker 5:  to see you, they will turn the lights off after whatever time you set. So
Speaker 5:  this solves that problem. So now I can like not have my lights turn
Speaker 5:  off in the middle of the day in my office when I'm sitting there just typing
Speaker 5:  at my computer or you know, eating dinner in the dining room and things like
Speaker 5:  that. So I'm, I'm really excited. This came out in China a year or so ago.
Speaker 5:  They've got a new version that's coming to the US that's a little bit smaller,
Speaker 5:  a little bit more compact and, and, and I'm pretty excited about it.
Speaker 4:  Is it gonna support matter?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, so the way that ACA supports matter is through its hub.
Speaker 5:  So hubs, the hub is going to be updated and,
Speaker 5:  and then yeah the the hub, I believe the M two
Speaker 5:  hub is going to be the first one that's going to get their software update
Speaker 5:  to support matter. And then all the devices that connect to that hub, which
Speaker 5:  use ZigBee will be available to other matter
Speaker 5:  devices. I would say that like with a Cara matters
Speaker 5:  not that big of a deal because a car itself already
Speaker 5:  supports all of the major smart home platforms you can integrate into Home
Speaker 5:  kit. It supports Google Assistant, it supports Amazon's, it supports smart
Speaker 5:  things outta the box. So maybe Matter will open that up to even other or
Speaker 5:  future smart home platforms that we don't know about yet. But for now at
Speaker 5:  least matter's not going to change much for your car experience,
Speaker 5:  but they're getting it so good. Cool.
Speaker 4:  Are, would you be able to like use it? Cause you said it can detect breathing.
Speaker 4:  Would you be able to use it like point it at somebody and be like, are they
Speaker 4:  dead flash the lights in the house if they stop breathing
Speaker 5:  In theory
Speaker 4:  Like new sleep appia detector,
Speaker 5:  Like I I, I've seen some testing. There's been
Speaker 5:  some folks on YouTube who have purchased the Chinese version and like just
Speaker 5:  imported it where they were and have tested it. And like the level that
Speaker 5:  the, you can set it to like detect motion is so
Speaker 5:  finite. Like, and you can set zones of like, okay
Speaker 5:  beyond 10 feet, don't ignore anything. And that like, it's like
Speaker 5:  there's almost like a virtual wall right at 10 feet where it just stops detecting.
Speaker 5:  Oh
Speaker 4:  That's
Speaker 5:  Cool. Anything beyond that. And as soon as you break that barrier it,
Speaker 5:  it can detect you or sees motion, which is just wild. It's really cool.
Speaker 4:  That's very, very cool. Okay, nevermind. That sounds fun. That's,
Speaker 4:  that's not cheating. I'm gonna cheat though again and I'm gonna add one more
Speaker 4:  because there's an air conditioner Jen saw at
Speaker 4:  c e s that she did not mention in our excellent c e s
Speaker 4:  episode that went up this week. And it's an air conditioner with an L e D
Speaker 4:  screen on it. It's a mini split AC
Speaker 4:  unit with a digital photo frame, 27
Speaker 4:  inches made for by lg. It uses the think
Speaker 4:  queue app. It appears to just be one of the 27 inch ultra wide
Speaker 4:  monitors slapped on the front.
Speaker 5:  That's what it looks like.
Speaker 4:  This air conditioner with like a big like
Speaker 4:  garish frame. I've never been more delighted by something
Speaker 5:  I, I like what they're trying to do here. Yeah, like because those mini-split
Speaker 5:  acs are not attractive and when you have them in your home to be
Speaker 5:  effective, they basically have to be in almost every room, right? So you've
Speaker 5:  got a bunch of them and you've gotta cut hole in the wall and install them
Speaker 5:  and stuff like that. And they're not pretty to look at. So this is like an
Speaker 5:  attempt to kind of mask it with technology and design
Speaker 5:  and like they get a little way there. It's, it looks better than
Speaker 5:  a non mini-split I think. And maybe it's supposed to be like maybe someone
Speaker 5:  isn't gonna notice that there's an air conditioner up there behind it. I
Speaker 4:  Don't know. Just be like, why do you have this 27 inch digital
Speaker 4:  picture frame with some water in it on
Speaker 5:  Your wall? Hot mounted high up on the wall. Like yeah, why is it like all
Speaker 5:  the way up there towards
Speaker 4:  The ceiling? The ceiling? Why is it pointed towards your fan?
Speaker 4:  What's happening here? It's so good.
Speaker 5:  Mini split are very good for efficiency though. So like they do have lots
Speaker 5:  of benefits. Mini design is not
Speaker 4:  One of them. I just love like so many ways they could have gone about, they
Speaker 4:  could put some wood paneling on there. They could have put like some, I don't
Speaker 4:  know, some leaves or something about it and said they were like, cuz
Speaker 4:  everybody has just leaves randomly hanging in their home. Instead they're
Speaker 4:  like, we're gonna put a picture frame on it. A 27 inch monitor. Just
Speaker 4:  slap it on there.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, well now they can sell you an art subscription.
Speaker 4:  Oh there we go
Speaker 5:  To display on the screen. So that's, it's got recurring revenue.
Speaker 4:  There you go. You
Speaker 5:  Gotta think about the business here. Alex, I
Speaker 4:  I have. I'm so sorry, I forgot. Yeah, there's no pricing on it. There's no
Speaker 4:  release state. So if you were looking for a new mini split
Speaker 4:  and this sounds incredible to you, I'm sorry,
Speaker 4:  you're probably gonna have to wait a little while. This might not ever appear
Speaker 4:  but you can just do this with your current minis split. Just, just go buy
Speaker 4:  a 27 inch monitor and duct tape it up there, right?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. You know bolt aase amount to it. And
Speaker 4:  Guys, that is it for the Verge Cast this
Speaker 4:  week. We will be back next week, next Wednesday. We've got a great episode.
Speaker 4:  Monica is coming on to talk about laptops and a lot of the stuff she saw
Speaker 4:  at CES Victoria Song is gonna be there and talk about all sorts of
Speaker 4:  weird FDA regulatory weird wonkiness
Speaker 4:  that is happening that kind of started to come out of c e s. And then
Speaker 4:  we'll be back for the regular Friday show next week. It's gonna be super
Speaker 4:  fun and you can reach us all on Twitter or
Speaker 4:  if you wanna hit up Richard, you can go buy some
Speaker 4:  FTX coins from him. He's still selling some. He would love to sell them to
Speaker 5:  You. Some rich coins. I
Speaker 4:  Got 'em all rich coins. You can also reach Richard on Twitter
Speaker 4:  at J C C. Dan is DC
Speaker 4:  Seafer. I am Alex h Cran. I can
Speaker 5:  I just clarify if you can find me on Twitter. I don't really use Twitter
Speaker 5:  anymore. You can, you can also find me on Mastodon. I'm gonna be the the
Speaker 5:  Rogue one using Mastodon. But if you go to my Twitter account, wow, that
Speaker 5:  Alex just mentioned, there's a link to my Mastodon where I actually post.
Speaker 4:  All right. So go to his Twitter account and then go to his Macedon account
Speaker 4:  and then buy some cryptocurrency from Richard Eli is so
Speaker 4:  sorry he missed this week's episode. That's it. I'm not gonna say rock and
Speaker 4:  roll instead Andrew, shut up Sir.
Speaker 5:  Siri
Speaker 4:  Saying it for you instead. Andrew, play us some rumors. Hey
Speaker 4:  Siri, play Rumors by Fleetwood Mac. Oh, I
Speaker 4:  didn't work.
Speaker 5:  Shock. I'm shocked that Siri didn't
Speaker 4:  Work. All right. That's it. That's it. We'll see you
Speaker 4:  next week.
Speaker 5:  Rock and roll.
Speaker 10:  And that's a wrap for Vergecast this week. Thanks for listening. If you
Speaker 10:  enjoy the show, subscribe in the podcast app of your choice or tell a friend,
Speaker 10:  you can send us feedback at vergecast@theverge.com. This
Speaker 10:  show is produced by me, Liam James, and our senior audio director, Andrew
Speaker 10:  Marino. This episode was edited and mixed by Amanda Rose Smith.
Speaker 10:  Our editorial director is Brooke Min and our executive producer is
Speaker 10:  Eleanor Donovan. The Vergecast is a production of the Verge and Box Media
Speaker 10:  Podcast network. And that's it. We'll see you next week.