# Transcript
ID: 7de38470-991c-11ed-898d-c37386576d63
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Apple announces M2 MacBook Pros, a Mac Mini, and a new HomePod
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/2591134522549563672/-6069801370289969997/s93290-US-5331s-1674258311.mp3
Description: Today on the flagship podcast of automated content creation:
02:23 - The Verge's Nilay Patel, Alex Cranz, Richard Lawler, and Alex Heath start the show with an overview of what we've learned from Elon Musk running Twitter over the past few months.
24:50 - Inside CNET’s AI-powered SEO money machine
48:34 - Apple's Mac and HomePod announcements from this week
Speaker 1:  Today on the Vergecast, oh boy. Where to begin? Reid Hastings. C e o of Netflix
Speaker 1:  is out. Microsoft might be doing layoffs. Elon Musk is still bad at business.
Speaker 1:  There's new MacBook Pros and a home Pod. Big and Cena's using AI to
Speaker 1:  write their articles. All this so much more coming up right after this
Speaker 3:  Sport for today's show comes from Deloitte. What does a future look like?
Speaker 3:  It's a question that drives progress, but more importantly, how do you
Speaker 3:  get there? It's curiosity, resourcefulness and bold ideas that
Speaker 3:  can drive us even further than new technology. Because while technology can
Speaker 3:  take you far, human exploration could take you even farther. Deloitte
Speaker 3:  helps businesses build the future only they can imagine by melding deep business
Speaker 3:  acumen and innovative technology with a vast team of tech savvy
Speaker 3:  professionals. Unlock technology as powerful as your vision and push
Speaker 3:  the boundaries of the possible so that you can stay a step ahead with the
Speaker 3:  thinking to help you transform what's next into what's now helping
Speaker 3:  you see the extraordinary potential in the seemingly ordinary while blending
Speaker 3:  the possible with the practical is what Deloitte does. See how you
Speaker 3:  can engineer advantage with Deloitte at
Speaker 3:  deloitte.com/us/engineering advantage.
Speaker 4:  Dating apps, whether you're single in a relationship or summer in
Speaker 4:  between, you can't get away from them, but what happens when your romantic
Speaker 4:  life is part of a company's bottom line? How did dating
Speaker 4:  become a multi-billion dollar business? I'm Lakshmi
Speaker 4:  Renin.
Speaker 5:  And I'm Sangin Kurtz. We are hosting Land of the Giants,
Speaker 5:  a podcast about the biggest tech companies of our time.
Speaker 4:  This season we're exploring how apps like Tinder, hinge and Bumble
Speaker 4:  impact our search for love
Speaker 5:  Land of the Giants dating games from the Verge, the
Speaker 5:  Cut, and the Vox Media podcast network. Subscribe for free
Speaker 5:  wherever you listen.
Speaker 6:  Hello and welcome to Vergecast Flagship podcast of automated content
Speaker 6:  creation. Can someone make a chat G p t episode of the Vergecast for us?
Speaker 6:  It would be great. I could use a break. I was on on the show last week, but
Speaker 6:  I could use a longer break. You know what I'm saying? That'd be good. I'm
Speaker 6:  your friend Eli, Alex Franz is here.
Speaker 3:  I'm your friend who wrote this intro from TE G P T. You
Speaker 6:  Didn't know it. That's good. I can't wait to talk about the chat. I can't.
Speaker 6:  I'm like bursting to get to the chat G B T section of today's
Speaker 6:  episode. Richard Lawler's here
Speaker 7:  And I have not resigned as Co C o
Speaker 6:  A lot of things. You don't know this cuz you're in your car, you're just
Speaker 6:  like driving along. It's a normal day for you. We are recording later
Speaker 6:  than usual because right when we sat down to record a
Speaker 6:  flurry of news took place, including Reid Hastings, a cosio of
Speaker 6:  Netflix. Just dipping. Just screw it. I'm out. So we're a little bit later
Speaker 6:  Richard, who runs our news team, a little bit of a scramble. If you hear
Speaker 6:  the the frenzy in his voice, that's where that came from. We'll get to all
Speaker 6:  of that. But first, Alex Heath is here. Hey Alex.
Speaker 8:  Hey guys. Good to be here. It's been a minute,
Speaker 6:  It's been a minute. You have accomplished a lot in that minute. You launched
Speaker 6:  a new paid newsletter called Command Line full of Dish and gossip
Speaker 6:  Industry goings on. I recommend people go subscribe to it immediately.
Speaker 8:  Yes, please.
Speaker 6:  Every couple days I get a note from Alex being like, guess you signed up
Speaker 6:  and I wish I could reveal that information to you,
Speaker 6:  but I'm just telling you, if you sign up for Command Line, you will be in
Speaker 6:  some pretty good company. I would say.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, we can't disclose, you know, GDPR and all that, but
Speaker 8:  just take our word for it.
Speaker 6:  The European police are outside of Alex's house right now, actually finally
Speaker 6:  being very European. They're just smoking and gr like grumbling at the ground.
Speaker 6:  They have no authority here. But Alex, you're here because this week we
Speaker 6:  published a gigantic feature story in collaboration with our sister publication
Speaker 6:  New York Magazine, and our friends at Platform are Casey Newton and Zoe Schiffer
Speaker 6:  about the first 90 days of Twitter under Elon Musk.
Speaker 6:  Just that list of collaborators. You can tell this is a big story
Speaker 6:  and then obviously a lot has happened in 90 days of Elon Musk. Tell us about
Speaker 6:  that story.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, this was a fun one, Zoe
Speaker 8:  Schiffer and Casey and I have obviously been reporting on this
Speaker 8:  saga, the mini twists and turns of it from the beginning since Musk
Speaker 8:  walked in with the kitchen sink. And you know, if
Speaker 8:  you're listening to this, you probably have been following it as well. A
Speaker 8:  lot of the details we hoped that with this story we could put together
Speaker 8:  not only all the, just, you know, bit by bit crazy moments
Speaker 8:  that unfolded after Musk came in, but also kind of
Speaker 8:  just show thematically what it was like working there during this
Speaker 8:  time. Because a lot of the coverage has been centered on Musk and on Twitter
Speaker 8:  as a business and the Apple stuff, which I came on and talked about last
Speaker 8:  time. But you know, with this, we really wanted to focus on
Speaker 8:  the thousands of Twitter employees who lost their jobs as a result of Musk
Speaker 8:  acquisition. Interviewed several of them, some on the record,
Speaker 8:  some not to really try to show like this is what it was
Speaker 8:  like working in this place. And it's, it's crazy.
Speaker 8:  I mean it's, it's, you can't really, you couldn't write it as a
Speaker 8:  screenplay, as ridiculous as it is in real life. And
Speaker 8:  yeah, we hope that it kind of accurately portrays what life has been
Speaker 8:  like inside Twitter. And i, I I think we did that. But
Speaker 8:  yeah, it was really fun working with Casey and Zoe. Obviously they're, they're
Speaker 8:  crushing it on this beat at at Platform where, and we're all continuing to
Speaker 8:  cover it. But yeah, get a, get a copy of extremely hardcore
Speaker 8:  wherever magazines are sold near you, I guess, I guess
Speaker 8:  you can also read it online. Yeah. Since people do that, but I
Speaker 8:  actually haven't seen a print copy of it yet, but they exist,
Speaker 8:  I'm told, I'm told magazines are a thing.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it's a real, as somebody who has exclusively run a digital
Speaker 6:  publication for over a decade every, this is our third collaboration
Speaker 6:  with New York magazine and obviously they run a great website too, but they
Speaker 6:  make up print magazine and they have for over 50 years. And so
Speaker 6:  sometimes like whenever we collaborate with them, like, oh this is, this
Speaker 6:  is different, it's different. It's
Speaker 8:  Just very different. And I'm, and I'm, I'm obviously like kidding about like
Speaker 8:  people don't, don't re I actually do New York Mag is low-key, like a great
Speaker 8:  magazine and, and yeah,
Speaker 6:  I don't even low key, they're just a
Speaker 8:  Great magazine, but like, you know, it's, you, you gotta be subtle with like
Speaker 8:  your magazine flexes, you know, you don't want to be too
Speaker 6:  Over
Speaker 8:  The top. But yeah, I, I highly recommend
Speaker 8:  reading it in print I haven't gotten to yet, but they did an amazing job
Speaker 8:  and our team did an amazing job on the site too with the wealth meter,
Speaker 8:  which I think was your idea Eli, kind of
Speaker 6:  My only true contribution to the story. Well, so I mean I'll actually, let's
Speaker 6:  talk about that for a minute. Yeah, so not the wealth meter itself, which
Speaker 6:  is very funny. And that's the rest of the episode actually. It's just me
Speaker 6:  taking credit for the gimmick that I put in
Speaker 8:  The story. Yeah, shout out Graham. Shout Graham. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Our engineer Graham built that for me. I didn't like the last minute, but
Speaker 6:  the where that came from and really the, the story
Speaker 6:  is we, we are like, we should do a big feature about Elon and Twitter and
Speaker 6:  then it's like what, what is the thesis statement of that story? What is
Speaker 6:  the end of that story? Like a great story. This is
Speaker 6:  a kindergarten level writing assignment has a beginning, a middle, and an
Speaker 6:  end. We barely have a middle of this story,
Speaker 6:  right? There's this really chaotic beginning period
Speaker 6:  we think it feels Alex, I mean this is my question to you really is
Speaker 6:  have we reached a steady state of Twitter under
Speaker 6:  Elon? I don't know the answer to that question. We certainly do not have
Speaker 6:  an end, right? It is not a success or a failure. I, my instincts
Speaker 6:  tell me it's going in one direction and not the other. But we don't know.
Speaker 6:  So like how do you even write this story? And so we picked linear time.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Like here's 90 days, let's see what happens.
Speaker 8:  And we have reached an end, which was Twitter as it was
Speaker 8:  premus, right? So all the employees who are not either,
Speaker 8:  basically you fall into the camp of you're there for visa
Speaker 8:  healthcare work stability reasons, or you're
Speaker 8:  a kind of a mercenary, you're trying to rise up through the power vacuum.
Speaker 8:  Anyone who doesn't kind of fall into those camps has left by now. So
Speaker 8:  the company's a shell of what it once was, both in terms of
Speaker 8:  scale, size of people, but also the DNA of,
Speaker 8:  of the people who made the company over the last, you know, decade
Speaker 8:  plus. And so yeah, I think that was the bow on the story was
Speaker 8:  just kind of like he's flushed everyone out and now they're all suing him.
Speaker 8:  And I think the current, the current stand is there's
Speaker 8:  over 800 individual ex-employees
Speaker 8:  filing in arbitration cases against Twitter right now, which
Speaker 8:  Twitter has to pay those legal fees, which are, can be in the tens of thousands
Speaker 8:  per arbitration.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Yeah. So this a, a fa this is like a
Speaker 6:  fascinating, I don't know c plot of the Twitter story is this
Speaker 6:  arbitration thing.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. Musk no stranger to employment disputes
Speaker 8:  is now finding himself with even more. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And well he's, this is like the cutting edge of employment
Speaker 6:  disputes. So the, the backstory of the arbitration thing is all these companies
Speaker 6:  wrote arbitration, mandatory arbitration clauses
Speaker 6:  into their employment contracts that went up to the Supreme Court and Supreme
Speaker 6:  Court said that's fine. And so then the strategy is because of what
Speaker 6:  you're saying because the companies agree to take on those costs because
Speaker 6:  the calculation in their minds was we'll go to arbitration, which is
Speaker 6:  friendlier to the corporation, we'll agree to pay the costs and will come
Speaker 6:  out ahead. And so what employment lawyers like plaintiff employment
Speaker 6:  lawyers have discovered is, oh, we can just find a
Speaker 6:  thousand people who are mad at you and file 1000
Speaker 6:  individual arbitration cases that you have to pay for
Speaker 6:  and that you cannot collect and do a class action or
Speaker 6:  join the cases like you would in a normal court. Now you just have 1000
Speaker 6:  cases to pay for all individually. And that's like when
Speaker 6:  they
Speaker 7:  Wrote those policies, they didn't realize that they would be laying off thousands
Speaker 7:  of people at once who were all going to be extremely pissed.
Speaker 6:  I just think they thought everyone else's, like there's like a level of a
Speaker 6:  giant corporation where it's like you think everyone's stupid, you know,
Speaker 6:  and that you're smarter than 'em and you like realize like, oh crap, like
Speaker 6:  this is an unexpected consequence of this thing. And it is very much
Speaker 6:  the cutting edge of employment law. This is a new development that
Speaker 6:  passed like two years, maybe not even. And so Musk is like at
Speaker 6:  the cutting edge of this style of employment dispute. He's
Speaker 6:  invented a lot of things. The Rockets land themselves. I'm not sure that
Speaker 6:  he wants to spend his time inventing an outcome to mass
Speaker 6:  simultaneous arbitration.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. Which
Speaker 6:  Is like, there are rich people, there are smart people who are very engaged
Speaker 6:  in inventing at the end to this cuz it's the cutting edge. I don't think
Speaker 6:  that's where Elon wants to be.
Speaker 8:  No, he doesn't. I don't know where he, he definitely doesn't want to be anywhere
Speaker 8:  near San Francisco, as I'm sure you may talk about later. He tried
Speaker 8:  unsuccessfully to get another lawsuit over his Tesla tweeting
Speaker 8:  moved out of San Francisco due to apparent, you know, bias. His lawyer
Speaker 8:  argued there in San Francisco. They couldn't find jurors was the argument
Speaker 8:  that didn't, you know, that would have a neutral view of us. Didn't Yeah.
Speaker 8:  Which we, you know, I don't, we need to get into a tangent, but I thought
Speaker 8:  it was, there was a tweet thread of his lawyer arguing in court the other
Speaker 8:  day that the reason the four 20 tweet should not be,
Speaker 8:  you know, considered as, you know, something that he
Speaker 8:  has to worry about is that he's a reckless tweeter and like this is his personal
Speaker 8:  lawyer being like, this is our legal defense. He is a reckless tweeter,
Speaker 8:  the CEO of Twitter. Let's
Speaker 6:  See how that works
Speaker 8:  For him. But yeah, no, I think the current, the current state, so now that
Speaker 8:  we've moved from, you know, the really chaotic him taking over
Speaker 8:  phase to now trying to figure out how to land the
Speaker 8:  plane, I think he drew analogy to like, this is a plane flying into the ground
Speaker 8:  at at top speed financially is
Speaker 8:  Twitter, blue is a dud. I just saw some analysis that
Speaker 8:  he hasn't even even managed to double the subscription count from before
Speaker 8:  he took the company. So there's less than 300,000 Twitter blue
Speaker 8:  subscribers.
Speaker 6:  You know what, he has doubled. He's doubled a number of people who show up
Speaker 6:  in my mentions whenever I tweet after having said a moment, I
Speaker 6:  have to break my previous relationship with Twitter. That's like, you're
Speaker 6:  back and all of those people pay for Twitter
Speaker 8:  Blue. Yeah, that's true. There's a nice overlap of like, you have 12
Speaker 8:  followers and some kind of weird like
Speaker 8:  Joe Byron thing in your bio and you're a Twitter blue subscriber.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. If you're one of those like sunglass truck guys, he's
Speaker 8:  Got you. But yeah, so that's a dud. The company's revenue was down
Speaker 8:  40% year over year as of this month.
Speaker 8:  So losing hundreds of millions of dollars since he took over and they're
Speaker 8:  auctioning off all the furniture. So that's the current state
Speaker 8:  of of Twitter. That's
Speaker 6:  A bad place. Yes. That's where our story ends. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  Did, did we put, did TC put a bid in on the bird logo?
Speaker 6:  Tcs really thought about 20, $18,000 on the bird logo.
Speaker 6:  I'm not sure if he mean, he obviously thought about it enough that he did
Speaker 6:  not spend $18,000 on the bird logo, but he, he thought about
Speaker 6:  it more than anyone should. Like I thought about spending $18,000 on
Speaker 6:  the bird logo and the way that you always think about buying anything, you're
Speaker 6:  like, that'd be great. And they're like, wait, this is stupid. TC kept going
Speaker 6:  for a little bit longer than
Speaker 8:  18,000. That's gonna be the price of a used Tesla in a few months. Well
Speaker 6:  That was the open, that was the opening bit. I'm not even sure where it's
Speaker 6:  at now.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, well you know, they need all the money they can get and that's
Speaker 8:  the current state. But yeah, I guess just to like bring it full circle with
Speaker 8:  the piece, like I think we accurately captured the frank
Speaker 8:  cruelty of how Musk treated the employees
Speaker 8:  there. Which like you can say what you want about Musk as a innovator.
Speaker 8:  As a technologist. His track record does speak for itself there.
Speaker 8:  He treated these people horribly and you know, it's not that
Speaker 8:  we also talk about how in the piece like Twitter was not run well. People
Speaker 8:  there knew that it needed a reset, it needed a kick in the pants, but I
Speaker 8:  don't think anyone was necessarily expecting just the,
Speaker 8:  the cruelty of how like the first month unfolded. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  And now the chickens are are are roosting and like, you know, there's
Speaker 8:  800 arbitration cases. So
Speaker 6:  I feel like we have to issue this disclaimer that we do every time we talk
Speaker 6:  about Twitter criticizing the Elon Musk regime of Twitter is in no way
Speaker 6:  condoning or saying the previous regime did anything good
Speaker 6:  at any time. Yeah. Like it was bad then it was really
Speaker 6:  bad and now it's still pretty bad and it's that middle period, it's the transition.
Speaker 6:  This hasn't really happened to any company ever where in the middle of the
Speaker 6:  Halloween party an acquisition closes and the executives get marched
Speaker 6:  out the door. Yeah. Which is an incredible scene in this story.
Speaker 8:  Well the, to make things even better is that this is how crazy things were
Speaker 8:  that week. Like there was a, a scarecrow walking around with a handler
Speaker 8:  at the party and everyone thought it was Musk at first
Speaker 8:  because of the handler and the way it was the gonna be the mc for the evening.
Speaker 8:  And they're like, the Scarecrow is gonna remove its mask and it's
Speaker 8:  gonna be Musk after he just escorted Rgc out of the building. But yeah,
Speaker 8:  it's, it was, it was an insane time and I don't think it's gonna get
Speaker 8:  less insane. I think it'll probably just get weirder with Twitter, but
Speaker 8:  Yeah. You know, Elon's still tweeting through it and while we all watch
Speaker 8:  So fun story.
Speaker 6:  So here's a, the thing that I've been thinking about and the, the question
Speaker 6:  I I've been wanting to ask you, but we needed to wrap this story up so don't
Speaker 6:  wanna distract you. It feels like the, you know, the window, the chaos is
Speaker 6:  over, like the window of the chaos story. Everyone gets it. All the
Speaker 6:  people are gone. The people who are left are either people. I think
Speaker 6:  the three of you wrote about it and the story is people who see chaos as
Speaker 6:  a ladder, they see the power vacuum, they see the opportunity to move up,
Speaker 6:  they wanna be close to Elon or it's people who are stuck there on visas or
Speaker 6:  need health insurance, right? So you got this weird two classes
Speaker 6:  of people, but the kind of chaos is over the everyday
Speaker 6:  machinations of chaos have at least simmered down a little bit. Now it's
Speaker 6:  like what is next? Like if Twitter blue isn't working and the
Speaker 6:  advertisers aren't coming back and the revenue is down and you know, the
Speaker 6:  loans are coming due against the Tesla stock and Tesla stock is down
Speaker 6:  the next turn seems actually way more devastating.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, I mean there is a real, I mean he's been a, he's used the, it's hard
Speaker 8:  to, to separate when Musk is just kind of using a shtick
Speaker 8:  versus what, when he actually means what he's saying. He said before
Speaker 8:  at his other companies that they're on the verge of bankruptcy and it's been
Speaker 8:  more of a way to motivate people to kind of get through a hard time. He's
Speaker 8:  been saying the same thing now inside Twitter. You know, we could go bankrupt.
Speaker 3:  What a management style
Speaker 8:  Get through this. I don't think that actually happens, you know, I
Speaker 8:  don't even with how, you know, Musk appears to be going off the
Speaker 8:  rails in some ways. Like I don't think he's actually gonna light 44 billion
Speaker 8:  on fire in under a year. He's definitely on the way,
Speaker 8:  but there's a lot of people with a lot of stake in Twitter trying to
Speaker 8:  figure this out that I, I just, I think he would be something he couldn't
Speaker 8:  really come back from necessarily. But
Speaker 3:  I mean haven't that's been like nobody thought he was gonna
Speaker 3:  light the money on fire, but he still did it. Like when he said I'm gonna
Speaker 3:  buy it Yolo, what was it, 42, 20 or whatever,
Speaker 3:  like that initial price that he did. Yeah. 54 20. Like he
Speaker 3:  still repeatedly has said, no, it's, it's
Speaker 3:  fine, I'm cool. And then absolutely fallen on his face.
Speaker 3:  So I don't think it's outside the realm of possibility that he's gonna fall
Speaker 3:  on his face again with Twitter.
Speaker 8:  No, it's not. It's not. And I think with every passing week
Speaker 8:  that looks more likely, but for
Speaker 8:  now it's, you know, he, he said the goals to be break even this year.
Speaker 8:  And I think you can do that. But I mean, Twitter
Speaker 8:  as a product, I don't know about you all. Like it's, it's getting worse.
Speaker 8:  It's getting uglier to look at both in terms of what they're recommending
Speaker 8:  and just like the pixels and the way things are organized.
Speaker 8:  So yeah, I, I don't know. I I
Speaker 8:  want to try to like, you know, I want Twitter to live. I don't, you know,
Speaker 8:  it's, we, I think a lot of us who have fond memories of Twitter don't want
Speaker 8:  it to die, so we'll see. But it's not looking, it's not looking
Speaker 8:  hopeful. I also just like haven't succumbed to the, to Mastodon
Speaker 8:  and I don't really think there's any other clear alternatives.
Speaker 8:  So there's not, I I don't know, you know, we all came back on Twitter
Speaker 8:  to promote the, the features, the cover story, like
Speaker 8:  Yeah. I
Speaker 6:  Was like, what else?
Speaker 8:  So
Speaker 6:  I should have made like a TikTok, like one of Thoses of me like on green
Speaker 6:  screened over the story
Speaker 8:  Likey
Speaker 6:  At the headline. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  I don't know. I I think we did kind of summarize the chapter
Speaker 8:  that has now ended and now we're in this uncertain period of can he keep
Speaker 8:  it from totally, you know, burning and
Speaker 6:  You know, you, you mentioned Macon, so I have not joined Macon either.
Speaker 6:  I don't, I haven't had Twitter on my phone for months now. I I only use it
Speaker 6:  at work and I just use it to basically retweet people who tweet
Speaker 6:  decoder. It's a great way to use Twitter. What I miss, the thing
Speaker 6:  that I miss the most is Twitter during n f L games
Speaker 6:  and I find myself bringing my laptop to the living room
Speaker 6:  so I can just like read sports writers cuz they're still using it. That's
Speaker 6:  it. Everything else is like, I come to it and I look at it during the work
Speaker 6:  day. I'm like another scandal that will come to nothing.
Speaker 6:  It's erupted on Twitter. Just, it just doesn't, I don't care about the
Speaker 6:  royal family so good though. And I close my laptop and I walk away. That's
Speaker 6:  fair. I don't, my people have escaped them twice. Right. I'm an
Speaker 6:  Indian American. Yeah, that's two times fair. And I'm, I'm out. It's not
Speaker 6:  for me. That's my go-to line. Someone's gonna steal it from me and they're
Speaker 6:  gonna make a million dollars in the back of that line. That person's gonna
Speaker 6:  be Mindy Kaling. Anyhow, all I'm saying is like, it feels
Speaker 6:  like my brain is healing because I don't have feed-based social media in
Speaker 6:  my life and I, I I think I may might eat it back.
Speaker 6:  You know, like
Speaker 8:  Yeah, you're like, I'm I'm twitchy now.
Speaker 6:  I'm like Jonesy, I feel too healthy. Did I tell this to you when you guys
Speaker 6:  were I had massive fomo CS and I actually, I got a text
Speaker 6:  from a dear friend you, so you will can obviously guess who
Speaker 6:  it is. And he is like, I'm jonesing for a vape. And I
Speaker 6:  was like, oh, my body just wants nicotine during the first week of January.
Speaker 6:  Like, that's, that's what I've been doing for a long time.
Speaker 6:  I've been in Vegas and like, that's how I feel about like this weird feed-based
Speaker 6:  social media that has been at the center of the media ecosystem for a long
Speaker 6:  time. And I, maybe I'll come back to it. Maybe I'll sort of mast, maybe I'll
Speaker 6:  turn the whole version of mast on like, who knows. But it
Speaker 6:  right at this second, it's like, oh, I should just let my brain heal. And
Speaker 6:  I feel like a lot of the ecosystem is in that moment where it's not like
Speaker 6:  we have to immediately go to Mastodon and it's like, oh, we can play with
Speaker 6:  this a little bit, but it's actually better for everyone if we walk away
Speaker 6:  from this for a
Speaker 8:  Second. Neil, you know, the fans, the readers want a verge
Speaker 8:  mastodon. They want, they want us in the fed averse.
Speaker 6:  If you are a software developer with a vengeance and you want to turn the
Speaker 6:  entire verge into a maid on instance,
Speaker 8:  That's going to happen
Speaker 6:  Now. I'll hear you out.
Speaker 8:  No, it's going to just happen this weekend. Someone's
Speaker 6:  Gonna be like curious. We're just gonna do it. I I'm not, not kidding. Like
Speaker 6:  Macon is really just a micro blogging platform. Yeah, it's not a Twitter
Speaker 6:  clone. Right. You can do a lot with
Speaker 8:  It. It's like, it's like WordPress but harder to understand. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  It's a, it's just a syndicated blogging platform. They just made the UI look
Speaker 6:  more like Twitter than not. So people think it's a replacement. But that
Speaker 6:  means if you were to start a publication like ours from scratch,
Speaker 6:  you could actually start, you could do that Macon, which is a fascinating
Speaker 6:  thought
Speaker 8:  Experiment. Well, medium Medium did this. They have a Macon instance, so
Speaker 8:  you know, that means Macon is here to stay
Speaker 6:  Soon they will begin paying some writers pennies to publish our medium.
Speaker 6:  Yes. And then they'll take that money away and shut it.
Speaker 8:  We're gonna clap for our toots. Well, I
Speaker 8:  I I should probably go and finish command line, but I I I just want to
Speaker 8:  Yeah, plug it shamelessly like you did at the top and say
Speaker 8:  especially you guys are gonna talk about chat g p t later. I, so by the time
Speaker 8:  this comes out, I'll have an interview with the CEO of Notion, they're doing
Speaker 8:  a really interesting implementation of chat G P T. They have unique
Speaker 8:  visibility into the space. I think people will find that interesting. Already
Speaker 8:  have done interviews with Jack Dorsey, c of Shopify, CTO
Speaker 8:  of Meta have had some scoops, some people
Speaker 8:  moves. Yeah, check it out. It's, it's an experiment. I'm having fun.
Speaker 8:  verge.com/command line. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it is very fun. I encourage people to go read it and
Speaker 6:  honestly, if you wanna be ahead of the curve, that's, that's the place to
Speaker 6:  be. I'm trying to sell here fir like first I'm selling my idea that we should
Speaker 6:  trend the entire version of mass on server and now have opened the Overton
Speaker 6:  window. I'm like, you should subscribe to a newsletter. You see, it's a tactic,
Speaker 6:  escalating levels of commitment. All right Alex, it's great to talk to you
Speaker 6:  man. We'll talk to you soon.
Speaker 8:  Thanks guys.
Speaker 6:  Thanks to Alex. We're gonna take a quick break. We'll right back. We have
Speaker 6:  a lot to talk about today. We'll grab.
Speaker 1:  Today's episode is sponsored by Aura. Here's the riddle. What's the
Speaker 1:  point of a sleep tracker if it's so bulky that wearing it keeps you awake?
Speaker 1:  Lots of stuff is trackable these days. Your heart rate, your steps, but you're
Speaker 1:  only going to get something out of the data if you have a device you actually
Speaker 1:  want to wear. But the Aura Ring gives you personalized health insights, all
Speaker 1:  from a comfortable to wear water resistant ring during the daytime. The
Speaker 1:  ring sensor technology tracks heart rate, calories burned in your activity
Speaker 1:  levels, and then at night it tracks info on your body temperature, trends,
Speaker 1:  sleep quality, respiratory rate and more. You get all that personalized
Speaker 1:  data in your Aura app so you can work on building healthy habits. What I
Speaker 1:  like about the Aura Ring is that it just disappears. I forget I'm even wearing
Speaker 1:  it. One small ring could make a world of difference in your health visit
Speaker 1:  or ring.com/verge to find out the right ring for you and get
Speaker 1:  $15 off your purchase. That's or
Speaker 1:  ring.com/verge. Don't forget to use our link to save
Speaker 1:  $15 on your Aura ring.
Speaker 9:  Hi, I'm John Glenn Hill and I'm the new host of The Weeds,
Speaker 9:  a podcast from Vox all about politics and policy.
Speaker 9:  Our mission is to take deep dives into policies shaping our world,
Speaker 9:  everything from crypto regulation to immigration to
Speaker 9:  climate change. And this week for my first
Speaker 9:  official episode in the host chair, we're firing up the weeds time machine.
Speaker 9:  And taking a trip back to 1965
Speaker 10:  Today is a triumph for freedom. As
Speaker 10:  huge as any victory that's ever been won
Speaker 10:  on any battlefield
Speaker 9:  To talk about one of the most significant pieces of civil rights legislation
Speaker 9:  in US history, the Voting Rights Act, and with
Speaker 9:  questions swirling around election integrity and the future of American democracy,
Speaker 9:  we figured there's no time like the present to look back on it,
Speaker 9:  subscribe to the weeds for new episodes every Tuesday.
Speaker 6:  All right, we're back. There's a lot to talk about. There's
Speaker 6:  obviously new Apple News, there's new MacBook Pros with M two chips.
Speaker 6:  There's a new HomePod. I'm making the most sarcastic
Speaker 6:  of air quotes possible. There's a new HomePod, I could hear 'em,
Speaker 6:  there's Microsoft layoffs and this thing about their hardware portfolio.
Speaker 6:  Netflix just got a new ceo. There's like a lot going on and all
Speaker 6:  this stuff happened like in the minutes before we were set to start recording.
Speaker 6:  But I can we talk about CNET and AI and chat G P T and
Speaker 6:  and what's going on over there first?
Speaker 9:  Yes,
Speaker 6:  The robots took our jobs. I, I dunno what else there used to say the robots
Speaker 6:  are coming for our jobs. So last week, so I called
Speaker 6:  futurism, broke this story. CNET is secretly using
Speaker 6:  AI to write articles and it was like, I I would say it was
Speaker 6:  90% a secret cuz the byline
Speaker 6:  on the articles. So CNET money staff. And then if you like clicked it,
Speaker 6:  it would tell you that it was written by AI with a human editor. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  I've run a digital news site for a long time, no one's clicking. So it
Speaker 6:  was, it was, it was not hidden but it was hidden, right? The story picks
Speaker 6:  up. People go wild obviously in the context of chat G p T, there's just
Speaker 6:  unhinged discourse. The robots are coming for our
Speaker 6:  jobs. Journalism is, journalism is over. Why do you even need this? We started
Speaker 6:  looking into it. Mia Sato on our team and James Vincent, who's our AI reporter,
Speaker 6:  he's been on the first cast recently assigned him to a go figure out what's
Speaker 6:  going on here. And they came back, we, we just published the story
Speaker 6:  and what we'll kind of get to the story itself in a minute, but they came
Speaker 6:  back with what I think of as just like a dead ahead
Speaker 6:  verge creator story. Like there's a platform, it has
Speaker 6:  an algorithm. People try to game the algorithm to make more money. Like
Speaker 6:  the bones of this story are the same as YouTubers gaming, YouTube
Speaker 6:  or TikTok ERs gaming TikTok or Instagramers Gaming Instagram or
Speaker 6:  whatever. It's just the platform is
Speaker 6:  Google search. And the web and CNET,
Speaker 6:  instead of being a TikTok is a voracious private
Speaker 6:  equity money machine. Well not cnet, so it's just not it like,
Speaker 6:  it's just not as in it. But the the basics of it are the same but
Speaker 3:  Not cnet, it's Red Ventures, right? That now
Speaker 6:  Owns cnet. Right? So we should, we should say the top CNET is our
Speaker 6:  competitor. This is a disclosure. Do I need to disclose that? The Verge
Speaker 6:  competes against cnet. The verges competing against CNET for a long time
Speaker 6:  when we were all little babies and we just started the thing. We're like
Speaker 6:  we're gonna get seen like whatever we did it wired in cnet. Those are always
Speaker 6:  our competitors. We are friends with a great many people who
Speaker 6:  work at CNET who have worked at cnet. We just were talking about kc. KC came
Speaker 6:  to us from cnet. We've sent people to cnet Socos,
Speaker 6:  it's a big industry. CNET in 2008
Speaker 6:  was worth 1.8 billion. And it was, I
Speaker 6:  know this because C Bs bought it for 1.8 billion,
Speaker 6:  which is just a crazy sentence just you car
Speaker 6:  pull over and I want you to say out loud to yourself. In
Speaker 6:  2008, one year after the iPhone was released,
Speaker 6:  C Bs bought CNET for
Speaker 6:  1.8 billion.
Speaker 6:  That's more than Facebook bought. Instagram for Facebook, bought
Speaker 6:  Instagram for a billion, that's more than Google bought YouTube
Speaker 6:  for Google was bought YouTube for 1.65 billion
Speaker 6:  C Bs bought CNET for
Speaker 6:  1.8 billion in 2008.
Speaker 3:  You don't think that was a
Speaker 6:  Goodbye? So I, I get it with
Speaker 7:  Last fm, it's a content strategy that makes sense. I understand it.
Speaker 6:  Fast forward, many things happen between 2008 and
Speaker 6:  2020. Again, this is one year after the iPhone is released.
Speaker 6:  So one year after the Comet hits the earth, they're like
Speaker 6:  1.8 billion on CNET
Speaker 6:  the com. The comet it turned out had hit the earth upends the entire media
Speaker 6:  ecosystem upends the world, right? Mobile upends the world 2020
Speaker 6:  C B s flips CNET to a company called Red Ventures for
Speaker 6:  500 million. I think it is safe to say this was not a good
Speaker 6:  investment for them. Flip it to this company called Red Ventures. Red
Speaker 6:  Ventures is, they're not a secret. They've been profiled them in the
Speaker 6:  New York Times. They own a lot of things. They own the Points
Speaker 6:  guy, they own bank rate.com, they own credit cards.com.
Speaker 6:  Are you sensing a theme here? They own things that people with
Speaker 6:  credit cards go to visit a lot and they, it's a
Speaker 6:  massive portfolio. They own a lot of like search content
Speaker 6:  farms. Like when you're searching for some, when you're searching for like
Speaker 6:  credit card are the best points and you land on the Points guy and the Points
Speaker 6:  guy's great. We know people who work there too. Yeah, and you land on the
Speaker 6:  points guy. How does the Point Sky make money? It's affiliate links to sign
Speaker 6:  up for credit cards. So Red Ventures is buying all of these
Speaker 6:  sites that have lots and lots of search authority and they're like
Speaker 6:  pumping them full of affiliate links, which again is a totally
Speaker 6:  like well-known content strategy. The wire cutter, another competitor of
Speaker 6:  ours, I feel like I just like, if it's a website, it competes with us. Like,
Speaker 6:  I'll just be honest, the the wire cutter started by
Speaker 6:  Brian Lamb who started Gizmoto way back in the day. Yep. He started, it was
Speaker 6:  basically like, here's the best phone and you, I'm just like one phone and
Speaker 6:  here's the link to buy it. Totally monetized by affiliate links. He flipped
Speaker 6:  that to the New York Times for 30 million. And then the, you can ask
Speaker 6:  a lot of people how it's going over there, but whatever.
Speaker 3:  Now he surfs
Speaker 6:  And now Brian mostly surfs his car. His Instagram is, he's a great carpenter.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. So Cena gets bought by this private equity company called Red
Speaker 6:  Ventures for 500,000,002 years ago. And then all of this
Speaker 6:  AI stuff starts showing up. And so they got caught out last week,
Speaker 6:  but me and James go and do their reporting and it turns out that Red
Speaker 6:  Ventures is pretty much open about the fact that they use
Speaker 6:  AI across their portfolio. They've been doing it on CNET for a while. Every
Speaker 6:  single morning CNET again, our com our competitor, I think it's
Speaker 6:  fair to call them a tech publication every single morning around
Speaker 6:  nine o'clock CNET publishes, here are today's mortgage rates and here are
Speaker 6:  today's mortgage refinance rates.
Speaker 6:  Let's just imagine if a Virgin did like you would, people would kill me,
Speaker 6:  like our staff would kill me
Speaker 3:  First quick
Speaker 6:  Post. They're obviously doing that because those people search for that.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And that's a service you can provide people. Like here's, here's the
Speaker 6:  information. But why do you do that if Santa Cuz you're huge, you have a
Speaker 6:  lot of search authority and when people go to sign up for a new
Speaker 6:  mortgage or to refinance their mortgage, you collect an affiliate bounty
Speaker 6:  on the back of it.
Speaker 3:  And I don't think we can overstate how much authority seen it has because
Speaker 3:  it's been around, it was created what, in like the 1990s?
Speaker 6:  It was, yeah. It was created so long ago that c b s bought it for one point
Speaker 6:  billion in 2008.
Speaker 3:  Like it has a lot of authority and that's one of
Speaker 3:  the reasons it stayed one of the top ranks tech sites in the world is because
Speaker 3:  it has so much authority. You go and you Google something, you're probably
Speaker 3:  gonna find a CNET link and you're probably gonna cook on it because you're
Speaker 3:  like, I recognize them. And so like, I think that was the reason Red Ventures
Speaker 3:  bought them, right? Was because they wanted that authority.
Speaker 6:  I mean, if someone's like, Hey, this thing was worth 1.8 Billy, but you could
Speaker 6:  have it for 500 million, why not? You know, like,
Speaker 3:  Hey, what a deal. What a deal. Sometimes
Speaker 6:  You just gotta Tumblr it, man, this couch just needs to be reupholstered.
Speaker 6:  You know, you, you did a thing where you cut the skirts off the bottom, you
Speaker 6:  exposed the legs, you saw it on Facebook Marketplace for five times what
Speaker 6:  you bought it Red Ventures. So, but if that's your game, right? This is your
Speaker 6:  monetization. You're gonna buy all these sites with search authority for
Speaker 6:  really high value search terms and then you're gonna put affiliate links
Speaker 6:  on those pages and then when people click on them, you get paid.
Speaker 6:  And this is a real thing, particularly for credit cards. We were doing some
Speaker 6:  research. The number, if you click on a credit card affiliate link
Speaker 6:  on one of these sites and you sign up the bounty, the
Speaker 6:  Affiliate Bounty is right now like $250
Speaker 6:  in the past for Red Ventures specifically
Speaker 6:  $900. Wow. Right? So if
Speaker 6:  you, if they can get you to sign up for one of these crazy credit cards,
Speaker 6:  like, you know, the metal and all the, all the point system is all this stuff,
Speaker 6:  the high end, the top tier ones, the visa infinites, and you actually
Speaker 6:  sign up through one of their links up to $900.
Speaker 6:  So this is a totally lucrative play for them. A totally lucrative play for
Speaker 6:  the points guy on all these other sites that they, that they own. But that
Speaker 6:  means you're not really trying to do anything except
Speaker 6:  get people to click those links on your pages. Right. I will disclose, we
Speaker 6:  also have affiliate links on our pages. We disclose them per the FTC
Speaker 6:  guidelines. They're, they're connected to our reviews program. But like our
Speaker 6:  reason for being is tech journalism. And we do
Speaker 6:  that stuff to pay for the tech journalism. I, I think
Speaker 6:  that makes sense. Like if you read our reviews, a lot of them are like, you
Speaker 6:  shouldn't buy this.
Speaker 7:  It made a lot more sense before you just told me that they're getting $900
Speaker 7:  on each referral link. I don't
Speaker 6:  Right. A lot, a lot of their, you should sign up for the XX card and that's
Speaker 6:  just across the portfolio. So if you, if that's the game you're playing your
Speaker 6:  private equity and this is the money machine you're running and you're just
Speaker 6:  trying to pump Google search with content so you can convert on
Speaker 6:  these links. Like why would you have people do that work?
Speaker 6:  Like you, you can't, there's no way an actual human being wakes up every
Speaker 6:  day at CNET and like looks up the mortgage rates, fills out this template
Speaker 6:  and hits published every single day between nine and
Speaker 6:  9:30 AM for like two years.
Speaker 7:  I bet there's someone on TikTok doing an absolutely unhinged to get ready
Speaker 7:  with me every morning, nothing but the mortgage rates and putting on makeup.
Speaker 7:  I I can find them. I'll, I'll look.
Speaker 6:  I'm just saying. But that's like you would, you would want a robot to that.
Speaker 6:  You should have a robot to that.
Speaker 7:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  If I assigned one of our reporters to do that job, they'd be like, screw
Speaker 6:  you, get a robot to do it. Or they were sold, you don't have reporter. They
Speaker 6:  would say they were doing it and figure out how to make a robot do it on
Speaker 6:  their own. Right? Like if you have an office job in America today and you
Speaker 6:  have not figured out Excel automations, like you're just robbing yourself
Speaker 6:  of time, that's time you could be on TikTok. It's like, why wouldn't you
Speaker 6:  do this? And the answer is like, oh, you should do this a lot. Of course
Speaker 6:  you should have AI write content with a capital C
Speaker 6:  against popular search terms and publish them just at
Speaker 6:  mass volume on your site with an enormous amount of search authority so that
Speaker 6:  you can convert affiliate links at $250 or $900 a piece.
Speaker 6:  The problem is one that that can't be
Speaker 6:  self-sustaining. Right? At some point you're just not gonna have a staff
Speaker 6:  left to even turn on the robots because journalists don't wanna be around
Speaker 6:  that two, eventually you're gonna destroy your brand,
Speaker 6:  right? Like CNET will be known for just being a content farm. And then three,
Speaker 6:  and I think this is like the big story and honestly, and it's like this is
Speaker 6:  gonna be the big story of the year. Eventually Google's gonna be like, yo,
Speaker 6:  our search results are full of garbage, right? Yeah. People will type in
Speaker 6:  what is the best credit card and you just get, which they
Speaker 3:  Do robots
Speaker 6:  Trying to get you to sign up for credit cards and like, why would I use Google
Speaker 6:  then?
Speaker 3:  And Google hates that. Like, to be clear, Google hates when you try to game
Speaker 3:  the system every couple of years they do like a big panda update
Speaker 3:  and they're like, our job here is to destroy this gaming. And then
Speaker 3:  you watch a lot of companies who are like, their whole business is
Speaker 3:  gaming the SEO go, oh crap. And trying to figure out how to game it again.
Speaker 3:  And so like, I don't think there's a long runway for this ai, well
Speaker 3:  there's a long runway, but I don't think there's a good ending for this AI
Speaker 3:  gaming with Google.
Speaker 6:  I I think Google honestly to me, like, yes, this story c yes, story about
Speaker 6:  a competitor. I mean the story itself is great. You should read it. The,
Speaker 6:  an editor resigned and wrote a letter to hundreds of of people that
Speaker 6:  she had the letter written by chat G p T, which is like
Speaker 6:  a perfect detail. And in the letter she accuses CNET slash
Speaker 6:  Red ventures of sending out a cybersecurity newsletter
Speaker 6:  written by AI without disclosing it and saying like, there's actually bad
Speaker 6:  advice in there. That's a, that's just a straight up scandal, right?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. You have this line that the last line of the story is
Speaker 6:  CNN employees do not fear AI more than they fear the numerous layoffs. Red
Speaker 6:  Ventures insist upon everyone at CNET is more afraid of red ventures than
Speaker 6:  they are of ai. Like there's a, there's a story here. It's not really about
Speaker 6:  cnet, right? It's about private equity gaming, Google
Speaker 6:  search and the affiliate marketing ecosystem.
Speaker 6:  Ruthlessly and I, you know, they're private. It's like being mad at a tiger
Speaker 6:  for being a tiger. It's a PE company. Like this is what they, it's their
Speaker 6:  job. They buy companies and squeeze them for money and they move on. Like,
Speaker 6:  I'm mad at the locust, like, what are you gonna do? CNET though is
Speaker 6:  like the storied news powerhouse and it's, it's being gutted by these
Speaker 6:  forces. And honestly it's because Google search is
Speaker 6:  gameable in this way and yet they do panda updates. But just
Speaker 6:  compare that to other platforms. Compare that to YouTube, compare
Speaker 6:  that to Instagram, compare that to TikTok, compare that to even Twitter,
Speaker 6:  right? YouTube is like, boy, there's a lot of garbage on our platform.
Speaker 6:  We're just changing the algorithm to deran it or demonetize it and we'll
Speaker 6:  change the incentive so people make this other thing that we want. And then
Speaker 6:  the garbage, I mean, Google struggled with proliferates and then it comes
Speaker 6:  back like whatever. But all the other platforms do that Google
Speaker 6:  search is just subtly getting worse, right? It's like it
Speaker 6:  hasn't, it does not incentivize good stuff in the way that
Speaker 6:  the other platforms at least give like lip service to
Speaker 6:  incentivizing good stuff.
Speaker 3:  I do wonder, is there a cur, is there, like, like with Google,
Speaker 3:  there's an entire industry, they're called like the SEO
Speaker 3:  industry. It's all these people trying to game Google and it's been around
Speaker 3:  since as long as Google's existed. Is there like an SEO
Speaker 3:  industry for TikTok and for YouTube and for these other
Speaker 6:  Platforms? Oh yeah, dude, yeah.
Speaker 3:  But is it as big?
Speaker 6:  It's, I don't know if it's as big, but I, the difference
Speaker 6:  is like the SEO industry is, it's
Speaker 6:  diffuse, right? It's like copy writers and keyword
Speaker 6:  experts and whatever. Like there are agencies and they have different kinda
Speaker 6:  like pieces of the puzzle and there's just like a lot of like yeah.
Speaker 6:  Generalized SEO knowledge that exists because Google is big and
Speaker 6:  it's like hard to wrap your head around the fact that Google search is a
Speaker 6:  platform, right? You think the web is a platform, right? But like Google
Speaker 6:  search is a, pla is a discovery platform, just like Instagram is a discovery
Speaker 6:  platform. The other platforms, TikTok, whatever, because there's like
Speaker 6:  a unification there between the creation tool, the distribution tool, and
Speaker 6:  the discovery engine. Those people are not like SEO experts, they're just
Speaker 6:  like a TikTok creative agency. Yeah, right. Like our audience team is
Speaker 6:  like, here are the TikTok trends that we should do on, on the vir decoder
Speaker 6:  this week. And I'm like, we don't do, we should do them more. Like,
Speaker 6:  you know, there's that one where like people were like sad on a boat and
Speaker 6:  like the decoder team was like, you gotta make a deco that's, we're actually
Speaker 6:  doing that next week. I was like, I dunno, I can do this.
Speaker 6:  I love boats, but I don't like being sad on them. And I, there's, I I think
Speaker 6:  that unification from the other platforms makes makes them easier to perceive,
Speaker 6:  right? You can like I like that. Yeah, Instagram is a platform. You can
Speaker 6:  kind of see the beginning and end of it. You can see the whole thing Google
Speaker 6:  search, like no one can perceive it, right? And it feels organic.
Speaker 6:  And again, these are like very sarcastic air quotes. Like it feels like you
Speaker 6:  ask the robot a question, the robot tells you to answer it, but then you,
Speaker 6:  you like really poke at it. You're like, oh, it's like better to search Reddit.
Speaker 6:  Right? Or it's like there's a reason people think that chat G P T will replace
Speaker 6:  Google. It's because it doesn't return SEO spam to you. It just
Speaker 6:  confidently lies to you. And like it turns out, like what
Speaker 6:  is, what is the lesson of the world of the immediate ecosystem from 2016
Speaker 6:  on confident lies are very popular. I'm sorry, I'm laughing.
Speaker 7:  Well, I think something that I've noticed with kind of the way that people
Speaker 7:  are using search engines and we, we sometimes we talk about how, especially
Speaker 7:  young people, they'll search TikTok or something instead of searching Google.
Speaker 7:  And I was talking to a friend of mine the other day and, and I had a thought
Speaker 7:  that it's not necessarily that they trust the results
Speaker 7:  of when you search on TikTok, those things are, are black boxes. You, you
Speaker 7:  still don't know why it gave you this result or that result over another.
Speaker 7:  It's, but for us old people, when we used to dial
Speaker 7:  into a, a customer service line and hit zero or we're yelling
Speaker 7:  operator, you just want hear from a person. Yeah. And
Speaker 7:  that's what TikTok or Instagram can give you is an, or Reddit
Speaker 7:  especially, can give you an answer that appears to come from a person now
Speaker 7:  with chat G P T, who knows? But yeah, it appears to come from a real
Speaker 7:  human being somewhere. And there, there's, there's something about that that
Speaker 7:  you'd probably have the, you'd probably rather have that than the correct
Speaker 7:  answer. And, and Google has been promising the correct answer and it's not
Speaker 7:  delivering that anyway. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And I I'm telling you, Google, this is gonna be a bad year for Google. They've
Speaker 6:  got, they've gotta deal with it from both sides, right? So first people are
Speaker 6:  gonna start talking to chat G P T and Google itself cannot deliver
Speaker 6:  that technology. They invented it like that Transformer tech, the t and chat
Speaker 6:  G B T is Google Transformer like they made it and they
Speaker 6:  have the big models, they have LLMs that can compete that they, like
Speaker 6:  Google will tell you are better than chat G P T, but they can't release it
Speaker 6:  because they know it will confidently lie to people. It will tell people
Speaker 6:  the wrong answer. It will feed people misinformation with such
Speaker 6:  confidence that people will believe it. And if you're Google, that is
Speaker 6:  a, that's existential risk for you.
Speaker 3:  We did a, we did a story this week about how this guy had made
Speaker 3:  use chat g p t to make an entire voice assistant. And he
Speaker 3:  was like, yeah, it works really well. It works so much better than Siri.
Speaker 3:  I hope I didn't just Siri, but
Speaker 3:  the reason he was like this would never make the mainstream is that this
Speaker 3:  thing will confidently tell you the wrong information or confidently be like,
Speaker 3:  now you're a white supremacist like chat. G p t doesn't have all those
Speaker 3:  barriers in place that Google's put up, but Google is also getting
Speaker 3:  so gamed by other people and has like failing
Speaker 3:  to stop that gaming. I keep wondering, is somebody gonna make an add-on
Speaker 3:  for Google where you just automatically blacklist sites that you know,
Speaker 3:  ooh, suck and don't actually give you answers.
Speaker 6:  Right? But
Speaker 3:  Actually I have to go talk to Graham, excuse
Speaker 6:  Me, but here's what I'm saying something Google
Speaker 3:  Right
Speaker 6:  Now, so Google's got an input problem,
Speaker 6:  right?
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Man, what I'm gonna get this wrong. If you can do the framing of this
Speaker 6:  better, please let me know. Google has a supply problem.
Speaker 6:  That's the first thing. So Google, it's the
Speaker 6:  suppliers are websites, the, the Verge polygon, whatever it is.
Speaker 6:  And we publish stories and we hope Google searches them. And if you
Speaker 6:  search for inside Twitter's first 90 days, we very much hope
Speaker 6:  that you land on the verge.com. Okay? Fair enough. The
Speaker 6:  problem is the supply that is being fed into Google is being overrun
Speaker 6:  by SEO optimized AI garbage, right? And so Google has to deal
Speaker 6:  with that first. Then they've got like a, a demand
Speaker 6:  problem. This is where if you have a better framing, let me know they have
Speaker 6:  a demand problem, which is the people coming to
Speaker 6:  Google are increasingly like, but I could just ask chat g p t
Speaker 6:  and they won't deliver me this garbage. Or I could just ask Alexa, or I could
Speaker 6:  just ask Siri or Bing actually has a, you know, Microsoft has a
Speaker 6:  huge funding. The old open AI Bing is gonna integrate traction.
Speaker 6:  Maybe maybe people are gonna start asking Bing
Speaker 6:  what the stranger things have happened. Apple came back from the dead, right?
Speaker 6:  CBS bought CNET for 1.8 billion in 2000.
Speaker 6:  Who knows what's gonna happen? So they've got like this weird supply problem
Speaker 6:  or a demand problem where the people who use Google increasingly think the
Speaker 6:  product is not good and they're searching Reddit or they're searching TikTok
Speaker 6:  or whatever. And the suppliers of Google's results
Speaker 6:  are increasingly cynical and flooding it with garbage, which makes the
Speaker 6:  demand problem worse. Right? And how do you, how does Google get,
Speaker 6:  this is their money. This is what they got. Yeah. Right. Like I,
Speaker 6:  there's not a Google messaging platform that makes money or exists
Speaker 6:  or is used, right? Like they, they have this and they have YouTube and
Speaker 6:  if this goes away, like Google Falls apart, and I, I think they just gotta,
Speaker 6:  I don't, they have to articulate a path through it and they have not done
Speaker 6:  that yet. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Well, and they've, they often refuse to like, this isn't a new problem.
Speaker 3:  SEO gaming in absolute garbage being the top of the search results is
Speaker 3:  a problem they've been dealing with for the, for the entire time Google's
Speaker 3:  existed. But they never articulate that problem or treat it as
Speaker 3:  what they are they, what you said, their platform. They don't
Speaker 3:  view themselves as a platform. They don't view their problem as a platform,
Speaker 3:  as a content moderation problem. They view it as like an engineering
Speaker 3:  really Twitter, Elon Musk kind of way. They view it as an engineering problem.
Speaker 3:  And as long as they continue to do that, I think we're gonna just have garbage.
Speaker 3:  When you go search Google and then you go to Reddit,
Speaker 7:  You remember before Google when there were search engines that
Speaker 7:  weren't Google that people used and they were just indexes mama. And there
Speaker 7:  was just some guy who was like, these are the TV websites or these are the
Speaker 7:  websites that you can go to for NFL Richard
Speaker 6:  Lawler tv websites list.com
Speaker 7:  Down. You can go down folders to the entire end of the internet
Speaker 7:  because someone had listed every single thing and there was, there was at
Speaker 7:  his heart a person. Yeah. And now you have Google, which
Speaker 7:  assumed that all the data coming into it was reliable that all those links,
Speaker 7:  they meant, they meant something that, that if you, if you link something,
Speaker 7:  it must have been a person who put that there because they liked it. And
Speaker 7:  that just isn't true anymore. That just, that that world is gone now. I
Speaker 6:  Like that your fut your prediction of like the future of the web is back
Speaker 6:  to Yahoo, like OG Yahoo
Speaker 7:  InfoSec
Speaker 6:  Obviously Infoseek, we should make a custom cure. I have
Speaker 6:  so many products. Okay, if you can turn the Verge home page into a mass instance,
Speaker 6:  like let me know. We'll just do that on the side and I'll go to the CO and
Speaker 6:  be like, Hey, look at what I did and we'll see how long I stay in this drum
Speaker 6:  open to it. Hit me up. And if you want to code like a hand
Speaker 6:  curated like vintage 1999 search engine.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Could be pretty sweet. I'm gonna lie,
Speaker 6:  be sick. But I really do think like ye yes. Cena, yes ai,
Speaker 6:  yes, it's a scandal. And you should read that story. Mia and James did a
Speaker 6:  fantastic job of that story. I'm just telling you that is a scandal. That
Speaker 6:  it's like the symptom and the disease is
Speaker 6:  the absolute rot of the web platform. And in
Speaker 6:  particular how Google search has influenced the web platform. And like I'm
Speaker 6:  tell like this year I will tell you is it's either up or down.
Speaker 6:  Like there something is gonna happen in there because all of the other places
Speaker 6:  people make content are, are effectively closed. Right? And
Speaker 6:  I always joke that at, you know, the, the end point of every U YouTuber's
Speaker 6:  initial life cycle before they become a butterfly is the video where they're
Speaker 6:  like, I'm pissed at YouTube. And then like, yeah, the light bulb goes off
Speaker 6:  and they realize, oh, I'm just playing the game. Right? And that doesn't
Speaker 6:  happen on the web and it's because, because we don't recognize that like
Speaker 6:  Google is the controlling influence of the web. I think it's because its
Speaker 6:  name is Google and it's like logo looks like it was made by a five-year-old.
Speaker 6:  Like we just don't, we can't perceive it. Well I
Speaker 3:  Think you have, you have different paths into, into websites than you do.
Speaker 3:  Like Google is the primary path for the majority of people for like the vast,
Speaker 3:  vast majority of people. More people than most of our listeners. Probably
Speaker 3:  fully understand Google is that way. But there's still other ways. You still
Speaker 3:  go and read places like the verge.com and we point you to cool stuff
Speaker 3:  or your mom sends you a cool link. Like there's still other ways to get to
Speaker 3:  this stuff. That's
Speaker 6:  It's just third product. Third product and it's just a distribution system
Speaker 6:  for Alex's mom to send people links. It
Speaker 3:  Would be terrible. You'd get one link
Speaker 6:  A day and I guarantee you we'll be able to game that one better than anyone
Speaker 6:  else. But it'll be honest.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, you'll know a person did
Speaker 6:  It. You'll know that I made Alex specifically tell her mom to pick the
Speaker 6:  verge version of the story.
Speaker 6:  All right, we gotta take another break. We'll be right back. We gotta talk
Speaker 6:  about this new Apple stuff. M two chips and new. It's great. We'll be right
Speaker 6:  back.
Speaker 6:  All right, we're back a bunch of stuff. We have lot to talk about, all of
Speaker 6:  which like happened in the last eight seconds. We announced a new
Speaker 6:  MacBook Pro with the M two PRO and M two max chip, a New Mac mini with
Speaker 6:  M two and M two pro ships, then new HomePod. There's a rumor that
Speaker 6:  they're doing some sort of weird Google homey smart display.
Speaker 6:  Microsoft had layoffs. They're talking about Reju a hardware portfolio, which
Speaker 6:  is really interesting. And of course Netflix, Reed Hastings,
Speaker 6:  founder and CEO step down new co CEOs at Netflix.
Speaker 6:  Let's start with Apple. I feel like we have to, we've made people sit through
Speaker 6:  Yeah, a, a long and winding
Speaker 6:  argument about the future of the web. I would say that's why you come here.
Speaker 6:  But I think you also come here for us to complain about the MacBook Pro.
Speaker 6:  So
Speaker 6:  this is more or less what we are expecting. Don't you think that it's the
Speaker 6:  same design and then Yeah, the M two PRO and M two max
Speaker 6:  kind of the same basic idea as the M one PRO and M
Speaker 6:  one max. They just stitched more 'em
Speaker 3:  Together. Yeah, it's, it's just the M one faster
Speaker 6:  Like, and like linearly faster, right? Like faster by
Speaker 6:  core counts.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. They were like, we added more cores, now it's faster. And you're like,
Speaker 3:  thank you. They, that's what I wanted.
Speaker 6:  They did say that these are the longest battery life
Speaker 6:  ever in a Mac laptop, which is pretty incredible
Speaker 3:  That I'm really excited about because the M two didn't,
Speaker 3:  when we, when we reviewed the M two in the MacBook Air, it didn't get better
Speaker 3:  battery life, but it also had a totally different design than the M
Speaker 3:  one MacBook Air. So I'm really, really curious to see how these M two
Speaker 3:  14 and 16 inch laptops hold up to the previous version.
Speaker 6:  It's also interesting to me that Apple is starting to just admit that people
Speaker 6:  use Creative Cloud. So they say the Macro Pro MT Pro is able to process
Speaker 6:  images in Adobe Photoshop up to 40% faster than the M one Pro and up to
Speaker 6:  80% faster than MacBook Pro with a core I nine. Okay. I mean, I
Speaker 6:  have an M one Pro, MacBook Pro 16 inch is the best computer
Speaker 6:  I've ever owned. Yeah, you love it. I mean, I don't, I don't use Photoshop
Speaker 6:  enough to need a 40% boost, but that's pretty impressive from one
Speaker 6:  generation to another, I think.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Yeah. And like the, the, the jumps sound really, really
Speaker 3:  impressive. And I think we just have to wait and see because Apple is
Speaker 3:  also still learning how to talk about processors and speed bumps and they
Speaker 3:  still do lots of charts that have no meaning. And so we
Speaker 6:  Still need to Oh, can I talk about these fucking charts?
Speaker 3:  Let's talk about the charts. I think
Speaker 6:  They made them just
Speaker 3:  For you. I was hoping you'd wanna talk about the charts.
Speaker 6:  Okay. So usually I complain about these charts. You do.
Speaker 6:  And usually what I complain about is that the Y axes aren't
Speaker 6:  labeled.
Speaker 3:  It's simply good.
Speaker 6:  Pretty normal. If you're in the, if you're in the business of complaining
Speaker 6:  about charts like isn't chestnut, you just bring this outta your back pocket.
Speaker 6:  You're like, they didn't label the Y axes. And everyone's like, oh. And like
Speaker 6:  you playing the hits, you know,
Speaker 6:  app Apple has now gotten to a place where
Speaker 6:  there are effectively no axes at all. Yes.
Speaker 6:  And nothing is labeled. So it's like, see how the M two PRO and
Speaker 6:  M two max stack up and then it's just some lines
Speaker 6:  with no axes and it just, the M two
Speaker 6:  max MacBook Pro is purple and it just says
Speaker 6:  15.9 x
Speaker 3:  I, I wanna judge them. But when I was first doing
Speaker 3:  processor benchmarks and I would post charts, I also
Speaker 3:  did that cuz I was like, people just wanna see a line go up. They don't care
Speaker 3:  about the
Speaker 6:  Axes. Yeah. No, dude, who are you talking about? They're chip nerds.
Speaker 3:  Commenters schooled me on how wrong I was.
Speaker 6:  These are, they're their brains are graphs.
Speaker 3:  I, I, I picked up eventually.
Speaker 6:  It's like an EKG machine.
Speaker 3:  I don't, but I don't judge 'em because I personally, I just wanna see it
Speaker 3:  go up As
Speaker 6:  Long
Speaker 7:  As the one number is higher than the other number. That's all that matters.
Speaker 7:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  That is the, the only, I'm just telling you, you look at the track, go on
Speaker 6:  apple.com/macbook Pro 14 and 16, like that's not
Speaker 6:  quite the url. But you'll, you'll get there, you'll click on it, you'll understand
Speaker 6:  that I was close enough and you scroll down and you're like, okay, this purple
Speaker 6:  line is 9.4 x compared
Speaker 6:  to Intel-based MacBook Pro. And you're like, what does that
Speaker 6:  mean? Is it in time?
Speaker 6:  Is it in units of performance? Is it in just
Speaker 6:  fast? Is it in smiles? There's not,
Speaker 6:  there's not a unit. I'm one assumes it's
Speaker 6:  time, but is it minutes? Is it seconds? Like
Speaker 12:  Wait, there's a three, there's a three. There's a, there's a note at the
Speaker 12:  bottom. I'm still scrolling.
Speaker 6:  Go ahead.
Speaker 12:  I'm still there. Testing can, oh, this is what it's testing on.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, no, I read the note dog. It's not
Speaker 6:  gonna help you. Doesn't
Speaker 12:  Say no answers there.
Speaker 6:  It's just a list of specs in the, the frame rate of the movie file
Speaker 6:  and the resolution in the file that it transcoded. I I'm just telling you,
Speaker 6:  you it is, it's bold, it's powerful. It's
Speaker 6:  avant-garde. It's now to say, you know what NEA yelled at us about the
Speaker 6:  YIs for so long, it's killed it. We're taking out the fucking X axis and
Speaker 6:  units fine. Like fine.
Speaker 3:  It's
Speaker 6:  Just fast. The next, I guarantee you the next time around it's just gonna
Speaker 6:  be a purple bar with no units. Like, not even this like relative
Speaker 6:  9.4.
Speaker 3:  I'm just gonna say
Speaker 6:  Fast. I'm sure the chip is very fast. I I, again, I
Speaker 6:  have a M one Pro MacBook Pro, great computer,
Speaker 6:  best computer I've ever earned. Every time I look at these units, every time
Speaker 6:  I look at these charts, I'm just like furious with
Speaker 3:  That. I like that the M one max is faster than the M two
Speaker 3:  Pro, but you wouldn't necessarily notice that because it's a different color.
Speaker 3:  Oh yeah, yeah, yeah. And almost the same color as like
Speaker 6:  The background. I'm just, I'm telling you right now, if you just look at
Speaker 6:  these charts, oh, that's the other thing. So it's video. They changed
Speaker 6:  the comparison
Speaker 3:  What
Speaker 6:  Things left a color on 16 inch model, which has the M two max
Speaker 6:  is compared against a core I nine and radi on Pro 5,600
Speaker 6:  M. That is the, that bar is one. And then you click to the
Speaker 6:  14 inch model and it's a shorter bar,
Speaker 6:  but it's a MacBook Crow with an Intel core I seven and presumably integrated
Speaker 6:  graphics. There's just no way to know what's going on
Speaker 6:  here.
Speaker 3:  I'm loving it.
Speaker 6:  Probably still bad at gaming.
Speaker 3:  This is great. Is
Speaker 6:  That's brutal. So they're claiming longest battery life ever in a Mac. The
Speaker 6:  16 inch model with the M two PRO is supposed to get
Speaker 6:  22 hours in video playback. Which again, we should caveat you should go watch
Speaker 6:  Joanna Stern's video. That's with all of the radios off and the brightness
Speaker 6:  turned all the along and like looping one video in QuickTime.
Speaker 6:  And if that's you, you're getting almost a full day of that
Speaker 6:  experience.
Speaker 3:  Enjoy.
Speaker 6:  Like let me know if that's you. And then 15 hours of
Speaker 6:  wireless web browsing that's supposed to be an hour longer than the previous
Speaker 6:  M one Pro, which we got 16 hours out of when we actually did it, which was
Speaker 6:  longer than their average. So we're very excited to test the
Speaker 6:  battery life on these things. Test the performance again. The chip seems
Speaker 6:  great. I think the Mac mini at 5 99, that's, that's, it's getting
Speaker 6:  real close to impulse by territory for me.
Speaker 3:  That's
Speaker 6:  A good, like I don't need that computer and I'm like, Ooh. But that's, it's
Speaker 6:  pretty good.
Speaker 3:  I like, I don't wanna bully you into buying things, but you should buy
Speaker 6:  It. You know, I bullied David Pearson to buying an M one mini. He was like
Speaker 6:  complaining about his computer. I was like, dude, it's like 5 99. He was
Speaker 6:  like, oh, it's a good deal.
Speaker 3:  Just do it. Well and this
Speaker 6:  Is the first, so there's a, there's some weirdness here, right? With the
Speaker 6:  Mac Mini? Yeah, the Mac Studio, the forthcoming Mac Pro, which we're now,
Speaker 6:  you know, Germin at Bloomberg reported it's gonna be in the same case and
Speaker 6:  there's just some weirdness with that part of the Mac line.
Speaker 6:  But I would tell you that I'm fully accepting of it because
Speaker 6:  Apple's Mac line used to be weird in the wrong way. This
Speaker 3:  Is a good weird,
Speaker 6:  Which is like they clearly hated these products and didn't want you to buy
Speaker 6:  them. And now it's weird in the best way and that there are too many good
Speaker 6:  choices. Like I'll I'll take that.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Like I have no FOMO about my my Mac studio. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  I feel great. I I didn't look at this MAC Mini and go, oh man I should've
Speaker 3:  waited another year with my 2012 MacBook Pro.
Speaker 6:  The, the second this thing goes on sale or there's like a good refurb, it's
Speaker 6:  over. Ugh. Like I'll be like Max, you're not going to college. But the chip
Speaker 6:  in this computer is named after
Speaker 7:  Hd my 2.1. What were
Speaker 6:  You supposed to do? Yeah, no that's right. Right. I get AK monitor. What's
Speaker 6:  the only thing I've ever complained about with my MacBook Pro is it have
Speaker 6:  HCA 2.1, do I consistently plug it into a seven 20 P
Speaker 6:  curve monitor Curve TV that I use only for Zoom? I do.
Speaker 6:  But should that be HDMI 2.1? It should, yeah.
Speaker 3:  But you can get the MAC
Speaker 6:  Mini in general. I mean these are fine refreshes. Here's the weird thing.
Speaker 6:  So they put them out with just kind of like press releases. They
Speaker 6:  both have like long videos with them about the new Mac, the new chips. It
Speaker 6:  feels like there was supposed to be an event, like this is the cut up of
Speaker 6:  the event video that we would otherwise see and they just like did it
Speaker 3:  Right
Speaker 6:  And like was there supposed to be an event and they just
Speaker 6:  didn't have, they didn't have the ER glasses or whatever it is and they're
Speaker 6:  like, we're just putting 'em out.
Speaker 3:  Yeah cuz Germin is saying that there was supposed to be an event
Speaker 3:  and the glasses were gonna be there and now they're like Ugh, the glasses
Speaker 3:  aren't ready. Don't worry about the glasses.
Speaker 6:  I am. Keep going. I'm right now lt, here's what I tell you in my heart, I
Speaker 6:  think AR glasses are in the exact same hype timeline as self-driving
Speaker 6:  cars.
Speaker 3:  Oh I like
Speaker 6:  That. I think we're gonna be a lot older before we see self-driving cars
Speaker 6:  or AR glasses. For real.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Like it would be wild if, if Apple had solved the
Speaker 3:  display issues with AR or all of the other myriad of issues
Speaker 3:  with
Speaker 6:  Yeah, we've gone through the stack many times in the show. You need to build
Speaker 6:  a display that has sufficient resolution to look like reality. But you
Speaker 6:  can still see through that mounts on your face and is comfortable to wear.
Speaker 6:  You need to have a processor that can do all of that in real time.
Speaker 6:  You need to put cameras around that display so you can, the processor can
Speaker 6:  see reality image it and spit out an augmented version of reality
Speaker 6:  on top of it. Then you need to have a battery and then you need to have connectivity
Speaker 6:  and all of it. Can't get too hot and eats last all day. Like good luck. Like
Speaker 6:  we're gonna be a lot older. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  De Coil is never happening. But I don't, I don't know they,
Speaker 7:  it seems like they're kind of close with the $3,000 headset that no one's
Speaker 7:  actually going to buy with an M two chip in it and of VR chip and
Speaker 7:  it's people
Speaker 3:  Are
Speaker 7:  Gonna buy that something that goes into your back pocket, they're going to
Speaker 7:  buy it and do what?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. No they have the Quest
Speaker 3:  Pro YouTube videos showing
Speaker 6:  This is the Quest Pro problem. The Quest Pro is this product. Yeah. And maybe
Speaker 6:  it's a little worse than Apple's product. Maybe on some dimension it's a
Speaker 6:  little bit better. Who knows? But it's basically this product, it has worse
Speaker 6:  software, whatever. But you're like, oh this is woo, like the ar
Speaker 6:  pass through of that thing isn't like not good. And like the Metaverse is
Speaker 6:  no fun and the the children are still looking for Addie cuz she was the
Speaker 6:  only girl.
Speaker 6:  We'll we'll see, I but you get the feeling there was supposed to be something
Speaker 6:  else and this was supposed to be an event and they can't have an event to
Speaker 6:  announce a chip bump in the MacBook Pro. It's like here we are. They can't
Speaker 6:  have an event to be like the Home pod's back. So they just like put it out.
Speaker 6:  Oh the home pod's back and it's still the same speaker. Apparent should,
Speaker 6:  we should talk about the HomePod. So those are the Macs. We're M two. They
Speaker 6:  seem cool. We're excited to test them when we get them. Cool
Speaker 6:  the next day. Another press release, another video.
Speaker 6:  The home pod's back y'all.
Speaker 3:  Woo.
Speaker 6:  And I, I think people were expecting it to be changed more than it
Speaker 6:  is. No,
Speaker 3:  I, no I don't think anybody was. Cuz all you wanted was thread
Speaker 3:  and to not feel like you're gonna go to jail when you take the court
Speaker 3:  out and now you can take the court out without feeling like
Speaker 3:  you're gonna break something.
Speaker 6:  The European police are coming for you.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, they are
Speaker 6:  Right now. So it's 2 99. It looks We have, we
Speaker 6:  have to see them the same. Same. But it looks the same as the original
Speaker 6:  HomePod. They're saying there's a new color which they're calling midnight.
Speaker 6:  It's, yeah, it's the same. It's, they make, there's a, a white-ish
Speaker 6:  one and there's a black-ish one. I dunno what to tell you.
Speaker 6:  Before it was gray, now it's midnight. They've added thread in matter support.
Speaker 6:  Although apples matter support, it's a little rocky right now. Yeah. It has
Speaker 6:  temperature and humidity sensors. The HomePod Mini also has temperature and
Speaker 6:  humidity sensors. Those are being enabled now.
Speaker 3:  Which got activated. Yeah. Like those, those HomePod mini sensors got
Speaker 3:  activated with this announcement. Okay. If you have the software update,
Speaker 6:  That's cool. It has worse wifi for some reason.
Speaker 6:  Deeply confusing. But honestly who cares
Speaker 3:  Unless tweeters.
Speaker 6:  Right. So the, if you remember the first generation HomePod, I went outside
Speaker 6:  California. I went to Apple's big audio testing facility. It
Speaker 6:  was, it was a cool day. You know they put, you know they put me in one of
Speaker 6:  those rooms where like, you can't hear anything. Yeah. Are you crazy yet?
Speaker 6:  And I was like, no it's fine. But you know, like everyone, it's like you
Speaker 6:  go to enough events like this and people show you the, they all have the
Speaker 6:  same room with like the foam spikes and you can't hear anything. You're like
Speaker 6:  yeah, like people have these and they play the speaker for you and they always
Speaker 6:  play Hotel California cuz Apple is at it's heart a boomer company.
Speaker 6:  Yes. It's just real. And so this time and, but the point at the
Speaker 6:  HomePod at that time was that it was the best sounding speaker, right? All
Speaker 6:  of their emphasis was on speaker stuff. And they had the
Speaker 6:  four inch low excursion woofer.
Speaker 6:  They had seven tweeters. They're doing all this beam forming. They were measuring
Speaker 6:  how far away you were from the wall so they could bounce audio
Speaker 6:  off the wall and send it to you all at the same time and create a bigger
Speaker 6:  stereo sound. Feel they're getting more bass. It was cool. It sounded fine.
Speaker 6:  I would say, I think I, I went back and reread my original HomePod review.
Speaker 6:  You should go watch it. It was very fun to do. I have a lot of speakers in
Speaker 6:  my house. The whole video team came to my house, like set up all the speakers
Speaker 6:  everywhere. It was like fun. And our takeaway was, you know, it's like the
Speaker 6:  HomePod that whatever high end Alexa device was back then, the Sonos one,
Speaker 6:  we just had a whole list of, we had a Bluetooth speaker and we're like, of
Speaker 6:  the ones that you think of as the competitors, the HomePod and the Sonos
Speaker 6:  say they sound different. The HomePod wins some, the Sonos wins. Some
Speaker 6:  others. If you are not comparing them directly side by side,
Speaker 6:  they're indistinguishable. Like you will just be happy with iron. They
Speaker 3:  Both sound nice
Speaker 6:  And so you should pick the one that fits into the ecosystem of your life.
Speaker 6:  And foremost, people that was not the HomePod, like couldn't do two
Speaker 6:  timers at once, didn't recognize multiple users. Just,
Speaker 6:  it was just weird. It was just a weird product in like the
Speaker 6:  Sonos products, like Alexa products or whatever else. They were all better
Speaker 6:  because they were better smart home products. Now the thing's back, I think
Speaker 6:  the HomePod mini has been more of a success than like Apple Times was cheap
Speaker 6:  success, but it's like doing fine. But the hobo itself failed. Now it's back.
Speaker 6:  They've cut down the tweeters from seven to five.
Speaker 6:  They've cut down the microphones from seven to five.
Speaker 6:  They say it sounds better than the original. We gotta do a head-to-head
Speaker 6:  all the same beam forming, processings, whatever. We'll see. But the real
Speaker 6:  thing is like matter support is there thread support is there, home kit has
Speaker 6:  been improved. Siri can set two timers at once. Now I think
Speaker 6:  is that, is that enough?
Speaker 3:  Only when it remembers to be connected to the internet, which
Speaker 3:  it still sometimes is. Like, I'm not connected to the internet even while
Speaker 3:  it's playing your music. So it won't stop your music because it doesn't think
Speaker 3:  it's connected to the internet. That just happened yesterday. Sorry, I'm
Speaker 3:  really heated about
Speaker 6:  It. Oh, I'm sorry. It is slightly different in terms of design. It's a little
Speaker 6:  shorter. It's 0.2 inches shorter and it weighs
Speaker 6:  5.16 pounds instead of 5.5. But that's what you get when you lose two tweeters
Speaker 6:  in two minutes. I
Speaker 7:  Feel like we saw the same thing with the original Google Home and then the
Speaker 7:  speaker that they came out with after that that like the first one was slightly
Speaker 7:  over-engineered in terms of what they were able to do with the audio, with
Speaker 7:  the hardwood that they had in it. And then the second one, they took a lot
Speaker 7:  of that out. They said, yeah, we don't really need all of these parts. Yeah,
Speaker 7:  we, we can, we can sell the people who are going to buy these. Don't care
Speaker 7:  if it's five or seven. Yeah. So we'll just go with five.
Speaker 6:  Well here's what I know. Yeah. Every tech company, when they sell you, when
Speaker 6:  they sell their first speaker, like people care about sign quality
Speaker 6:  and then they try really hard and God bless them
Speaker 6:  baby's first speaker, you gonna try really hard. And they ship to speaker
Speaker 6:  and he turns out people care about his convenience and price and
Speaker 6:  people will throw away sound quality at the drop of a hat. And I think that's
Speaker 6:  very much been the experience of the HomePod. And now they're here. There's
Speaker 6:  some TV stuff that's good Richard. So it can pair with an Apple tv.
Speaker 6:  Apple TV's not support er. So
Speaker 6:  in a bizarre signal chain, you can plug your Apple TV
Speaker 6:  into your smart tv, plug your PS five into your smart tv,
Speaker 6:  have the PS five, send audio to the tv, the tv, send audio back
Speaker 6:  out to the Apple TV over er, the Apple tv, then send the audio
Speaker 6:  to your Apple Home pods. And then you listen to your PS five
Speaker 6:  on your home pods.
Speaker 3:  Or you could just buy a receiver.
Speaker 7:  The latency,
Speaker 6:  I mean, yeah, the receiver crew rise up,
Speaker 6:  you know,
Speaker 3:  But with an pl with airplay too in it. And boom,
Speaker 6:  Done. People like using their home pods with their Apple TVs. And now with
Speaker 6:  with er, you can eat your game consoles. E even could get, you have an
Speaker 6:  Apple TV plug in your smart TV and you're somehow using a smart TV app,
Speaker 6:  sending the audio out from ER through an Apple TV to your HomePod.
Speaker 3:  Oh my gosh, that's just
Speaker 6:  Nasty. Just email us. I wanna know who you are and how you've come to that
Speaker 6:  position in your life.
Speaker 6:  Dying to know. There
Speaker 7:  Was a discussion about where you were going to put speakers and the only
Speaker 7:  thing that someone would let you put was two home pods that no one can see.
Speaker 3:  Oh, I know why they would do that. Because for the longest time
Speaker 3:  you, the Apple TV didn't do like
Speaker 3:  4K hdr Dolby Vision. I think it was 4K Dolby vision on Amazon Prime.
Speaker 3:  So you could only do that with the native,
Speaker 6:  But it does it now
Speaker 3:  Smart TV apps. But maybe that person
Speaker 3:  hasn't updated their Apple
Speaker 6:  Tv, but somehow they've updated it to the, the only, the new ones I have.
Speaker 6:  Er
Speaker 3:  Look, I don't know this person's life
Speaker 7:  They've made, they've made some choices.
Speaker 6:  And then lastly, the HomePod supports spatial audio. Toby Atmos,
Speaker 6:  I'm just gonna say this out loud directly, full
Speaker 6:  honesty, full transparency. HomePod announcement comes out, I'm like, oh,
Speaker 6:  HomePod, I love speakers. Read about the speakers, read about spa audio.
Speaker 6:  Everyone's excited. I have an atmos, I have a real receiver
Speaker 6:  5.2 0.2 set, big, the whole thing. I'm like, I'm
Speaker 6:  listen to some Atmos music. Cue up Apple Music on the Apple
Speaker 6:  tv, pick their spatial audio show off playlist list. It fucking
Speaker 6:  sucks. Spatial audio sucks. It's horrible and I
Speaker 6:  hate it. It's the worst.
Speaker 3:  Why does
Speaker 6:  It suck? Because it removes all the impact for music.
Speaker 6:  Because everyone's drunk on having so many channels. It's
Speaker 3:  Sneaking up on you.
Speaker 6:  They spread everything out. And so everything, like you just have this
Speaker 6:  massive sound stage for no reason. You don't need it. And like all the
Speaker 6:  bottom end, all the impact, all the presence is like deleted.
Speaker 6:  And it just, every single time it sounds worse
Speaker 6:  in particular on the low end, it texted somebody who would know and
Speaker 6:  they're like, yo, yeah, you gotta turn your sub's way up if you're listening
Speaker 6:  to Atmos. And it's like, what? Because to compensate for like the
Speaker 6:  drunk sound engineers of Hollywood being like, put it in all the channels
Speaker 6:  instead of concentrating it into stereo channels. The one
Speaker 6:  Atmos track I listened to yesterday on this person's recommendation was boom
Speaker 6:  by tto. It was awesome. I will admit this was awesome because
Speaker 6:  it is a high energy dance track with lots of beeps and boobs and
Speaker 6:  it was clearly made to fuck with people on drugs and the beeps and boobs
Speaker 6:  just swirl around you in like an ever oh, ever escalating
Speaker 6:  sound field. And I was like, if I was on drugs, this would rule, like this
Speaker 6:  would be the best experience in my life. And that was the only one. It sucks.
Speaker 6:  I don't like, why do we have to keep lying about spatial audio being any
Speaker 6:  good? I don't know anybody who likes it. We don't. I ask music executives,
Speaker 6:  do you think it's good? And I'm like, it's getting better.
Speaker 3:  Tim Cook just standing behind them. We
Speaker 6:  Had Charlie Harding on Decoder. That's a fun episode. We talked about
Speaker 6:  music and street, Taylor Swift, all this stuff. And he was like, the only
Speaker 6:  reason Apple is this invested in spatial is because
Speaker 6:  they need it for all their ar metaverse play that
Speaker 6:  they're, they're trying to do. Right? So they they need all these extra channels
Speaker 6:  in the music. They need spatial audio so that when they put you in the, the
Speaker 6:  virtual reality or they put you in AR and all this stuff and you're
Speaker 6:  moving around, they can manipulate the music properly. And like
Speaker 6:  maybe I believe that
Speaker 3:  Wait is, is Apple's ar killer
Speaker 3:  app gonna be like going to concerts?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. So it's like if you do, if you have a good spatial mix and Apple puts
Speaker 6:  you in like a Metaverse concert or whatever, they already have the content.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. More importantly, they've already built like the spatial audio
Speaker 6:  pipelines and the processing into their consumer devices and
Speaker 6:  AirPods and whatever, right? Like they've built an ecosystem around spatial
Speaker 6:  audio so that when that stuff is there, there's content, there's user experience,
Speaker 6:  there's lots of people know how to use the tools like it's primed and ready
Speaker 6:  in the best Apple way. That's Apple's very good at sort of like stepping
Speaker 6:  you up layer by layer and then launching the device that adds it all up.
Speaker 6:  I'm just like, but right now it sucks. Look,
Speaker 6:  it, this is like a, it's like a real deal at most system.
Speaker 6:  It's, it's, I was like, this sucks. Like this is making my stereo sound
Speaker 6:  bad. Yeah. And I tried it. Get headphones like these make my headphones.
Speaker 6:  I don't know if you love facial audio, let let me know. But I, I think there's
Speaker 6:  a reason it's always demoed with like live recordings of the Eagles.
Speaker 6:  Mm. Because like one,
Speaker 3:  That's all
Speaker 6:  I listen to is the reporters get, is the influencers and reporters get younger,
Speaker 6:  they have no idea what they're listening to. And you can just be like kids
Speaker 6:  back in the day, Don Henley, you know Don Henley is
Speaker 6:  listen to those guitar talents man. And they're like a guitar and like, fine,
Speaker 6:  we used to have bands, right? It's like an you can just confuse people by
Speaker 6:  playing the Eagles at them, but I'm just telling you, turn it off and just
Speaker 6:  listen to how much more impact like literal impact music has when it's off
Speaker 6:  versus on and you're like, why? What am I gaining? And the answer is nothing.
Speaker 6:  Sorry, I'm just ranting on spa audio now. It's horrible.
Speaker 3:  I like, I I haven't turned it on and on.
Speaker 7:  Get get it off you obviously you, you have feelings about this. We're here
Speaker 7:  for you.
Speaker 6:  It's just therapy about spatial
Speaker 6:  si. Alright. How
Speaker 3:  Does it make
Speaker 6:  You feel? Oh, Liam's says spatial. There are some other home pods. See Liam's.
Speaker 6:  Liam's. Liam wanted us to talk about the HomePod. Liam, do you have any thoughts
Speaker 6:  about the HomePod to add here? Thes? No.
Speaker 6:  All right, I'm gonna come down. We should talk about two more
Speaker 6:  things. We're talk about Netflix or Microsoft first. We gotta get through
Speaker 6:  'em.
Speaker 3:  Let's do Netflix real fast.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. All right. Richard, tell us what's going on with
Speaker 7:  Netflix. Netflix for the first time in, I guess, ever
Speaker 7:  has a CEO that is not Reid Hastings in, in, at least as long as I can remember,
Speaker 7:  in
Speaker 3:  Co ceo,
Speaker 7:  Two co CEOs because in 2020, Reid added
Speaker 7:  Co C Coco, he added Ted Sereno who kind of runs the content
Speaker 7:  business a as his as his co c o. And now today
Speaker 7:  on on Thursday sixth, we're recording this, Reid announced that he's stepping
Speaker 7:  down as as co c o and elevating Greg Peters, who was the chief
Speaker 7:  operating officer who will now be Coco around along with Sarandos. And
Speaker 7:  the timing of this is really interesting because this is at the exact same
Speaker 7:  time that Netflix is just starting to roll out two things that Reid Hastings
Speaker 7:  does not like advertisements and kind of their,
Speaker 7:  their pushback against password sharing, which for all, for the many years
Speaker 7:  of them building up streaming, he's been saying password sharing. It's not
Speaker 7:  that bad. It doesn't, it doesn't really affect us. He's been saying we won't
Speaker 7:  do ads. Those two things have changed. And now Reid Hastings is an executive
Speaker 7:  chairman and, and kind of some will be in, in much less of an active
Speaker 7:  role. And now, now it's relying on the, these, these two men, as Netflix
Speaker 7:  becomes a very different company, they now have hundreds of millions of subscribers.
Speaker 7:  They're trying to get into gaming. They maybe can't find new
Speaker 7:  customers and they're trying to find ways to make more money from the customers
Speaker 7:  that they have. And that that is the struggle that they have and the, the
Speaker 7:  case that they're making to Wall Street is how profitable they are versus
Speaker 7:  their competitors who are spending and losing money, handover fist, trying
Speaker 7:  to build up a, a subscriber base and content like Netflix has
Speaker 7:  and, and apps, I guess let's not even get into how all the other
Speaker 7:  apps are. Netflix isn't that great and every other app is worth Yeah.
Speaker 7:  But the, the tech platform, the content, everything about it,
Speaker 7:  they haven't really matched up to Netflix yet. And they're spending, so they're
Speaker 7:  setting money on fire to try and catch, to try and catch Netflix. And that
Speaker 7:  that is what Netflix brings up every earnings cost that they're profitable
Speaker 7:  and the others are not. But that's what they've got.
Speaker 3:  I mean, Netflix set money on fire for years
Speaker 7:  That, that's been their whole thing until now when that was no longer
Speaker 7:  advantageous.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. And, and we've, we saw that they, they they've been doing a slew of
Speaker 3:  cancellations. They've been much more mercenary about what shows
Speaker 3:  get extended in, what shows don't. And I think they were
Speaker 3:  even doing like unexpected cancellations, like pulling stuff. They'd already
Speaker 3:  green lit and stuff
Speaker 7:  Shows that, that people really liked and that that seemed to do well suddenly
Speaker 7:  disappear. And I, I think it's, it's interesting to me thinking about the
Speaker 7:  history of Netflix streaming and where we went from when Netflix watch
Speaker 7:  instantly had kind of the b list of shows that no one had ever
Speaker 7:  heard of and movies. And it was really interesting though. I liked it. And
Speaker 7:  then they started making content. They had that werewolf show and then they
Speaker 7:  had House of Cards and then it just kind of zoomed from there. And now they
Speaker 7:  have a trillion things and nothing to watch. And you can't start
Speaker 7:  any new show because you know, it won't get to a second season. And the algorithm
Speaker 7:  that Netflix was so famous for, it would find something for you that you
Speaker 7:  would watch. Everyone hates it because you can't just find the thing you're
Speaker 7:  looking for. It won't show you. You can't just go through the categories
Speaker 7:  and no, and no one's happy again. We, we all cut the cable and now we
Speaker 7:  have us streaming.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. See Richard has feelings about Netflix, like, keep going.
Speaker 3:  I was like, Ooh, keep going Richard. This
Speaker 7:  Is, this is, this is my life. This is a, it's, it's, it's a moment, man.
Speaker 7:  This is when, when I, when I saw this come across, I was like, wait, is this
Speaker 7:  really happening? Because I, I've kind of been anticipating it. We had so
Speaker 7:  many tech execs go away and I was like, yeah, Reid's gonna be the next one
Speaker 7:  and now it's here. And I, I don't even know how to do. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  So in his resignation note, he calls out Bill Gates,
Speaker 6:  Jeff Bezos, right. Moving up to executive chairman,
Speaker 6:  piecing out, handing the reins over. But usually you do that
Speaker 6:  at the top. I wanna say like, Netflix isn't a
Speaker 6:  challenging position and the things you called out, the changes it has to
Speaker 6:  make password sharing, adding advertising are things that he did not want
Speaker 6:  to do. So you have to wonder if he's just like, eh, I don't wanna do these
Speaker 6:  things.
Speaker 3:  But there are things that the c the NewCo CEO was
Speaker 3:  doing, like he was in charge of these, these initiatives and so now he's
Speaker 3:  coming in to like finish the job.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I mean I, I do wonder, and we, we don't know, and
Speaker 6:  I'm sure there'll be more reporting, but fundamentally Ted Sandos is the
Speaker 6:  content ceo, the Hollywood ceo, and Reid has been the product ceo.
Speaker 6:  Right. And it's interesting that he was like, we still need a product ceo.
Speaker 6:  So it's this person, not, we're a Hollywood company that runs a tech
Speaker 6:  platform, which is very flexy in its way. But you have to wonder if
Speaker 6:  the future of the product roadmap around ad you know, they, they have a big
Speaker 6:  partnership with Microsoft to deliver this advertising. The future of their
Speaker 6:  product roadmap is not the recommendation algorithm. It's
Speaker 6:  not this other stuff. It's like adding ads, it's detecting
Speaker 6:  password sharing, it's figuring out how to make people open Netflix on their
Speaker 6:  phones so they can play mobile games and like maybe Reid's like, I don't
Speaker 6:  wanna do it. It's
Speaker 3:  Real tech-heavy stuff.
Speaker 7:  They, they've become Comcast.
Speaker 6:  That's a bruiser.
Speaker 7:  This is the same stuff that Comcast was doing 10, 12 years ago. They were
Speaker 7:  like, you
Speaker 6:  Gonna put games in podcast? Fine, Richard, I I'll do the disclosures. Oh,
Speaker 7:  Is that your
Speaker 6:  Disclosure? I am the EP of a Netflix show. It's called The Future of
Speaker 6:  You Should Watch It. I'm heavily biased in favor of that show.
Speaker 6:  That's true. And then Comcast's NBC Universal Division is
Speaker 6:  a minority investor in Vini, the ver parent company. The end.
Speaker 6:  I also read a book about HBO last week. It was good. What what do you want
Speaker 6:  from me?
Speaker 3:  You wrote a book.
Speaker 6:  You read a book. I read a book I like, wow. It's called, it's not tv. It's
Speaker 6:  very good. We're gonna have the authors on decoder soon. It's great. I highly
Speaker 6:  recommend it. Those are all the disclosures. Do we have anymore, I invented
Speaker 6:  something called the Go 90 Scale of Tomb Streaming Services because
Speaker 3:  I was like, we've, we've cruised through like most
Speaker 7:  Of the big ones. But you didn't invent it for Quickster because we should,
Speaker 7:  we should say that we, we we should, we should bring up Quickster. It's,
Speaker 7:  it's a day to to
Speaker 6:  All right, go ahead. Talk, talk about, talk about Reed's greatest failure.
Speaker 7:  It's a little mean, isn't it? But we'll go there. It, it was the
Speaker 7:  last time Netflix messed up when they decided they were gonna split up
Speaker 7:  streaming in disks. And I, I remember I, I got a phone
Speaker 7:  call like at like 11:00 PM that they were gonna do this thing and it was
Speaker 7:  insane. And then they didn't do it. They, they rolled it
Speaker 7:  all back because everyone hated it. The subscriber numbers dropped and for
Speaker 7:  10 years it was just up, up, up until last year when it wasn't.
Speaker 7:  And now Reid is gone. Yeah. And, and I just, I
Speaker 7:  don't know what Netflix is gonna feel like, you know, a couple of years down
Speaker 7:  the road as you're saying, they, they have a new product lead that is not
Speaker 7:  Reid Hastings. And that just hasn't been the case throughout any of the things
Speaker 7:  that we've talked about for Netflix. Everything, the way that it's organized,
Speaker 7:  the entire kind of idea about how Netflix is and what it is,
Speaker 7:  is not going to be different then.
Speaker 3:  Well, I mean, they've been, the, the new co c o has been groomed for
Speaker 3:  this. We were seeing him in a lot more of the earnings calls in the last
Speaker 3:  year or so. Like they knew this was coming. They knew he was probably
Speaker 3:  gonna be taking on this role. So I, I anticipate in the couple of next couple
Speaker 3:  of years, there's not gonna be really significant changes from what we've
Speaker 3:  already seen, which is killing password sharing and adding advertising.
Speaker 3:  Like I think we're gonna continue to see Netflix do its thing where it struggles
Speaker 3:  with the, with its viewers and in this whole idea of like, we can't like
Speaker 3:  a show because it's gonna get canceled unless it's the most popular show,
Speaker 3:  in which case it'll probably be fine. And they're, they're gonna have to
Speaker 3:  deal with that. But ultimately, like they're gonna just continue to print
Speaker 3:  money probably on the go 90 scale. They're like at a 10.
Speaker 6:  Yeah,
Speaker 7:  I agree with you. And I think you're probably right, but two years ago, Bob
Speaker 7:  Chap probably thought the same thing. Where is he now?
Speaker 7:  Seriously? Where is he now? He can find it
Speaker 3:  On the beach. Hey, join himself.
Speaker 6:  Tiger is facing down an activist investor right now named Nelson
Speaker 6:  Peltz at Disney. We, you should just Google it and read
Speaker 6:  the slide deck that Disney filed to, to beat this activist
Speaker 6:  investor back. They're like, you know nothing about us, you know nothing
Speaker 6:  about television and you're a dummy. And like that's the slide deck.
Speaker 6:  It's a very, you could tell they had a good time putting it together, but
Speaker 6:  all is not well in streaming world, just like across the board.
Speaker 6:  And I think Reid is like, screw it, I dragged this into
Speaker 6:  existence and I'll still be around but I, you know,
Speaker 6:  I, I'm gonna do whatever Bezos is doing. I'm gonna get yoked and do a, and
Speaker 6:  do a rocket. Like let's do it. I'm like
Speaker 6:  just
Speaker 3:  Shredded. I
Speaker 6:  Gotta say I see the appeal like my, I'm the
Speaker 6:  executive chairman,
Speaker 3:  His suits aren't gonna close anymore. He's just gonna be so buff.
Speaker 6:  I love this. I need to buy a $10,000 black t-shirt that makes my arms look
Speaker 6:  great. And then we can move on to the next thing. Speaking of the next thing,
Speaker 6:  big Microsoft News this week they're laying off 10,000 people, which is very
Speaker 6:  sad. Yeah. Condolences to them. It's the second biggest
Speaker 6:  layoffs in Microsoft history. The first biggest also
Speaker 6:  Sasha Nadela, he led a 14,000 people when he shuttered
Speaker 6:  the sort of Windows phone division and sent
Speaker 6:  12,500 Noki employees away. He got rid of it. So
Speaker 6:  kind of a different context, right? This is the economy's bad. Second biggest
Speaker 6:  layoffs. The biggest layoffs where he shuttered an entire division and got
Speaker 6:  rid of a company. So a little bit context but huge, right?
Speaker 3:  This was across
Speaker 6:  The board, but Microsoft has 220,000 people. So not massive. He published
Speaker 6:  a letter. So there, and there's this paragraph in his note that I think is
Speaker 6:  just really interesting. I'm like worth pulling apart focus on. So he says
Speaker 6:  we have to continue investing strategic areas for a future. These are the
Speaker 6:  kinds of hard choices we have made through our 47 year history to remain
Speaker 6:  a consequential company in this industry that is unforgiving to
Speaker 6:  anyone who does not adapt to platform shifts. Which is a really
Speaker 6:  fascinating thing about in the context of Nadella and Microsoft and
Speaker 6:  mobile in the last platform shift they missed, right? And then he said, this
Speaker 6:  is the very next sentence, we're taking 1.2 billion charge
Speaker 6:  related to severance cost changes to our hardware portfolio
Speaker 6:  and the cost of lease consolidation as we they do return to office.
Speaker 6:  So he's saying he thinks there's a platform shift and they have
Speaker 6:  to change something to get there. And then they're changing their hardware
Speaker 3:  Portfolio, which we'd already started to
Speaker 6:  See then. Yeah, I don't know what he thinks the platform shift is. And I
Speaker 6:  asked around and Tom asked around, and you would think
Speaker 6:  that this hardware portfolio change would be shutting down HoloLens
Speaker 6:  cuz they have effectively shut down HoloLens. And if you'll remember,
Speaker 6:  Nadela was on stage with Zuckerberg saying they were gonna put software on
Speaker 6:  the Quest Pro. So you would think that like what they're talking about is
Speaker 6:  shutting down hos. We asked around and it's not, it's more than that,
Speaker 6:  right? Like
Speaker 3:  Well they also close, they they they're not doing another version of the
Speaker 3:  duo, right? Like they got rid of the phone.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. So is it it that's the surface line. So are they gonna change the surface
Speaker 6:  line or are they gonna change the Xbox line
Speaker 6:  or are they gonna pair back whatever they're doing in Surface?
Speaker 6:  And then you put that in the context of platform shift, right? We have to
Speaker 6:  adapt to the platform to remain a consequential company
Speaker 6:  that has to adapt to platform shifts. We have to do this thing.
Speaker 6:  Okay, what platform shift and is selling
Speaker 6:  surface Windows laptops enough to remain consequential through a
Speaker 6:  platform shift there? I'm just telling you that paragraph, it just jumped
Speaker 6:  off the page at me.
Speaker 3:  It's super weird
Speaker 6:  That Microsoft is making some kind of bet that we can't see
Speaker 6:  and maybe that bet's just ai, right? They have a huge investment in open
Speaker 6:  ai. Again, maybe chat G V T is gonna save Bing.
Speaker 6:  Maybe it's cybersecurity. They, they've talked about that a lot. Maybe it's
Speaker 6:  more Azure work that's Ella's favorite thing in the entire world.
Speaker 6:  Like it, it might be something more obvious, but they're saying
Speaker 6:  we think there's a platform shift and we have to change our hardware. We're
Speaker 6:  we've preemptively shut down a hardware portfolio. And like I said, Tom and
Speaker 6:  I both went and asked, rounded some reporting cuz we we're like, oh, it's
Speaker 6:  HoloLens like let's confirm that. No, it's more than that.
Speaker 7:  What the only thing that I can think of that we haven't mentioned is
Speaker 7:  them putting stuff like obviously O Office has moved to the cloud, we've
Speaker 7:  had the Office 365 huge shift, but windows are suddenly in the cloud. If
Speaker 7:  they're thinking that like the kind of concept of the personal PC license
Speaker 7:  is going away.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Oh that's interesting. Or Xbox in the cloud, right? They're gonna stream
Speaker 6:  the games to you. They've thought about this a lot. They've got, you know,
Speaker 6:  if they can break through the regulatory barriers and get the European
Speaker 6:  police to let Apple do game streaming. Yeah. Like maybe there's a lot
Speaker 6:  here that you can,
Speaker 3:  If they can get the internet better.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Internet's better. They're
Speaker 3:  Like, they've got a bunch of hurdles
Speaker 6:  But not in Europe. Yeah. The Internet's a great in Europe, right? And it's
Speaker 6:  just our country that seems destined to do monopoly
Speaker 6:  internet access disclosure. Comcast is a minority investor.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I just think it's fascinating like that line and
Speaker 6:  we've, we've seen it, you know, all these other, there's lots of tech layoffs
Speaker 6:  across tech industry except for Google and no one's, no one's seen that coming
Speaker 6:  for Google. I maintained that. This is gonna be weird. Well,
Speaker 7:  Google had, like, they have sort of had layoffs. They cut back a lot of those
Speaker 7:  experimental projects. We know that they've put people on kind of these
Speaker 7:  plans where, you know, you need to find another job within Google. They've
Speaker 7:  cut hiring. Apple also has, has kind of done the same thing where they haven't
Speaker 7:  done the massive playoff, but they did slow down hiring over the last like
Speaker 7:  year or so. So in, in kind of a, a stealth way. They, they all have
Speaker 7:  have gone through that and, but what this reminds me of is the meta layoffs
Speaker 7:  just because it was so huge and it was affecting so many departments and
Speaker 7:  it feels like kind of everything got cut back.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, we'll see again, you know, Microsoft I think has more focus
Speaker 6:  than meta. Like Microsoft knows what it's selling right now.
Speaker 6:  It's just this line about platform shift. Just like what what's c c in No
Speaker 6:  one else sees what's the, I don't see a platform, if you were to go up to
Speaker 6:  the, the average Vergecast listener and say what's the next platform shift?
Speaker 6:  I'm guessing most people in their cars just like yelled out like
Speaker 6:  ar like vr, like it's, that's what we've been told for years.
Speaker 6:  But Microsoft is just divesting from all of that right now so that I don't
Speaker 6:  think that's it. And so I I think it probably looks like cloud
Speaker 6:  operating system or cloud gaming delivery, but they, they gotta get
Speaker 6:  that on phones and Apple does not wanna let them do that. So we'll see. Totally
Speaker 6:  fascinating line. Yeah. From Microsoft. I do think if there is a
Speaker 6:  platform to shift coming
Speaker 6:  Microsoft, this isn't, I brought up Nadela in the Nochi layoffs in the beginning
Speaker 6:  to be like, this is, that's the fire he was born in as Microsoft ceo,
Speaker 6:  right? Like Walmart bought Nokia, our boy
Speaker 6:  Steven eop just fully eop the entire nation of
Speaker 6:  Finland, like destroy its national champion,
Speaker 6:  Whatever. And then they nadela became the CEO and he had to just undo it
Speaker 6:  all and be like, we're gonna lose mobile. And that's like, that's the fire
Speaker 6:  that fortune. So I'm very curious to be like, to see what he thinks that
Speaker 6:  platform shift is and how Microsoft can win. Cuz I very much doubt that he
Speaker 6:  wants to lose again, you know, a platform shift.
Speaker 3:  Are you, are you gonna pitch that? He should come on de coder. Are we gonna
Speaker 3:  take that opportunity now that if he's listening, he should come on. I
Speaker 6:  Mean, we make that a, we make asks all the time. I will tell you that CEOs
Speaker 6:  do not want to go on hour long podcasts after they've laid off 10,000 people.
Speaker 3:  That's fair.
Speaker 6:  The problem with decoders, you have to want to come on. I can't just be like,
Speaker 6:  all right, sit down for your deposition.
Speaker 3:  You just unfurl your list of notes, all your questions.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, it's great.
Speaker 6:  It's like, all right, where were you on the night of October 11th
Speaker 6:  when Stephen eop crept back into Microsoft's office
Speaker 6:  and destroyed Nokia? All right. I encourage you to go Google
Speaker 6:  the words burning platform platform. Stephen eop, one of the greatest memos
Speaker 6:  written of all time.
Speaker 6:  Very good. If you have not read the Zoe Schiffer, Casey New and
Speaker 6:  Alex Heath feature about Twitter, honestly go buy it
Speaker 6:  on an end. Buy a copy Newark May. That's cool. It's cool that we get to do
Speaker 6:  that with them. It's cool that we have a company that allows us do that stuff.
Speaker 6:  It's cool. They gave us their cover. That's awesome. It's cool to work with
Speaker 6:  'em. So you can read on our site, go by and you stand. It's very good. We'll
Speaker 6:  be back on Wednesday. Oh, Alex, what are you guys doing on Wednesday?
Speaker 3:  Yeah, so on Wednesday we are gonna be talking with Dr. Margaret Omar,
Speaker 3:  who is a professor and knows a lot more about non-competes than I do
Speaker 3:  and how they helped build Silicon Valley in really weird
Speaker 3:  and interesting ways. This is on the news that happened with ftc with the
Speaker 3:  FTC a couple of weeks ago. And then we're gonna be talking with Charles Pulley
Speaker 3:  Moore all about the last of us and try not to spoil
Speaker 3:  our audience. So if you guys haven't had an opportunity to go watch, so you're
Speaker 3:  all primed. And then we're gonna be doing a really fun hotline segment, so
Speaker 3:  you should totally call us on the hotline. That's 8 66 Verge 11
Speaker 3:  again, eight sixty six Verge 11 call now.
Speaker 6:  That's very good. I keep trying to get Charles to engage with me on the idea
Speaker 6:  that there's a massive backlash against the rock because of black Adam and
Speaker 6:  he just like won't Yeah. Accept it. If you could just sneak that into that
Speaker 6:  episode, he refused. That'd be great. Sorry,
Speaker 3:  I'll, I'm, I will try, I'll try.
Speaker 6:  All right. Thanks to Alex Heath for joining us earlier. That was fun. Thank
Speaker 6:  you for listening in your cars. Drive safe,
Speaker 6:  everyone. The self-driving isn't coming and neither are the ER headsets.
Speaker 6:  This is just real. You can tweet at us. But
Speaker 3:  There is a platform shift.
Speaker 6:  There's a platform shift, it's a burning platform and Stephen Alop wants
Speaker 6:  to push you into the fridge and waters of the ocean.
Speaker 6:  I don't know how this episode got to Steven.
Speaker 6:  You can tweet at us for some reason. Alex is Alex h
Speaker 6:  Crans. Alex Heath is Alex E. Heath. Richard is at rj.
Speaker 6:  Ccc. I'm at Reckless. I, yeah, I do open it and I'll, I'll, I'll throw
Speaker 6:  you a like, but if you, if you tweeted me and it's like you're back, like
Speaker 6:  I didn't say I was throwing it into the ocean. I just said I wasn't gonna
Speaker 6:  tweet as much and I haven't been tweeting as much. That's life. That's the
Speaker 6:  ver fucking roll.
Speaker 1:  And that's a wrap for Verge this week. Thanks for listening. If you enjoy
Speaker 1:  the show, subscribe in the podcast app of your choice or tell a friend, you
Speaker 1:  can send us feedback at vergecast@theverge.com. This show is
Speaker 1:  produced by me, Liam James, and our senior audio director, Andrew Marino.
Speaker 1:  This episode was edited and mixed by Amanda Rose Smith. Our
Speaker 1:  editorial director is Brooke Min, and our executive producer is Eleanor
Speaker 1:  Donovan. The Vergecast is a production of the Verge and Box Media Podcast
Speaker 1:  Network. And that's it. We'll see you next week.