# Transcript
ID: f6f6b0d0-d940-11ed-ab57-63c6b05045fa
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: The best streaming services in 2023
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-8494037558138206714/1962576710706478516/s93290-US-3280s-1681310854.mp3
Description: What are the best streaming services in 2023? Nilay, Alex, and David decide in the most chaotic way possible: with draft-style picks. The crew debates the best roster for the future of entertainment — from Netflix to Hulu to HBO Max to a few surprises. Who is the MVP, and who gets snubbed? Find out in our inaugural Vergecast streaming draft.
Read more: theverge.com/streaming-wars
Vote for us in the People’s Voice Webby Awards for Best Technology Podcast: http://bit.ly/3moCTDs
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we love hearing from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Disabled
Speaker 2:  Welcome to the Vergecast, the flagship podcast of Rabbit Ear Antennas.
Speaker 2:  I'm your friend David Pierce, and I am doing maybe the weirdest thing on
Speaker 2:  my to-do list in a while. I am reordering all of the apps on my
Speaker 2:  Roku. I have 94 things installed it looks like, which is a
Speaker 2:  way too many, and B, total chaos because everything
Speaker 2:  is in a totally bonkers order and I can't find anything. So I'm moving stuff
Speaker 2:  around trying to get all of my important services up to the top. It is
Speaker 2:  way, way too much work. It's like six button clicks every time you want to
Speaker 2:  even just move an app, which is why it's taken me months to finally get fed
Speaker 2:  up enough to do it, but I'm doing it anyway. Today's show is actually
Speaker 2:  all about these streaming services. We've been trying for a while to figure
Speaker 2:  out a good way to answer a really simple but really important question. What
Speaker 2:  are the best streaming services? So we picked the most
Speaker 2:  subjective, most chaotic way we could think of to actually answer that question.
Speaker 2:  Eli, Alex and I are going to draft streaming services and see who
Speaker 2:  picks the best roster for the future of entertainment. That's the whole show
Speaker 2:  today, and it's coming up in just a second. But first I have to figure out
Speaker 2:  whether Hulu or ESPN plus belongs on the second row of my
Speaker 2:  Roku. This feels like a surprisingly big decision. This is the cast.
Speaker 2:  See you in a sec.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. This is the Great Verge streaming
Speaker 2:  draft of 2023, which I'm saying so that it sounds like an annual
Speaker 2:  thing, so that we require ourselves to do this every year from now on
Speaker 2:  ne lapel. Hello and welcome to the draft. I've
Speaker 4:  Tried to pull that trick so many times. There's so many things we don't do
Speaker 4:  every year that I've insisted that we're gonna do every year, but we're gonna
Speaker 4:  do this every year.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, we're gonna do this every year. It's gonna be great. Alex Cranz. Hello.
Speaker 5:  What happens if all of the streaming services die next year? Will it
Speaker 5:  just be super competitive?
Speaker 2:  There's like a 60% chance that none of these things will exist. Okay, a year
Speaker 2:  from now, we'll be picking go 90 again. Yeah, it's gonna
Speaker 4:  Be great. The only thing on my list is Quibi, y'all. Let's just be honest.
Speaker 2:  I'm not gonna lie. The word Quibi appears in my notes somewhere in all the
Speaker 2:  prep that I did for this, but we'll, we'll come to that later. Okay, so let
Speaker 2:  me just quickly explain how this draft is gonna work and then we'll get into
Speaker 2:  it. We're gonna do five rounds and we're doing a snake draft. So the
Speaker 2:  person who picks first, then they go second, then they go third, and the
Speaker 2:  person who picks third then picks fourth. So we're, we're, we're going around
Speaker 2:  and around. We're gonna pick 15 total things over the course of this. And
Speaker 2:  the idea is that whatever you pick is what you're stuck with for the next
Speaker 2:  12 months. Like the imagine it like you're drafting a team, right? This is
Speaker 2:  your exclusive five streaming services for the next year. I will take
Speaker 2:  any single subscription as one draft pick. So you can draft
Speaker 2:  the Disney bundle as one thing because that is one thing with one price.
Speaker 2:  But also you can draft Disney Plus and ESPN Plus and Hulu as their own things
Speaker 2:  because you can pay for them separately. That's the only one like that that
Speaker 2:  I can actually think of. But if there are others, feel free and try to convince
Speaker 2:  me otherwise. But what you can't do is the, the like Amazon
Speaker 2:  channels, like subscribe to stars through here thing cuz that's a separate
Speaker 2:  thing that you pay for separately. So one bill, one price,
Speaker 2:  one pick.
Speaker 5:  Do like adjacent services count, things that
Speaker 5:  are like streaming but maybe don't have their own
Speaker 5:  content on them or a lot of their own content.
Speaker 2:  Sure. If you wanna pick Plex is the answer to your question. If you wanna
Speaker 2:  pick Plex, knock yourself out. That's an awful draft
Speaker 4:  Pick. You can't just pick Plex, you gotta pick. Alex has to pick her own
Speaker 4:  Plex surfer, right?
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I pick my Plex surfer. Yeah, that I will allow. And as for
Speaker 2:  what counts, any streaming service counts, free, paid, whatever. It just
Speaker 2:  has to be primarily about entertainment. I'm gonna do my best to
Speaker 2:  keep track of the cost of all these things. And one fun wrinkle that I just
Speaker 2:  came up with is whoever spends the least money in these five picks
Speaker 2:  gets one extra free bonus pick at the end.
Speaker 4:  So you understand that the last pick of this draft is a punishment.
Speaker 2:  You get to have another streaming service, right? Instead of five streaming
Speaker 2:  services, you get to have six. You can pick, I don't know, quibi,
Speaker 4:  I'm gonna
Speaker 2:  Say something.
Speaker 4:  Punishment, not a reward.
Speaker 2:  That yeah, you're, you're not wrong. If there are any disputes, Andrew, our
Speaker 2:  producer is in charge.
Speaker 6:  Thank you David.
Speaker 2:  He rules and his word is final. He's the, he's the commissioner of
Speaker 2:  our league. All right, Andrew is here to pick the draft
Speaker 2:  order. None of us know the draft order, cuz as far as I know there isn't
Speaker 2:  one yet. Andrew,
Speaker 5:  Give it to me. Give it to me. I deserve
Speaker 2:  It. Andrew, you're gonna tell us who's picking first, second, and third.
Speaker 2:  What do you have for us?
Speaker 6:  Okay, so NEI responded to your message in Slack
Speaker 6:  first today. So Neely's gonna go first.
Speaker 2:  Oh, what a surprise. Give the boss the first pick in the draft. Yes. What
Speaker 2:  a shocking twists everybody's boss gets to go first. This
Speaker 5:  Commissioners terrible
Speaker 4:  Surprise. That's right. I'm the Dallas Cowboys baby sleep.
Speaker 4:  You can't run this league without me.
Speaker 6:  And then Alex is gonna go second. Yes. And David is gonna go third
Speaker 6:  cuz he's the host.
Speaker 2:  This sucks. I don't wanna do this
Speaker 4:  Anymore. David. Trades are allowed, man.
Speaker 2:  I bet I'm still gonna get my first pick at third, so this is fine. Andrew,
Speaker 2:  do you have another song for us? It's Go Time
Speaker 2:  All Eli Patel, you're on the clock. First pick
Speaker 4:  TikTok.
Speaker 2:  Wow.
Speaker 4:  Zero hesitation TikTok,
Speaker 2:  Explain. Wow.
Speaker 4:  It provides the most value for the zero listed dollars. It is the only
Speaker 4:  streaming service that reliably produces videos of trucks trumping over things
Speaker 4:  and into rivers. That's very important to me. And I don't know if it's gonna
Speaker 4:  get banned or not, but I want to be, I wanna be on the ride if that's gonna
Speaker 4:  happen.
Speaker 2:  Well, so that's the, this is like the most high risk, high reward pick ever.
Speaker 2:  Right? Because there's a decent chance that literally it will not be available
Speaker 2:  to you when we do this draft again in 12 months. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  And you know what? Sometimes you gotta draft a quarterback who's definitely
Speaker 4:  gonna get hurt. You know what I'm saying? Like, I just think about where
Speaker 4:  do I spend the most time? It's TikTok as we go through the draft, I think
Speaker 4:  this choice will be rewarded. I might not need any other picks.
Speaker 2:  Okay? So my reasoning for being anti TikTok as the
Speaker 2:  first pick is that there's no, like prestige
Speaker 2:  TikTok is like not a thing. And like
Speaker 2:  what I want from one of my picks here, and maybe I'll get it later, but
Speaker 2:  is the like cultural relevancy of something where it's like everybody's very
Speaker 2:  excited about the most recent episode of succession and you're gonna have
Speaker 2:  to watch it in two minute increments cobbled together across the
Speaker 4:  Internet. Well, I do have other pegs, right? Like I can
Speaker 4:  pick Alex's Plex server second. We have not, actually, this is a
Speaker 4:  rules clarification. Am I still allowed to buy things?
Speaker 2:  Oh yes. You are allowed to buy things.
Speaker 4:  Like I can rent movies,
Speaker 2:  We'll leave like the voodoos of the world separate. If you wanna pay
Speaker 2:  four bucks to rent a movie that's allowed that,
Speaker 2:  that exists outside of this,
Speaker 4:  I'm ever more comfortable with this
Speaker 2:  Choice. Interesting. Okay. Alex, what do you think? Good choice. Bad choice.
Speaker 5:  Terrible choice. Just why I watched TikTok last night
Speaker 5:  while I was watching succession and that was a bad choice.
Speaker 2:  That might be a proof of New Life's point. You might have just proved me
Speaker 2:  ICE's case.
Speaker 5:  Basically it was, it was a bad choice. So like, I'm trying to, to
Speaker 5:  have less TikTok in my life.
Speaker 4:  That's fair. No, that's fair. Yeah. You gotta cut back.
Speaker 2:  Alex. Let's go second pick. What
Speaker 5:  Do you have? Oh, it's h b o max. Who?
Speaker 2:  Okay,
Speaker 5:  I'm coming out the gate Strong. I'm, I'm, I'm, I'm aggressive.
Speaker 2:  All right. Defend
Speaker 5:  Because succession, but also I watch a lot of stuff
Speaker 5:  on, on HBO Max. There's, there's a lot of good content on it as long as it
Speaker 5:  survives. So I've got this for like, what another month.
Speaker 4:  Immediate theme in this draft of I need to ride this out while it
Speaker 2:  Lasts. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  So I'm gonna enjoy it for a month. I'm gonna watch, you know, maybe rewatch,
Speaker 5:  warrior rewatch sex lives of
Speaker 5:  college girls, whatever that show's called. That sounded really bad
Speaker 5:  saying it out loud, but it's gonna be a great time for the next month.
Speaker 2:  Okay, here's, here's a philosophical question. Are we streaming
Speaker 2:  services with ads people or spend the extra $5 for no ads? People?
Speaker 5:  Oh, this is with the extra $5. I don't do ads. Okay.
Speaker 2:  So we're, we're spending the money to not get any ads. Yeah. Unlike ne Eli
Speaker 2:  who says, just give me every ad,
Speaker 4:  Scroll right by 'em. Man, don't worry about it.
Speaker 5:  Every 30 videos just, there's your ad
Speaker 4:  Nii, you got a mag save charger. This is the best ad targeting you can do.
Speaker 2:  Nela, are you an ads person? Do you pay for no ads?
Speaker 4:  Oh yeah. I, I pay for no ads everywhere. Okay. Which is funny because we
Speaker 4:  run an ad supported website. Please don't skip over the ads on this podcast,
Speaker 2:  But also pay for all of our paid things. Yeah. And those don't have ads.
Speaker 4:  Maybe I'm, I'm, I'm trying to bring these ideas together as much as I can.
Speaker 2:  Verge plus
Speaker 4:  That's my last pick. If I win this bonus pick, I'm picking that cuz it doesn't
Speaker 4:  cost any money. Okay. Because it doesn't exist. You see, you see the logic
Speaker 2:  Here. Alex, what do you do with the fact that the HBO Max app is like a
Speaker 2:  horrible pile of garbage that doesn't work? 40 to 60% of the time.
Speaker 5:  I just like close my eyes and think of the good content that
Speaker 5:  I'll get to when I eventually find it and the app works.
Speaker 2:  You watch TikTok until the page loads
Speaker 5:  Just avert my eyes and I press go and 30 minutes later maybe
Speaker 5:  my show plays and I'm really excited. And that like, once that 30 minutes
Speaker 5:  hit, then I've, I've got like, you get all those old movies cuz they have
Speaker 5:  like the whole, they have all the, the Turner Classic stuff.
Speaker 4:  This is a strong pick because of the catalog for sure. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It's, it's all about the catalog for me and the app is like just an
Speaker 5:  unfortunate byproduct that I have to deal with.
Speaker 4:  Also, whenever you want, you can watch a square version
Speaker 4:  of Justice League.
Speaker 5:  That's all I've, that's what I'm gonna do right after this cuz it's my
Speaker 5:  first pick. I can watch it any time.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, HBO X was gonna be my second pick specifically because it is like when
Speaker 2:  you make a list of like relevant cultural shows that people care about, they
Speaker 2:  are overwhelmingly on hbo. It's insane. So by not having HBO
Speaker 2:  O Max nea, you and I are just resigned to being sort of social
Speaker 2:  outcasts.
Speaker 4:  Don't worry, I got a Plex server coming up.
Speaker 2:  Alex is gonna rip everything from HBO O Max to her Plex server.
Speaker 2:  Problem solve
Speaker 5:  Would never do that. That's wrong.
Speaker 2:  Okay, so I'm up third and for my third pick I get my first pick,
Speaker 2:  which is YouTube. This is the easiest decision of all time. I cannot believe
Speaker 2:  neither of you picked YouTube. It's 2299 a month
Speaker 2:  for YouTube premium, which is insane. And which I did not realize I had been
Speaker 2:  paying all this time because they raised the price. Yeah. And which is, yeah,
Speaker 2:  it's outrageous. That's like the family plan. It's ridiculous. What do
Speaker 5:  You get for that?
Speaker 2:  So you get no ads. Okay. Which is great. You get background
Speaker 2:  listening, you get a music service for free, which is compelling.
Speaker 2:  And now I don't have to pick Spotify or Apple Music or anything else because
Speaker 2:  I just have YouTube music and all the music streaming services are the same.
Speaker 2:  So it's, it's kinda like getting two picks in one, but also it's like YouTube
Speaker 2:  over the last like 12 months for me has become the place
Speaker 2:  I go when I don't know what I wanna watch and I just have like 15 minutes
Speaker 2:  to kill. And I think part of this is, I just had a kid, so I, my windows
Speaker 2:  of time to just sort of sit and do nothing went from being like hours long
Speaker 2:  to like minutes long. But it's like highlights of
Speaker 2:  soccer games that I missed because I have a small child and
Speaker 2:  Hot Ones interviews is basically like my entire YouTube
Speaker 2:  algorithm right now. And it's great. And I have, I have nothing against it.
Speaker 2:  It feels like it is the biggest one. It's also the only one of our three
Speaker 2:  so far that will probably still exist 12 months from now. So I feel very
Speaker 2:  good about that. I'm honestly shocked neither of you picked this. I felt
Speaker 2:  like YouTube was like the obvious first choice.
Speaker 4:  It would've been my, it would've if I hadn't gotten, if I hadn't gotten TikTok,
Speaker 4:  I would've gone YouTube Premium.
Speaker 2:  Good. All right. Well then I also get the fourth pick because
Speaker 2:  of the way this draft works last. Yeah. Andrew, I've come around. I've decided
Speaker 2:  you, you were right to give me the third pick. Thank you.
Speaker 4:  That was secret. Wow.
Speaker 2:  So there's three I can choose from here and I'm gonna, this is the, I'm gonna
Speaker 2:  regret this choice, but I'm gonna make it, I'm gonna pick Peacock. Ooh.
Speaker 5:  Which
Speaker 2:  I would not have expected to do. But the honest truth is Peacock is
Speaker 2:  where the office is and it's where Parks and Rec is. And for me that is
Speaker 2:  like 45% of my TV viewing between those two shows.
Speaker 2:  And the, the other 45 exists on another service that I hope I get to pick
Speaker 2:  later. But it's just that like Peacock has some nifty stuff with
Speaker 2:  live tv, they have some sports, they're starting to grow. But it is like
Speaker 2:  fundamentally it is the place where the office is and I have to have the
Speaker 2:  place where the office is on my list. I already regret this choice as
Speaker 2:  I'm saying this, I drafted this too. High disclosure.
Speaker 4:  Oh
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Peacock has operated by NBC Universal, which is owned by Comcast, which
Speaker 4:  is minority investor in Vox Media, parent company. David, I hope you got
Speaker 4:  some sort of kickback for this miserable
Speaker 5:  Choice. I think this is a good choice. This is, this is like,
Speaker 5:  if you watch a lot of tv, peacock is a very solid choice.
Speaker 4:  I think what we're we're gonna discover in this is that some of you watch
Speaker 4:  vastly more television than I do. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  That's probably, that's probably true. But no, for me it's like I dabble
Speaker 2:  in lots of TV and then I have like four shows that I cycle between over and
Speaker 2:  over and over and over again. And two of them are the office in Parks and
Speaker 2:  Rec, both of which are on Peacock. And I think I can reliably say
Speaker 2:  both of which are never leaving Peacock because they are part of the company
Speaker 2:  that owns Peacock. So I'm not afraid that six months from now they're just
Speaker 2:  gonna suddenly disappear. Unlike on some other services that have
Speaker 2:  gained and lost my
Speaker 5:  Shows until Peacock dies and they have to like sell to
Speaker 5:  another company.
Speaker 2:  There is that, but Peacock's doing kind of, well it
Speaker 2:  went from being like a total disaster to like a kind of me success ish.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  It's like, it's like trending in the right direction from really bad to
Speaker 2:  kind of bad. It's like, you know, in Arrested Development, they go from like
Speaker 2:  a cell to don't buy and they're like thrilled about it. Like that's peacock.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I just think you're gonna find yourself using the custom video player
Speaker 4:  UI that they developed for no reason. And you're like,
Speaker 4:  this is my third pick. Like, that's just how that's gonna feel for you.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. If the space bar on my iPad doesn't pause your video
Speaker 2:  player, you've done it wrong. And Peacock has done it wrong.
Speaker 2:  All right, Alex, you're up next.
Speaker 5:  I don't think this is gonna shock anybody but Paramount Plus. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Wow. That does not shock
Speaker 4:  Me. Wow. The reaches in these rounds are out of control.
Speaker 2:  I had that so much lower on my list.
Speaker 5:  I get Star Trek Love a Star Trek. I get most of
Speaker 5:  Yellowstone The good, the good versions. Evil. That's lovely.
Speaker 5:  The good fight. A bunch of like random CBS stuff like Ghosts and
Speaker 5:  most importantly of all 60 Minutes.
Speaker 4:  So you're buying shows. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I'm, I'm all about the shows. Okay. For the most part. I got, I
Speaker 5:  got some others here, but for the most part it's about like the shows for
Speaker 5:  me, but all like, it's like peacock where you get a bunch of live stuff too,
Speaker 5:  so, so I can like watch live news if I need to, that sort
Speaker 5:  of thing. Yeah. And then I gotta see what's gonna happen on Picard next week.
Speaker 5:  Like I can't, I can't lose that. I
Speaker 4:  Mean, I guess like saying you're buying shows at like, at the end we're all
Speaker 4:  just fine content. Yeah. Like no one's like I'm buying this for a great ui.
Speaker 4:  Like it's all content. But you very specifically are like these four shows
Speaker 4:  Yes. Are why I'm drafting this service.
Speaker 5:  A hundred percent. Also like the Peacock UI is fine.
Speaker 5:  It's better than HBO kind
Speaker 2:  Of in that, like the app loads from time to time. Yes.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Like once you actually use it, it's miserable and I hate it.
Speaker 5:  But otherwise it's, it's, it does the job.
Speaker 2:  So I will say when I first did my rankings, I had Paramount plus
Speaker 2:  really, really, really low. And then the Final four happened
Speaker 2:  and the masters happened, and both of those things only streamed on
Speaker 2:  Paramount Plus. And all of a sudden it's like, as a person who also likes
Speaker 2:  to watch like Champions League soccer, like Paramount Plus has a sneaky amount
Speaker 2:  of like really good, really high end sports that for
Speaker 2:  me are like, I actually don't subscribe to Paramount Plus. And there were
Speaker 2:  a couple of times the last couple of weeks I almost did and I suspect I'm
Speaker 2:  gonna end up having to do so you'll
Speaker 5:  You'll
Speaker 2:  Like it. Even though I don't care about Star Trek. Like, to me Paramount
Speaker 2:  Plus is just like, where do you go if you like Star Trek and there's lots
Speaker 2:  of those people and I am not one of them. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  It's, it's, there's a bunch of other stuff. Like obviously the Star Trek
Speaker 5:  is really big right now at the moment for me. But for the most part it's
Speaker 5:  all of the other content that I, I watch and now I can keep up with
Speaker 5:  everybody in, in at home who all watch Yellowstone
Speaker 5:  and all of those shows so I can like, have conversations with my family.
Speaker 5:  That's very exciting.
Speaker 2:  That's real. Okay, here's the rules question. Are you paying
Speaker 2:  9 99 a month for just Paramount? Or are you paying 1199 a month and also
Speaker 2:  getting Showtime?
Speaker 5:  Oh, 1199 a month.
Speaker 4:  No, that's the easy, yeah, that's the easiest trade up of all time.
Speaker 2:  That's just the price for Yellow Jackets. Right? You pay $2 a month to watch
Speaker 2:  yellow jackets. A
Speaker 4:  Hundred percent. That's how they make billions.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Yeah. I'm so sorry.
Speaker 5:  So smooth.
Speaker 2:  Okay, so you take Paramount plus of Showtime for 1199 a month.
Speaker 2:  I actually think that was a pretty good pick. Eli here up. What do
Speaker 4:  You got? Oh, this is hard. I can go two ways.
Speaker 2:  Well, okay. And you're gonna get a pick and then we're gonna take a break
Speaker 2:  and then you're gonna get another pick. So
Speaker 4:  Oh yeah, no, no, that's actually super easy then. Disney plus.
Speaker 2:  Okay, why
Speaker 4:  Child? Yes,
Speaker 7:  You
Speaker 4:  Have a child, child Bluey, I'm, I'm, I'm drafting Bluey. This
Speaker 2:  Is the Bluey
Speaker 4:  Pick. Very specifically Bluey, frozen, Moana,
Speaker 4:  like this stuff just flows through the house like water. Okay. Also
Speaker 4:  it is like the single app on her iPad that I trust
Speaker 4:  in like, in any way, shape or form, like YouTube Kids is
Speaker 4:  just a disaster clown car of a situation. Yes,
Speaker 4:  she loves it. But you've taken it off the board, right, because you took
Speaker 4:  YouTube totally off the board. So YouTube kids went for the ride.
Speaker 4:  Right. So you gotta, the kid pick has to be d
Speaker 2:  Plus. Okay. So and also, well I was, I have two follow up questions. One
Speaker 2:  is, are you just taking Disney Plus or are you taking the bundle and also
Speaker 2:  getting Hulu and ESPN Plus it's more expensive but
Speaker 2:  you get more stuff.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I'm taking the bundle. Okay. Hulu's fine. My que
Speaker 4:  actually, my question was if I take the bundle, you can still pick Hulu,
Speaker 4:  right? That's right. Okay. So yeah, I'm taking the bundle not totally strategic.
Speaker 4:  If I was taking it totally off the board, zero, like that's just draft
Speaker 4:  strategy, right? Sure. But there's, yeah, Hulu has a reasonably good catalog.
Speaker 4:  It's got some movies on there. The real thing I'm taking is ESPN
Speaker 4:  Plus, which has the one show I watched during football season more consistently
Speaker 4:  than anything else. NFL primetime. Which is great.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, you two are the two people I know that are like ESPN plus.
Speaker 2:  It's
Speaker 4:  Great. Yeah, it just for one show.
Speaker 2:  Do you wanna watch college softball on a Saturday afternoon? Like they got
Speaker 2:  you. Yeah. Four night at night a month. Let's go. Also, you just made an
Speaker 2:  interesting point, which is you sound like a person who would be against
Speaker 2:  doing what everybody thinks is gonna happen, which is that Disney just pulls
Speaker 2:  all of the Hulu stuff into Disney Plus because it's a better and more successful
Speaker 2:  app anyway. But it sounds like in the, like it's the one app I trust on the
Speaker 2:  iPad fame. Maybe you don't want that to happen.
Speaker 4:  I we can age gate it already. So like she's already got the
Speaker 4:  kids version of D plus, which is like, there, there's a lot of age gates
Speaker 4:  built into it. Like they know that their audience is kids. So I'm not worried
Speaker 4:  about the catalog and the app expanding cuz I think that Disney of all companies
Speaker 4:  will be good at knowing that my daughter is five. You know, like it's, it's
Speaker 4:  actually hard for her to get some movies. Like some Pixar movies are rated
Speaker 4:  pg and she can't get them in her version of d plus, like, we have to use
Speaker 4:  my account. So I'm not so worried about that. I do think,
Speaker 4:  like, the reason I was like, whatever on Hulu is like Hulu will go
Speaker 4:  away before TikTok goes away.
Speaker 5:  Oh really? Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Like
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Or it will outlast us all. Those are the only two outcomes.
Speaker 2:  Season 61 of The Handmaids Tale coming
Speaker 4:  Soon. Exactly. Like every one of its corporate owners
Speaker 4:  has tried to kill Hulu and it has survived. It has outlasted all of them.
Speaker 4:  But I think in this particular round of the streaming wars,
Speaker 4:  neither Disney nor Comcaster League wants it to exist.
Speaker 4:  It just seems like the, if you're taking it, you should take it part as part
Speaker 4:  of this bundle, but it's a a it's a risky early round pick right now.
Speaker 2:  Alex, what do you think? This would've been my next pick. So I'm, I'm very
Speaker 2:  on board for this. Alex, what do you think?
Speaker 5:  I mean, I assumed one of you with children was gonna pick it, so
Speaker 5:  I was just waiting for one of you with children to pick it. I, I don't need
Speaker 5:  a lot of this stuff on there.
Speaker 2:  It does kind of feel like if you don't have kids or care about Marvel
Speaker 2:  and Star Wars, Disney Plus is actually like mostly useless to you.
Speaker 2:  But if either of those things apply to you, it is like the most important
Speaker 2:  thing in the universe.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It's like I can just go see those movies when they come out and like
Speaker 5:  the TV shows have all been fine.
Speaker 4:  People should know that if I could draft Disney Plus without drafting Star
Speaker 4:  Wars, I would do it. If I could just leave that on the
Speaker 4:  table, it would be fine. This is very much the Bluey draft
Speaker 4:  pick and if you have a child, you know how important this pick is.
Speaker 2:  That's fair. All right, we're through two rounds. We should take a break
Speaker 2:  and then we're gonna do the rest. Let me just recap the first two rounds.
Speaker 2:  So after two, after two rounds, NII has picked TikTok and the Disney bundle,
Speaker 2:  which is Disney plus, Hulu and ESPN plus. Alex has
Speaker 2:  HBO Max and Paramount plus slash Showtime and I have
Speaker 2:  YouTube and Peacock. I feel like I'm losing so far, I would say.
Speaker 2:  I also just wanna say, I was so thrown off by not getting the first pick.
Speaker 2:  You guys like, it's, it's bad. It's going bad for me, but I'm gonna, I'm
Speaker 2:  gonna come back strong from the break. I also just wanna say we are six picks
Speaker 2:  in and no one has picked Netflix and that's kind of wild. Yeah. But I suspect
Speaker 2:  that's coming up soon. Let's take a quick break and then we'll get back into
Speaker 2:  it. We'll be right back.
Speaker 8:  Support for this podcast comes from Slack. Some of you might remember work
Speaker 8:  before the internet. Some of you might not. Either way. Work today relies
Speaker 8:  on the internet and if your team hasn't made the switch to Slack, you might
Speaker 8:  find it just as vital a tool for staying connected and getting work done.
Speaker 8:  It's built to make work simpler and more connected. Not to mention more
Speaker 8:  pleasant. Slack is a productivity platform that connects all your team members
Speaker 8:  together instantly. It's built to help your team with a host of features
Speaker 8:  like huddles for quick check-ins and clips for recording and sharing video.
Speaker 8:  Slack also makes it easy to search and find the right information you need.
Speaker 8:  You can even integrate the apps you use in your normal workflow, like
Speaker 8:  your calendar or project management tools so you can stay focused on the
Speaker 8:  work that matters and get more done. So if you wanna make sure your team
Speaker 8:  has all the tools they need to work well then check out Slack. Learn more
Speaker 8:  at slack.com/productivity.
Speaker 9:  I'm Preed Barara, the former US attorney in Manhattan. My
Speaker 9:  podcast stay tuned is about law, justice and politics.
Speaker 9:  The Manhattan District Attorney's case against Donald Trump is one of the
Speaker 9:  most consequential, legal and political stories of our time. So
Speaker 9:  this week I was joined by two top legal experts, former US Attorney
Speaker 9:  Joyce Vance and Law Fair editor Ben Witi, to analyze the
Speaker 9:  charges.
Speaker 10:  While I don't think this is a no-brainer case to bring,
Speaker 10:  I do think there is a fairly solid basis
Speaker 10:  for it.
Speaker 9:  The potential evidence,
Speaker 11:  I think the jury hearing the evidence that at least if Brad can
Speaker 11:  prove what he's laid out in the statement of fact, the evidence will
Speaker 11:  be compelling on these charges.
Speaker 9:  And where we go from here, it's not clear that a conviction on
Speaker 9:  one or more of these felony counts would result in prison
Speaker 9:  sentence or a substantial prison sentence to listen. Just search. Stay
Speaker 9:  tuned wherever you get your podcasts. New episodes drop every
Speaker 9:  Thursday.
Speaker 9:  Stay tuned.
Speaker 2:  All right, we're back. Round three streaming draft. Andrew, do you have any
Speaker 2:  more music for us?
Speaker 2:  Yes,
Speaker 12:  It's the birthday streaming draft. Come at you live in New York
Speaker 12:  City,
Speaker 2:  Brought to you by Monster F
Speaker 2:  All right, Eli round three.
Speaker 4:  This is my reach. This is the one that is, it's an obvious
Speaker 4:  bad idea, but I'm doing it cuz it's, it's gonna blow the cost
Speaker 4:  structure for me. It's, it's, it's over, there's no way I'm getting the bonus
Speaker 4:  pick after this YouTube TV was Sunday ticket.
Speaker 2:  Ah, ooh, that's expensive, right?
Speaker 4:  It's like 80 bucks a month plus like $300 to for Sunday
Speaker 4:  ticket in Ren zone.
Speaker 2:  Yep.
Speaker 5:  Per month or
Speaker 2:  Just, yeah, it's, it's 72 99 a month right now for just
Speaker 2:  YouTube TV because the price goes up like every three to four days.
Speaker 2:  And Sunday ticket they just announced yesterday as this goes live,
Speaker 2:  the price for Sunday ticket is gonna be $289 in a presale and
Speaker 2:  3 89 if you buy it season. Are you sure you're you're sure about this pick?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I mean they got me, what, what am I gonna do? I mean, I will say Alex
Speaker 4:  brought up Yellowstone. I watched all of Yellowstone on our YouTube
Speaker 4:  tv cuz Paramount channel's in there so you can just like DVR and skip
Speaker 4:  the ads. It is an election year. I feel like I'm gonna watch, end up watching
Speaker 4:  a lot of cnn. I appear on CNBC sometimes my wife likes
Speaker 4:  to watch me on television. Like I can concoct argue. It's like mostly
Speaker 4:  nonsensical arguments, right? Yeah. But I can concoct arguments for the
Speaker 4:  value of, of live cable television. But if not for Sunday ticket,
Speaker 4:  I would not be drafting this high, it's Sunday ticket that I'm drafting.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, it's football for me it's Red zone. Just the, the like that's the
Speaker 2:  only way I watch football anymore. And there's a lot of money I would pay
Speaker 2:  and do pay every year to do it. But I can do it through YouTube.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, right. You can, you can buy the Red Sun Channel through YouTube. Right.
Speaker 4:  But you already have it right. Again, I'm off the cost curve. It doesn't
Speaker 4:  even matter. But I'm buying the version that comes with Red Zone cuz there's
Speaker 4:  a cheaper one that doesn't.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, you really did just kind of give yourself an insurmountable lead in
Speaker 2:  the spending a lot of money every month. $73 a month.
Speaker 4:  All right. All the rest of mine are gonna be free. Free V baby. Let's do
Speaker 4:  this thing.
Speaker 2:  Is the YouTube TV over like Hulu with live TV or any of those other ones?
Speaker 2:  Just purely it's, it's football.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I, I can't imagine why I would pay for the one without football.
Speaker 4:  I think that's YouTube's calculation here.
Speaker 2:  I was gonna say, I feel like you just explained why YouTube spent all this
Speaker 2:  money on football
Speaker 4:  Also. I mean I've, I've used the other ones. They're fine. I think the YouTube
Speaker 4:  TV interface is better. Does it matter? Like Yeah,
Speaker 4:  it's football. I'm buying football.
Speaker 2:  Alex, did you have live TV on your list at all?
Speaker 5:  Kind of.
Speaker 2:  I feel like if you don't care about sports, why would you? I
Speaker 5:  Mean I've got Paramount plus I've got another pick potentially. But
Speaker 5:  yeah, I don't really care about sports so I don't really care about most
Speaker 5:  live tv.
Speaker 2:  The $75 a month for live TV is not blowing your mind.
Speaker 5:  No. Okay. I just pirate it. Okay. I mean I can just watch it over
Speaker 5:  the air. Over the
Speaker 2:  Air. You haven't drafted your Plex server yet. Don't forget it's still out
Speaker 2:  there. All right, well then let's move on. What's your next pick?
Speaker 5:  Okay, this one's a toughie. I'm gonna do something really, speaking of live
Speaker 5:  tv, I'm gonna do something really cheap. I'm gonna do, not Plex
Speaker 5:  but Channels, which is a DVR service because
Speaker 5:  it can work with TV everywhere. So anything that potentially is
Speaker 5:  TV everywhere accounts, I can DVR those.
Speaker 4:  But then you need a cable subscription.
Speaker 5:  Not necessarily, it's not just cable. It's a bunch of other stuff too. Oh,
Speaker 5:  I see. So I, I think it might work with Parallel Plus I can find out. But
Speaker 5:  then it also gives me all the live TV and it gives me access to like
Speaker 5:  two B and all of those things, which gives you CNN and all of that.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Wait, so explain how channels works for people who don't know this
Speaker 2:  is, this is like deep streaming nerd stuff. You gotta, you gotta walk us
Speaker 2:  through it.
Speaker 5:  So it's basically a D V R service
Speaker 5:  and you can plug in, if you've got a HD home run tuner
Speaker 5:  you, you just plug that in and it automatically pulls down anything you get
Speaker 5:  over the air and you can DVR that. But you can also attach
Speaker 5:  M three U playlists, which is what, two B and Pluto
Speaker 5:  and all of those free services offer. So you can then
Speaker 5:  have all of those channels as well and just like watch
Speaker 5:  all of the channels. Like you watch normal tv so I can watch all of the
Speaker 5:  Carol Burnett show I want and that's all I care about in the
Speaker 4:  World. This is a power move.
Speaker 2:  This definitely like violates the spirit of the game, but I like it. So we're
Speaker 2:  gonna allow it. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  This is great. But you should definitely draft a kicker in the first round.
Speaker 4:  Like, I
Speaker 2:  Don't know a hundred percent. Yeah. I'm just drafting all the
Speaker 2:  teams all at once. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Yeah. All of them. It's, it's an absolute cheat and if you
Speaker 5:  tell me no, I'll, I'll, I'll accept it. I'll accept it.
Speaker 4:  No, this is absolutely, this is a paid streaming service. It's in the rules.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. This totally counts. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It's a paid service and it requires way more work and
Speaker 5:  effort than any of the other ones we've discussed here so far. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  I've never gotten past the sort of like initial setup hurdle of channels
Speaker 2:  cuz it is, like you said, you need special hardware. You need to like, have
Speaker 2:  done real work to get it set up once it's like up and running. Is it
Speaker 2:  easy or do you have to like Tomagotchi style tend to your channels? Yeah,
Speaker 5:  It's totally easy. Like I was getting, there was some
Speaker 5:  sport, I don't remember which one that my brother couldn't get with
Speaker 5:  Fios at his house, but I could get it over the air. And so
Speaker 5:  I just sent him the code, like the IP address for my
Speaker 5:  server and he was just watching his sport live and was totally
Speaker 5:  fine. And he lives many miles away from me. So it
Speaker 5:  works super, super easy once you get it set
Speaker 2:  Up. I mean I I I do feel like anything that starts with the phrase I sent
Speaker 2:  him, the IP address of my server is objectively not super,
Speaker 2:  super easy.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It was just like a phone number. He was just like, I need a number
Speaker 5:  for this. What's the number? And I sent him the number and he's like, okay,
Speaker 5:  done.
Speaker 2:  That's fair. Type these numbers. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  So it it works, it works great. Okay. But you do have to get it set up.
Speaker 2:  We should probably should have said at the top that we all get the, the over
Speaker 2:  the air broadcast channels for free. Right? That's yeah. That's just you,
Speaker 2:  you can't help but have those, they're just there. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  You can't draft an antenna.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, right. You can't draft an antenna, you just have one.
Speaker 5:  So I'm just, I'm just enjoying all of them waiting for ATS
Speaker 5:  3.0. ATSC 3.0 to save our lives. It's never gonna
Speaker 5:  happen. Oh
Speaker 2:  Boy. I look forward to you drafting ATSC 3.0 every draft for the
Speaker 2:  next 20 years.
Speaker 5:  You're just throwing away all of your picks on that one.
Speaker 2:  Ooh, I get two picks now and I have three that I'm choosing from. And I need
Speaker 2:  the two of you to help me. We're just gonna talk through this together. We're,
Speaker 4:  I'm your enemy. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  No, just we're just, we're gonna talk this through. It's ultimately my decision
Speaker 2:  and I know you're lying to me so it's, we'll, we'll get there. So there's,
Speaker 2:  there's Netflix, there's Amazon Prime video and there's Discovery
Speaker 2:  Plus These are the three I'm debating between. Wow. Really These are all
Speaker 2:  the kind of like volume plays, right? Like, like a Prime video
Speaker 2:  just has a billion movies to watch. Most of them are bad, but they're there.
Speaker 2:  Netflix has infinite stuff including like every bad
Speaker 2:  reality show that I like right now. And then Discovery Plus is
Speaker 2:  basically for me, it's like the HGTV and murder shows
Speaker 2:  for my wife service. So these all kind of serve of the same purpose.
Speaker 5:  But you already have YouTube, right? Like YouTube has all the HG
Speaker 5:  TV kind of shows only they're made by, they're like
Speaker 5:  uglier because they're made by just a dude in his house.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. There's just worse. Like I have watched a lot of the Architectural
Speaker 2:  Digest celebrities show you their house tours. Love. I love that videos.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. But sometimes I wanna see people try and fail to flip their own
Speaker 2:  house.
Speaker 2:  It's very important to me. I think I have to pick Netflix here just because
Speaker 2:  Netflix is like, yeah, it's both a giant of the
Speaker 2:  space and also just has a mountain of content that really nobody else can
Speaker 2:  touch.
Speaker 4:  This is your background music choice. This is what you're saying. You just
Speaker 4:  want stuff that's on.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, this is my like something good to watch, but I
Speaker 2:  don't have a specific desire for what I wanna watch
Speaker 2:  because the flip side is like Apple TV Plus is still sitting there, right?
Speaker 2:  And Apple TV plus is like three shows that I love. And that's it. That's
Speaker 2:  the whole service. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  That's the, I'm drafting content. This is, this is why I asked Alex that
Speaker 4:  question earlier, right? Like Right, you can either draft content or you
Speaker 4:  get to this point and you're like just stuff.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And I think, I think for me, I'm still in the just
Speaker 2:  stuff mode. I just don't have enough show
Speaker 2:  loyalty is the thing that I'm realizing. Like I don't have that many things
Speaker 2:  that I care so much about that I can't, like
Speaker 4:  I used the first pick of the draft on stuff. Like that's what, it's just
Speaker 4:  stuff like I get, I
Speaker 2:  Feel you. I think what I'm gonna do here is I'm gonna do Netflix and I'm
Speaker 2:  gonna do Discovery Plus. Wow. And I now have just
Speaker 2:  several lifetimes worth of relatively mediocre stuff to
Speaker 2:  watch. And also whenever the next Squid game comes out, I have that
Speaker 4:  Disclosure. We, I'm in a Netflix ep, this show's called The Future Oven.
Speaker 4:  David Chick watched. It's
Speaker 2:  Very good. I can watch it now. I'm the only one of us who's allowed to watch
Speaker 2:  it from now on. Yeah. So there we go. I took it. I have Netflix. This is
Speaker 2:  good. I feel better now. I was doing bad after two rounds. Now I feel like
Speaker 2:  I'm winning.
Speaker 5:  It wasn't even on my list.
Speaker 2:  Netflix wasn't on your
Speaker 5:  List. It wasn't even on my list. Wow. I got really mad at, they canceled
Speaker 5:  some show I liked and so I stopped watching it for like three weeks and I
Speaker 5:  was like, oh, I don't actually miss it that much.
Speaker 2:  So that has been consistently my thing. I will say the, the reason I was
Speaker 2:  bummed to not get HBO O Max was that it's really the only one that I
Speaker 2:  would like super, super notice if I didn't have it anymore.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. All the rest are like varying levels of good shows. But HBO Max is
Speaker 2:  the one that's like, like I watched Succession religiously and almost
Speaker 2:  all of the shows that I watch religiously on purpose are on H B O,
Speaker 2:  which is crazy and wild and kudos to HBO O for
Speaker 2:  continuing to be the only one to do that. But yeah, Netflix is like, it's
Speaker 2:  just a lot of stuff and it's better stuff than most of the other
Speaker 2:  companies stuff, but it's still just stuff. Yeah. So I think I feel good
Speaker 2:  about that. I'm taking Netflix for 20 bucks a month and Discovery Plus for
Speaker 2:  seven bucks a month. And now my wife has all of the murder documentaries
Speaker 2:  she could possibly want. You're welcome Anna. I love you.
Speaker 4:  Here's a question, did you expect Netflix to fall this far? I definitely
Speaker 4:  did. Is what? I'll tell you I have, I ha it's on my list, but like, it's
Speaker 4:  like a late round Nice to have pickup.
Speaker 2:  Well, so that was the thing that was most surprising to me in going through
Speaker 2:  this was how few incredibly compelling
Speaker 2:  reasons there were to pick Netflix. Like Yeah. And
Speaker 2:  this is the thing we've talked about a lot on this show, right? Like Netflix
Speaker 2:  is great at having lots of shows and being available everywhere and it's
Speaker 2:  AppWorks pretty well, but they're still in search of like
Speaker 2:  the things that draw people to come to it on purpose and really
Speaker 2:  like create cultural moments. They have, they've had some
Speaker 2:  wins. Like Squid Game was huge. Tiger was huge. Like they have these
Speaker 5:  Beats Wednesday.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Stranger Things Wednesday. Outer banks. Like if you're a teenager in
Speaker 4:  America, you're, they've got you.
Speaker 2:  I've been watching The Night Agent recently. It's very good. It's just the
Speaker 2:  like pulp spy show. But it's excellent. But yeah, and I don't know, I just
Speaker 2:  feel like part of this, I'm definitely holding out hope that the next Gray
Speaker 2:  Man movie on Netflix is better than the first one because I love that book
Speaker 2:  series and I hate that movie.
Speaker 4:  No, no, no. They, they, this whole thing that they do where they're like,
Speaker 4:  rich people make movies for lots of money. The Rock. You have an idea.
Speaker 4:  Put Cal Gao like stop it. Like you don't know what you're doing.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. None of them have been any good.
Speaker 4:  What was the Michael Bay one with the numbers in the title?
Speaker 2:  Oh, was it six Underground Guys?
Speaker 4:  Yes. Six times the numbers in the title. That's what I got for you.
Speaker 2:  That movie, like the description of Six Underground is
Speaker 2:  like meant for me specifically as a person. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And you don't have any recollection of that happening to you at
Speaker 2:  All? No, I really don't. It was, it was bad is all I remember.
Speaker 2:  But I feel good about picking it up here cuz I feel like I'm, I'm always
Speaker 2:  gonna have something to watch and it'll always be fine.
Speaker 5:  Totally adequate content.
Speaker 2:  All right, so now we are, we are into round four already. Alex,
Speaker 2:  you're up next. What do you got?
Speaker 5:  Ooh, I'm gonna go Criterion. Oh, I pay for
Speaker 5:  it already. I really enjoy it. It's probably got the
Speaker 5:  best set of Hong Kong action films that you can
Speaker 5:  find in streaming. It's really hard to find those in streaming. And it's
Speaker 5:  actually got a whole bunch of 'em. Especially they like a bunch of Michelle
Speaker 5:  yo stuff is just popped up on there. It's got a lot of like old classic
Speaker 5:  musicals, which that's like some people watch YouTube. I just
Speaker 5:  go and like, watch specific dance scenes from old classic musicals and
Speaker 5:  I can just do that on Criterion and it's got a bunch of documentaries. Like,
Speaker 5:  I'm enjoying My Choice. This
Speaker 2:  Is a good pick. I didn't even have Criterion on my list. But that's a, that's
Speaker 2:  a really good pick. And Criterion also does a really good job with like,
Speaker 2:  they have a lot of bonus features they do. Cool. Like behind the scenes stuff,
Speaker 2:  it's like, it is probably like the film buffs, most
Speaker 2:  film buffs.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Thing. There's like a ton of movies on there. I will never ever watch.
Speaker 5:  But I, I like that I could, if I really wanted to. If I wanna go
Speaker 5:  watch some French NuWave, I can do that. I'm not going to, but
Speaker 5:  I like that. I know I
Speaker 2:  Can. But you, you can Neela Did you have Criterion on your list?
Speaker 4:  I did not.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, you should have waited on Criterion. It's a good pick, but I had not
Speaker 2:  even, it had not even occurred to me to think about it.
Speaker 4:  Once we get in these rounds, it's all bets are off. Like Alex is just off
Speaker 4:  in the woods, she's like, all right channels and the criterion streaming
Speaker 4:  service like
Speaker 5:  Wee over in a corner. I'm having a great time.
Speaker 4:  No, it's, it's an excellent pick by the way. I think that's
Speaker 5:  Very smart. Yeah, it's just a big nerdy art pick.
Speaker 2:  And ironically maybe the single most likely candidate to still
Speaker 2:  be around a bunch of years from now. Like, I don't know if I would pick against
Speaker 2:  Criterion in this longevity fight. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Because they got killed once and they came back like, yeah, they're gonna,
Speaker 5:  they're gonna live forever now.
Speaker 2:  People still like black and white movies, including my father-in-law
Speaker 2:  who every time we go visit is like, have you seen this movie from 1936? And
Speaker 2:  I was like, Nope, haven't seen it. He's like, well let's watch it tonight.
Speaker 2:  So I'm getting a film education. It's lovely. All right, now
Speaker 2:  O'Neil, you get two now. Wait,
Speaker 4:  I feel like this is unfair cuz we, you and I keep getting two in our own.
Speaker 4:  Alex is going in between us. I'm
Speaker 2:  Like, hi. Yeah, but it means we have to wait longer. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I feel like this draft order makes more sense when you have more people.
Speaker 2:  I will say, I think Alex has gotten every single thing she wanted. So
Speaker 5:  That's
Speaker 4:  I'll bad.
Speaker 5:  I've been, you guys are off in sports land over there and I'm a little gremlin.
Speaker 4:  I'm like doing strategy. All right. I have a rules
Speaker 4:  question. She, you said this about YouTube that you get a music service for
Speaker 4:  free. Are we only drafting video services or
Speaker 4:  do I have to put a music service in the mix?
Speaker 2:  If you want a music service, you can draft a music service.
Speaker 4:  But if I don't, like are we just assuming that everyone has a Spotify subscription
Speaker 4:  on the side? Or if I don't draft one, do I not listen to music?
Speaker 2:  If you don't draft one, you get ad supported Pandora. That's, that's that's
Speaker 2:  the baseline.
Speaker 4:  All right. Just I that was important cuz you, you took YouTube music.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. All right then I'm taking Apple Music easy. Ah,
Speaker 5:  She knew I should have picked that last.
Speaker 2:  Why Apple Music?
Speaker 4:  I'm an Apple Music person. I, I I I think the interface is calmer. It
Speaker 4:  doesn't seem like the music industry is perpetuating some sort of three card
Speaker 4:  Monty situation with me every time I open it. Fair. I like that they have
Speaker 4:  lossless. I can't tell you if I can actually hear it or not, but I, I like
Speaker 4:  that it's there, it's like a binky for me and you know, I'm an
Speaker 4:  old head so it sort of seamlessly imported my iTunes library
Speaker 4:  from way back then. I still just like gaze upon it from time to
Speaker 4:  time.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. How much of the music service choice is like
Speaker 2:  inertia as opposed to anything else? Cause I even had this thought when
Speaker 2:  I picked YouTube and got YouTube music, I was like, ugh, do I still need
Speaker 2:  to pick Spotify? Cuz I've like had Spotify for 10 years and it's gonna be
Speaker 2:  a gigantic pain in the ass to switch. Is it just the switching costs? Like
Speaker 2:  if you were starting over, would you still pick Apple Music? Well,
Speaker 4:  It depends. I think the switching cost, it's not money, right? It's
Speaker 4:  like well have my music, like I am not a curated playlist
Speaker 4:  person unless I'm just like yelling at a voice assistant to start playing
Speaker 4:  some music, you know? Sure. I'm like, I'm gonna listen to this album. I wanna
Speaker 4:  listen to these songs. So there's just a part of me that's very much, it's
Speaker 4:  hard to switch unless you know that I want the entire like
Speaker 4:  clash catalog, the entire Cure catalog. Like I'm still
Speaker 4:  there. I'm still doing that thing. And so that if, if that was easier, I
Speaker 4:  would happily switch. But having like open an app and like go tell it which
Speaker 4:  18 records I want to prepopulate and have downloaded again is a very high
Speaker 4:  switching cost and I don't have to pay it with Apple Music.
Speaker 2:  All right. Mila, you have another pick, but we're gonna pause between your
Speaker 2:  picks again. We're gonna take one more break and then we're gonna come do
Speaker 2:  the last round and then all the insane cleanup we have to do to make any
Speaker 2:  of this make any sense. We'll be right back.
Speaker 13:  All right, Naima, I need three reasons why people should listen to On with
Speaker 13:  Kara Swisher, what have you
Speaker 14:  Got? Okay. First you interview smart, powerful people like Hillary Clinton,
Speaker 14:  mark Benioff and Stacey Abrams. Second, you grill them harder than most
Speaker 14:  people would dare. And third, the podcast will make you think, it'll make
Speaker 14:  you laugh and it'll make you smarter. How's that?
Speaker 13:  That's like five things, but good enough on with Kara Swisher
Speaker 13:  wherever you get your podcast.
Speaker 2:  All right, we're back. Let's just recap. We've done four rounds. We have
Speaker 2:  one more round to go. So far Eli has picked TikTok, the Disney bundle,
Speaker 2:  YouTube tv, and Apple Music. And just based on my
Speaker 2:  math here is spending like a little over a hundred dollars a month so far.
Speaker 2:  So great job.
Speaker 4:  I'm living the brand name lifestyle, man. I'm the luxury mall.
Speaker 2:  You really are you. It's really true. Alex has picked HBO Max
Speaker 2:  Paramount plus slash Showtime, the channels app and the
Speaker 2:  Criterion Collection because Alex exists on a different planet from the rest
Speaker 2:  of us.
Speaker 4:  Alex lives in Brooklyn.
Speaker 13:  Yes, true.
Speaker 2:  And Alex is spending in the realm of like
Speaker 2:  $45 a month, somewhere in that range. I have
Speaker 2:  YouTube, peacock, Netflix, and Discovery Plus because I live in the Midwest
Speaker 2:  and I am, I am, I am an American mom.
Speaker 13:  You got the little haircut to the side. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  And let's see, I'm spending 60 bucks all in. So
Speaker 2:  I would say it's very unlikely that Nii loses the, who spends the most.
Speaker 2:  So congrats to Ni Eli already. And now we are onto our
Speaker 2:  fifth and final round. Nii, you're up. What do you got?
Speaker 4:  All right. I'm picking between two. They're radically different, but I'm
Speaker 4:  gonna do it. I'm just gonna say this out loud. I'm picking my buddy Viens
Speaker 4:  Plex server.
Speaker 13:  It's
Speaker 4:  Really good. I can just text him.
Speaker 2:  Tell us about villain's Plex Server.
Speaker 4:  So I've known Vivin for a long time. He's, he's been running this thing for
Speaker 4:  a long time. He has, it's au all automatic, it's all legal content. It's
Speaker 4:  just Linux distributions. Yeah. And whenever I want a new Linux distribution,
Speaker 4:  I just text him and it appears
Speaker 13:  Channels does that too.
Speaker 4:  You
Speaker 2:  Don't have to ask questions about where they come from.
Speaker 4:  Look, every now and again, I'm like, oh, I need the latest version of Red
Speaker 4:  Hat.
Speaker 4:  Vi's daughter is about the same age as my daughter. So it's, it's often that
Speaker 4:  he has the same needs of Linux on his Plex
Speaker 4:  server.
Speaker 2:  How are Viens metadatas?
Speaker 4:  My understanding is that much of the metadata
Speaker 4:  cleanup you need to reliably distribute Linux around your home
Speaker 4:  is automated.
Speaker 2:  Sometimes you just wanna watch Linux, you know what I mean? Sometimes it's
Speaker 2:  Friday night and you just wanna put on Linux and watch it for two hours.
Speaker 4:  Every now and again, you're just like, yeah,
Speaker 5:  Are you paying for Plex Pass?
Speaker 4:  No, no, no, no,
Speaker 5:  No. So no, no offline.
Speaker 4:  No. Yeah. This is just a, this is just a, a cleanup pick at the end here,
Speaker 4:  you know? Yeah. If you draft your first round quarterback and you pick one
Speaker 4:  in the seventh round, just to put some competition and make sure that's what,
Speaker 4:  that's why I'm doing this.
Speaker 2:  I like it. What was your other choice if you didn't pick that?
Speaker 4:  Hilariously randomly. Sirius xm. What? Yeah,
Speaker 4:  that, and that's straight up. There's like three shows that Becky listens
Speaker 4:  to that are only unserious. You
Speaker 2:  Just almost picked Apple Music and Sirius XM back to back. Yeah. Do you live
Speaker 2:  in a car?
Speaker 4:  I picked the general hilarity of the Linux conversation over the actual
Speaker 4:  need of making my wife happy.
Speaker 2:  What does she listen to on Sirius?
Speaker 4:  There's like a bunch of comedy podcasts that she listens to on Sirius. They're
Speaker 4:  only on Sirius, so she like, that's why we have it. And then I do actually
Speaker 4:  live in the car. And so I listen to a lot of Sirius in
Speaker 2:  The car. What's your go-to? What do you listen to? Are you a yacht rock guy?
Speaker 4:  Not yacht, rock, lithium, the, obviously the Turner Rock. Oh. And
Speaker 4:  First Wave. Nice. You can tell where my music tastes like fully lie.
Speaker 4:  The other thing that's completely insane to do, if you have a serious subscription,
Speaker 4:  you spend a lot of time in the car and you just need voices, is you can listen
Speaker 4:  to CNBC as an audio stream. And that is the
Speaker 4:  most insane podcast that you can listen to. Like Jim Kramer
Speaker 4:  eight in the morning, just like yelling about money is
Speaker 4:  like, I definitely don't feel sleepy, I'll tell you that much.
Speaker 2:  And it's Jim Kramer saying, look at this chart. And you saying, Jim, I can't
Speaker 4:  Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 2:  Can't see the
Speaker 4:  Chart. It is a vastly different experience to listen to it as an audio feed
Speaker 4:  in the morning.
Speaker 2:  Okay. I just wanna say about Sirius XM that I bought a car, which meant that
Speaker 2:  I got three free months of Sirius xm, which I used zero times because I couldn't
Speaker 2:  even figure out how to set it up. And then since it elapsed,
Speaker 2:  I would say I either get a phone call or a piece of physical mail from SiriusXM
Speaker 2:  asking me to resubscribe every single day. And I have
Speaker 2:  now become resolute that I will never, ever, ever listen to
Speaker 2:  SiriusXM as long as I live. I refuse.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I mean, but I'm commuting from the woods to the city once a week. So
Speaker 4:  I spend five hours in a single day in the car often. And it's
Speaker 4:  like, great. But like why, like honestly for the purpose of this draft, that's
Speaker 4:  very utilitarian, like we're making entertainment here and it's, it's VIP
Speaker 4:  and Flex Server,
Speaker 2:  Which I'm assuming is Free Vipin doesn't charge you server fees.
Speaker 4:  We again, we're friends for a long time. It, it all evens out in the end.
Speaker 4:  All right. I've bought him a lot of drinks over the years.
Speaker 2:  We're, we're putting a zero next to vi's Flex server. We'll put,
Speaker 2:  we'll put 99 cents cuz you have to buy 'em a beer every once in a while.
Speaker 2:  Cost 99 cents a month. All right. All right. Last pick. Alex,
Speaker 2:  what do you got?
Speaker 5:  What's the, what's the Apple service thing? That's the Apple Music and the
Speaker 5:  Apple tv.
Speaker 4:  Apple one. Apple one.
Speaker 2:  Apple
Speaker 4:  One. Oh, that's good.
Speaker 2:  That's a good pick.
Speaker 5:  Gonna spend a bunch of money and do that one because I too
Speaker 5:  like Apple Music more than Spotify and Apple Music,
Speaker 5:  classical. I've actually been using that way more than I thought I would.
Speaker 5:  And then I think Apple TV's like it's got good content.
Speaker 2:  What do you watch? What are your shows really
Speaker 5:  Into Dickinson. I loved that when it came on Severance for all
Speaker 5:  Mankind. The Morning show. I don't watch the morning show.
Speaker 5:  That's a lie. But it's there. Ted Lasso.
Speaker 4:  I haven't watched the season of Ted Lasso. I think that says a lot. It's,
Speaker 4:  it has even occurred to me to spend time doing it. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  It's fine. It's a, it's a show. You know what is good is Hello? Tomorrow?
Speaker 5:  Is it actually good?
Speaker 2:  Weird but delightful. I've only watched like four episodes, but it's very
Speaker 2:  good shrinking also very good. This is the thing about Apple TV plus it doesn't
Speaker 2:  have that much stuff, but it's like good show to bad show ratio
Speaker 2:  is probably higher than any other platform I can think
Speaker 5:  Of. Like Dickinson is a show. I will, I will rewatch. It's one of my rewatch
Speaker 5:  shows at this point. I just, I love it. And then for all
Speaker 5:  mankind, like it's great you watch people get progressively worse makeup
Speaker 5:  as they pretend to age 10 years every season and then go into space with
Speaker 5:  iPods. That's
Speaker 2:  Ra. Alex, that was a really good pick. I'm sort of annoyed because you also,
Speaker 2:  for Apple One, you get Apple Arcade and you get a bunch of iCloud storage
Speaker 2:  that you'll never use. But that's a, that's a pretty good pick. If
Speaker 4:  I, if iCloud storage isn't, then Alex is finally with the last pick,
Speaker 4:  snaked the most important pick in the draft.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. You guys are all gonna be getting that obnoxious iCloud
Speaker 5:  notification now.
Speaker 4:  I don't think iCloud storage accounts, like if not, we need to redo this
Speaker 4:  whole pick.
Speaker 2:  I'm gonna take Dropbox Business. It's my last pick.
Speaker 2:  Okay, so what's
Speaker 5:  Your final
Speaker 2:  One? I have two left on my list, which serve very different purposes for
Speaker 2:  me. One is Amazon Prime video, which was what I was gonna pick if I didn't
Speaker 2:  get YouTube because it's another one that's just like a big bunch of content
Speaker 2:  plus of music service for free. So that was exciting. And then there's
Speaker 2:  Hulu with live tv, which I want to pick because I
Speaker 2:  like Hulu because it also has a couple of my like endlessly rewatched
Speaker 2:  shows. And because I need live sports, I think I'm gonna pick
Speaker 2:  Hulu. I think Hulu with live tv, which is 70 bucks a month. It comes
Speaker 2:  with, well, okay, here's a rules clarification question. If I sign up for
Speaker 2:  Hulu with live tv, I also get the Disney bundle. I like back into the Disney
Speaker 2:  bundle. Does that count?
Speaker 4:  Wait There's no way to get Hulu with live TV without getting Disney Plus.
Speaker 2:  No, you just get it for free. It's 70 bucks a month. Like they're just, they're
Speaker 2:  like, sure, I have Disney you
Speaker 5:  Some, some
Speaker 4:  Money. Yeah, I mean, I think this is allowed. Okay, good. I, I came at Hulu
Speaker 4:  the other way, but if I hadn't blown the salary cap with Sunday ticket,
Speaker 4:  we, we would be competing here and I think it would be fair.
Speaker 2:  Okay. All right. Good. I buy it then. Yeah. I'm taking Hulu IV 70
Speaker 2:  bucks a month. I get Disney plus I get ESPN plus I get New Girl, which is
Speaker 2:  just about to leave Netflix and go to Hulu, which is another one of the shows
Speaker 2:  I've watched 700 times. Shit's Creek is there. It's another one I've
Speaker 4:  Watched. Oh my God. This is an incredible sleeper final pick.
Speaker 2:  Oh yeah. I feel really good about this,
Speaker 5:  But like Neil and I both have access to that. He can just hit up his buddy.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Can I just get Zins, my last pick is Neely giving me Zins number.
Speaker 4:  That's my,
Speaker 2:  That's my final pick.
Speaker 4:  All that's on there is Linux. You guys
Speaker 5:  Just love that Red hat. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  I really like, I did not mean to do this. I accidentally ended up with like
Speaker 2:  the most down the middle set of streaming
Speaker 2:  services. This is really upsetting. Alright, so we have done five picks.
Speaker 2:  Congratulations to everybody. We completed the draft. Andrew, do you have
Speaker 2:  a cool last sound for the end of the draft?
Speaker 2:  Andrew, you've been keeping track of everything, all the math, all the money
Speaker 2:  totaled up for us. How are we doing?
Speaker 6:  Okay, so Eli, despite picking two streaming services that
Speaker 6:  did not cost any money collectively,
Speaker 6:  1 0 4 98
Speaker 5:  A
Speaker 6:  Month plus the 2 89, right? For the Sunday
Speaker 6:  ticket, which would be 3 93 96.
Speaker 6:  One time payment of that 2 89, but still Alex,
Speaker 6:  it's lowest here at 63 92. Good work.
Speaker 6:  Frugal. David, you really added it up with Hulu at live
Speaker 6:  TV coming at 1 29 95. Whoa.
Speaker 4:  Oof. A month. I got, I got football and a kind
Speaker 4:  of cheaper monthly
Speaker 2:  Picking. Netflix was a mistake. Now that I'm looking at it, 20 bucks for
Speaker 2:  Netflix was a bad use of 20 bucks a month.
Speaker 6:  YouTube premium family is a lot of money.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. But, but the reason, okay, let me defend family real fast.
Speaker 2:  I don't have to watch ads. Even when Anna wants to watch YouTube,
Speaker 2:  which
Speaker 4:  Is worth the extra money. That's true. That's true.
Speaker 2:  But okay, so that means Alex, you get, you get the free pick here at the
Speaker 2:  end. Ooh. Anything you want sky's the limit.
Speaker 5:  Okay. Does this one count Libro fm?
Speaker 4:  Oh my god. Alex, I gotta read my books. So it's an audiobook service.
Speaker 2:  Doesn't count.
Speaker 5:  Doesn't count. Okay. I
Speaker 2:  Don't know why. It just, it just doesn't, I just like, no,
Speaker 4:  I can't do it. That's an audiobook streaming service or is that just like
Speaker 4:  a, like a
Speaker 5:  Book? It's an audiobook service. And you get like a credit to buy a book
Speaker 5:  each month? No. Okay. All right, cool. Well that's great. I, I still,
Speaker 5:  I still can read books on my own time and you didn't make sure
Speaker 5:  I was gonna be allowed to read books. What's the Microsoft,
Speaker 5:  the Microsoft streaming cloud thing for games. Oh,
Speaker 2:  That's interesting.
Speaker 5:  I like, I think of it as Microsoft X Cloud, but whatever it's actually called
Speaker 5:  now, that one,
Speaker 2:  I just call it Game Pass. I think it has a more complicated name, but everybody
Speaker 2:  just calls it Game Pass. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  That's a good, that's also a good way to put it. Yeah. Game Pass.
Speaker 4:  So you ended up with the two game services with Apple One. You got Apple
Speaker 4:  or K and I are, you're going with Game Pass. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And then I play the other games while I'm watching my Criterion.
Speaker 4:  Really good. Wild Card pick at the end. Man,
Speaker 2:  That is a really good pick. Huh?
Speaker 5:  This is either that or Plex, but I already did Channels, which gives me the
Speaker 5:  same benefit as Plex, but a better DVR layout. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Stuff still sometimes adds to it when I don't DVR it. It's wild. It's
Speaker 4:  Crazy. Does it, this means that Amazon Prime went completely unpicked.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Which I, I think is not totally surprising.
Speaker 5:  How often are you like, oh man, I just really gotta watch like
Speaker 5:  extraction, but even more boring and on a worse UI
Speaker 4:  Again, because Becky is so into comedy every now and again,
Speaker 4:  there's like one comedy special on Amazon Prime. Yeah, I think that's it.
Speaker 2:  I'm really angry at this pick Alex, that was a really good pick that I feel
Speaker 2:  like I, if I had thought of that I probably would've picked a while ago.
Speaker 2:  Game Pass is good and also like a strong future bet. Like if we come
Speaker 2:  back in, the question is like, how did all our bets do? Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Game Game Pass is gonna exist. Yeah. Like the majority of mine will still
Speaker 5:  be around except for probably my first two. Maybe
Speaker 4:  I feel great about my draft. This is a gonna be, it's a, this is a solid
Speaker 4:  year ahead
Speaker 2:  On my list. The only things that went unpicked that I still have on my list
Speaker 2:  are nobody picked Prime Video. Nobody picked Spotify, which is
Speaker 2:  very interesting. We're all happy with our other weird services or
Speaker 2:  free Pandora and, and then I have a bunch of, like,
Speaker 2:  I wrote down, you know, Freek and Tubi and Pluto TV and the Roku channel
Speaker 2:  and all that stuff and Sling and nobody picked any of that. I'm not super
Speaker 2:  shocked.
Speaker 5:  But see I get, I get the Roku channel because it does an M three U
Speaker 5:  playlist so I can watch it anytime on channels. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Here's what I'm saying. I, if this drafted had like two or three more people
Speaker 4:  in it, I think the drafting around those channels would've been
Speaker 4:  intense, especially cuz then they would've been how you would strategically
Speaker 4:  have lowered the cost to try to get that extra pick.
Speaker 2:  All right, well next year, we'll this draft will include 13 people.
Speaker 2:  We're gonna have a 32 team draft next year and everybody gets
Speaker 2:  five picks. It's gonna get outrageous.
Speaker 4:  Although I will say even in this draft, David, I felt as though I was stealing
Speaker 4:  picture from you and I don't think I did that really, except maybe for Sunday
Speaker 4:  ticket. Neither of us was competing with Alex. No,
Speaker 5:  No one
Speaker 4:  Was really competing. Alex is fully trust the process. Like whatever was
Speaker 4:  going on over there.
Speaker 2:  I will say I was hoping that my three and four picks were gonna be YouTube
Speaker 2:  and TikTok. That was gonna be the turn I made at three and four. I thought
Speaker 2:  one of you would take hbo, one of you would take Disney, and then I would
Speaker 2:  get YouTube and TikTok and just like laugh at you old people about how I
Speaker 2:  understand the future. And it didn't really work out that way.
Speaker 4:  Unfortunately. No one took Instagram reels.
Speaker 2:  Well, you took TikTok, so you basically took Instagram reels.
Speaker 4:  It's brutal. But if you want, if you wanted that thing Instagram, right?
Speaker 4:  You want Diet TikTok, you take Instagram
Speaker 2:  Reels. True.
Speaker 5:  I like that. I'm not gonna know anything about the real world ever with
Speaker 5:  my picks. I don't know what's
Speaker 2:  Happening in world, which is not that different from what you came into this
Speaker 2:  with. So you're, you're good there.
Speaker 5:  I, I've learned nothing about the draft in this whole process and I'm not
Speaker 5:  going to with my picks.
Speaker 2:  All right. We should go. We're gonna do this again next year and we're gonna
Speaker 2:  have to come up with some score by which we see how we did this year.
Speaker 2:  Also, today as this show goes live, there's an event at which
Speaker 2:  HBO Max and Discovery Plus may cease to be what they
Speaker 2:  currently are. So this might all get real weird real fast, but we'll have
Speaker 2:  lot more to talk about. Thank you both for doing this. This is very fun.
Speaker 2:  This is great. Yeah. Super fun.
Speaker 2:  All right. That is it for the Vergecast today. Thanks to Eli and Alex for
Speaker 2:  being here and going through this crazy process with me. And thank you so
Speaker 2:  much for listening. There's a whole lot more from this conversation and all
Speaker 2:  of our streaming coverage on the verge.com. We put some links in the show
Speaker 2:  notes, but there's all kinds of stuff all over the website and I really,
Speaker 2:  really, really want to know what you think of our picks. Who won the draft?
Speaker 2:  What was the most surprising undrafted service? What
Speaker 2:  obvious stuff did we miss? Who's the stupidest of the three of us? You can
Speaker 2:  email us all of your thoughts at vergecast@theverge.com or call
Speaker 2:  the vergecast hotline eight six six Verge 11. We'd love
Speaker 2:  hearing from you and I want to hear all of your thoughts on the streaming
Speaker 2:  draft, including ideas for next year, because like I said, I intend to do
Speaker 2:  this every year until the heat death of the universe. This show is produced
Speaker 2:  by Marino and Liam James Brook Min is our editorial director of Audio.
Speaker 2:  The Vergecast is a verge production and part of the Fox Media podcast network.
Speaker 2:  We'll be back on Friday with Eli and Alex to talk about what's going on with
Speaker 2:  Elon Musk and Twitter, electric cars, Microsoft teams, and a whole bunch
Speaker 2:  of other stuff. See you then. Rock and roll.