# Transcript
ID: 30f51fc0-bc80-11ed-a0df-f3ecae73300a
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Solo Acts: McRib Locator's Alan Klein
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-5313655083728285350/-8646229356276219270/s93290-US-2301s-1678149426.mp3
Description: In this next episode of our Vergecast Solo Acts mini series, Ashley Esqueda talks with Alan Klein, the creator of the McRib Locator, a website that helps people track and submit where McDonald's BBQ pork sandwich is available in stores.
Alan shares what drove him to make this free tool for people back in 2009, what he does with the data he's collected, what's next for the site after the McRib's "farewell tour" this past fall, and more.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Disabled
Speaker 1:  Support for this podcast comes from Toyota Crown, the all new Toyota Crown
Speaker 1:  wants to help you make a statement each and every time you drive. Find yourself
Speaker 1:  immersed in the premium driver focused interior that puts you in control.
Speaker 1:  Not to mention that the Toyota Crown is equipped with Toyota Safety Sense
Speaker 1:  3.0 featuring lane tracing, assist full speed range,
Speaker 1:  dynamic range cruise control, automatic high beams, and so much more.
Speaker 1:  Toyota says, wherever you go in the all new Toyota Crown, you make a
Speaker 1:  statement. The car that says so much. Visit
Speaker 1:  toyota.com/crown to learn more. Toyota,
Speaker 1:  let's go places.
Speaker 3:  Welcome to the Ver Vercast, the flagship podcast of snacks
Speaker 3:  with a little M S G in them. Just, just a little. I'm your friend Alex
Speaker 3:  Cranz. And today we have a new episode of the Solo Acts miniseries,
Speaker 3:  which features interviews from people who are working independently to create
Speaker 3:  great things on the internet. Every Monday on the Vergecast, our friend Ashley
Speaker 3:  Escada is curating and hosting these interviews and sharing with us everything
Speaker 3:  she's learned. Hello Ashley.
Speaker 4:  Hi, how are you?
Speaker 3:  I'm doing good. I'm a little hungry. It's getting around lunchtime here.
Speaker 4:  Oh, I have the perfect interview for you. It's gonna make you extra hungry.
Speaker 3:  Yes, because last week you talked Toka pop from Hive Social. Who do you have
Speaker 3:  for me this week?
Speaker 4:  Yes, I, I'm very excited today to have the creator
Speaker 4:  of the M Rib Locator, Alan Klein. Ooh.
Speaker 4:  This is a website where users can track how they
Speaker 4:  can find a McDonald's McRib sandwich.
Speaker 5:  The mc McRib is back on the new taste menu at McDonald's, but only for a
Speaker 5:  while. So hurry in for that. One-of-a-kind super saucy piled on a Homestyle
Speaker 5:  roll taste. Have
Speaker 4:  You Miss Alan might actually be the biggest Mick McRib fan
Speaker 4:  on the planet. Okay. And we are gonna talk about why he spent
Speaker 4:  so much of his free time making this website, what he does with all of the
Speaker 4:  Mick Rib location data, which is very interesting and the future of his
Speaker 4:  work since the Mick Rib went on a farewell tour last year.
Speaker 3:  All right, well I know I'm gonna be absolutely starved by the end of this,
Speaker 3:  so let's go ahead and get to it.
Speaker 4:  Hi Alan.
Speaker 6:  Hi Ashley. Thanks for having me today.
Speaker 4:  Oh man. I cannot wait to talk to you about Mick Rib
Speaker 4:  Locator. So I have given a very broad description of
Speaker 4:  the site, but Alan, do you mind explaining to our
Speaker 4:  listeners in more detail about M McRib locator and how it
Speaker 4:  works?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, sure. So the Mc McRib locator webpage, it's, it's really a
Speaker 6:  crowdsource driven page where people from across the world, it's not just
Speaker 6:  the United States, have the M McRib, they can come and contribute to the
Speaker 6:  page saying, I found a McRib at a given location. And then, and as a addition
Speaker 6:  to that, fans can come in and say, yes, I agree there was one there. Or I
Speaker 6:  can dispute that finding cuz sometimes, you know, we get some that are a
Speaker 6:  little bit overexcited fans that may be a little bit too soon. So we, we
Speaker 6:  build up this base of places on a map so people can see where can I find
Speaker 6:  the nearest McRib because we never know when they're going to be around or
Speaker 6:  how far we have to, to go to find them.
Speaker 4:  That's so intriguing that it's all user-generated data. This
Speaker 4:  reminds me a lot of Gawker stalker or that old
Speaker 4:  website for finding iPhones when it right be before we could really kind
Speaker 4:  of order them online. Do you remember when you ate your first McRib?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I do. It, it's, it's a memory from back way in my youth.
Speaker 6:  I grew up on a family farm in South Dakota and, and we would, we raised hogs
Speaker 6:  and we took 'em to town one day to market. And I remember with my dad, right
Speaker 6:  after taking 'em to the, to the marketplace, we went over to the local McDonald's
Speaker 6:  in town and they happened to have the M McRib on the menu. And I remember
Speaker 6:  eating the McRib, not necessarily so much for the McRib itself, but having
Speaker 6:  a kind of surreal moment as a child realizing like, we just took hogs
Speaker 6:  to market and now here we are eating, you know, the byproduct of all of our
Speaker 6:  efforts. And it's, it's not just feeding ourselves, it's like feeding, you
Speaker 6:  know, essentially the entire world.
Speaker 4:  That's so fascinating that you, that was your first
Speaker 4:  Mick McRib experience. That is very surreal.
Speaker 6:  It really is. Cuz you do all that work, you know, you do all the work on
Speaker 6:  a farm and you, you know, it goes somewhere. But when you finally have that
Speaker 6:  realization like, holy smokes, like I've, I'm doing something much larger
Speaker 6:  than just something here locally.
Speaker 4:  I would imagine it would also be so interesting to have had the
Speaker 4:  experience of growing up on a farm, raising hogs. You have a
Speaker 4:  very different idea of what pork should taste like
Speaker 4:  as opposed to the very processed version of what
Speaker 4:  a Mick rib is that's made, I mean they make it with a mold so, right.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. The, the Mick McRib itself, right. It comes from, it's a pork shoulder
Speaker 6:  is what they've said in the past and they, they process it down and like
Speaker 6:  you said, they put it through a mold processes to get it down to that rib
Speaker 6:  like shape that they, they distribute. Yeah, it's definitely the pork itself
Speaker 6:  when you have it as a different, you know, if you go get a pork chop or a
Speaker 6:  pork loin, it's a little bit different, right. Cuz it's not that processed
Speaker 6:  part. But it's still like the McRib itself still produces that, that feeling
Speaker 6:  of, you know, the, the taste of the pork itself.
Speaker 4:  So what is it about the mc McRib that sparks joy for you? So much joy
Speaker 4:  that you made a website about it?
Speaker 6:  You know what it's always been from, even when the origins of the micro
Speaker 6:  locator itself, it was like helping other people isn't that it's no longer
Speaker 6:  just the sandwich itself For me that keeps it going. It's, you know, I'm
Speaker 6:  helping a larger community. It's fellow fans like myself and
Speaker 6:  that really is what keeps me driven to keep doing it because the
Speaker 6:  sandwich itself I've always enjoyed, right? It's a, it's a barbecue pork
Speaker 6:  sandwich. You don't really have a comparable thing on the market
Speaker 6:  in the fast food industry. You know, there's been a few other efforts of
Speaker 6:  people trying to produce something very similar, but for a long time if you
Speaker 6:  wanted a pork product, you know that you're looking at the McRib, when's
Speaker 6:  it coming? And there's that alert because for a long time it
Speaker 6:  was an offering that was stored by store decisions. So you would go in a
Speaker 6:  region like where I'm at now in Minnesota, we wouldn't have the McRib for
Speaker 6:  a very long time and suddenly, oh look it's back and you get those memories.
Speaker 6:  For me it's some of those memories again of my youth. But for a lot of people,
Speaker 6:  like it's just something you can't get somewhere else at barbecue sandwich
Speaker 6:  in a pork sandwich in a fast food venue.
Speaker 4:  So when did you realize there needed to to be a tool for finding the Mick
Speaker 4:  McRib? When did you decide to build the site? How long did it take?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, so back, you know, a number of years ago around that 2008,
Speaker 6:  2009 era, I was working in meteorology at the time. I have a meteorology
Speaker 6:  degree so let's where my, my story starts for for professionally.
Speaker 6:  And I was looking to make a product that was something to help find storm
Speaker 6:  chasers. Cause it really wasn't something at the time really to help coordinate
Speaker 6:  your chasing. And it's more of where are my friends at where you're at in
Speaker 6:  the storm, those types of things. And I was working on it and working on
Speaker 6:  it and while I was at work one day the McRib was back somewhere nearby
Speaker 6:  and it turned out there were a few other Avid fans at my workplace and we
Speaker 6:  talked about how, boy it's been a really long time since I've been able to
Speaker 6:  get one. And it's always such a pain to find it. So this idea sparked of,
Speaker 6:  well instead of a storm locator, why couldn't it just be a Mick rip locator?
Speaker 6:  And it kind of took off from there. Like I started putting the pieces together
Speaker 6:  after work, you know, kind of my free time, something fun learning and kept
Speaker 6:  evolving it. And you know, I don't remember exactly how long it took. There's
Speaker 6:  a period of time where you have a product that's available as a webpage and
Speaker 6:  then there's the how long does it take before people start using it. Hmm.
Speaker 6:  And I don't know if it was months or I don't, you know, I don't really exactly
Speaker 6:  remember the timeframe anymore, but I know it existed for some period of
Speaker 6:  time before it really started to get its publicity out there.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I would imagine the Mick McRib came back kind of nationwide in
Speaker 4:  2012, is that right? Like right, yeah. Around that timeframe. So I would
Speaker 4:  imagine it was probably around then when people were really clamoring to
Speaker 4:  find their mick ribs. I can't believe the Mick rib locator was originally
Speaker 4:  a tornado locator. Right. Pretty wild. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And in know there was sort of those struggles of, as a storm chaser, you
Speaker 6:  wouldn't be able to get that accurate precision of location and
Speaker 6:  you remembering back to 2008 and nine, our phones weren't always the best
Speaker 6:  at producing that geolocation data in a right, in a friendly format back
Speaker 6:  to webpages. So that's sort of what helped me pivot cuz a McDonald's location
Speaker 6:  is static, right? It's not moving. So you're not so worried about how do
Speaker 6:  I keep real time? It's just these are the places and that that also helped,
Speaker 6:  you know, make my solution a little easier because I could see like,
Speaker 6:  okay, it's just a location now not trying to find a floating location.
Speaker 4:  Right. It's a, it's fixed for the most
Speaker 6:  Part. Yeah, exactly. It's, it's fixed.
Speaker 4:  And so over the course of all of these years
Speaker 4:  you've I'm sure amassed some great deal of data
Speaker 4:  on people who are reporting M McRibs is looking for M ribs, right?
Speaker 4:  What do you do with that data? Does McDonald's call you up? Do they say,
Speaker 4:  Hey, we're just doing some market research on the M McRib and
Speaker 4:  you're it? Can we take a peek at your books?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it's a great question. And honestly the data itself, I keep it
Speaker 6:  internal, you're right, that would be a valid exercise of that data. But
Speaker 6:  that's never really been my application of it. It's more where are people
Speaker 6:  reporting them at, you know, where are the fan base at. So I can try to help
Speaker 6:  maybe guide some of my traffic that direction. Like I can see, hey, it comes
Speaker 6:  back in this part of the country first, or you know, a couple years back
Speaker 6:  I produced a map of, here are the states that are most likely to have a McRib
Speaker 6:  back if it's not a nationwide release because that's sort of the data I'm
Speaker 6:  collecting, right? It's like these are the reports. So yes, certainly there's
Speaker 6:  more locations than what I have on my map because it's crowdsourced, but
Speaker 6:  it's still the same premise of here are the hotspots for fans reporting the
Speaker 6:  McRib. So I kind of have an idea of if I wanna find one year to
Speaker 6:  year, these are the most likely places. So, so mostly the data has
Speaker 6:  just been internally used. Just to kind of my own curiosity, I did have someone
Speaker 6:  this year reach out to me kind of trying to get information of, hey,
Speaker 6:  in the Chicago land area, when's the McRib available? And he was trying to
Speaker 6:  correlate when the McRib was available to when the Chicago Bears win games
Speaker 6:  or not, which was kind of a fun exercise for him to do. But again,
Speaker 6:  it's, it's very anonymous, right? I'm not, I'm certainly not intending to
Speaker 6:  send any personal data out.
Speaker 4:  Was there anything over the years that struck you as interesting about the
Speaker 4:  data? Is there, is there a region that reports the most sightings?
Speaker 4:  Is there, do you find that there's a specific part of the country
Speaker 4:  or globally that just gets really jacked
Speaker 4:  up about the McRib coming back? Like what, what is the data that you have
Speaker 4:  seen that you find the most interesting?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it is interesting, you know, more when we've done over the years where
Speaker 6:  the releases have not been nationwide, trying to see how it trickles out
Speaker 6:  to what regions get it first. And we definitely get a lot of traffic coming
Speaker 6:  from the southeast. We get it from the south and we do get it
Speaker 6:  a little bit out to the west too. But there are certainly states that are
Speaker 6:  voids whether it's just, there's not as many fans there, maybe they're not
Speaker 6:  as, you know, maybe they're not unaware of the McRib locator that's possible.
Speaker 6:  But there are certainly some states we don't see it much. I see tons of traffic
Speaker 6:  from New England states asking will it be back? Because there are part of
Speaker 6:  the country that very often gets skipped. They don't get the M McRib for
Speaker 6:  one reason or another. I remember a couple years ago, well it's been a number
Speaker 6:  of years ago now, New York City area, all the McDonald's store owners were
Speaker 6:  trying to decide should we bring the M McRib back? And one of the locators
Speaker 6:  stores, they really wanted it back, but the majority said, no, we,
Speaker 6:  we don't think we wanna offer it this year. So that owner actually went on
Speaker 6:  Twitter and was like, Hey everybody, I really tried for you. But it, it just
Speaker 6:  didn't work out. So we, we see a huge draw to areas that don't get it because
Speaker 6:  they wanna have it again. So the last couple years having it
Speaker 6:  nationwide has been, you know, it's been really nice for all the fans that
Speaker 6:  are out there.
Speaker 4:  So right now, currently, we should elaborate on this for
Speaker 4:  people who are maybe less Mick aware of the Mick
Speaker 4:  McRib status. So the, the Mick McRib currently is retired,
Speaker 4:  they had a farewell tour last fall.
Speaker 6:  That's what they say, right? We've done this before. Like this isn't new
Speaker 6:  for Mick Rib fans. That's, that's sort of part of the alert for some, right?
Speaker 6:  Like will it be back or won't it be back thus far? We see,
Speaker 6:  you know, every year McDonald's reports how much revenues they've had in
Speaker 6:  the quarters and we've seen whenever the McRib has been back, those quarters
Speaker 6:  seem to do better for them. So it's an interesting idea of, well it's retired
Speaker 6:  in the United States because keep in mind in Germany you can always get the
Speaker 6:  McRib. It's there year round, it's always available and it does pop up in,
Speaker 6:  in other parts of the world from time to time. We had Malta this year, I
Speaker 6:  hadn't seen them for a long time or Australia even. There's people down there
Speaker 6:  that get it or Japan, it floats around where it comes. And oftentimes those
Speaker 6:  international options are maybe a little bit different spin on the McRib,
Speaker 6:  but it's still the McRib, they still advertise it that way. Central America
Speaker 6:  gets them every year now too, where they have these little variations on
Speaker 6:  them that are kind of fun. But yeah, I mean the fans come, they come in from
Speaker 6:  most places cuz they all want to participate and help each other, which is
Speaker 6:  really what I like about the webpage.
Speaker 4:  Okay, we're gonna take a quick break, but when I come back I'll chat with
Speaker 4:  Alex Kranz about McDonald's making their own version of the McRib
Speaker 4:  locator and how Allen felt about that.
Speaker 1:  This episode is sponsored by Toyota Crown Crown's available hybrid
Speaker 1:  max powertrain and standard all-wheel drive makes this sedan a leader in
Speaker 1:  the field from the premium driver focused interior that says you're always
Speaker 1:  comfortable in the spotlight to the stylish exterior that says Trendsetter
Speaker 1:  Toyota says, wherever you go in the all new Toyota crown, you make a statement,
Speaker 1:  the car that says so much, visit toyota.com/crown
Speaker 1:  to learn more. Toyota, let's go places.
Speaker 4:  Okay, we're back. And Alex Kranz is here. Hi Alex.
Speaker 3:  Hello. You guys have made me absolutely starving.
Speaker 4:  Good. I could not have imagined that there was a whole underbelly,
Speaker 4:  a pork underbelly, if you will. There's just a whole underbelly
Speaker 4:  world of finding a m McRib, like the M McRib has such a, has such a fan
Speaker 4:  base.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, and I remember like used to it was, it was temporary. And so when he
Speaker 3:  started this in 2009, it was like a limited offer and
Speaker 3:  kinda like the Shamrock Shake. And then in 2016
Speaker 3:  McDonald's had their own like app called the Mick McRib finder, which
Speaker 3:  kind of felt like a clone.
Speaker 7:  Well Friends, the Cult classic is back at McDonald's,
Speaker 7:  the McRib, if you wanna make sure where you can find it, they actually have
Speaker 7:  a M McRib locator app. So you go into your app store and you
Speaker 7:  can download this app and it's a M McRib finder, but
Speaker 4:  They absolutely must have known about Alan's page and then
Speaker 4:  just, you know, just, just Facebooked it just Facebooked it for themselves
Speaker 4:  as I, as I like to call it. Yeah, it was a very, obviously a very
Speaker 4:  influential website for Mick McRib lovers everywhere. Yeah. And clearly
Speaker 4:  a very good idea. So they launched the Mick McRib finder not locator.
Speaker 4:  Fun fact about that. It's not around anymore. So Alan's own Mick
Speaker 4:  McRib locator completely outlasted McDonald's official offering.
Speaker 4:  Oh
Speaker 3:  My God, I love that. So how does, how does Alan actually feel about
Speaker 3:  McDonald's kind of aping his work?
Speaker 4:  Well, I asked him about that, so let's hear,
Speaker 6:  I remember it coming out and going, well wow, they're doing something just
Speaker 6:  like I'm doing. But you know, the, the main difference always was is mine
Speaker 6:  was crowdsourced. So the McDonald's webpage at the start OFM McRib season,
Speaker 6:  they don't always show the availability that's truly in store because they're
Speaker 6:  showing what's available for their consumers and their app, or that's what
Speaker 6:  it is nowadays. That's what's available on the app. And those early days,
Speaker 6:  they don't show the m McRib is available. We, I remember this year someone
Speaker 6:  said they went like two or three weeks before it actually became available
Speaker 6:  on the register in store. They could still order it, but that was being
Speaker 6:  rung up as a different product. And it certainly is certainly more interesting
Speaker 6:  toward the end of the season too, is are they still there? And certainly
Speaker 6:  the McDonald's app today at least their mobile ordering app is certainly
Speaker 6:  more accustomed to catching that toward the end. But that initial upfront
Speaker 6:  is where my webpage continues to provide value for Mick McRib fans because
Speaker 6:  it's, it's not there on the menu, but we know it's there.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I mean the, the reflection of live reporting
Speaker 4:  is certainly a much more powerful tool for anybody actually
Speaker 4:  seeking a Mick rib. So you're, you're gonna keep going, you're gonna
Speaker 4:  keep the site up, you're gonna keep it running. Do you consider yourself
Speaker 4:  a Mick influencer? Are you, like is this a thing that you've, that has gone
Speaker 4:  a little bit beyond McRib locator or do you feel like it's pretty contained
Speaker 4:  to just like running this website and specifically supporting people
Speaker 4:  who would like to enjoy a mc McRib?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, there've been, people reach out in the past asking for other products
Speaker 6:  perhaps that we would, we would try to pursue. And I did do another one where
Speaker 6:  for the, the Shamrock Shake, right, the Shamrock Shake used to be one that
Speaker 6:  wasn't always a perennial this time of year. So I had another idea why I
Speaker 6:  did the Shake Locator, but it wasn't as popular because again, it was a product
Speaker 6:  that became more consistently available and it still lives,
Speaker 6:  it just isn't used all that much because fans know, oh, it's coming to be,
Speaker 6:  you know, around St. Patrick's Day will get a shamrock shake nowadays. But
Speaker 6:  it certainly lives on, I mean, I certainly have no intention of
Speaker 6:  disbanding the McRib locator. And I, I don't really see myself
Speaker 6:  as an influencer per se. I mean, my efforts are always focused on the mcg
Speaker 6:  McRib and I'm certainly going to promote because it, you know, obviously
Speaker 6:  it helps myself get other fans onto the page, you know, hey, the mcg McRib
Speaker 6:  is back and I have had regional McDonald's locations contact me saying, Hey,
Speaker 6:  you know what, these particular stores are gonna start serving it these days.
Speaker 6:  You know, they want to help get the information in, but there's, it's more
Speaker 6:  of a mutual conversation so than an influence type position.
Speaker 4:  So I know that part of the website allows you to report
Speaker 4:  anonymously and if you do that then you're, you show up as the
Speaker 4:  hamburger on the map. Right. Which is delightful. It's a great detail,
Speaker 4:  but I, I can't make a a a mick disinformation joke here.
Speaker 4:  That's word doesn't sound great, it's not funny. But
Speaker 4:  how do you, how do you deal with moderation? How do you deal with false reports?
Speaker 4:  Have you ever had a situation in which you've been swarmed by people trying
Speaker 4:  to sort of falsely claim a Mick rib is somewhere, I know this is like the
Speaker 4:  smallest of problems for people, like I've come to this McDonald's
Speaker 4:  and the, the hamburger said there was a mc McRib beer and there isn't one.
Speaker 4:  But how do you, how do you deal with that? Or, or have you ever had to deal
Speaker 4:  with that?
Speaker 6:  No, it's, it's a very real problem. I, I do get plenty of reports every year
Speaker 6:  from people for one reason or another. Another, maybe they thought they were
Speaker 6:  going to say I'd like to have one. Or maybe they were just being funny with
Speaker 6:  their friends to say, look, it's on a map that seems to be most likely the
Speaker 6:  case. That's where each of those reports before they're confirmed, there's
Speaker 6:  an option to say, I think it's here or I dispute that it's here
Speaker 6:  cuz that helps me hone in on the ones that are most likely a suspicious
Speaker 6:  reporting. Obviously like this time of year, I know most likely it's going
Speaker 6:  to be not real if it's in the United States, but I can still go flush out,
Speaker 6:  go look, do my diligence to find out is it actually there. And I remember
Speaker 6:  a couple years ago where one fan, you know, it's just myself
Speaker 6:  and my wife helps do some of the social media stuff for me it's just a two
Speaker 6:  of us. Keep in mind it's not, it's not like a team of McRib locator
Speaker 6:  staff here going through trying to track things down. So it's, you know,
Speaker 6:  as I get to it outside of my normal day job or whatever we have going on,
Speaker 6:  and I remember one particular day I got this email from someone,
Speaker 6:  they're like, please take this location off the map. We're getting bombarded
Speaker 6:  with calls. We don't have the McRib. And I apologize to them like, I'm so
Speaker 6:  sorry that happened. I went in and removed it immediately. Cuz obviously
Speaker 6:  nobody wants that experience, but it, it's a real problem. So it's, it's
Speaker 6:  more as best I can, I stay up with those reports to flush 'em out.
Speaker 6:  And then again, having the fans also help contribute to say, no that's not
Speaker 6:  true. That helps me focus in on those ones to start with.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, it's, it is very interesting that you seem to
Speaker 4:  have kind of grassroots cultivated a very
Speaker 4:  transparent and willingly honest group
Speaker 4:  of users who, who seem very dedicated to making sure that accurate
Speaker 4:  information is on your website. Like I, I think that seems like a very
Speaker 4:  baseline expectation, but I also believe that
Speaker 4:  right now in 2023 it is actually maybe, maybe not a
Speaker 4:  baseline expectation and it is a pleasant surprise.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And again it's not like you're saying the majority of the users that
Speaker 6:  come in, they're there for the honest reason of I'm interested in the McRib.
Speaker 6:  And it's not terribly hard when people put in their fake
Speaker 6:  reports. Oftentimes there's things about those reports that make it very
Speaker 6:  clear by the name or whatever it is that's in there that these aren't real
Speaker 6:  reports. So by and far the fans are people who
Speaker 6:  legit. I want to contribute back to the MCG McRib community.
Speaker 4:  There's something really special about weird websites right now.
Speaker 4:  We discussed this just a little bit when I did a soundcheck with you last
Speaker 4:  week. There is an era of the internet from
Speaker 4:  around the early aughts where you could just find
Speaker 4:  the strangest websites, the most niche websites
Speaker 4:  and they would be so delightful and bizarre
Speaker 4:  and serve a very specific group of people. And it feels like
Speaker 4:  the M McRib locator is sort of an echo of that
Speaker 4:  bygone era because really we don't have that as much anymore or
Speaker 4:  it's all shifted really to social media. You have kind of your favorite weirdo
Speaker 4:  niche accounts across social, wherever that may be. And I would
Speaker 4:  love to hear your thoughts on that. Thoughts about the Mick McRib locator
Speaker 4:  still being a a a traditional website number one and, and not having
Speaker 4:  moved to an app or something that's a little bit more
Speaker 4:  siloed off because you mentioned the McRib locator is a
Speaker 4:  global tool and there are a lot of people who do not use smartphones
Speaker 4:  in other markets. And so the ability to use the M McRib locator
Speaker 4:  seems very critical to me no matter what type of phone
Speaker 4:  you're using. And I, I would love to hear your thoughts on that and and just
Speaker 4:  in general that sort of having a website that is a little weird, a little
Speaker 4:  different that has echoes of that long gone era of weird
Speaker 4:  websites you can find.
Speaker 6:  Yeah it definitely does do that. It and a lot of, I think like
Speaker 6:  we said, those earlier years you had something you would come in for, there
Speaker 6:  was new content so you kept coming back or there was a particular item
Speaker 6:  not really all that much different from things going, you know, viral as
Speaker 6:  they do today. You had this thing like, hey this is really cool and you would
Speaker 6:  go and you'd enjoy it for a while and if there was nothing new you kind of
Speaker 6:  moved on. And the difference with the McRib locator was obviously the data
Speaker 6:  comes and goes, right? It's not, it's not just a one time, this is it type
Speaker 6:  of thing. And I think that's what's helped keep the interest up in it. It
Speaker 6:  certainly helps with a product that comes and goes off the market at
Speaker 6:  certainly no, no good reason. But yeah, it, it has always been very
Speaker 6:  interesting to see these pages that come up that go away. You know, they,
Speaker 6:  they do a lot of things and there's, I think part of the reason they go away
Speaker 6:  maybe is there's a lot of upkeep for some webpages, right? Like the more
Speaker 6:  and more you build into it, the more and more upkeep there is. And that was
Speaker 6:  sort of the same thing cuz I, I used to have an app for mobile devices that
Speaker 6:  I used, but it, it didn't really have the draw that the page itself did.
Speaker 6:  Like you said, I think because people were more, I'm willing to go to a webpage,
Speaker 6:  I'm a little hesitant to download an app and, and maybe even in this case
Speaker 6:  like this is a really strange, maybe I'll use it one time kind of thing.
Speaker 4:  It's an extra step that people are hesitant to do because your
Speaker 4:  phone has, you know, precious real estate app wise and it's like there's
Speaker 4:  that transaction there where you're like, oh I feel obligated to use this
Speaker 4:  if I'm gonna install it on my phone.
Speaker 6:  Right. And I certainly have had people still reach out like, Hey I really
Speaker 6:  miss that app. And I'm like, well you know, I, it just, there's not enough
Speaker 6:  time to keep it, you know, keep it modern to keep it useful. And it was an
Speaker 6:  okay app. I mean it certainly had things that needed improvements on, but
Speaker 6:  it was still more like coming back to the webpage still gave you that full
Speaker 6:  experience because you could still contribute by looking at the map, you
Speaker 6:  could still contribute by, you know, helping prove if a McRib report if you
Speaker 6:  thought it was true or not, if it's fake or not. And those kinds of things
Speaker 6:  kept people coming back and I think that's really what a lot of those other
Speaker 6:  pages, I mean they were great pages but they just, they didn't have something
Speaker 6:  to keep getting someone to come back. And that's I think why they've more
Speaker 6:  or less either been absorbed into somewhere else or like you said, maybe
Speaker 6:  they found better avenues through social media. Like this works better for
Speaker 6:  us to have the content come here exclusively. And and we do. Yeah, we, we
Speaker 6:  certainly also have the social media page is that or out there to help communicate
Speaker 6:  cuz that helps garner traffic from a different avenue as well. Cause it's
Speaker 6:  a lot easier nowadays to go out on social and say, Hey, news, news,
Speaker 6:  news versus before is like, well I hope you come back to my webpage when
Speaker 6:  there's something new. So yeah, it's a little, a little bit different transition
Speaker 6:  over the years.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And you, you mentioned having a day job. I am
Speaker 4:  going to assume McRib locator is not your day job.
Speaker 6:  No it is not.
Speaker 4:  But does it make enough money to sustain itself? Is this something
Speaker 4:  that you just, you know, sort of pay for out of pocket? Do you have ads?
Speaker 4:  How do you make money or do you make money on Mick Rib
Speaker 4:  locator? What's the process there?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, so the, the early years of the Mick McRib locator, there was absolutely
Speaker 6:  no ads. I was like, I don't want ads on this thing. This is, this is what
Speaker 6:  it is. And I had pay for it out pocket. And then over the years it's like,
Speaker 6:  well you know, there's, if I put a couple ads here and there, there's no
Speaker 6:  no reason they can be there. They'll generate enough revenue to help pay
Speaker 6:  for the page. And it does, there's a little bit in excess every year that
Speaker 6:  I put back toward other ideas. Like, you know, a number of years ago we gave
Speaker 6:  our make McRib locator pens or other types of merchandise that people
Speaker 6:  are really interested in. We, we try to find these things that we can send
Speaker 6:  out. We had stickers, we had, we've done various things over the years. Like
Speaker 6:  give something back to the fans cuz that's how you keep people interested.
Speaker 6:  That's sort of what we've done with it. It's certainly not something I'm
Speaker 6:  losing money on anymore, but it is certainly not something I'm looking to
Speaker 6:  make tons of money on either cuz I'm not, I'm not interested in doing that
Speaker 6:  per se.
Speaker 4:  You're not buying a McDonald's with
Speaker 6:  It. Yeah, yeah. I'm not trying to buy a McDonald's with it. I'm not, I'm
Speaker 6:  certainly not trying to do anything like that. I'm just, it's just keep it
Speaker 6:  rolling as long as we can because it's, it's one of those things, like you
Speaker 6:  said, you never really know when the fan base is gonna say, well
Speaker 6:  I've had enough.
Speaker 4:  Okay, we're gonna take one more break, but when we come back we're gonna
Speaker 4:  get really extra nerdy about the Mick Rib. So stay tuned.
Speaker 1:  This podcast is sponsored by Toyota Crown. The all new Toyota
Speaker 1:  crown is breaking new ground when it comes to the premium sedan with an
Speaker 1:  available hybrid max powertrain. The Toyota crown is the perfect combination
Speaker 1:  of power, style and elegance. Making it the car to glide in
Speaker 1:  from a driver focused interior that says you're always comfortable in the
Speaker 1:  spotlight to the stylish exterior that says I have arrived.
Speaker 1:  Toyota says, wherever you go in the all new Toyota crown, you make a
Speaker 1:  statement. The car that says so much, visit
Speaker 1:  toyota.com/crown to learn more. Toyota,
Speaker 1:  let's go places.
Speaker 4:  All right and we're back. I've got Alex here again.
Speaker 3:  I'm just like, I don't know how I'm gonna survive. I gotta go get on some
Speaker 3:  Uber Eats.
Speaker 4:  If you're not eating a Mick McRib by the end of this interview, I'm gonna
Speaker 4:  be very disappointed.
Speaker 3:  I really, really love how passionate Alan is about this. Like he
Speaker 3:  really loves the Mick McRib but also like supporting the other
Speaker 3:  fans of the Mick McRib and it, it kind of seems like he's gonna keep doing
Speaker 3:  this as long as he can.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, you know, the mc McRib is not around right now. It went
Speaker 4:  on that farewell tour and you know, he's gonna keep the website up
Speaker 4:  because he really thinks it's gonna come back someday.
Speaker 4:  And it's pretty interesting in the mc McRib fan base, which
Speaker 4:  is such a strange term, but it exists. There are actually a couple of
Speaker 4:  different theories about predicting when the M McRib might
Speaker 4:  return. And I did a little bit of digging about this because I was very curious.
Speaker 4:  I really fell into a M McRib rabbit hole and it seems like a really
Speaker 4:  good way to predict the return or the retirement of the McRib
Speaker 4:  is to keep an eye on the USDA's monthly
Speaker 4:  cold storage report.
Speaker 4:  You're laughing because it is the best thing I've ever heard in my life.
Speaker 4:  And it's specifically stocks of frozen pork belly year over year.
Speaker 4:  So the report comes out and people can look at the year
Speaker 4:  over year stocks of frozen pork belly and if there's a surplus
Speaker 4:  then maybe the Mick McRib will be back and if you start seeing it fall, then
Speaker 4:  maybe the Mick McRib goes away. And so it's a very interesting
Speaker 4:  predictive, I won't say it's a tool because it's not always a hundred
Speaker 4:  percent accurate to the stocks. Yeah. But it is a
Speaker 4:  generally good indicator of when it might come back.
Speaker 4:  So I started wondering here if there were any plans on
Speaker 4:  incorporating that data into the actual Mick r locator website
Speaker 4:  so that people can kind of get a magic eight ball kind of, you know, outlook,
Speaker 4:  like not likely, you know, just sort of that that like, hey, is the Mick
Speaker 4:  R gonna come back soon and just immediately have a thing that says like no
Speaker 4:  prediction, say maybe just, maybe you're gonna have to wait for Mick Rib
Speaker 4:  for a while. Outlook not so good. Yeah, outlook not so good. Or like Mick
Speaker 4:  rib imminent, like maybe that's like a, you know, that seems really fun.
Speaker 4:  So I asked Alan about that.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, no that, that's a great avenue to follow. I've had people over the
Speaker 6:  years contact me to get, again, get the anonymized data to say, hey, I would
Speaker 6:  like to prove if this is a thing or not. And what they were always looking
Speaker 6:  at more directly was the, the current pricing of of hog market
Speaker 6:  value. Because they would say, Hey look, the values are very low so
Speaker 6:  McDonald's is going to buy now. And it makes sense from a very pure financial
Speaker 6:  perspective, why would McDonald's buy when the market's high? They should
Speaker 6:  always buy when it's low to maximize profits. That makes perfect sense from
Speaker 6:  a business perspective. It's not something that I've directly keep an eyeball
Speaker 6:  on because it's, it's hard to gauge certainly over the last couple
Speaker 6:  years the, with the way the meat markets have been fluctuating, not just
Speaker 6:  pork but just in general to be able to say like absolutely certain that's
Speaker 6:  what's going to happen. But yeah, it makes a lot of sense and it would certainly
Speaker 6:  be something worth tracking and it wouldn't take a whole lot of effort to
Speaker 6:  do that. To say, Hey, here's what we've had a number of years ago.
Speaker 6:  It's been quite a few where I would have someone from one of the, the meat
Speaker 6:  packing plants, they'd be like, Hey, secret, secret. We're starting to make
Speaker 6:  McRib Pat's
Speaker 4:  Anonymous tips. I love
Speaker 6:  This.
Speaker 4:  Yes, it is literally the secret world of the mc McRib and I I,
Speaker 4:  this is so interesting that you're get, you get anonymous tips from factories,
Speaker 4:  that's incredible.
Speaker 6:  Right? And that, and that's certainly always been again understanding
Speaker 6:  that the McRib is like this very, very niche thing, right? Like
Speaker 6:  you have people who really, really like it and you have the other people
Speaker 6:  who like, I don't understand why is this fan base exist? But
Speaker 6:  that's how anything, anything is anymore. Like with the modern era of internet,
Speaker 6:  you can go out and find like-minded people that are really avid about
Speaker 6:  something and apparently that's where they come to see my Mick Rib locator.
Speaker 4:  I think that brings me to kind of the pen ultimate question here,
Speaker 4:  which is the Mick rib as we mentioned, is made with a
Speaker 4:  mold. It is not a traditional actual rib, it's
Speaker 4:  boneless. There has been some speculation that now that the
Speaker 4:  Mick McRib has been retired once again and we are seeing
Speaker 4:  the rise of plant-based foods that we may see the
Speaker 4:  Mick McRib return in a completely different form, which would be a plant-based
Speaker 4:  Mick rib. I am curious as to your thoughts on that and if
Speaker 4:  it does come back as a plant-based McRib, and I'll paraphrase
Speaker 4:  Shakespeare here, would a m McRib by any other ingredient
Speaker 4:  taste as sweet?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, you know, I've, I've not really thought much about a plant-based
Speaker 6:  driven m McRib like product over the years. You know, I've,
Speaker 6:  I've seen people just in general conversations like the sauce is different,
Speaker 6:  it has to be different or the bread has to be different. Like there's been
Speaker 6:  years where people pick up on subtlety of, of changes in the, in the house
Speaker 6:  produced. So I would suspect that fans switching to a plant driven M rib,
Speaker 6:  while some people would certainly be willing to try it, which I would be
Speaker 6:  one, I'll try something once. I don't think it would probably garner the
Speaker 6:  same fan base. It's a little bit different group of people, right?
Speaker 6:  It's, there's nothing wrong with the plant-based driven foods, it's just
Speaker 6:  that's not quite what everyone's looking for just yet. It is certainly an
Speaker 6:  up and coming and it's a very interesting idea to have this. Again, it's
Speaker 6:  a molded shape so you could certainly make a plant-based driven, McRib
Speaker 6:  shaped item to serve. I'm just not sure if it would have the same
Speaker 6:  popularity.
Speaker 4:  I just realized what the name of this product should be. And I shouldn't
Speaker 4:  laugh at my own jokes, but I mean it's right there.
Speaker 4:  McDonald's, you gotta name it. The mc fib.
Speaker 6:  Yeah the mc fib. Yes,
Speaker 4:  Yes. If they do that, you owe me a lot of money. McDonald's to be called
Speaker 4:  the mc fib. If they ever did that, let's say they
Speaker 4:  split it and they said we're gonna make the M McRib but we're also gonna
Speaker 4:  make this plant-based rim McRib, would you continue to only support
Speaker 4:  the authentic m McRib or would you say okay well now we have two different
Speaker 4:  types of m McRibs and we'll have it, you know, we'll have identifiers for
Speaker 4:  those at each location because maybe one in Silver Lake here
Speaker 4:  in Los Angeles maybe only has the plant-based McRib and not the
Speaker 4:  meat-based one or maybe ones in other parts of the country
Speaker 4:  would not carry the plant-based one and vice versa.
Speaker 6:  N no that, that's absolutely something that would be worth tracking and it
Speaker 6:  wouldn't take, again, nothing is a terrible amount of effort. So doing something
Speaker 6:  like that would make a lot of sense because there certainly would be the
Speaker 6:  fans at in a much more restricted, much more limited release of a product.
Speaker 6:  Having that availability would be very helpful because again, you can use
Speaker 6:  the McDonald's app in general when things have been on the market for a while
Speaker 6:  to find things. But it's generally trying to find you the closest store where
Speaker 6:  like the McRib locator, it's where's this pocket at? Because
Speaker 6:  honestly like if you're gonna make some sort of journey, which there have
Speaker 6:  been many people take very long journeys. Years ago somebody went from Colorado
Speaker 6:  clear down, I forget how many hours they went to go bring back a
Speaker 6:  big ton of, no big ton isn't quite the right phrasing, but they brought back
Speaker 6:  a lot of McRibs back to the Colorado market cause they hadn't had it. So
Speaker 6:  you don't wanna make that journey if it's not available. So being able to
Speaker 6:  see like there's a pocket of 'em here or a pocket of 'em there you have that
Speaker 6:  boost of confidence of I'll get there, it'll still be there. Now
Speaker 6:  in that same mindset, I always suggest people, even with the webpage for
Speaker 6:  what it is, you know, if it's getting late in the season, it's usually best
Speaker 6:  to give a little buzz ahead to make sure they're still there. Because again,
Speaker 6:  my reports on the page, they're at that moment of time.
Speaker 6:  So after so many days they, you know, maybe isn't as accurate anymore.
Speaker 4:  I know that there has been some speculation that McDonald's will let the
Speaker 4:  M McRib rest this year that we may not see it back. How do you
Speaker 4:  recover users? How do you, how do you get the word out when the M McRibs
Speaker 4:  been gone for a long enough time to sort of exit the collective
Speaker 4:  awareness of it,
Speaker 6:  Right? And it's really about trying to find that information to
Speaker 6:  tell someone that it's going to come back. Cuz if you can share that like
Speaker 6:  through the social media avenues like it's coming back, come back to the
Speaker 6:  webpage, that's our best avenues. We also get pickups and
Speaker 6:  as the news in general picks up on Amic McRib possibility, that
Speaker 6:  drives people back to that curiosity of, hey, I remember that webpage I used
Speaker 6:  to go to. Let's go see if it's still there. Like, you know, hey maybe it's
Speaker 6:  still there and hey look, there's data there that I can look at to say that
Speaker 6:  I can go get a McRib now. And it's kind of a fun journey in that way.
Speaker 4:  What is the most amount of users, unique visitors you've had in
Speaker 4:  a day?
Speaker 6:  In a particular day? I'd have to go back and look. I mean, I can
Speaker 6:  tell you this, last year in October for the month of October, we had about
Speaker 6:  200,000 unique users on the webpage at some point during the month. Man,
Speaker 4:  That's a lot of Mick McRib fans.
Speaker 6:  It's a lot of people coming to look to see what's going on. And I, I think
Speaker 6:  the individual days was, you know, tens of thousands probably. Cuz again,
Speaker 6:  as people pick up on the news outlets that say, Hey Mick McRibs back, they
Speaker 6:  start searching for McRib, right? And, and search is happening and one of
Speaker 6:  those results is gonna be the MCG McRib locator and they're gonna go, oh
Speaker 6:  cool, lemme go check that out. And that's where those, you know, fans
Speaker 6:  helping each other really comes into play because people are very curious
Speaker 6:  when it's back, where can I find it?
Speaker 4:  I love this cycle of boom and bust, the mc McRib boom and bust cycle,
Speaker 4:  the bell curve of, of the Mick McRib.
Speaker 6:  But you're right there, there's always this constant concern like maybe it
Speaker 6:  won't be back this year. You know, I'm, I'm disappointed as a fan myself,
Speaker 6:  I'm disappointed as the operator of the webpage, but it's still like,
Speaker 6:  we'll see how it goes. You know, as a fan, obviously I want to be nationwide
Speaker 6:  every year because I want people to be able to get it wherever they can.
Speaker 6:  And in the same token as a, as a webpage, you know, when it's more
Speaker 6:  restricted I get more traffic. So it's that kind of catch of, well, which
Speaker 6:  one's? Right? And I've always preferred, you know, get it wherever you can.
Speaker 3:  Okay, thank you. That is it for the Verge cast this week. Although Ashley,
Speaker 3:  I gotta say mc fib
Speaker 4:  Alex, look, no one's sending me any royalties. Everyone on Earth has thought
Speaker 4:  of mc fib. I realized this the second the interview was over and I
Speaker 4:  was like, oh no, everyone's gonna just think I'm the dumbest human being
Speaker 4:  alive.
Speaker 3:  I mean, I don't judge you. I do a lot of puns on the show, so like anything
Speaker 3:  pun adjacent, I'm here for Thank you. I
Speaker 4:  Appreciate it. Me too. And honestly, I really hope that beyond
Speaker 4:  the absolutely terrible Mc fib, I hope that you all
Speaker 4:  out there listening learned something today, not just about the Mc McRib,
Speaker 4:  but also about how one person can create a useful tool for a
Speaker 4:  passionate community because Alan really is so passionate and it
Speaker 4:  is a useful tool for anybody looking for the mc McRib.
Speaker 3:  Well, thank you Ashley. She's gonna be back next week with another
Speaker 3:  episode of Solo X because we're doing this special series every Monday for
Speaker 3:  the next few weeks. What's going on next week?
Speaker 4:  I'm very excited. Next week we are gonna be talking to a solo game
Speaker 4:  developer. Her name is Madison Carr and she has a game
Speaker 4:  that actually just launched called Birth. She just launched it on
Speaker 4:  Steam very recently and she is gonna talk to us about
Speaker 4:  making games all by yourself, which is quite a feat. All video
Speaker 4:  games are miracles, I've said this many times. And to do it alone
Speaker 4:  is pretty outstanding and she has a lot of great things to say about
Speaker 4:  the steam deck and indie games and a lot of other
Speaker 4:  things that go into making a game by yourself.
Speaker 3:  Well, I am terrifically excited. I can't wait to listen. It's gonna
Speaker 3:  be great.
Speaker 3:  This show is produced by Andrew Marino and Liam James Brooke Mentors is our
Speaker 3:  editorial director of audio. The VER is a Verge production and part of the
Speaker 3:  Vox Media podcast network. If you have thoughts, feedback, feelings, you
Speaker 3:  can always email us@vergecasttheverge.com or call the
Speaker 3:  hotline at eight six six eleven. That's 8 6 6 Verge 11.
Speaker 3:  We'll be back on Wednesday for an all new episode of the Vergecast. Until
Speaker 3:  then, stay classy.
Speaker 1:  Thanks to Toyota Crown for supporting this episode. The all new Toyota Crown
Speaker 1:  lets you separate from the crowd as soon as you step inside the car. It's
Speaker 1:  equipped with a cutting edge design with an available hybrid max powertrain
Speaker 1:  that generates an exceptional 340 combined net horsepower. The
Speaker 1:  dynamic placement of the electric motor between the engine and the transmission
Speaker 1:  allows for power to be transferred without any lag. The result,
Speaker 1:  zero to 60 seconds in 5.7 seconds. Toyota
Speaker 1:  says, wherever you go in the all new Toyota crown, you make a statement,
Speaker 1:  the car that says so much. Visit toyota.com/crown to
Speaker 1:  learn more. Toyota, let's go places.