# Transcript
ID: 4997f33b-0dd8-4c9d-b14c-889554de17d3
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Apple mysteries and Google trials
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-3318158995515815967/5167957261317047979/s93290-US-4032s-1694996837.mp3
Description: It's been a week! The Verge's Nilay Patel, David Pierce, and Alex Cranz rejoin the studio to process all the tech news and announcements. Apple had its annual hardware event where the iPhone 15 and new Apple Watch lineup were shown off.
Later, senior tech and policy reporter Adi Robertson joins the show to walk us through the US v Google antitrust trial that kicked off earlier in the week.
Speaker 4:  Island.
Speaker 5:  Again, again,
Speaker 4:  It's, it's really the same show as last time. We've
Speaker 4:  just slightly changed it a little bit and now everyone has
Speaker 4:  to just as a group agree that
Speaker 4:  it's important.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. The island so
Speaker 5:  Important. It's the most it has ever been.
Speaker 4:  I'm your friend Neli. I'm here. David. Pierce is here.
Speaker 5:  Hi. We're all in the studio. This is great
Speaker 4:  City. We're all together in this
Speaker 5:  Studio and you're back. The rage that people have felt about how long you've
Speaker 5:  been gone, Neli, I cannot describe to you. I am not people just to
Speaker 5:  be
Speaker 4:  David's like, don't over here Alex. Cranz is here.
Speaker 6:  I'm okay with Neli being back. Okay.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. You're sort of whatever about it. I'm happy.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. It's nice. It's nice that we're all in the studio together. It's
Speaker 5:  Nice. I agree with that.
Speaker 6:  We're gonna talk about some phones. Yeah. Talk about some, some stuff that
Speaker 6:  happened this week that aren't, isn't phones, like it's good
Speaker 4:  Times. I'm excited about that. I can spend hours talking about my newfound
Speaker 4:  ability to crimp ethernet cables, which is what I've been doing in my
Speaker 4:  new home.
Speaker 6:  That's what we're pivoting to.
Speaker 4:  That's, I can just talk about that the whole time. The number of YouTube
Speaker 4:  channels that are like extremely
Speaker 4:  hardcore and they make a lot of videos that get about 40,000
Speaker 4:  views that are just about ethernet. Yes. And
Speaker 4:  it's, it's just a business. It's just an ecosystem over there. They're, they're
Speaker 4:  not like huge views, but it's all very passionate.
Speaker 5:  Oh yeah. They're so earnest. It's like you're the guy who knows everything
Speaker 5:  about ethernet and no one has ever asked you one question about it before
Speaker 5:  and now there are people who wanna know. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  It's like the greatest thing ever. Every now and again, you're like, oh,
Speaker 4:  the internet's good. Yeah. Like all these people exist. They've like built
Speaker 4:  a little media ecosystem together and if you happen
Speaker 4:  to need to remind yourself how to crimp an ethernet cable, they are
Speaker 4:  there for you. That's
Speaker 6:  Why they're so good.
Speaker 4:  I have encrypted ethernet cable since I was like 19 years old working in
Speaker 4:  the college computer lab. Yes. And I was like, I remember how to do this
Speaker 4:  now. That's what I've been doing. That's why I have been on the show. We
Speaker 4:  moved house. I don't have a podcast set up in that house yet where
Speaker 4:  it's all happening. But I now have a Cat five E line
Speaker 4:  running from my office all the way to the Verizon modem. That's
Speaker 5:  Very exciting.
Speaker 4:  That's nice. And that took a long time to figure out. That's nice.
Speaker 5:  How are your five G speeds?
Speaker 6:  Are you doing surgery?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. No, I've done a number of surgeries.
Speaker 5:  Where's the banana?
Speaker 4:  We do have a lot talk about today that isn't just ethernet cables. Addie
Speaker 4:  Robertson's gonna join the show in a little bit. Talk about the Google antitrust
Speaker 4:  trial that happened this week, and it is happening for the next
Speaker 4:  nine weeks. The government is suing Google for what
Speaker 4:  they claim is the illegal dominance of search
Speaker 4:  and using the dominance of search to support its other businesses in ways
Speaker 4:  that are illegal, paying for default placements, killing other search
Speaker 4:  products left and right. We don't know what the outcome of that will be.
Speaker 4:  We dunno if the government will win. They're not doing great at winning these
Speaker 4:  cases, but if they do win, you could, you could see a breakup of Google and
Speaker 4:  this is just happening very quietly. Yeah. In the background.
Speaker 5:  We'll, we'll come back to this later, but it's been very strange to be
Speaker 5:  here not at the Apple event this weekend. There's this very like
Speaker 5:  Cupertino thing that happens at the Apple event where it, apple is very good
Speaker 5:  at being the only thing in the universe and not being
Speaker 5:  there, just sitting here being like, okay, new phone. That's a lot like the
Speaker 5:  old phone biggest tech trial in 25
Speaker 5:  years. It, and, and, and we've just, we've talked a lot
Speaker 5:  about the one and not that much about the other. So I'm, I'm glad we're gonna
Speaker 5:  catch up on the phone. It, it takes 10 weeks, which is too
Speaker 5:  long. Like when Microsoft wanted to buy a gaming company, they did it in
Speaker 5:  five days and we were all very interested and it was fine. 10 weeks is just
Speaker 5:  like, can I, how, how long can we talk?
Speaker 4:  It's engine, it's a lot of what's happened this week is Google's chief
Speaker 4:  economist has been called to account for his emails from
Speaker 4:  two decades ago and it's like, all right, this is all happening. We're covering
Speaker 4:  it. Addie's gonna join the show in a little bit, talk about it in detail
Speaker 4:  and talk about kind of why it's so quiet. It is hard to
Speaker 4:  cover this trial.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, it's,
Speaker 4:  But we'll get to that. We're also gonna get to the Unity drama, which Alex
Speaker 4:  has promised to explain to me.
Speaker 6:  I swear I'm gonna do it. Okay. It'll be fine. It's gonna be great.
Speaker 4:  I literally was like, again, I was at Apple
Speaker 6:  And this was happening during Apple during
Speaker 4:  The event. Like
Speaker 6:  Ash was like, can someone help me do math? And we were like, no Math only
Speaker 6:  iPhones.
Speaker 4:  So all I know about this is that there are death threats involved in the
Speaker 4:  pricing structure of a game engine. Yep. So, we acceptance. We're gonna,
Speaker 4:  we're gonna get to that. People get mad Becausecause, that seems very important,
Speaker 4:  but let's start it. It is sort of the end of iPhone week. There's a lot of
Speaker 4:  what you might think of as pickup news. Like we've just asked a lot
Speaker 4:  of questions and we've gotten a lot of answers. Let's start with the enduring
Speaker 4:  mystery of the Thread radio. David, do You know what's going on with the
Speaker 4:  Thread radio?
Speaker 5:  No. So this is sort of my favorite part of the iPhone
Speaker 5:  launch because there's that like 36 hours where it's just infinite
Speaker 5:  numbers and information and videos to
Speaker 5:  watch and all kinds of stuff. And then everybody kind of takes a deep
Speaker 5:  breath, gets on a plane and you're like, wait, what
Speaker 5:  just happened? Yeah. And, and you guys were talking about this on the show
Speaker 5:  on Wednesday, the like enduring mystery of the Thread radio
Speaker 5:  and gen two. And our team did a really good job of basically running down
Speaker 5:  all of the possibilities. One is that there's a sneaky smart
Speaker 5:  home play that Apple is going for here, where you could use your phone as
Speaker 5:  a Thread border router to connect directly to all your devices. One is that
Speaker 5:  even Apple isn't really sure what it's doing. One is that it got it for free
Speaker 5:  with the chip that it's doing wifi and Bluetooth on. I think all of those
Speaker 5:  are totally plausible. We have no idea. Yeah. I
Speaker 5:  will say the thing that has jumped out to me is I would put exactly no
Speaker 5:  credence behind Apple saying, well, you don't know what's like, of course
Speaker 5:  that's Apple's gonna say like, apple is going to come out a year from now
Speaker 5:  and pretend that it invented Thread and have some cool feature. Right. Like
Speaker 5:  that's how this works. But the other thing that I keep thinking about is
Speaker 5:  like Apple has made very clear to us over the years that it hates Bluetooth
Speaker 5:  in so, so many ways. Yeah. And I think it can't replace Bluetooth for
Speaker 5:  things like headphones, but it can absolutely figure out how to replace
Speaker 5:  Bluetooth for connecting to your other devices. And it has the ultra
Speaker 5:  wideband chip, it's doing all this stuff. But if you can use Thread as just
Speaker 5:  like a free way to get rid of this awful power hungry standard
Speaker 5:  that no one really likes. That makes a lot of sense to me as
Speaker 5:  a thing Apple might do. There's a long road to get there. You have to put
Speaker 5:  in all the devices, you have to put it on all the phones. But like if you
Speaker 5:  were going to start somewhere, it makes sense to start with the iPhone Pro.
Speaker 5:  It makes sense to sort of slowly trickle it out. And then in two years they're
Speaker 5:  gonna have a big smart home event and tell us all the cool things they've
Speaker 5:  done with Thread. Like I can see how we get from here today. What
Speaker 6:  Would the cool things be? Just like turning off
Speaker 6:  bulbs.
Speaker 4:  Yes. What are the cool things?
Speaker 6:  I mean, I like to turn, like using Thread is nice to turn off bulbs.
Speaker 6:  I enjoy it as much as you can enjoy doing
Speaker 6:  that. But like,
Speaker 5:  No, the the, the answer is we made the smart home work,
Speaker 5:  right? Like if I'm Apple, I'm looking at matter being like, well that's a
Speaker 5:  gigantic disaster. We'll figure that out eventually Matter is the long-term
Speaker 5:  answer. It's not the short-term answer, but what Apple can do is come out
Speaker 5:  and say like, we now have a solution in
Speaker 5:  which you go to your iPhone and you hit the button that says Turn
Speaker 5:  my lights on. And it connects to the lights and turns them on
Speaker 5:  no other steps. Yeah. Yeah. That's powerful. And would mean things to
Speaker 5:  people. You don't have to worry about your Hue bridge. You don't have to
Speaker 5:  make sure that your network is working. You don't have to like, you just,
Speaker 5:  you have a device. That device is over there. You hit a button, it turns
Speaker 5:  on. That's an Apple story would
Speaker 6:  Work without needing wifi. Right.
Speaker 5:  You wouldn't.
Speaker 6:  Which is the best part of Hu hu
Speaker 4:  Again, here's my question and I I I believe you that it
Speaker 4:  is unlikely that Apple announced it without a plan, but it's weird that they
Speaker 4:  announced it without a plan.
Speaker 6:  Well, they didn't announce it though, right?
Speaker 4:  They did. It's on the It's during the keynote. It's in the Bento in the Bento
Speaker 4:  box and it's in the press release. Yeah. But that's like, they could have
Speaker 4:  just not told anybody that. That's
Speaker 5:  Fair. Also, do you remember when they, they upgraded the home app and they
Speaker 5:  were like, it's for future architectural improvements. What the hell does
Speaker 5:  that mean? Like Apple, I think I really genuinely believe
Speaker 5:  Apple thinks the smart home is for nerds. Yeah. And is just like very
Speaker 5:  slowly building up a thing that at three years from now they're
Speaker 5:  gonna be like, we've invented the smart home. And it starts in that
Speaker 5:  little radio. It's
Speaker 6:  Gonna be like a slow zoom on a light bulb and then it just pops on. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Right. And we're gonna be like, wow.
Speaker 4:  No, no, no, no, no,
Speaker 5:  No. This is gonna happen.
Speaker 4:  They built that entire house that they do their announcements and it dubbed
Speaker 4:  into dc Right. They're like Apple's smart house, more like
Speaker 4:  beautiful people are doing beautiful things all the time. And like someone's
Speaker 4:  making a pancake and a home pod minis like opening a garage. Like
Speaker 4:  they, they, they can't ret Con not having done
Speaker 4:  that.
Speaker 5:  They absolutely can.
Speaker 4:  They
Speaker 5:  Absolutely can.
Speaker 6:  There will be a birthday party, the lights are gonna pop on and everybody's
Speaker 6:  gonna go,
Speaker 4:  Wow. Yeah. We've gotten a number of emails with Thread theories.
Speaker 4:  I think the most interesting ones are all about local connectivity. A lot
Speaker 4:  of people think, well this could be better for connecting to smart watches
Speaker 4:  or AirPods the answer. And you should read Jen's piece. We'll link it. It's
Speaker 4:  very good. She basically ran everything down as David said. And she's got
Speaker 4:  a bunch of actual reporting from people at other companies who use Thread.
Speaker 4:  Like Google product managers are in this piece talking about what they would
Speaker 4:  put Thread in a smartphone for, which is really interesting. So go read that
Speaker 4:  piece. But basically the bandwidth of Thread is not gonna let you
Speaker 4:  build that like tiny personal area network that people are talking about
Speaker 4:  at this moment. And then there's a lot of like, is it for presence
Speaker 4:  detection and all this other stuff you can think of. And the
Speaker 4:  problem with that is that Bluetooth low energy does exist.
Speaker 5:  It does. It's still
Speaker 4:  There. It is there, it, it does that job actually quite
Speaker 4:  well. And so you're, you're just in this weird
Speaker 4:  place where you have ultra wideband, you have Thread, you've got B L
Speaker 4:  E and everyone's like, well maybe we'll use this one to do the thing that
Speaker 4:  that one's designed for. Like have you seen these new, well how do you
Speaker 4:  pronounce this company? A, A Aqura? Yes. Ara Aqua. They've got the presence
Speaker 4:  sensors now. Yeah. And so they have basically u w E presence sensors and
Speaker 4:  they can tell where you are in a room. Like you can set them up, it'll map
Speaker 4:  out the room. You walk into the room and beyond just there's motion in the
Speaker 4:  room, turn on the light. It's like I'm at the desk. Yeah. Turn on the desk
Speaker 4:  light because I'm at the desk and when I leave the desk and go to the couch,
Speaker 4:  turn off that light and turn on this thing now that's terrifying. I
Speaker 6:  Was just thinking how I was like, I need to go get that sensor.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. There, there's a, I You go watch the videos of people using. It's
Speaker 4:  so cool. Yeah. And like it is a big unlock. Again, Jenna's
Speaker 4:  written about all this stuff. It is a huge unlock for smart home ideas because
Speaker 4:  knowing you're in a room is actually not that useful. Knowing
Speaker 4:  where you are and what you might be doing in a room is very useful. But then
Speaker 4:  you have to tell computers where you are and what you are doing in a room.
Speaker 4:  And then the computers will know and store that data
Speaker 4:  and
Speaker 6:  Or you can use home assistant and then a lot of that data
Speaker 6:  and stuff is not stored Yeah. By the companies. Instead it's just your
Speaker 6:  data.
Speaker 4:  I you Plex home assistant.
Speaker 6:  I'm, I'm out there. I'm out there at the edge. No one's got my data
Speaker 6:  literally
Speaker 4:  At, on the edge on. But anyway, so all this stuff
Speaker 4:  is just, all these, these kinds of radios, the blurry lines
Speaker 4:  between them are ever more blurry. Yes. And Apple in the,
Speaker 4:  in the phone has all three of them. You know there's a second
Speaker 4:  gen ultra wideband ship in these phones. And then there's
Speaker 4:  just, it's like, I know they didn't announce it without a plan. I know there's
Speaker 4:  a plan. They're not telling us. Yeah. But the announcement is an
Speaker 4:  announcement without a plan. They're gonna
Speaker 6:  Announce it like, dub up.
Speaker 5:  If you just got it for free with the chip, you don't put it in the
Speaker 5:  Bento. You let like I fix it, open it up and be like, huh, weird. There's
Speaker 5:  a Thread router in there. And then never touch it again.
Speaker 5:  And don't talk about it. Don't answer questions. Like, we've seen Apple do
Speaker 5:  this before where you're like, what is this for? And Apple's like, what do
Speaker 5:  you mean? Like that's all fine. But Yeah. I I think it's right that they're
Speaker 5:  like, they, they wanna put Thread in people's minds and exactly why
Speaker 5:  that is. I don't know. But I think you're right that there's, there is some
Speaker 5:  kind of bet there. It's just a question of like how big and how soon. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  We're gonna see something out of that.
Speaker 4:  And what what's fun for us is that Vergecast
Speaker 4:  listeners, Verge readers are, they're as interested in this mystery.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Like this post, like what is Thread in the iPhone for is like right
Speaker 4:  up there with like iPhone announced. Oh yeah. And it's great. Like that's
Speaker 4:  why we do the thing that we do. Other stuff that we picked up Lightning is
Speaker 4:  not totally gone. Yep. It's still around. I mean Apple still sells the ninth
Speaker 4:  Gen I've iPad. All the AirPods except for the AirPods pros still have it.
Speaker 5:  It does seem like we're gonna, we're in for probably, I don't know, what
Speaker 5:  would you say, 12 months of kind of slowly wiping those things out. Like
Speaker 5:  if we get to this time next year and there is still a single Apple
Speaker 5:  device with a Lightning port, I'll be very
Speaker 6:  Surprised It'll be a budget iPad maybe. And it'll be there for like three
Speaker 6:  more years with the, with the, the pencil that you plug
Speaker 6:  in and then three years. No,
Speaker 5:  They're gonna gonna leave the Magic Mouse with the stupid ass Lightning port
Speaker 5:  on the bottom just to troll everybody.
Speaker 4:  Well I mean that stuff is really interesting 'cause those are wholesale
Speaker 4:  redesigns. Yeah. You know Apple's view of USB C is basically we
Speaker 4:  invented this port, it's ours and it's it's true. Yeah. With
Speaker 4:  that first baby MacBook, of which by the way, I got rid of them. Very sad
Speaker 4:  about them when we moved. I was like, it's time. Ah, Dieter sold me one a
Speaker 4:  long time ago.
Speaker 5:  R i p Terrible beautiful computers.
Speaker 4:  The ultimate plane computer. I kept them in my house for years after they
Speaker 4:  were obsolete thinking I will have these just for airplane rides. And then
Speaker 4:  every now and again I'd be like, go on a long flight and I would open one
Speaker 4:  up and be like, this is so much slower than that. This is so much
Speaker 4:  objectively worse than any iPad in this house, including Max's iPad,
Speaker 4:  which is like lockdown kids mode. Did
Speaker 6:  You put like Chrome OS on it?
Speaker 4:  No, I thought about it. I was like, I can just purchase a
Speaker 4:  Chromebook for no money
Speaker 5:  And not spend
Speaker 6:  Like six hours.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Like you walk into like any carrier retail store and you're like, I
Speaker 4:  might upgrade my plan. They're like Chromebook. Yeah. Do you want one crisp
Speaker 4:  be it at you Anyhow Apple invented the USB C
Speaker 4:  port basically because the USB i f was going down
Speaker 4:  a bad direction and they wanted it for that MacBook. Yeah. So Apple's view
Speaker 4:  is like
Speaker 5:  Apple invented is strong, but it's not that far off. Like
Speaker 4:  Well, it's like
Speaker 6:  What? It participated hard.
Speaker 5:  Apple probably deserves more credit than any other company for the existence
Speaker 5:  of USB C. But like a lot of people made USB C, which is why
Speaker 5:  USB C is good. Right. Because everybody sat in a room and agreed this is
Speaker 5:  the standard we're gonna Yeah. Live with it.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. But like in that room, apple had a knife.
Speaker 5:  Sure. It's like, it's like Google and Chromium, right? Yeah. Like Chromium
Speaker 5:  is technically an open source browser and you can do whatever you'd like
Speaker 5:  with it. But someone from Google will stand outside of your house. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  Exactly. If you Yeah, like Apple's, like we know where all of you live, you
Speaker 4:  have our phones, right? We've handed your iCloud credentials to the Chinese
Speaker 4:  government. It's just the thing that we've done. Yes. Don't worry about it.
Speaker 4:  But anyway, so Apple in in general is like happy about USB
Speaker 4:  C I think they're not happy about losing the revenue. I think they're not
Speaker 4:  happy about being forced to it because of the Europeans. But you can't just
Speaker 4:  switch the iPad, the ninth gen iPad to pc. You have to re-architect
Speaker 4:  that product. Yes. So I think that just gets phased out. AirPods,
Speaker 4:  Max, apple doesn't even acknowledge that these, this product exists. And
Speaker 4:  I see more of them than anything else. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  They're clearly very popular.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Always on the planes. Yeah. Like I, I think that I need to buy them
Speaker 6:  when I get on a plane. I'm like, well everybody, everybody has them. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  I should have them too. They're everywhere.
Speaker 4:  Have you ever stopped to ask these people like, so tell me about the case
Speaker 4:  it came with, do you use it?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I never see the little purse. Never see the purse.
Speaker 4:  But like Lightning on the AirPods Max, the regular
Speaker 4:  AirPods. Like, I mean this is a lot of products that need to be updated.
Speaker 4:  I don't think it's quite as simple that Mouse, there
Speaker 5:  Are a handful of them that they can just kind of get for free. Yeah. Right.
Speaker 5:  That you just stick a new port in and it'll be fine. Like the, the
Speaker 5:  magic keyboard is a good example, right? Like changing that to USB C will
Speaker 5:  not be hard work. I actually think that base level iPad, I think
Speaker 5:  you're right, is the most interesting one because A, that thing is probably
Speaker 5:  due for a bit of a redesign anyway. B, it's
Speaker 5:  clearly very popular. Like Apple talks about that thing way more than you
Speaker 5:  would think it would for like a pretty cheap entry level product. It's clear,
Speaker 5:  it's a meaningful thing to Apple. And so I suspect that one is going
Speaker 5:  to be the one that we see like look the most different. Yeah. And also come
Speaker 5:  with USB C Well
Speaker 6:  And a lot of that was like they're trying to get rid of old inventory and
Speaker 6:  stuff too here. Right. Like that's why they, it still has the, the dorky
Speaker 6:  pencil and everything like that. No disrespect. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Some some disrespect.
Speaker 6:  Some disrespect. Yeah. Some some, I I do think it's gonna be a
Speaker 6:  minute. I don't think they're just going to flip a switch because they do
Speaker 6:  still need to get rid of all of that stuff. Yeah. And that's why they're
Speaker 6:  so rich now is because they're really good at like unloading old crap
Speaker 6:  that they're great at it. The iPhone
Speaker 4:  Mini. How'd get Mini? How Get Rich Tim? Well I unloaded old crap. But
Speaker 6:  They, they would like, they they they jazz it up. Like they put some makeup
Speaker 6:  on, like it they, they'd contour like it looked nice. Wow.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. That the iPhone Mini man it was gorgeous.
Speaker 4:  Gorgeous device. It was so gorgeous Old phone. Just like the iPhone 15.
Speaker 5:  It sounds so dead. I just saw what So, so, so, so dead.
Speaker 6:  Our producer has one and it's the cutest little thing in the world.
Speaker 5:  Andrew Marino, our producer just bought another one like a
Speaker 5:  psychopath because it's about to be gone forever. Liam, our
Speaker 5:  other producer is holding on God The Verge cast. What a disaster of a show.
Speaker 5:  This is just all minis. There's just iPhone Minis.
Speaker 4:  They're wave at us.
Speaker 5:  They're the last two.
Speaker 4:  This is like Walt Mossberg at the end of the MacBook Air Run. He just bought
Speaker 4:  like two of them. Yeah, yeah. To have them in case Apple screwed it up in
Speaker 4:  the future. That's
Speaker 6:  Smart. I I
Speaker 4:  Would do that. That's good. Speaking of USB C in general, we've
Speaker 4:  learned a lot about the Port and what it will
Speaker 4:  support and basically the answer is everything. Like Apple did this the right
Speaker 4:  way.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It seems to be
Speaker 4:  So back 'cause they had
Speaker 6:  A moral obligation to David. God
Speaker 4:  That's what gets Apple to think. Yeah. So Backbone one controllers are just
Speaker 4:  gonna get upgraded and they're gonna work with the iPhone and I actually
Speaker 4:  saw some Backbone folks at the event they were
Speaker 4:  excited and they were just handing out the Android Backbone controllers to,
Speaker 4:  there were a lot of games reporters there. Yeah. So that's cool. Like it's
Speaker 4:  cool that that just works. Apparently you can plug in just sort of any
Speaker 4:  USB C hub and get like ethernet on your phone. Oh wow. Like
Speaker 4:  basically anything that would work on the iPad Pro is gonna just
Speaker 4:  happen over here.
Speaker 5:  That's cool. That's much bigger than I expected
Speaker 6:  Actually. Well you're at the office and you have the crappy wifi and they're
Speaker 6:  always the, it is always like just plug into the ethernet and you're like
Speaker 6:  I hate you. I'm on my phone now You can just be like,
Speaker 5:  Plug your phone in. Fine. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I don't know how any of that's gonna work. My experience doing any of this
Speaker 4:  stuff with an iPad is always a little like you just hope the
Speaker 4:  You know the magic of the iPad magics at you. It's gonna be even
Speaker 4:  weirder with a phone. I and You know I s 17 is another bit of a wild
Speaker 4:  card here. So, but theoretically we
Speaker 6:  Have decks for the
Speaker 4:  Phone. It's just gonna work. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I mean the Backbone thing to me is like the perfect example of how this ought
Speaker 5:  to be and I think it's very exciting where they're just like, oh this thing
Speaker 5:  that used to fit on these phones now also fits on these phones and so it's
Speaker 5:  going to work. Like this is the point of having a universal standard. This
Speaker 5:  is why the EU mandated this. Yeah. This is why we were excited about this.
Speaker 5:  It's like it's gonna be good for the accessories market, it's gonna be good
Speaker 5:  for users, but you're gonna be able to share stuff with people. You're gonna
Speaker 5:  be able to buy things without that. Like does this work with my
Speaker 5:  phone question? Which is a really complicated question
Speaker 5:  for lots of people. Yep. And yeah, the fact that Apple seems to have gone
Speaker 5:  about this about the most open way possible is great and frankly
Speaker 5:  very surprising.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And they didn't Nerf any of the charging speeds or transfer speeds.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I mean except the F 15 is at USC two but Well
Speaker 5:  Yeah that's, but again that's like it's good enough for most people. It'll
Speaker 5:  be fine. I don't think there are that many people buying an iPhone 15 desperate
Speaker 5:  for ultra fast. Yeah. Data transfers piece.
Speaker 6:  I think those people are getting a pro if they care enough, if they know
Speaker 6:  what USB two is, they're getting a pro. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  I think that's right. We should by
Speaker 4:  The way, the word pro means. I just wanna be clear, my contribution to
Speaker 4:  iPhone reviews this year is gonna be just a little weirder. 'cause I have
Speaker 4:  the code conference to deal with that's very distracting. But I'm
Speaker 4:  like, what if my only contribution to this review is
Speaker 4:  2000 words on the meaning of the word pro. A word that has lost
Speaker 4:  all meaning in which in this case for Apple this year
Speaker 4:  means good at video games. That's what pros. They don't have another, they
Speaker 4:  don't have another answer for it. Which is wild.
Speaker 5:  Okay. I see it exactly the opposite. We should get to
Speaker 5:  Google after this. Yeah. 'cause this is enough Apple talk. But I think to
Speaker 5:  me the fact that a big part of the way Apple showed off the pro was
Speaker 5:  by showing you how you can like rig up a camera in a studio and shoot
Speaker 5:  to external storage. Like that's Yeah, that's pro,
Speaker 5:  that's how you tell a story that is different about that phone than
Speaker 5:  the other phones. Whether that's like real and how people will do that. Like
Speaker 5:  you were on the show on Wednesday making fun of the idea that you would like
Speaker 5:  use your iPhone in a studio to take professional pictures. People do that
Speaker 5:  all the time. Yeah dude. Like that's like life now. Stephen Soderberg iss
Speaker 5:  out here just like shooting movies on his iPhone for fun all day. Like it's
Speaker 5:  a real thing. And the idea that they're gonna take the
Speaker 5:  pro and like give it genuinely new things to do, especially as
Speaker 5:  a camera. I think like if you want to tell a pro story, that's where you
Speaker 5:  do it. They're like, we are gonna turn this thing. Right. And
Speaker 4:  I'm saying what they're saying is look at how good it is at video games.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Not that thing
Speaker 5:  Sort of, I mean they did a little bit of the other story. They spent way
Speaker 5:  too much time talking about games. This is like Apple does this all the time
Speaker 5:  where they're like, they're, this is, we made a phone. This is my
Speaker 6:  Favorite thing in the world. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  It's, you're going to use it for games occasionally. So we're gonna tell
Speaker 5:  you about every single game that exists on the iPhone. So
Speaker 4:  Two things and Then we can wrap up as always. I've asked people to email
Speaker 4:  us with their hardcore Android gamers. So. we got one from
Speaker 4:  Evan. He said, I am here to inform you that I've been gaming on Android for
Speaker 4:  as long as The Verge has existed. And it's a long list of all the phones
Speaker 4:  you've ever got. Lg, Optimus G. He played Need for speed on it.
Speaker 4:  Wait, LT Launch. She's got Stadia. Anyway, this email ends with, I
Speaker 4:  did just buy an iPhone 11 primarily to play games.
Speaker 5:  There it is. There it is.
Speaker 4:  Yep. It's well done Evan. Easily the funniest turn. It's a, it's a good long
Speaker 4:  email. Easily one of the funniest turns in an email saying you're wrong about
Speaker 4:  Android games. It was a very good, we've
Speaker 6:  Email
Speaker 4:  And Then, we got an email from Colin 'cause we were
Speaker 4:  wondering who would buy the Lightning to USB C Dongle for 20
Speaker 4:  bucks. And we hypothesized that some people would buy them for their cars
Speaker 4:  and he emailed us to tell us Yes, his friend is buying one for his car. He
Speaker 4:  has a custom setup and he, it's apparently easier to pay
Speaker 4:  20 bucks for the dongle than to tear open his car and put in
Speaker 4:  a USB c cable custom
Speaker 6:  Set up with a built-in U
Speaker 4:  Lightning cable. Yeah. That's
Speaker 6:  Incredible.
Speaker 4:  I love this stuff. He's probably one of these people with like an iPad in
Speaker 4:  the center of the the car. Oh yeah. Oh yeah. Well Colin, we want pictures
Speaker 4:  of your friend's car. So get in there, send it. But there are some
Speaker 4:  people out there who are buying the dongle. 'cause they have basically fixed
Speaker 4:  Lightning cables.
Speaker 6:  A lot of like coffee shops are gonna buy the dongle. I
Speaker 5:  Also think a lot of people are gonna buy the dongle because the idea of buying
Speaker 5:  an entirely new cable feels annoying. And I'm gonna spend a lot of
Speaker 5:  time like running around to relatives being like, don't buy the Don, go buy
Speaker 5:  a new cable. It costs, it's the same price, it's gonna be
Speaker 5:  fine. Everything's okay. Like I'm, I'm gonna end up with just like
Speaker 5:  a giant You know bucket full of two meter
Speaker 5:  long USB C cables. And just every time I go into a room with family members,
Speaker 5:  I'm just gonna start hucking them at people. Yeah. That's my, everybody's
Speaker 6:  Gonna little rat tail on the, on the bottom of their phones. Exactly. Because
Speaker 6:  they always have to have that, that dongle.
Speaker 4:  This Hong Kong, like people did it with the headphones. And lastly, I'm just
Speaker 4:  gonna say this, I have heard that not everyone at Apple
Speaker 4:  pronounce it's Heath. Whoa. That Hef.
Speaker 4:  There's more diversity of pronunciations inside
Speaker 4:  of Apple in Tell me more.
Speaker 4:  Well, I was just like, does this whole company call it Heath? And then some
Speaker 4:  people contacted me and was like, not all of us say
Speaker 4:  Heath,
Speaker 6:  You can't, you can't share, like you don't wanna disclose your short sources.
Speaker 4:  No, this is, this is some of the most sensitive reporting I've ever done.
Speaker 4:  I,
Speaker 6:  We appreciate it.
Speaker 4:  And I'm just saying he f might've been pushed out into
Speaker 4:  the world,
Speaker 5:  But it's out there now. If you're the one on ca, if you're the one on camera,
Speaker 5:  you get to decide how it's pronounced and
Speaker 4:  And it's Heath. It's
Speaker 5:  Heif now.
Speaker 4:  All right. We gotta take a break. That is enough iPhone stuff for a
Speaker 4:  week. We'll be back with Addie Robertson to talk about us. If you Google,
Speaker 4:  which is a big deal, we'll be right
Speaker 4:  back.
Speaker 5:  couple weeks and there's tons of people talking about that. There was the
Speaker 5:  Microsoft Activision Blizzard trial, there was the Elizabeth Holmes trial.
Speaker 5:  Like we've had a run of these very high profile
Speaker 4:  Cases. Apple, Samsung,
Speaker 5:  Apple V Samsung. We've had a run of these over the last few years and this
Speaker 5:  feels by far like the one that is getting
Speaker 5:  the least attention despite being potentially like the most
Speaker 5:  consequential by a million miles. Yeah, it's very strange. I think
Speaker 6:  It's because Google's just really good at like flying under the radar. 'cause
Speaker 6:  even with the, the Google v Epic. No,
Speaker 4:  That's what I meant. I said Apple v, Samsung and then,
Speaker 5:  I mean that one happened too. I mean Apple
Speaker 4:  V
Speaker 6:  Epic, like they all happen, right? Like Apple v Epic was a big
Speaker 6:  deal. Yeah, Google v Epic. We were like, yep, now they're doing it. I
Speaker 6:  mean Google
Speaker 9:  Has also been trying to keep like as much of the trial under wraps
Speaker 9:  as possible here. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  Yeah. So just
Speaker 6:  Unlike their phones,
Speaker 4:  It's very good. So just to lay that stage here, then I want to add, to talk
Speaker 4:  about what's actually happening in trial. It is impossible to cover this
Speaker 4:  trial. There's no audio stream of it.
Speaker 9:  There was an audio stream very briefly
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Of of just the opening arguments, but none of the witnesses, there's
Speaker 4:  barely a schedule. If reporters go into the courtroom, they can't have
Speaker 4:  devices, they have to take all their notes longhand. It is just
Speaker 4:  ridiculous. Yeah. But the government might get to a
Speaker 4:  place where it breaks up Google and the process by which that is
Speaker 4:  happening is basically impossible and
Speaker 4:  opaque because we cannot just cover it unless we send
Speaker 4:  someone to the courtroom every day for nine weeks to take notes with a
Speaker 4:  pen and a scroll, which we are thinking about doing and
Speaker 4:  obviously other other larger competitors like Bloomberg and the Times are
Speaker 4:  doing. But you just contrast that with all of the other
Speaker 4:  trials and it, for some reason these decisions have been
Speaker 4:  made. It's, I dunno, it's, I find it very frustrating
Speaker 4:  obviously because I think about Google all day every day. But this is the
Speaker 4:  trial where You know Google putting out memos to its own employees saying
Speaker 4:  we do not use words like Lockin.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Or scale. Or
Speaker 4:  Scale. Yeah. Right. We don't use the word leverage when we talk about search.
Speaker 4:  Like they're instructing their own executives how to email each other.
Speaker 4:  They're in trouble for destroying evidence in this case.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. There's that amazing message where Sundar, Petra, the c e o popped
Speaker 5:  into a a Google chat group and said something to the effect of
Speaker 5:  like, we should talk about this. Can we turn off
Speaker 5:  history for this chat session? And then that's obviously
Speaker 5:  the last message anyone can see. And yeah, I mean Addie,
Speaker 5:  my impression, and this is based on very little except just thinking about
Speaker 5:  incentives here, is that Google has everything to gain
Speaker 5:  from burying as much of this trial and process as possible,
Speaker 5:  right?
Speaker 9:  Yes. I mean with the caveat that it's not going to matter if the, A
Speaker 9:  judge is like, we're breaking up Google. Google is still getting broken up
Speaker 9:  even if it's in secret. And again, to be clear, that's one of
Speaker 9:  the less likely outcomes. Yes. But yeah, I think that it benefits
Speaker 9:  Google to not have to deal with a lot of the
Speaker 9:  arguments being made here as it does it would for really most
Speaker 9:  plaintiffs, like as it would for Apple in Epic versus Apple.
Speaker 9:  And then there's also a lot of other companies implicated here. Like obviously
Speaker 9:  this is about, Google's deals with companies like Apple. And so
Speaker 9:  Apple has appeared and tried to like, it's tried to get its
Speaker 9:  executives out of testifying. So there's really
Speaker 9:  just a lot of companies here and a lot of very sensitive information going
Speaker 9:  around. And so on one hand it's, it's not really surprising that they would
Speaker 9:  try to keep a lot of this secret. But on the other, it also means that you
Speaker 9:  don't hear as much about what the Justice Department is saying Google is
Speaker 9:  doing.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And the case fundamentally turns on on these deals.
Speaker 4:  Right. So the case was pretty wide ranging. It's been, this has been
Speaker 4:  going on for three years now. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It was 2020 the first suit was filed. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And so it's like all things, as it approaches trial, it's
Speaker 4:  been narrowed down to a handful of issues. The most I think
Speaker 4:  important and relevant. One is Google's deals to be the default search engine
Speaker 4:  on the iPhone and other platforms. So of course the Justice Department
Speaker 4:  wants Tim Cook to testify and Apple's like, no,
Speaker 4:  no, no, no, no, we're not doing. And, but that makes sense. They wanna do
Speaker 4:  that. But just again, I'm just coming back to this last, this
Speaker 4:  week while Apple was announcing pretty light refreshes the
Speaker 4:  iPhone that captured all the attention, but the
Speaker 4:  trial in which the Department of Justice is saying, the deal in which
Speaker 4:  Google pays Apple money to be the default search provider on the
Speaker 4:  iPhone is anti-competitive and illegal
Speaker 4:  is like totally under the radar and impossible to cover. And I just think
Speaker 4:  that's weird.
Speaker 9:  I think there's also, it's also just easy to be sort of cynical because we've
Speaker 9:  been seeing these cases try to make a dent in companies for
Speaker 9:  years and years and years. Like the, there was this
Speaker 9:  entire gigantic, ostensibly bipartisan tech
Speaker 9:  lash starting in really about 2016, building up
Speaker 9:  20 17, 20 18 and nothing happened. Yeah. I just, I think it's really
Speaker 9:  easy to look at this and go, it is very, very hard to win an
Speaker 9:  antitrust case. The Federal Trade Commission, which is not
Speaker 9:  the one bringing the suit, but is, which is part of the Biden administration's
Speaker 9:  attempt to get antitrust to happen in the us It has had a couple of
Speaker 9:  really high profile losses. Epic versus Apple.
Speaker 9:  Really it means that Apple is going to maybe have to do
Speaker 9:  something that Apple has been fighting tooth and nail to not do, but it's
Speaker 9:  still basically determined, look, apple can just charge these fees. I think
Speaker 9:  that it's very easy to look at this and worry that just nothing's going to
Speaker 9:  come of it. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I I like that. That was what I was gonna say. I think, I think cynicism
Speaker 6:  is, is the right word here. People are cynical. Like we've seen this
Speaker 6:  happen so many times
Speaker 6:  and not just in tech. You've seen it happen in a lot of places where it's
Speaker 6:  just like, okay, so when is the government gonna actually do something? When
Speaker 6:  is this gonna happen? We're just gonna continue on. And this is like
Speaker 6:  a really good opportunity for the government. And even the government seems
Speaker 6:  like reluctant, right? Like they could probably make this a lot more public.
Speaker 6:  They could make this more of a show. Well, and it might be in their best
Speaker 6:  interest to like get the public support behind it,
Speaker 6:  but they, even the government is playing it so safe. You're like, well, you're
Speaker 6:  playing it that safe. Are you really gonna do it? Well,
Speaker 4:  There are many branches of government three, I'm told there's
Speaker 4:  three. So You know, I don't know why the judge, in this
Speaker 4:  case, judge Meta is logging it down the way he is. Obviously Google
Speaker 4:  wants it that way and there's requests and there's private stuff, but like
Speaker 4:  not having audio streams of the witnesses seems, I don't, I I just don't
Speaker 4:  understand that at all. And then there's the D O J, which is You know they're
Speaker 4:  prosecutors. They're not supposed to do it that way.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. But Right. You know. It's like I, there's a little bit of a gap there.
Speaker 4:  The thing I would give you is the same week we did
Speaker 4:  watch the European government successfully pressure Apple into changing the
Speaker 4:  port in the iPhone. And that's a good outcome. And even
Speaker 4:  in our videos, like our hands-on video where we are like Apple
Speaker 4:  changed it, the comments are like the Europeans changed it. Yep. Yeah. Like
Speaker 4:  people understand the mechanism by which the change was made.
Speaker 5:  Yes. Well, and that's what we've been talking about in the US for the last
Speaker 5:  couple of years, right? Is that like a, a clearer part of the ftc, which
Speaker 5:  again is not involved in this particular trial, but what they're trying to
Speaker 5:  do is sort of lose in such a way that it eventually we have to
Speaker 5:  legislate answers to this. And it's like what the EU did was make laws Yeah.
Speaker 5:  They like, there was no big court case about the Lightning port. They just
Speaker 5:  made a law about common chargers. And it feels like
Speaker 5:  that's, if our, if our system worked better, it's, it
Speaker 5:  might be different
Speaker 4:  Here, but so the EU has made a lot of laws, so many about Google search,
Speaker 5:  Many, so many,
Speaker 4:  They have done more aggressive enforcements about Google
Speaker 4:  search than would ever be contemplated in this
Speaker 4:  company. Yes. Down to designing the startup flow of an
Speaker 4:  Android phone. And Addie and I have been talking about this for years. None
Speaker 4:  of it has worked. Like Google is dominant in Europe, when you open an Android
Speaker 4:  phone, it asks you if you wanna use Chrome. It asks you, it has a browser
Speaker 4:  ballot and a search engine ballot. Right. And no,
Speaker 4:  everyone's just like, okay, like we're gonna pick Chrome and Google
Speaker 4:  because I bought a Android phone. Like, what else do you think
Speaker 4:  I'm doing here?
Speaker 9:  DuckDuckGo?
Speaker 5:  How
Speaker 4:  Did you see any similarities between that
Speaker 4:  version of the European enforcement, which has been
Speaker 4:  unsuccessful and what is happening in this case?
Speaker 9:  I mean, that entire thing you've just said is kind of Google's argument is,
Speaker 9:  look, even when we don't, don't get the default placement, even when we
Speaker 9:  don't do this thing that the Justice Department is saying is illegal, we
Speaker 9:  win. So clearly we're just the
Speaker 9:  best.
Speaker 5:  I just wanna say that is my absolute favorite thing that has been happening
Speaker 5:  in this trial so far is binging is everybody's punching
Speaker 5:  bag.
Speaker 10:  And
Speaker 5:  But like Google's argument is essentially Microsoft makes
Speaker 5:  binging the default on Windows in the same way. That word the default in
Speaker 5:  lots of places. And still overwhelmingly people choose Google because Bing
Speaker 5:  sucks. And the government's case is, well, binging sucks and
Speaker 5:  nobody uses it. And that's Google's fault.
Speaker 10:  And and
Speaker 5:  It's very funny to me that like it's, it's a shame that there's not a better
Speaker 5:  product to argue about here. Yeah. And I think it just
Speaker 5:  kept coming up over and over and over. And like in a funny
Speaker 5:  way, if Google wins this case, I think Microsoft is going to have
Speaker 5:  been a huge ally for Google in winning this case. Because what Google
Speaker 5:  is saying, and Addie, I don't know if this was your impression, but listening
Speaker 5:  to the opening arguments over an at t conference call, which was very funny
Speaker 5:  for an antitrust trial, which is, but
Speaker 5:  it, the overwhelming thing Google kept saying was like, we are not the
Speaker 5:  company with infinite resources that is able to do whatever we want and outbid
Speaker 5:  everybody to do everything because Microsoft exists. Microsoft is also a
Speaker 5:  trillion dollar company with limitless money to do whatever it wants. They
Speaker 5:  keep trying to put binging in front of people. Windows exists. Microsoft
Speaker 5:  has a long history of doing antitrust things and binging still sucks and
Speaker 5:  nobody uses it. And I actually think like of all of the Google arguments
Speaker 5:  I have heard so far, that is by far the most compelling to me. I don't know,
Speaker 5:  Addie, did you read that differently on the first day? Yeah.
Speaker 9:  And I think that the Justice Department is trying to counter it by basically
Speaker 9:  saying the reason Google is so good and is so untouchable is
Speaker 9:  because we all agree here, Bing, it
Speaker 9:  sucks.
Speaker 10:  They're,
Speaker 9:  They're not that strong,
Speaker 10:  But they
Speaker 9:  Is that Google gathers has so much data from searches
Speaker 9:  that it basically got this flywheel effect of just being able to get
Speaker 9:  to fault placements. So then people type things into Google and then Google
Speaker 9:  learns how people search for things and then Google could deliver better
Speaker 9:  results. And then this just keeps going. And even though Microsoft has
Speaker 9:  tried to do things, it's tried to set its own defaults, it has
Speaker 9:  partnered with Yahoo at thing that's come up to do a data sharing deal
Speaker 9:  in order to get more queries, that that just hasn't been enough.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Yeah. One of the things that Judge Meta asked, I think like
Speaker 5:  within the first hour or so of testimony on the first day
Speaker 5:  was he asked the, the D o j lawyer, how long has
Speaker 5:  Google been a monopoly? Which I thought was a really interesting question.
Speaker 5:  And, and I think the answer was it has been illegally protecting that
Speaker 5:  monopoly since 2010, which, which assumes that it was a monopoly
Speaker 5:  before that. Right. But I think once,
Speaker 9:  I think he was saying it's been, it's had really heavy market power since
Speaker 9:  about 2007. Okay.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So I
Speaker 9:  Think, and then yes, it's been illegally maintaining the monopolies since
Speaker 9:  2010.
Speaker 5:  Right. And so that's, that's the do j's argument. But what I think is really
Speaker 5:  interesting there is like, obviously Google came out in 1998 and no
Speaker 5:  one is debating the fact that Google, at least for a long time was vastly
Speaker 5:  better than everything else and won purely on the merits. And then what
Speaker 5:  we're debating now is did it go from winning on the merits
Speaker 5:  to buying merits and essentially making it
Speaker 5:  impossible for anyone else to do to like Google what Google did
Speaker 5:  to Alta Vista and everybody else 25 years ago. And
Speaker 5:  that turn and trying to figure out like where it happened and what it looks
Speaker 5:  like is I think why we've come down to these default deals. Because ultimately
Speaker 5:  that's the question, right? Is like Google's out here saying there are a
Speaker 5:  million ways to find information on the internet and the D O J is saying
Speaker 5:  like general search, which they keep calling it is this different thing from
Speaker 5:  what TikTok is and what chat G P T is. But they have to figure out
Speaker 5:  like, okay, when did Google go from just objectively being the best search
Speaker 5:  engine? And so everybody uses it, which is not illegal to
Speaker 5:  being the best and making sure that no one else can be, which is a much
Speaker 5:  trickier thing than like what Microsoft did, which is just like boot Netscape
Speaker 5:  off the internet. And I don't know, it's, it just set us off down this kind
Speaker 5:  of odd path where like it's almost not obvious what everyone is
Speaker 5:  arguing at any given time, right? No matter what side you're
Speaker 4:  On. This general search thing is ridiculous.
Speaker 4:  Like the F T C what, what, they've done a bad
Speaker 4:  job in many of their cases. Like they did the entire Activision trial
Speaker 4:  and forgot to mention cloud gaming and then they lost and then they were
Speaker 4:  like in the background being like, we're gonna appeal on cloud gaming. And
Speaker 4:  it's like, yeah, that was the, that was the argument
Speaker 4:  the whole time here. The d oj I think is getting suckered into
Speaker 4:  this ar like every antitrust trial comes down to like, what is the market?
Speaker 4:  Yep. Let's have an increasingly esoteric debate about what
Speaker 4:  market is being dominated. And then obviously Google's like the
Speaker 4:  market is the use of computers and we are, but one
Speaker 4:  tiny fraction of why one might compute, sir. Right? Right. And then the D
Speaker 4:  O J is like general search, which means fucking nothing. And the answer is
Speaker 4:  like, no, it's searching the web. Yeah. There are a handful of products that
Speaker 4:  search the web. Yep. People use them all day long and
Speaker 4:  there's one search engine that matters in the web.
Speaker 9:  Yes. To be fair, that is what their definition of general search is, is a
Speaker 9:  thing that searches sources that is not sources beyond one
Speaker 9:  site on the web. Right. Right.
Speaker 4:  But that even that definition is like, it, it just, it's so not
Speaker 4:  the, like if you tried to explain that to a normal person, you'd be like,
Speaker 4:  all right, so there's, there are sources beyond one site, right? Like you,
Speaker 4:  like, I'm not even gonna say the word web to you. And it I I would
Speaker 4:  just say if you, you just look at the web today, we've talked about this
Speaker 4:  so many times. It is so obviously influenced by Google's wants and
Speaker 4:  needs that you can't not say this thing is
Speaker 4:  dominant. It is the only incentive structure that exists in the web really
Speaker 4:  is Google's wants and needs. 'cause that's how people get traffic to the
Speaker 4:  websites. Okay. Like just start. And the
Speaker 4:  D O J has just been suckered into this conversation about general search
Speaker 4:  and whether the kids are using TikTok. Right.
Speaker 6:  And like that's totally different.
Speaker 4:  I mean if Apple changes the default search on the iPhone to be
Speaker 4:  TikTok
Speaker 6:  Horrible experience.
Speaker 4:  Right. And it's like, but that's so just generally nonsensical to think of
Speaker 4:  that. Yeah. The kids love iPhones, the kids love TikTok,
Speaker 4:  mung 'em together, all these other searches that we're talking about in the
Speaker 4:  category of general search that Google wants you to consider. I would just
Speaker 4:  say, come back to the thing at issue, which is the default deals on
Speaker 4:  these platforms and say, can you replace them? Could you
Speaker 4:  replace the default search on the iPhone with a YouTube search?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And like no, basically you need web
Speaker 4:  search and I Google's protection of that web search. Well
Speaker 4:  yeah, there's the data argument that they've been making for a long time.
Speaker 4:  Like everyone's been making, Google has the most data they can do it, but
Speaker 4:  next to it Addie are these like vertical search engines like Yelp and
Speaker 4:  these other companies that are like, we're much better in these very specific
Speaker 4:  domains and we can barely even get to a customer because of
Speaker 4:  Google's deals. Yeah,
Speaker 9:  Yeah. Which was a bigger part of the case originally and then got trimmed
Speaker 9:  out of it. And so is not coming up in this as much. Do
Speaker 6:  You think it'll come up later in these 10 weeks?
Speaker 9:  So the Department of Justice is making its case first, and that
Speaker 9:  claim was part of the state attorney general suit that's gonna come up later,
Speaker 9:  but it also got cut mostly from that suit. So I think we're not actually
Speaker 9:  going to hear nearly as much about it as we could have even though those
Speaker 9:  search engines come up. Which
Speaker 6:  Is a bummer because that feels like the real issue, right?
Speaker 6:  Like the fact that they're doing these exclusivity deals is on
Speaker 6:  its face totally a like monopoly behavior. But also
Speaker 6:  in this case, Google is actually really good at search. So of course like
Speaker 6:  it makes
Speaker 4:  Sense. Well no, it's like, let's say you ask Siri to find
Speaker 4:  you a plumber. Yeah, right. In
Speaker 4:  a competitive world, apple goes and makes a deal with Yelp
Speaker 4:  or
Speaker 6:  AngelList. AngelList
Speaker 4:  Or whatever, right. And they're running that search on a specialized
Speaker 4:  service. Google's deal means like that's all going through Google. Oh,
Speaker 4:  okay.
Speaker 6:  Okay then. Yeah. No, they're a monopoly. Let's get rid of
Speaker 4:  'em. I mean like I don't dunno if that's good or bad, bad. Well it's also
Speaker 4:  right, I'm just saying but that's, that's sort of the, the shape of it and
Speaker 4:  Addie's, right? It's been trimmed outta the suit although, well
Speaker 6:  No, this part that
Speaker 9:  Got trimmed outta the suit was not the thing you're describing. It was the
Speaker 9:  idea that when you go to Google itself Yeah, yeah. And you're trying to find
Speaker 9:  a thing on Google. Google makes it hard to find these places like Yelp
Speaker 9:  or TripAdvisor or whatever through Google
Speaker 9:  specifically. So that got mostly cut out of the suit
Speaker 4:  And the judge sort of rightfully was like, well, Google's allowed to do whatever
Speaker 4:  it wants on Google. But there is that vertical search thing from what
Speaker 4:  I read of the decision, the judge is basically like, I need to see more evidence,
Speaker 4:  we'll get more evidence at trial and I will decide how big of a deal that
Speaker 4:  is. And so we'll see what hap what the states do. But you just look at all
Speaker 4:  of the things Google does and again, it's instructions to
Speaker 4:  its own people to not talk about doing those
Speaker 4:  things.
Speaker 9:  Ooh. That seems illegal. I mean I don't think that it is necessarily illegal,
Speaker 9:  but it is de certainly the kind of thing you can bring up to, to say it's
Speaker 9:  shady. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I mean that we don't, we don't leverage anything. It is like a very funny
Speaker 4:  thing to say. So Addie, what's been going on this week? It's just been Google's
Speaker 4:  chief economist, Hal Vian, have we learned anything in
Speaker 4:  particular?
Speaker 9:  So the first day was after opening statements, Hal Vian who,
Speaker 9:  where they really honed in on the idea that we're gonna go to the
Speaker 9:  metaphorical tape and look at all of these emails that Google execs have
Speaker 9:  sent about how important scale is and how important data is. And
Speaker 9:  then there are these internal arguments where
Speaker 9:  Arian wrote this, did this interview with cnet, where he says, look,
Speaker 9:  the argument that that data is like the be all and end all and that
Speaker 9:  Microsoft has to make this deal with Yahoo to get data that's bogus. And
Speaker 9:  then there was this internal fight where people were just saying, look, that's
Speaker 9:  ridiculous. No data. Obviously if they had the data we did, we would be in,
Speaker 9:  they would be incredible. Like they would be much better than they are
Speaker 9:  now. So there's that. And then this was also where we got a lot of
Speaker 9:  the we at Google, we do not say market share, we say query
Speaker 9:  share. We do not bundle, we do not tie. And then beyond that,
Speaker 9:  we've also, there's been a behavioral economist that they've brought that
Speaker 9:  the Department of Justice has brought up to emphasize the quote sort of power
Speaker 9:  of defaults that that's been their first expert witness. He spent a bunch
Speaker 9:  of time on the stand. And so that's
Speaker 9:  been a lot of presentations both about stuff Google has said
Speaker 9:  internally, which echoes sort of the varying testimony and just
Speaker 9:  experiments and other data that has been collected
Speaker 9:  elsewhere. That just says in general, people choose defaults.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And I do think if you wanted to boil this case all the way down to
Speaker 5:  one question, it's the power of defaults. Like do defaults
Speaker 5:  matter is in a big way, it seems like what a lot of this is going to
Speaker 5:  hinge on, because Google's argument is they
Speaker 5:  matter a little, right? It's why we pay for the defaults. Like Google cannot,
Speaker 5:  in any kind of reasonable way, say defaults don't matter at all
Speaker 5:  because it pays tens of billions of dollars a year. Yeah. To be the
Speaker 5:  default. So it's, it's like all that is fine and good, but the two arguments
Speaker 5:  it makes is that defaults don't matter that much because people choose Google
Speaker 5:  even when it's hard to, or even when there is a fairly level playing field.
Speaker 5:  And because binging sucks, because binging sucks. And also that we
Speaker 5:  only pay to be the default because we're the good, we're the best product.
Speaker 5:  Everybody tells us we're the best product. That's the only thing that matters.
Speaker 5:  The end there. And then the D O J is out here saying, no, you are the
Speaker 5:  default you pay to be the default So, we can't even reasonably start to
Speaker 5:  answer the rest of these questions. Right. And that's what all the like little
Speaker 5:  search engines will tell you. That's what all the failed competitors will
Speaker 5:  tell you is that like, we don't even know if we could have beaten Google
Speaker 5:  or tried or caught up. We just, there's no runway, there's no way to
Speaker 5:  even get into this space. Right.
Speaker 4:  You just wrote the obituary of Neva
Speaker 5:  Basically. Yeah. And Neva has already come up a bunch in this trial. And
Speaker 5:  Sridhar Ram Swami, the c e O of Neva who used to run the whole ad business
Speaker 5:  at Google is going to take the stand during this trial. Like that is a
Speaker 5:  key part of the argument is like, defaults are so important that because
Speaker 5:  Google pays all this money to be the default, we don't exist. And
Speaker 5:  that's like if the d if the D OJ can prove that it might win. And it's
Speaker 5:  very hard to prove that. Yeah. It seems to me
Speaker 9:  There's also the argument that it's that specifically, it's not just small
Speaker 9:  search engines. It is Go Apple that one of the things that hasn't come up
Speaker 9:  really in testimony as much, but was part of the opening statements is that
Speaker 9:  Google has been basically paying Apple to not build a search
Speaker 9:  engine.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I mean I, every year at wwc, apple does something
Speaker 4:  that hints at an interest in doing more searches.
Speaker 5:  Yes.
Speaker 4:  Right. And every year You know we get the new version of iOS and it's like,
Speaker 4:  pull down and now you can type this and this will come up automatically.
Speaker 4:  Or
Speaker 5:  Yeah, you can do image search and spotlight now it's like, it's right there
Speaker 5:  if you wanted
Speaker 4:  To do it, it's right there. Yeah. And then every year I, we get some notes
Speaker 4:  from some Googlers. They're like, Apple's coming from us. And it's like,
Speaker 4:  no, they're not. Right. I'm very curious. You know
Speaker 4:  if, if they do put Tim Cook and Eddie Q and the rest on the stand,
Speaker 9:  We're gonna get Eddie Q we're, it's far as I know not getting Tim Cook
Speaker 4:  Full Hawaiian shirt, Eddie Q on the stand. Right. It's the, the question
Speaker 4:  I would ask is, look at all this marketing about privacy, look at
Speaker 4:  all this marketing about not tracking you. And look at the billions of
Speaker 4:  dollars you take from the largest ad tracking thing that has ever existed
Speaker 4:  in human history. How do you score that circle beyond just taking the
Speaker 4:  money? 'cause I don't think Apple's ever been held to account for this.
Speaker 4:  Certainly people have tried asking and they're like, people love
Speaker 4:  Google. And that's the end of it. Like Google's available in
Speaker 4:  the app store. The app store has created more economic opportunity
Speaker 4:  for people than ever. And it's like, where, where did you go? Come
Speaker 5:  One, one place that has already kind of come up is with Mozilla.
Speaker 5:  And Mozilla is another company that says a lot of things about privacy in
Speaker 5:  the open web and believing in the internet. And also takes a lot of money
Speaker 5:  from Google every year to be the default search engine in Firefox.
Speaker 5:  And Google's case, and this has actually worked in Google's favor
Speaker 5:  fairly well so far it seems, is that Mozilla at one point stopped
Speaker 5:  using Google as its search engine provider signed a deal with Addie, was
Speaker 5:  it Yahoo? I think it was Yahoo.
Speaker 9:  Okay.
Speaker 5:  And then went back to Google for exactly that reason. Alex,
Speaker 5:  because that's the face everybody makes when they have to use Yahoo search.
Speaker 5:  And so Google is like, they had choices and they picked Google,
Speaker 9:  Hilariously, the Department of Justice's counter to this is that
Speaker 9:  Yahoo could have been viable, but it was so expensive to beat Google that
Speaker 9:  they had to lard down their service with ads that suddenly made Yahoo search
Speaker 9:  awful. And that's why Yahoo search was dropped.
Speaker 5:  It's the bing sucks argument, right? Like, are all other search engines bad
Speaker 5:  because of Google is such a weird question, but is like kind of
Speaker 5:  core to a lot of this case. Yeah. Like there are no other good search
Speaker 5:  engines. Is it because Google is great or because Google has so
Speaker 5:  aggressively it's both defeated everyone. It it probably is both,
Speaker 5:  right? Like I think the answer is probably somewhere in the middle, which
Speaker 5:  is why it's gonna be very hard for Google to lose this case, it seems.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I mean even if they do, you just have to look at Europe
Speaker 4:  where for over a decade now, the
Speaker 4:  princes and princesses of Europe have shaken their pitchforks at Google and
Speaker 4:  said, we will undo this dominance. And the people of
Speaker 4:  Europe have said down with the
Speaker 4:  king no nay good, sir. They have
Speaker 5:  Googled for news about that happening.
Speaker 4:  We shall continue Googling it. No,
Speaker 4:  absolutely not. French revolution, the whole thing. This
Speaker 4:  is, it's it's very complicated over in Europe. They're still kings,
Speaker 4:  I'm told. Yes. I
Speaker 6:  Dunno why S and princesses everywhere. Just everywhere. No one
Speaker 4:  Knows why my people have run away from them twice. I'm Indian
Speaker 4:  American. Anyway, we're gonna cover the hell outta this trial. We're gonna
Speaker 4:  figure out how to get into that courtroom basically every day with a series
Speaker 4:  of quill pens and parchment, because that's how the
Speaker 4:  government wants us to cover U US v Google. David,
Speaker 6:  Could you take the parchment and have it so it like goes out of
Speaker 6:  the room as you write? Oh,
Speaker 5:  That's fun.
Speaker 4:  Oh, that's good. That's good. And
Speaker 6:  The Addie can just be on the other side. Oh, I
Speaker 5:  Like that.
Speaker 4:  OCRing the parchment in the world.
Speaker 5:  My thing is, I'm gonna, I'm gonna bring in increasingly less technologically
Speaker 5:  advanced devices every day until it's okay if I
Speaker 4:  Come in until judge is like, fine, bring a Chromebook.
Speaker 5:  If I come in with like an e ink notebook that I can write on, is that electronics?
Speaker 5:  Like what are we doing? Are we good? If, if if I'm not touching the screen,
Speaker 5:  it's not drawing any power for you. A
Speaker 6:  Remarkable too and just be like, what? This
Speaker 5:  Is what I'm saying? Yeah.
Speaker 9:  Okay. So fun detail. When you go through the battle detector in the courtroom,
Speaker 9:  you have to take out all your cables.
Speaker 6:  Oh, this is, no, this
Speaker 9:  Not a fun place to be if you have as many cables as I do.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I was like, s Neli can never go there. No, I'm
Speaker 4:  Not allowed in there. That's not gonna happen. We are, we're again,
Speaker 4:  we're covering the how this trial, there's gonna be a bunch of big witnesses
Speaker 4:  on the stand. We're gonna get as much coverage to you as we can. I think
Speaker 4:  it, it's a big deal just because no one pays
Speaker 4:  attention to Google search. Like we have been running the series about Google
Speaker 4:  search and what it means, and Google turning 25 all year. We'll link it in
Speaker 4:  the show notes. David's Neva pieces in there. Our Google Reader piece is
Speaker 4:  in there. We have a bunch of ss e o stories coming about the culture of S
Speaker 4:  E O. I think they're gonna be really good. And what has been apparent in
Speaker 4:  doing those stories is that Google hates it when you talk about
Speaker 4:  search is anything other than like water. Yep. They're like, what searches
Speaker 4:  just the oxygen of the internet. It's just around you at all times. It keeps
Speaker 4:  us all healthy. And it's like, no, this is a business, a business that you
Speaker 4:  ruthlessly protect and instruct your people to never
Speaker 4:  discuss in words that sound ruthless. And I,
Speaker 4:  that gap I think is what this trial, even if the government loses
Speaker 4:  the trial, will narrow the gap in the perception of Google
Speaker 4:  search is just a benign thing that happens right. In a
Speaker 4:  very, very ruthlessly run business. And I say ruthless, I don't mean that
Speaker 4:  in a negative way. I think Google does a good job of running
Speaker 4:  its business and making a lot of cash on Google search and then funding a
Speaker 4:  bunch of shit. It shuts down two months later. Right, right. Like that's
Speaker 4:  the engine of Google it. It's basically, it's only business and then a little
Speaker 4:  bit of YouTube and then a little bit of Google Cloud. But like it's search
Speaker 4:  that funds a whole bunch of stuff. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And Google wants you to think about it as this like inevitable thing that
Speaker 5:  just sort of has to exist the way that it does in order for Yeah. The internet
Speaker 5:  to work like, like you're saying, it's, they want you to think it's water
Speaker 5:  and it is like a series of very specific choices that people made in
Speaker 5:  how this thing works. And if nothing else, we're going to learn a lot about
Speaker 5:  the choices. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And I, and we'll do it with Quill pens and parchment if you have
Speaker 4:  to. Okay. We gotta take a break. Addie, stick around. We're gonna take a
Speaker 4:  break when we come back. I need you and Alex to explain what is going on
Speaker 4:  with Unity To me. We'll be right
Speaker 4:  back.
Speaker 1:  cost. With the broadest and deepest application development capabilities
Speaker 1:  at your fingertips,
Speaker 6:  reach, like, if you sell enough product, then you're gonna have to
Speaker 6:  start paying them for every download. Every install. Yeah, every
Speaker 6:  install. So Monica and Allison are just gonna bankrupt companies
Speaker 6:  every time they review new products because
Speaker 4:  They install the games and all these phones that they review.
Speaker 6:  Right? So, so basically they, they've, they've walked some of it back. But
Speaker 6:  if you're making, I think if you're a, a smaller developer and you're making
Speaker 6:  like over 200,000 a year from your game, you're gonna have to start paying
Speaker 6:  these fees. And if you're a larger developer and I think it's over a million
Speaker 6:  a year, you're gonna have to start paying these fees. And these fees like
Speaker 6:  are fairly small.
Speaker 4:  What is the argument for per install fees?
Speaker 6:  Money,
Speaker 4:  But like, certainly as union made any argument that's not
Speaker 6:  No. This, that's part of the frustration here. The frustration is less about
Speaker 6:  the money being asked for because a lot of the Developers are
Speaker 6:  like, yeah, if this is a cost of doing business, that's a cost of doing business.
Speaker 6:  This was communicated to us in the worst way possible in the middle of an
Speaker 6:  like a big Apple event. It gets communicated. There was no
Speaker 6:  prep. Usually they'll go to like bigger Developers and be like, Hey, we're
Speaker 6:  thinking about charging you more money. None of that happened in this
Speaker 6:  case. And, and Unity is really like digging
Speaker 6:  in on this every single time we'd get another thing, we'd get another
Speaker 6:  report from a game developer saying, oh, we're gonna just delete our game
Speaker 6:  rather than have to pay this. Which is what the cult of Lamb Developers said.
Speaker 6:  I think they're still gonna keep their game up. But, and there are a
Speaker 9:  Couple of really specific big problems too. The first being that it's not
Speaker 9:  even necessarily clear how they track installs. That they're basically
Speaker 9:  saying, yeah, we have this model, it's totally data compliant with data
Speaker 9:  regulations. Totally not privacy. Invading also totally accurate. And also
Speaker 9:  it totally won't, if somebody decides they hate you and they want to run
Speaker 9:  a giant like route install bombing campaign to drive up your costs, it will
Speaker 9:  also totally not include that. But no one has really figured out exactly
Speaker 9:  what that means. And second, that installs are just not a thing that inherently
Speaker 9:  makes Developers money. So they're charging for this thing that doesn't actually
Speaker 9:  tie directly to revenue. Right.
Speaker 6:  And that's what's, that's what's got people pissed is this thing is just,
Speaker 6:  feels really, really egregious to them. It feels like it came on really,
Speaker 6:  really quickly and there's zero communication Unity's just saying,
Speaker 6:  yeah, we know you pay us every year to use our
Speaker 6:  engine. Now you have to pay us more. Oh, you've had this game you
Speaker 6:  developed on this engine for the last 10 years. We'll either learn a new
Speaker 6:  engine or cough up the cash. And that just feels like
Speaker 6:  extortion. It's not legally extortion, but it sure feels like it to
Speaker 6:  Developers.
Speaker 5:  How real do you think the threat is from all these Developers who are saying
Speaker 5:  basically we'll leave Unity instead of pay these fees.
Speaker 6:  Looking into that? I think it's, for a lot of 'em it's not realistic. If
Speaker 6:  you've got, I mean it's
Speaker 5:  Gotta be a gigantic amount of work.
Speaker 6:  It's a huge amount of work. So, so for most of them it's probably not realistic.
Speaker 6:  But Mo a lot of 'em are saying, well I'm never gonna develop in Unity again.
Speaker 6:  Sure. And I'll probably pull those games. Right. Life is long. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  If, if you're a big developer, you can afford to pull a game that's made
Speaker 6:  you a little money and you don't wanna pay anymore and go off and do something
Speaker 6:  else. So it's kind of wild that Unity
Speaker 6:  did this and the theories are, everybody's got a theory on why
Speaker 6:  they did it. The most common one is they like money, which is
Speaker 6:  fair. A lot of people think it might be because against an impact, which
Speaker 6:  is huge on mobile and makes a lot of money and,
Speaker 6:  and Unity would like some of that money
Speaker 5:  And has been established Alison Johnson downloads 650 times a year.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, very true. Yeah. So here's, here's a question I have. So you, you mentioned
Speaker 4:  the iPhone Addie Apple's pushing into spatial
Speaker 4:  computing with the Vision Pro. They basically need game
Speaker 4:  engines to make a bunch of Vision Pro stuff.
Speaker 6:  And Unity is core to that. Like Unity, right?
Speaker 4:  Unity is a big deal in that world. It's big meta and Apple hates Epic, which
Speaker 4:  makes the big competitor, right? Like Unreal is not gonna
Speaker 4:  show up on Apple platforms as the alternative to Unity.
Speaker 4:  Right?
Speaker 6:  Well
Speaker 4:  Anytime soon
Speaker 6:  Are different engines like Unity is better for Monument in
Speaker 6:  Valley and in smaller games like that, it's graphically intensive, but it's
Speaker 6:  not like that photorealism, you don't see that as often in Unity games as
Speaker 6:  you do in Unreal. Which makes sense because that's also less like taxing
Speaker 6:  to the processor, which is one of the reasons Unity is so popular. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  With Meta also because deals were made and stuff like that.
Speaker 9:  But it's still one of the relatively, you have fewer options for developing
Speaker 9:  three D and spatial games than you do for developing two D
Speaker 9:  games. And Unity is definitely one of the huge
Speaker 9:  three D options. Yeah. Because there are plenty of games that are three D
Speaker 9:  but not photo realistic including a lot of like VR games, right? Yeah.
Speaker 4:  So I'm just wondering is is in the midst of all of this, just turning the
Speaker 4:  screw one time, you've covered VR more than anybody that
Speaker 4:  I've ever met, this has some huge impact on how Apple's
Speaker 4:  relationship to Developers is gonna go as they roll out the Vision Pro, right?
Speaker 4:  Like if all the Developers are mad at the main engine, where else are they
Speaker 4:  gonna go?
Speaker 9:  It's a very good question and it's partly a question Ash is actually doing
Speaker 9:  reporting on right now. Like there are alternatives that you can use. One
Speaker 9:  of them is Gado, which is an open source engine, which is
Speaker 9:  very tiny and is very hard. But yeah,
Speaker 9:  it's, it's a good question whether that's a thing that makes Unity
Speaker 9:  feel like it can flex,
Speaker 4:  Right? That's kinda what I'm wondering. Like where's this leverage coming
Speaker 4:  from? Like if you're like, we're gonna piss off everyone,
Speaker 4:  usually it's because you can't, like you're Reddit. I was
Speaker 5:  Just gonna say, this is what Reddit
Speaker 4:  Did. Reddit's like, we need more money. We're gonna piss off everyone, but
Speaker 4:  But are you gonna go? Yeah. And they just waited and it's, some parts of
Speaker 4:  Reddit are still just a mess, but they just waited and it's
Speaker 4:  fine. 'cause where are you gonna go? Who's the competitor? And it, there's
Speaker 4:  just an echo of that in this Unity conversation. I'm especially as it relates
Speaker 4:  to iOS, because the thing that is the natural
Speaker 4:  competitor is at such odds with Apple at the corporate
Speaker 4:  level.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I'm gonna be really curious to see how Apple responds to this over
Speaker 6:  the next few weeks because it happened in the middle of their event. Like
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I wonder if Apple even knew as
Speaker 5:  Apple was talking so much about mobile gaming.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. It's just, it feels like, like I don't think Apple knew or that probably
Speaker 6:  wouldn't have happened that way. It's also not
Speaker 9:  Particularly good for Apple. Like it's not great for Apple if one of
Speaker 9:  the bottlenecks for their platform is suddenly taking a big fee from
Speaker 9:  Developers that Apple doesn't see part of.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Only Apple gets to take fees.
Speaker 4:  The Apple doesn't like money changing hands if it doesn't take 30% outta
Speaker 4:  that money. All right, well we're gonna keep covering it. It sounds like
Speaker 4:  Ash has a lot of reporting in the works. We'll put that on the site. It's
Speaker 4:  a big deal. Like Unity canceled events. There were death threats over this.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Which again, I will point out is inappropriate.
Speaker 6:  Don't do that.
Speaker 4:  Socos, that's, that's life on the internet for you. There's bunch of stuff
Speaker 4:  on the site that isn't Apple or the Google trial B'S just an
Speaker 4:  overhauled its entire lineup of headphones. The Spectra Fold is out, which
Speaker 4:  a foldable 17 ish pc, which is a very cool, Monica wrote that. Weird laptops.
Speaker 4:  I love a weird laptop. And the workers of the big three auto Makers on strike
Speaker 4:  this week, which Andy wrote about,
Speaker 5:  And a million new video games
Speaker 4:  And a million new video games intended to direct in the Sony state of play
Speaker 4:  this week as well. On top of that, it continues to be September,
Speaker 4:  just relentlessly. September. Ah, that's the name of my new
Speaker 4:  album Relentlessly September by Neli Patel. It's,
Speaker 4:  it's avant-garde, but I think you'll like it. We've had a bunch of events
Speaker 4:  coming up. The code conference is at the end of this month. Here's
Speaker 4:  the news. Virtual tickets for the code conference are now in sale. All the
Speaker 4:  main tickets are sold out. So you can, if you wanna watch the code conference,
Speaker 4:  go to Vox dot com slash code and you can sign up
Speaker 4:  for virtual ticket and stream the thing. Mike Krieger from Artifact is coming.
Speaker 4:  He's xct of Instagram now. The co-founder of Artifact, the news app
Speaker 4:  David just wrote about it. They, they rolled out links. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  They wanna be like the, the place to share cool stuff on the internet. 'cause
Speaker 5:  Twitter used to be that and now Twitter's dead.
Speaker 4:  And we, we love that. So Casey's gonna talk about Mike about that. And
Speaker 4:  then, I dunno if you even pay attention to little company called
Speaker 4:  Disney. Lots of weirdness in Disney World
Speaker 4:  and lots of Liz, Disney World, lots of weirdness. And
Speaker 5:  Mickey Mouse is coming to Code
Speaker 4:  Disney. Bob Iger has been hinting that he might sell a, b, c,
Speaker 4:  get rid of a bunch of stuff. Partner with E S P N, all this stuff. Byron
Speaker 4:  Allen, who is the owner of the company that owns the Weather Channel, we
Speaker 4:  invited him. 'cause they're doing a bunch of AI stuff on the Weather channel,
Speaker 4:  climate change, ai, whole thing. It turns out he wants to buy a B,
Speaker 4:  C for $10 billion. It's
Speaker 6:  Like him and Next Star. Yeah. So both of them are are
Speaker 6:  smaller companies. They're less known for for Yeah. Being Disney.
Speaker 6:  They're not Disney, but it's a big deal.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. So Julia Worton's gonna interview by Allen about, well,
Speaker 4:  what we thought was gonna be about using AI to
Speaker 6:  Now it's all abc, all
Speaker 4:  People local communities deal with climate change. But now we're gonna talk
Speaker 4:  about whether or not he's gonna buy a, B, C. There's a bunch of other great
Speaker 4:  speakers. I'm excited about it.
Speaker 5:  Also, next week we have Microsoft event and an Amazon event. Yeah. 'cause
Speaker 5:  this just does not stop.
Speaker 4:  And there's a YouTube event
Speaker 5:  And a YouTube event. Oh, wow. That made by YouTube.
Speaker 4:  There's a calendar. We'll put it in the show notes. We, we made a calendar
Speaker 4:  so you can just subscribe to it and then you can follow all the events with
Speaker 4:  us. It's gonna be a crazy month. We're excited about it. Okay. That's it.
Speaker 4:  That's The. Vergecast. We've gone far over. You're looking at me expectantly.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  We're we're just, we're we're just vibing. Liam is looking at me expectantly.
Speaker 5:  I
Speaker 4:  Have to look at you. You expectantly. See You know. It's like a Tero prism
Speaker 4:  of glares. That's it. That's Vergecast Rock and
Speaker 4:  roll.
Speaker 5:  And that's a wrap
Speaker 8:  For Vergecast this week. We'd love to hear from you. Shoot us an email at
Speaker 8:  Vergecast at The Verge dot com. The Vergecast is a production of The Verge
Speaker 8:  and the Vox Media Podcast Network. The show is produced by me, Liam James,
Speaker 8:  and our senior audio director, Andrew Marino. Our editorial director is Brooke
Speaker 8:  Miners. That's it. We'll see you next
Speaker 8:  week.
Speaker 3:  Support for this episode comes from Zelle. You'd never
Speaker 3:  fall for an online scam. Right. You use
Speaker 3:  two-factor authentication. Ignore calls from everyone
Speaker 3:  named spam risk and never use the
Speaker 3:  password. Password. But scammers
Speaker 3:  are getting more sophisticated and more active, which means they're finding
Speaker 3:  millions of new victims every single year.
Speaker 3:  The good news is that there's a lot you can do to protect yourself on the
Speaker 3:  Wild, wild Web. For starters, Zelle wants to
Speaker 3:  remind you only send money to people You know and
Speaker 3:  trust. Zelle is available to United States Bank account holders only
Speaker 3:  terms and conditions
Speaker 3:  apply.
Speaker 1:  Support for this episode comes from Amazon Web
Speaker 1:  Services. Your applications are the cornerstone of
Speaker 1:  your business. So how are you staying ahead with a
Speaker 1:  w s? You can innovate without limits. A w S
Speaker 1:  provides extensive, reliable, and secure
Speaker 1:  infrastructure designed to deliver the best performance at
Speaker 1:  an optimal cost. With the broadest and deepest application
Speaker 1:  development capabilities at your fingertips, you can reimagine every
Speaker 1:  application. Innovate without limits. learn more
Speaker 1:  at go.aws/aea.