# Transcript
ID: 61c25f0d-2ca8-4dec-9002-2728e3287bdb
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: The future of EV charging and Hollywood on strike
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-1223786807224350091/7553522564110988477/s93290-US-5483s-1689933421.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, Alex Cranz, and David Pierce discuss all the gadget news from this week, the state of EV charging for non-Tesla owners, the unions of Hollywood on strike, and much more.
Speaker 3:  Hello, I'm Esther Perel. I'm a psychotherapist and host of
Speaker 3:  the podcast. Where should we begin? I invite you to
Speaker 3:  enter into my office and to listen in on the sessions
Speaker 3:  that I conduct with people from all walks of life,
Speaker 3:  grappling with the challenges and choices in their
Speaker 3:  relationships. Join me in my office every
Speaker 3:  Monday morning for a new episode. Listen and
Speaker 3:  follow. Where should we begin on your favorite podcast
Speaker 3:  app?
Speaker 4:  Hello and welcome to the Vercast Flagship podcast of Windshield
Speaker 4:  wipers, intermittent fast speed, the little nozzles
Speaker 4:  that spray. We're gonna get into it all on this episode of The Vergecast.
Speaker 4:  They work and every episode of The Vergecast from here on out,
Speaker 5:  We're pivoting guys. We're actually pivoting. It's
Speaker 4:  What's your favorite brand of washer fluid call the hotline.
Speaker 5:  Is it just Windex?
Speaker 4:  Does anyone have a favorite brand? Actually, I'm dying to know. Is there
Speaker 4:  an iOS versus Android of windshield washer fluid?
Speaker 5:  A hundred percent. There is a hundred percent.
Speaker 4:  Email us. No, no,
Speaker 1:  No. Sorry. Just email nili specifically. Please don't email any of the rest
Speaker 1:  of us.
Speaker 4:  The, the Rain X fan Boys are coming. Hi, I'm your friend. Neli.
Speaker 4:  That's David Pierce. Hi. Alex. Cranz is
Speaker 5:  Here. I'm also here. I think just Windex is fine. Like I think you just
Speaker 5:  pour that in. It's, it's okay.
Speaker 4:  Just raw Windex. Just
Speaker 5:  Raw Windex. Just that raw. I feel like a mechanic once told me never do
Speaker 5:  that. But I also think he's not here. And I don't remember his name,
Speaker 5:  so it's probably fine. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  If you forget a guy, what he said is definitely wrong.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, that's how this works.
Speaker 4:  All right, well go ahead and pour some raw Windex into your windshield foot.
Speaker 4:  I'm just trying to, like, on Instagram threads the other day, you know the
Speaker 4:  platform is rife with engagement. Ba Adam Sary straight up was like, Android
Speaker 4:  is better than iOS. In response to Marquez, Brownley a
Speaker 4:  million responses. I put that in a quick post on our site
Speaker 4:  just to make a joke about Instagram engagement bait being out of
Speaker 4:  control. And then that post got 40 comments about
Speaker 4:  Android versus iOS. It's, it's just the easiest thing we can
Speaker 4:  do. I'll say it right now. Android's better than iOS. Leave a comment on
Speaker 4:  YouTube. Boost that algo. It works every time. I
Speaker 4:  got you. I'm just saying is does that exist for windshield
Speaker 4:  washer fluid?
Speaker 5:  It has to
Speaker 4:  Because it exists for things like blenders. you
Speaker 5:  Know, it exists,
Speaker 4:  Has shark versus Vitamix. You can get into it.
Speaker 5:  It exists for like car leather cleaner,
Speaker 4:  I, Meg Wes versus
Speaker 5:  Something else. Maybe follow some, some car detailers, and
Speaker 5:  it's like ASMR for me. It's just like, oh, that's so soothing. And they're
Speaker 5:  like, this is the one you want to use. Somebody tells you another one. It's
Speaker 5:  garbage
Speaker 6:  Alex. Are you talking about the videos where they, they do the like super
Speaker 6:  cut of them just like wiping all the dirt off the cars. you
Speaker 6:  know, those are always like six different cars that they do that to. And
Speaker 6:  it's just a full lie. No, this
Speaker 5:  Is always one car.
Speaker 6:  No, no. You're just being lied to the thing. Alex, I'm really sorry to be
Speaker 6:  the one to break this to. Oh,
Speaker 4:  David is finally like, it's all the same. Both operating systems are the
Speaker 4:  same. Yeah. Here's what I want. I want a list of
Speaker 4:  vitriolic consumer product debates. So you got, you
Speaker 4:  got your Xbox versus PlayStation. That's N number one.
Speaker 4:  Dan, I think number two is iOS versus
Speaker 4:  Android. Miele versus I think Windows. Windows versus Mac has actually
Speaker 4:  fallen off. I think that's like, no one cares anymore. Like you walk into
Speaker 4:  a, a room full of people using Windows and you're like, I have a Mac. And
Speaker 4:  everyone's like, we know.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. They all just sort of shook hands and walked away. Like I think that's,
Speaker 6:  that's basically over. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Like they all have iPhones.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, but
Speaker 5:  I think Miele versus Dyson, I would say that's probably one. Oh, that's good.
Speaker 5:  I feel like people have strong opinions about which $600 vacuum cleaner.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. They came for
Speaker 4:  And all of them are far outdone by sharks. I'm just letting you know.
Speaker 4:  All right. That's enough of this. It's
Speaker 5:  The Linux of
Speaker 4:  Vacuums. But I, I'm dying to know this is your engagement bait homework.
Speaker 4:  Leave it in a comment on the, on the post, on the CI or on YouTube or wherever
Speaker 4:  you're listening. What's your number one silly
Speaker 4:  consumer product battle? And you can't pick iOS versus Android. You can't
Speaker 4:  pick Xbox versus PlayStation or Windows versus Mac. We know, we know.
Speaker 4:  No Marvel
Speaker 5:  Versus dc. That's
Speaker 4:  Not, is that even a fight? No,
Speaker 6:  It's just Marvel versus Zack Snyder's box of
Speaker 6:  movie
Speaker 5:  Supergirls. Cool.
Speaker 4:  I got a, I got a reply on Threads. It was like, dude really said at and t
Speaker 4:  screwed up its network to make Grace Scale. Justice League. And. I was like,
Speaker 4:  sure did. Yep. A hundred percent said that. No regret fully stand by it.
Speaker 5:  It's true too. It's still true.
Speaker 6:  Liam, our producer has been begging for us to do a segment
Speaker 6:  called Verge Debates. Ooh, where we just put people on
Speaker 6:  different sides of an argument and make them fight to the death about different
Speaker 6:  things. So if, if everyone sends us enough of these
Speaker 6:  Holy Wars in the tech industry to fight about, Liam's gonna get to launch
Speaker 6:  this show and he's gonna be so happy. So please send them to us first. casters.com.
Speaker 6:  Send them all. We will fight about them. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Or, or in the YouTube comments or on the site. You already have comments.
Speaker 4:  Send it to five of your friends and have them comment too. Let's make this
Speaker 4:  go viral. you know, like can ring that bell. Is that
Speaker 4:  what the kids say? It's horrible. All right. There's a lot to talk about
Speaker 4:  this week. Starting of course with the latest photo of the Cybertruck
Speaker 4:  wiper, which we'll get to. That's how this all started.
Speaker 4:  There's new beat Studio Pro headphones that are really interesting. Actually.
Speaker 4:  There's some charging news from Tesla. Really interesting Laptop comparisons
Speaker 4:  for Monica that we should get into. Then Hollywood's on strike. Yep.
Speaker 5:  No movies
Speaker 4:  Because of streaming services. It just says TREE LAW and all capital letters.
Speaker 4:  And the rundown here. Dying to know what that means. Netflix had earnings,
Speaker 4:  then we got a lightning round. So's sorry. Some gadgets. It's been a minute
Speaker 4:  since we just sat in Gadget World. What do you think? Start with the Beats.
Speaker 6:  Let's do Beats first. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I'm fascinated by these headphones. Me too.
Speaker 5:  Why? I'm not Please explain.
Speaker 6:  Okay, Cranz here. Here's the, here's the big question. I've been debating
Speaker 6:  for like 36 hours now since I first saw this review. So the thing about these
Speaker 6:  headphones, they're the Beats Studio Pro headphones. They're Beats latest
Speaker 6:  over the ear headphones. They have some cool upgrades. They have transparency
Speaker 6:  mode. They have Lossless U S B C audio. They look
Speaker 6:  exactly the same as the old beads, headphones. And Chris
Speaker 6:  Welch who wrote a review, it's very good. We'll put it in the show notes.
Speaker 6:  You can feel him in this review trying to decide if that's a good thing or
Speaker 6:  a bad thing. That it's like, there's nothing wrong with this design, but
Speaker 6:  they look like the old headphones. Is that bad?
Speaker 6:  And I. Wanna know what you guys think? Like, I think this is Beats is a very
Speaker 6:  good design. They make good headphones like LeBron James wears them. That's
Speaker 6:  all great. Beats has good reasons for not changing it. Is this like an old
Speaker 6:  design that needs to die or once you nail it, do you just never mess with
Speaker 6:  it again?
Speaker 5:  Ooh. That's interesting. Okay. Nevermind. These are interesting, right? I
Speaker 5:  like, I wanna debate that,
Speaker 4:  That cause the feature set is really wild for
Speaker 4:  Apple. Apple supporting Lossless u s BBC
Speaker 4:  audio is bonkers
Speaker 6:  And it natively supports both iOS and Android. So it is in
Speaker 6:  most ways, feature wise, this is the best pair of headphones Apple
Speaker 6:  makes. Yeah. Like hands
Speaker 4:  Down. But, but do you know where you, what You can't get lossless u s BBC
Speaker 4:  audio off of an iPhone.
Speaker 4:  Like
Speaker 5:  What
Speaker 4:  About adapters? It's a, it's just a wild feature for them to support on these
Speaker 4:  headphones. But I'm utterly fascinated by the fact that Beats exists.
Speaker 4:  Apple has stuck with it. It's obviously a big market because they
Speaker 4:  sell so many phones to Android users and they are catering to Android users
Speaker 4:  with this sub-brand and they're building features that are
Speaker 4:  just off to the side of everything they're doing
Speaker 4:  with headphones in Apple. Well that's
Speaker 5:  How they, they get you in. You're like, wow, I really love the
Speaker 4:  Usbc. I don't I don't think you buy these headphones for, for Lossless U
Speaker 4:  US bbc. I'm the only person who's gonna buy them. It's me and The Vergecast
Speaker 4:  team. That's correct. That's the listener. We now call the listeners part
Speaker 4:  of the Team Vergecast listeners, And I are going to buy these headphones
Speaker 4:  for Lossless u uss BBC audio. No one jumps from there to a pair of
Speaker 4:  AirPods with utterly compressed Bluetooth audio. Like that's
Speaker 4:  not the path. So it's just the features here are going this
Speaker 4:  way. Well, Apple's doing spatial audio this way and it's, it's
Speaker 4:  Beats gets to be its own little thing. And I think they maybe just don't
Speaker 4:  have designers or Apple doesn't want to pay the money
Speaker 4:  for new tooling on the headphones. Or
Speaker 6:  There's nothing wrong with the design. Don't change it. Like,
Speaker 6:  like look at the pictures of these headphones and tell me what's wrong with
Speaker 6:  the design. Other than I've seen this before on an older pair of, of headphones.
Speaker 5:  I mean they look like beets and beets are inherently kind of ugly. And I
Speaker 5:  associate with cheapness. Because remember when the Beats used to stick weights
Speaker 5:  in there before Apple owned them, they'd stick weights in. Yeah. To make
Speaker 5:  'em more expensive. So that like, but you didn't change that after that happened.
Speaker 5:  so like at this point, beets as beets, that's the brand. I kinda like that
Speaker 5:  they didn't change it cuz like REOs and nobody's out there being
Speaker 5:  like, why aren't the REOs getting a whole new redesign? Yeah.
Speaker 6:  They're like made of wood and people like, well they sound good. That's fine.
Speaker 5:  Carved differently. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I think, I think Apple doesn't want these to get too much attention.
Speaker 4:  I I, I think they, they bought Beats for the music streaming service that
Speaker 4:  turned into Apple Music. They inherited a headphone company and
Speaker 4:  turning off free money is just, it's against everything Tim Cook stands for
Speaker 4:  in this world. And so if you can just like upgrade the headphones and keep
Speaker 4:  selling 'em at high margins inside the same case and what really what you've
Speaker 4:  changed is some chips and some software, you're gonna keep doing that
Speaker 4:  forever. Like I think that's what's happening here. But I, does Apple want
Speaker 4:  Beats to be a world conquering success? Like absolutely not.
Speaker 4:  They want AirPods Max to be a world conquering success. And it's probably
Speaker 4:  time. I bet they change the design of the AirPods Max before they change
Speaker 4:  design of Beats to
Speaker 5:  A hundred percent. But that's,
Speaker 6:  That's all interesting and probably true. But that's like a, that's a business
Speaker 6:  story, right? Does that make the headphones
Speaker 6:  worse in any meaning? Like should you not buy these headphones as a
Speaker 6:  result of that? That to me is really the question.
Speaker 5:  No, you should still buy 'em. I mean I personally think they're ugly, but
Speaker 5:  I would never buy them.
Speaker 6:  But you would've thought that about the last generation. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I would've thought that about every generation. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  You're just not a Beats person. But
Speaker 5:  If you're, if you are a Beats person, I don't see why you should be like,
Speaker 5:  oh man, I really want, like, I want 'em to look more like Apple headphones
Speaker 5:  or Sony or something. Like, Sony changes theirs every few years and they're
Speaker 5:  always,
Speaker 4:  I'm skipping this generation. Okay, And I gotta wait like five years to
Speaker 5:  Upgrade my Sony bought this generation at an airport Texas
Speaker 5:  place cuz I was going on a trip. That's how they get you And. I got on the
Speaker 5:  plane and the battery on 'em is dead. Oh
Speaker 6:  No,
Speaker 5:  That's right. And, I can't return them because it was the airplane port.
Speaker 5:  That's right. So I gotta go deal with that. But they're terrible. But yeah,
Speaker 5:  like I bought 'em because the sound was better. I didn't really
Speaker 5:  care about the look of them.
Speaker 4:  Sure. And they're on your head. Yeah. It's, it's actually very hard to see
Speaker 4:  headphones that you are wearing. True. It's just one of those
Speaker 4:  facts. But look, these headphones are all really expensive. These are three
Speaker 4:  50 bucks. That 350 bucks has gotten you better and better
Speaker 4:  build quality over the years. So the Sonys that we
Speaker 4:  all talk about, the bows that we all talk about, the quiet comforts the money
Speaker 4:  has gotten you better headphones, better build quality, better materials
Speaker 4:  year on year. And with Beats it's like here they
Speaker 4:  are. The finish gets fingerprints on them the same as they ever did
Speaker 4:  to. I just think that to me, the discrepancy in the two
Speaker 4:  apple headphone ecosystems is utterly fascinating.
Speaker 5:  I love it.
Speaker 4:  And I. I think the reason the materials are have stayed, they're not cheap
Speaker 4:  but stayed cheap to manufacture because they're already manufactured at
Speaker 4:  scale is cuz Tim Cook is like 70%
Speaker 4:  margins. Let's go. That's why
Speaker 5:  I, that's why I like it. It's so indicative. Yeah. Of like
Speaker 5:  Tim Cook's Apple. Like Steve Jobs never would've let this happen,
Speaker 4:  Do you think? He says, let's go in meeting, let's go.
Speaker 5:  He doesn't like in the Mario Voice,
Speaker 4:  I would pay $1 million to hear Tim Cook do the Mario
Speaker 4:  voice.
Speaker 5:  Same.
Speaker 4:  Just putting that out there. I don't, I don't have it, you know, but I'll
Speaker 4:  get it.
Speaker 5:  We'll figure it out. We'll crowdfund that.
Speaker 4:  All right. Let's talk about some laptops real quick. Lots of Laptop news
Speaker 4:  this week. Shawn got to play at the Framework Laptop 16, which is the Framework
Speaker 4:  Laptop that has a discreet replaceable gpu. That's
Speaker 4:  really something
Speaker 6:  Everyone should go watch that video that he made and read his story by the
Speaker 6:  way. Because the joy that man felt in using this
Speaker 6:  computer was so wonderful. It's very cool. I mean the, the
Speaker 6:  Framework Laptop 16 is like the most modular Laptop I've ever seen.
Speaker 6:  Right. And and it's big thing is you can actually can is can we make modular
Speaker 6:  a verb? You can modular in a discreet
Speaker 6:  gpu and that's big and exciting and it seems to work and it's very cool.
Speaker 6:  But like you can just feel Sean being like, this is the computer I have been
Speaker 6:  dreaming of for so many years. And I mean it's, it just makes me so happy.
Speaker 6:  Everyone should go read that story and watch the video.
Speaker 5:  I like that it doesn't, for a while there, there were modular laptops
Speaker 5:  kind of like the area 51 m and, and a bunch of like
Speaker 5:  origin and, and folks would make their own versions and they all looked the
Speaker 5:  exact same. And that's, they were very deeply ugly and this one looks like
Speaker 5:  a nicer iteration of that. Yeah, it looks
Speaker 6:  Like a Laptop. Like who was to Framework for doing a good job of making a
Speaker 6:  modular Laptop that looks like a Laptop
Speaker 5:  But not like a gaming, like a cheap gaming Laptop. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Like for a while there all the modular ones look like cheap gaming laptops
Speaker 5:  and now it's like, oh, I mean this is still not the most attractive thing
Speaker 5:  in the world. But that's what you, that's the exchange. You do, you get
Speaker 5:  modular, it's a little less attractive.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, yeah. Your GPU is two feet long and it weighs a hundred pounds. Like
Speaker 6:  you don't have, you're not gonna make an attractive computer out of that,
Speaker 6:  but, but that's okay. The, it is what it is and they seem to have
Speaker 6:  gotten almost everything else about it. Right. Which I think is very cool.
Speaker 6:  Yes. Framework in general I think is like a company worth rooting for for
Speaker 6:  a lot of reasons. And I think continues to be delivering
Speaker 6:  on the thing that it said it was going to do and a lot of people didn't think
Speaker 6:  it could pull off And I. Just think that's cool.
Speaker 4:  Let me just read you this sentence in response to that Sure statement. David,
Speaker 4:  this is Sean. My only regret is, I can't give you any idea how well it works
Speaker 4:  because Framework broke the fans on the only GPU module in the United
Speaker 4:  States. It's, it's fine prototypes. We were only
Speaker 4:  able to run a few smooth minutes of Eldon ring before the system began
Speaker 4:  throttling itself due to the utter lack of cooling.
Speaker 6:  I did enjoy that. The game was so sick and then I burned my house
Speaker 6:  down.
Speaker 4:  So they, they're shipping another one from
Speaker 4:  Taiwan. I'm just saying it's still a very complicated
Speaker 4:  problem. Yes. It's a very cool,
Speaker 6:  It is very I mean and cooling. That was a good pun. You just did by accident
Speaker 6:  there because the cooling seems to be the thing. And Sean actually talked
Speaker 6:  to one of the people who worked on the area 51 M and the big
Speaker 6:  thing is like, how do we get a GPU into this computer and
Speaker 6:  keep it and the computer cool. And so Framework has a different idea about,
Speaker 6:  you know, putting the fans in with the gpu. But that is
Speaker 6:  the question. Like that is the thing to solve to make this thing work. And
Speaker 6:  you're right Neil, we have not successfully actually seen this thing work
Speaker 6:  yet. Yeah, but I'm, I'm still hopeful. Let me have this, it's good progress.
Speaker 4:  Well there's two things. There's one, does this one work and then
Speaker 4:  there's the whole point of making the
Speaker 4:  discrete GPU with a connector work, which is then you
Speaker 4:  will sell me a new GPU in the future. And
Speaker 4:  that is, I would say an 80% commitment.
Speaker 4:  80, 85. Now it's a vibes commitment,
Speaker 4:  not a we will sell you a GPU that uses this connector and
Speaker 4:  works in this Laptop in
Speaker 5:  The future. I think it's, it's notable that he talks a lot about the area
Speaker 5:  51 in in this and that one also promised to
Speaker 5:  me and a lot of other folks that was gonna have replaceable GPUs
Speaker 5:  and people actually tried to file a class action lawsuit because
Speaker 5:  the, the GPU never came. They couldn't do it. They've all settled out of
Speaker 5:  court in arbitration. But like it's a hard project and, and if
Speaker 5:  the companies of AMD Nvidia OEMs have zero
Speaker 5:  desire to do it, it's not gonna happen. And right now they
Speaker 5:  have some, some desire. Yeah, a little bit, a little bit of its
Speaker 6:  Design. Well and and part of the reason that like Framework is because it
Speaker 6:  is, it's a place those companies can put that desire, if that makes sense.
Speaker 6:  Like it is, it is the one company actually sort of pushing on this so
Speaker 6:  that if you want to do this and you are an executive at AMD or
Speaker 6:  Nvidia or one of these companies, you actually have a partner with which
Speaker 6:  to spin up a project on some of this stuff. And so much of this kind of stuff
Speaker 6:  that we've seen, this just makes me think of like, you know, the project
Speaker 6:  Aura at, at,
Speaker 4:  I knew, I knew we were coming back to
Speaker 6:  Project Ara, my favorite gadget of all time. I will die on the hill of Project
Speaker 6:  Aura. And I. Guess I'm already dead cuz it died a long time ago. But anyway,
Speaker 6:  it's
Speaker 5:  Very
Speaker 6:  Dead. It was like these things have just sort of been one off
Speaker 6:  Skunk works in there. And I think just the fact that Framework exists and
Speaker 6:  is selling real products to real people puts that further along.
Speaker 6:  It's not gonna work forever.
Speaker 5:  Dell was doing it. Alienware was doing it and there was all these other
Speaker 5:  smaller OEMs who were trying to promise the same thing. This was like
Speaker 5:  2019 was the last time we saw this And I think it's no mistake that like
Speaker 5:  heavily involved in this project is amd is Frank Azer who was
Speaker 5:  at Dell at the time right? And was spearheading that for
Speaker 5:  Alienware. And it's a hard, like the, the cooling is a hard pro
Speaker 5:  problem that he gets into here. And it's one that they are always pretty
Speaker 5:  reluctant to overcome because these GPUs are just getting hotter and they're
Speaker 5:  getting bigger and, and who like nobody wants to be like, okay,
Speaker 5:  well we made a run as good as last year's, but it can go in your replaceable
Speaker 5:  Laptop. Like that's a bad buy for people. So how do they get, like they have
Speaker 5:  to think from the ground up about that heat situation. And
Speaker 5:  that I think is gonna be really tricky to get Nvidia and Am MD to do,
Speaker 5:  even with Frank Asher's involvement in this project.
Speaker 4:  And I. I also think there's just a good utility for Framework to exist for
Speaker 4:  almost all these companies because right to repair laws are not going away.
Speaker 4:  Yep. They are bipartisan, they're showing up. People want them.
Speaker 4:  Europe continues to exist somewhat befuddling, they seem to
Speaker 4:  want things all the time. I, I don't know, I dunno what's going on over there.
Speaker 5:  They got feelings about laws
Speaker 4:  And here's this company that has made the most right to repair product. And
Speaker 4:  so I think there's, there's a value in Framework continuing to
Speaker 4:  iterate and like pushing the industry forward even if the products aren't
Speaker 4:  successful or whatever. Because at some point the demand
Speaker 4:  for everyone else to figure it out is going to be there. I
Speaker 5:  Mean, if it gets successful, that's, that's the win, right?
Speaker 5:  Like if this thing gets any market share beyond
Speaker 5:  like two people buying it, Shawn and myself, that that's,
Speaker 5:  that's a win because that means, oh, there's actual appetite and everybody
Speaker 5:  else is gonna be like, oh, maybe I sh everybody besides Apple, apple will
Speaker 5:  never ever do this. Just, just Apple
Speaker 4:  Won't admit that GPUs exist. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It's,
Speaker 4:  They're like, no, no,
Speaker 5:  Never hap
Speaker 4:  You'd be quiet now.
Speaker 5:  But like I could see a Lenovo or an HP being like, yeah, let's,
Speaker 4:  Let's, so let's talk. So, well two things. One, in order for you and Sean
Speaker 4:  to buy the Laptop, they need more than zero functional GPU U
Speaker 5:  In the United States.
Speaker 4:  So that's a big, that's step one. Like guess a time. How do we sell two?
Speaker 4:  We need two like business 1 0 1 2. Let's talk
Speaker 4:  about the flip side of it, which is Monica's Laptop piece this week comparing
Speaker 4:  the HP Spectre x 360 to the, the Dell
Speaker 4:  XPS 13. This is the other side of Laptop world,
Speaker 4:  like tiny, highly integrated jewel like Windows
Speaker 4:  laptops. These
Speaker 6:  Are the MacBook Air competitors are, these are the MacBook Air competitors,
Speaker 6:  the, the pe the the random people in your life who say, what computers should
Speaker 6:  I buy? It's these two and the MacBook Air are like the three go-to answers
Speaker 6:  in the world that exist.
Speaker 5:  Ooh,
Speaker 4:  I will say that she was like, she did a versus article and gave them both
Speaker 4:  an eight. It's a good talk about it. There's your engagement
Speaker 4:  be I would just looking at this,
Speaker 4:  I I would lean Spectre. I, I think HP is on a track here that's
Speaker 4:  really fascinating and the screen is 3.2. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  I like that. HP is always willing to like do
Speaker 5:  weird stuff in their Laptop designs. They have been for a while
Speaker 5:  now. Remember when they did like wooden laptops, like they had wooden
Speaker 5:  Palm rests. Yes. I love it. I like get quirky. It's
Speaker 5:  fun.
Speaker 6:  No disagree. Get quirky over there and then just
Speaker 6:  make a Laptop. That is good because the Windows world is
Speaker 6:  like severely short on laptops that are just good. But
Speaker 6:  Nili, while we're talking about this HP Laptop, can I read you a sentence?
Speaker 6:  Yes. Here is the whole sentence. I average just over four hours
Speaker 6:  from continuous use of this OLED device. Four hours.
Speaker 4:  That's just Windows Laptop world man.
Speaker 6:  That is honestly, I, I believe to my bones that that is an
Speaker 6:  unacceptable amount of battery life in the year 2023. Like that's
Speaker 6:  so, so, so bad. And this to me is like where
Speaker 6:  Apple has just absolutely lapped everybody. Like the the
Speaker 6:  Spectre in particular that moniker viewed is, is beautiful. The
Speaker 6:  screen is great. The speakers seem to be good. The video chat stuff is fine.
Speaker 6:  It has some nifty features. Four hours is not enough. Four hours
Speaker 6:  is like I take out my computer when the wifi
Speaker 6:  starts on my flight from DC to San Francisco and it's dead before I get to
Speaker 6:  San Francisco. And that doesn't work. Yeah. That's just not,
Speaker 6:  it's, it's a deal breaker for me. And that kills me that that is still the
Speaker 6:  thing that holds back so many of these Windows computers.
Speaker 5:  How much of it can be designed out of, right, like, like Apple. The
Speaker 5:  reason the Apple battery life is so good is because Apple controls every
Speaker 5:  single element of it, including the processor so they can have it all work
Speaker 5:  together really, really well. Everybody else is using to some extent off
Speaker 5:  the shelf parts. Like they have to work with Intel or am amd to
Speaker 5:  get those processors that work really, really well and then have all the
Speaker 5:  like and windows and whatever the battery manufacturer is. Like that's a
Speaker 5:  lot more complex. This is not me supporting vertical integration, but it
Speaker 5:  has resulted in a lovely Laptop like
Speaker 4:  What if Microsoft made its own laptops, would they get better Battery life?
Speaker 5:  Is the surface battery life good?
Speaker 4:  The surface Laptop Yeah. Has different chips.
Speaker 5:  That's right. They do.
Speaker 4:  So these are, these are, it's older, but I, I think Monica
Speaker 4:  got like 11 hours from like a rise ship. Okay. In a surface
Speaker 4:  Laptop the last time. Ooh. But that's, it's, it's rough. Yeah. Right.
Speaker 4:  It's like it's better
Speaker 5:  Than the
Speaker 4:  HP. It's like saying your Honda Civic, it gets better gas mileage than your
Speaker 4:  p Like, it, it's, it's just like hard to compare. It's, but you're right,
Speaker 4:  the problem is the same, right? Yeah. The things are not engineered together.
Speaker 4:  And, I, it's tough even for Microsoft, but it, it, it is more fully
Speaker 4:  down to AMD and Intel than it is to
Speaker 4:  Windows. Yeah. And I think this is, and that's my read of it.
Speaker 6:  This is where you can lay most of the blame at Intel's feet. Like in a, in
Speaker 6:  a super real way, right? It's like it is possible for these other devices
Speaker 6:  to get good battery life and run windows, but they come with all these
Speaker 6:  other sacrifices like you're talking about such that Intel has spent
Speaker 6:  so long making sure it is like the Windows thing, like
Speaker 6:  everything good about Windows is is made with Intel in mind
Speaker 6:  and Intel just can't hack it battery lifewise
Speaker 6:  anymore. It just can't. And it just needs to get its crap together.
Speaker 6:  And it
Speaker 5:  Even switched its philosophy on how it designs these things. And
Speaker 5:  it's still so far Ha far
Speaker 4:  Behind. Oh man, okay. I just looked it up. Okay,
Speaker 5:  How
Speaker 4:  About that Surface Laptop fourth an AMD chip. Okay, that was 10 hours and
Speaker 4:  52 minutes. The new one that Monica just reviewed
Speaker 4:  with an Intel chip. Seven hours and 51 minutes.
Speaker 5:  We can't be going backwards guys. No. Like I have to give up
Speaker 5:  my headphone jack. I have to give things up in the name of progress.
Speaker 5:  Where is my progress that I'm gaining in losing battery life? This
Speaker 4:  Is what I'm, when I say the Windows versus Mac debate, it's like it's just
Speaker 4:  fallen off the list. Like you can walk into the Windows Users
Speaker 4:  club with your Mac Laptop and they're like, we know your battery life. Shut
Speaker 4:  up. We have, we have GPUs. I get 10 minutes
Speaker 4:  from the Nvidia gpu.
Speaker 6:  The frustrating part is like, I actually think you can have a really interesting
Speaker 6:  like Windows versus Mac os debate. Like Richard Lawler
Speaker 6:  on our team will occasionally just show up in Slack and drop 650 consecutive
Speaker 6:  messages about how annoying he finds Mac Os because it doesn't
Speaker 6:  do anything. You have to like download apps if you wanna move windows around.
Speaker 6:  And he's right about that. Like Windows is a much
Speaker 4:  More
Speaker 6:  Capable in certain ways operating system than Mac
Speaker 6:  os is. You can have that debate, but like Apple just makes better laptops
Speaker 6:  and it's not close. Like it's it's probably still true that a like
Speaker 6:  hack and to MacBook Air is the best Windows Laptop at the moment. It is
Speaker 6:  harder to do
Speaker 4:  That now. It's harder to do that. And you still have crap battery life.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, but it's so do my Windows computer,
Speaker 4:  Whatever. I'm just taking, I'm taking a spectra. I'm buying an anchor USB
Speaker 4:  battery. That's my look at these laptops. They're beautiful. You have not
Speaker 4:  checked on the state of Windows laptops and you, you, you think
Speaker 4:  they're still where they were? I just go look at Monica's
Speaker 4:  comparison to these two laptops. Look, they are beautiful. Like Apple should
Speaker 4:  boost some ideas from these hardware designs
Speaker 4:  where Apple just has the opportunity is like the chips make
Speaker 4:  the MacBook carrier is just a, a wi wisp of a thing now. But
Speaker 4:  these computers are absolutely beautiful and yeah,
Speaker 6:  This Spectra has these like gold accents and this like soft touch thing.
Speaker 6:  Go. It's lovely. It's beautiful. Very end of this computer
Speaker 4:  And for the 20 minutes you can use it if we have to plug it into your
Speaker 4:  10,000 mil
Speaker 5:  Battery. Should we talk about speaking of impractical? Yes. Have you
Speaker 5:  have you, you've, you've looked at it, the, the
Speaker 5:  Tesla
Speaker 6:  Speaking of him.
Speaker 4:  That's good. That was a good segue.
Speaker 6:  That's very good. You've
Speaker 5:  Looked at the window, the windshield
Speaker 4:  Wiper. I would like to be congratulated. Yeah. For not starting the show.
Speaker 4:  And I ending the show. So proud of you only on the show talking about this
Speaker 4:  wiper. I guess I did start with the wiper did. All right.
Speaker 5:  You just alluded to it.
Speaker 4:  So Tesla had earnings this week. Okay. They announced a bunch of stuff Tesla
Speaker 4:  revenue way up cuz they keeps slashing prices. Their margins are coming
Speaker 4:  down. Elon said they would license full self-driving each other automaker
Speaker 4:  and apparently there's an automaker interested. He talked about the charging
Speaker 4:  network and how that's gonna be a source of revenue. So Tesla, you know,
Speaker 4:  in a moment of change, I I would just say right, lower
Speaker 4:  prices, higher revenue, lower margins. Interesting place for Tesla to
Speaker 4:  be opening up the software stack. Fascinating. They said they're
Speaker 4:  doing release candidates at the Cybertruck from their factory. You see them
Speaker 4:  rolling around Texas. It's very funny, but I
Speaker 4:  just, you guys, we'll put it in the show notes. You go
Speaker 4:  look on our site, there's a picture of the Cybertruck
Speaker 4:  off-roading covered in mud with its big silly
Speaker 4:  wiper trying to wipe the mud off the windshield and the wiper
Speaker 4:  sucks. This is an Official Tesla press
Speaker 4:  photo. This isn't me concocting some sort
Speaker 4:  of fake biased mud trial because I hate Elon Musk. I'm looking
Speaker 4:  at the photo the company sent us of it's
Speaker 4:  wiper, supposedly wiping and it fucking
Speaker 4:  sucks.
Speaker 6:  I mean it honestly, a, it doesn't wipe
Speaker 6:  completely
Speaker 4:  And b
Speaker 6:  It only even attempts to wipe like
Speaker 6:  60% of the, you know this like
Speaker 4:  If you are in the passenger side of this truck, you're not
Speaker 4:  seeing anything.
Speaker 6:  Have you ever done the thing when it's cold and you have like snow
Speaker 6:  on your windshield so you like pull your sleeve over your hand and you just,
Speaker 6:  you do this sort of one big wipe just to get some of the snow off. Do you
Speaker 6:  know what I'm talking about? Yes. Yeah, that's what this windshield wiper
Speaker 6:  does. It's just your dumb jacketed
Speaker 6:  arm just going, that's your
Speaker 6:  windshield
Speaker 4:  Wiper. I mean. It's just like, I can't believe they release this like at
Speaker 4:  least Photoshop it ask mid journey to be like insert clean
Speaker 4:  windshield
Speaker 5:  That
Speaker 4:  They don't you need to do. But this photo is Ho. It's just objectively
Speaker 4:  hilarious how bad the wiper is in Tesla's own
Speaker 4:  photo. I I cannot believe we all just let it slide this. We are
Speaker 4:  recording a day after this photo came out. And I. I'm just,
Speaker 4:  I'm flabbergasted that we as a society, this is why Elon
Speaker 4:  bought Twitter. So we couldn't all just cloning on this photo.
Speaker 4:  Like look, just look at it. I beg you. Is it gonna look at this
Speaker 4:  photo? This is our, the country's finest engineering minds. And they're like,
Speaker 4:  I dunno, this wiper fine. It's, it's nuts. Everything else about the Cybertruck
Speaker 4:  kind of interesting right? They made it, it's much smaller. The packaging
Speaker 4:  is much smaller. So it has a six and a half foot bed in a
Speaker 4:  sub 19 foot frame. A regular pickup miah pickup truck is
Speaker 4:  longer than 19 feet. It has a five foot, five foot.
Speaker 5:  This one. So this one is because it can park in normal garages.
Speaker 4:  Yes it can fit in a normal garage. Do you have
Speaker 5:  A special garage?
Speaker 4:  No. I, to get the rafter in my garage, you get two inches on a side.
Speaker 4:  It is horrifying but I'm really good at it now. And now I think I can drive
Speaker 4:  that car anywhere. And. I. I should not, that's not, that's not
Speaker 4:  the, that's not accurate. But trucks are getting much longer. Yeah. So this
Speaker 4:  one has a longer bed and a shorter package. It's super interesting packaging
Speaker 4:  innovation from Tesla. They're getting better at manufacturing it, which
Speaker 4:  is a very complicated thing to manufacture. They, I'm just saying they have
Speaker 4:  not in any way figured out how to wipe the
Speaker 4:  windshield. Just, I just not, they haven't
Speaker 4:  solved it.
Speaker 5:  Why is it hard to do
Speaker 4:  Wipe the windshield? I
Speaker 5:  I my car. It's not does it quite easily?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, we've solved this problem. We have such good windshield wiper technology
Speaker 6:  now that Tesla is choosing not to use.
Speaker 5:  Why? What is the rationale there besides like we don't look
Speaker 4:  Past it. Windshield is at such an extreme angle and it's so large. Okay
Speaker 6:  Because big wiper. Why have good wiper when you can have big
Speaker 4:  Wiper? It's true. So el again, we've covered this extensively. Elon has said
Speaker 4:  the wiper like gives him the most like anxiety about the
Speaker 4:  Cybertruck cuz I think mounting sta standard wipers on that
Speaker 4:  angle for that size, like it does, I think it would be less
Speaker 4:  effective than the one big wiper.
Speaker 5:  How likely is this thing as soon as you get it on the road behind like a
Speaker 5:  gravel truck to just be the most useless windshield of
Speaker 4:  The world? Well, based on the evidence I have from the companies on marketing
Speaker 4:  materials,
Speaker 5:  It's just wrecked.
Speaker 4:  I just, just look at the picture. It's incredible. Everything. Like, I'm
Speaker 4:  curious about this car. I like trucks. I think it would be fun
Speaker 4:  to go really fast in a triangle.
Speaker 5:  I wanna see this into it on a ranch. I wanna see
Speaker 5:  this driving through, like dealing with cattle, feeding the
Speaker 5:  cattle big shiny metal thing that'll burn at the
Speaker 5:  touch. Just like,
Speaker 4:  Oh yeah, how's it gonna say called who knows more
Speaker 5:  Questions and answer starting grass fires with the reflection.
Speaker 4:  So it's not supposed to ship until late next year really, but they have started
Speaker 4:  production. So that's like the big news. And then the other news that I think
Speaker 4:  is just surrounding Tesla that's worth talking about is the flood of
Speaker 4:  companies that are adopting the N A C S charging standard, which is the Tesla
Speaker 4:  plug abandoning ccs, which is the other garbage plug.
Speaker 4:  Quite frankly, it's an unusual case of the right
Speaker 4:  standard winning and turning into a standard
Speaker 4:  versus whatever ba like the proprietary thing is gonna become the
Speaker 4:  standard good on Tesla for making that happen. The mechanics of it I think
Speaker 4:  are still really unclear. Like these companies are signing deals to use this
Speaker 4:  connector. It's not just US standard, yet unclear how that will
Speaker 4:  work. The Society of Automotive Engineers, they say they're gonna
Speaker 4:  make it a standard. You can See how Tesla is sort of being
Speaker 4:  incentivized by government subsidies to enable people to use it in
Speaker 4:  order to get tax rebates on, on charging network and other things.
Speaker 5:  Tesla hit a point where they say they start charging astronomical
Speaker 5:  fees for you to use this charging standard and companies are
Speaker 5:  forced to pay those fees otherwise they can't have their cars
Speaker 5:  charged
Speaker 4:  Across. Like, can, can Elon do a rug pull on an ecs? Yeah, I don't think
Speaker 4:  so. I I I'm reasonably certain that
Speaker 4:  he can't fool every major car manufacturer. Like maybe
Speaker 4:  one, like maybe if like Nissan was like we did it, we'd be like, eh, eh,
Speaker 4:  you picked Chimo the last time. Like, you know like, like I don't know like
Speaker 4:  yeah you're bad at this, but they, he's got four gm,
Speaker 4:  Volvo, vw like just down the line. He's got them
Speaker 4:  all and more signing every day. So you, you get the feeling at least in the
Speaker 4:  United States, they're gonna end up here and the thing will actually become
Speaker 4:  a standard electrify. America's gonna use it. And what we're just ending
Speaker 4:  up with right now is like this weird interstitial
Speaker 4:  period where it's dongle town for cars,
Speaker 4:  which is not great driving
Speaker 5:  The
Speaker 6:  Dongle town. It was great. Andy Hawkins wrote a story about this and, and
Speaker 6:  had a quote from somebody who said, I feel like I'm driving a beta Max. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Which is just a really delightful because
Speaker 5:  You are
Speaker 6:  Neli correct me if I'm understanding this wrong, but this seems like the
Speaker 6:  kind of thing where the best case
Speaker 6:  scenario everybody wins, which is that
Speaker 6:  basically we get a charging network that everybody needs
Speaker 6:  including Tesla, that Tesla doesn't have to build for itself, that works
Speaker 6:  for everybody, thus makes people worry less about range anxiety,
Speaker 6:  thus makes more people buy EVs, thus is good for the government and Tesla
Speaker 6:  and all these other companies like who loses in this. It seems
Speaker 6:  like the, the part that's sketchy is that a company invented
Speaker 6:  the thing that is becoming the standard and that that company is Tesla, which
Speaker 6:  is sort of run by a man who is not famously predictable but like
Speaker 6:  everything else about this seems like it's heading in a good direction, right?
Speaker 6:  Am I missing something? I
Speaker 4:  Think that's right. I think maybe the, the people who are the most upset
Speaker 4:  are Tesla's shareholders who think that Tesla should be a
Speaker 4:  monopoly. Sure. Right? But even Elon Musk doesn't apparently think Tesla
Speaker 4:  should be a monopoly. But for a minute, if you want an electric car, the
Speaker 4:  only viable choice was a Tesla even today. And there are really
Speaker 4:  good EVs out there right now. Even today, if you wanna travel a
Speaker 4:  lot in your EV, you need to buy a Tesla cuz they have the
Speaker 4:  infrastructure to support that kind of EV travel. Now you
Speaker 4:  don't right? Because they're just gonna open up the charging network and
Speaker 4:  their big moat that made their car the best car is gone
Speaker 4:  or loosening. You can still argue that they have the best software experience
Speaker 4:  and the best full self driving, but that's just car stuff now. Before it
Speaker 4:  was like, you buy this car and there are not enough gas
Speaker 4:  stations for you and that's gone right? With, with these deals. So I I
Speaker 4:  I think Tesla's just in a more competitive environment,
Speaker 6:  It would be like Apple supporting rcs. It's like literally, you know, giving
Speaker 6:  up one of your biggest pieces of lock-in willingly,
Speaker 4:  Right? And I. I I really do think that Tesla had to do it because of
Speaker 4:  various basically Biden administration policies that that made them do it
Speaker 4:  to get the tax credits in various ways. I think they had to do it because
Speaker 4:  if they didn't then Ford and GM and whoever else
Speaker 4:  would actually invest in Electrify America would actually make that
Speaker 4:  network possible because they, they need it to compete. And I, think
Speaker 4:  Ford Jim Farley has been on decoder and said, we know the charging experience
Speaker 4:  sucks. They have this massive investment in Mustang Lockey and F-150
Speaker 4:  lightnings and all these other EVs that aren't moving the way they were moving
Speaker 4:  last year with all the tax credits because of the partially cuz of the charging
Speaker 4:  network problems. So I I you just see like, okay, do I want to
Speaker 4:  face off against all the world's biggest automakers who will band together
Speaker 4:  and pick the bad standard? Or do I want to try to make some money off the
Speaker 4:  supercharging network that I've spent tons and tons of money building
Speaker 4:  and I'll maybe I'll charge higher rates to afford customer like the they
Speaker 4:  can play these games. The problem is gonna be, and this is really in Andy's
Speaker 4:  piece, the software that makes all this work seamlessly for
Speaker 4:  people is gonna be nuts. Yeah. Right? Like if you
Speaker 4:  roll up to a supercharger, which doesn't have a screen and you wanna pay
Speaker 4:  for it and you need one app, a Tesla app to pay for it, and you roll up to
Speaker 4:  Electrify America or charge net or whatever, and you need another app and
Speaker 4:  all those different billing systems and your car's sort of incompatible with
Speaker 4:  every like, ugh, sorry. I think there's, there's a layer of software compatibility
Speaker 4:  that needs to happen here that, I dunno, it does feel like I have a Jeep
Speaker 4:  with an old, the old, the now the old connector, the CCS connector. I'm like,
Speaker 4:  crap, I bought Thero wrong charging station for my garage. I got this dumb
Speaker 4:  beta Max car. It's, this feels like a bad time to buy an EV in
Speaker 4:  a way that is the opposite of the intended result, right? Like you
Speaker 4:  buy a new Kia and you're like, welcome to Dongle town. Like that sucks.
Speaker 1:  This is like
Speaker 6:  That. Do you remember when everybody was buying combo vcr, DVD players?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. This is like, this is that moment and then eventually we'll get to
Speaker 4:  Somewhere. We had a good comment on Andy's piece actually, I can't remember
Speaker 4:  who it was, but somebody was complaining about dongles and the response,
Speaker 4:  what I thought was really smart was, this isn't like a phone. Cars are really
Speaker 4:  big. You can put the adapters almost anywhere. That's
Speaker 4:  fair. They're like, we have trunks and front trunks and glove boxes. Like
Speaker 4:  you'll be fine. And that's probably correct. That
Speaker 6:  Is fair. True.
Speaker 4:  All right, we gotta take a break, man. We been out gadgets. We gotta take
Speaker 4:  a break. We'll come back, we'll do maybe a little more gadgets, then we'll
Speaker 4:  talk about Hollywood. We'll be right
Speaker 4:  back.
Speaker 4:  Today's show comes from the podcast, business Wars. Business Wars brings
Speaker 4:  you drama filled feuds from some of the world's best known companies.
Speaker 4:  Like on New Year's Day 1960 Cardenas Cuba, when
Speaker 4:  soldiers seized the Havana Club Rum distillery, or in
Speaker 4:  the 1980s when two hippies in Burlington, Vermont had to fight to save
Speaker 4:  their business before all their ice cream dreams melted away.
Speaker 1:  Warren 2010. When a series of deadly tragedies to factory in
Speaker 1:  Bangladesh drew global attention to the fast fashion
Speaker 1:  industry, what lengths would they go to in order to keep up with customer
Speaker 1:  demand from Wondery? It's not another crime podcast,
Speaker 1:  it's Business Wars hosted by David Brown. Business Wars is
Speaker 1:  in an award-winning series that examines some of the greatest business
Speaker 1:  rivalries of our time. From a rum battle in Cuba to a
Speaker 1:  global war over fast fashion. There are over 75
Speaker 1:  seasons for you to explore, follow business wars wherever you get your
Speaker 1:  podcasts. You can listen ad free on Amazon music or the
Speaker 1:  Wonder
Speaker 1:  App.
Speaker 4:  All right, we're back. Welcome back to Wiper Talk. Do you have a favorite
Speaker 4:  brand of wipers?
Speaker 5:  I've, again, I'm sorry. I think those detailers will will have one
Speaker 4:  By the way. Car detail, TikTok, one of my favorite toss. Oh yeah. Could
Speaker 4:  watch it all day long. The
Speaker 6:  The people who just like take the little brush to paint the stripe and just
Speaker 6:  do it freehand all the way down the ugh. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  It's beautiful.
Speaker 4:  And then you're like, don't do that to the car. Why? Why do you have this
Speaker 4:  still? Yeah. Was that why? Why did the market create the need for this product?
Speaker 4:  Little
Speaker 5:  Loopy.
Speaker 4:  All right, let's talk about Hollywood. But I think the way to talk about
Speaker 4:  Hollywood is to start by talking to ai.
Speaker 5:  Oh yeah, that works.
Speaker 4:  Right? There's some AI news I think that will lead us into the interlocking
Speaker 4:  strikes that have Yes. Brought Hollywood to its knees, which are in
Speaker 4:  their core about ai. But there's a bunch of actual AI news this
Speaker 4:  week. So first Germin reported at Bloomberg that
Speaker 4:  Apple has an AI chatbot. They haven't quite figured out what to
Speaker 4:  do with it, which is funny all on its own. I
Speaker 5:  Love why they made it though. They made it because they didn't want their
Speaker 5:  employees using like Bard or ChatGPT for security reasons.
Speaker 5:  And so they're like, okay, well we'll just make our own now we did it. What
Speaker 5:  do we do
Speaker 4:  With it? And then here's the fascinating part. They're running it on Google
Speaker 4:  Cloud. Yes. Yeah. Yes. Which is just wild. It makes sense. Like
Speaker 4:  Apple has a bunch of products that could use an L l M, the new keyboard
Speaker 4:  in IO 17 where it has a language model sort of built into it for better
Speaker 4:  autocorrect. By the way, have you seen this conspiracy theory, I dunno what
Speaker 4:  you wanna call it, this claim that the key autocorrect in the current iOS
Speaker 4:  keyboard is very bad. Is And
Speaker 6:  Getting worse. Yes.
Speaker 4:  And getting worse. Yes. Taylor Lorenz made a Instagram video and
Speaker 4:  it like tagged me in. It was like, figure this out. And I was like, it seems
Speaker 4:  fine for me. I don't know how to, it's just a vibe.
Speaker 5:  It is. I can't tell you how many times somebody says, I'm sorry, what did
Speaker 5:  you say? And then I have to go look back and be like, that's not what I typed.
Speaker 4:  You think it's getting worse? I
Speaker 5:  It's, it feels like it's getting worse. I'm dying.
Speaker 4:  So maybe my fingers are DM an email. Leave us a comment if you think it's
Speaker 4:  getting worse. This is a very difficult thing to measure. Yeah. I
Speaker 4:  have not noticed it, but it seems like Alex has. David, what about you?
Speaker 6:  I definitely have not noticed it getting worse. It seems, it seems
Speaker 6:  fine to me.
Speaker 4:  Here's my theory, it's the summer and everyone's drinking.
Speaker 5:  I was, I was about to say this hap this happened to be on the path train
Speaker 5:  today where I was so
Speaker 4:  Where everyone's hammered.
Speaker 5:  There were some hammered people, but I was sober and it still did it.
Speaker 5:  But it does also happen. Seems to happen more when Yeah. You're having a
Speaker 5:  good time.
Speaker 4:  I'm just saying like you, you soak that iPhone in Rose keyboard doesn't work
Speaker 4:  so well just woo. Conspiracy. But I'm dying. you know, people
Speaker 4:  have seen it cuz I've seen this around. Yeah. Like I said, Taylor tagged
Speaker 4:  me in a video she made. I've seen other videos about it, but I, it's, it's
Speaker 4:  like impossible to measure. So we just need a lot of like anecdote.
Speaker 6:  My, my running hypothesis is that this is kind of along the
Speaker 6:  lines of the, my phone is listening to me conspiracy theory
Speaker 6:  in that like, you see 700,000
Speaker 6:  ads a day and the one that happens to have been
Speaker 6:  perfectly targeted is the only one you pay attention to. Which ironically
Speaker 6:  is a statement about how good targeted ads actually are,
Speaker 6:  but is also the thing that makes people think they're listening. It's like,
Speaker 6:  no it's just, it, it's, it's a one in 700,000 chance and you just
Speaker 6:  only notice the one that got it. Right. This strikes me as sort of the same
Speaker 6:  thing where like people type a lot into their phones and these things make
Speaker 6:  mistakes and some of them are weird. The ones that always get me are the
Speaker 6:  people who type a word and it pops up the little autocorrect bubble
Speaker 6:  trying to auto correct it to something insane. Yeah. I have not noticed that
Speaker 6:  again on my phone. But there are lots of people who say that it has,
Speaker 5:  It changed. What are you doing to water
Speaker 5:  doing? I'm like, that's just no one talks like that
Speaker 5:  Apple
Speaker 4:  People from Pennsylvania,
Speaker 6:  I've
Speaker 5:  Not from there. Just
Speaker 5:  assumed.
Speaker 4:  Alright, we started by talking about AI and we ended up with this keyword
Speaker 4:  thing. Let me know. Let us know. Yeah. We're dying to know. Yes. We, I'd
Speaker 4:  love to run this story to ground in the only way we can do it. There's responses.
Speaker 4:  So Apple's building this thing called Ajax are running and Google cloud,
Speaker 4:  they are doing LMS in the keyboard. You can See how they would wanna plug
Speaker 4:  this thing into Siri. It is wild to me that
Speaker 4:  Amazon hasn't plugged an LLM into Alexa and Google hasn't plugged
Speaker 4:  one into assistant Siri. No one's gonna be like, oh no, you changed
Speaker 4:  Siri like five. Like let's
Speaker 4:  Siri try to come onto you a little bit.
Speaker 5:  One person is, I don't know who you are, but you're out there and you're
Speaker 5:  gonna be really upset and I'm so
Speaker 4:  Sorry. It's, it's amazing to me that at this moment in time Microsoft has
Speaker 4:  horny or products than Apple.
Speaker 5:  No, that doesn't shock me at all. Microsoft always
Speaker 5:  much more low key horny than Apple. No. Since the beginning.
Speaker 4:  No. Now we gotta, no I disagree. I don't know how, I don't know how to further
Speaker 4:  this conversation.
Speaker 5:  This is our inaugural debate. I don't for a future
Speaker 5:  podcast,
Speaker 4:  I've never wanted to not have a conversation but
Speaker 4:  also viscerally disagree with you as much as I do right
Speaker 4:  now
Speaker 5:  I win. You can't argue
Speaker 4:  I win. I don't, I dunno how to say that's just wrong.
Speaker 5:  Please don't debate me in the Vercast emails with this one either, folks.
Speaker 5:  I don't, I don't need it.
Speaker 4:  That's fine. All I'm saying is it's weird that Bing is like let's do it.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I
Speaker 6:  Agree with that.
Speaker 4:  The thing
Speaker 6:  That's not weird, you said it's weird that these things haven't been integrated
Speaker 6:  into like Alexa and assistant in Siri yet they're bad. Like it's really
Speaker 6:  important to remember that like Chad g p t is bad. It's
Speaker 6:  like, it's fascinating and it's interesting and there's so many things you
Speaker 6:  can do with it that are very cool. It's wrong a lot and And I think
Speaker 6:  like Siri sucks but it's not prone to lying to
Speaker 6:  you. And, I think all this stuff that we're reckoning
Speaker 6:  with with like what does it mean that ChatGPT exists? Like what if I asked
Speaker 6:  Siri to turn off Bluetooth and the large language model like told me Bluetooth
Speaker 6:  doesn't exist and like invented a conspiracy theory about Bluetooth
Speaker 6:  and how's h Bluetooth is what my phone is using to listen to me. Wait,
Speaker 4:  I just wanna point out that might be a better situation than
Speaker 4:  whatever happens with Siri now
Speaker 6:  When it says here's some web results for Bluetooth.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, exactly. That's not helpful. Like fine spin me a yard about the
Speaker 4:  pirate named Bluetooth. Like I don't, at least it's interesting.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. But I think this is my, this is why I like this Apple story because
Speaker 6:  like if you follow the timeline here, this is what Apple does, right?
Speaker 6:  They let everybody make the products and then Apple comes in and says, we're
Speaker 6:  the ones who made this good. I think what is very clearly
Speaker 6:  true is that you cannot yet solve all of the problems of these large language
Speaker 6:  models. We just haven't figured out how to do it. And there's no
Speaker 6:  indication really ever that Apple has some like
Speaker 6:  generations ahead AI thing going on. If anything, apple has been behind on
Speaker 6:  this stuff for a decade and so I think Apple is probably in here
Speaker 6:  being like, we can build a better ChatGPT. And then they just built a ChatGPT
Speaker 6:  and they're like, well shit, now what do we do with this?
Speaker 6:  And they're, if, if they can figure out how to make that a
Speaker 6:  product people actually want to use that lives up to like Apple's standards
Speaker 6:  and that they can tell a privacy story about, that'll be cool and exciting.
Speaker 6:  I don't see that happening anytime soon.
Speaker 4:  I mean honestly at this point with Siri, Siri's response to every query was,
Speaker 4:  let me spin you a yarn about the pirate.
Speaker 6:  It's like hilarious lie. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  I'd like way better.
Speaker 4:  I maybe that's fine. Do it. you know the Amazon side of it and the Google
Speaker 4:  side of it that makes sense to me why they haven't integrated it. Right?
Speaker 4:  That's boring business stuff. Like Alexa is not a business.
Speaker 4:  They haven't figured out how to make it a business. It's been years.
Speaker 4:  They cut some of the Alexa team earlier this year cuz there's
Speaker 4:  no path to some huge profitable business. All these queries cost
Speaker 4:  money. So you're like, we're gonna make it more expensive to run Alexa
Speaker 4:  against No business is not a good decision.
Speaker 4:  Right?
Speaker 6:  So where you see Amazon investing is like, how do we use
Speaker 6:  LLMs on amazon.com right? Yeah. Which is, that's the business that
Speaker 6:  actually will make Amazon money in the long run.
Speaker 4:  Right? Can we make, can we make the descriptions of items on Amazon better
Speaker 4:  and richer and more fun to read that will sell more things. Google has the
Speaker 4:  same problem, right? Like Google Assistant for all of it's crowing about
Speaker 4:  how it's the future over the past years. Like Google Assistant is not a
Speaker 4:  business. It it, it's useful. I like, I am the only person that
Speaker 4:  likes Google Home and it's because the displays have the cool photo
Speaker 4:  feature where they are reflective. That's it. That's why we are a Google
Speaker 4:  family. so
Speaker 5:  Like nothing to do with the Google assistant?
Speaker 4:  No, very little to Google assistant. It's the, I think the hardware is
Speaker 4:  superior hardware. Oh yeah. To the Amazon hardware because of the, the photo
Speaker 4:  reflectivity feature. And I. Think Google Photos is superior backend for
Speaker 4:  photos and the Amazon thing and fine and Google Assistant exists. You may
Speaker 4:  set timers from E Google given you've passed the first two
Speaker 4:  doors. you know, like would it, would it be cool if Google Assistant was
Speaker 4:  more conversational and like more useful than that? Sure. But then they have
Speaker 4:  to run an ln query, which costs infinitely more money
Speaker 4:  than whatever steam engine Google Assistant is
Speaker 4:  running on now. you know? And is slower
Speaker 6:  And more error prone and harder to guess what it's gonna
Speaker 6:  do and harder to sort of manually program like these things are
Speaker 6:  bigger and weirder and wackier, And, I think that's gonna make them be
Speaker 6:  much slower for a lot of this stuff.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And I think, especially now as people are getting more used to
Speaker 4:  what LMS can do and can't do. You're just seeing like, oh these
Speaker 4:  things are like, as you said, David, they're mostly a c plus. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And like in
Speaker 5:  Some cases they're getting dumber.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. What is that study this week that ChatGPT is getting dumber at math,
Speaker 4:  right? Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It's getting worse at maths. That's amazing. That's that's great. Cuz
Speaker 5:  we are all bad at math
Speaker 6:  And it's learning from us.
Speaker 4:  Stupid computer
Speaker 5:  That'll learn you like why were we ever scared Where're the where
Speaker 5:  we're the, the source material? Of course it's gonna be fine.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I mean, and then there's the idea of model collapse. Did you see this
Speaker 4:  week Wix announced Wix is a website host. Yeah. They
Speaker 4:  announced you could create an entire website and deploy it with just a couple
Speaker 4:  of like chatbot
Speaker 5:  Prompts. But they were also very clear, like, don't just use the copy
Speaker 5:  rewrite. It's, it's written by like ChatGPT I think, oh I've
Speaker 4:  Got, and they're like, I've got bad news for Wix. People are just gonna use
Speaker 4:  the copier. Oh yes. And then there's a turn in there that is really fascinating
Speaker 4:  to me. So the their demo. The Wix demo was for like an
Speaker 4:  online fitness company or something. so like training company, like something
Speaker 4:  with classes. Yeah. so like they, like I have a company that
Speaker 4:  does trainings, make me a website and then it's like, it
Speaker 4:  showed picture of like instructors and it was like, pick an instructor that
Speaker 4:  matches your vibe. And they obviously picked like the coolest one and then
Speaker 4:  it made a whole website. And then the next turn was, we are
Speaker 4:  also managing the scheduling of your classes. We see you have some
Speaker 4:  open slots. Do you want us to make a social media
Speaker 4:  marketing campaign? Whoa. To get customers for you? And
Speaker 4:  you're like, yes. And it just fired off some Instagram assets or
Speaker 4:  whatever and it published them and said, it's done using the existing and
Speaker 4:  it's like at some point and you're not even running the business. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And then I saw someone else tweeted at me just pointing out a
Speaker 4:  startup guy who's like, I just published
Speaker 4:  250,000 words of content to like 45
Speaker 4:  niche interest websites that I started. They're all just at SEO honeypots
Speaker 4:  and I'm making money. And it's like, oh the, the cannon of c plus
Speaker 4:  content is here. Yep. Yeah. At scale. Like massive scale.
Speaker 4:  And that's, I, you know, you know how I feel about the web Come, come
Speaker 4:  with me to my private web of people. The robot
Speaker 4:  web continues to grow. So this is actually the next piece of
Speaker 4:  AI news. Meta is giving away it's AI stack, it's
Speaker 4:  called Llama and it's called Llama two. They're running it on Azure. It's
Speaker 4:  a Microsoft service. So Microsoft's kind of the overall winner, right? Big
Speaker 4:  investment in OpenAI. OpenAI is using Azure. Now this partnership with
Speaker 4:  Meta, Microsoft is a big investor in Meta from like way back now.
Speaker 4:  Meta's Stack is gonna run on Azure. So Microsoft's just like, just run
Speaker 4:  it here, just optimize for our chips and our services and our data
Speaker 4:  centers and we're the winner. Like everyone's just gonna pay us the fees.
Speaker 4:  The fascinating thing about Metas announcement is they keep claiming that
Speaker 4:  they've open sourced their model, which is fascinating because
Speaker 4:  it already leaked, if you'll recall. So Meta's l LM leaked,
Speaker 4:  people were using it, they, you know, running on laptops. So it's not a great
Speaker 4:  outcome for a variety of reasons, mostly about safety. But that led
Speaker 4:  to a memo inside of Google that said, we have no moat. These open source
Speaker 4:  models will kill us. Big controversy there. So now Matt's saying,
Speaker 4:  okay fine, we're just gonna open source the whole thing. But then they didn't
Speaker 4:  actually open source it. They didn't. So the license is not actually an open
Speaker 4:  source license. It's not an Official open source license. It doesn't meet
Speaker 4:  the definition. What is it? It has all these restrictions in it. And if you
Speaker 4:  are a big company with over 700 million active
Speaker 4:  users, you don't get to use it at all. Yes. So it's just like not
Speaker 4:  open source
Speaker 6:  Is that, that's literally just Google and Apple
Speaker 4:  And Snap I think is the smallest of the companies.
Speaker 6:  Interesting. Hit the threshold. And, I. Guess like Telegram now. Sure. Sorry.
Speaker 6:  Telegram.
Speaker 4:  And they're like, if the our competitors wish to use it, they can make a
Speaker 4:  deal with us. And it's like, guys, that's not open source.
Speaker 5:  I love that. I open source asterisk.
Speaker 4:  I mean they keep saying it's open source. It's like you read the license,
Speaker 4:  it's like not an open source license. Well
Speaker 6:  It's just asterisk. Like when, when Elon Musk keeps saying he's gonna open
Speaker 6:  source the, the Twitter algorithm and it's like posting some of the
Speaker 6:  code is not the same as Opensourcing.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It's like, you know who the most pedantic nerds of all are
Speaker 4:  are open source nerds. Yeah. Like you say it's open
Speaker 4:  source and you like, here's our model. And it's like what community do you
Speaker 4:  think that you are interacting with right now?
Speaker 5:  I would honestly rather have like an open source
Speaker 5:  aficionado read a contract I need to sign before a contract lawyer. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Like they will go through every single, they'll find
Speaker 5:  everything. Every, I don't
Speaker 4:  Have to worry about it. Like I'm renting this car. Is it open source? Anyway,
Speaker 4:  it's just we, we've asked Meta about it. I'm very curious what the reasoning
Speaker 4:  here. It's like why they're using this term. It is going to land them in
Speaker 4:  some amount of trouble with like the open source community. But they keep
Speaker 4:  saying it. And I think the reason they're saying it is cuz they want to be
Speaker 4:  perceived as a provider of models people have a dependency on. But if you're
Speaker 4:  gonna do, if you're gonna open source, you have to actually do it. You have
Speaker 4:  to actually give the source code to people and let them use it however they
Speaker 4:  want basically. And that is like, here are a bunch of rules and restrictions.
Speaker 4:  Like the words open source and acceptable use
Speaker 4:  policy are not aligned. Like those are
Speaker 4:  not concepts that plug into each other. This is
Speaker 6:  Much more in along with like the creative commons where it was like the,
Speaker 6:  like on flicker a million years ago. Right. They would, they would be the
Speaker 6:  license that it was like, you can use this photo only for your personal
Speaker 6:  use and yeah, you have to give credits to the original author. And that's
Speaker 6:  kind of a foundational thing on the internet. That's not open source. Open
Speaker 6:  source means you can have it and do what you want with it,
Speaker 6:  generally speaking.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Open source licenses are copyright licenses. Yeah. They're like rooted
Speaker 4:  in the fact that you own the copyright and you're like offering terms of
Speaker 4:  a license, but they're very rarely
Speaker 4:  like conditional in the way that this is conditional. And yeah, now
Speaker 4:  we're 40 years into the open source experiment. There are
Speaker 4:  governance bodies that are like, these are the licenses that
Speaker 4:  count and these are the ones that don't. And Meta didn't pick one that does,
Speaker 4:  you know, and like is this biggest deal in the world? It's not the biggest
Speaker 4:  deal in the world. Can I tell The Vergecast audience about open source licenses?
Speaker 4:  I can And I. I think Meta should be like, we should stop using this word
Speaker 4:  because it just doesn't mean the thing that it's supposed to mean. And it's
Speaker 4:  like to me, important they're
Speaker 5:  Going to keep doing it until they get in trouble.
Speaker 4:  Well that's why I mean that's the sheriff of open source is here. Yep. I
Speaker 4:  dunno if you know my fourth title here at Fox Media, they call me the
Speaker 4:  sheriff. Well, but I'm saying that community before we noticed it. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  That open source community said, what are you doing here? And I. Think it's,
Speaker 4:  it is important for how software is made that those words, me continue
Speaker 4:  to mean the thing they're supposed to mean. All right. I promised we would
Speaker 4:  segue from this AI conversation to the Hollywood AI conversation.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I'm gonna figure out a way to segue it. Okay.
Speaker 6:  I I can segue this with a question. So I've found myself for whatever reason
Speaker 6:  listening to a lot of podcasts about the strikes happening in
Speaker 6:  Hollywood. And the reason I think we should talk about the strike right now
Speaker 6:  is there's a lot of different things floating around, a lot of
Speaker 6:  different arguments being had. There are two separate strikes happening that
Speaker 6:  are kind of connected and kind of not. And the biggest thing I cannot
Speaker 6:  figure out, And I want you to answer this for me, Cranz is, okay,
Speaker 6:  how much is this actually about ai? Because what the writers have been saying
Speaker 6:  is we don't want studios to be able to use ChatGPT and other tools to generate
Speaker 6:  scripts. The actors were saying, we don't want you to be able to use our
Speaker 6:  likenesses and like make deep fakes of us to go into movies. And then I
Speaker 6:  listened to all these like big wigs in the entertainment business saying,
Speaker 6:  no, that's all sort of a, a far off farce. What they're actually arguing
Speaker 6:  about is streaming residuals. Which one is it? Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Streaming residuals are the, like residuals is the core
Speaker 5:  thing here. Because residuals is how the majority of both actors and writers
Speaker 5:  get paid.
Speaker 6:  Okay. So let's, let's come back to that. But let, yeah, tell me how much
Speaker 6:  AI actually matters first.
Speaker 5:  AI matters because in both cases they're worried about the potential
Speaker 5:  future use, not the current use to some extent. Okay. To a large
Speaker 5:  extent. And so they're worried about that potential future use and they wanna
Speaker 5:  make sure that the studios don't be assholes further down the line.
Speaker 5:  So for the writers, they're specifically saying, we want certain
Speaker 5:  protections. You can't give us, you can't have ChatGPT go
Speaker 5:  come up with a script and then make us write it and then not pay us for
Speaker 5:  coming up with the ideas for the script. Like we don't wanna have to
Speaker 5:  be using ChatGPT prompts to write. And so
Speaker 5:  that's like the core thing there is they, they don't want, they want
Speaker 5:  AI to be treated as a tool, not as like a creative force
Speaker 5:  that can be copyrighted and everything like that.
Speaker 6:  But no one is out here thinking that tomorrow
Speaker 6:  ChatGPT could write a great script that would turn into a blockbuster mark.
Speaker 6:  Oh,
Speaker 4:  Some people, yeah. I don dunno if they're correct
Speaker 5:  I mean the studios
Speaker 6:  Are totally, totally I mean. They're definitely not
Speaker 5:  Correct. Yeah. The studios are very interested in, in AI and they would like,
Speaker 5:  they would love to be able to cut the writers out entirely or just pay
Speaker 5:  writers to edit whatever ChatGPT wrote, which
Speaker 5:  like they would love to do that and they'd love to do that consistently.
Speaker 5:  And the writers are like, you can't do that yet. You will probably be able
Speaker 5:  to do that in a few years and we wanna go ahead and just nip that in the
Speaker 5:  but now. Okay. So that's what's happening with the writers. For the actors.
Speaker 5:  It's specifically right now, if you're an actor you just go get
Speaker 5:  scanned. Like you signed a contract for a new show or something, a
Speaker 5:  new movie, you go and they're gonna like scan your face, they're gonna scan
Speaker 5:  your body and then they just take that data and walk away with
Speaker 5:  it. And right now there's, it's not clear where they take that
Speaker 5:  data and if, you know, hit me up cause I'd love to know, but specifically
Speaker 5:  background actors, they're saying, well, we would love to take a background
Speaker 5:  actor's face and scan it and then never pay them for that initial
Speaker 5:  scan and never pay them again and use their face however
Speaker 5:  we want forever in, in our films and TVs. And
Speaker 5:  so background actors are like a, like that's how you get your card,
Speaker 5:  that's how you kind of get into sag. That's a, for some of them it's not
Speaker 5:  a livelihood, but it's, it keeps the lights on right. Between that and their
Speaker 5:  DoorDash side hustle or whatever. And so they, they, they obviously don't
Speaker 5:  wanna do that. So that's where they're concerned there because most of the
Speaker 5:  big actors like the Matt Damons, the Killian Murphy's Yes. I saw Oppenheimer.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  You see it in 70 Millimeter? No, with the Palm Pilot,
Speaker 5:  But I saw it with Christopher Nolan and so I think it's okay if we don't
Speaker 5:  see it at IMAX. I think it's okay. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Flex. So just to put a point on that, so I was thinking about this
Speaker 6:  because have you guys seen the new Indiana Jones movie? No,
Speaker 5:  Not yet. But they, they age stuff they do in that. Yeah. So
Speaker 6:  For the first like 20 minutes of the movie, I guess this is a spoiler alert,
Speaker 6:  but like whatever, it's in Neogen, he's de aged, like
Speaker 6:  digitally de aged. And it is, it is
Speaker 4:  Both. How's a spoiler? The best. You think that's a spoiler. Don't email
Speaker 4:  us. Go ahead.
Speaker 6:  If if you think it's a spoiler, you already have commented on The Verge dot
Speaker 6:  com about it, so I understand. But it, it's better than any
Speaker 6:  version of that I've seen before and it's also still pretty bad.
Speaker 6:  And it also clearly still requires Harrison Ford.
Speaker 5:  So that one was unique though because they used
Speaker 5:  Lucas film had tons of footage of him. They had all these
Speaker 5:  dailies from all the other projects, all the Star Wars Sure. And Indiana
Speaker 5:  Jones they've used when he was that age. And so they actually used all of
Speaker 5:  that footage to recreate his face.
Speaker 6:  So that's actually maybe closer to the kind of thing you're talking about
Speaker 6:  than most of what we've seen in the past.
Speaker 5:  And that one was okay because like should it, it was like the stuff, they
Speaker 5:  weren't using it in other things. And and for someone of his
Speaker 5:  level, like they're gonna go and make a a different deal Like, he Yeah. Presumably
Speaker 5:  he's gonna, he's gonna have like a SAG contract, but he's also gonna have
Speaker 5:  this other contract and, and, and they'll, they'll make those agreements.
Speaker 5:  This is to protect all those people who don't have these other, these other
Speaker 5:  con separate contracts to make sure that they don't get screwed
Speaker 5:  over. So that like you're a background actor, you hit it big and
Speaker 5:  then suddenly you're just popping up all over the place
Speaker 5:  because Right. 20 years ago, somebody got the rights to your face.
Speaker 5:  Okay. That's what they're trying to avoid.
Speaker 4:  So what's fascinating about that is the
Speaker 4:  writers are sort of operating in the bounds
Speaker 4:  of existing copyright law. Yes. Because they write
Speaker 4:  things. Yeah. And they, you can make copies of it and the
Speaker 4:  law understands all of that. And so the writers are like, we
Speaker 4:  wanna get paid these rates for these kinds of work. Your
Speaker 4:  face is not a copy of anything.
Speaker 5:  It's just
Speaker 4:  Your face or should not be. And the idea that you can scan it and that
Speaker 4:  becomes a copy of your face and you've made a copy of your face doesn't exist
Speaker 4:  anywhere, but it exists in some state level likeness law.
Speaker 4:  Right. Of publicity law. There's no copyright law for
Speaker 4:  your face. This is just a new problem. And so
Speaker 4:  it's, I think Hollywood is gonna have to invent a solution to this problem
Speaker 4:  that is way ahead Yeah. Of the government of
Speaker 4:  courts or whatever because there's just no answer for, you can't
Speaker 4:  go and find the answer to this question inside the law. Well, And, I'm not
Speaker 4:  saying the writers don't have complicated problems of their own, but
Speaker 4:  they're at least inside of something that makes sense that there's a Framework
Speaker 4:  for talking about, I'll give you an example. Just this week there was a court
Speaker 4:  case where a bunch of photographers had sued first
Speaker 4:  Buzzfeed and then Instagram because Buzzfeed
Speaker 4:  had embedded Instagrams of their photos. So
Speaker 4:  that Right. The photographers are taking some photos posted on Instagram.
Speaker 4:  Buzzfeed embedded the Instagram posts onto Buzzfeed
Speaker 4:  articles and the photographer sued Buzzfeed and Instagram said,
Speaker 4:  this is copyright infringement. Haven't
Speaker 6:  We had this debate before? I'm getting like real dejavu, were listening to
Speaker 6:  you explain
Speaker 4:  This. Yeah. This happens all the time. And so the courts over the years,
Speaker 4:  this is a true thing in our law. No one talks about it. Like we're, if you
Speaker 4:  look at people on the social networks, they're all like, LLMs are fair
Speaker 4:  use training. This like this is where we are. In reality, in
Speaker 4:  2023, the courts applied what is known as the server
Speaker 4:  test and they said no copy of this photo
Speaker 4:  was ever made on buzzfeed. The photo still
Speaker 4:  existed on Instagram servers and the user's web
Speaker 4:  browser called Instagram servers. Thereby the
Speaker 4:  server test, which is now part of United States copyright law
Speaker 4:  is there's no copyright infringement with photographers loose.
Speaker 6:  But if Buzzfeed had screenshotted that Instagram and put it on its
Speaker 6:  site, it might have been a different fight.
Speaker 5:  And that's why you don't screenshot
Speaker 4:  And to the user, there's no difference in those things. Right, Right. Wild.
Speaker 4:  And we are, we are at, where is the copy I I'm gonna keep, I'm gonna end
Speaker 4:  up saying this on the show a thousand times during this AI battle copywriter
Speaker 4:  law is about copies the court in deciding whether embedding
Speaker 4:  an Instagram post on a Buzzfeed article is copyright infringement, goes
Speaker 4:  and finds the copy of the photo and it's on Instagram
Speaker 4:  server because that's where the photographer themselves put it in accordance
Speaker 4:  with Instagram's terms of service. And the court said, Nope, Buzzfeed can
Speaker 4:  use it for free because it's on Instagram server. And if they had
Speaker 4:  screenshotted it like David said and put it on a thing, which is to
Speaker 4:  you exactly the same experience and in many cases
Speaker 4:  good journalism practice. Right. Because Instagram could take a photo down.
Speaker 4:  Who knows? Like then they might have lost because the copy of the photo would've
Speaker 4:  been on Buzzfeed servers and that is the game,
Speaker 4:  like where is the copy? Yeah. And so the writers on, on their
Speaker 4:  side, they have copy, they have I mean it's hundreds of years of copyright
Speaker 4:  law about writing things down and making copies of them and putting them
Speaker 4:  here and who owns what's rights. And then you get to faces and you're like,
Speaker 4:  we just don't do this. There's, there's, there's a vacuum of
Speaker 4:  this because you can't do it. There's just never been occasion to care about
Speaker 4:  it before. Right, right. Yeah. You've made a copy of my face, you're like,
Speaker 4:  oh that's a, that's nothing. Yeah. That's what that is. Yeah. Right. Or
Speaker 4:  you've made a movie and like for me to be in your movie, there's some laws
Speaker 4:  about like my life, there's cases about re-edits of movies that you can,
Speaker 4:  like we've covered because they're complicated. But you've never
Speaker 4:  had the, you took my whole face and now you can use my face as many times
Speaker 4:  as you want. We
Speaker 5:  Have though. We like, we see this sometimes like in Hollywood there is a
Speaker 5:  little bit more law here. And, I'm
Speaker 4:  Yeah. California state law. Yeah. Because of Hollywood exists
Speaker 5:  Because like Sma Lou, the, the actor who was in Shang Chi
Speaker 5:  last year for Marvel, before he was a big famous actor, he went out and did
Speaker 5:  a whole bunch of photos for pub. Like just
Speaker 5:  yeah, go use them and show shutter soccer, whatever. And so then now
Speaker 5:  you can go find those and be like, put him put this big
Speaker 5:  celebrity
Speaker 4:  Like royalty free.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. This royalty free big celebrity thing. That was great. And and we've
Speaker 5:  seen this happen a couple of times and then they'll usually be
Speaker 4:  Like, but you can do that. You can't, he can't tell you to take him down
Speaker 4:  cause they're royalty free stock photos of him. Right.
Speaker 5:  But like but
Speaker 4:  Even that is a photo that's not his face. Yeah. You haven't
Speaker 4:  made him do something he wasn't doing before because you have a digital
Speaker 4:  model of his face. Yeah. And there's just no, as far
Speaker 4:  as I know, there's not like a great Framework for that. There's some in
Speaker 4:  some, once people have come up out of Hol cloth, like that horrible Will
Speaker 4:  Smith movie that they shot at 120 Hertz. Do you know what I'm talking
Speaker 4:  about? Gemini Man, if you watch it, the intended frame rate, it looks like
Speaker 4:  a CGI demo reel. It doesn't even look like A real movie. Like why'd you do
Speaker 4:  this? It's like an unreal engine commercial. Yeah, yeah. For that
Speaker 4:  movie. He signed a deal where I think he owns that model. He didn't
Speaker 4:  want the studio to have it, but he's Will Smith. He has the leverage to do
Speaker 4:  it. These background actors, they, they're only way to get leverage is
Speaker 4:  by going on strike.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And so that's what they're doing. They're all on strike and it's
Speaker 5:  gonna last a while. It seems like everybody's really entrenched in
Speaker 5:  their positions. The producers don't wanna give over more money. Cuz this
Speaker 5:  is ultimately, this all boils down to money, right? Yeah. Streaming makes
Speaker 5:  a lot of money. Streaming is we, we like to talk about, oh, which streamer
Speaker 5:  is gonna be go nine on the go nine day scale. But they all make money.
Speaker 5:  They're all doing pretty Okay. Some Netflix way better
Speaker 5:  than everybody else. Right. They're doing, they're doing great.
Speaker 4:  And Netflix, they rolled out the ad tier subscriptions went
Speaker 4:  up.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And Netflix also was one of the first to figure out how
Speaker 5:  to, I don't wanna say manipulate, but aggressively use
Speaker 5:  the current contracts to cut down on how much they pay
Speaker 5:  people. And that's what they're trying to get rid of. That's what they're
Speaker 5:  trying to fix. Right. And naturally Netflix doesn't
Speaker 5:  wanna help them on that cause they wanna keep all the money for themselves.
Speaker 4:  So Netflix is really interesting. It's time for the disclosure block.
Speaker 4:  We're way late on this. Yeah. I apologize. We're we're minutes late to this
Speaker 4:  series of escalating disclosures. Ooh one, we made
Speaker 4:  a Netflix show. I'm the EP of that Netflix show. It's called The Future of
Speaker 4:  You Should Go Watch It. Two. Our company makes all kinds of other Netflix
Speaker 4:  shows with all the other streamers that division, our company is called Box
Speaker 4:  Media Studios. You should watch everything they make and then send us cash
Speaker 4:  in an envelope. Our newsroom is unionized. The Writers School of America.
Speaker 5:  I'm in the wga. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  Here she is. It's true. She's she's on strike.
Speaker 5:  I'm not on strike. She's not on strike. I'm not, I'm not on a contract that
Speaker 5:  is currently on strike. Alex
Speaker 6:  Will not be in the background of your movie.
Speaker 5:  That too
Speaker 6:  Until future notice.
Speaker 4:  And then NBC is one of these company
Speaker 4:  Universal.
Speaker 5:  N yeah. NBC Universal is currently
Speaker 4:  Ooh And I own a chunk of Vox media. They
Speaker 6:  Do. We all watch shows from time to time. This,
Speaker 4:  There's, there's all,
Speaker 5:  They are actually at the heart of a lot of the, the, the strike stuff happening
Speaker 5:  this week. NBC Universal. Really?
Speaker 6:  Yep. Do so.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So this is, we're getting into TREE LAW now. Oh,
Speaker 4:  Here we go. TREE LAW.
Speaker 6:  All caps. TREE LAW. Just to be clear. Yes. This is not lowercase. This is
Speaker 6:  all caps.
Speaker 5:  NBC Universal is one of the many studios that is currently, they're,
Speaker 5:  they're having strikes outside of them. And so picket lines go out there
Speaker 5:  and they march and it's A real honest to God picket line. Like you see from
Speaker 5:  history. The
Speaker 6:  Signs are incredible by the way, just as a, as a side note, like an incredible
Speaker 6:  genre of the internet right now is writer and
Speaker 6:  actor picket signs. They're just phenomenal.
Speaker 5:  If you ever wanted to go meet an actor, they might be on a picket line right
Speaker 5:  now and you can go meet them, but you should also be picketing and like give
Speaker 5:  them water and stuff. Yeah. But so planned picket lines were to happen outside
Speaker 5:  of NBC Universal. They have a whole bunch of trees which provide lovely
Speaker 5:  shade. Those trees are owned by Los Angeles because
Speaker 5:  they're outside of the studio. Those trees were all mysteriously
Speaker 5:  trimmed just before the picket line was supposed to
Speaker 5:  happen. So there was no shade. And it's like a hundred degrees in
Speaker 5:  Hollywood right now. And so there was a lot. NBC Universal
Speaker 5:  said it's just standard. We always trim these trees down to the, like
Speaker 5:  the limbs,
Speaker 4:  The hubs.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. This is totally normal. It's fine. It's
Speaker 5:  not. LA is like investigating them because TREE, LAW,
Speaker 5:  TREE LAW, it's, you can't, that's not their trees to go trimming. And it's
Speaker 5:  apparently really bad to trim those trees to that length in the
Speaker 5:  summertime.
Speaker 4:  That's just cartoon villainy. Serious.
Speaker 6:  Seriously.
Speaker 4:  Like I was gonna say the thing about Netflix, which all the producers are
Speaker 4:  doing Cartoon villain in some way. Yeah. The true law thing is ridiculous.
Speaker 4:  Woof Netflix got a pass on this contractual obligation stuff, right? Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Because if you think back a year ago or two years ago, Netflix was
Speaker 4:  just writing checks. Nobody could match. Oh yeah. They're like, Shonda Rhimes,
Speaker 4:  here's a billion dollars. Make as many shows as you can. Right. And what
Speaker 4:  has turned is Netflix needed to be profitable. So stopped writing those
Speaker 4:  checks. It burned a lot of those creators by not renewing their shows.
Speaker 4:  It burned a lot of the fandoms of those shows. Yep. By not renewing the shows,
Speaker 4:  it has all this content. No one's making any residuals. And then the most
Speaker 4:  important thing is that all the other companies Chase Netflix into that business
Speaker 4:  model. Yep. So they all felt like they had to compete. They had to
Speaker 4:  outspend Netflix. So for a minute, Netflix is the industry hero cuz they're
Speaker 4:  writing big checks and they have a business model that seems to
Speaker 4:  work and they I mean it does because they're profitable. And then at the
Speaker 4:  other end of the Rainbow is, oh, the whole industry adopted this business
Speaker 4:  model. The, the financial structure of how
Speaker 4:  we get paid is now gone because we were addicted
Speaker 4:  to cable reruns and selling internationally
Speaker 4:  into different markets. And now it's all just on HBO Max or Peacock or
Speaker 4:  Netflix or whatever. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Cuz these shows are like, if you look at the contract, these shows look appear
Speaker 5:  differently in the contract. They don't appear as linear tv. They don't appear
Speaker 5:  as cable tv. And so in order to hit like that threshold to
Speaker 5:  start paying higher residuals, they have to make more content. And
Speaker 5:  it's usually like, I think after the second season is when things start to
Speaker 5:  go up. Which is why you see so many Netflix shows canceled after the second
Speaker 5:  season because then they, they don't have to pay increased
Speaker 5:  residuals. But Camika Glenn was a actress on Oranges of the
Speaker 5:  New Black. She was a main character on that show. She was in, I think she
Speaker 5:  started in like the second or third season is when she appeared on the show
Speaker 5:  in a ton of it. Main character making maybe if she's
Speaker 5:  lucky 50 cents per
Speaker 5:  episode in residuals when like she's a star of the
Speaker 5:  show. And that's most of that cast, which was all primarily
Speaker 5:  people who weren't normally seen on tv. Yeah. It was a big deal that they
Speaker 5:  all got these roles and they were all having to work second jobs,
Speaker 5:  their jobs to afford it. And it's still are like this did not open the world
Speaker 5:  to them and make them all fabulously ri rich. Maybe other shows did, if
Speaker 5:  they went were lucky and got a network show. But if you're on a streaming
Speaker 5:  show, you're not like, you cannot support yourself. You have
Speaker 5:  to have a second job. Which means you will see an actor you love at Target
Speaker 5:  and you should be really polite to them because they're probably working.
Speaker 5:  Just be chill.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. It's like Mandy Moore who is like a huge star and was
Speaker 6:  on This Is Us, which was a giant hit, was talking in an interview I think
Speaker 6:  this week about the residuals check that she's been getting from Hulu, which
Speaker 6:  now has, this is Us. And she said there was one check that was one penny.
Speaker 6:  There was one that was 2 cents. There was one that was 81 cents. It's like,
Speaker 6:  this is not it. This is not actual money that these folks are getting.
Speaker 6:  But the thing that I struggle with is, if you rewind
Speaker 6:  five years, there were a lot of very smart people who were
Speaker 6:  like waving their hands saying this is unsustainable. Netflix is spending
Speaker 6:  money, it doesn't have, it's in crazy debt. We're due for some consolidation.
Speaker 6:  This is all getting outta control. And for years, everybody just like
Speaker 6:  blissfully danced along and a lot of people made a lot of money off of these
Speaker 6:  streaming services. Like Shonda Rhimes made a ton of money and employed a
Speaker 6:  lot of people. And so was, were we
Speaker 6:  just always due for this correction? Yes. Is this is just the pendulum
Speaker 6:  swinging to the other side before we get to the middle.
Speaker 5:  This is totally cuz the WGA strike back in
Speaker 5:  2007 was about residuals then too for streaming.
Speaker 5:  They saw this was like totally nascent at this point that I think there were
Speaker 5:  like maybe three web series disclosure. I was actually
Speaker 5:  writing for one of those at the time. Yes. Good disclosure. It was Lifetime.
Speaker 5:  That's a disclosure.
Speaker 4:  That's so much better than my Joseph and the amazing technic code disclosure.
Speaker 5:  I, I wrote one episode. What was it called? It was, the show was called Inspector
Speaker 5:  Mom. Oh my
Speaker 4:  God. Incredible.
Speaker 5:  Wait, starring Janet Keller.
Speaker 4:  Danica Kel. Wow.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, she's lovely.
Speaker 4:  Wow. Yeah, it's fancy.
Speaker 5:  But so back in 2007 it was like us and Battle Star
Speaker 5:  Galactica. And I want you to be be cl very clear. We were
Speaker 5:  in no way in the same level as Battle Star Galactica. One
Speaker 4:  Of those, one of those was a hit. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  One of those, you know the other one you just learned
Speaker 5:  about. But there was, but there wasn't a lot. But everybody was super interested
Speaker 5:  in it. Yeah. And at the time, everybody was doing it as an ultra low
Speaker 5:  budget. And when you're producing these things as ultra low
Speaker 5:  budget, you don't have to pay as much. You, you can really dick
Speaker 5:  people around and you can pay them a lot less. You can pay your writers less,
Speaker 5:  you can pay your actor's list and everything like that. And they were like,
Speaker 5:  well, this is gonna be a whole new thing. We clearly need to make sure our
Speaker 5:  writers get paid. And so that's why they went on strike back in
Speaker 5:  2007 to, to make sure that they were gonna get that money. And they
Speaker 5:  were really not as aggressive as they should have been. There was a big argument
Speaker 5:  within the WGA about it at the time. The people who
Speaker 5:  were like, don't worry about it. One, all the other people were like, what
Speaker 5:  did we say for the last 15 years? Yeah. And so now we're at this point, like
Speaker 5:  they've been waiting for a very long time. This was
Speaker 5:  always probably going to happen. And I. Think the biggest surprise is that
Speaker 5:  the dga, the Director's Guild isn't a part of this
Speaker 5:  because so many, I think the reason that didn't happen for them
Speaker 5:  is so many of them are also producers. Much more of them
Speaker 5:  like Standard are producers as well. So they're like, this
Speaker 5:  works for us, we're fine. Yeah, we can, we can make it work.
Speaker 4:  But they're also and directors in a very real way. You
Speaker 4:  can't copy their work. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Like, like a lot of those big existential questions that are facing
Speaker 5:  the writers and the actors directors don't have to deal
Speaker 5:  with and, and these other ones are having to face that like writers having
Speaker 5:  to face. Okay, if the producer like goes and
Speaker 5:  writes a prompt and sends me that prompt that like writes a
Speaker 5:  prompt. ChatGPT spits something out, he sends that to
Speaker 5:  me. Who owns the And I Write a whole script. Do I own the
Speaker 5:  copyright to my script? Does ChatGPT own the copyright to the script? Does
Speaker 5:  the guy who like busted out a quick prompt own the copyright to my
Speaker 5:  script and everything in it and all the, the, the intellectual material.
Speaker 5:  Like they gave me 150 words. And I turned that into a two hour
Speaker 5:  movie. Why should the studio get to own that?
Speaker 4:  So again, there's just a long history of concepts. Yeah. That
Speaker 4:  might help you answer that question. I don't know what, where they're gonna
Speaker 4:  land. What I, what I know is the
Speaker 4:  money that they're looking for. The challenge is that
Speaker 4:  either it doesn't exist the way that it used to
Speaker 4:  or it exists, but it's flowing to the
Speaker 4:  CEOs slash it's being used to fund
Speaker 4:  vastly more projects than before. So friends, I think friends is like the
Speaker 4:  example here. All the people who made friends are rich and they're gonna
Speaker 4:  keep being rich and whatever. They're doing great, they're doing great. Seinfeld,
Speaker 4:  another example, they made friends, they put it on broadcast
Speaker 4:  television. They sold a bunch of ads against that broadcast television. They
Speaker 4:  paid all the actors a million dollars an episode for friends because just
Speaker 4:  that first cut was so valuable with ads on broadcast television. Everybody
Speaker 4:  watched it every Thursday. Then they sold it again
Speaker 4:  to four syn countries and to syndication and the cable networks. Then they
Speaker 4:  sold it at 15th time to Netflix. Then I came off of Netflix and
Speaker 4:  they sold it at 16th time to, what is it, Hulu? Where is it now? Wherever
Speaker 4:  it is now. I
Speaker 6:  Think it's on Peacock now.
Speaker 4:  It's on Peacock.
Speaker 5:  It's on Peacock, yeah.
Speaker 4:  Where they sold it to themselves the last time.
Speaker 6:  Well, and it was a big deal. Do you remember how big a deal that was actually?
Speaker 6:  Because they were leaving a ton of money on the table to bring it back to
Speaker 6:  Peacock as a big bet on what Peacock was like. Do that, that thing held its
Speaker 6:  value for so long.
Speaker 4:  Right? Because it's a, it's an asset. Like it's a very, I don't know, you
Speaker 4:  make a widget and you can sell it however many times. The Stream model is,
Speaker 4:  you make a show and you sell it once.
Speaker 4:  Yep. Probably to yourself. And then you hope it brings in
Speaker 4:  subscribers and you, you kinda end up in this horrible Spotify situation
Speaker 4:  where you're like, okay, you pay me $9 a month. You what? You play this much
Speaker 4:  Taylor Swift. We're gonna divide up the total number of streams. And Taylor
Speaker 4:  Swift gets a penny, but she gets a billion streams. So it's a billion. And
Speaker 4:  like the contractor they're negotiating now has to contend with that math
Speaker 4:  versus the, we made you a show and you have sold it for
Speaker 4:  dollars over and over and over again. Now it's, we made you a
Speaker 4:  show and you're gonna sell it for pennies once.
Speaker 5:  Well see we're seeing a big change there. Like David Z. Love, love to rip
Speaker 5:  on the guy. Cartoonish fell in in many ways, but, but he is big on
Speaker 5:  like, show doesn't work for us or whatever. We can go and sell it again.
Speaker 5:  We saw that with Westworld. And, I think we're gonna see more of that. Especially
Speaker 5:  some of it is we need to unload these assets that just aren't doing it for
Speaker 5:  us. Maybe they'll do better on Peacock because nobody
Speaker 5:  subscribes to Peacock except for me.
Speaker 4:  Maybe do Better on Peacock. That's gonna save the industry. That's a, that's
Speaker 4:  a sign, that's a strike sign right there.
Speaker 5:  But, but they, they are thinking about like we, we like, they're starting
Speaker 5:  to think about how we need to sell these things and, and make more money
Speaker 5:  off of it. The studios are thinking that. Not just the, the writers and actors
Speaker 5:  and producers and everybody who are making no money in
Speaker 5:  per perpetuity on these projects. So I think we
Speaker 5:  are gonna see some changes there. I think we're gonna see kind of a
Speaker 5:  return to some extent of that current like that TV model from 10,
Speaker 5:  15 years ago. And I don't think it's gonna be as lucrative as it was then.
Speaker 5:  And it's
Speaker 6:  Gonna be 2003. Again, this is just what we're doing here. And I. Think
Speaker 5:  We're gonna see. I think what we're really gonna find out is how powerful
Speaker 5:  the Netflix voting block and the Producers union is.
Speaker 5:  Or the producers Guild. That's the real thing. Cuz Netflix
Speaker 5:  doesn't wanna ever move to that model. They wanna have everything owned by
Speaker 5:  them and then never pay you residuals. A lot of these other studios have
Speaker 5:  been doing this a lot longer and they're gonna be more inclined
Speaker 5:  to go in a different direction. So we're gonna see, I'm really
Speaker 5:  curious to See how this ends.
Speaker 4:  I think it's gonna be a long time. I think we're in for,
Speaker 5:  We're in for mid months
Speaker 4:  Into, into winter. Yep. Basically. All right. We gotta take a break. We come
Speaker 4:  back. We're gonna do lightning round. Maybe some more gadgets. Yeah, I talk
Speaker 4:  some CMS. People have asked before. We'll be right
Speaker 4:  back.
Speaker 4:  We're back. Lightning around time. We went way over. We're already over.
Speaker 4:  Oh yeah.
Speaker 5:  You get me talking about unions in Hollywood. Whew. That's you in
Speaker 5:  copyright.
Speaker 4:  That's and it's all at the same time. Oh my
Speaker 5:  God. Poor David. Sorry.
Speaker 4:  David's just been holding up a stopwatch in the background. Like red cards,
Speaker 4:  like Stop, stop Nerds, please. Nerd.
Speaker 4:  Car going off Cliff. All right. Lightning round. David, you wanna
Speaker 4:  start?
Speaker 6:  Sure. So, well, I have two. One is just that
Speaker 6:  Andrew Marino, And I figured out why there's a Palm Pilot in your favorite
Speaker 6:  IMAX theater and you should go read our story. Very good. The answer turns
Speaker 6:  out to be like very small and slightly boring, but also deeply hilarious
Speaker 6:  and it makes me very happy.
Speaker 4:  Can I just say, the sourcing of that story is incredible cuz you keep referring
Speaker 4:  to a well-placed sort and it's like, I'm not, I'm not gonna reveal who it
Speaker 4:  is. It just, it makes it sound like you're reporting on the CIA in the best
Speaker 4:  possible way. I
Speaker 6:  Think the, the truth of the matter is there aren't that many people who
Speaker 6:  know. Let's just say that it's my source is Christopher Nolan.
Speaker 6:  Let's just, just, let's just do it now. No, I wanna talk just very
Speaker 6:  briefly about this new thing called the US Cyber Trust Mark, which
Speaker 6:  is basically a label that is going to be affixed to
Speaker 6:  products that are, I don't know, safe in a
Speaker 6:  cybersecurity way. And I. Both want to know what you guys think of the
Speaker 6:  logo, which I have deeply mixed feelings about. To me it looks like a, like
Speaker 6:  second tier Turkish soccer team. Crest. That's the
Speaker 6:  vibe I get here. But it's like a shield with some
Speaker 6:  dots and some lines
Speaker 5:  Too busy.
Speaker 6:  It's just not great. And this is supposed to connote like the, this is an
Speaker 6:  Official government approved
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Cyber secure thing. To me, this strikes me as a good idea
Speaker 6:  in theory, right? Like having a thing that is like this is a secure device
Speaker 6:  that has passed some measure of testing and will not do sketchy things. Great
Speaker 6:  idea. It's along the lines of the like, you know, privacy, nutrition
Speaker 6:  labels. Apple does in the app store. Big fan. I don't see any
Speaker 6:  world in which this is enforceable or holds up
Speaker 6:  over time. Threats change devices change standards
Speaker 6:  change things go outta date. There's always some new hack. And the idea
Speaker 6:  that one of the things they wanna do is put a QR code on the box so you can
Speaker 6:  scan the QR code to see if it's up to date and still safe. So
Speaker 6:  actually the badge doesn't mean anything. You have to scan the QR code to
Speaker 6:  see if the badge still applies. I just think this is one of those like good
Speaker 6:  ideas that nobody actually thought all the way through. And
Speaker 5:  If I was a horrible person, I would go print out a bunch of these
Speaker 5:  fake labels and put 'em on real products and like Best Buy and
Speaker 5:  then, and then
Speaker 6:  Have people
Speaker 5:  Shit out. Yeah. When then when people scan it, oh my God.
Speaker 5:  Just, I don't have the technological know-how and I'm not
Speaker 5:  that horrible yet, so I won't do this. But like, it seems like a very
Speaker 5:  easy way to cheat this system and screw over a lot of people also. It's
Speaker 5:  ugly.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It's, it's not beautiful.
Speaker 6:  Yes. I'm, I'm really out. But like,
Speaker 4:  Are they gonna make like a beautiful label that's like insecure wifi?
Speaker 5:  You know, the UL label is gorgeous.
Speaker 4:  No one knows what that means.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I don't know what it means, but I know it's pretty
Speaker 6:  That's fair. But my thing with this is I think like the, the one of the
Speaker 6:  comparisons that the FCC, Jeff Jess Rosen made is to like the
Speaker 6:  Energy Star logo. Yeah. Which is a useful thing, right? And they're talking
Speaker 6:  about this a lot with Right to repair stuff too. That you should have these
Speaker 6:  quick visual signals that like this passes some kind of
Speaker 6:  test that I approve of, right? Like it is, it is energy certified. That's
Speaker 6:  good. It the vibes are good. Right? And with right to repair, it's like that's
Speaker 6:  good too. And this one just seems way
Speaker 6:  higher stakes because you're, what you're asking me to do is make like A
Speaker 6:  real problematic decision about this thing. Whether
Speaker 6:  it is safe or not for me to use based on this label. And with
Speaker 6:  that just would need to come this really complicated enforcement mechanism
Speaker 6:  that I'm not sure is even really possible to do. Well
Speaker 5:  I like that even the Official
Speaker 5:  like mockup of it from the FCC is hard to
Speaker 5:  read. Like you have to do some really bad design
Speaker 5:  to be like Yeah, it's also terrible to read. It's, I'm just,
Speaker 5:  it's ugly. And I. Think you're right. Like how are you supposed to, nothing
Speaker 5:  is secure if it's connected to the, the internet, it's in some way can
Speaker 5:  be hacked. Someone will figure it out. Well yeah, but
Speaker 4:  I, yes, I, I agree with you broadly on that front. That's
Speaker 4:  how
Speaker 5:  I have lived my life.
Speaker 4:  She said with her Laptop and phone and smartwatch hack
Speaker 4:  me. That's true. But like, we've now covered
Speaker 4:  enough fly by night products. Yeah. I'm thinking
Speaker 4:  of wise, right? Where they made claims, they're backed up by no
Speaker 4:  one. They're unenforceable cuz they're backed up by no one. Like this is
Speaker 4:  a very sort of like, how does a market capitalist
Speaker 4:  government fix problems? Like this is like, we'll put a
Speaker 4:  nutrition label on it. Yeah. And like, this is the answer to every question
Speaker 4:  is like, consumers will count calories, but for gadgets. But like, at least
Speaker 4:  if you put this label on and you lie, you people can
Speaker 4:  sue you.
Speaker 5:  That's
Speaker 4:  True. And that fair is as much of a corrective as anything.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Okay. I'll
Speaker 6:  Give you that. I almost feel like it should be more like the, the like surgeon
Speaker 6:  general's warning on a pack of cigarettes that's just like this thing connects
Speaker 6:  to the internet. Be worried about that is like that's, I, that feels to me
Speaker 6:  like it would be more immediately productive. Yeah. Update.
Speaker 4:  Often the difference between the American surgeon general warning and like
Speaker 4:  the British one is that we, we should do the British ones. Like in Europe,
Speaker 4:  the cigarettes should say, this will kill you. Yeah. Here it's like
Speaker 4:  Surgeon general's warning a bunch of stuff. And like over there it's like
Speaker 4:  death. Death lurks here. Delicious
Speaker 4:  death. You'll never stop thinking about it for the rest of your life. If
Speaker 4:  you do this in your twenties.
Speaker 5:  Neil's just quietly pulling the cigarette out as we speak.
Speaker 4:  Oh my God. So good. The first one after a drink, but
Speaker 4:  it'll kill you. All right, I'll stop now.
Speaker 5:  I was like, I don't even smoke And. I. Want a cigarette now?
Speaker 4:  Have you ever had one of these after a big dinner? Woo. That'll kill you
Speaker 4:  for sure.
Speaker 5:  Steak dinner covered in butter.
Speaker 4:  This is the worst lighting round.
Speaker 6:  That's mine. Neil, what's yours? Wait, I'm sorry. You have four assigns to
Speaker 6:  you here. This podcast has been very long. Pick one
Speaker 4:  All I'm picking one. I'm gonna pick the WordPress one. Okay. Yeah. So our
Speaker 4:  company this week announced that we're switching CMSs. This
Speaker 4:  is so nerdy, but people ask me to talk about it. So if you have been
Speaker 4:  following us since 2011, you know that right now one of our
Speaker 4:  CMSs that we use is a proprietary CMS called Chorus that we have made a lot
Speaker 4:  of noise about over the decade of this company. Chorus
Speaker 4:  is a lot of things. If you are a webinar nerd, you know that a CMS
Speaker 4:  is. It's the database from which we serve the
Speaker 4:  website. And CMSs can do an awful lot of things at a
Speaker 4:  basic level. The CMS is a text editor and a database of
Speaker 4:  content. And sometimes it's also the front end of the
Speaker 4:  website. So you, you can separate those things with our
Speaker 4:  redesign. We decoupled the front end of the website. The thing that you all
Speaker 4:  look at at The Verge dot com from the back end, which is what we all type
Speaker 4:  in. So now through an api, you go to Verge dot com, the API pulls
Speaker 4:  outta the database, whatever, which means you can sw swap out the backend
Speaker 4:  of the thing. We already use multiple CMSs to
Speaker 4:  make The Verge all the time. One of our CMSs is Google Sheets. And. I
Speaker 4:  Promise you every big publisher from the time on Down has content that is
Speaker 4:  served out of Google Sheets.
Speaker 6:  I can confirm this. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  It's just a useful, like, it's a really powerful spreadsheet that never
Speaker 4:  goes down. Like you could, if you need to make that kind of thing, you can
Speaker 4:  do it. When we do our live blogs, we use a CMS called NorCon
Speaker 4:  Live Center, which hilariously is, I think most of our clients are like English
Speaker 4:  Premier League blogs. So there's a bunch of features in Live
Speaker 4:  Center that I always want to use that make no sense. Like a running
Speaker 4:  score tally
Speaker 6:  A button that just says Goal.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, that's like very funny. We, I just, I'm dying to use
Speaker 4:  those features. If you can figure them out, we'll do them in the next Apple
Speaker 4:  event. But that's another CMS we use. I I think all of you know, I'm excited
Speaker 4:  about Activity Pub. I think plugging a social
Speaker 4:  network into our stack of things, you can
Speaker 4:  See how a threads post and a quick post on our front page are closer in
Speaker 4:  spirit than not. There's a lot you could do there if you think of that as
Speaker 4:  a CMS. So we're swapping out chorus, which
Speaker 4:  is our main CMS that we write most things in for WordPress. But we're keeping
Speaker 4:  the front end experience of the site cuz we've decoupled the two things.
Speaker 4:  That's the answer it. And it's a big emotional decision at our
Speaker 4:  company. A lot of us, I, most of my life's work has
Speaker 4:  been produced in chorus. There, there it is. I I, I feel a
Speaker 4:  way about it, but people ask me why it's happening. Cause I saw the Axios
Speaker 4:  article and it's, you wanna spend your developer effort on
Speaker 4:  building new kinds of products. Not making a word processor in a
Speaker 4:  database. That's, that's life and software. I keep sending people the video
Speaker 4:  of Steve Jobs doing a funeral for macOS nine. I don't think this is going
Speaker 4:  over as well as I wanted to, but I think it's very funny. Jesus, that's what
Speaker 4:  I got for you. All right. What's your lightning around Alex?
Speaker 5:  Omar thought he ordered coffee this week. Okay. And he's like, wait a minute.
Speaker 5:  I don't, I don't use the Starbucks app that often. And it was because there
Speaker 5:  was a bug with a Starbucks app and so it told a whole bunch of users that
Speaker 5:  they all ordered coffee this week. Amazing. Very good. Everybody was like,
Speaker 5:  wait a minute, but I didn't And I. Just think that's
Speaker 6:  Hysterical. Was it the intern? This is my favorite thing that happens. Like
Speaker 6:  when that, what was it? The HBO sent that test email to like millions of
Speaker 6:  people a while ago. Cuz somebody pressed the wrong thing. It's like
Speaker 6:  when, when you hit the, when you mean to hit the test button and you accidentally
Speaker 6:  hit the, send this to everybody button it just know that it always makes
Speaker 6:  me happy every single time.
Speaker 5:  What they, what they told Omar was earlier today, a push notification from
Speaker 5:  the Starbucks app was sent as an error. So yes,
Speaker 5:  it probably was. And then turned
Speaker 6:  Somebody clicked the wrong button. Boop.
Speaker 5:  Yep. Everybody got coffee. Nobody's getting free coffee out of this. You
Speaker 5:  still have to pay for coffee at Starbucks.
Speaker 6:  But I do. It's also like Starbucks should learn from this because
Speaker 6:  this is an incredible marketing thing to do to just randomly ping
Speaker 6:  someone's phone and say your order is ready. It's like, oh yeah. The
Speaker 6:  Pavlovian thing that would happen to me where I would just go to Starbucks
Speaker 6:  if I got that notification, I'd be like, I don't remember ordering Starbucks,
Speaker 6:  but there's like a 60% chance I did. I'm gonna go, it would work.
Speaker 6:  I'm just saying Starbucks.
Speaker 4:  I would definitely think that my identity had been stolen. I would've a vastly
Speaker 4:  different response. I'd be like, I need to throw my phone in the ocean right
Speaker 4:  away and call my mom. Like
Speaker 5:  I would just assume I blacked out and ordered Starbucks.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, fair enough. I can't believe we just gave Starbucks this idea. I'm
Speaker 4:  so sorry. Talk about engagement based
Speaker 5:  To delete the Starbucks app.
Speaker 6:  Did I ever tell you about the time I gave Amazon an idea
Speaker 6:  for an ad that they used and didn't give me credit for? And I'm furious about
Speaker 6:  it.
Speaker 4:  Gee, you should go on strike. Yeah, go
Speaker 5:  On strike. Don't give
Speaker 4:  Your ideas. We're way over. We will tell you that story next week. Fair enough.
Speaker 4:  On this The Vergecast, some things I want you to read on our site, we
Speaker 4:  have an excerpt of John Romero's autobiography Doom Guy, which is a story
Speaker 4:  of S software. Go read that. It's a great story's great good yarn. And then
Speaker 4:  McKenna Kelly wrote an incredible profile of Gigi Sohn and how her
Speaker 4:  nomination to be an Fs sec commissioner was basically
Speaker 4:  just overturned by weird, dark money in telecom lobbyists.
Speaker 4:  It'll make you angry, but in a like a righteous way, it's good's. Great.
Speaker 4:  That's a good feeling. You wanna harness that, that feeling. And then on
Speaker 4:  the Dakota, I asked the CEO, Squarespace, why anyone should make a website
Speaker 4:  And. I'm pretty sure I sold him a pressure washer. That's, it's a weird
Speaker 4:  one. It was. It was those, those two
Speaker 4:  ideas, I promise they connect. It was great. Okay, that's it.
Speaker 4:  That's for
Speaker 4:  Chas
Speaker 1:  And that's a wrap for Vergecast this week. We'd love to hear from you. Shoot
Speaker 1:  us an email at Vergecast The Verge dot com. The Vergecast is a
Speaker 1:  production of The Verge and the Vox Media Podcast network. The show is produced
Speaker 1:  by me, Liam James, and our senior audio director, Andrew Marino. Our
Speaker 1:  editorial director is Brooke Minters. That's it. We'll see you next week.