# Transcript
ID: 326ca05d-3537-46c1-a270-877403b51ec0
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Samsung foldable software, eye-scanning orbs, and the future of the arcade
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/6875978995141352667/5416438324661530522/s93290-US-5306s-1690962810.mp3
Description: Today on the flagship podcast of texting on the outside screen:
03:28 - The Verge’s David Pierce chats with Allison Johnson and Dan Seifert about the software design of Samsung’s new Galaxy Z Flip 5 and Galaxy Z Fold 5.
32:54 - David takes a trip to the Dave & Busters to find out why the games on your phone ended up in your local arcade.
49:48 - Alex Heath joins the show to discuss his experience getting his eye scanned by an orb from Worldcoin, a crypto startup co-founded by OpenAI CEO Sam Altman.
1:14:45 - Our hotline question of the week about wearables without screens.
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we love hearing from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Disabled
Speaker 2:  Welcome to The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of texting on the outside
Speaker 2:  screen. I'm your friend David Pierce. And. I am doing a little belated
Speaker 2:  digital spring cleaning. Normally every few months I try to back up
Speaker 2:  all my important documents, put all my photos on an external hard drive that
Speaker 2:  I keep in a safe, clean up my computer, all that good stuff. This year
Speaker 2:  I've done a bad job of keeping on top of all that. So in my spare moments
Speaker 2:  this week I'm trying to catch up. Today's project is to clean up some of
Speaker 2:  the old stuff in my downloads folder. Actually, should we just do this together?
Speaker 2:  You wanna hear what's in here? This is sort of terrifying. Let's see. Okay,
Speaker 2:  we go to date added and we go to oldest first.
Speaker 2:  First thing I have is a bunch of PDFs of boring minutes
Speaker 2:  from F C C meetings for some reason, not really sure what that's about.
Speaker 2:  I have screenshots from a Slack redesign. I have a bunch of receipts
Speaker 2:  from food that I don't think I actually care about at all.
Speaker 2:  I have a photo of a weird thing that Starbucks did where they
Speaker 2:  made a thing that looks like, I think they were Galaxy Buds
Speaker 2:  headphones case, but it looks like a latte. Sure. I have
Speaker 2:  a picture of that meme that says I'm, you know,
Speaker 2:  I'm not reading all that but I'm happy for you. Or sorry that happened. I
Speaker 2:  have that picture here somewhere. I guess I used that. I have a bunch of
Speaker 2:  photos of apps that I can't even identify as I'm sitting
Speaker 2:  here. Oh, one of them is the weather app for I iPad oss. I have
Speaker 2:  audio of my baby's first heartbeat. That's nice. I'll keep that. I have a
Speaker 2:  bunch of pictures of the Lego n e s system for you know,
Speaker 2:  obvious reasons. A lot of old pictures. I have a bunch of U p s
Speaker 2:  labels that I for sure don't need anymore. This is the point,
Speaker 2:  right? This is why I need to do this more than once a year because otherwise
Speaker 2:  I go back and I'm like, why do I have a four megabyte image of
Speaker 2:  a Kindle cover just chilling on my computer, do some spring cleaning
Speaker 2:  folks. It helps. Anyway, we have a great show coming up for you today. We're
Speaker 2:  gonna dig back into the new Samsung phones, the Z Flip five and Z Fold five
Speaker 2:  and try to figure out what they can actually do that makes them special
Speaker 2:  and see if as a result you might need more flip and Fold in your life.
Speaker 2:  Then we're gonna talk about Arcade and how it happened that the games on
Speaker 2:  your phone ended up in your local arcade. This is the thing I've been wondering
Speaker 2:  about for a while and we finally, I think got to the bottom of it. And finally
Speaker 2:  we're gonna talk about Worldcoin, one of the most ambitious, bizarre,
Speaker 2:  and frankly interesting crypto things you've ever seen. All that's coming
Speaker 2:  up in just a sec. But first I have to do my number one favorite
Speaker 2:  ritual in all of the digital spring cleaning process, which is just to
Speaker 2:  select everything in my downloads folder that's either a screenshot, a zip
Speaker 2:  file, or more than a year old. And just delete It all feels so
Speaker 2:  good. Y'all And I have never regretted it Once. This is The
Speaker 2:  Vergecast. We'll be right back.
Speaker 3:  Right now the biggest song of the year so far is a country song
Speaker 3:  last night by Morgan Wallen. But in spite of country's
Speaker 3:  dominance, country radio by the numbers
Speaker 3:  is still more than 99% white.
Speaker 4:  What is it about country music that has not changed the way
Speaker 4:  rock music has changed the way hip hop has changed soul r and b,
Speaker 4:  how is that possible? How is that feasible?
Speaker 3:  We talk country's race problem this week on Intuit
Speaker 3:  Vultures Pop Culture podcast.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. So we talked on the show last week about the new Samsung
Speaker 2:  phones, the Z Flip five and the Z Fold five. But I wanna
Speaker 2:  dig back into them, especially now that we've had a chance to actually try
Speaker 2:  the phones a bit because I continue to think the most interesting question
Speaker 2:  about these phones is just what do they actually add to your
Speaker 2:  life? This is true of all flip phones and foldable phones by the way. Does
Speaker 2:  having a small screen that folds into a big screen
Speaker 2:  meaningfully actually change what you can do with your phone
Speaker 2:  and how you do it? What about a phone that folds closed? Does that
Speaker 2:  do anything? So much of Samsung's efforts with the Z Flip and the Z
Speaker 2:  Fold series, especially on the software side, have been about trying to find
Speaker 2:  answers to that question. And I think every year it gets a little bit closer.
Speaker 2:  So I wanna see what's actually happened this year and whether we think
Speaker 2:  Samsung's really getting there. And as always, when we're talking about this
Speaker 2:  stuff, there are just two people in the world I really need here with me.
Speaker 2:  The Verge is Allison Johnson and Dan Seaford. Hi Allison. Hello
Speaker 2:  Dan. Hello,
Speaker 6:  Hello.
Speaker 2:  My Flip and Fold people. This is, this is what has happened. This is what
Speaker 2:  we have come to and it makes me very happy that anytime I want to litigate
Speaker 2:  flip and Fold phones, I have to do it with the two of you. So Allison, you
Speaker 2:  have these phones now, correct? The last, I was on vacation last week. I
Speaker 2:  listened to the podcast. You seem devastated that you did not have the phones
Speaker 2:  yet. There was
Speaker 5:  A devastating 48 hours where I did not have the phones. And I was supposed
Speaker 5:  to, but it's resolved. I have them all as well.
Speaker 2:  Okay, I'm, I'm very happy to hear this. Dan, do you, did you get the phones
Speaker 2:  this year?
Speaker 6:  I did not. Ah, so I'm living vicariously through Allison's experience.
Speaker 2:  Samsung, how could you, that's what we're gonna do here. We're gonna spend
Speaker 2:  the next 30 minutes talking about why Samsung didn't send you a review unit.
Speaker 2:  Stan, this is gonna be great.
Speaker 6:  In all fairness to Samsung, I did get a pile of tablets this morning.
Speaker 6:  So
Speaker 2:  One of which is, if I remember correctly, 40 to 60 inches in screen
Speaker 2:  size. Okay. Did you hang
Speaker 5:  It on the wall?
Speaker 6:  Okay.
Speaker 2:  So y'all did a segment Allison last week about the phones and we
Speaker 2:  got a bunch of responses from people saying talk more about how these things
Speaker 2:  work. Which I actually think is interesting and very instructive because
Speaker 2:  especially with flip and foldable phones, we're
Speaker 2:  still in the like what are these things for phase and
Speaker 2:  Samsung as we've talked about, is deeper down the what are
Speaker 2:  these things for road than just about anybody and has some truly wild ideas.
Speaker 2:  But I want to like get back into this idea of are these things
Speaker 2:  meaningfully different? Do they change the way that you experience and use
Speaker 2:  and interact with your phone? Is it worth right now like the extra cost
Speaker 2:  but also the trade-offs that you make in order to get one of these over the
Speaker 2:  candy bar phones we've all spent with the last decade? So
Speaker 2:  let's start with the flip. 'cause I think this year that seems to be the
Speaker 2:  most interesting one and also the place where Samsung pushed the
Speaker 2:  hardest on the software. Allison. Let's talk about the outside screen
Speaker 2:  first because as we have talked about the, these big outside screens make
Speaker 2:  a big difference and in this case it seems like just poking around and looking
Speaker 2:  at videos. This thing Samsung did, I think it's called the, the flex window
Speaker 2:  where you can, you can basically like swipe through a bunch of widgets on
Speaker 2:  the outside and you have this sort of big, almost smart watchy
Speaker 2:  looking thing that you can mess around with. What's been your
Speaker 2:  impression so far? How does it feel?
Speaker 5:  It's great and I'm gonna compare it to the Motorola Razor 'cause that's
Speaker 5:  kind of the only reference I have. But my quick take
Speaker 5:  is that I like how Samsung is handling
Speaker 5:  widgets. The widgets that they have that you swipe through on the cover screen
Speaker 5:  are just way better, like way more informative. You've got like
Speaker 5:  weather in your calendar and set a quick timer.
Speaker 5:  There's more ways to interact with them and
Speaker 5:  view them. You can like pinch and zoom out and you'll see them
Speaker 5:  all kind of in a tile interface. So that's, that's one
Speaker 5:  point for Samsung here. And this is, I wanna preface like
Speaker 5:  this is like sicko territory of like using flip phones,
Speaker 5:  running full apps. I'm liking better on
Speaker 5:  the Motorola phone and they're both kind of like, they
Speaker 5:  both put the, the option to run like a full app on the cover
Speaker 5:  screen kind of out of sight 'cause it's maybe not a great idea.
Speaker 2:  No, it's objectively no maybe involved. It's, it's a bad idea and you shouldn't
Speaker 2:  do it.
Speaker 5:  But it is, it's surprisingly like Samsung kind of puts it at
Speaker 5:  more of an arm's length. Like you can add Google maps
Speaker 5:  and messaging like without jumping through too many hoops
Speaker 5:  it's in the labs feature. But if you wanna do anything beyond that you have
Speaker 5:  to and you have to go to the Galaxy store
Speaker 2:  Where everyone goes from time to time.
Speaker 5:  Yeah you have to download Good Luck and then you have to download like
Speaker 5:  a specific module for good luck to
Speaker 5:  enable a launcher for the cover screen.
Speaker 6:  I just wanna jump in and say if you are a sicko,
Speaker 6:  good luck is like your favorite best friend ever. Like, like good luck
Speaker 6:  is the reason to create the stupid Samsung account to get to the stupid Samsung
Speaker 6:  store and download it. Especially if like you really want to like
Speaker 6:  do anything with your Samsung device. I think the people that make Sam
Speaker 6:  the Good Luck modules and stuff are all a bunch of like really
Speaker 6:  nerdy Samsung engineers that just wanna do weird stuff with these, this hardware
Speaker 6:  and that is like, that is your path to do that. So yeah, keep going. Allison,
Speaker 6:  I just wanna say good luck. It's a lot of fun. Well
Speaker 2:  And I, I, I will say to that point actually one of the things that seems
Speaker 2:  to have happened with this round of these phones is that Samsung
Speaker 2:  is pushing more towards the thing it's gotten better at with the galaxies
Speaker 2:  over the years. Which is like giving you lots to do but only
Speaker 2:  sort of showing you the easy stuff. Or like for years
Speaker 2:  you I I, my experience is always I would get Samsung's newest phone,
Speaker 2:  it would boot up, I would log in with my Google account and then it would
Speaker 2:  present me 1000 options. And I had to make a decision about
Speaker 2:  every one of those 1000 options and they eventually got to the
Speaker 2:  point where they're like, okay, there's still a thousand options and if you
Speaker 2:  want to do stuff there's more stuff to do on a Samsung phone than basically
Speaker 2:  anybody else. But they've done a much better job of saying here are the things
Speaker 2:  we wanna sort of put in front of you and then here are the things we wanna
Speaker 2:  let you find. And. I feel like good luck is a perfect example of like, it's
Speaker 2:  great that that exists. I think it's awesome that that exists. That absolutely
Speaker 2:  is not a thing that most people should even need to know exists.
Speaker 2:  Yeah
Speaker 6:  And they won't find it either. Like right to know about good luck means
Speaker 6:  that you have to have been told about good luck. Right, right, right. Either
Speaker 6:  through a blog or your friend or something.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. You typed into Google how do I do this on my Samsung phone?
Speaker 5:  Exactly. Yeah. I just think it's interesting that Motorola like
Speaker 5:  doesn't make it that hard. There's sort of an apps panel
Speaker 5:  for the cover screen and then you, you go in and you enable every app
Speaker 5:  individually and it gives you a warning or something. It's like this might
Speaker 5:  be a dumb idea but it's much more like permissive. And there are
Speaker 5:  certain apps I think are pretty good and like helpful to have on the cover
Speaker 5:  screen like Google Maps, which you wanna glance at some
Speaker 5:  directions. Like I'm the worst when I get out of like not in
Speaker 5:  Seattle but like out of a subway stop. I'm like, I have no idea which, oh
Speaker 5:  yeah. Direction I need to be going. And that's when you just kinda like
Speaker 5:  glance at Google
Speaker 6:  Maps. I'm, I'm curious, I assume that both Motorola and Samsung have like
Speaker 6:  a widget to like play pause and skip your music tracks
Speaker 6:  that's playing, but can you run, I guess you can
Speaker 6:  force like Spotify to run if you wanted to like browse
Speaker 6:  to a different playlist or something like that. Is that like a, a thing that
Speaker 6:  is like feasible or doable or even a good experience if you do that
Speaker 5:  So questionable whether it's a good experience? So the way Motorola
Speaker 5:  does it, there's a Spotify widget like specifically okay
Speaker 5:  it's broken like most of the time so it's
Speaker 5:  not very helpful. you know the bulk, they'll both give you the like media
Speaker 5:  player like pause or fast forward whatever happens to be playing.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. If you want to browse Spotify or do anything
Speaker 5:  beyond that and the Samsung phone, you gotta do the good luck thing.
Speaker 5:  And then I was just looking through it and like I got a popup
Speaker 5:  about some new Spotify feature. I was like well this is blocking the
Speaker 5:  whole screen and I need to quit this app now. So
Speaker 5:  not great on either. I
Speaker 2:  Suspect that stuff will get better. And I do think one of the interesting
Speaker 2:  questions developers are gonna have to ask is like what is our outside screen
Speaker 2:  experience gonna be? Because the, you can just run the full
Speaker 2:  app thing as a useful hack, but if these phones are gonna get popular and
Speaker 2:  they're not there yet, but if they are going to get there over time
Speaker 2:  Spotify's gonna have to figure out like what is the closed screen experience?
Speaker 2:  And. I.
Speaker 6:  Don't think Spotify's ever gonna figure that out.
Speaker 2:  It may not.
Speaker 6:  I think Samsung's gonna have to figure that out. Interesting. And then like
Speaker 6:  Samsung is going to have to be like, we reformatted your app
Speaker 6:  to fit this screen because I think that what's gonna happen is the same thing
Speaker 6:  that we saw with Android tablets forever and ever is that like
Speaker 6:  the companies are not gonna really invest a lot in the app experience for
Speaker 6:  the different size screens that are not phone shaped and phone size. But
Speaker 6:  Samsung will do the legwork to like allow you to run a
Speaker 6:  window or allow you to split the screen in different ways or make use of
Speaker 6:  the larger screen or in this case the smaller screen in a way
Speaker 6:  that is more practical and more useful. And I would be, I would not be
Speaker 6:  surprised if we don't see like Spotify widget by Samsung that like,
Speaker 6:  you know, kind of addresses those problems because Spotify won't do it or
Speaker 6:  Amazon won't do it or whatever. you know, name your app developer.
Speaker 5:  I think widgets, it's the year of the widget. I think it really is. Let's
Speaker 5:  just have more, let's keep going with widgets.
Speaker 2:  I'm, I'm into it. And so one, one more thing on the Google Maps thing.
Speaker 2:  'cause I, I was watching a video in which they were all excited about Google
Speaker 2:  Maps navigation on the outside screen and it made me think, so if I have
Speaker 2:  a flip phone, And I open up my phone or I guess I
Speaker 2:  take my phone out of my pocket and I'm like, I need to navigate home. Am
Speaker 2:  I gonna open up the phone, type it in, start the
Speaker 2:  navigation and close it and then like dock it to the thing in my
Speaker 2:  car. And I gonna leave it open. Like I don't know what the
Speaker 2:  correct phone behavior is anymore. And it feels very weird in that
Speaker 2:  sense. Like to close my phone and then look at navigation seems weird
Speaker 2:  even though that's possible. And then it's like, if I want to add a stop,
Speaker 2:  should I open my phone? Should I leave my phone closed? Does it not matter?
Speaker 2:  Is this too many options? Like, I don't know, it just feels weird.
Speaker 5:  I I've definitely have those moments where I was, you try and do too
Speaker 5:  many things on the cover screen and you're like, oh okay, I've I've pushed
Speaker 5:  it too far. This is like one too many things. It's just not
Speaker 5:  a comfortable experience. Yeah, I, I find myself when I'm starting
Speaker 5:  navigation or whatnot, you know, opening the phone,
Speaker 5:  doing the like fiddly stuff and then I think if I was
Speaker 5:  driving with it I would would keep it open. But if I'm
Speaker 5:  walking then I close it, put it in my pocket and that's when I'm like, I
Speaker 5:  might need to glance at something or check, you know, respond to a
Speaker 5:  text message. It's sort of like a choose your own adventure. And,
Speaker 5:  I. I think there's, if you're going to buy a flip phone right now, I
Speaker 5:  think you need a little bit of that kind of sense of adventure or
Speaker 5:  like you're sort of excited about figuring those things out.
Speaker 5:  You can use it and just out of the box just have like a fine
Speaker 5:  experience with widgets. But I think like the people who
Speaker 5:  are gonna get the most out of it are kind of like Ooh. I have options. I
Speaker 5:  can do this on the cover screen or the inside screen or run a app.
Speaker 6:  Can you take a call on the cover screen?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And it goes automatically to the speaker phone.
Speaker 6:  Okay. So you're not holding half of a phone up to the side of your face.
Speaker 5:  Right. Hello? Okay. Yeah, I I don't answer the
Speaker 5:  phone so
Speaker 2:  Yeah, it's just all robocalls. What's the that's who it's trick question.
Speaker 6:  I know where the flip five, one of the Samsung six sing is a new hinge. Is
Speaker 6:  this hinge any more one Hable Flickable
Speaker 6:  than we've seen in the past?
Speaker 5:  I hate doing that. I've like, I don't know.
Speaker 2:  I No 'cause that's the like done, right? That's the best part.
Speaker 5:  I don't, I don't enjoy it. Like you gotta get your, I'm already
Speaker 5:  putting my nails like under the screen in a way that I don't
Speaker 5:  like And I wouldn't say it's any better or worse. It's the same
Speaker 5:  And. I don't recommend it. I think it's bad.
Speaker 6:  I think we've talked about this before, but we need a button that you push
Speaker 6:  a button on the side and you got the spring loaded action. Yes.
Speaker 2:  Yes.
Speaker 6:  Like, you know, one of those switchblade combs
Speaker 2:  Give me the thing he has in the matrix. That is the answer. That is the correct
Speaker 2:  answer. I totally agree. We should get off of the outside screen here in
Speaker 2:  a sec. But customization is the other thing that Samsung made a big deal
Speaker 2:  about being able to change the background and move the widgets around and
Speaker 2:  have it look like your thing. And obviously like this is,
Speaker 2:  this is the lock screen of this phone in a super real way.
Speaker 2:  Have you been playing around with it? What, what kind of cool stuff have
Speaker 2:  you discovered?
Speaker 5:  I've, I went pretty intense with it. Yeah. Like
Speaker 5:  I've got like the font, I've got a cute picture of my kid I turned,
Speaker 5:  there are a lot of options and yeah you can, you can
Speaker 5:  treat it as like first of all there's an always on display
Speaker 5:  so that's an option. You don't get on the Motorola and you get little app,
Speaker 5:  you know icons for your notifications. You can turn on the battery
Speaker 5:  percentage or turn that off. Yeah, it's pretty customizable and
Speaker 5:  flexible and you get to a point where you're like which of these
Speaker 5:  background colors goes best with this photo of my
Speaker 5:  kid wearing sunglasses in a funny way, And I. I went
Speaker 5:  down the rabbit hole this weekend so I'm very pleased.
Speaker 2:  Are y'all big lock screen customizers in general? Yeah,
Speaker 5:  I am. I get into it.
Speaker 2:  I believe that. Dan what about you?
Speaker 6:  Yes, but I view it from the lens of
Speaker 6:  productivity 'cause I'm a huge nerd. I'm like, no
Speaker 6:  there are no kids on my lock screen. More widgets. What are, what are the
Speaker 6:  most useful widgets and what is the wallpaper that signifies I'm in work
Speaker 6:  mode now. So that, that's kind of how I do it. I
Speaker 6:  know with Samsung And I know with Android 14 they added a bunch of like
Speaker 6:  wallpaper lock screen customizations that I've not really played with a bunch,
Speaker 6:  but at least on an iPhone what I've done is set up a bunch of different ones
Speaker 6:  that tie into the focus mode that I'm using at the current moment and then
Speaker 6:  it switches. And so my weekend one has kids
Speaker 6:  that's nice, but the weekday one doesn't,
Speaker 2:  Dan Seaford loves his kids but only on the weekends. That's the, that's the
Speaker 2:  takeaway. No, my customization has been, I have discovered
Speaker 2:  it is actually very powerful to not have app icons
Speaker 2:  accessible to me. So all the customization I've done now is mostly on my
Speaker 2:  home screen, which is just, I have one that I hit at the end of the workday
Speaker 2:  that just makes it much harder for me to open Slack and I've just discovered
Speaker 2:  that even that tiny little bit of friction goes a very long way. So I, I've
Speaker 2:  become a big believer in, in that kind of customization, but only really
Speaker 2:  in the last like six months. Alright. Allison, before we switch to the
Speaker 2:  Fold, anything else on the flip that you've noticed in terms of like how
Speaker 2:  you use it? I saw the, everybody's doing the, the new gesture where you can
Speaker 2:  like flick a thing up to the top screen so you can do stuff on the bottom
Speaker 2:  screen. How does that work?
Speaker 5:  You know, I, I go right for the camera. And I, that's a thing
Speaker 5:  I like on this form factor on the flip phones and
Speaker 5:  I'm just enjoying the hell out of it. Like you can, you
Speaker 5:  can do so many things. You can make it like a little, like a little view
Speaker 5:  camera where you're, you've got it folded in half and you're looking at the
Speaker 5:  image on the bottom. You can record video. Like I, I like that
Speaker 5:  Becca pointed that out in our hands-on, you can kind of flip it like a
Speaker 5:  cam recorder. All those things are, they're not new but they're
Speaker 5:  still here and I'm still enjoying them.
Speaker 2:  And one question we've gotten a bunch is the transition from the
Speaker 2:  different modes. If you're using something with it closed or you have it
Speaker 2:  flipped around in one of the viewing modes and then you open up the phone
Speaker 2:  to use it like a normal phone, how does, how do all those transitions work?
Speaker 5:  I'm not noticing like I think Samsung treats the
Speaker 5:  two screens as two different sort of experiences more
Speaker 5:  than Motorola. Like if you're doing something on the cover screen and you
Speaker 5:  open the phone, you're like this is frustrating, I need to open the phone
Speaker 5:  and do it. It'll open that app or whatever you were working
Speaker 5:  on. But something I think the Motorola phone does a little better
Speaker 5:  is if you're, you're like in Google Maps and you set up navigation and
Speaker 5:  you close the phone, Motorola will give you a little icon
Speaker 5:  that's like, do you wanna open this on the cover screen? And Samsung is
Speaker 5:  just kinda like, you're done.
Speaker 2:  Interesting Case closed. Yeah, I feel like in both directions I would want
Speaker 2:  some continuity there. And it's like back to the Spotify thing, right? If
Speaker 2:  I start playing Spotify And I close my phone, I feel like the correct thing
Speaker 2:  to do would be pop up Spotify controls on the outside screen. Yeah. Or at
Speaker 2:  least ask me if that's a thing that I want. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  It might give you media controls at that point. I, I think the default behavior
Speaker 5:  is to just like the, the screen goes dark. You're okay, you're done.
Speaker 2:  So when you close your phone, Samsung is like you are finished. Yeah. Okay.
Speaker 6:  I, I think that's what I like most of the time because I know with the folding
Speaker 6:  the Fold and like the pixel Fold and stuff like that, there are some people
Speaker 6:  who like to like close it and then continue what they're doing when it's
Speaker 6:  closed. If I'm closing the device, I'm probably putting it down or putting
Speaker 6:  it in my pocket or putting it in a bag or something like that. Like that
Speaker 6:  is my signification that or signifier that like I'm done doing what I'm doing
Speaker 6:  and if there's music playing in the background, it'll continue to play, that's
Speaker 6:  fine. But I don't want it to like light up again or throw something at
Speaker 6:  me unless I pick up the phone again with intention to like keep using it.
Speaker 2:  You know what gesture I love to that end is on the flip five,
Speaker 2:  if you have it closed and you get a phone call, you silence it by putting
Speaker 2:  your hand over it. Kinda like you do on the, on the, on the watch where you
Speaker 2:  just like cover it with your hand and it shuts down. Yeah. I think that should
Speaker 2:  be like a universal gesture for all things, right? Like talk to the hand
Speaker 2:  literally like that is a way of just saying sort of I am finished.
Speaker 2:  Like I love so much, it's a power move. It really is. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  I love it. It's like no more out of you. Yeah. Like whatever you're doing
Speaker 2:  just stop it.
Speaker 2:  Exactly. So all right, let's talk about the Fold a little bit. Dan I'm
Speaker 2:  particularly curious for you as the the Fold sicko of of our little family
Speaker 2:  here. Anything in the Fold five that blows your mind? It seems like the big
Speaker 2:  upgrade here this year was the hinge. Was there any software stuff we're
Speaker 2:  excited about?
Speaker 6:  So Allison can confirm but I believe that there are two software
Speaker 6:  features, both of which are gonna be coming to the four and maybe the
Speaker 6:  three and the two or whatever. The first one is you get on
Speaker 6:  the task bar at the bottom, which is like a permanent strip of your apps.
Speaker 6:  You get another slot for a recent app. So instead of like two or three, it's
Speaker 6:  now up to four, maybe five now. Okay. Which is cool.
Speaker 2:  I will just say the fact that you led with that as the first Yes software
Speaker 2:  feature is not super exciting. The
Speaker 6:  Other software feature that I'm aware of is if you are
Speaker 6:  organizing your home screen you can now like tap and hold and
Speaker 6:  pick up an app and then use another finger to like swipe to a different screen
Speaker 6:  and then drop the app which you've been able to do on an iPhone or an iPad
Speaker 6:  and it makes it a lot easier to like kind of organize your home screen. Samsung's
Speaker 6:  now added that otherwise it's got a new hinge.
Speaker 2:  Yeah,
Speaker 6:  I'm gonna be like perfectly blunt here. I think that Samsung should have
Speaker 6:  done so much more this year than it did. It needed to do the hinge, like
Speaker 6:  that was a necessary thing and they needed to finally get rid of the gap
Speaker 6:  and they did that And, I'm happy that they did and they made it ever so slightly
Speaker 6:  lighter or whatever. But the processor upgrade is just your standard
Speaker 6:  Qualcomm chip bump. I don't think anybody really had any performance issues
Speaker 6:  with the four. so like are you gonna notice any difference in the five? No
Speaker 6:  the camera's exactly the same. The screens are basically exactly the same.
Speaker 6:  The software is almost identical and it's going to be back ported to the
Speaker 6:  older devices. So at least for people that already have a Fold four,
Speaker 6:  even with Samsung's like incredible trade-in promotions, it's really
Speaker 6:  hard to justify buying a Fold five And I. I like, I own a Fold four
Speaker 6:  And I have no intention to buy a Fold five. And it's really interesting that
Speaker 6:  this is the year when Samsung finally has some competition and it's done
Speaker 6:  maybe it's most iterative update to the, to the phone ever.
Speaker 6:  And all of the updates have been really iterative but this one is most iterative.
Speaker 6:  So I was really hoping Samsung would do more kind of knowing that Google
Speaker 6:  had the Pixel Fold working, we all knew Google was working on the Pixel Fold
Speaker 6:  for like two years. Like that's, it's not a surprise, but
Speaker 2:  On the software front, Samsung is still a mile ahead of Google, right? Yeah.
Speaker 2:  And we talked about this with the Pixel Fold, like the Z folds ability to
Speaker 2:  move apps around is so much better than
Speaker 2:  anything on any other Android large screen device. And in a lot of
Speaker 2:  ways it's better than the iPad. Like it's, it's very good at letting you
Speaker 2:  move a bunch of things around on the screen and put apps where you want them
Speaker 2:  to go and like it, it's, it seems a little clunky in spots but like
Speaker 2:  it's very powerful.
Speaker 6:  Yeah and and like, like we were talking about with Goodlock, like we said
Speaker 6:  on the show before, Samsung software makes the Fold phone feel like
Speaker 6:  a PC that you shove in your pocket with all of the like good and bad that
Speaker 6:  comes along with that. So if you want a portable computer,
Speaker 6:  like the Fold Five's gonna do all of that stuff just as well as the Fold
Speaker 6:  forwarded. so like if You don't have one already, sure you're getting a slightly
Speaker 6:  refined experience this year, but if it didn't like really
Speaker 6:  like if you weren't sold by that pitch a year ago, I don't think the Fold
Speaker 6:  five's gonna change anything in that matter.
Speaker 2:  That's fair. Allison, have you noticed anything that feels different in
Speaker 2:  actually using the thing?
Speaker 5:  No, it's feels very much like using the Fold four
Speaker 5:  fair I mean just coming from the Pixel Fold more
Speaker 5:  recently, I do notice that it's quite a bit lighter than the
Speaker 5:  Pixel Fold, which the Fold for was lighter also.
Speaker 5:  So I'm, I'm appreciating that the kind of like, yeah there's more
Speaker 5:  like drag and drop options you can kind of like, there's a
Speaker 5:  two handed copy and paste which didn't work
Speaker 5:  the first three times. So I tried it but I finally got it working.
Speaker 2:  Wait, explain what, what is a two-handed copy and paste? Is this, is this
Speaker 2:  a good thing?
Speaker 5:  So the the you, you have a, a picture in the like Samsung
Speaker 5:  gallery app and you can do that like long press on a person
Speaker 5:  and it'll cut it out thing.
Speaker 2:  I see sure.
Speaker 5:  And then you can, you can leave that finger there and
Speaker 5:  grab another app, open another app with your other hand and
Speaker 5:  it'll just like drag and drop the image to the new app
Speaker 5:  and voila, I don't know but like Dan
Speaker 5:  said, that's going to come to the older Fold phones
Speaker 5:  soon-ish and they never say so yeah there's, there's really
Speaker 5:  not much here. If you, if you have a Fold four, if you were sort
Speaker 5:  of on the fence before and this year's the year to
Speaker 5:  buy a foldable for some reason like yeah get get the
Speaker 5:  Fold five. That's nice. But that's about it.
Speaker 2:  It is interesting how quickly the Fold in particular seems
Speaker 2:  to have settled into the, like it's very mature and now just gets slightly
Speaker 2:  better every year thing and maybe there are more sort of big turns to have
Speaker 2:  but it feels like with you know, regular smartphones it took a lot longer
Speaker 2:  to get to the like we know what this thing is and it's just gonna sort of
Speaker 2:  slowly improve over time phase and Samsung is already there.
Speaker 6:  I mean, I think Samsung thinks Samsung is there fair they're are
Speaker 6:  absolutely a list of things that I would've loved for them to address on
Speaker 6:  the Vault four that they did not on the vault five. Tell us
Speaker 2:  The list Dan. That's what we're here for.
Speaker 6:  All right, so this doesn't matter as much to me but it matters to the vast
Speaker 6:  majority of people. The camera is exactly the same. Mm. And the camera we
Speaker 6:  know is not as good as the camera that you can get on other phones for half
Speaker 6:  the price. They did nothing there to improve that. so like that could have
Speaker 6:  been an improvement. It they did make it a little bit lighter. It's 10 grams
Speaker 6:  lighter, two nickels as Allison says that's great. But
Speaker 6:  it's also like barely perceptible And we've seen phones
Speaker 6:  from China from Honor and Huawei and Xmi and other brands that
Speaker 6:  are noticeably lighter, like 40 grams lighter. They're thinner.
Speaker 6:  They are, they're more pocketable and and portable would've loved to
Speaker 6:  see improvements there. It's great that they fixed the hinge but it's still
Speaker 6:  kind of a chunky thick phone. The outside cover display
Speaker 6:  is a big blocker for a lot of people in that it is still weird and
Speaker 6:  narrow and awkward. It's
Speaker 2:  Still a TV remote.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it's still a TV remote. I kind of understand why Samsung is using
Speaker 6:  that and we talked about this in the past of like when you open the phone
Speaker 6:  the screen experience is better because it matches your apps better and things
Speaker 6:  like that and that kind of dictates the covers geometry
Speaker 6:  and dimensions. But again we've seen phones from China that have
Speaker 6:  a portrait oriented inside display but have larger outside
Speaker 6:  displays that are wider and more normal aspect ratios and are easier
Speaker 6:  to use. So I would've loved to seen Samsung make some progress or forward
Speaker 6:  momentum there. They still are not
Speaker 6:  dust resistant. I know Allison just wrote a piece on the site that it
Speaker 6:  looks like they are exploring ways to make them dust resistant but they're
Speaker 6:  still the same level of dust resistance as before. They still have the same
Speaker 6:  kind of like construction on the inside of the screen panels and
Speaker 6:  cover and like screen protectors and things like that. So you have to be
Speaker 6:  careful with these and things like that. so like there's a lot of progress
Speaker 6:  And, I think what I would like to see is more experiments and more
Speaker 6:  innovation from Samsung that we're not, they've kind of like settled into
Speaker 6:  this. We're going to make very tiny tweaks to this formula because we
Speaker 6:  screwed it up the first year and are very scared of screwing it up again.
Speaker 6:  And so that's kind of like what we're getting. But a another example, you
Speaker 6:  still can't put the spen in the phone. You have to buy a case to hold the
Speaker 6:  spen and it's like external and they made the spen smaller and they came
Speaker 6:  up with a new case design to like hold it and stuff like that. It's great
Speaker 6:  and all put a silo in the phone that you can put the spen in like, like there's
Speaker 6:  like so many things that they could be doing but they are just like either
Speaker 6:  planning them out over a 10 year period and doing one at a time or
Speaker 6:  they're just, they just feel like it's not worth the time. So I don't know.
Speaker 6:  The last point is it's still $1,800. Yep. And that is the biggest turnoff
Speaker 6:  to everybody that you talk about about this phone. They didn't move the price
Speaker 6:  budget anywhere. There were rumors that it was gonna be more expensive because
Speaker 6:  of inflation and and what have you and they kept the price the same which
Speaker 6:  is great but still $1,800 or $2,000 if you
Speaker 6:  upgrade the storage or whatever it is, is still like just completely
Speaker 6:  non-starter for for very massive amounts of people. so like why
Speaker 6:  couldn't we get it to 1500 or 1400 or closer to a thousand
Speaker 2:  Whatever. Well and this goes back to why I think the flip continues to be
Speaker 2:  the more interesting of the two phones at the moment. Partly because they
Speaker 2:  just did more to it this year. But also because I think even
Speaker 2:  in the early days of these foreign factors where there's not some sort of
Speaker 2:  instant killer app that's like if you, if you buy a Z flip you can
Speaker 2:  do this, this and this that you just straight up can't do on your
Speaker 2:  normal Galaxy phone. It's an interesting tiebreaker right? And like kind
Speaker 2:  of what you're talking about Allison that it lets you do different stuff,
Speaker 2:  different ways. It gives you these kinds of new ideas about when your
Speaker 2:  phone should work and how you interact with it and all this stuff. And if
Speaker 2:  that appeals to you, terrific. You have to make what seems to be relatively
Speaker 2:  small camera trade-offs and there is the dust proof issue but you get
Speaker 2:  something in exchange for that for about the same price the
Speaker 2:  Fold comes with all of those trade-offs and another
Speaker 2:  eight or $900 in cost and that's just tough.
Speaker 2:  And so I think the thing we're at right now is it seems like the flip five
Speaker 2:  is a phone that a lot of people might actually stand in the store and think
Speaker 2:  about buying instead of the SS
Speaker 2:  27,000 or whatever we're gonna get next. And I
Speaker 2:  think that's really exciting and it feels like Alison, you And I have both
Speaker 2:  written that like this is kind of the moment for flip phones and it seems
Speaker 2:  like the flip five genuinely has a shot to be kind of the the first
Speaker 2:  real one for a lot of people.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I had some friends over this weekend and the phone was on
Speaker 5:  the table and generally my friends are extremely uninterested
Speaker 5:  in whatever phone I'm reviewing, but they were kind of like, what is
Speaker 5:  this? you know, tell me more And I think their reaction is totally
Speaker 5:  different if I have the Z Fold out. It just sort of
Speaker 5:  has, I think instantly someone who's not super
Speaker 5:  into tech or phones is like, oh I can tell that's not for
Speaker 5:  me that that looks pretty intense. But the flip form factor
Speaker 5:  is it's familiar. We had flip phones back in the day, we kind of know
Speaker 5:  what that is and and you can see immediately like I'm,
Speaker 5:  I'm showing them the widgets on the cover screen and how I open
Speaker 5:  the daycare app to sign my kid out without flipping the phone open
Speaker 5:  and ooze and ahs, you know, from the crowd.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, no I, I agree. I think you're gonna have to keep us posted on how your
Speaker 2:  reviews come because I wonder if there are big messy
Speaker 2:  things left to be discovered. 'cause we are like all these apps have to figure
Speaker 2:  out how this is gonna work. Samsung has to figure out how people are gonna
Speaker 2:  use it and like as all the Flip and Fold phones get more popular,
Speaker 2:  we're just gonna discover new ways in which they're still early and broken.
Speaker 2:  I think it's gonna be fascinating.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I'm excited.
Speaker 2:  All right, well thank you both. I am confident that we will have more reasons
Speaker 2:  to talk about flips and folds in the next few months so we'll be back soon.
Speaker 2:  But thank you both.
Speaker 6:  Thank you.
Speaker 7:  Thanks.
Speaker 2:  Alright, we gotta take a break and then we are gonna come back with a little
Speaker 2:  bit of an investigation into the present and future of arcade
Speaker 2:  games. We'll be right back.
Speaker 7:  This episode is brought to you by Shopify. That's the sound
Speaker 7:  of switching your business to Shopify, the global commerce platform that
Speaker 7:  supercharges your selling harness, the best converting checkout and same
Speaker 7:  intuitive features, trusted apps and powerful analytics used by the
Speaker 7:  world's leading brands. Stop leaving sales on the table. Discover why
Speaker 7:  millions trust Shopify to build, grow and run their business.
Speaker 7:  Sign up today for your $1 per month trial period at Shopify dot com
Speaker 7:  slash tech 23.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. Have you ever seen those videos on TikTok of people
Speaker 2:  playing that arcade game? I don't know what it's called, but it's the one
Speaker 2:  where you just put the quarters in and then you try to use that quarter
Speaker 2:  to push a bunch of other quarters off the edge.
Speaker 8:  Leave a lock on the video for that win right there.
Speaker 8:  That is amazing.
Speaker 2:  The game is sort of dumb and watching other people play it on TikTok is
Speaker 2:  definitely dumb, but I had this phase where I was watching a
Speaker 2:  surprising amount of it. It fell
Speaker 9:  Right off of the pusher.
Speaker 10:  There was a massive tower of quarters sitting inside the coin
Speaker 10:  pusher
Speaker 11:  To turn this $5 bill into 20 by winning it on the edge of this coin pusher.
Speaker 2:  There's just something about seeing the quarters like teetering over the
Speaker 2:  edge that is surprisingly riveting. At least for
Speaker 2:  me.
Speaker 9:  There's a whole bunch.
Speaker 2:  Anyway, the TikTok algorithm pretty quickly decided that I must
Speaker 2:  love arcade games, which isn't untrue. I do like
Speaker 2:  arcade games. I especially used to play that old Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles
Speaker 2:  side scroller one all the time, but it's been a few years since I was
Speaker 2:  in an arcade at all. But I started seeing these videos all the time
Speaker 2:  just of people hanging out at Dave and Busters trying to hack the games to
Speaker 2:  get more tickets. Yo,
Speaker 12:  Today we be show you guys how to get unlimited Dave and Busters tickets
Speaker 12:  with the board. Yes sir. You already know. Let's get it.
Speaker 2:  We're just straight up cheating. There's a lot of TikTok videos of just
Speaker 2:  people cheating. Like there's one I saw where this guy is just climbing
Speaker 2:  into the machine where you throw the ball to knock the clowns over and just
Speaker 2:  knocking all the clowns over with his hands. This
Speaker 8:  Dude out here really cheating.
Speaker 2:  I guess that's fun. I also came across a lot of people claiming to have
Speaker 2:  tricks to get you enough tickets to get a PSS five and one guy who
Speaker 2:  calls himself the arcade goat who says he got 10 Oculus
Speaker 2:  quests just from playing arcade games,
Speaker 12:  Tip play, games of skill, not luck.
Speaker 2:  In watching all of these videos, I started noticing games I
Speaker 2:  recognized. Not arcade games I recognized, but games I know because
Speaker 2:  they're on my phone.
Speaker 2:  Angry Birds, flappy Bird, Crossy Road. I saw console
Speaker 2:  games like Halo and Mario Kart two. This all seems really
Speaker 2:  strange to me. Why would I go all the way to an arcade to pay a bunch of
Speaker 2:  money to play games I already have on my phone? Is it just for the
Speaker 2:  tickets? Like are people making these games so that people will play these
Speaker 2:  games just to get a PSS five? That seems strange. Is it just fun that
Speaker 2:  it's louder and not in my house and they serve beer? It's all
Speaker 2:  very confusing to me. So one afternoon I went to the Arcadian
Speaker 2:  arcade. I could think of the Dave and Buster's location in Times Square
Speaker 2:  in New York City where I would only go for journalism.
Speaker 2:  All right, the Dave and Buster's here is located on the third floor. So
Speaker 2:  I'm on an escalator going up to Applebee's and then Dave and
Speaker 2:  Busters. This is actually one of the biggest and in a lot of ways most popular
Speaker 2:  arcades in New York City. You can go to places like Barcade where they are
Speaker 2:  really focused on re stuff, but this is just all about gaming. So here we
Speaker 2:  go. Eventually I made it past the Applebee's, passed all the tourists,
Speaker 2:  got upstairs to dvs, waited for my turn and went
Speaker 2:  in and had a look around. Alright, I made it into the arcade. And I already
Speaker 2:  cannot believe how many games I recognize from console games
Speaker 2:  and even just pop culture, like there's Tomb Raider and Star Trek and Jurassic
Speaker 2:  World and all that kind of stuff, but especially from Mobile, there's a
Speaker 2:  Crossy Road game. There's a floppy bird game that they call Dave
Speaker 2:  and Buster's floppy tickets, even though it's just straight up floppy bird.
Speaker 2:  Love that. There's a Mario Kart game that is one of those arcade games with
Speaker 2:  the chairs and the steering wheel and you actually drive. There's Candy Crush.
Speaker 2:  You can just stand here and play Candy Crush. And it is precisely the
Speaker 2:  same game I would play on my phone except the screen is bigger and the room
Speaker 2:  is louder and it feels more exciting somehow.
Speaker 2:  After that, I did a couple more laps. I played some Crossy Road and some
Speaker 2:  Mario Kart arcade gp and then I played more Mario Kart. And then after that
Speaker 2:  I think I played more Mario Kart. Alright, as expected, Mario
Speaker 2:  Kart in an arcade is amazing. It makes me want to get one of those big
Speaker 2:  $10,000 racing simulator kits, but not play
Speaker 2:  Grant CMO or any cool games just go hard into Mario
Speaker 2:  Kart. It's also maybe the most popular game in this entire arcade.
Speaker 2:  It's either that or the air hockey. But there is a long line for Mario
Speaker 2:  Kart and I keep winning, so they keep letting me back,
Speaker 2:  but I figured I'd give somebody else a chance.
Speaker 2:  It's not that there are no older school arcade games left anymore.
Speaker 2:  David Busters still has ski ball and the Papa Shot Basketball
Speaker 2:  one and a new and kind of high def Space Invaders and
Speaker 2:  Pac-Man and a bunch of those racing games where you just sit in the seat
Speaker 2:  and grab the steering wheel. I will say though, there's a lot less pinball,
Speaker 2:  a lot less of the side scrolling games like the Teenage Mutant Ninja
Speaker 2:  Turtles, one that I loved and The Simpsons and that X-Men one
Speaker 2:  that everybody used to play. Most of that is just not here
Speaker 2:  anymore. And the real truth is the arcade, as it used to
Speaker 2:  be, is mostly dead in general. We don't need to go too
Speaker 2:  far into all of that. But the arcade as a place you used to go
Speaker 2:  and hang out was a staple of American life for like decades.
Speaker 2:  A huge portion of the gaming world as we know it now wouldn't exist without
Speaker 2:  Arcade. And now all we're left with is Dave and Busters and a bunch
Speaker 2:  of bar arcade things and not much else. The reason why
Speaker 2:  that happened is pretty obvious, right? It's that we all started playing
Speaker 2:  games at home on consoles and then on our phones, and why
Speaker 2:  would I go all the way to an arcade and pay money just to play the same game?
Speaker 2:  I can play as long as I want for free in my living room.
Speaker 2:  All of that is all the more reason I'm fascinated by these mobile games
Speaker 2:  in the arcade. If Dave and Busters and all these other arcades are having
Speaker 2:  trouble convincing people to come out and play games at all, wouldn't it
Speaker 2:  be the worst idea ever to make those games the same games
Speaker 2:  you can already play on your phone? It's like, come pay us money
Speaker 2:  to play the game you got for free already. Seems like the worst pitch of
Speaker 2:  all time. And I. Think the best example of all those games in Dave and
Speaker 2:  Buster's is probably Angry Birds.
Speaker 2:  Angry Birds in general is one of those totally unavoidable
Speaker 2:  franchises. You can play a million different versions of it on every
Speaker 2:  imaginable screen and surface. You can buy Angry Birds Cereal, you can
Speaker 2:  get plush toys. There was an Angry Birds movie and like a million other things
Speaker 2:  I have very deliberately ignored over the years. So what's it doing in an
Speaker 2:  arcade? Asking for my money to answer that question, I called
Speaker 2:  up the people who made that game.
Speaker 14:  I am Drew Krause, I am the c o o And I Run Development here at Ice
Speaker 15:  And, I Amm, Josh Krause. I run our home arcade game sales,
Speaker 15:  marketing, and advertising here at Ice.
Speaker 2:  Ice makes a lot of arcade games, including a bunch you probably know, like
Speaker 2:  the one where you throw the ball and try to knock the clowns over that everybody
Speaker 2:  on TikTok likes to cheat at, or the air hockey game that they have called
Speaker 2:  Extreme Air fx. The company actually started with Bubble Hockey,
Speaker 2:  which is apparently still super popular in arcades and more recently they
Speaker 2:  also made a game called Angry Birds Arcade.
Speaker 2:  The Kres has told me that the whole mobile games to Arcade Trend has actually
Speaker 2:  been happening for a while, and the reason is honestly pretty simple.
Speaker 14:  You know, notoriety, it gets you to walk up to it no matter what. So
Speaker 14:  that's a huge, huge plus. Now, a lot of the arcades like it
Speaker 14:  because it brings licensed brands to their location. A big facility
Speaker 14:  like a Dave and Busters who has 160 across the country, you know
Speaker 14:  they have movie studios coming to them saying, Hey, Ghostbusters
Speaker 14:  19 is coming out, can you guys do a Ghostbusters game? I mean that's how
Speaker 14:  Ghostbusters, you know, we're talking to Sony and looking at products and
Speaker 14:  then Sony's talking to Dave and Busters all of a sudden says, Hey, I like
Speaker 14:  Ghostbusters. Hey, we're doing a Ghostbusters, let's do a Ghostbusters game.
Speaker 14:  It just, sometimes it falls into place like that.
Speaker 2:  So if you're trying to make games that will make people walk up to them.
Speaker 2:  Angry Birds was a pretty easy win. It's one of the biggest games ever.
Speaker 2:  So when Ice reached out to Royo, the company that made Angry Birds, drew
Speaker 2:  said, they started talking about an Angry Birds arcade game with one
Speaker 2:  really specific question in mind. How do we build something you
Speaker 2:  can't do at home?
Speaker 14:  So I start to bring in physical attributes like, Hey, what would
Speaker 14:  Angry Birds be? Even better if it was Angry Birds Plus, right? So,
Speaker 14:  alright, I actually wanna launch a physical ball 10 feet across the
Speaker 14:  room and hit a touchscreen monitor, and to me, that's where my brain starts
Speaker 14:  going to
Speaker 2:  That mechanic he's describing is actually how Angry Birds Arcade works.
Speaker 2:  You walk up to the game, you grab that mechanical slingshot in two hands,
Speaker 2:  and then you aim and launch these pool ball sized balls with
Speaker 2:  birds painted on them at the huge screen. When it hits the screen, the
Speaker 2:  pigs go flying. Or at least if you're any good, that's what happens.
Speaker 2:  The best thing I can compare it to is like one of those golf simulators where
Speaker 2:  you see people smack the ball into a screen, which then simulates where it
Speaker 2:  goes and how far it's like that. It's really fun and genuinely
Speaker 2:  does feel different from swiping my finger on the screen.
Speaker 2:  ICE's, drew Kraus told me that making these onscreen games more
Speaker 2:  physical like that is a huge part of the job.
Speaker 14:  You know when you asked, Hey, I saw a bunch of these games just show up
Speaker 14:  in the arcade on a giant screen. I'm gonna say 90% of those, they
Speaker 14:  lasted for about 60 to 90 days, lasted as far as they
Speaker 14:  made money. Okay, you play it once. Oh, this is the same thing I have on
Speaker 14:  my phone, just giant. It gets sold real quick.
Speaker 2:  The other part of the job for anyone making arcade games is to make sure
Speaker 2:  the game is not only fun, but fun to play over and over.
Speaker 2:  Arcades want games that you'll play for a minute and then pay to play again,
Speaker 2:  not pay once and play forever or pay once and then immediately leave.
Speaker 2:  Repeatability is the thing. That also means making games easy
Speaker 2:  for people to figure out in the first place because as Drew said, people
Speaker 2:  expect to just walk up and start playing, especially a game they've seen
Speaker 2:  before.
Speaker 14:  When you're home on your phone, you can lose a hundred times, not
Speaker 14:  get frustrated. You go into an arcade and, oh, I know what Doodle
Speaker 14:  jump is. I've never played it. You go play it in the arcade and you've gotta
Speaker 14:  figure out puzzles, you're putting a dollar in, you're not happy.
Speaker 14:  you know, sometimes you have to teach them how to play opposed to expecting
Speaker 14:  everybody can walk up to it and play. So it took me And I a while
Speaker 14:  to learn some of those nuances. When we take what we think is easy,
Speaker 14:  bring the app to the market.
Speaker 2:  That means basically two things as far as I can tell. Making the game
Speaker 2:  skill-based as much as possible so you're not just playing a slot machine
Speaker 2:  every time you step up and giving people tickets for their successes. That's
Speaker 2:  how you get people to keep playing. Speaking of Doodle Jump, by the way,
Speaker 2:  that's another game Ice worked on. Drew told me that at first they had a
Speaker 2:  ball kind of like golden tea to move things back and forth, but it landed
Speaker 2:  on this big yellow joystick, which you slide from left to
Speaker 2:  right to move your character as it jumps between things. That's the physical
Speaker 2:  object, kind of like the slingshot in Angry Birds. Again, it's super simple.
Speaker 2:  Maybe too simple for me, actually, I'm not sure I'd spend a ton of money
Speaker 2:  on Doodle Jump in an arcade, but it's actually been a huge hit for ice rice.
Speaker 2:  Anyway, with all of this in mind about physicality and big screens
Speaker 2:  and all this different stuff, I went back out to a different arcade to see
Speaker 2:  if I could make sense of all these games in a new way. Alright, it's been
Speaker 2:  a few weeks and now I'm at a different arcade. This is
Speaker 2:  the Fredericksburg Funland in Fredericksburg Virginia, and after talking
Speaker 2:  to some of the folks who make these games, I'm starting to see the mechanics
Speaker 2:  they talk about everywhere. Fruit Ninja is here, it's called Fruit
Speaker 2:  Ninja fx, and it's basically you just stand in front of a large screen and
Speaker 2:  swipe on it the way you would in Fruit Ninja, and that's all fun and good,
Speaker 2:  but the best ones of these games, and the ones I'm seeing the most people
Speaker 2:  play are the ones where they make it physical in some way.
Speaker 2:  There's one game where all you do is try to explode something and launch
Speaker 2:  someone out of a cannon, and they made this very cool lever
Speaker 2:  that actually feels like you're pressing it and it's different than it would
Speaker 2:  feel if you were just playing it on your phone. Even a really big version
Speaker 2:  of your phone, there's a Space Invaders game, which is like from a
Speaker 2:  million years old video game, but it's this huge screen and you actually
Speaker 2:  sit there in a seat with a blaster. It takes the same mechanic, it's just
Speaker 2:  these eight bit aliens coming at you, but it feels bigger and
Speaker 2:  cooler and different because it has this physical mechanic
Speaker 2:  to it. This is the kind of thing I think about as we move all of the
Speaker 2:  online digital screen-based culture into the world. How do you make this
Speaker 2:  stuff more than just bigger screens, but actually make it physical?
Speaker 2:  Also fun fact, the most popular thing here again, is
Speaker 2:  Mario Kart gp, but the one other one I wanna talk about is Guitar Hero. This
Speaker 2:  is the other one I keep seeing at all these arcades, and it might actually
Speaker 2:  be the best earliest example of this that I can think of.
Speaker 2:  It's a video game. It's a thing that happens on a screen, but your controller
Speaker 2:  is part of the game. You don't just touch or press
Speaker 2:  buttons, you're actually playing guitar and it works at home for the same
Speaker 2:  reason. It works in an arcade. It just feels like you're doing
Speaker 2:  something even though all you're doing ultimately is playing a game on a
Speaker 2:  screen. It's very cool. I'm now seeing this absolutely everywhere I go. I
Speaker 2:  love it. I really did think a lot about Guitar Hero
Speaker 2:  through this whole process and Dance Dance Revolution also, and
Speaker 2:  really everything Nintendo has done since the we, the gaming
Speaker 2:  industry, has been exploring ideas about how to make controllers more than
Speaker 2:  controllers for a long time and how to bring your body into the
Speaker 2:  equation more and more. That's what the Connect was, right? That's what the
Speaker 2:  PSS move is, all these different ideas, and as VR gaming continues
Speaker 2:  to become a thing, we're gonna get entirely new explorations of that
Speaker 2:  idea. Mobile games, I think maybe more than most, need a lot, lot of help
Speaker 2:  figuring that out. So many of the games we play now, whether it's Angry
Speaker 2:  Birds and Cut the Rope, or more complicated things like Clash of Clans and
Speaker 2:  Subway surfers, they were built on swiping and tapping, but that's
Speaker 2:  never been the most fun or immersive way to play these games. Even just
Speaker 2:  looking at the app store's, top charts right now, it's fun to imagine how
Speaker 2:  a game like Alto's Odyssey or even something like Fortnite or Roblox
Speaker 2:  might go way beyond screens and controllers and just
Speaker 2:  sitting at my tv. It won't work for everything, but I suspect the next
Speaker 2:  turn for a lot of these games is going to be back toward the physical in
Speaker 2:  that way. Figuring out how to build new mechanics and new control
Speaker 2:  systems and new ways to bring more than just your finger into the game.
Speaker 2:  Think about something like the Apple Vision Pro headset. I can basically
Speaker 2:  guarantee you that there will be Angry Birds for the Vision Pro at
Speaker 2:  some point, but it'll be a huge bummer if all that is is
Speaker 2:  a big screen. You tap to do stuff that just feels
Speaker 2:  unambitious. It feels like not enough. I don't really think arcade are gonna
Speaker 2:  become what they once were playing games at home or on my phone is just too
Speaker 2:  fun and too easy for me to venture back out every time I want to play Angry
Speaker 2:  Birds. But there's some part of me that kind of hopes I'm wrong, that
Speaker 2:  physical gaming spaces do become a big thing again and bring people back
Speaker 2:  together in the real world, even to do screen-based things. Drew
Speaker 2:  Krause is obviously biased towards that perspective since, you know, he makes
Speaker 2:  arcade games, but I like the way he thinks about bringing together the best
Speaker 2:  of both worlds.
Speaker 14:  Let's stay in the reality and if we can make you throw a ball instead of
Speaker 14:  flicking on your phone. I think we won, right?
Speaker 14:  I'm just trying to bring people back to being a kid and playing with physical
Speaker 14:  stuff. A game by adding in cool apps, cool ideas
Speaker 14:  and video, right?
Speaker 2:  I think I agree with that. And I. Think it's gonna be fascinating to see
Speaker 2:  what it looks like to bring the best of our screens out into the world More.
Speaker 2:  Think about headsets. Are we gonna use headsets to bring technology with
Speaker 2:  us more places or are we gonna use them as ways to be home and
Speaker 2:  be in our own worlds more often? I don't know. I know I'm looking
Speaker 2:  forward to getting screens out more because I know I own Mario
Speaker 2:  Kart at home and yet I spent objectively an upsetting amount of money
Speaker 2:  playing Mario Kart GP at both Dave and Busters and at Funland,
Speaker 2:  I don't know the chair and the steering wheel and the loud crowd. Just do
Speaker 2:  something for me. you know, I don't think I can get that at home.
Speaker 13:  Little Mario start. Mario is
Speaker 13:  closing in.
Speaker 2:  Alright, we gotta take a break and then we're gonna talk crypto, but not
Speaker 2:  the crypto you're probably thinking of. We'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. So if you've been following crypto over the last couple of
Speaker 2:  years, Worldcoin is probably one of the companies you've heard the
Speaker 2:  most about. It was co-founded by Sam Altman, who's one of the founders of
Speaker 2:  OpenAI, which makes chat g p t and g p t four and obviously is a big
Speaker 2:  deal just because it's related to Sam, but it also has really big ideas
Speaker 2:  about not just creating a currency, but for helping identify
Speaker 2:  all the humans in the world and universal basic income and all this
Speaker 2:  big sort of heady futurist stuff. Even if you don't know about
Speaker 2:  Worldcoin, I bet you've heard about the orb, which is the
Speaker 2:  big metal ball that Worldcoin wants to use to scan your
Speaker 2:  irises, to verify your human. This all sounds insane, even as
Speaker 2:  I'm saying it out loud. And I feel obligated here to give you a
Speaker 2:  thousand disclaimers about the risks of investing in crypto and the
Speaker 2:  huge environmental implications of the blockchain and the many, many,
Speaker 2:  many, many scams that have come through this space. And actually, you know
Speaker 2:  what, let's just get started and we can get to all of that. Alex Heath recently
Speaker 2:  became our foremost Worldcoin expert. He's here now. Let's
Speaker 2:  talk about it. Hi. Alex.
Speaker 17:  Hey David.
Speaker 2:  We're gonna talk about Worldcoin because you just had a very interesting
Speaker 2:  experience with Worldcoin. How would you put Worldcoin as a thing
Speaker 2:  in kind of the broader crypto landscape? It's not Bitcoin in the sense that
Speaker 2:  it's just a thing that people buy and sell to make money, but it's not, not
Speaker 2:  Bitcoin. Like how, how do you think about Worldcoin in that space?
Speaker 17:  Yeah, I would say to understand Worldcoin, you have to really
Speaker 17:  understand Sam Altman, okay, so he's the c e O of
Speaker 17:  OpenAI, which makes chat G P T obviously. And his stated goal with
Speaker 17:  OpenAI is to build artificial general intelligence,
Speaker 17:  a g i. And the thinking here is that a g I will eventually happen
Speaker 17:  and when it does, machines will be smarter, more
Speaker 17:  capable than humans. AI, for example, are already starting to
Speaker 17:  evade caps, but the thinking that is eventually they're gonna run the world
Speaker 17:  for us or maybe over us as the dystopian view of that. And
Speaker 17:  so in that future theoretical world run by a g I,
Speaker 17:  you know, to borrow from Westworld you kind of need to know who is a
Speaker 17:  human and who is a host. And so I would actually describe Worldcoin
Speaker 17:  and we can talk about the crypto aspect of it. But in totality, Worldcoin
Speaker 17:  is in a way an antidote to what Sam Altman is building
Speaker 17:  with his other company OpenAI. And he's not running
Speaker 17:  Worldcoin day to day, but he's the co-founder kind of public face of it.
Speaker 17:  He's been tweeting about the lines people are forming to, to get their
Speaker 17:  eyes scanned and kind of using his clout to advance the project.
Speaker 17:  So you know, he also, Altman is a huge fan of this
Speaker 17:  idea of universal basic income. I've heard him talk about this
Speaker 17:  in interviews. He uses this example of, you know, eventually we have these
Speaker 17:  A g I controlled robots and they're doing solar power
Speaker 17:  farming on our behalfs in mines. They're running
Speaker 17:  things for us. Basically humans won't need to work as much, they'll
Speaker 17:  make our homes for us, they'll do everything for us. And so in a future
Speaker 17:  world like that, maybe you do want some kind of universal
Speaker 17:  basic income. The problem with that obviously is governments
Speaker 17:  may not like that U B I has never worked to date at scale in the modern
Speaker 17:  world. It's actually funny, you know, researching this, I, I found out that
Speaker 17:  U B I actually dates back to the Romans in Julius Caesar. So it was something
Speaker 17:  that happened a long time ago. So yeah, the goal really simply
Speaker 17:  is to scan every eyeball on earth so that you can then
Speaker 17:  distribute Worldcoin the token and eventually down the
Speaker 17:  road in some kind of theoretical future that token will be used for some
Speaker 17:  kind of universal basic income. Now this sounds like the kind of pitch
Speaker 17:  that I can totally imagine some venture capitalists falling in love with
Speaker 17:  as they're walking through the Presidio Yeah. In San Francisco.
Speaker 17:  But you know, the criticism is that it's a solution in search of a
Speaker 17:  problem, but that, that's in a nutshell kind of the philosophy
Speaker 17:  behind Worldcoin and what Altman is doing.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I it to me, this just strikes me as like a series of solutions in
Speaker 2:  search of a problem. And I think to some extent, I actually don't wanna like
Speaker 2:  litigate Worldcoin because it's, it's sort of in this crazy world that if
Speaker 2:  everything were different this might be useful and necessary and that's all
Speaker 2:  fine and good. I do think the question of how
Speaker 2:  currency and the identification thing fit together is really interesting
Speaker 2:  because the, the pushback on this has been basically a lot of people are
Speaker 2:  being asked to give their iris scans to this
Speaker 2:  company and in exchange they're getting some amount of this currency and
Speaker 2:  then it's like fast forward a bunch of years, this becomes a very important
Speaker 2:  currency. Could be super interesting. Who knows we'll save that for another
Speaker 2:  day. The thing on the ground is that there are a lot of people who are like,
Speaker 2:  there's this sort of meaningless, not staked to
Speaker 2:  anything money that is just being passed around in an exchange or taking
Speaker 2:  a huge amount of my data in order to verify that I'm a person Because
Speaker 2:  of the other tools that you've made, which are getting so good so fast that
Speaker 2:  you're now solving the problem you've created with a new creation that
Speaker 2:  creates its own problems. And, I just I get like twisted into knots trying
Speaker 2:  to figure out even like which part of this to sort of be annoyed by.
Speaker 17:  Yeah, there is a lot to be potentially annoyed by, a lot to be skeptical
Speaker 17:  of. I think the people at Worldcoin and the parent company, which is called
Speaker 17:  Tools for Humanity of course have high minded
Speaker 17:  intentions here. I guess maybe it's helpful to rewind just a little bit.
Speaker 17:  Up until last week, Worldcoin was not out in the world. It wasn't a
Speaker 17:  token that you could access at all. And what Worldcoin had been doing for
Speaker 17:  the last couple years is going around mostly in poorer
Speaker 17:  countries outside of the US and and Europe though they did quite a bit of
Speaker 17:  this in Europe as well, but particularly in in Africa, parts of
Speaker 17:  India, they would go out and send contractors to
Speaker 17:  basically convince people in villages, people who
Speaker 17:  maybe just got a smartphone for the first time to have their
Speaker 17:  eyes scanned in exchange for you know, some,
Speaker 17:  some tether or some Bitcoin or a nominal amount of money. And
Speaker 17:  they claim that over 2 million people have already scanned with the
Speaker 17:  orb and now with the token out importantly it's
Speaker 17:  not available in the US for reasons we can talk about or in China. Yeah,
Speaker 17:  so the whole world aspect of that is kind of defeated on on day one
Speaker 17:  but now that the token is out, basically all those people had IOUs
Speaker 17:  in the form of you're going to get the token at some point and now it's
Speaker 17:  out and to the idea of it being a currency, it's actually a horrible
Speaker 17:  currency because it behaves like a security and that's I think why it's
Speaker 17:  not available in the US is the S E C and
Speaker 17:  regulators here in the US have started cracking down on crypto quite a bit.
Speaker 17:  We've seen a lot of lawsuits, stuff going on with Coinbase that's still
Speaker 17:  ongoing and there's this whole debate about, you know,
Speaker 17:  should these tokens be regulated like securities which come with important
Speaker 17:  disclosures that right now the crypto economy does not have,
Speaker 17:  if you're thinking about this as a currency, a, it can't be used for anything
Speaker 17:  right now. So it just exists in the world app when you get it airdropped
Speaker 17:  if you're not in the US. So it's not really good currency in that respect
Speaker 17:  though. They plan to eventually let people send it back and forth. It also
Speaker 17:  fluctuates like crazy the price of it because it behaves like a speculative
Speaker 17:  asset. So immediately this became one of the 10 most valuable crypto
Speaker 17:  tokens in the world. The week it launched the app, the world app was
Speaker 17:  the number one downloaded app on iOS and Android in Kenya
Speaker 17:  where a lot of people had already been doing signups pre-launch. There's
Speaker 17:  just a lot of pain that's gonna happen here with normal people
Speaker 17:  who are doing this because they want some kind of magic bean and then they
Speaker 17:  realize the price of that bean is not going to be what it was when
Speaker 17:  they signed up. And we've seen this time and time again with crypto
Speaker 17:  projects, And, I think that's been the harshest criticism I've seen of the
Speaker 17:  way that they're structuring the actual token so far.
Speaker 17:  And I think that's fair. I mean I think if you're trying to build a utility,
Speaker 17:  if you're trying to build something that everyone in the world is theoretically
Speaker 17:  gonna have one day, I don't really understand the way they've rolled it
Speaker 17:  out initially.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, that's fair. And I think one of the things I've wondered about this
Speaker 2:  project the whole time has been to what extent Worldcoin would
Speaker 2:  be as kind of interesting and big as it is if Sam
Speaker 2:  Altman weren't involved. Because obviously in the world of a g I, there are
Speaker 2:  very few people who have done more and put their money where
Speaker 2:  their mouth is more often than Sam Altman like guy has a history
Speaker 2:  of being right? And some of the stuff we're talking about I think is sort
Speaker 2:  of specific to Worldcoin, right? Like the underlying tech, the iris scanning
Speaker 2:  stuff, all of which we're about to get into that is different. But some of
Speaker 2:  these like big long term promises that they're making
Speaker 2:  about you know, banking the unbanked and helping create
Speaker 2:  one single global financial system. Like that's what everybody in the crypto
Speaker 2:  industry has been saying for a long time. And I think you've been obviously
Speaker 2:  following this and Sam for a while, like is a lot of the hype here
Speaker 2:  just that Sam is kind of the Midas of
Speaker 2:  this industry and everything he touches seems to work and people wanna be
Speaker 2:  along for the ride?
Speaker 17:  Yeah, absolutely. you know, he's been going around the world on behalf
Speaker 17:  of OpenAI over the past several months meeting with regulators holding
Speaker 17:  talks in different countries and he's been mentioning Worldcoin, he's been
Speaker 17:  helping to hype it. I saw him tweet a god, what is it x a photo now
Speaker 17:  of him in Europe finally getting scanned himself a month or two
Speaker 17:  ago. So yeah, the halo of Altman around this is certainly helping,
Speaker 17:  you know, this is also like a company that's raised a lot of money. Like
Speaker 17:  we should note they've raised hundreds of millions of dollars from Andreessen
Speaker 17:  Horowitz. I should note one of their earliest investors was actually Sandbank
Speaker 17:  been freed, believe it or not. Oh boy. Which you know, obviously
Speaker 17:  that's, that's a problem. But they've moved on from that and yeah they have
Speaker 17:  a lot of money and it's not a nonprofit either. So
Speaker 17:  you know, right. There is a business here somewhere, you know, investors
Speaker 17:  in the project have told me that the kind of initial business plan is to
Speaker 17:  create a kind of a p i business is for other companies to be able to access
Speaker 17:  the world IDs so that they can verify that someone is who they say they
Speaker 17:  are theoretically. so like Okta for example, I think just
Speaker 17:  in Germany has already rolled out world ID as a way that you can
Speaker 17:  authenticate. So yeah, I guess like right now, yes the
Speaker 17:  project is technically only like two weeks old, At this point, but world
Speaker 17:  ID and Worldcoin can't really be used for much of
Speaker 17:  anything except hoping that world coin's price continues to
Speaker 17:  go up.
Speaker 2:  Right. And that's where it becomes like Bitcoin. So Okay. There are a million
Speaker 2:  disclaimers and a million questions and generally I think most crypto stuff
Speaker 2:  is nonsense and to all of that we will just leave aside for now. 'cause I
Speaker 2:  think if nothing else, this is a show about weird technology
Speaker 2:  and how it makes us feel. And you just experienced this thing,
Speaker 2:  you have seen the orb, this thing's been out for a while. Like you said,
Speaker 2:  it's been kind of out in the world but it hasn't sort of officially been
Speaker 2:  launched and now it is officially launched and you got to try
Speaker 2:  it. So tell me about it. Like what happened, how did this happen? Are you
Speaker 2:  okay? Do you need me to call someone?
Speaker 17:  I'm okay so far. We'll see if there's any drones around
Speaker 17:  my house afterwards here. Yeah, so I guess it was the day after the token
Speaker 17:  launch. I'd been following Worldcoin kind of leading up to this, but not
Speaker 17:  super in depth but I was kind of reading up on it and then I saw that they
Speaker 17:  weren't making the token available in the US but they were still doing orb
Speaker 17:  scans in a handful of cities. And I just
Speaker 17:  went online to their website. It was like booking through Calendly or
Speaker 17:  something. Like I looked for like two hours out on the very same day and
Speaker 17:  there were a ton of appointments at multiple locations in la. So I
Speaker 17:  booked one for about an hour out. I got on my car, drove across town
Speaker 17:  to West Hollywood here in Los Angeles to this non-descript coworking space
Speaker 17:  to get my eyeballs scanned by Sam Alton's or Yeah.
Speaker 18:  Before we get started, do you have any questions about the project or the
Speaker 18:  OR or anything? No, I was reading
Speaker 17:  That like your biometrics don't leave the device
Speaker 18:  Right? So that is correct. However, when you
Speaker 18:  accept the terms of service, there'll be a third optional thing where
Speaker 18:  you can keep your iris image stored in their
Speaker 18:  databases on cloud. Okay. You don't have to. Okay. And the
Speaker 18:  only benefit of it is if they do an update that
Speaker 18:  requires you to like, that changes their algorithm for hashing
Speaker 18:  your iris image, the iris code you'd have to re-scan.
Speaker 17:  Oh, okay.
Speaker 18:  So it's a convenience thing. Oh okay. Don't want it's stored then Yes, it
Speaker 18:  will be used on the orb to hash and they will delete drainage.
Speaker 17:  It was kind of funny because it's a coworking space, right? So there's a
Speaker 17:  bunch of like people there kind of working around different desks, just
Speaker 17:  kind of like plugging away like normal. And then in the various center you've
Speaker 17:  just got this like frankly kind of weird dystopian looking,
Speaker 17:  shiny metallic orb. It looks like Howl 9,000 from Space
Speaker 17:  Odyssey just sitting there. It's about a foot tall with a guy
Speaker 17:  behind it who's the orb operator so to speak. So the,
Speaker 17:  oh you gotta look right now. Oh okay.
Speaker 18:  Now's the time. Okay moment.
Speaker 17:  All right.
Speaker 18:  So yeah, now it should be verifying you on the cloud. Make sure that you
Speaker 18:  didn't try to sign up twice and trick us. Okay. And then you get a sticker.
Speaker 18:  Okay. And you get a badge and then you're
Speaker 17:  Done. Okay. you know, I guess the weirdest part of all of this is that
Speaker 17:  my orb operator didn't ask who I was, didn't ask me to confirm my
Speaker 17:  appointment time or even my email or anything like that.
Speaker 17:  He never knew my name. He just walked me through the process. And I was
Speaker 17:  scanned and gone within five minutes. Wait what? I know. Yeah, that's the
Speaker 17:  reaction. It's like what? But that's kind of the point. The point of this
Speaker 17:  technology is that Worldcoin and other companies
Speaker 17:  that use their A P I one day don't need to actually know who you are.
Speaker 17:  They just need to know that you're a human being. And so through a kind
Speaker 17:  of complicated process, I won't go super in depth on here.
Speaker 17:  Basically what happens is the orb scans your eye,
Speaker 17:  makes some little noises and then it creates this hash
Speaker 17:  of numbers tied to your IRIS scan that theoretically
Speaker 17:  is not supposed to leave the ore but helps them assign you a world id.
Speaker 17:  And then there's a corresponding code that's then eventually put on this
Speaker 17:  Ethereum based blockchain that corresponds to your iris hash.
Speaker 17:  But because of fancy cryptography technology, there's no way
Speaker 17:  of linking the two. Basically it's like just having a code saying
Speaker 17:  I am real according to the orb, my operator for the orb was of course
Speaker 17:  a guy who said he works in web three but he wasn't a Worldcoin employee.
Speaker 17:  you know, they're using contractors and paying them per scan to do this.
Speaker 17:  So he tried to answer some of my questions but couldn't really
Speaker 17:  answer all of them. Do you work at Worldcoin or? I am
Speaker 18:  A community specialist.
Speaker 17:  Oh, okay.
Speaker 18:  So I don't work full-time. I actually, I work in web
Speaker 18:  three full-time, but this is just my like fun little
Speaker 17:  Oh cool. I saw, yeah I saw the, the token launch. Are
Speaker 17:  people coming in like for mainly to get the token
Speaker 18:  Or, so in the US you don't get tokens.
Speaker 17:  Oh yeah. So you won't get tokens. So it's basically just to have your id.
Speaker 18:  It's just to have your id like, I guess maybe they think if they're like
Speaker 18:  they, they do early engagement, maybe in the future there might be a, but
Speaker 18:  like nothing of Official has been announced like that. Oh wow.
Speaker 2:  You're making me feel a lot of feelings I did not expect to feel right now.
Speaker 2:  But I think the, the thing that I had not fully processed about
Speaker 2:  Worldcoin until you just explain that, is that Worldcoin doesn't care
Speaker 2:  who you are, it just caress that you're a person. That's right.
Speaker 2:  Which I had not really thought about. Like I, I've been thinking about world
Speaker 2:  ID as like a, a sort of blockchain identity system, right? That eventually
Speaker 2:  they'd be like, we're gonna get rid of your physical passport and exchange
Speaker 2:  it for something on the blockchain. And part of me just like wants to give
Speaker 2:  that two middle fingers but they're not doing that. They're going one step
Speaker 2:  like much higher in the obstruction layer. They're just saying this is
Speaker 2:  a person and we can now sufficiently
Speaker 2:  convincingly say this is a person and that's, that's the goal here. That's
Speaker 2:  it.
Speaker 17:  Yeah. That's literally the only goal. And that now you know, the fact that
Speaker 17:  you have been verified by an orb is theoretically
Speaker 17:  provable on a blockchain and other
Speaker 17:  companies can know this and use that identity layer for their
Speaker 17:  services.
Speaker 2:  Did this whole thing seem legit to you? Like you're, you're in a,
Speaker 2:  you're in a coworking space, it's just like a contract person. We've read
Speaker 2:  all these stories about the people who are like in malls doing iris scanning.
Speaker 2:  This strikes me as the kind of thing that you'd see in a sci-fi movie and
Speaker 2:  they would be in like the top floor of a huge skyscraper and there would
Speaker 2:  be like people in white lab coats doing this. This is so different from that.
Speaker 17:  Yeah, it's very bottoms up community organized.
Speaker 17:  Like obviously these people are getting paid to do these scans but they're
Speaker 17:  really just enthusiasts. Like my operator said he worked in the web three
Speaker 17:  space of course and that he was just interested in the
Speaker 17:  technology and that most of the people that he's scanned
Speaker 17:  were coming in kind of just because they thought it was like a cool idea.
Speaker 17:  Maybe they saw Sam Altman tweet about it. He did say that a fair number,
Speaker 17:  like maybe a quarter 20% of people were asking where are my tokens?
Speaker 17:  Even though they're not available in the US there's certainly like people
Speaker 17:  are token farming. There's already been reports of people buying
Speaker 17:  world IDs on like the dark web so that they can then get the tokens
Speaker 17:  associated with that world id. So this is by no means a fail
Speaker 17:  proof system, but yeah, that's what they're doing at a high level and they're
Speaker 17:  doing with flare. you know, like this orb was designed by
Speaker 17:  Thomas Meyer Hoffer who was, Johnny i's first designer hire
Speaker 17:  at Apple and you know they've hired a lot of, you know, big names a
Speaker 17:  across the tech industry. So yeah, it's definitely this kind of weird
Speaker 17:  sci-fi thing meets reality but definitely did not feel as like high
Speaker 17:  stakes as I thought it would when I walked in.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, it's really interesting. What is your sense of what they're trying
Speaker 2:  to do with the hardware? Because I, I kind of see it a bunch of ways. On
Speaker 2:  the one hand you have this thing that they would want to make seem as normal
Speaker 2:  and uns scary as possible. If they could just like point their
Speaker 2:  phone at you and make it seem every day that that would be great. On the
Speaker 2:  other hand they seem to have leaned into this very futuristic idea.
Speaker 2:  It's this big shiny object like you said, it looks like Howl
Speaker 2:  9,000. It just looks like a robot. And I can't imagine that was not intentional.
Speaker 2:  Like what did you make of the actual hardware itself?
Speaker 17:  Yeah, I mean it's designed to look like an eye, like you're looking into
Speaker 17:  an eyeball, which is pretty creepy but it was like super
Speaker 17:  fast. It made some cute noises and over time I
Speaker 17:  think what's interesting is that tools for humanity, the parent company
Speaker 17:  says they want to open source the design of the
Speaker 17:  orbs and let other people make them and distribute them. So it becomes this
Speaker 17:  like kind of decentralized thing on top of the, the blockchain
Speaker 17:  aspect of this sounds pretty problematic 'cause what happens when
Speaker 17:  some kind of vendor installs malware or like
Speaker 17:  something into the orb that isn't, you know, to spec and there's a huge
Speaker 17:  data leakage or something. But for now it's all designed and operated and
Speaker 17:  maintained by Worldcoin. These are very expensive devices. I think they
Speaker 17:  cost like 5,000 plus each to build. But yeah, eventually
Speaker 17:  the goal is that the whole company moves towards this Dow model, a
Speaker 17:  decentralized autonomous organization where not only are the orbs able
Speaker 17:  to be operated by other people and made by other people, but the
Speaker 17:  Worldcoin itself can be used to vote on how governance works
Speaker 17:  and how the company operates. So they wanna move to this foundation model
Speaker 17:  that would also govern the orbs. They haven't done that yet. I think that's
Speaker 17:  another pretty fair criticism of doing this right now is it's kind of putting
Speaker 17:  the car before the horse on what a lot of they're trying to do. But I also
Speaker 17:  see the other side, you know, investors are telling me like, look they gotta
Speaker 17:  start somewhere. This is a chicken and egg problem. How else are you gonna
Speaker 17:  incentivize people to scan their eyes in this frankly kind of creepy thing.
Speaker 17:  So yeah, that's, that's kinda where it stands now.
Speaker 2:  Okay. And what do you get as a person who has now had your irises scanned?
Speaker 2:  Do you got a sticker which is like rad, I love a sticker and you have an
Speaker 2:  app that I guess like says you're human. Like what, how, how
Speaker 2:  has your life changed now that you've had your irises scanned?
Speaker 17:  Yeah, I've got my unique human sticker and then I've got in the
Speaker 17:  world app that says I'm verified, I'm anonymous but I'm
Speaker 17:  verified with an or. It says when I was verified and at some point in the
Speaker 17:  future I guess 'cause I'm in the US I probably won't get the world coins
Speaker 17:  but at some point in the future this ID I may be
Speaker 17:  able to use to log in somewhere I guess would be the most immediate
Speaker 17:  implication of having it. But for now it's just, just this little
Speaker 17:  virtual badge
Speaker 2:  That is I mean. One of the things that is very funny to me about
Speaker 2:  Worldcoin is there's a version of its story that if you play out the future
Speaker 2:  in one direction it is this like huge
Speaker 2:  society shaping thing, right? Like if you go all the way out into universal
Speaker 2:  basic income and a G I and we end up in this totally different place than
Speaker 2:  we are now. Something like Worldcoin could be really interesting and really
Speaker 2:  important I would say in a much more sort of immediate
Speaker 2:  and plausible worldview. It's just like a fancy login
Speaker 2:  system. Like it's very funny to me that it's integrating with Okta because
Speaker 2:  it's just Okta like in a lot of ways it's like this is a person who
Speaker 2:  would like to log into a website and it just has cooler
Speaker 2:  technology hardware than like my Apple Watch Okta
Speaker 2:  Verify app.
Speaker 17:  Yeah. Or you could be more cynical and say it's actually just a pump and
Speaker 17:  dump scheme. So 25% of all world coins are held by the company
Speaker 17:  and it's investors and they have not been able to sell any of that yet.
Speaker 17:  They're in a lockup. So a bunch of Worldcoin is gonna get dumped
Speaker 17:  you know in a year or so most likely. And you know,
Speaker 17:  retail again like has been the case and so many of these crypto stories
Speaker 17:  will be left holding the bag. Yeah, I think what's clear in the short term
Speaker 17:  is the only reason to own Worldcoin is because you think the price will
Speaker 17:  go up. But in the long run, if you buy this U B I
Speaker 17:  thing and you buy AI may one day rule the world, you may want to have it.
Speaker 17:  But it comes back to what I was saying originally. Like this is a solution
Speaker 17:  in search of a problem. And I think whatever happens. I guess I find the
Speaker 17:  idea behind Worldcoin to be deeply unsettling because
Speaker 17:  it suggests a future in which humans are indistinguishable
Speaker 17:  from machines. And I know we've had that in sci-fi, you know, I love
Speaker 17:  Westworld as much as the next person. But the idea that, you know,
Speaker 17:  Sam Altman, one of the leaders in this space is actively
Speaker 17:  building towards this future that he thinks is definitely going to
Speaker 17:  happen is pretty unsettling. And I think, you know,
Speaker 17:  we as a society may be having bigger conversations about this in the coming
Speaker 17:  years.
Speaker 2:  I think that's right. I think the thing that gives me immediate hope is that
Speaker 2:  this launch happened at a very funny time, which is right around the same
Speaker 2:  time that OpenAI ditched its project for figuring
Speaker 2:  out what text was created by AI because it
Speaker 2:  didn't work. And I just think we're, we're at this funny phase now where
Speaker 2:  like it keeps making me think of, I watch a lot of H G T V and there
Speaker 2:  was this whole run of H G T V shows where it was like regular people learn
Speaker 2:  how to flip houses and then there was a whole other run of H G
Speaker 2:  T V shows that were regular people tried to flip their houses and screwed
Speaker 2:  them up so badly that they had to call in professionals. And now that's what
Speaker 2:  that show is about. There's just literally a show called like Help I wreck
Speaker 2:  my house. And it's just like that's the phase of AI that I
Speaker 2:  think we're heading into where it was like, okay, AI got outta control, we're
Speaker 2:  gonna build tools to fix the ai, those aren't gonna work
Speaker 2:  so we're gonna, we're gonna bring in people to fix the AI but then we're
Speaker 2:  gonna use the AI to beat people and it's just like we're like caught in this
Speaker 2:  loop forever and it just sort of seems like Sam Altman is gonna be the one
Speaker 2:  sitting on every side of it, just like laughing hysterically as he makes
Speaker 2:  billions and billions of dollars. Yeah. So to some extent like, you know,
Speaker 2:  kudos to Sam Altman forgetting it like coming and going
Speaker 17:  I mean. Yeah, there's nothing like building the problem and the antidote
Speaker 17:  and being able to profit off of both, right?
Speaker 2:  Seriously,
Speaker 17:  Altman is such an important aspect of this as we've been saying. you know,
Speaker 17:  the fact that it's not launching in the US as he's really wooing regulators
Speaker 17:  going to DC meeting with President Biden about AI stuff
Speaker 17:  recently for example. you know, a lot of this is wrapped up in him and his,
Speaker 17:  how he's perceived and it makes sense to me now a little bit
Speaker 17:  more why he's been this super vocal voice talking to regulators saying
Speaker 17:  we need safety around ai. Guess what? He's got a solution, right?
Speaker 17:  He's got a for-profit solution to the problem. And so yeah, we've been
Speaker 17:  hearing a lot about chat G P T in the broader world
Speaker 17:  and society. I do think we'll start hearing more about Worldcoin
Speaker 17:  in the coming months as Altman starts talking about it more and using his
Speaker 17:  platform. So say stay tuned and you're listening to this episode, you're
Speaker 17:  getting kind of the the early look And I think something that everyone else
Speaker 17:  is gonna be talking about.
Speaker 2:  All right Alex, appreciate you stopping by as always and this time
Speaker 2:  thank you especially for scanning your eyes for journalism. If you do end
Speaker 2:  up needing new eyes by the way, let us know because that's like truly excellent
Speaker 2:  forge cast material. So keep us posted. You can read more about Alex's experience
Speaker 2:  with the orb in Command line, his excellent newsletter, which you can sign
Speaker 2:  up for at The Verge dot com slash newsletters. Alright,
Speaker 2:  one more thing to do and then we're gonna get outta here. Let's answer a
Speaker 2:  question from the Vergecast hotline.
Speaker 2:  As a reminder, the hotline number is 8 6 6 Verge one one.
Speaker 2:  Please call and ask us all your deepest, darkest, weirdest tech
Speaker 2:  questions. We love them all. You can also email Vergecast at The Verge dot
Speaker 2:  com, send us a voice memo, whatever makes you happy. We love hearing our
Speaker 2:  questions. For this one, I brought in V Song Hy-Vee.
Speaker 19:  Hey, what's up?
Speaker 2:  I have not played you this question I just, I gave you like a vague sense
Speaker 2:  of what's coming. So let's, let me just play the question. I think you'll
Speaker 2:  be ready for this, but I'm excited to see where we go 'cause I also have
Speaker 2:  this question here we go.
Speaker 20:  Hey guys, it's Mark again. And I had a question
Speaker 20:  about wearables or particularly wearables without screens
Speaker 20:  because I have a pretty, well I think they're listing
Speaker 20:  it's a cool little GShock slash vintage Cassia watch collection.
Speaker 20:  And. I really enjoy wearing them. But I also would really
Speaker 20:  love to get a lot of the health tracking and sleep tracking features of
Speaker 20:  something like an Apple Watch or whatever Samsung's rolling out these
Speaker 20:  days. And so I tried an Apple watch for a little bit, I
Speaker 20:  just don't really care for a screen on my wrist, I'm being honest
Speaker 20:  with you. I already feel like the notifications on my phone are a little
Speaker 20:  bit too much. So I'd rather avoid that on my wrist too. But I
Speaker 20:  also would really like to track my health sub. So I'm wondering are there
Speaker 20:  any wearables without a screen these days? Something kind of closer to like
Speaker 20:  the Fitbit Flex that used to exist, r i p or
Speaker 20:  also anything that's like not frankly what I think is kind of expensive,
Speaker 20:  like the aura ring. Anyways, thanks for the help. Bye. Okay,
Speaker 2:  You're, you're making the face that made me want to do this question. It's,
Speaker 2:  it's bleak dude.
Speaker 19:  It's bleak. Like when you said something not as expensive
Speaker 19:  as the aura ring, I was like, oh, because yeah, that is
Speaker 19:  basically what I think fits 99% of
Speaker 19:  what Mark's asking for because it's, it's going to get you
Speaker 19:  really great clinically, I don't wanna say validated, but
Speaker 19:  clinically tested sleep tracking. Like they just, I've been on
Speaker 19:  calls with them and they just told me how like their sleep tracking is,
Speaker 19:  I wanna say around 75, 70 9% corresponds to
Speaker 19:  polysomnography, which is the gold standard. So if you want really accurate
Speaker 19:  sleep tracking the AAA ring is one of the best options for it. It's
Speaker 19:  not invasive in the sense that you never get a single
Speaker 19:  notification from this on your, on your body. Yeah. Like the only
Speaker 19:  problem with that is it can run out of battery and then you're like, oh
Speaker 19:  I missed two nights because I missed that one notification on my phone
Speaker 19:  that says charge this thing up. Yeah. So that's the one thing with
Speaker 19:  that. The other one would be whoop and
Speaker 19:  whoop is still kind of expensive.
Speaker 2:  Yeah and whoop also picks it's, it has such a different idea about what
Speaker 2:  to measure and what you care about that I've always had a hard time
Speaker 2:  recommending it to people because it's like, like Mark wants step tracking
Speaker 2:  and sleep tracking fundamentally, right? All the other stuff is well and
Speaker 2:  good, but that's fundamentally what it wants. And Whoop has this very different
Speaker 2:  picture of how you should measure health and if that works for you. It makes
Speaker 2:  a lot of sense. It's really interested in recovery and lots of different
Speaker 2:  ideas about how to sort of track exertion. That's all fine and good but it's
Speaker 2:  not step tracking and sleep tracking.
Speaker 19:  Well it is sleep tracking because the sleep tracking kind of feeds into
Speaker 19:  their recovery metrics. That's true but it's, it's not really gonna help
Speaker 19:  you so much on the step tracking part of it. It's really
Speaker 19:  geared towards people who have, you know, ambitious
Speaker 19:  training regimens and who really care about their H R V and they wanna
Speaker 19:  check their exertion and want to be at optimal like priming.
Speaker 19:  That's, those are the two that are like the most well-known
Speaker 19:  Screenless devices. The other one would have been the Amazon
Speaker 19:  Halo, but that's kaput 'cause they also went to this
Speaker 19:  Screenless route. There is the Fitbit
Speaker 19:  Inspire three which has the most like not
Speaker 19:  even a screen screen because it's just, it's, it's basically kind of like
Speaker 19:  the Fitbit flags a little bit. It's, it's got a, oh let's screen now.
Speaker 19:  So it's not as the the monochrome L C D as it used to be,
Speaker 19:  but you know, it's really not gonna tell you much 'cause it's a tiny little
Speaker 19:  screen and you're not really gonna be looking through notifications on that.
Speaker 19:  So that is an option if you don't mind double wristing as as I do.
Speaker 19:  But you know, there is a couple of smart rings that are coming
Speaker 19:  out. I've got a sizing kit for one, so I'm gonna be testing that
Speaker 19:  and if that's an option, that'll be cool. But the problem with smart
Speaker 19:  rings is that they all kind of cost around the amount that the Aura Ring
Speaker 19:  does. There's not really a, what I would call a super
Speaker 19:  affordable option for Screenless at
Speaker 19:  the moment because they're, they're being like,
Speaker 19:  the people developing the Screenless tech at the moment are the ones who
Speaker 19:  are really invested in research and that sort of stuff. So
Speaker 19:  you're gonna get people who are like, Hey, you want a subscription so you
Speaker 19:  can fund our research? And the answer is always no, I don't want the subscription.
Speaker 19:  But if you're looking into like cost effectiveness, whoop
Speaker 19:  recently lowered their subscription prices, so if you wanna lock yourself
Speaker 19:  in there for a long time, you can get a lower
Speaker 19:  monthly subscription and the hardware is quote unquote free.
Speaker 19:  You know, they, they say that it's never free, it's just built into a much
Speaker 19:  higher monthly subscription. So if you wanna, and you know, I
Speaker 19:  I believe they have like year long commitments, so that's kind of not
Speaker 19:  my favorite thing. But yeah, so the OR Ring is still
Speaker 19:  unfortunately, I think your best bet, unless you're willing to cobble
Speaker 19:  together multiple devices to you see like
Speaker 19:  Jerry Rig something, I unfortunately don't think that that's
Speaker 19:  really great. But if sleep tracking is your number one thing, there are
Speaker 19:  actually a number of sleep trekking apps on your phone that are pretty good.
Speaker 19:  There's sleep cycle. I like rise
Speaker 19:  Rise science, which is, that does have a yearly subscription, but I believe
Speaker 19:  it's like $60 and if you really get on top of
Speaker 19:  that sleep habit, then it's not really gonna be a forever
Speaker 19:  thing Rise is interesting because it takes into account your
Speaker 19:  circadian rhythms and based on like your phone
Speaker 19:  cracking you and your sleep, it'll be like, oh, okay, this is your sleep
Speaker 19:  need, this is your sleep debt. Like these are the times of the day where
Speaker 19:  you should plan high intensity activity and these are the ones where
Speaker 19:  you should do like lower intensity because your energy is gonna dip. And
Speaker 19:  I've done, I've been doing that for I wanna say six, seven months now. It's
Speaker 19:  interesting. After a while I don't pay attention to it anymore. So that's
Speaker 19:  kind of the trap with sleep tracking apps. So I, I feel really
Speaker 19:  bad Mark because I have very unsatisfying answers for you.
Speaker 19:  But yeah, I, I do think the Aura Ring is like 99% of what he
Speaker 19:  is looking for except for price, which is always the issue with the Aura
Speaker 19:  ring.
Speaker 2:  That's exactly where I landed too, is I did a bunch of research and landed
Speaker 2:  on the Aura is kind of the only answer. And that's really the, the last thing
Speaker 2:  I'm curious about from you before, before we let you here is I think
Speaker 2:  what it seems like has happened is the whole market for people like
Speaker 2:  Mark has disappeared, right? For a while we had, you could buy a
Speaker 2:  thing that looked more or less like a bracelet, like the original Jawbone
Speaker 2:  is still my favorite wearable of all time. It was that nice sort of, it was
Speaker 2:  like a little too snap bracelet looking, but it just like fit
Speaker 2:  around a wrist. It looked much less like technology and more like a thing
Speaker 2:  you might actually wanna wear on purpose, which was great. And then there
Speaker 2:  were the Fitbit trackers that you could clip to things. Those were cool.
Speaker 2:  Like we had this run of things that weren't smart watches and
Speaker 2:  all of those have died in favor of either smart watches on one end, that's
Speaker 2:  kind of the mainstream idea or the like capital ss
Speaker 2:  scientific tools that are very expensive and designed for people who want
Speaker 2:  to do like clinical studies on themselves. And it seems like the middle ground
Speaker 2:  is just gone. Is that ever gonna come back? Like have, my argument
Speaker 2:  would be that we've pushed too many people towards smart watches, including
Speaker 2:  a lot of people who actually don't want smart watches and that maybe there
Speaker 2:  is room in the middle, but maybe I'm crazy.
Speaker 19:  No, you're not crazy. You're 100% correct. So what ended up
Speaker 19:  happening is one Google bought Fitbit and that kind of killed
Speaker 19:  the middle market Fitbit smart watches are
Speaker 19:  blah, especially with the latest generation, but I still think that
Speaker 19:  the Inspire three is quite good. And I believe with the Inspire three you
Speaker 19:  can pop out the, the main unit and you can stick it
Speaker 19:  in like different accessories. So that, that's one option.
Speaker 19:  Garmin makes a single fitness band at the moment, which actually
Speaker 19:  may be more up Mark's Alley now that I think about it. The only
Speaker 19:  issue is that Garmin sleep tracking kind of sucks. So that's, that's
Speaker 19:  actually the, the, the worst part about a Garmin is that it's sleep tracking
Speaker 19:  is I think not good. It's good enough to
Speaker 19:  do your like recovery metrics because that's pulling on different things
Speaker 19:  like heart rate variation, but in terms of like you wanting to sleep better,
Speaker 19:  it's not very helpful.
Speaker 2:  And even that the, the Vivosmart falls into that same, it's a smaller
Speaker 2:  screen but it's still a screen category.
Speaker 19:  It's still a screen. So months ago I was reviewing
Speaker 19:  Amaz Fit a Maze Fit, I still dunno how to pronounce it. Me neither
Speaker 19:  am Mafi Band seven. It is a $50 fitness
Speaker 19:  tracker and it, if you wanna throw back to all the different
Speaker 19:  mid-range fitness bands of yesteryear, that's a really great
Speaker 19:  option. It has a lot of the health tracking features, the sleep tracking
Speaker 19:  is all right. The battery life is pretty good. It's not a
Speaker 19:  Looker, it's fairly, you know, I want, I don't wanna say
Speaker 19:  Chinsy, but it's, it's not the best looking device. It's very
Speaker 19:  utilitarian. The only issue I've seen with
Speaker 19:  recommending this to people is that people are like, well it's a Chinese
Speaker 19:  company and Chinese company's don't have my health data. No thank you. To
Speaker 19:  which, you know, the problem is, is that Fitbit started
Speaker 19:  dying off because these Chinese company like Xiaomi and
Speaker 19:  Amaz Fit, they basically came in and was like, Hey, what if we sold you
Speaker 19:  these fitness bands for not a hundred dollars like Fitbit's asking
Speaker 19:  for, but somewhere between 20 to $50 and it's largely
Speaker 19:  gonna get you a good portion of the experience. So
Speaker 19:  that just kind of cannibalized the whole market. you know, I had a reader
Speaker 19:  ask me the other day, why didn't Samsung update the, the it's fitness
Speaker 19:  spans? And I was like, honey, they have not updated these since
Speaker 19:  the last time I went to efa, which I think was like 2019
Speaker 19:  past 20 18, 20 19, maybe even 2017, like it was a really,
Speaker 19:  really long time ago. So I too, you know,
Speaker 19:  I might, I might end up blogging this, but like I too have wondered where
Speaker 19:  the fitness bands have gone. And I get a lot of
Speaker 19:  questions like those from Mark And, I feel really bad that I'm like, well
Speaker 19:  if you got built a time machine and traveled back to 2014, I have some options
Speaker 19:  for you there. But all of those options have since lost
Speaker 19:  support because the companies went under as well. So you are kind of stuck
Speaker 19:  with smartwatches, which I do think is tragic because
Speaker 19:  not everyone wants a smartwatch. I even take smartwatch free days once in
Speaker 19:  a while to maintain my own sanity. So it's, I really feel
Speaker 19:  for Mark. But you know there, you know, thinking about it, I do have a sleep
Speaker 19:  tracker buying guide or sleep tech buying guide, which if sleep
Speaker 19:  is really your main thing, there are non-invasive
Speaker 19:  non-contact sleep options. The Nest Hub is one it, it'll track you via
Speaker 19:  radar. The Ying sleep mat I believe it's called
Speaker 19:  is like a $100 sleep mat that you stick under your mattress and
Speaker 19:  it can read your heart rate and all of that stuff. So that's kind of cool.
Speaker 19:  I have an eight sleep pod pro cover, which is not
Speaker 19:  cheap, that is even more expensive than the Ora Ring, but it does offer
Speaker 19:  temperature cooling. So you know, you're either
Speaker 19:  gonna, if you really wanna avoid the screens and sleep track, you're gonna
Speaker 19:  have to go with like six different devices at which point it's kind of
Speaker 19:  gonna add up to the cost of an ora ring. So, you know,
Speaker 19:  I, I am gonna say right now your best option is the Ora ring until more
Speaker 19:  people like you start complaining that screens are ruining their lives
Speaker 19:  and then we can get our more simple fitness tracker blast
Speaker 19:  from the past bands back. Which, you know, I would actually be really
Speaker 19:  happy about. I miss, I miss the old Fitbit days sometimes.
Speaker 1:  Alright,
Speaker 2:  That is it for The Vergecast today. Thank you to everyone who came on the
Speaker 2:  show and thank you as always for listening. There's lots more on everything
Speaker 2:  we talked about from sleep tracking, buying guides to Worldcoin
Speaker 2:  orb experiences on The Verge dot com. We'll put some links in the show notes.
Speaker 2:  But as always, read the website, leave us a comment on the
Speaker 2:  post about this episode. We'd love to hear everything you think and we do
Speaker 2:  answer at least one hotline question every episode. So keep em coming.
Speaker 2:  This show is produced by Andrew Marino and Liam James Brooke Mins is our
Speaker 2:  editorial director of Audio The. Vergecast is Verge production and part of
Speaker 2:  the Vox Media podcast network. Neli Alex, And I will be back on Friday to
Speaker 2:  talk about probably more Samsung, the latest going on with the
Speaker 2:  X sign on top of the Twitter building and lots more. See you then. Rock and
Speaker 2:  roll.