# Transcript
ID: d4ccd473-3d30-4857-9f61-aa56851126f8
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: AI voices are taking over the internet
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-4963541293670325956/2071838724434312655/s93290-US-1507s-1694996835.mp3
Description: In part one of The Vergecast's AI mini series, David Pierce dives into the boom of voice synthesis and artificially generated speech. The process is a lot more accessible for everyone, but how realistic can it sound?
Speaker 2:  Welcome to The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of Neurological Engines
Speaker 2:  for overdubbing. I'm David Pierce and hang on one second. Actually, I
Speaker 2:  just gotta finish something. Once upon a time, a white snake and a
Speaker 2:  green snake living in a remote mountain became immortal and obtained
Speaker 2:  superpowers after centuries of practice. Okay,
Speaker 2:  sorry. I'm back, and before you worry that I just like had a stroke or
Speaker 2:  something live on the microphone, I should tell you that I'm actually in
Speaker 2:  the middle of training an AI to mimic the sound of my voice. This
Speaker 2:  one is on the iPhone. It's called Personal Voice and products like this
Speaker 2:  are what we're gonna talk about today. The idea of being able to
Speaker 2:  create your own AI voice clone has been around for a while.
Speaker 2:  We actually talked a bunch about it on this show in 2021. I'll link to it
Speaker 2:  in the show notes. A lot of it holds up really well, but over the last couple
Speaker 2:  of years it's gotten both drastically easier to make a vocal
Speaker 2:  AI and the results have gotten drastically better. You can even
Speaker 2:  do it on your phone like I'm doing now with just a few minutes of really
Speaker 2:  awkward reading of sentences. Here's what mine sounds like. Hi, I am
Speaker 2:  David Pierce's, ai iPhone voice. I'm kind of like David, but kind of not.
Speaker 2:  So today on the show we're going to dive into the boom of voice ai
Speaker 2:  and then we're gonna try to figure out if I can actually make something that
Speaker 2:  sounds like me. This is The Vergecast. We'll be right back.
Speaker 3:  Support for this show comes from a w s. Innovations in
Speaker 3:  machine learning and AI have completely changed the game, but
Speaker 3:  as with any cutting edge technology, it's important to stay ahead of the
Speaker 3:  curve or you risk getting left behind. Amazon Web Services
Speaker 3:  can help your small business stay ahead of the competition. A w
Speaker 3:  s provides a framework for businesses to navigate the fast changing landscape
Speaker 3:  and helps businesses harness the emerging capabilities of AI and
Speaker 3:  machine learning. It's time to imagine how a w s can
Speaker 3:  transform your business. Go to AWS is how.com
Speaker 3:  to learn more.
Speaker 2:  All right, we're back. Before we get too deep into the world of AI voices,
Speaker 2:  let's try and quickly understand why this is such a big thing right now.
Speaker 2:  And as far as I can tell, there are basically three reasons this kind of
Speaker 2:  tech is booming. The first is because audio in general is
Speaker 2:  booming with podcasts and voice messages and those generated
Speaker 2:  spoken captions you hear on TikTok and all sorts of other things.
Speaker 2:  If you think about it, you probably hear the internet a lot more than you
Speaker 2:  used to, and like any other creative feature on the internet, a lot of
Speaker 2:  tools exist to help you make it. One app we use is called
Speaker 2:  Script. It's an app that a lot of people use for editing audio and video.
Speaker 2:  It has this feature called Overdub Voices and one of the script's coolest
Speaker 2:  features in general is that you can edit audio and video basically by editing
Speaker 2:  text. You import a file, it gives you a transcript, and if you
Speaker 2:  delete the word in the transcript, it'll also try and
Speaker 2:  seamlessly delete the from the actual audio file. It's not
Speaker 2:  perfect, but it works pretty well and it kind of feels like magic to use
Speaker 2:  it with overdub. Descrip can go even further. Let's say you
Speaker 2:  forgot something or you stumbled on a word or transition, you can
Speaker 2:  now make an AI copy of your own voice and insert new
Speaker 2:  audio just by typing the text you want to appear. So let's say I say
Speaker 2:  the sentence, the iPhone came out in 2007 when Steve Jobs announced
Speaker 2:  it as three things, a wide screen iPod, a revolutionary mobile
Speaker 2:  phone, and a breakthrough internet communicator. Alright, let's just hear
Speaker 2:  that sentence back. The iPhone came out in 2007 when
Speaker 2:  Steve Jobs announced it as three things. A widescreen iPod, a
Speaker 2:  revolutionary mobile phone, and a breakthrough internet communicator. Wait,
Speaker 2:  sorry, I got that slightly wrong. He called it a breakthrough internet communications
Speaker 2:  device. I could rerecord that whole thing or I could just go into the
Speaker 2:  script, retype the transcript, and here's what I get. The iPhone
Speaker 2:  came out in 2007 when Steve Jobs announced it as three things,
Speaker 2:  a widescreen iPod, a revolutionary mobile phone, and a breakthrough internet
Speaker 2:  communications device. It's not bad. I wouldn't wanna
Speaker 2:  listen to a whole hour of that voice, I don't think, but in small
Speaker 2:  bits, and especially in the context of something larger, I'm not even sure
Speaker 2:  you'd always notice it there. There are other apps out there like podcasts
Speaker 2:  all doing the same kind of thing, and I suspect you're gonna see tools like
Speaker 2:  this show up anywhere that people make audio.
Speaker 2:  Okay, so that's the first use case. The second is kind of the flip side.
Speaker 2:  There are also a bunch of tools out there using AI voices to read written
Speaker 2:  stories out loud. The Atlantic, for instance, is working with a company called
Speaker 2:  11 Labs to have an AI narrator read some of the stories
Speaker 2:  on the website.
Speaker 4:  For years, the American approach to protein has been a never ending
Speaker 4:  quest for more. On average, each person in the United States
Speaker 4:  puts away roughly 300 pounds of meat a year.
Speaker 2:  Again, it's not perfect and I don't know that it always sounds like a person,
Speaker 2:  but I kind of can't believe how good it's, it wasn't that
Speaker 2:  long ago by the way that these generated voices sounded like
Speaker 2:  flat tone less robots like, here's Sophia, the robot from
Speaker 2:  2016 that was considered to be one of the most advanced robots ever created
Speaker 2:  on The Tonight Show.
Speaker 5:  I traveled to over 25 countries, appeared on the cover of
Speaker 5:  Cosmopolitan Magazine, met German Chancellor Anger La
Speaker 5:  Merkel, and the actor Will Smith and became Twitter friends with Chrissy
Speaker 5:  Tegan,
Speaker 2:  And here is that same thing Sophia said, which I just typed into the generator
Speaker 2:  on the 11 Labs website. I picked a voice name, grace, put this in there,
Speaker 2:  click generate, and after about 10 seconds, this is what came out.
Speaker 6:  I traveled to over 25 countries, appeared on the cover of
Speaker 6:  Cosmopolitan Magazine, met German chancellor Angela Merkel
Speaker 6:  and the actor Will Smith and became Twitter friends with Chrissy Teigan.
Speaker 2:  I mean, it's night and day right? I think you're gonna start to see this
Speaker 2:  everywhere, articles, whole websites, entire books,
Speaker 2:  all read aloud, all using generated AI and the product itself
Speaker 2:  is actually starting to be pretty good.
Speaker 2:  It is also, of course, a huge ethical and legal disaster
Speaker 2:  all the way back in 2019 again, before the tech was nearly as good
Speaker 2:  as it is now. A bunch of publishers sued Audible over a feature called
Speaker 2:  Audible Captions, which would read a book aloud to you as you look to the
Speaker 2:  page. It seems like a normal useful feature, right?
Speaker 2:  Also seems like an existential threat to the entire idea and industry of
Speaker 2:  audiobooks. Audible and the publishers settled in 2020, but that was
Speaker 2:  only the beginning of the bigger questions here, some audiobook
Speaker 2:  narrators have worried that their voices are being used to train algorithms
Speaker 2:  that might someday replace them, and they're not really wrong. All this
Speaker 2:  is not at all theoretical. If you go into the Apple Books app and search
Speaker 2:  for AI narration, you'll find a bunch of audio books that say they are narrated
Speaker 2:  by Apple Books. Apple says that that means that they are quote
Speaker 2:  narrated by a digital voice based on a human narrator. Here's just a
Speaker 2:  sample from a book called Language of Love by Kristin Ethridge. A lot of
Speaker 2:  these AI narrated books are romance novels by the way, for whatever reason,
Speaker 2:  and this one sounds to my ears, shockingly like a human red audiobook,
Speaker 8:  He raised his fist and wrapped on the solid wood. After about 30
Speaker 8:  seconds of silence, the distinct sound of the lock turning broke
Speaker 8:  through a woman of average heights stepped into the sliver of
Speaker 8:  an opening.
Speaker 2:  The other version of this that you might have heard about or even encountered
Speaker 2:  without knowing is celebrity AI voices. Like there was a pretty
Speaker 2:  big backlash a couple of years ago when a documentary about Anthony Bourdain
Speaker 2:  called Roadrunner, which came out after Bourdain's death, trained an
Speaker 2:  AI model on his voice and then used it to generate narration for the film.
Speaker 2:  The director Morgan Neville said that he only used the AI to say words that
Speaker 2:  Bourdain himself had written, which was an ethical choice for him, and I
Speaker 2:  guess I can see where he's coming from. I still don't know whether any of
Speaker 2:  that feels okay to me or awful. It's all really
Speaker 2:  complicated and examples like this exist everywhere. AI helped
Speaker 2:  Val Kilmer speak after he lost his voice due to throat cancer. Lots of celebrities
Speaker 2:  trained AI to do things like give you Waze directions. All this too
Speaker 2:  is pretty controversial. One of the things Hollywood is on strike about right
Speaker 2:  now is AI's potential to scan their likeness so that they never need to
Speaker 2:  be actually used in films again. Imagine an AI trained on
Speaker 2:  Morgan Freeman's voice that could narrate every documentary ever without
Speaker 2:  paying Freeman a dime. This stuff all gets really messy really
Speaker 2:  fast. Okay, and Then, we have the third and probably most
Speaker 2:  newly mainstream use case here, accessibility.
Speaker 2:  Apple launched a new feature this year in iOS 17 called Live Speech,
Speaker 2:  which you can use to type something and have it said out loud in phone calls
Speaker 2:  or even for in-person conversation, and when you pair it with personal voice.
Speaker 2:  Another new feature this year, the one I was testing up at the beginning
Speaker 2:  of the show, you can create an AI version of your own voice just
Speaker 2:  by recording yourself, talking into your phone, and then use that to generate
Speaker 2:  your live speech. It's all a little like the incredibly powerful
Speaker 2:  system that the late Stephen Hawking had, which let him speak through a computer.
Speaker 9:  A cat offers a list of predictions based on an analysis of
Speaker 9:  the English language in my previous usage.
Speaker 2:  Okay, again, not to keep belaboring this point, but that video is from eight
Speaker 2:  years ago. Think about how much better a system like Hawkings would sound
Speaker 2:  today. Although I have to say I do love how much Hawking
Speaker 2:  embraced that robotic sound and made it his own.
Speaker 9:  It has become my trademark and I wouldn't change it for
Speaker 9:  a more natural voice with a British accent.
Speaker 2:  Samsung is building a similar feature with Bixby so that you can now speak
Speaker 2:  with your own voice through your Galaxy. Phone works kind of the same way
Speaker 2:  and on a similar line, lots of people have used screen readers for years,
Speaker 2:  which are able to speak aloud, whatever's on a screen. Those are also getting
Speaker 2:  vastly better, both because the voices are improving and because AI systems
Speaker 2:  are getting much better at actually understanding the contents of
Speaker 2:  webpage and apps and anything else you're looking at. All of that is super
Speaker 2:  exciting and I'm also really into the idea of being able to use machine
Speaker 2:  translation in these voices to be able to speak simultaneously in
Speaker 2:  lots of languages someday, not that far from now. This podcast
Speaker 2:  with my voice could be available in basically any language on
Speaker 2:  earth. That's really cool. It's also a really hard problem and we're definitely
Speaker 2:  not there yet, but in general, being able to speak with your own voice,
Speaker 2:  even when you can't do that, is a big deal. It's complicated
Speaker 2:  ethically and morally and legally and in so many other ways,
Speaker 2:  but it's a big deal nonetheless.
Speaker 2:  Alright, we need to take a quick break and then when we come back, we're
Speaker 2:  gonna investigate what it takes to actually make an AI voice and see if
Speaker 2:  it's really possible to do it well. We'll be right back.
Speaker 3:  Support for this show comes from a w s. We are living
Speaker 3:  in the future and artificial intelligence is completely transforming
Speaker 3:  how business is done, but without an experienced developer on your team,
Speaker 3:  how can you make the most of these emerging technologies? Amazon
Speaker 3:  Web Services can help. A w s has been democratizing
Speaker 3:  access to AI and machine learning for companies and customers.
Speaker 3:  They've invested $100 million to build their generative AI
Speaker 3:  innovation center to help customers understand and deploy generative
Speaker 3:  AI to predict trends and prototype with data-driven design.
Speaker 3:  Just imagine how a w s can transform your business. learn
Speaker 3:  more at a w ss is how.com.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. Let's make some AI voices, shall we?
Speaker 2:  The idea with most of these systems is basically the same because the way
Speaker 2:  you train an AI model in general is just to give it lots and lots and lots
Speaker 2:  of data and just kind of watch it churn through and see what it learns.
Speaker 2:  But in the systems I've been trying, there is one important distinction.
Speaker 2:  Some tools like Descrip, just ask for a huge batch of audio.
Speaker 2:  They'll give you a script if you want it, but really the goal is just to
Speaker 2:  upload hours and hours and hours of the sound of your voice and see what
Speaker 2:  happens. Others go one step further and we'll ask you to record
Speaker 2:  yourself saying a series of specific and often weird and often
Speaker 2:  thoroughly random things. So like when I open up podcast to create
Speaker 2:  my digital AI voice, it had a lot of really specific instructions.
Speaker 2:  Okay, now time to do 70 sentences. Here we go.
Speaker 2:  Everything seems better. In summer. I asked my
Speaker 2:  dad if he could help me look at that lovely cat
Speaker 2:  That he had it 70 sentences later, I waited a while and
Speaker 2:  the next day I got an email saying my digital voice was ready. You wanna
Speaker 2:  hear it? Hi, I'm David Pierce, except not
Speaker 2:  really. I'm an AI bot, but I've been trained to sound like David
Speaker 2:  Pierce. Is this convincing? That one's not great,
Speaker 2:  not super impressed, but let's give it a little more to work with and see
Speaker 2:  how we do. While we're on the subject of ethically dubious things, I'm gonna
Speaker 2:  grab the text of one of my favorite TV moments ever. It's
Speaker 2:  a Dwight Shroud speech from the office.
Speaker 10:  What is my perfect crime? I break into Tiffany's at midnight.
Speaker 10:  Do I go for the vault? No. I go for the chandelier. It's priceless.
Speaker 10:  As I'm taking it down, a woman catches me. She tells me to stop. It's her
Speaker 10:  father's business. She's Tiffany. I say, no, we make love all
Speaker 10:  night. In the morning, the cops come and I escape in one of their uniforms.
Speaker 10:  I tell her to meet me in Mexico, but I go to Canada. I don't trust her
Speaker 10:  besides, I like the cold. 30 years later, I get a postcard. I have
Speaker 10:  a son and he's the chief of police. This is where the story gets interesting.
Speaker 10:  I tell Tiffany to meet me in Paris by the trod. She's
Speaker 10:  been waiting for me all these years. She's never taken another lover. I
Speaker 10:  don't care. I don't show up. I go to Berlin. That's where I stashed the
Speaker 10:  chandelier.
Speaker 2:  I mean, it's just like 60 perfect seconds. I love it so much. Let's have
Speaker 2:  ai David take a run at that speech. Here goes, what is my perfect
Speaker 2:  crime? I break into Tiffany's at midnight. Do I go for the
Speaker 2:  fall? No. I go for the chandelier. It's priceless. As
Speaker 2:  I'm taking it down, a woman catches me. She tells me to stop.
Speaker 2:  It's her father's business. She's Tiffany. I say, no, we make
Speaker 2:  love all night. Okay, so I hear that and it's like,
Speaker 2:  yeah, that sounds like me, but it also doesn't sound like a human, if
Speaker 2:  that makes sense. in general, podcast was really easy to use, but
Speaker 2:  I'm not terribly impressed with the outcome. So now let's try script,
Speaker 2:  which is I think in general a significantly more sophisticated piece of
Speaker 2:  audio software. It too is a process. So I go to
Speaker 2:  voices. Yeah, we're creating a new voice. Alright,
Speaker 2:  we'll do a few recent Friday Verge casts. How about
Speaker 2:  that? Preparing and uploading. Okay, it
Speaker 2:  finally uploaded all my stuff. Let's go. We click Submit Training data and
Speaker 2:  now it says, ready to create your overdub voice record your voice Id press
Speaker 2:  record and read the statement below. All right, let's do it. We hit stop.
Speaker 2:  We submit it. We are uploading. It says, putting the finishing touches on
Speaker 2:  your training project. Your voice is now training. We'll email you when it's
Speaker 2:  done. Here we go. I ended up submitting about four
Speaker 2:  hours of my own voice to make this happen because luckily, I already have
Speaker 2:  hours of my voice recorded from just being on The Vergecast and
Speaker 2:  like with podcast. It took a while to process everything and then I got an
Speaker 2:  email that my voice was ready, which is a very funny email to receive. Here's
Speaker 2:  what it sounded like. Hi, I'm David Pierce, the ai, David Pierce,
Speaker 2:  the descrip version of ai, David Pierce. How do I sound?
Speaker 2:  All I hear in that is that I feel like that's what I might sound like if
Speaker 2:  I'd gone to like a really fancy New England boarding school and
Speaker 2:  also had a really, really nasty head cold, but I don't think in general
Speaker 2:  that one sounds like me at all really, but let's try it again with our
Speaker 2:  Dwight Fruit speech. What is my perfect crime? I break into
Speaker 2:  Tiffany's at midnight. Do I go for the vault? No, I go for the chandelier.
Speaker 2:  It's priceless. I have a son and he's the chief of police. This is where
Speaker 2:  the story gets interesting. I tell Tiffany to meet me in Paris by the
Speaker 2:  trod. She's been waiting for me all these years. She's never taken another
Speaker 2:  lover. I don't show up. I go to Berlin. That's where I stash the
Speaker 2:  chandelier. The strange thing about this one is the intonation, the
Speaker 2:  kind of ebb and flow of the sentences here. It's really not bad. It's
Speaker 2:  a little stilted, but it does move more or less like you would
Speaker 2:  expect a human to talk. It just doesn't sound right and it
Speaker 2:  seems to skip a bunch of words and sentences when it doesn't quite know what
Speaker 2:  to do. My takeaway is basically descrip is fine for those little filler words
Speaker 2:  like we were doing earlier, but that's about it.
Speaker 2:  I would say in general so far my takeaway is that these things aren't amazing,
Speaker 2:  but they're decent and honestly it's really easy to make them like much easier
Speaker 2:  than I expected. So let's keep going. Let's do a couple more.
Speaker 2:  11 Labs, the company we've talked about a bunch so far has the simplest process
Speaker 2:  of any that I've seen. You just sign up, upload a few minutes of audio. It
Speaker 2:  actually explicitly says you only need about five minutes and that anything
Speaker 2:  more is just overkill and you're off and running. So I added some Vergecast
Speaker 2:  stuff about 15 minutes and all because You know I'm an overachiever and
Speaker 2:  then just waited a while. This one only took a couple of minutes and we were
Speaker 2:  up and running. Hi, it's AI David Pierce again. This time I'm made by 11
Speaker 2:  Labs, but I'm still me sort of. I think You know what I mean.
Speaker 2:  I'm not gonna lie it, that one kind of gave me goosebumps. It goes a little
Speaker 2:  fast like I don't think that's how you'd say that sentence, but this is way
Speaker 2:  better than anything else I've tried or even heard, and it took a grand total
Speaker 2:  of about 90 seconds to put together. What's weird though is
Speaker 2:  that it's not always this good. I clicked generate again with the same
Speaker 2:  text and it spit back something subtly different and I think
Speaker 2:  slightly worse. Hi, it's AI David Pierce again. This time I'm
Speaker 2:  made by 11 labs, but I'm still me sort of. I think You know what I mean.
Speaker 2:  Again, really good, better than anything else we've tried, but not quite
Speaker 2:  as good as that first one, which is odd. It's just that pause in the first
Speaker 2:  one right before the word sort of is like exactly how I
Speaker 2:  would've said that in real life. I still kind of can't get over it. It freaked
Speaker 2:  me out. Anyway, let's try this model with our Dwight True Speech.
Speaker 2:  What is my perfect crime? I break into Tiffany's at midnight. Do I go for
Speaker 2:  the vault? No. I go for the chandelier. It's priceless.
Speaker 2:  As I'm taking it down, a woman catches me. She tells me to stop.
Speaker 2:  It's her father's business. She's Tiffany. I say, no,
Speaker 2:  we make love all night. In the morning, the cops come and I escape
Speaker 2:  in one of their uniforms. I tell her to meet me in Mexico, but I go
Speaker 2:  to Canada. I don't trust her besides, I like the cold.
Speaker 2:  30 years later I get a postcard. I have a son and he's the
Speaker 2:  chief of police. This is where the story gets interesting. I tell Tiffany
Speaker 2:  to meet me in Paris by the ero. She's been waiting for me all these
Speaker 2:  years. She's never taken another lover. I don't care. I
Speaker 2:  don't show up. I go to Berlin. That's where I stashed the chandelier.
Speaker 2:  That one's not perfect and it seems to me that it got a little worse
Speaker 2:  as it went on. The cadence got a little less human and a little more just
Speaker 2:  kind of robot monotone. Everything takes the same time to say
Speaker 2:  You. know what I mean? But I bet I could use that voice on almost anyone
Speaker 2:  for a minute or two and get away with it. What is my perfect crime? Okay,
Speaker 2:  let's try one more. This is the Apple personal voice feature. The one that's
Speaker 2:  gonna come to lots of people's iPhones. I suspect a lot of people are gonna
Speaker 2:  set this up pretty soon. This one took by the way, the longest by far of
Speaker 2:  any to set up, so the first thing I have to do is decide, do I wanna share
Speaker 2:  across devices? Sure. Do I wanna allow apps to request to
Speaker 2:  use? Why would I want that? Creating my personal voice. I'm gonna
Speaker 2:  read 150 phrases aloud, which may take about 15 minutes. Then
Speaker 2:  it's gonna generate it, and then we'll go from there. All right. Let's see.
Speaker 2:  That was the best movie I've ever seen. Are you still hungry?
Speaker 2:  It's a beautiful day today. It's an extension of the nearby sea.
Speaker 2:  Her style of painting shows the influence of the French artists.
Speaker 2:  Then once it was set up, it also took the longest to finish. Your phone has
Speaker 2:  to be charging and not in use because all the training happens on your device
Speaker 2:  and takes up a huge amount of energy. I love that it happens on device. That's
Speaker 2:  good for privacy reasons, it's good for lots of reasons, but it does take
Speaker 2:  a while. So it took a couple of days, but I eventually had my voice ready
Speaker 2:  to go. Hi, I am David Pierce's, ai iPhone voice. I'm kind
Speaker 2:  of like David, but kind of not. Are we? Our phones? Are our phones
Speaker 2:  us Ordinarily, I think I would've been impressed by that,
Speaker 2:  but after hearing that 11 labs, one, I'm kind of meh on this
Speaker 2:  one. Let's try the Dwight TR test. 30 years later, I get a
Speaker 2:  postcard. I have a son and he's the chief of police. This is where the
Speaker 2:  story gets interesting. I tell Tiffany to meet me in Paris by the TRO cero.
Speaker 2:  She's been waiting for me all these years. She's never taken another lover.
Speaker 2:  I don't care. I don't show up. I go to Berlin. That's where I
Speaker 2:  stashed the chandelier. Still pretty okay, right? It kind of works, but
Speaker 2:  nobody's gonna confuse this with human David and in general. I
Speaker 2:  actually think that might be okay.
Speaker 2:  AI voices are one of those things where the better they get the stranger
Speaker 2:  they get. Seriously, that feeling I got listening to the first time
Speaker 2:  11 labs spit out that thing saying I'm David Pierce was
Speaker 2:  genuinely kind of disconcerting. It raises all these big questions
Speaker 2:  that like with so many things about ai, we've really only begun
Speaker 2:  dealing with what does it mean that I can create a replica
Speaker 2:  this good and that they're only going to get better and easier over time?
Speaker 2:  What responsibilities do I have as the person who made it and is using it
Speaker 2:  even though it's my voice? What responsibilities do other people have?
Speaker 2:  What responsibilities do the services who make these voices for me have now
Speaker 2:  that they have this incredibly personal thing of mine on their
Speaker 2:  servers? We're having a lot of debates over AI music right now. Obviously
Speaker 2:  as artists', voices are being used to train models that can make pretty convincing
Speaker 2:  songs in just about anyone's voice. You go on YouTube and you can
Speaker 2:  hear AI Taylor Swift sing almost anything. You can hear ai Patrick from
Speaker 2:  SpongeBob sing almost anything. All of that is going to
Speaker 2:  spawn like a decade of interesting court cases and ethical debates.
Speaker 2:  But those same issues are coming just for you and me in our everyday lives.
Speaker 2:  How do we use these tools? How do we talk about the fact that they exist
Speaker 2:  and how we're using them? Is it even possible to get the good,
Speaker 2:  helpful, democratizing things from them without all the deep fakes
Speaker 2:  and downsides? I don't know, but I do know it's well past time
Speaker 2:  we started talking about it because the tech is really good right now and
Speaker 2:  it's getting better really fast.
Speaker 2:  Alright, that is enough AI talk for one day. We're gonna be back
Speaker 2:  next week to talk even more about AI music because I think that is one of
Speaker 2:  the most interesting things in this space right now. Not just because of
Speaker 2:  the big heady debates about it all, but because I think there are really
Speaker 2:  interesting ways that AI can both help people make music
Speaker 2:  and totally change all of our ideas about what music even
Speaker 2:  is. It's gonna be fascinating. We will also be back in
Speaker 2:  this feed on Wednesday too, with a big episode all about this week's Apple
Speaker 2:  event. But until then, ai David, you wanna do the credits.
Speaker 2:  This show is produced by Andrew Marino and Liam James. Brooke Miners
Speaker 2:  is our editorial director of Audio The Vergecast is a Verge production
Speaker 2:  and part of the Vox Media Podcast network. If you have thoughts, questions,
Speaker 2:  ideas or anything else, you can email Vergecast The Verge dot com or
Speaker 2:  call The Verge hotline at eight six six Verge 11.
Speaker 2:  We'll be back on Wednesday with a special show all about the Apple event
Speaker 2:  and with all the rest of this week's news on Friday, we'll see you then.
Speaker 2:  Rock and roll.
Speaker 2:  Okay, not bad, pretty good ai, David, for your first try, but
Speaker 2:  it's Vergecast at The Verge dot com for the emails, and we really gotta work
Speaker 2:  on the Signoffs. Say it with me. Rock, rock. Rock and roll.
Speaker 3:  Support for this show came from a W Ss machine
Speaker 3:  learning cloud computing, generative ai. Things
Speaker 3:  are changing and they're changing fast. It can be hard to keep up with
Speaker 3:  cutting edge technologies, let alone knowing how to use them effectively.
Speaker 3:  Amazon Web Surfaces may be able to help. They make it easy
Speaker 3:  for businesses of any size to identify opportunities that
Speaker 3:  generative AI and machine learning offer and provide a proven
Speaker 3:  framework for best practices, all with customer support. For any
Speaker 3:  technical and non-technical questions you might have. Just
Speaker 3:  imagine how a w s can transform your business.
Speaker 3:  learn more at AWS is how.