# Transcript
ID: 788862b7-255f-4127-93b4-499a663e5844
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Spotify and Disney have everything-app dreams
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/7469321725058638394/-6420724559694566182/s93290-US-4809s-1700046898.mp3
Description: Today on the flagship podcast of machine learning-based recommendation systems:
03:31 - The Verge’s David Pierce chats with Spotify’s co-president and chief product officer Gustav Söderström about recommendations, audiobooks, app design, what Spotify wants to be, and whether it’s possible to do it all well.
Spotify - The Verge
44:08 - Alex Cranz joins the show to discuss a bunch of recent streaming news, including the plan to combine Disney Plus and Hulu.
Streaming - The Verge
1:10:28 - Chris Welch joins the show to help answer this week’s Vergecast Hotline question about mp3 players.
The Mighty — an iPod shuffle for Spotify — finally arrives for $85
bemighty.com
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we love hearing from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (6 ads detected)
Speaker 2:  Welcome To The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of machine learning based
Speaker 2:  recommendation systems. I'm your friend David Pierce and I am on a
Speaker 2:  walk. So I've been trying this thing where instead of sitting in front of
Speaker 2:  screens all day, which I do, way too much of my back hurts, my eyes hurt.
Speaker 2:  It's just bad times. I try to get out in the world once a day
Speaker 2:  and just kind of wander around. A lot of smart people say that if you want
Speaker 2:  to think something through or be creative or process something, there's
Speaker 2:  really nothing better for you than to just go for a walk, leave all your
Speaker 2:  technology at home and just walk until you've figured it out. It's a
Speaker 2:  kind of romantic idea. I really love it. But so far in my experience,
Speaker 2:  I've found that I spend a lot of time just like walking, singing
Speaker 2:  1 21 Pilots song to myself over and over
Speaker 2:  again, and then I get home and I'm like, did I actually just accomplish
Speaker 2:  anything? I don't know. Maybe it's like meditation where you have to do it
Speaker 2:  a lot and you get better at it. But I feel like when I go on a walk and I'm
Speaker 2:  like, I'm gonna think deep thoughts, it's not going super great so far, but
Speaker 2:  at least the walking is nice and it's definitely good to not look at screens
Speaker 2:  for at least a little while every now and then. Anyway, we have an awesome
Speaker 2:  show coming up for you today. The first person I'm gonna talk to is Gustav
Speaker 2:  Soderstrom, who's the co-president of Spotify. He also ran product for
Speaker 2:  Spotify for a long time and he is the person I most wanted to talk
Speaker 2:  to about what Spotify is trying to be. It's trying to be
Speaker 2:  this incredible AI recommendation system that knows exactly
Speaker 2:  what you wanna listen to and exactly what you're doing at exactly the right
Speaker 2:  time. It's also kind of trying to be TikTok and it's doing audiobooks and
Speaker 2:  it's doing podcasts, and I'm trying to figure out how you do
Speaker 2:  all of that all in one place without making a total mess
Speaker 2:  out of Spotify. So that is what Gustave and I talked about. He's very open
Speaker 2:  and very smart about all of it, and it was a really fun conversation after
Speaker 2:  that. I'm gonna talk to Alex Cranz, who is my favorite person to talk to
Speaker 2:  about all things streaming. We're gonna talk about Disney and
Speaker 2:  Hulu And, what Verizon is doing with Netflix and Max and what's going on
Speaker 2:  with Marvel movies and just what to make of all of this
Speaker 2:  upheaval. We both have strong theories about ads and bundling and we had
Speaker 2:  a lot of fun hanging out. And of course we're gonna get to the virtual cast
Speaker 2:  Hotline, we have a really fun one this week. All that is coming up in just
Speaker 2:  a second, but first I have like three more blocks on this walk
Speaker 2:  and I'm gonna go try and think some deep thoughts on my way back. This is
Speaker 2:  The Vergecast. See you in a sec.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back, So, I. Didn't think any deep thoughts, but that
Speaker 2:  1 21 pilot song is now deeply lodged in my
Speaker 2:  head, probably forever. And also I'm cold All, right?
Speaker 2:  Let's get into it. I think Spotify is one of the most interesting companies
Speaker 2:  and apps on the planet right now. It's a huge winner as a music
Speaker 2:  streaming app, but it turns out there's really no money in being a
Speaker 2:  music streaming app. So it's trying to figure out podcasts and
Speaker 2:  audiobooks and in general being whatever the
Speaker 2:  TikTok for audio is. That's what CEO Daniel Eck has called it
Speaker 2:  before and it sort of makes sense. But then as a user of Spotify
Speaker 2:  mostly I worry that all of that stuff is just gonna clutter up
Speaker 2:  the app and confuse my playlists and make everything about it
Speaker 2:  worse. I think a lot that maybe Spotify should just be a really good
Speaker 2:  music app instead of trying to take over the world and shove
Speaker 2:  a lot of audio into one place. I don't know. Gustav Soderstrom,
Speaker 2:  Spotify's co-president and chief product Officer is the person
Speaker 2:  responsible for making all of this stuff make sense together. So I brought
Speaker 2:  him onto the show to talk about everything from recommendations to audiobooks,
Speaker 2:  to app design, all to try and figure out what Spotify wants to
Speaker 2:  be and whether it's possible to do it all really well. We
Speaker 2:  started by going back a few months to this spring when Spotify
Speaker 2:  announced a more visual, more TikTok style
Speaker 2:  redesign for the app. Here's Gusav at Spotify's Stream on event explaining
Speaker 2:  kind of the big idea behind it.
Speaker 5:  The Spotify we're revealing today is built to feel alive.
Speaker 5:  The interface is dynamic. It's easier than ever to
Speaker 5:  scroll and swipe and load it with all new ways for
Speaker 5:  listeners to enjoy your work. The Reimagine Home Feed will show better
Speaker 5:  recommendations from your favorites, the fresh content with
Speaker 5:  richly animated images and videos.
Speaker 2:  I asked Gustav to dig a little deeper on that and to explain what Spotify
Speaker 2:  was trying to do with this redesign because I think the
Speaker 2:  redesign actually says a lot about what that app wants to be.
Speaker 2:  So what was Spotify trying to do here?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, so if we go all the way back to to what we were trying to achieve
Speaker 6:  something like a year ago plus a bit more actually. So we kind
Speaker 6:  of pride ourselves on being good at discovery. Sometimes we say we think
Speaker 6:  that we're the best at discovery if we ask our users, but it's a certain
Speaker 6:  type of discovery. It's kind of the type of discovery we call background
Speaker 6:  discovery. When you're listening to a playlist, we're very good at
Speaker 6:  finding tracks that fit that playlist that you might like so forth. We also
Speaker 6:  have a lot of specific playlists for Discovery, You know, discover
Speaker 6:  Weekly and Daily Mix and so forth. But there's a different type of discovery
Speaker 6:  which we sort of called foreground Discovery. When you're finding, for example,
Speaker 6:  a new act and a genre that you didn't even know you liked,
Speaker 6:  it's not actually similar to anything you're listening to right now. And
Speaker 6:  the truth is that most of that type of discovery doesn't happen on Spotify.
Speaker 6:  We're really good at inserting more of what you're already listening to.
Speaker 6:  You know if you're, if you're into certain genre, we're really good at finding
Speaker 6:  other things that isn't that genre that we think you'll like. But if you
Speaker 6:  want to explore a completely new genre, those things actually often happen
Speaker 6:  off platform. They happen on YouTube, they happen on TikTok, they happen
Speaker 6:  in other places And and two things are important there. When you are
Speaker 6:  evaluating a lot of sort of new music that you don't even know if you like,
Speaker 6:  you usually don't listen to the full songs so you and spend
Speaker 6:  hours, you're kind of evaluating much more quickly.
Speaker 6:  And secondly, you're also quite interested when you discover band in, in
Speaker 6:  sort of seeing what they look like and so forth, right? And and that's mostly
Speaker 6:  the first time we're interested in that. Not the 10th time that you listen
Speaker 6:  to the song, but the first time it kinda matters, right? So we've been in
Speaker 6:  this symbiotic relationship with these other services where You know there's
Speaker 6:  a lot of foreground discovery that happens all over the place, but then you
Speaker 6:  usually save that track to Spotify and that's where you spend most of your
Speaker 6:  consumption. And that's, that's fine by us. It's worked for us really well.
Speaker 6:  It means that we could focus our investment on the sort of background moment,
Speaker 6:  background discovery being a really good background application. But we decided
Speaker 6:  about a year plus ago that we want to become a really good place for when
Speaker 6:  you wanna explore something completely new as well. And when you want to
Speaker 6:  break out of your show. That's, that's the feedback that we got like Spotify's
Speaker 6:  really good for already already like, but it's not that easy to break out
Speaker 6:  of your sort of taste bubble. And this is what brought brought about the
Speaker 6:  whole redesign and it, it was across music but also across
Speaker 6:  podcast and now recently across audiobooks as well. How do you
Speaker 6:  evaluate a lot of items in more of AGTD get things
Speaker 6:  done way where the hit ratio may be low, maybe
Speaker 6:  it's one great candidate in 10, well then you
Speaker 6:  better need to be able to quickly get through those 10 versus in the
Speaker 6:  background, if we had a one in 10 hit ratio, you would hate Spotify. It has
Speaker 6:  to be like nine in 10, right? So you have to be much more careful and so
Speaker 6:  forth. So we saw that's, that was the impetus like why we did it because
Speaker 6:  we also wanted to, in addition to staying very good at background discovery,
Speaker 6:  we wanted to bring foreground discovery or or being able giving you tools
Speaker 6:  to quickly break out your taste bubble and find something completely
Speaker 6:  new.
Speaker 2:  What's really interesting about that is that that strategy makes absolute
Speaker 2:  perfect sense. I think especially the idea of trying to make it easier for
Speaker 2:  people to find stuff they don't like. Which sounds weird. Like the the sort
Speaker 2:  of lowering the penalty of guessing wrong. Exactly. Makes total sense to
Speaker 2:  me. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  What is often called like fault tolerant in like product speak,
Speaker 2:  Right? And I think like if TikTok did one incredible thing for the world,
Speaker 2:  it was that like it it is the most fault tolerant app that has ever existed.
Speaker 2:  Exactly
Speaker 6:  What
Speaker 2:  I think is really interesting and and the way you describe that makes me
Speaker 2:  think that if Spotify had always done that
Speaker 2:  kind of thing, it would make perfect sense to everybody. But there's something
Speaker 2:  about coming back around to the foreground piece where it's like we
Speaker 2:  want you to be more in the app. We're gonna make the app more enticing and
Speaker 2:  more inviting. We want you to scroll more, we want you to do more stuff.
Speaker 2:  And I'm just like thinking about all of the like mad people on Reddit
Speaker 2:  when the redesign started coming out and that sort of instinctive reaction
Speaker 2:  some people had to seeing the way the new app looked and even as what you
Speaker 2:  described as very much sort of the other side of the coin of a thing that
Speaker 2:  already exists, it's just so different. Did you expect the kind of
Speaker 2:  visceral reaction of like we're doing a very different thing even in
Speaker 2:  service of the same activity.
Speaker 6:  So let's dig into it because it was a combination of a few things. I sort
Speaker 6:  of did expect it any like I've redesigned like the entire thing
Speaker 6:  a few times in my career and people are always very upset. Sure.
Speaker 6:  The problem with that is that they can be upset but it's
Speaker 6:  right. They just don't understand it yet. You know the Steve Jobs view.
Speaker 6:  Sure. Or they can be upset because it's actually bad and wrong. And the question
Speaker 6:  is how do you tell those two apart? And so it was a little bit of both in
Speaker 6:  this case. So this was impetus. It was to give users tools for much better
Speaker 6:  foreground discovery and be able to effectively try a completely new
Speaker 6:  genres and so forth. Now what happened when we launched this even before
Speaker 6:  people got to try it, to your point like even when we showed it, I think
Speaker 6:  the big challenge is that we were trying to do something very different with
Speaker 6:  these feeds. We were trying to get you to go through
Speaker 6:  as much music as possible in order to find stuff to save to your
Speaker 6:  library to listen to later. So it's actually discovery but not
Speaker 6:  consumption. Our point was to get you through this thing as fast as possible
Speaker 6:  and the thing we measure is sort of saves per minute. Whereas if you look
Speaker 6:  at TikTok or or YouTube shorts or reels, the feed is
Speaker 6:  the consumption. It's not discovery. The feed is consumption. The point is
Speaker 6:  to keep you there as long as possible. So I, think what happened when people
Speaker 6:  saw this. They were like, oh my god, I don't want another TikTok feed. Like
Speaker 6:  I have three now You know I have shorts and I have reels and I have TikTok
Speaker 6:  like why aren't they sticking to the music thing that I like them for? Why
Speaker 6:  they wanna become TikTok? Because that's honestly what it looks like when
Speaker 6:  you see a feed of moving images. And so there was that like
Speaker 6:  visceral reaction to it, which is just like a problem of communication. And
Speaker 6:  the idea is, well when you start using it you'll understand that that's we're
Speaker 6:  actually trying to get you out of the feed as pos as much as possible and
Speaker 6:  get you to save as much and actually listen to it later. 'cause that's when,
Speaker 6:  I mean we don't gain anything unless you listen to it later. This is a
Speaker 6:  tool for for creating more sessions down the line. But then we also made
Speaker 6:  a few mistakes in the first iteration of it, which was that we were
Speaker 6:  so keen on adding foreground discovery that when we redesigned
Speaker 6:  the experience, we changed the balance of what the homepage specifically
Speaker 6:  did quite drastically. If you think about it from like the product team's
Speaker 6:  point of view, you look around and you see like there is, there's YouTube
Speaker 6:  over there. It's kind of similar long form experience music. It's just a,
Speaker 6:  it's just a feed You know everything is just a feed as the as the start page.
Speaker 6:  So you could guess that that's what users want. They wanna feed us a start
Speaker 6:  pitch and So I think we got a little bit too jealous of the
Speaker 6:  competition. And so You know we had these shortcuts on top of our home, but
Speaker 6:  then pretty quickly we went into like fullscreen carbs 'cause that's kinda
Speaker 6:  what word looks like and people were quite upset. And so we looked at this
Speaker 6:  and we realized that to our benefit we were doing something quite well
Speaker 6:  that we didn't understand that we broke. So our homepage was
Speaker 6:  quite different from from these competitors, which was just like full card
Speaker 6:  feeds. We had these shortcuts and then we had these shelves. And, what they
Speaker 6:  did, which I think we saw much better than competition, is that they
Speaker 6:  managed to keep you in a lot of sessions at the same time. You might be
Speaker 6:  in the middle of two podcasts now, one audiobook and a playlist
Speaker 6:  and you might be into a set of playlists right now. And our homepage managed
Speaker 6:  to solve what we call recall really well. It made it really easy without
Speaker 6:  having to go into your library and search to get back to those sessions.
Speaker 6:  The one the store really relevant to you, we had this balance between
Speaker 6:  recall and discovery where when we looked at the metrics, You know how much
Speaker 6:  of the consumption from the homepage is sort of recall. You go back into
Speaker 6:  sessions that you had previously visited or were in the middle of versus
Speaker 6:  how much is you truly listen to new one. It was almost like 90% recall
Speaker 6:  and 10% discovery. And when we flipped it around, we sort of
Speaker 6:  turned it into 10% recall, like the top shortcuts and 90%
Speaker 6:  discovery. And you could see this in the metric and on Twitter. So on Twitter,
Speaker 6:  if you squinted through all the swearing and cursing and this guy should
Speaker 6:  get fired and I was be put in a lion cage and all these things, you could
Speaker 6:  see the actual feedback being like, where the hell am I playlist? Where am
Speaker 6:  my podcast? Right? And then you look at the consumption data and you see
Speaker 6:  the same thing. You see traffic going to search and to library people were
Speaker 6:  trying to find their playlist. So we realized the error that we have flipped
Speaker 6:  the ratio too much into almost like forced discovery.
Speaker 6:  And then we, we said, okay, let's look at this and let's embrace what people
Speaker 6:  loved. If we were really good at recall, instead of even just going back,
Speaker 6:  let's make sure that the redesign, we leverage that and we become even better
Speaker 6:  at recall. The weird thing for us then was we looked at competition and like
Speaker 6:  they're actually not doing this at all and people don't seem to complain
Speaker 6:  and be angry like what's the problem? And we realized that we're probably
Speaker 6:  very good at recall keeping in many sessions at the same time.
Speaker 6:  And our competition is probably not. But the, the thing is they were never,
Speaker 6:  if you only ever had like a single feed, you think about something like a
Speaker 6:  YouTube or something, it's very hard to actually get back into the session.
Speaker 6:  You have to click at the bottom right and scroll back in history. So maybe
Speaker 6:  it was just a case that they don't complain because it was never good there.
Speaker 6:  As we try to then reverse and lean into let's be really good at recall. So
Speaker 6:  we actually made it even better and we got the recall metrics measured as
Speaker 6:  like how many people find a relevant session on home without having to go
Speaker 6:  to search or library? Got that even better. And then the problem was obviously,
Speaker 6:  well we wanted to achieve foregone discovery, so how do we solve this? And
Speaker 6:  we switched our tactic to instead being voluntary entry
Speaker 6:  points into, instead of these cards that ought to play in a very high
Speaker 6:  up. We have two mechanisms now. One is we have these, what we call
Speaker 6:  watch feeds or discovery feeds, which are these small cards that you can
Speaker 6:  click and then you go into feed only optimize for this, but it's, it's voluntary.
Speaker 6:  Like you click through and it's just like, Hey, we found a bunch of new songs
Speaker 6:  for you. We have a bunch of podcasts for you. The idea now is as soon as
Speaker 6:  you feel a little bored and trapped in a taste bubble, it should be one click
Speaker 6:  away to just get into very effective discovery. And then when you scroll
Speaker 6:  down the homepage, you actually get to these cards and we, we, we think of
Speaker 6:  that as like, if you keep scrolling, well then you probably didn't find anything.
Speaker 6:  So now you are interested in discovery. And to cut a long story slightly
Speaker 6:  shorter, where we are now finally is now the new homepage is,
Speaker 6:  is out to a hundred percent of existing users. So we're back to like one
Speaker 6:  homepage, which You know being on two stacks, it's very, very expensive
Speaker 6:  and very frustrating. And we see what we wanna see. So in this watch feed
Speaker 6:  for example, we actually see 50 times the saves per minute
Speaker 6:  versus any other session. Wow. Versus like You know a Discover Weekly or
Speaker 6:  something. Not, they're not saving 50 tracks per minute, but 50 times
Speaker 6:  more saves per minute. So we're seeing what we want to see finally and
Speaker 6:  and users now seem happy. So that's a long version of what actually
Speaker 6:  happened.
Speaker 2:  No, it's super interesting and you, you actually brought up kind of the the
Speaker 2:  like two central questions of what Spotify is that have
Speaker 2:  always fascinated me. I think part of the reason people flipped
Speaker 2:  out at having all of this discovery added was that Spotify is the app that
Speaker 2:  you use all the time, but hardly ever touch. Yeah. Right. And that's, that's
Speaker 2:  a really valuable thing and it's, it's a thing that I know Spotify in the
Speaker 2:  past has been very proud of, right? You can use Spotify for hours and hours
Speaker 2:  and hours without ever looking at it. And in a time when every app is
Speaker 2:  demanding my full face attention at all times,
Speaker 2:  that's good thing. Very true. But then how to marry that with this
Speaker 2:  idea of obviously You know you, you we, we wanna build a video ads business
Speaker 2:  and we also want to en engender this foreground discovery and like I can
Speaker 2:  see why there are lots of perfectly valid polls back into the app, but
Speaker 2:  it just breaks that sort of core behavior that is so good
Speaker 2:  about Spotify. Like I don't go to TikTok to listen to songs because it's
Speaker 2:  a pain in the ass to find songs on TikTok, right? I go to Spotify because,
Speaker 2:  and that's like the purpose it has served. And I feel like trying to pull
Speaker 2:  that thing back into it, even if it's the right call, is just a challenge
Speaker 2:  to do. Right? But then the other flip side of that is, and this is I feel
Speaker 2:  like the, the sort of great product journey of Spotify is how to do
Speaker 2:  a lot of things in one app in a way that makes sense, right? And and this
Speaker 2:  is like, this goes back to the question you and I have talked about before
Speaker 2:  about like how do you do podcasts and audiobooks and
Speaker 2:  music in a single interface in a way that makes sense? And
Speaker 2:  I'm still not convinced you're all the way there. I I, I'd be curious to
Speaker 2:  hear how you think you're doing. I got chapter three of an audiobook in my
Speaker 2:  release radar, which like you just cannot convince me is a good user experience.
Speaker 2:  But that's
Speaker 6:  A great chapter, I promise you.
Speaker 2:  I'm sure it was. But I think that question continues
Speaker 2:  to be kind of the big one, right? Like if you want to be the TikTok for audio
Speaker 2:  that Daniel has talked about in the past, like you have to figure out how
Speaker 2:  to put all these things in one place, but doing it in a way that feels like
Speaker 2:  it doesn't compromise each one of them along the way just gets harder every
Speaker 2:  new thing you add.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. So you're, you're completely right that, that there are two dimensions
Speaker 6:  here. One is the who we have to call foreground versus background. So we're
Speaker 6:  still a vast majority background service. Sure. Meaning what percentage of
Speaker 6:  the time is the phone in your pocket? Most of the services, to your point,
Speaker 6:  they're like You know 90% in the foreground and we're sort of the opposite,
Speaker 6:  right? So that's one dimension and that's what we try to find is
Speaker 6:  so when the, that phone is in the foreground and you're bored, that's when
Speaker 6:  we have to have these tools for you to find a lot of music for that sort
Speaker 6:  of 80, 90% background listening. And that's a, that's a tricky balance and
Speaker 6:  we, and we rebalance the homepage to reflect too much of the,
Speaker 6:  the time that you're in the foreground, which is the minority. Sure. And
Speaker 6:  sort of focusing on, it still needs to be insanely simple to get to your
Speaker 6:  favorite sessions. But
Speaker 2:  That thing, and by the way, that user flow you've landed on in which you
Speaker 2:  say basically like I'm in discovery mode, you just like bang bang, bang through
Speaker 2:  a bunch of stuff, pick a bunch of stuff you wanna listen to click play and
Speaker 2:  put your phone away. Like that's a very Spotify version of the thing you
Speaker 2:  described, right? Like that's much closer to the way that the app has always
Speaker 2:  been. Exactly.
Speaker 6:  That's that's a plan. And that's where I feel we've landed now. But there
Speaker 6:  was a bit of wilderness wandering to get there.
Speaker 2:  There always is. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And then the other thing you mentioned is, well a cross content right now
Speaker 6:  there certainly shouldn't be audiobooks chapters in your daily mix or something
Speaker 6:  that, that that's just a bug that we need to fix. But there is
Speaker 6:  that question of how is You know? Is that the best product
Speaker 6:  experience? How much is that a strategy that we need to adopt because it's
Speaker 6:  a distribution strategy versus what is best for the, for the consumer. I
Speaker 6:  choose to see it as a very interesting challenge and it puts a lot
Speaker 6:  of requirements on our experience team, right? Because the challenge
Speaker 6:  is in order to keep sort of the complexity as we call it internally to
Speaker 6:  keep the entropy down, you need to make things look as similar as
Speaker 6:  possible so that it doesn't get very confusing. Right. And and the notion
Speaker 6:  is that well it's all audio, right? Music is audio, podcast is audio, audiobooks
Speaker 6:  is audio, but then it's also very different. Music is like three minutes,
Speaker 6:  audiobooks, maybe podcast, maybe an hour an audiobook, 20 hours or something,
Speaker 6:  right? Yeah. So it's also very different. So the the real big challenge
Speaker 6:  that we just have chosen to accept given our strategy is to make it sort
Speaker 6:  of to consciously misquote Einstein as similar as possible,
Speaker 6:  but not more similar than possible. Right. Okay. And so
Speaker 6:  what what's an example of that? You know, you can say that it's all cards.
Speaker 6:  Like there's an, there's a track card and there's a playlist card and there's
Speaker 6:  a, an episode card and an audio book card, which is kind of true. But
Speaker 6:  on the other hand we also have to realize where they're different. So, so
Speaker 6:  for an example, one thing that we're working with right now is the feedback
Speaker 6:  to the algorithm. We, we actually, we've been playing around with giving
Speaker 6:  people tools of feedback on the algorithm and it turns out people love that
Speaker 6:  even when we had like on the three dots a hidden option, I was amazed at
Speaker 6:  how many people found that and said like, I didn't want this recommendation,
Speaker 6:  I wanted this. So we're making that easier. But you run into these problems
Speaker 6:  where, where it's different. So for example, we're experimenting with these
Speaker 6:  things where you can say like, this is a bad recommendation or, or more like
Speaker 6:  I don't want this recommendation You know, which gives the user a way to
Speaker 6:  back the fault tolerance to solve when we were wrong quickly. But it also
Speaker 6:  gives us a lot of super valuable signal to improve for the user. But then
Speaker 6:  for a podcast episode, it's pretty straightforward. You just say like, this
Speaker 6:  was bad recommendation, don't show it again. And we can interpret it as like
Speaker 6:  bad recommendation for a playlist. It's tricky because if you say that maybe
Speaker 6:  it was that you didn't like the song, but did you not really like the playlist?
Speaker 6:  Should we actually show the playlist again, but not with the same songs.
Speaker 6:  And then for audiobook, you have a different problem which we realized, which
Speaker 6:  is when you say like, sort of thumbs down, it could be
Speaker 6:  because you hated this recommendation or it could be because you love this
Speaker 6:  recommendation, but you already listened to the book or read the book years
Speaker 6:  ago. Oh, interesting. So we are trying to find the exact balance. We will
Speaker 6:  have different controls on all the books and on episodes and on tracks, but
Speaker 6:  we also need, need to still make the system similar enough that it makes
Speaker 6:  sense as as one app. So this is where we're putting most of our effort and
Speaker 6:  and we think we're, we think we're doing a good job if you just look at the
Speaker 6:  metrics and and user engagement. But it is kind of the, the strategy
Speaker 6:  and path we have now. I always tell the team that the challenge
Speaker 6:  is like how do you choose between these things? You know, should we show
Speaker 6:  a podcast or an audiobook or music? I choose to say that we're just
Speaker 6:  being more honest with ourselves than other companies. So if you think about
Speaker 6:  something like Apple, they also have a music app, podcast app, an audiobooks
Speaker 6:  app. It is the same user in front of the iPhone. Sure. The three
Speaker 6:  teams treat it as different users, right? And they all try to compete for
Speaker 6:  the user, right? But it is the same user, the same 24 hours.
Speaker 6:  They're just fooling themselves. There's three different users. We're just
Speaker 6:  being honest to ourselves. No, it's the same user. Yeah. So it's, it's it's
Speaker 6:  in a way a harder challenge but it's in a way true for everyone. It's just
Speaker 6:  one user and we just have to be more explicit about how
Speaker 6:  we solve that problem. But the user can't listen to all three at the same
Speaker 6:  time anyway. Right. And and I think when people say like if you just had
Speaker 6:  three apps, you don't have to worry about it. I'd say like no, it's the same
Speaker 6:  David, it's still gonna have to choose between the three apps. So why not
Speaker 6:  solve it in one app if we can. It's just less clicks. That's kind of how
Speaker 6:  I think about it.
Speaker 2:  I agree. I think this has become a somewhat controversial stance over time,
Speaker 2:  but I actually think doing all of these things in one app is the right path.
Speaker 2:  I think these sort of wilderness stuff for Spotify so to
Speaker 2:  speak, would be the thing where it's like, okay, what what we actually need.
Speaker 2:  And I think people accuse Spotify of this more than at least I've actually
Speaker 2:  seen it in the wild. But it does seem like one possible endpoint of this
Speaker 2:  is like, how do we mix your favorite songs with
Speaker 2:  a bunch of podcasts you might wanna listen to and then we'll throw an audio
Speaker 2:  book in there. And to me that's just not even remotely what I want.
Speaker 2:  Like sometimes I wanna listen to a book and sometimes I wanna listen to a
Speaker 2:  podcast and sometimes I wanna listen to music. I always know
Speaker 2:  which one I want. And for Spotify to guess or try to
Speaker 2:  intermingle them all that strikes me as like borderline impossible to
Speaker 2:  do. Well
Speaker 6:  So when, when you do that on, if we had three different apps, you would just
Speaker 6:  go into three different apps. Right? Exactly. Because you would know, right?
Speaker 6:  So the way we solve this is we land you own a homepage where
Speaker 6:  we have a pretty good guest, we're trying to, we have these shortcuts, but
Speaker 6:  you are in multiple sessions at the same time. So you can actually continue
Speaker 6:  in that playlist, you can continue in that audiobook and there's like in
Speaker 6:  the middle of that episode or those two episodes you were in. So hopefully
Speaker 6:  it's like super easy to, to solve it. But then back to fault tolerant UIs.
Speaker 6:  This is also why you see these tabs where you can say like, you click the
Speaker 6:  music tab totally. And then it's music only or the podcast tab or the order
Speaker 6:  books tab. So which which is almost the same as opening the separate
Speaker 6:  app. So this is how we're trying to solve it with trying to program for
Speaker 6:  you and then have a fault tolerance solution if we're wrong or if your
Speaker 6:  intent was super high. But we do statistically see that It
Speaker 6:  works that we actually managed to get people to listen to podcasts
Speaker 6:  who didn't. And and hopefully the same for audiobooks. So, so it seems to
Speaker 6:  work, but I think you, I think it's a statistical question. I think you're,
Speaker 6:  you're, you're right, but my h is, it's like 80% of the time or 90 people
Speaker 6:  know what they want, but the other, the other 10% of the time are incredibly
Speaker 6:  valuable. 'cause that's when you find this new podcast or book and it's back
Speaker 6:  to this like why we need to be 90% recall and 10% discovery and we went wrong
Speaker 6:  with 90% discovery.
Speaker 2:  The upside of doing all those things together is you, you can do a
Speaker 2:  sort of one-on-one makes three thing where it's like the podcast I listen
Speaker 2:  to probably do inform the kinds of books I might like and the kinds
Speaker 2:  of music that I listen to probably informs the kind of podcast I like. So
Speaker 2:  if you can actually having all of those things together in one place lets
Speaker 2:  you do stuff. But that stuff is not
Speaker 2:  shove stuff in front of me that I don't wanna listen to, I think. But I,
Speaker 2:  I think you're, you're increasingly getting away from that, which I think
Speaker 2:  is very good.
Speaker 6:  I'm glad to hear that we're trying hard,
Speaker 2:  But that also brings me to ai, which I think you're using kind
Speaker 2:  of in, in both directions of that, right? Like it seems like the
Speaker 2:  AI stuff I'm seeing floating around both what's been released And, what
Speaker 2:  random people are finding in code on Spotify is that both,
Speaker 2:  you want to use AI to be smarter and more proactive about what people
Speaker 2:  might want. Like the day list thing I think is really fascinating and the
Speaker 2:  names are all deeply weird, put in really interesting ways. Yeah. And then
Speaker 2:  on the other side there's this idea of like, what if you could just make
Speaker 2:  a playlist with a prompt? What if you could just sort of declare to Spotify
Speaker 2:  what you wanna listen to and it can do that. And that's the kind of thing
Speaker 2:  that as far as I can tell, these large language models are relatively capable
Speaker 2:  of. That's data that you have. Like that becomes a
Speaker 2:  whole new sort of tool for finding stuff to listen to. Again, if,
Speaker 2:  if your idea is like get back into the pocket as quickly as you can, that's
Speaker 2:  a pretty powerful one.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, for sure. I I think you're completely right. I'm, I'm very fascinated
Speaker 6:  about both of those directions. So, so one way to sort of retell what you
Speaker 6:  said is you could think one way is to You know everyone tries to reduce friction
Speaker 6:  and get even better at predicting what you wanted to do. And, and certainly
Speaker 6:  these LMSs help with that in many ways you get larger
Speaker 6:  embeddings that makes the content understanding better. So just the recommendations
Speaker 6:  of songs get better. In podcast you obviously have the whole
Speaker 6:  safety thing. You can now have machines pre-list to the podcast,
Speaker 6:  make sure that we can do safe fix or exploit, which can surface podcast
Speaker 6:  to you that we couldn't have done before because we didn't feel
Speaker 6:  literally safe e exploring content that we didn't understand
Speaker 6:  ourselves. So, so there's just making the recommendations better and hopefully
Speaker 6:  even better at this homepage predicting the right thing, the thing that you
Speaker 6:  had in your head. So we reduce friction and we're doing that and we're seeing
Speaker 6:  benefits of that. But to your point, I think the other direction is really
Speaker 6:  interesting as well. Sometimes you want more control, like you don't want
Speaker 6:  to be sold to everything and so can we build even more powerful tools for
Speaker 6:  you where you can have a lot of fun with the podcast catalog and the music
Speaker 6:  catalog. That is something I'm very fascinated about.
Speaker 6:  Can't comment too much about things that aren't live, but you're certainly
Speaker 6:  right. That's an area that I think is super interesting and having,
Speaker 6:  having a conversation around music with an entity that is
Speaker 6:  very knowledgeable about the global music culture. Everything has been written
Speaker 6:  on Wikipedia, every concert ever happened, but that also super knowledgeable
Speaker 6:  about you because it has your music taste, I think can be a really cool experience.
Speaker 2:  That is cool. And how has that changed the way that
Speaker 2:  you think about the kind of human machine interaction that
Speaker 2:  you've always talked about at Spotify, right? I think like the, the sort
Speaker 2:  of human curated playlists with machine help is like a core tenet
Speaker 2:  of what Spotify has always been. But if we're headed into this place of sort
Speaker 2:  of mass personalization, both that you're bringing to me and that I
Speaker 2:  can ask for myself, does that change that dynamic?
Speaker 6:  I think over time it probably will if you think
Speaker 6:  that the the, the systems are getting more and more
Speaker 6:  intelligent, they can do more and more of that. But what we are
Speaker 6:  right now, I think it's still the same world where
Speaker 6:  you, you look at Twitter and you see these 100% automatic things. There
Speaker 6:  are very cool demos. You don't see a lot of applications of them. And then
Speaker 6:  when you do some, when you apply something, it's actually almost
Speaker 6:  always including humans in the loop. It's just that they're m they get
Speaker 6:  much more leverage. That's fair. Yeah. So, so for example, if we look at
Speaker 6:  something we did recently with the dubbing for example, it's
Speaker 6:  quite straightforward. I wouldn't say straightforward, but it's getting quite
Speaker 6:  easy to, to use a service to get like a, a pretty good
Speaker 6:  translation and a generation of a voice in another
Speaker 6:  language. But if you put that to a native speaker, that language, they're
Speaker 6:  gonna drop off because the translation is not gonna sound like a podcast
Speaker 6:  or it's gonna be like correct grammatically, but very formal. The intonations
Speaker 6:  are off. And so what we find is that
Speaker 6:  you need to use these technologies and they're amazing, but you still need
Speaker 6:  people in the loop to make it truly great. So we keep
Speaker 6:  applying that recipe and we think of it more as getting more
Speaker 6:  and more leverage of those people on those people rather than
Speaker 6:  replacing more and more of those people, if that makes sense. You know the
Speaker 6:  same amount of people, but they can do more and more and more. If you think
Speaker 6:  about Steve Jobs old notion of You know the computer is a bicycle for the
Speaker 6:  mine. I think the LLM is like, it's like, I don't know, like a
Speaker 6:  motorcycle for the mine or a mountain bike or something. It's just that on
Speaker 6:  steroids. Yeah. So that's how I, I tend to think about it like that for any
Speaker 6:  type of creation. If you're an artist, if You know, I think the big
Speaker 6:  benefit of this will be it's an incredibly powerful bicycle for
Speaker 6:  the mine. And, and sure you can automate some things, you can
Speaker 6:  do elevator music and so forth. And that's not the interesting part. I think
Speaker 6:  the inter, inter interesting part is as augmentation to people.
Speaker 2:  No, I I think that's right. And actually the, I'm glad you brought up the,
Speaker 2:  the dubbing because that, and kind of on the flip side, the automated transcription
Speaker 2:  stuff I think is really interesting because like you said, it, it opens up
Speaker 2:  sort of new avenues both for people to reach people and for like
Speaker 2:  new ways of consuming this kind of stuff. To me, like automated
Speaker 2:  transcription and making podcasts searchable is like incredible. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  And we're finally getting to the point where the LLMs are good enough at
Speaker 2:  speech to text that it's actually pretty plausible, which I think is very
Speaker 2:  exciting. But I am curious from a, from a creator standpoint, like I, I make
Speaker 2:  a podcast and I've been trying to figure out how I feel at
Speaker 2:  just like a very personal level about the idea of my
Speaker 2:  voice being translated into tons of different languages all over the
Speaker 2:  world. And most of me thinks it's very cool. Part of me is sort of horrified
Speaker 2:  by it in a way. I can't even totally describe, it just feels odd. It's like
Speaker 2:  it's me but it's not me in some way that I can't
Speaker 2:  totally wrap my head around. And it feels like in so many ways with ai we're
Speaker 2:  headed down that road of, of feelings in a lot of ways.
Speaker 2:  But what are you hearing from creators and people who are, are
Speaker 2:  using this tech already? Like what do they make of all this new leverage
Speaker 2:  you're giving them?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. So as you say, our focus is really on, on helping
Speaker 6:  creators, giving them tools rather than trying to replace them. Other people
Speaker 6:  may have that as a strategy, but our, our, our tool is really to try to empower
Speaker 6:  creators, giving them more and more tools and, and dubbing is one of those
Speaker 6:  and, and we're working on other tools as well that we think are very interesting
Speaker 6:  for creators. But if, if we look at dubbing your notion like it's
Speaker 6:  weird in a way, there's a lot of these things I think we're gonna get into
Speaker 6:  that feels weird the next few years. Sure. But from another point of
Speaker 6:  view, if you look at non podcasters, You know book authors and
Speaker 6:  TV movies, they've been dubbed for tens of years. That's true. And with
Speaker 6:  completely different voices and, and sometimes You know in certain markets
Speaker 6:  with just ducking the original audio, it's like really crappy in a sense.
Speaker 6:  So, so from that point of view, this is just the same but's much more authentic.
Speaker 6:  It's really you instead of someone else trying to pretend to be you. So I,
Speaker 6:  I, my hunch is podcasters are gonna, are sort of gonna get over
Speaker 6:  that feeling, certainly will be heard from the podcasters we worked
Speaker 6:  with is that their fear was the opposite. That
Speaker 6:  when we contacted them, they're like, I don't think it's gonna really sound
Speaker 6:  like me. Will I have like a, an accent where I sound like a, instead
Speaker 6:  of a good Spanish speaker, I sound like a slow American You know
Speaker 6:  heavy American accent, right? I just sound dumb. Somehow they're really very
Speaker 6:  predictably very concerned about what they appear like in that language.
Speaker 6:  So that's what we put a ton of effort on details. Like it's a
Speaker 6:  translation not just grammatically correct, but is this what a, this person
Speaker 6:  would sound like? What a, is this a relaxed podcast conversation or a formal
Speaker 6:  lecture in that other language? Does You know Lex Friedman or Steven Bartlett?
Speaker 6:  Do they sound like they should probably sound in Spanish or do
Speaker 6:  they sound like someone who doesn't speak Spanish that well? But if it's
Speaker 6:  to Spanish it doesn't sound like them anymore. That's the balance we spent
Speaker 6:  a lot of time on and I think we found a good balance, at least they are very
Speaker 6:  happy. And and maybe even more importantly, when you look at the Twitter
Speaker 6:  feeds, what I take a lot of joy from is almost without a
Speaker 6:  fault. The feedback are like, I'm a native speaker and this
Speaker 6:  is amazing, which you don't see that much. I see people saying this is
Speaker 6:  amazing. And then you see native speaker saying, actually it's not that good
Speaker 6:  as a native speaker because it's wrong. And, and we really try to put effort
Speaker 6:  in was like sort of just quality of production and So I look
Speaker 6:  a lot at it's a creator happy, do they feel like what they should sound like.
Speaker 6:  But then I also look at the feedback from the native speakers and then obviously
Speaker 6:  I look at the episode and when do people drop off if it's not good enough,
Speaker 6:  if it's cool but not interesting, people are gonna drop off after to five
Speaker 6:  minutes. So that's kind of how we evaluate quality and so far we're
Speaker 6:  very encouraged by by what we're seeing. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  What are you telling the, the creators who are trying to figure out how to
Speaker 2:  navigate this stuff? I mean I just think about, we, we've talked a ton about
Speaker 2:  like the writer's strike on the Hollywood side and one of the things they're
Speaker 2:  worried about is like if you're an actor they can just take your voice
Speaker 2:  and never need you anymore. And then I, I listened to like, I was listening
Speaker 2:  to Bill Simmons and he's like, oh great, my voice can read our ads and I
Speaker 2:  don't ever have to. And so I'm like, well there's the two sides of the coin
Speaker 2:  right there. What are you telling folks who are, are trying to figure out
Speaker 2:  kind of how to navigate that? Like what, what does it mean that my voice
Speaker 2:  is now part of kind of an AI machine?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I I think it's very much about creator control. I think what you hear
Speaker 6:  Bill Simmons say this is because he feels like he's in control. Sure.
Speaker 6:  That's obviously when we do these dubbing things, we
Speaker 6:  we get no rights to that creator's voice for any other purpose. Right.
Speaker 6:  It's only for that purpose. Exactly. For that translation. So it's their
Speaker 6:  voice. I think that's the key. I think people will be fair, would feel very
Speaker 6:  uncomfortable, but giving away rights to their
Speaker 6:  likeness for like unknown purposes. So for, for us
Speaker 6:  back to like You know, we, we try to structure it as narrowly as possible
Speaker 6:  around like your voice for exactly this purpose and, and
Speaker 6:  You know it's your episode. So that's how we've solved it and I think
Speaker 6:  that's the, that's the fear that creates, I I would feel equally
Speaker 6:  concerned if, if someone had the rights to say whatever they wanted with
Speaker 6:  my voice.
Speaker 2:  Sure. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And that's also why we've been quite careful. I think that's why OpenAI who
Speaker 6:  we, we have worked with has been quite careful 'cause there is that
Speaker 6:  potential for abuse and I think that's why this was a good use case to start
Speaker 6:  with, where it's very clear that this is something those creators want and
Speaker 6:  it's voluntary and it's, it's, I think un unambiguously
Speaker 6:  good.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, no, I I that's, that's fair. And I think I, I definitely agree that
Speaker 2:  the right way to think about it is like these are, these are tools you can
Speaker 2:  give people to use. Not sort of things you're foisting on top of what
Speaker 2:  they're already doing. I think that that feels right to me. Yeah. So come
Speaker 2:  back to the ai AI playlist thing for a second because I, I've been thinking
Speaker 2:  a lot about DJ and I've been thinking a lot about day lists recently and
Speaker 2:  I think dj, which is seems to have done really well. Everybody I talked to
Speaker 2:  about DJ thinks it's the coolest thing ever, but it's this very
Speaker 2:  human thing, right? Like it's an AI generated thing that is
Speaker 2:  still meant to be sort of a character in my life. Yeah. But then
Speaker 2:  on the flip side, day list is just like a super curated list of
Speaker 2:  songs, right? Yeah. There are two sort of very different ways of thinking
Speaker 2:  about it should both be in there. Do you have a thesis about one or the other
Speaker 2:  that we land on over time? What do you think?
Speaker 6:  It's a great question and the truth is we, we don't know yet. Okay. Which
Speaker 6:  going to be the future play mode and I think people have different listening
Speaker 6:  modes. I still think there's always gonna be a mode where you want exactly
Speaker 6:  your playlist that you are you curated You know without our recommendations
Speaker 6:  in it or anyone commenting or anything like that. And then I think you're
Speaker 6:  gonna want these music sessions sort of like a daily mix or something where
Speaker 6:  you're asking for like a specific genre. You kind of know exactly what you're
Speaker 6:  gonna get on the genre and style, but not exactly which track.
Speaker 6:  But you don't want anyone talking in between the songs, the whole thing.
Speaker 6:  It's like a lean back session where it's what we call it like mind busy versus
Speaker 6:  mind free. Mm. I like that. And You know when when the mind is busy, music
Speaker 6:  fits mind busy 'cause you can think about something else, but then when someone
Speaker 6:  starts talking you have to stop thinking about someone else and pay attention
Speaker 6:  something else. Pay attention again. And, and this was one of the tricky
Speaker 6:  things with the dj. We, we've done some other experiments where we've had
Speaker 6:  like these sessions we can talk for a while and then play some music and
Speaker 6:  in theory people love it. In practice the problem is like
Speaker 6:  it's partially a podcast and you have to pay attention. Then the music comes
Speaker 6:  in you so not start thinking about something else and then it's like, oh
Speaker 6:  back now I have to pay attention again. You're switching between like mind
Speaker 6:  free and mind busy. And so what we saw in that data was people kind of
Speaker 6:  chose, either they listened to the podcast and skipped past the music or
Speaker 6:  they kind of did the opposite. So I definitely think we're gonna have these
Speaker 6:  music only sessions. And the notion for the DJ was actually taking that
Speaker 6:  learning and saying like that this is a music session first
Speaker 6:  and foremost the DJ needs to be quick, brief and get out of
Speaker 6:  the way. So it's not a podcast about music, it's a playlist
Speaker 6:  with some introduction to it. We may at some point do the opposite and have
Speaker 6:  a generated podcast about a track where it's like 90% talk and
Speaker 6:  10% music. But then it's a different hypothesis, right? But this
Speaker 6:  is the the dj, what's the point of this dj? Like why does it even
Speaker 6:  need to to talk? Well what we found was that even for the exact
Speaker 6:  same playlist, if you say like, Hey David, here's a playlist, these
Speaker 6:  five tracks are gonna come up. And when you look at that playlist, you're
Speaker 6:  sitting there thinking like, maybe I do, maybe I don't like that. Maybe it's
Speaker 6:  gonna feel like this and so forth. And there was a lot of like choice paralysis
Speaker 6:  and the, the kinda weird thing is when when we had the DJ say like, Hey David,
Speaker 6:  I'm gonna take you back to when you were like teenager, I'm gonna play this
Speaker 6:  track. And it's the exact same track that you would've seen in the playlist.
Speaker 6:  You stick around and listen. So there's something about, there's something
Speaker 6:  about removing choice and paralysis saying like, okay, just
Speaker 6:  take me somewhere where you seem to get inspired and enjoy it.
Speaker 6:  Sort of the exact same tracks you might have skipped if we showed you a list
Speaker 6:  or what's gonna happen in the future. And we're still not exactly
Speaker 6:  sure what that is, but it's very clear it's happening.
Speaker 6:  So, I think of this now as the, we have lots of choices. If You
Speaker 6:  know what you want or you sort of know what you want, we have genres and
Speaker 6:  hundreds of playlist for every type of genre and you have your own playlist.
Speaker 6:  We didn't have a good solution for like, hey Spotify, I have no
Speaker 6:  idea. So this is the solution for like, I know idea, but I want
Speaker 6:  music and then this is a, this is a really good tool and So I don't think
Speaker 6:  it's gonna switch to a hundred percent. I have no idea. I think you're gonna
Speaker 6:  have different moments.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, no, that makes sense. And that actually brings me to, I'm gonna just,
Speaker 2:  I'm gonna throw thesis at you and I want you to, to agree or disagree and,
Speaker 2:  and tell me why I'm right or wrong, go for it. It seems to me that we've
Speaker 2:  gone through this phase in this space where there were a lot of
Speaker 2:  betts in a lot of different directions, right? Everybody, everybody went
Speaker 2:  towards trying to figure out how to do exclusive content in
Speaker 2:  really cool ways. Everybody tried to build radically different
Speaker 2:  kinds of listening experiences. People tried to do live audio
Speaker 2:  and it, it seems like we're coming back to the idea that
Speaker 2:  actually there is this incredibly cool, interesting
Speaker 2:  library of content out there and the job of an app
Speaker 2:  like Spotify or any of your competitors is to find
Speaker 2:  ways for me to find that content and that content to find me just sort
Speaker 2:  of watching Spotify over the last, I don't know, 24 months. It feels like
Speaker 2:  to some extent you, you've kind of wound all the way back to like the core
Speaker 2:  competency, which is like, we're very good at telling you what to listen
Speaker 2:  to and it just feels like you, you've pushed back into
Speaker 2:  that in new ways over the last year or so. Is that fair?
Speaker 2:  Am I totally wrong? What do you think?
Speaker 6:  I think it is fair. I would say that we, we try to get more distinct about
Speaker 6:  separating the modes. So the DJ is still in this class. So like it's mostly
Speaker 6:  going to play things that we are quite certain
Speaker 6:  that you like back to like it's probably gonna be right nine out of 10
Speaker 6:  things. And then we need a different solution for when you wanna be exploratory
Speaker 6:  when we're only right one out of 10 instead of nine out 10, which is the
Speaker 6:  feeds, right? So we try to separate the two instead of having a bad average
Speaker 6:  of both. If the DJ was right one out of 10,
Speaker 6:  you would churn out, right?
Speaker 2:  Or if they're both five outta 10, I'm gonna churn out.
Speaker 6:  Exactly. That's a better point. If they're both five outta 10, both are bad,
Speaker 6:  right? So that is true. I think we got more confident that like let's build
Speaker 6:  this product for this purpose and this other product for that other purpose.
Speaker 6:  I also do think that, back to your questions on ai, in generative
Speaker 6:  ai, I have this obsession with as artificial
Speaker 6:  intelligence or machine intelligence or whatever you call it is getting more
Speaker 6:  and more capable. I've always had this obsession about everyone should be
Speaker 6:  able to really have a dj that sounds very natural, but that gets
Speaker 6:  more and more intelligent over time so it understands. So the DJ we have
Speaker 6:  now, it understands quite a lot about your music taste, but with a lamps
Speaker 6:  it will also start to understand a lot about music culture and the world
Speaker 6:  And, what happens. It can get more skilled at things like
Speaker 6:  mixing and like, I, I really want to build this perfect session
Speaker 6:  where you feel like a, a larger percentage of the
Speaker 6:  time you feel like Spotify is almost like a,
Speaker 6:  a friend, a person, a, a dj. I'm just gonna trust them. Then maybe
Speaker 6:  instead of 80% of the time you go and choose your playlist, maybe we get
Speaker 6:  down to like 2010, 20% of the time you're gonna have your playlist because
Speaker 6:  it's party or something. But most of the time you're gonna say like, Hey
Speaker 6:  Spotify my friend, just play something and I'll
Speaker 6:  feedback. I think that is entirely possible given
Speaker 6:  the insane development of, of intelligence. So
Speaker 6:  that's something I'm very passionate about. So I think we're gonna keep investing
Speaker 6:  in that. So in that sense, I think your thesis is right. We're getting
Speaker 6:  more confident in the ability to recommend and try to program to
Speaker 6:  you, but we still need to find this balance of being fault tolerant and
Speaker 6:  give you super easy ways to like say, now you're wrong. Gimme
Speaker 6:  control back.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, that's, that's totally fair. What playlist do you listen to
Speaker 2:  most?
Speaker 6:  I actually listen to with you statistically it's, it's the DJ by far that
Speaker 6:  I listen to the most and then I have a set of my, my own
Speaker 6:  curated holders and goalies. I
Speaker 4:  Like it.
Speaker 2:  I really appreciate you doing this. It's really fun to do this. I ho I I
Speaker 2:  I'm glad we got to make it happen even though we couldn't do it in person.
Speaker 6:  Likewise, always fun, happy to do
Speaker 6:  again.
Speaker 2:  Alright, we gotta take a break and then we're gonna talk about Streaming
Speaker 2:  because there is always something happening in Streaming. We'll be right
Speaker 2:  back.
Speaker 2:  All right We're back. We have kind of a grab bag of streaming news this
Speaker 2:  week from Disney to Verizon to Max to Marvel to Netflix. It's a
Speaker 2:  lot and it feels like there's a bigger story tying all of
Speaker 2:  it together. Or maybe a couple of them. So I grabbed Alex Cranz to talk
Speaker 2:  it through. Hi Alex. Hello. Whenever we have
Speaker 2:  streaming things to yell about, it feels important that you and I do it on
Speaker 2:  The Vergecast together. So I'm very happy to do this. The first thing we
Speaker 2:  need to do is we need to, we need to explain the truth to some people about
Speaker 2:  what is going on with Disney. The shortest bit of the history that I need
Speaker 2:  to give in order to get into this is what, a week ago now, two weeks ago
Speaker 2:  now, Disney and Comcast enacted their agreement
Speaker 2:  for Disney to buy the rest of Hulu from Comcast, which we've kind of always
Speaker 2:  known is gonna happen. That's the history. Explain to me these weird
Speaker 2:  things that have been happening around the Disney internet in the last few
Speaker 2:  days.
Speaker 7:  So Disney was doing its earnings call the other day and Bob
Speaker 7:  Iger said that they're gonna experiment with a beta
Speaker 7:  in December combining the content of Hulu and Disney
Speaker 7:  Plus. And that's, I think something we've talked about on The.
Speaker 7:  Vergecast was probably gonna be the outcome of all of this. So that was not
Speaker 7:  a surprise to us.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Disney has not hid that fact that ultimately what it was going to do
Speaker 2:  was probably combine them all into one streaming service.
Speaker 7:  He's been talking about this I think since May very openly that that was
Speaker 7:  his plan. But a lot of outlets, a lot of people have
Speaker 7:  gotten confused by that and assume that one or both of those
Speaker 7:  streaming services is gonna go away. And I think like a, A name is probably
Speaker 7:  gonna go away. I think Hulu or Disney Plus is probably gonna get retired,
Speaker 7:  but all the content is still gonna be there. It's just gonna be one app,
Speaker 7:  which in the United States is kind of tricky because the Disney
Speaker 7:  Plus app in the United States is for babies and the Hulu app is for
Speaker 7:  adults. I say that subscribing to both. Yeah, I am baby
Speaker 7:  here. But You know that that one is very much for kids. Your kids
Speaker 7:  are less likely to go find two people going at it
Speaker 7:  on Disney Plus
Speaker 2:  Hulu the one for sex. Like that's the The one
Speaker 7:  For sex. Yeah, that's the, I mean honestly in the United States, that's the
Speaker 7:  big differentiation. Sure. One is Bone Town, the other population,
Speaker 7:  none. It, one of the things that Bob Iger said was he was like, we're gonna
Speaker 7:  wait and take a minute because people are gonna need to like prepare and
Speaker 7:  think about child protection and stuff so their kids don't go to Bone Town.
Speaker 7:  He didn't say Bone Town, but
Speaker 2:  That's essentially what it means. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  And I think that got people kind of scared thinking that Disney Plus is going
Speaker 7:  away and it's like, no, it's, it's gonna be there so much.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. You're just gonna have to think a little harder about the accounts
Speaker 7:  you set up and make sure that one of 'em, if you don't want your kids
Speaker 7:  seeing Handmaid's Tale, that you block that
Speaker 2:  Everything you just said is true and correct. Except, except for one thing.
Speaker 2:  Okay. There is no question about which brand is going to go
Speaker 2:  away. It's going to be Hulu. Like I, I don't know how to be
Speaker 2:  clearer about this. Like Disney Plus is going to be the name of the
Speaker 2:  service. Hulu is going to be a section of the service that has some
Speaker 2:  of that more adult stuff. Maybe it'll be everything on Hulu. Maybe it'll
Speaker 2:  just be that more like adult subset of it. Right now there's like FX on Hulu
Speaker 2:  which is like yeah, kind of the way that that works. This is going to be
Speaker 2:  FX on Hulu, on Disney Plus. Like it's gonna be insane. But that's what it's
Speaker 2:  gonna be like. Let's not pretend that there is a possibility that Hulu is
Speaker 2:  like the main Disney brand forever. That's ridiculous.
Speaker 7:  I've got a cling to it.
Speaker 2:  Not only is this just like an objectively moral truth of the
Speaker 2:  universe, I just wanna read you the thing that Bob Iger said,
Speaker 2:  okay, from the earnings call, we expect that Hulu on Disney Plus
Speaker 2:  will result in increasing engagement, greater advertising opportunities,
Speaker 2:  lower return and reduce customer acquisition costs, thereby increasing our
Speaker 2:  overall margins. The beginning of that sentence is we expect that Hulu
Speaker 2:  on Disney Plus, I don't know how to be clear. Like he said it,
Speaker 2:  it's right there. Alex. It's right there. I know. I'm so tired of all of
Speaker 2:  these people being like, what if the Disney Plus brand dies? It's not gonna
Speaker 2:  die.
Speaker 7:  It's not gonna die. It's fun to think it will.
Speaker 2:  The way I see it and I, I went through, I wound up reading and listening
Speaker 2:  to this entire earnings call, which I like super don't recommend as a
Speaker 2:  lifestyle choice. Don't do
Speaker 7:  That folks.
Speaker 2:  But what's super interesting to me is Bob Iger at least feels very strongly
Speaker 2:  that Disney has two really good brands and it's Disney and it's
Speaker 2:  ESPN. Those are the flagships, those are the monoliths. Those are like the
Speaker 2:  things he believes in as brands. Everything else is like
Speaker 2:  subservient to those two things. And in an interesting way, he even kind
Speaker 2:  of intimated that ESPN might roll into Disney Plus, like Disney Plus
Speaker 2:  is the thing. It just is good idea, bad idea. It is the answer,
Speaker 2:  which
Speaker 7:  Is a better name. Disney Plus or Max for your
Speaker 7:  Giant, your Giant Everything App You
Speaker 2:  Know what Sucks is, I think Hulu is a better name
Speaker 7:  There. We gonna see Hulu Hulu
Speaker 7:  more captures the what the hell of all of it all. And I
Speaker 7:  like, I think that's one of the things that I'm a little questioning
Speaker 7:  myself is Disney Plus has a very firm brand in the United States of
Speaker 7:  population zero for Bone Down and, and that's not the case in
Speaker 7:  the rest of the world, but it is very much the case in the United States.
Speaker 7:  And I think like that's gonna be a real challenge for them branding wise.
Speaker 7:  But they probably will call it all Disney Plus and be like, now you can get
Speaker 7:  ESPN and Hulu there and then in a year everybody's gonna be like, why
Speaker 7:  Hulu?
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Hulu for me has like Google Energy in that.
Speaker 2:  It's like, not a word, but it's kind of a word and it's like fun to say and
Speaker 2:  it's a very good brand. I've always just really liked it as a, as a word.
Speaker 2:  Like even it's not knowing what it means. It's just a good word. It's
Speaker 7:  A good word. You're like hula, hooping, hula. What? You just dunno.
Speaker 7:  But You know that's where you could get your TV legally for a long
Speaker 7:  time.
Speaker 2:  I, I've come to think this strategy sort of makes sense for Disney because
Speaker 2:  like e even if what you're talking about like Hulu equals Bone Town, right?
Speaker 2:  It's gonna be like a checkbox in the Disney app that it's like
Speaker 2:  when you set it up for your family, you're like, my app has Bone
Speaker 2:  Town, the kids' apps No Bone Town. Yeah. And it, it's gonna be a pretty
Speaker 2:  easy toggle. Like I think where content goes
Speaker 2:  over time is gonna be kind of tricky and we've already seen some kind of
Speaker 2:  bleeding between the two over time, right? Where like some things are on
Speaker 2:  both services, sometimes they move between like it's already kind of complicated,
Speaker 2:  right? There's
Speaker 7:  Like a whole bunch of Fox films that really shouldn't be on
Speaker 7:  Disney Plus as we think of it today that are currently on Disney Plus and
Speaker 7:  you're like, oh no. Like kids are gonna see something. They might see like
Speaker 7:  the top of a boob. Oh no. And like this travesty
Speaker 7:  travesty for the children. So yeah. Yeah. They've already been
Speaker 7:  dealing with this problem and that was why he wanted to Burge the two,
Speaker 7:  right? Like he, he doesn't wanna have to think about that and I suspect it's
Speaker 7:  gonna be less Bone Town versus No Bone Town and more do you
Speaker 7:  want your kids to be able to watch mature rating stuff, right? And do you
Speaker 7:  want your kids to be able to watch like TV 14 and So I think they're gonna
Speaker 7:  really clinging to those TV ratings that they've kind of informally adopted
Speaker 7:  that they don't actually have to have at this point. Like
Speaker 7:  nobody's telling them these aren't broadcast on television. That's true.
Speaker 7:  They can do whatever ratings they want and they're still out there being
Speaker 7:  like, we thought of a good rating for this one at Disney. Which is
Speaker 7:  hysterical.
Speaker 2:  But I do think like even in that case having Hulu as the kind of shorthand
Speaker 2:  for like here's all of our sort of adult originals is probably pretty useful.
Speaker 2:  It's like I know what Disney gets me and I know what Hulu gets me and even
Speaker 2:  though they're in the same app, being able to kind of split them as I want
Speaker 2:  to makes some sense. I think
Speaker 7:  What we're really gonna start seeing as we get these more super apps, right,
Speaker 7:  which is Max Disney plus whatever Paramount and
Speaker 7:  Peacock end up joining together to make in order to
Speaker 7:  compete a, as we start to get these super apps, I think we're gonna start
Speaker 7:  seeing kind of the replica of TV that we had before where like
Speaker 7:  you knew you had your different channels and stuff. That's something ZZ love's
Speaker 7:  talked about. That's something that like Iger kind of hints at. I think that
Speaker 7:  that that idea, that concept of channels is gonna come
Speaker 7:  roaring back and some brand execs
Speaker 7:  somewhere are gonna be working their butt off, coming up with a whole bunch
Speaker 7:  of new channels or trying to resurrect old ones. Oh
Speaker 2:  That's interesting. So in the like Disney cable bundle universe,
Speaker 2:  Hulu becomes like the HBO right? Prestige adult
Speaker 2:  television channel, right?
Speaker 7:  You've got FX over still hanging out over there or
Speaker 7:  whatever and then like Disney XD for the kids. I think that's what
Speaker 7:  it was called. Oh that's interesting. I'm an old So I think it's Disney XD
Speaker 7:  and and So I think we're gonna see that sort of thing. You know freeform.
Speaker 7:  Well Freeform's Toast Freeform is not gonna survive the next couple
Speaker 7:  of years. Correct. But they might still keep that for like that
Speaker 7:  ya audience keep that young adult audience there with
Speaker 7:  Freeform.
Speaker 2:  You're making me realize now that if you, if you take what Disney is already
Speaker 2:  planning on doing like the way you describe and then you add ESPN's on demand
Speaker 2:  stuff and even the linear channel which Disney has talked about adding to
Speaker 2:  streaming and then you do the same with ABC news, you've just basically recreated
Speaker 2:  60% of the cable bundle. Yes. Like you're one Yes. NBC and
Speaker 2:  CBS broadcast channel away from just the full cable bundle, which
Speaker 7:  Is really, really compelling. Wait
Speaker 2:  And Hulu has Hulu with live tv. Yeah, we're just back, this is just, I'm
Speaker 2:  just paying Disney for my cable bundle now instead of Comcast. Oh I guess
Speaker 2:  this is where we should disclose Comcast is a
Speaker 2:  investor in Vox Media through its subsidiary NBC Universal.
Speaker 2:  Eli's not here. So I don't have to tell you about the Netflix show that he
Speaker 2:  humble brags about all the time. Alex has Paramount Plus, I don't know
Speaker 2:  like this is we, we have a bunch of complicated disclosures to do here
Speaker 2:  but that's, that about covers it. We both
Speaker 7:  Spend a lot of money on Streaming already. We do. We watch a
Speaker 7:  lot of streaming.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Which actually is a good segue to the next thing, which is the other
Speaker 2:  thing that Bob Iger talked about in the earnings call a bunch
Speaker 2:  that also there was some Verizon Netflix Max news on
Speaker 2:  this is that the advertising tier of
Speaker 2:  streaming continues to boom. Yes. In a way
Speaker 2:  that like kind of surprises me. Like I think Bob Iger said over
Speaker 2:  half of new Disney plus subscribers in this last quarter
Speaker 2:  were ad supported, which is huge.
Speaker 7:  I don't think that's like, that's not surprising to, to me at all.
Speaker 7:  People want things and they want things cheap
Speaker 7:  and TikTok and YouTube and everything else has totally prepared people to
Speaker 7:  be able to sit through it and broadcast TV has prepared people to sit through
Speaker 7:  an ad in order to get the content they want. So that's not
Speaker 7:  surprising to me. And I think the most surprising part of it is that advertisers
Speaker 7:  are so eager for it when they do have the ability to micro target on platforms
Speaker 7:  like TikTok and stuff. So that's the part that's
Speaker 7:  surprising. But I guess it's easy, you've got good partners with
Speaker 7:  Disney You know there's gonna be brand safety. You're not gonna have to worry
Speaker 7:  about some weird thing
Speaker 2:  Unlike TikTok and some of the other platforms you're talking about. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  You have
Speaker 7:  A lot more safety on something like Disney or Netflix or
Speaker 7:  Max than than you do on social media platforms. So,
Speaker 7:  I get it. Makes sense.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. It's also very funny. Like part of me wonders if part of the appeal
Speaker 2:  of that is just all of these ad agencies have been
Speaker 2:  making one specific kind of ad to go next to one specific kind of thing
Speaker 2:  for decades. And for a long time it was like, well where do we put that
Speaker 2:  thing now? Yeah. And now Netflix is just like, well instead of putting it
Speaker 2:  next to I, I don't know, like Chicago Fire
Speaker 2:  on television, put it next to Chicago fire on streaming and the
Speaker 2:  ad agencies are like, oh I know how to do that. That works for me.
Speaker 7:  I, I think that's a big part of it. I think it's just like this is a thing
Speaker 7:  they already, all the advertisers already know how to do. They know how to
Speaker 7:  sell it Disney, all of these companies know how to how to buy this
Speaker 7:  stuff and and and how to sell it. So everybody's just like, okay, we figured
Speaker 7:  it out. And now also instead of broadcast and and
Speaker 7:  cable and dealing with that, we can have it all internal. We can control
Speaker 7:  everything and that makes everything a lot easier and
Speaker 7:  cheaper. But also now Disney is gonna
Speaker 7:  own all the entertainment you wanna watch.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Like in a really real way.
Speaker 7:  Like Bob Iger is gonna be deciding what scripted TV you watch and that's
Speaker 7:  a little Ooh that has me a little concerned. I'm not crazy
Speaker 7:  about one company having that much power over what I watch. But
Speaker 7:  yeah, I do like how convenient it'll be.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Well one of the things I was reading was basically theorizing
Speaker 2:  that Disney is going to win because it did all of
Speaker 2:  its acquisitions before it became hard to do acquisitions. Both I guess for
Speaker 2:  like interest rate reasons, just the way the economy has gone and also
Speaker 2:  like there's more scrutiny over these mergers and acquisitions than there
Speaker 2:  used to be. If
Speaker 7:  You think about it, the, the fact that they were able to acquire Marvel,
Speaker 7:  they were able to acquire E-S-P-N-E-S-P-N led to the
Speaker 7:  acquisition of Marvel, right?
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And then Lucasfilm and Pixar, like the list is crazy.
Speaker 7:  It's insane and it really shouldn't have happened. But it was also, it is
Speaker 7:  Bob ER's legacy. It was the thing. Yeah. He did really, really well. He's
Speaker 7:  very proud of, I think every, when he was retired for that year and a
Speaker 7:  half or whatever, he spent all of his time going around being like, I did
Speaker 7:  this, I built this, this whole stable of, of assets for
Speaker 7:  us and now we can just go mint money and Disney
Speaker 7:  has,
Speaker 2:  Yeah, it was, it worked out super well for a minute. He saw
Speaker 7:  The writing on the wall and was really, really smart about it. Whether or
Speaker 7:  not he should be able to do that, the whole copyright situation, the fact
Speaker 7:  that he's gonna own all of these copyrights and, and
Speaker 7:  aggressively goes and has laws to stop this stuff from
Speaker 7:  like entering the public domain, that's less cool. But, but
Speaker 2:  The thing about that that's weird then is the flip side of that is like Disney
Speaker 2:  has lost just an essentially infinite amount of money on
Speaker 2:  streaming now it's betting on this future of like all of this is gonna come
Speaker 2:  together. And like I think with the Hulu thing, I see it more than ever
Speaker 2:  like the bundle, the way you describe it is like, oh, that that might work
Speaker 2:  and it might make Disney an awful lot of money pretty quickly.
Speaker 2:  But also it makes me wonder, can anyone come after Disney?
Speaker 2:  Like one of the things in the news this week was that Verizon is going to
Speaker 2:  start selling a combination of Netflix
Speaker 2:  and Max both ad supported for $10 instead of I think what would
Speaker 2:  be $17. And one of the, the theories I saw about that is basically like
Speaker 2:  ordinarily what would happen is these
Speaker 2:  two companies would merge, or two companies like them would merge
Speaker 2:  or they'd find some way to kind of be one and compete in a
Speaker 2:  real way head on. But they can't because
Speaker 2:  You know gestures broadly the world is what it is. And so they're having
Speaker 2:  to find all these ways to kind of put their pieces together in order to be
Speaker 2:  harder to turn away from. Do you buy that logic? Like is everybody else gonna
Speaker 2:  sort of sneaky bundle because they can't do what Disney is doing? Yeah, I
Speaker 7:  Think they have to. Right. Peacock and Paramount have to bundle
Speaker 7:  or they're gonna be toast. 'cause you've got the three or four big players.
Speaker 7:  There's Disney Plus with now 168, 200
Speaker 7:  million subscribers at this point. Just astronomical number. Amazon
Speaker 7:  with a similarly astronomical number. But that one's gonna be really curious
Speaker 7:  'cause how much of that is just people who bought Amazon Prime and how much
Speaker 7:  of it's actually users,
Speaker 2:  Which Amazon has never really talked about.
Speaker 7:  They've never disclosed. So there's always like a little asterisk when you
Speaker 7:  see them at the top of the list. Then you've got Max and you've got Netflix.
Speaker 7:  So there's those, those are the big four. Those are effectively your A,
Speaker 7:  B-C-C-B-S-N-B-C and Fox of 2023.
Speaker 7:  And I think everybody's gonna probably need to subscribe to most of those
Speaker 7:  if they wanna be able to have like intelligent conversations with their friends
Speaker 7:  about cultural moments. Yeah. And then there's everybody else
Speaker 7:  Paramount and, and Peacock and, and all these other ones are all
Speaker 7:  sitting at the bottom underneath them. They're the the WB and the
Speaker 7:  UPN of of this analogy.
Speaker 2:  I mean you're not wrong but brutal.
Speaker 7:  What a move for these guys. And I think the only way they're gonna be able
Speaker 7:  to compete is, is to start bundling and start offering that. Because right
Speaker 7:  now they're, they're really hedging their betts on being like better at programming.
Speaker 7:  And to their credit, they are much better at programming than
Speaker 7:  Netflix. Much, much better at it. But I don't
Speaker 7:  think just being really talented at one thing is going to pull
Speaker 7:  their butts outta the fire on
Speaker 2:  This. Yeah. And also the thing we seem to have learned over the last year
Speaker 2:  or so is that Netflix can just spend its way out of any problem that
Speaker 2:  it has. It just has so much more money that it's like, oh we can't make a
Speaker 2:  good original. We'll go get suits and make it a gigantic hit. Like it
Speaker 2:  just works.
Speaker 7:  Peacock's out there furious. I think Peacock was the owner of that. Well
Speaker 7:  that's the other thing we're seeing is we're seeing a lot of these companies,
Speaker 7:  You know, AVV said this last year, he said, we're open for business, we're
Speaker 7:  gonna start selling a lot of our properties. Yeah. We don't wanna hold everything.
Speaker 7:  It's not just for us. Like Disney is very much in the business of this is
Speaker 7:  our ip, this is our brand and you come to us for this IP and this
Speaker 7:  brand Max and Net and, and Peacock and Paramount, not
Speaker 7:  Netflix, but Max and Peacock and Paramount and those kind of competitors
Speaker 7:  are like, no, we want our brand to go everywhere. And the hopes that eventually
Speaker 7:  you say, I like this brand enough, I'm gonna come back and pay you. Right.
Speaker 7:  And we'll see how that works. I don't know if it's gonna work,
Speaker 7:  but it definitely means there's more stuff being purchased and moved around,
Speaker 7:  which is really, really, which is actually crucial to like a
Speaker 7:  good interesting set slate of content coming out. Because if all the
Speaker 7:  content is being made by four companies who are run by four white
Speaker 7:  guys who all have very similar tastes and stuff, you're not
Speaker 7:  gonna get a lot of diversity of content. You're not gonna get a lot of different
Speaker 7:  fun and exciting things happening. And so needing to sell to these smaller
Speaker 7:  ones, needing to keep their breast of that industry moving is gonna be important
Speaker 7:  for that diversity. 'cause otherwise it's just gonna be suits. Grey's
Speaker 7:  Anatomy, Riverdale, I don't know what are the like the most
Speaker 7:  Bo like
Speaker 2:  Fast talking dramatic white people is like essentially what I would call
Speaker 2:  all of their shit was just
Speaker 7:  A little Huh. Moments in there. Just a few huh?
Speaker 7:  Moments.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Swelling violins at the end of every episode. That's the, that's how
Speaker 2:  You know or
Speaker 7:  Chasing cars.
Speaker 2:  That's actually a, a good segue to the last thing we should talk about, which
Speaker 2:  is two things happen sort of simultaneously. One was Bob Iger
Speaker 2:  also said on the Disney earnings call that one of his big focuses
Speaker 2:  is to go back to the film studio. Like the core Disney thing
Speaker 2:  has always been, they develop, like you were saying, characters and movies
Speaker 2:  that people love. Right? And that that feeds movies, that feeds the theme
Speaker 2:  parks, it feeds the merchandising stuff they do, it feeds everything. And
Speaker 2:  that in recent years, especially with Pixar and especially with
Speaker 2:  Marvel, has started to wane. And so what he said
Speaker 2:  is, I'm gonna go back and really dig into that
Speaker 2:  space. And on the one hand it's like, okay, you're like an old rich white
Speaker 2:  guy. Like we've, we kind of know how that goes. But on the other hand, the
Speaker 2:  Marvels opened this past weekend horrible opening
Speaker 7:  To
Speaker 2:  The lowest in Marvel history. Right? It was the worst performing box
Speaker 2:  office for a Marvel movie ever.
Speaker 7:  Ton of asterisks next to it by the way. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  List them for me. Tell me the asterisks.
Speaker 7:  There was the sag strike. So they couldn't, they couldn't have Oscar winning
Speaker 7:  Brie Larsson out there having fun with Samuel Jackson getting
Speaker 7:  you excited for it, which they totally were gonna do. Yep. And so you had
Speaker 7:  the SAG strike. There was a, there's a, a large group of, of people in the,
Speaker 7:  that are fans of the MCU that are very upset with the direction of like the
Speaker 7:  more diverse direction that the, the franchise has taken over over the last
Speaker 7:  few years. And so they're all upset that this is starring ladies and
Speaker 7:  not, not dudes. There are some dudes in it, they're great. And
Speaker 7:  then you have, you have the real challenge of just Marvel fatigue.
Speaker 7:  There are so many Marvel movies that came out before and Man in Quantum Mania
Speaker 7:  is another one that got short shrifted because it came out four,
Speaker 7:  they had four months to like finish a whole bunch of
Speaker 7:  effects that they were supposed to have like a year to finish. So they had
Speaker 7:  to like rush their finish and that's why it looks like hot
Speaker 7:  garbage and you're like, oh this is an ugly movie. 'cause nobody has spent
Speaker 7:  the time so they, they've poisoned their brand. Which is a shame because
Speaker 7:  I think everybody who's going to see it really likes it. I wouldn't be surprised
Speaker 7:  if the, the scores coming outta the film are pretty high for it.
Speaker 7:  Like not astronomically high, but Disney historically has been really
Speaker 7:  good at making a movie that even if critics don't like
Speaker 7:  it, audiences really like it. And the last few, they really didn't
Speaker 7:  have that success. Particularly with Antman and Dr. Strange, they really,
Speaker 7:  really struggled with those cinema scores and So I think Marvel's probably
Speaker 7:  got much better cinema scores, but it's gotta carry so
Speaker 7:  much water that I think it's, it's gonna have that horrible
Speaker 7:  asterisk next to it forever.
Speaker 2:  Do you think it has a chance, like is the, it feels increasingly with every
Speaker 2:  one of these, like the Marvel fatigue is just irreversible. Even
Speaker 2:  the stuff that people mostly seem to agree is good, like low key season two
Speaker 2:  people seem to mostly like doesn't have that like cultural
Speaker 2:  force that it once did. Do you think we're just done with that phase and
Speaker 2:  it's time to figure out what's next for Disney and everybody? I
Speaker 7:  Don't think so. 'cause I think what people would need to remember is that
Speaker 7:  the original MCU with the exception of maybe the first Ironman movie was
Speaker 7:  just as calculated, was just as well planned out.
Speaker 7:  Like the reason Captain Marvel as a character exists today was
Speaker 7:  because they rewrote her in back in like 2011
Speaker 7:  to make her a better character to spit make it produce in
Speaker 7:  movies Miss Marvel herself. That was one of the reasons Miss Marvel that
Speaker 7:  character was created was for that same reason, like these characters were,
Speaker 7:  have always been manufactured to sell tickets. Guardians of the Galaxy was
Speaker 7:  their big, was that first big surprise where they made that film and it did
Speaker 7:  really, really well. And they're like, oh shit, we could make people care
Speaker 7:  about a sentient raccoon. We can do anything. And that's
Speaker 7:  still true. But, but if you don't have the marketing behind it and if you're
Speaker 7:  not making films that are entertaining, 'cause there was a lot of struggles,
Speaker 7:  like early on Marvel struggled with incredible Hulk and the first Thor movie
Speaker 7:  did not have the strongest cinema scores. And even at the time it was like,
Speaker 7:  oh, are we gonna get it? And then like they, they knocked it outta the park
Speaker 7:  with the Avengers and everybody's like, okay, nevermind. And so they were
Speaker 7:  able to kinda weather those bad times before, but they've just had a string
Speaker 7:  of horrible films that nobody cares about and they're so
Speaker 7:  focused on that crossover concept and that who are you gonna see
Speaker 7:  next that it's, it's just exhausting when it's like, no, just do what you
Speaker 7:  did at the beginning, tell really goods stories and then it's have Samuel
Speaker 7:  L. Jackson show up in the last five minutes to be like also
Speaker 7:  this guy showing up next week. Well
Speaker 2:  And that's one of the, that's one of the things that I, I haven't seen the
Speaker 2:  Marvels yet, but Byla Hunt did very well is like it's just a good
Speaker 2:  movie. But also if you're a super fan who has seen everything, it has
Speaker 2:  extra rewards for you. And that was the thing for me that like the
Speaker 2:  original movies did so well was like
Speaker 2:  I, I've probably seen 60% of the Marvel movies and it felt like the
Speaker 2:  longer I went, the more I was being penalized for not having seen them.
Speaker 2:  Whereas at the beginning it was like, if I had seen them, I got 10 more references
Speaker 2:  that I didn't get before, but it wasn't a huge problem
Speaker 2:  that I missed a bunch of them. Now it's like if I start watching
Speaker 2:  one of these movies and I haven't seen 65 other things, none of it is gonna
Speaker 2:  make any sense to me. And that is, that's too much. We've like, we've lost
Speaker 2:  the plot when we've gotten to there. Like literally lost the plot.
Speaker 7:  I think Ant-Man and the wasp in Qua into Quantum Mania or whatever the hell
Speaker 7:  it's called is probably like, that's the turning point because the
Speaker 7:  original Ant-Man franchise exemplified this better than anything. It was
Speaker 7:  just like, Hey look, we're doing a really cool thing. And oh, also like it's
Speaker 2:  Paul Rudd, he's so small.
Speaker 7:  Yeah and it's, it's loosely attached to this larger franchise, but you didn't
Speaker 7:  have to care about it. And then this third one, they were like, you must
Speaker 7:  care about this entire franchise and also this little man
Speaker 7:  named King. And you're like, what? I don't why stop
Speaker 7:  it and it looks like shit. So,
Speaker 2:  But you think we're forever like one or two good Marvel movies from it
Speaker 2:  being back on top of the world?
Speaker 7:  I, I think so. Disney is very good at making hits. Disney is better than
Speaker 7:  just about anybody on the planet at making you care about something and selling
Speaker 7:  it. So as long as Marvel's invested it's they're gonna, they're gonna do
Speaker 7:  well. I think what's gonna be curious to see is what lessons they take from
Speaker 7:  their recent failures. It's, it's not lost on me that the last
Speaker 7:  two re like the two biggest recent failures were also led by women
Speaker 7:  that big primary parts of the cast and I I live in ta, constant
Speaker 7:  terror that they're gonna do what they were always doing in like the, the
Speaker 7:  two thousands of being like, ugh, the woman led show bombed. So we gotta
Speaker 7:  kill all things where women lead that kind of group think is really popular
Speaker 7:  in, in Hollywood and I'm terrified of that happening again.
Speaker 7:  But Disney knows how to make hits. Marvel is not going away
Speaker 7:  until Bob Iger who or whoever decides it needs
Speaker 7:  to.
Speaker 2:  Fair enough. Thank you. All. right, we gotta take a break. Go see the Marvels.
Speaker 2:  Apparently it's great. Charles really liked it. Everybody who sees it seems
Speaker 2:  really like it. We gotta take a break. We'll kind of come back and do The
Speaker 2:  Hotline
Speaker 2:  All right Welcome back. Let's get to The. Vergecast Hotline. We take questions
Speaker 2:  every week and we try to answer them as sometimes helpfully as we
Speaker 2:  can. This week Chris Welch is here to help me. Hi Chris. Hello.
Speaker 9:  Good to be back.
Speaker 2:  We got a question about something that I honestly thought we would never
Speaker 2:  ever in our lives get a question about again on The Vergecast Hotline,
Speaker 2:  which is MP three players. But first let me just play the question. It
Speaker 2:  comes from Patrick.
Speaker 10:  Hi Verge team. This is Patrick from Tucson, Arizona. I'm trying to reduce
Speaker 10:  my reliance on my phone so that when I go to replace it I can get a dump
Speaker 10:  phone and replace all of its functions with standalone dumb or
Speaker 10:  semis smartt products. The one feature that's giving me the most
Speaker 10:  difficulty replacing is the ability to listen to my music from
Speaker 10:  Spotify, my podcasts and my audiobooks in my car in an
Speaker 10:  easy and automatically updating fashion. It seems that all of
Speaker 10:  the MP three players that remain on the market are either over
Speaker 10:  $600, at least like the Sony Walkman or under a hundred dollars and
Speaker 10:  limited to playing manually populated offline files. Is it true
Speaker 10:  that there's just no more mid-market for MP three players?
Speaker 10:  Thanks. I look forward to your insight as always.
Speaker 2:  Okay. Hmm. I have like an immediate visceral reaction to this
Speaker 2:  question but I'm curious what your instant thoughts are.
Speaker 9:  I think the main hangup and problem challenge here is that
Speaker 9:  podcasts part, like finding an MP three player that'll like automatically
Speaker 9:  update podcasts is not really what the ones that are out there these
Speaker 9:  days are for. Like he mentioned you can buy like a Sony Walkman for
Speaker 9:  300 $400 but that's like all Hi-Fi listening gear. It's not
Speaker 9:  really intended for like casual podcast listening. I don't know. What are
Speaker 9:  your vibes on the question? What are your feels?
Speaker 2:  I kind of have come to the point where I think the only reason to buy a
Speaker 2:  dedicated MP three player is if you really care about
Speaker 2:  Hi-Fi lossless and I think that's a perfectly valid thing
Speaker 2:  and reason to buy an MP three player if you're worrying about Spotify
Speaker 2:  and podcasts that is not you and So I kind of think
Speaker 2:  the market for those people for an MP three player is dead
Speaker 2:  To me the answer here is buy a cheap second
Speaker 2:  phone only download the two apps that you need.
Speaker 2:  Like I don't know, have somebody change your Google Play password so you
Speaker 2:  can't do anything else or whatever. And then just treat that like your device
Speaker 2:  basically try to like iPod touch if I a phone that you have. That's the only
Speaker 2:  answer I can think of that makes sense to me.
Speaker 9:  Steve, you still can buy like a used iPod touch. That's an option but it's
Speaker 9:  stuck on iOS 15 I think. So there will come a day where like Spotify no longer
Speaker 9:  supports iOS 15 and like same for Apple Music, which is very strange to
Speaker 9:  think about. So at some point the iPod touch will be be left behind. I've
Speaker 9:  got one, it feels so small these days that it like no longer feels like a
Speaker 9:  phone. I know
Speaker 2:  It's
Speaker 9:  Really true. It's like so tiny so You know it's got some charm
Speaker 9:  but yeah, software days are probably numbered. There's also, I don't know
Speaker 9:  if you remember The Mighty player, it's like that iPod shuffle device. Oh
Speaker 9:  yeah that can sink. That can sink Spotify and like Traps and
Speaker 9:  podcasts. So that's an option. But you would need a smartphone to sync it
Speaker 9:  to, so if you want a dumb phone therein lies the problem. But yeah, that's
Speaker 9:  still out there. I think they cost like 130 bucks so nowhere near the cost
Speaker 9:  of like a Sony Wman which right again is silly And for nerds like me who
Speaker 9:  like have like lossless audio libraries of fully
Speaker 9:  legally You know downloaded music. No question about that. That
Speaker 2:  Don't worry about it. Yeah.
Speaker 9:  But yeah for this question I would either like pursue an old iPod touch for
Speaker 9:  a few years at least it should be good for 1, 2, 3 more years. Or like you
Speaker 9:  said, buy a secondary phone that's You know does the job. The
Speaker 2:  Only other thing I could think of, and I did some research on this, like
Speaker 2:  I, I kind of wish we lived in the world
Speaker 2:  where Spotify's like car thing had been super
Speaker 2:  successful and it went down this road of building sort
Speaker 2:  of nichey music gadgets. 'cause I agree we should have more music gadgets.
Speaker 2:  Like I, I think the idea that my phone is my source of music makes some
Speaker 2:  sense because it's the device I have with me, whatever. But I kind of wish
Speaker 2:  there were more. And the thing I wish most of all is that
Speaker 2:  some kind of wearable was the answer and there's little bits of
Speaker 2:  stuff. Fitbit makes some stuff that has some pretty good integrations
Speaker 2:  with Spotify and geezer and some of these things. A lot obviously depends
Speaker 2:  on which apps you use. Like if, if you use Apple Podcasts, all of this is
Speaker 2:  moot by an iPod touch. But for some of these things there are like bits and
Speaker 2:  pieces of it you can get. But like you said, all of these are just phone
Speaker 2:  accessories. They, they require so much else to do on
Speaker 2:  your smartphone before you can get it onto your actual dedicated device.
Speaker 2:  Right?
Speaker 9:  Like it feels like the Apple Watch should be able to sync with a Mac at this
Speaker 9:  point in time and You know it's, god knows it's almost 2024
Speaker 9:  but you still need an iPhone there. So that would solve the problem immediately.
Speaker 9:  Like like You know buy an Apple watch that could talk to a Mac, you'd be
Speaker 9:  all good but that does not exist. But I would look at The Mighty honestly
Speaker 9:  You know it looks like an IPO shuffle, it's got some charm, you can wear
Speaker 9:  it if you want a dumb phone. It kind of fits that, that vibe. But you just
Speaker 9:  gotta figure out like what device will it sync with And I think, I'm sure
Speaker 9:  he's got some kind of phone lying around that can still You know run Spotify.
Speaker 2:  Yeah and the good news is, I would think on the phone front, if all you really
Speaker 2:  want is like Spotify and Pocket Casts or whatever,
Speaker 2:  I'll plug pocket cast 'cause it's my favorite podcast app. Same, you
Speaker 9:  Don't
Speaker 2:  Need much phone to do that, right? Like you can buy a pretty
Speaker 2:  small, pretty low end, pretty low powered phone I would say as long as
Speaker 2:  it's relatively modern in its software
Speaker 2:  capabilities. So it'll last a long time. Yeah. Like to
Speaker 2:  almost no one what I recommend most of the like one to $200
Speaker 2:  smartphones out there, but in that range you can get something that's gonna
Speaker 2:  serve you perfectly fine for these particular cases. If all you want
Speaker 2:  is like a thing to plug headphones into to listen to music, right?
Speaker 9:  Yeah. That or like check out like a Pixel seven A during the holiday sales
Speaker 9:  and see if you can get a good good discount on that. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Google gives those things away like six times a year. Yeah. You can probably
Speaker 2:  find one. Any other, are there any other interesting music gadgets
Speaker 2:  out there in the world right now? I feel like there's like is Neil Young
Speaker 2:  still doing the the Pono thing? Is that
Speaker 9:  Pono? God, what a time that was to be alive. That's not around
Speaker 9:  anymore. I mean I'm sure some of my readers are gonna have some very super
Speaker 9:  niche solutions that are out there, but yeah, off the top of my head I can
Speaker 9:  think of like Sony makes Cheap Walkmans that aren't that pricey, but those
Speaker 9:  are the manual loading on music and stuff and so those don't run Android
Speaker 9:  at all. And so that would not be a good solution. But yeah, I would buy an
Speaker 9:  old iPod touch secondary phone check out The Mighty for
Speaker 9:  like a hundred, 130 bucks and see if that'll solve your dilemma.
Speaker 9:  But yeah, that's a, that's a big challenge to find a device that can sync
Speaker 9:  your podcasts with a dumb phone.
Speaker 2:  It's a strange one and I really, I do support the overall theory of
Speaker 2:  trying to take all the things that your phone does instead. Absolutely. Instead
Speaker 2:  of split them out so that it's like instead of having everything with me
Speaker 2:  all at once in this one device, I can just have the tools that I need and
Speaker 2:  not worry about the rest. Like single
Speaker 9:  Purpose devices, You know the iPod.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Honestly, like I wish the answer was the new
Speaker 2:  iPod Classic, right? Like integrates with Apple Music and
Speaker 2:  Apple Podcasts and you can just live your life and that like that's the device
Speaker 2:  I want to exist
Speaker 9:  Seriously. Part of me will always miss the heyday of the iPod I think to
Speaker 9:  some degree, but, but this is the world we're in now so you gotta gotta work
Speaker 9:  with what we got.
Speaker 2:  I hope that helps. Chris, thank you as always.
Speaker 9:  Absolutely. Always a pleasure.
Speaker 1:  Alright,
Speaker 2:  That's it for The Vergecast today. Thanks to everyone on the show and thank
Speaker 2:  you for listening. There's lots more on everything we talked about from our
Speaker 2:  Spotify coverage to all the stuff going on in streaming at The Verge dot
Speaker 2:  com. We'll put some links in the show notes, but also You know read The Verge.
Speaker 2:  It's a great website. As always. If you have thoughts, feelings, questions,
Speaker 2:  weird Spotify playlists you wanna tell me about, you can always email us
Speaker 2:  at Vergecast at The Verge dot com or keep calling the Hotline 8
Speaker 2:  6 6 Verge one one. we love hearing from you. It's my favorite thing to do
Speaker 2:  on this show. This show is produced by Andrew Moreno and Liam James The.
Speaker 2:  Vergecast is The Verge production and part of the Vox Media podcast network.
Speaker 2:  Neli Alex and I will be back on Friday to talk about the PlayStation portal
Speaker 2:  more from Epic v, Google, and all the other news of the week. We'll see you
Speaker 2:  then. Rock and
Speaker 2:  roll.
Speaker 3:  This podcast is brought to you by Meta Quest three, the new mixed reality
Speaker 3:  headset from Meta Expand Your World in ways you never thought Possible
Speaker 3:  with the new Meta Quest. Three, put on the most powerful quest yet
Speaker 3:  and jump into fully immersive games like Assassin's Creed Nexus
Speaker 3:  or blend virtual elements into your surroundings in games like Stranger Things
Speaker 3:  vr. With over 500 titles, it's easy to dive into whatever
Speaker 3:  you're into. Expand your world with Meta Quest three. See child
Speaker 3:  safety guidance online accounts for 10 and up. Certain apps, games and experiences
Speaker 3:  may be suitable for a more mature audience. Learn more@meta.com.