# Transcript
ID: c41f6241-e502-410c-9b30-47e490ab2794
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: The race to win AI — and hack iMessage
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/1662191836486278507/-1100543975420941019/s93290-US-5167s-1702041883.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, Alex Cranz, and Dan Seifert discuss Google Gemini's attempt to compete with ChatGPT, Beeper Mini bringing iMessage to Android, and shakeups in the podcast industry, and much more.
Speaker 4:  Hello and Welcome. To Vergecast, the flagship podcast of Samsung
Speaker 4:  Decks enthusiasts
Speaker 5:  And me
Speaker 4:  And Alex Cranz. Hi, I'm Neli. I'm your friend. Alex. Cranz is here. I'm your
Speaker 5:  Don. Don't know what Dex is. Yeah, no, I've used it. I've used
Speaker 4:  It. You gotta find out. David Pierce refuses to use Dex.
Speaker 4:  So we've replaced him with Dan Siefert who's gonna show us his deck set up
Speaker 4:  today.
Speaker 6:  I'm the Dex Defender.
Speaker 4:  It's coming, actually, David's just on vacation. Yeah, but it for a moment,
Speaker 4:  you thought that I was so hardcore into Samsung decks
Speaker 4:  that I clipped my friend from his own show, didn't you? Yeah,
Speaker 5:  I, I would've believed it.
Speaker 4:  It's like that's who we are now. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  You, you and Dan are both like very passionate dex
Speaker 4:  Defenders in different directions.
Speaker 5:  Totally different directions. That's what's, and David's like. No. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  If You don't have a strong opinion about Samsung Dex, he can't be a pro or
Speaker 4:  con.
Speaker 5:  I'm, I'm forming one right now. So don. Don't get ejected from the room.
Speaker 5:  It's going. It's coming.
Speaker 4:  No, no. David is on a very well deserved vacation. Dan is filling in for
Speaker 4:  him. Hi Dan. How you doing? I'm All
Speaker 6:  Right? I am not recording through Dex, to be clear, we'll get
Speaker 6:  into it. Not the right tool for the job.
Speaker 4:  I saw Dan in the office the other day and he goes, look at this. And he pulls
Speaker 4:  out what, by all accounts, looks like a laptop and
Speaker 4:  we'll, we'll let people look at it in a minute. It's, I mean, it's nuts.
Speaker 4:  And he is got his like, phone ed on the side and he is like, it's Dex. And
Speaker 4:  I was like, that's awesome. And I was like, you have to come on The Vergecast
Speaker 4:  and talk about it. And the first thing Dan said to me was, I will not
Speaker 4:  record through this. I don't trust it enough.
Speaker 4:  He's just like, nothing mission critical is happening here. Dan, show us
Speaker 4:  your just frankly absurd galaxy fold Samsung
Speaker 4:  deck laptop set up. It's
Speaker 6:  Good. Alright, I'm gonna try and show it to the camera as best as I can.
Speaker 4:  But remember, it's a radio show. It's a radio
Speaker 6:  Show. But,
Speaker 4:  So if you're in your car right now, pull over and close your eyes. And in
Speaker 4:  your mind's eye, imagine what Dan is saying. Or alternatively,
Speaker 4:  pull over and watch this on YouTube. Those are your two choices. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  So this is like not a new thing. To be clear, I bought a
Speaker 6:  next doc, which is AOC thing.
Speaker 6:  It's been out for a couple of years. This idea has been out for like, well
Speaker 6:  over a decade. You plug your phone into it, it's a laptop looking thing,
Speaker 6:  but there's no guts inside of it. There's no computer inside of it. It's
Speaker 6:  just a touch screen. It keyboard, track pad battery, and you plug
Speaker 6:  your phone into it. But what I did was I got this
Speaker 6:  magnetic mount,
Speaker 4:  It's like a folding MagSafe mount
Speaker 6:  So I put a MagSafe. If anyone's been following me on any
Speaker 6:  threads or, or mast on, you might've seen that. I put a MagSafe ring on the
Speaker 6:  back of my Z fold and then I bought this magnetic mount that I stuck to
Speaker 6:  the back of the next dock. And so now I've got a deck set up
Speaker 6:  with my phone on the side and it, it's effectively
Speaker 6:  a dual screen decks. Yeah, that's what
Speaker 4:  I'm calling it. It's the world's worst chrome.
Speaker 5:  Wait, is it a dual screen or a, a triple screen? It's dual. Like is
Speaker 5:  the decks.
Speaker 6:  It's dual. See there's two.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. But the, the fold I almost feel like is a, a dual screen
Speaker 4:  Already. Technically it's triple screen. 'cause the back of the fold has
Speaker 4:  a screen that's not being used.
Speaker 6:  If I could display something on the screen for people sitting across from
Speaker 6:  me at the coffee shop,
Speaker 4:  I am actually astonished that Dex doesn't put up a full screen
Speaker 4:  ad on the back of the fold screen. That's like you're witnessing the power
Speaker 4:  of Samsung decks. Yes.
Speaker 6:  Now go buy a fridge.
Speaker 6:  That would be quite wonderful actually. But no, it's, it's, it's a dual screen
Speaker 6:  thing. I got my phone on one side. The cool thing about this setup is that
Speaker 6:  you can use the phone as a phone. And so like that looks like a
Speaker 6:  phone. Then on the other side is the Dex interface.
Speaker 5:  It is also significantly better than what you were rocking.
Speaker 4:  No, it is, it is such a vast improvement over my attempt to use Dex.
Speaker 4:  The problem with it is that you still have to use a Galaxy fold.
Speaker 5:  You have to buy this fake laptop. I
Speaker 6:  Don't have a problem with that, but yeah,
Speaker 4:  I, my, I did not enjoy one minute of using the Galaxy fold.
Speaker 4:  Just the every piece of that just made me, and I, that's not to say I don't
Speaker 4:  enjoy using Android. I like using Android. The
Speaker 4:  Galaxy Fold is a very particular device Yes. With very
Speaker 4:  particular demands. And I just didn't like it. It's
Speaker 6:  Got a particular set of skills. We
Speaker 4:  Could say that. Yeah. And the skills are being clunkier than a regular phone.
Speaker 6:  Ah, maybe. but it could do a lot more than a regular phone. You know,
Speaker 6:  I think like, just to like back up on the Dex conversation here.
Speaker 6:  I think there are like two things that are appealing about Dex. One
Speaker 6:  is what you've been trying to do, Eli, which is like, I'm going ultra lightweight.
Speaker 6:  I'm just traveling with my phone and I roll into the office. Yeah. Plug into
Speaker 6:  a hotel desk and I have a desktop set up with a keyboard, mouse, and
Speaker 6:  a big screen there. That is one dream. Yeah. The other way, the other path
Speaker 6:  that's interesting to me at least is the setup that I've got here, which
Speaker 6:  is like, you could say, well, you're just carrying around as much as
Speaker 6:  a MacBook error and a phone. Anyways, the difference is
Speaker 6:  I don't have to like sync between two different devices here. Everything's
Speaker 6:  running off the phone. All of my data is running off the phone and it's using
Speaker 6:  my phone's internet connection. So what this is doing is essentially giving
Speaker 6:  me a laptop like experience with integrated cellular that I can't really
Speaker 6:  get through Apple or really through a lot of other parties. So that is like
Speaker 6:  the interesting thing. All that said, both paths
Speaker 6:  can lead to madness and there's a lot of junk involved
Speaker 6:  in either one of them. I just find it pretty fascinating. A, that It works
Speaker 6:  at all and B, how far it's come since I first experienced Dex way back in
Speaker 6:  like 2018. It is, it is wildly
Speaker 5:  You, you don't find it fascinating. No, you are
Speaker 5:  delighted by it. I'm,
Speaker 6:  I'm delighted by gadgets. Even if they don't look, look as well as some other
Speaker 6:  solutions. I was getting this, they let me
Speaker 5:  Dms from you about this thing. You're just like, look at it. It works. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  it looks cool. It's very cool at it. It looks cool as hell.
Speaker 4:  Again. My my the beginning of my Dex journey started
Speaker 4:  by knowing Dan had been Dex pilled. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  But then what happened when you saw that there was like a fake laptop involved?
Speaker 4:  Well, so first I was like, okay, this is so much closer Yeah.
Speaker 4:  To what I thought I wanted. Right. And then he showed me the next stock,
Speaker 4:  which is the most aggressively 16 by nine laptop in the world. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Like the amount of bezel that is on the bottom of that display. You can
Speaker 5:  See it from here. It's,
Speaker 6:  It's, it's a good inch below the display of
Speaker 4:  Be, you could make that laptop four, three just by reclaiming bezels. Yes.
Speaker 4:  Yes. It's, it's a lot of bezel. And then
Speaker 4:  it's still decks, which is clunky and, and what
Speaker 5:  Have you left the laptop at work and
Speaker 4:  Just, yeah. What if I just had a desk with a laptop on it that I left here
Speaker 4:  like I used to do in the before time. That's,
Speaker 4:  that's where we're going. But
Speaker 5:  See if someone steals this one, they're not gonna get important neli secrets.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. You can't log into it if there's no phone. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It's just the fake laptop.
Speaker 4:  Look, I I know it's the, the dream is that you just walk around
Speaker 4:  with a cool phone. Yeah. Just plug it it into stuff and having it turn
Speaker 4:  into your thing. Yeah. That's the dream. We all agree. That's the dream.
Speaker 4:  A hundred percent. You throw it in a couple, your car, the car lights up
Speaker 4:  and it's your phone. Yeah. You can, you can sort of get there, but you have
Speaker 4:  to experience CarPlay for better or worse. It's
Speaker 5:  Great. You,
Speaker 4:  You, you come to the office, you throw it on a, a magnetic charger,
Speaker 4:  like a pad screen lights up, you're doing all your stuff.
Speaker 4:  Everyone knows what the dream is. Yeah. I get emails by people who are like,
Speaker 4:  I feel you on the dream. And then you sit down and you're like, I have to
Speaker 4:  use this galaxy fold. Which again, like the
Speaker 4:  screen, the screen is just like a bubbly, wavy experience.
Speaker 6:  I, I mean, I don't know if it was like your specific one or
Speaker 6:  whatever, but like,
Speaker 5:  No, yours is two Dan.
Speaker 6:  I mean, so if you look at mine,
Speaker 5:  I can see it from here.
Speaker 6:  Five. If you're looking at it off axis, then yeah, you can see that crease
Speaker 6:  and stuff like that. But when you're holding it straight on, you really don't
Speaker 6:  see the crease. And when the screen is on and you're like experiencing
Speaker 6:  content, you don't see the, the crease. It just disappears. It just
Speaker 6:  disappears. Like I've read like a hundred books on it this year. The
Speaker 4:  Pixel fold, which has I think the better aspect ratio
Speaker 4:  when it's full. See,
Speaker 6:  I disagree entirely because
Speaker 4:  I want to use it as a phone a lot of the time. And the galaxy fold does not
Speaker 4:  lend itself to being used as a phone. Yeah. 'cause it's too tall and too
Speaker 4:  skinny. So you're always unfolding it. The Pixel fold, at least folds in
Speaker 4:  that direction. And it got a big update this week along with the rest of
Speaker 4:  Pixel updates, which we'll talk about. There's actual news this week, like
Speaker 4:  quite a lot of it. But we're gonna do the first 20 minutes on Dex
Speaker 4:  anyway, the Pixel fold got an update this week that forces
Speaker 4:  any app to work on. Its on its version of a folding display at full
Speaker 4:  screen. Maybe I'll try that. but it doesn't have a dex mode.
Speaker 6:  No, you can't plug the Pixel fold into anything. It doesn't have video out
Speaker 6:  at all. Like,
Speaker 4:  Come on, turn it into a Chromebook. Let's do this first party decks. What
Speaker 5:  If you just like slap it into the back
Speaker 4:  Of one the flagship podcast of requesting Google make decks,
Speaker 5:  Do it Google
Speaker 4:  All. right. That's that. That's one thing. So the, the decks experiments
Speaker 4:  continue a pace. I don't recommend them, but if you have
Speaker 4:  strong opinions about Dex, we wanna hear from you two. And I just wanna mention
Speaker 4:  this before we begin. There's a big Supreme court case about the social
Speaker 4:  media moderation laws that were passed in Texas and Florida, which by I
Speaker 4:  I'm just gonna tell you, they're blatantly unconstitutional. Yeah. There's
Speaker 4:  pure violations of the First Amendment. They're government speech regulations,
Speaker 4:  but they're at the Supreme court. Supreme court's gonna, whatever
Speaker 4:  amicus briefs are being filed in these cases. One is by public
Speaker 4:  knowledge, which we, those
Speaker 5:  Are like supporting briefs,
Speaker 4:  Right? The supporting briefs not from the parties, it's just people with
Speaker 4:  strong opinions. Filing briefs is Supreme court. So you look at the dockets,
Speaker 4:  a bunch of people are filing them. Public knowledge, which is an organization
Speaker 4:  that we have talked to a lot. Folks from Public Knowledge you have encountered
Speaker 4:  on The Verge many, many times. John Bergmayer, public Knowledge, you have
Speaker 4:  probably encountered in our stories or our podcast in the past. He sent me
Speaker 4:  an email today. He is like, you're in our brief. And they cited Welcome to
Speaker 4:  hell. Elon. Yes. And the Supreme Court brief today, which
Speaker 4:  means Welcome to hell. Elon is now part of our government's history.
Speaker 4:  Like it's just, it's on, it's in, it's in the docket on a pivotal
Speaker 4:  First Amendment case.
Speaker 5:  I'm When do you think like law students are gonna start having to read? It's
Speaker 5:  required reading for 'em.
Speaker 4:  When my mom read this, she, she didn't even call me. She was so upset at
Speaker 4:  the number of F-bombs in the story that she called my sister.
Speaker 4:  And my sister had to call me to call my mother who then
Speaker 4:  said, why did you use some such language? And now,
Speaker 4:  now Clarence Thomas is gonna read that shit. And I just, I'm just, I'm
Speaker 4:  just, anything can happen. That's my message to the Youth of America. Any,
Speaker 4:  anything can, can happen. But I'm, I'm actually the these cases are, are
Speaker 4:  big deals. What's inside of it is do social networks have the right to
Speaker 4:  moderate their networks? Do they have their own First Amendment rights to
Speaker 4:  make choices on their networks? I think the answer has to be yes. It doesn't
Speaker 4:  matter which side of the aisle you're on. The answer has to be yes.
Speaker 4:  Because that way you can get things like subreddits. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And you need things like subreddits. You need, maybe you need something like
Speaker 4:  X that is moderated in one very specific way and something that is different
Speaker 4:  and to let people decide. So that's the heart of this case,
Speaker 4:  but it is just very funny to me. I
Speaker 5:  Think it's great. I'm very excited for
Speaker 4:  You. I'm just, again, I, I just hope Clarence Thomas, I describe the Supreme
Speaker 4:  Court in this piece as a group of uncool weirdos.
Speaker 5:  I mean, I think most of 'em will read that and be like, fair.
Speaker 4:  I, I hope so.
Speaker 5:  Most of them. Not to Clarence Thomas.
Speaker 4:  I feel like I can go through the nine and be like, who will, who will see
Speaker 4:  themselves and who will like, Alito is gonna be pissed. Yeah. Like Alito
Speaker 4:  is like, look at these Jordans. I'm cool as shit.
Speaker 5:  Kagan's gonna be like, I get it. Understood.
Speaker 4:  Just if anyone can AI generate for me to photograph of Samuel Alito
Speaker 4:  pointing at as Jordans saying, I'm cool as shit. I'm not sure what
Speaker 4:  we'll do with it, but I will accept it
Speaker 5:  Just into your heart. Just happy to experience it.
Speaker 4:  Same later in the Black Jordans. Okay. There is a lot of news this week.
Speaker 4:  Let's start with Google. We, we've already been talking about Google Big
Speaker 4:  News this week. They launched Gemini. It's the new AI model. They've been
Speaker 4:  talking about it for a while. They started talking about it even when they
Speaker 4:  launched Bard the first time, even at io, they were saying, we have this
Speaker 4:  new model called Gemini that they've been doing demos of it. It is finally
Speaker 4:  here. It is obviously meant to be the
Speaker 4:  big step change competitor to chat s GPT in particular. s GPT
Speaker 4:  four. Yeah. David talked to Sundar Phai and
Speaker 4:  Demi Sabas who runs Google DeepMind, the head of AI over there. They're,
Speaker 4:  they keep talking about benchmarks, which I, I would like to get your opinions
Speaker 4:  on. We've reviewed many products. There's,
Speaker 4:  there's an importance of benchmarks in the world. I
Speaker 4:  don't know what an AI model benchmark is, but they talked about
Speaker 4:  it a lot. They talked about it a lot on 30 out, 32 benchmarks.
Speaker 4:  Gemini Beats, s GPT four. That's like
Speaker 5:  A gamer's nexus. Number of benchmarks
Speaker 4:  To run. Yeah. I don't know man. So we should talk about that, what that means.
Speaker 4:  And if that is a useful measure for us as we can figure out like
Speaker 4:  how all of us should evaluate different AI systems. But that is their claim.
Speaker 4:  30 outta 32. Sam Altman, you're back. Guess what you
Speaker 4:  got fired again. Like I, don Dunno.
Speaker 4:  Sundar told David that eventually Gemini will be integrated into search.
Speaker 4:  It's ad products and a Chrome, like this is the thing they're gonna build
Speaker 4:  on. It's in Bard. You can play with Bard. I
Speaker 4:  wanna talk about Bard in a minute. And then the main, the main main thing
Speaker 4:  about Gemini is that it is multimodal from the jump. Right?
Speaker 4:  So it understands video and audio. It can spit some of that stuff
Speaker 4:  out. There's a really fun video that Google released where a person is drawing
Speaker 4:  a picture of a duck and it just sort of figures out that it's looking at
Speaker 4:  a duck. Cool.
Speaker 5:  That's cool as
Speaker 4:  Hell. I would, I would posit that hotdog, not hotdog again,
Speaker 4:  remains the baseline framework to understand the entire AI industry.
Speaker 4:  That's a duck. Yeah. You know what I mean? It's a duck.
Speaker 4:  So it's cool. It's like fun to play with. It's cool. The addition of multimodal
Speaker 4:  capabilities is what really happened this year in ai. That was the big step
Speaker 4:  change. And then obviously Google has new chips. It's more
Speaker 4:  efficient. They're excited about all that
Speaker 5:  Aspect. The multimodal stuff that's not actually live for, for
Speaker 5:  most people. That's only like, for like businesses. Right.
Speaker 5:  So these
Speaker 4:  Are the these are the three models. Yeah. So there's Gemini Nano, which runs
Speaker 4:  only on the Pixel eight pro. And Google's very excited about this.
Speaker 4:  Now the phone is the best phone for ai, da da. Yeah. So it's only in Pixel
Speaker 4:  eight Pro is Gemini Nano. That's the smallest version of the new model.
Speaker 4:  It can run on the Pixel, eights, tensor processing, all that stuff. Then
Speaker 4:  there's Gemini Pro, which is what you can go use in Bard today. Right.
Speaker 4:  And then there's Gemini Ultra, which is not out yet. Okay.
Speaker 5:  And, but that's the one like, because the pro version is still
Speaker 5:  just in Bard. Like that's the only way we can currently access it. And Bard
Speaker 5:  is still just text-based.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. The the pro version is still a chat bot type of thing where you
Speaker 6:  type in, it gives you typed responses back. And Ultra is the one that involves
Speaker 6:  vision and pictures and video and stuff like that. And you're right,
Speaker 6:  Alex, that is like the difference now. And so we can't really experience
Speaker 6:  the multimodal aspect of this just yet. Ultra is coming
Speaker 6:  out next year according to Google. And it will most likely
Speaker 6:  be used for the more enterprise applications that are the higher
Speaker 6:  demand, higher intensity stuff. Well that,
Speaker 5:  That's the part that like Google is the most excited about, like over and
Speaker 5:  over again. Yeah. Beside that and the benchmarks, they're like, yeah, it's
Speaker 5:  really fast and you do all this stuff and you can't see any of it yet. Well
Speaker 6:  It's, it's the new thing, right? Right. Like, like the, the chat interface
Speaker 6:  we've had all year with chat s GPT four and, and the others as well
Speaker 6:  as Bard. So like it a better chat interface is great. Appreciate
Speaker 6:  it. But like the new thing is the multimodal thing. So I. That's understandable.
Speaker 6:  Why Google is most excited about that. That is like the thing that if you
Speaker 6:  wanna put your, on your like predicting hat, like a robot is gonna use a
Speaker 6:  multimodal LLM AI interface in order to navigate the world. So like
Speaker 6:  that's like the exciting futurist stuff. So like, I get it. And
Speaker 4:  That's basically what de said in our piece. You can see how
Speaker 4:  we would get to robotics with a model like Gemini. Or at least they can see
Speaker 4:  it. What we can see is Google Park. Right. But you can see
Speaker 4:  how a robot looking at something would be able to make some interpretations
Speaker 4:  of it, spit out some new commands and go. So that, this
Speaker 4:  brings me back to like, how do we evaluate this stuff? I've been thinking
Speaker 4:  about this a lot. You've
Speaker 5:  Been playing with it a whole lot
Speaker 4:  Too. I, it's, I'm addicted to playing with Bard. 'cause there's nothing funnier
Speaker 4:  than asking a Google product how it will impact search. You know, it's just
Speaker 4:  like, it's, they gotta dance around it. So, I think playing with Bard is
Speaker 4:  really interesting. I think the connection that Bard has, or lack of
Speaker 4:  connection that Bard has to the Google search generative experience is
Speaker 4:  really interesting. So Bard is supposed to be
Speaker 4:  a pretty self-contained experience. Yeah. You open the chat bot, you ask
Speaker 4:  it for stuff, it can summarize things for you. They can watch a YouTube video
Speaker 4:  for you. Again, huge problems with that idea.
Speaker 4:  Like if the robot's watching the YouTube video for you, does the YouTube
Speaker 4:  creator receive any money? don don't know the answer to that question. don
Speaker 4:  don't think Google knows the answer to that question.
Speaker 5:  CliffNotes knows the answer problem.
Speaker 4:  Maybe So, I've been playing with Bart a lot Bar so
Speaker 4:  far. Barge just has confidently hallucinated at me left and right. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I asked it why a Google executive would be upset at The Verge, I
Speaker 4:  won't name names this time. You can go look at my threads post. And it like
Speaker 4:  made a list of answers and then it confidently hallucinated
Speaker 4:  complete with a link to YouTube. Yes. A Vergecast interview that
Speaker 4:  has never occurred.
Speaker 4:  It just took us to The Vergecast channel page. Aw,
Speaker 5:  Thank you for the promotion. Bard.
Speaker 4:  Great. I but that to me is so nuts. And then I
Speaker 4:  asked, why did you do this? Yeah. And it apologized to me
Speaker 4:  like, I'm very sorry. I misinterpreted some facts. I assumed this had happened.
Speaker 4:  I read some like titles of other Vergecast,
Speaker 4:  which random like not even relevant. Like even in the realm of relevance.
Speaker 4:  And it's like, but but it turns out on, on further examination, like
Speaker 4:  this didn't happen. And I was like, why do you do this? And I was like, I'm
Speaker 4:  every day I'm getting better. Like you. That's
Speaker 5:  How I, what I say whenever I like file a really bad blog. Yeah. And I get
Speaker 5:  hard edits. I'm like, don't look, I'm working on it day every day. I
Speaker 4:  Get better. I didn't, I didn't read the source material. Yeah. I'm very sorry.
Speaker 4:  I'm
Speaker 5:  Very sorry.
Speaker 4:  You put that up against 30 outta 32 benchmarks and it's
Speaker 4:  like, wait, there's only one benchmark, right? Yeah. Does it lie
Speaker 4:  to you all the time? Can you trust what it says?
Speaker 5:  I don't think they're benchmarking that.
Speaker 4:  I, it appears not. I think there are benchmarking things like can it do math?
Speaker 4:  Right?
Speaker 5:  Because a lot of the benchmarks that seem to be around coding and so there
Speaker 5:  was a ton of coding benchmarks and that's really where it sounded like Google
Speaker 5:  is the most excited about it, is it's gonna put a whole lot of
Speaker 5:  coders out of jobs 'cause it can do it as well or better.
Speaker 5:  And then not a lot of conversation about the hallucinations, which for me
Speaker 5:  and you, and I think most people is like, that's what I actually care about.
Speaker 5:  Like, I'm happy it can do Python really, really well, but I need to know
Speaker 5:  if it's gonna lie to me and destroy the world. Or just lie to me and,
Speaker 5:  and, and keep showing me fake Vergecast videos.
Speaker 4:  I'm gonna read you the, the some of the benchmarks. Okay. Okay. There's
Speaker 4:  MMLU, which is a massive multitask language understanding. Oh, it
Speaker 4:  scores a 90% compared to s GPT four is 86%. Ooh, that means something
Speaker 4:  to you. Yeah. There's big bench hard.
Speaker 4:  That's, that's called
Speaker 4:  these the, the, that's a reasoning one. That's the one we put on
Speaker 5:  The gaming
Speaker 4:  Laptops. Big bench hard. Right? It's a diverse set
Speaker 4:  of challenging tasks requiring multi-step reasoning. Gemini did 83 point
Speaker 4:  Gemini Ultra. Mind you 83.6%. GP four is
Speaker 4:  83.1. There's something called drop, which is reading comprehension
Speaker 4:  82.4 for Gemini Ultra 80.9 for s GPT four.
Speaker 4:  I swear to God this isn't a blog post that Google published. There's a reasoning
Speaker 4:  benchmark for AI systems called Hella swag.
Speaker 6:  All of these sound like the like skills comprehension
Speaker 6:  tests my kids go through in elementary school where they take the state tests
Speaker 6:  and they're like, are you at grade level? Are you above grade level? Are
Speaker 6:  you behind grade level? Yeah. That's what all of these sound like. Are you
Speaker 6:  at
Speaker 4:  Hella swag? Yeah.
Speaker 6:  It's like what is your hella swag level? Are you at, are you at
Speaker 6:  acceptable hella swag? Are you hella, hella swag? Are you
Speaker 6:  just swag?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Gemini is just swag. 87.8,
Speaker 4:  95.3. Hella swag score for s GPT four. Let's go.
Speaker 4:  I would remind you again that s GPT four is made by a company that is in
Speaker 4:  pure turmoil fired and rehired A CEO in
Speaker 4:  a matter of days. But
Speaker 6:  It's
Speaker 4:  Swag. It's super swag. There's some other ones. There's math ones
Speaker 4:  GSM eight K 94.4% for Gemini
Speaker 4:  92.0. So you could just read these. They're all in Google's blog posts. We
Speaker 4:  will link to it. My point is, you look at this
Speaker 4:  and with a benchmark test for a gaming laptop,
Speaker 4:  I I can draw some conclusions about, I don't know how fast the
Speaker 4:  laptop is. Yeah. How well it will play Shadow of the Tomb Raider. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  So, well a game people love the play the best.
Speaker 4:  People love it when we benchmark shadow the tomb writer, nobody loves
Speaker 4:  anything more. It's a, when we benchmark shadow the tomb writer. but it,
Speaker 4:  those things are related to what you might do. Right. And
Speaker 4:  I'm, I'm just reading these benchmarks for Gemini and I understand why Google's
Speaker 4:  proud of them. Yes, it is true. On 30 out of 32,
Speaker 4:  the number in their column is blue. And on two of 32,
Speaker 4:  the number in s GPT column is blue. That great you won.
Speaker 4:  It doesn't mean anything to me yet. And then in actually using the
Speaker 4:  product, I find myself saying, well if I
Speaker 4:  can't trust it, it doesn't matter. Yeah. It's,
Speaker 6:  It reminds me of the battery benchmark testing. Like
Speaker 5:  Yes, I was about to say the same. Like,
Speaker 6:  Manufacturers do rundown benchmark tests, all of them do this on laptops,
Speaker 6:  mobile devices, whatever. Whether they're Apple, HP, Dell, whoever. And they
Speaker 6:  will come out saying 22 hours of video playback time, which means
Speaker 6:  nothing when my laptop dies in five hours of me using it
Speaker 6:  for
Speaker 5:  Work. 'cause you, you look at it and you see there's usually an asterisk
Speaker 5:  and it's like, we've turned off the wifi, we've turned off the Bluetooth,
Speaker 5:  weve turned off the video Soul video. Like yeah, we, we, the screen might
Speaker 5:  not even be on, but we did it. And, and it's the same thing here
Speaker 5:  where it is actually really, really hard to test a battery because there,
Speaker 5:  because there are so many variables and in the same way there's so many
Speaker 5:  variables with hallucination. So it's, it's like, it's really hard. They
Speaker 5:  can't even figure out how to make something to test. If it's hallucinating,
Speaker 5:  how are they gonna make a benchmark Yeah. To test if it's hallucinating.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I mean I I I think it is fascinating that they have a benchmark for
Speaker 4:  understanding infographics. I think that's cool.
Speaker 4:  Like someone had to come up with that benchmark. Yeah. And, and someone had
Speaker 4:  to point out that Gemini Ultra gets an 80.3 on
Speaker 4:  that benchmark. Nailed it. Whereas the s GPT four gets
Speaker 4:  75.1. We can talk about the actual product. I'm, I'm focused on this
Speaker 4:  because I think there's a tendency with all tech products to try
Speaker 4:  to find some objective measure that will say that Apple is definitively better
Speaker 4:  than Microsoft or whatever it is. Windows Drools.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Look at this benchmark. Like we live in it and I'm just
Speaker 4:  trying to apply that instinctively to being shown some benchmarks.
Speaker 4:  And I'm like, but I don't,
Speaker 5:  I think it's so hard to do with AI because AI is like, especially large
Speaker 5:  language models so nebulous. It is so vast,
Speaker 5:  right? Yeah. Like, like the amount of stuff it's ingesting and then that
Speaker 5:  it can like recreate is enormous.
Speaker 4:  We are very close to being like, I'm gonna measure Gemini's skull and tell
Speaker 4:  you how smart it is. Yeah. Right. Like it's, it's like
Speaker 5:  Right there. It's like, oh, do we wanna do that?
Speaker 4:  So there, there's just some, some weirdness here. But at the same time,
Speaker 4:  knowing that one of these is good or worse at decoding infographics,
Speaker 4:  I shared a, a post with Andrew Moreno, our engineer the other day, where
Speaker 4:  someone was uploading all of the manuals to old Roland
Speaker 4:  synthesizers to
Speaker 5:  GP That would be something you two would talk about.
Speaker 4:  And then asking it how to make the Sounds on Cure records. And
Speaker 4:  it would just read the manual because those manuals are impenetrable. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And it would just like spit out some settings for various songs. That
Speaker 4:  is the coolest shit in the entire world. Were were they accurate though?
Speaker 4:  I don't know. It was just a threads post about somebody who was excited,
Speaker 4:  but it was cool. but it's like, I'm certain it got closer than if you were
Speaker 4:  just ice cold reading the manual. Right. Especially a manual
Speaker 4:  that that that, that's impenetrable. I mean
Speaker 6:  If it gave you some like Depeche mode settings when you asked for the Cure,
Speaker 6:  that would not be very good. Right.
Speaker 4:  I mean, that would cause a Holy War. Let's be fair. Careful. That's my point.
Speaker 4:  But I, there's, there's some of that which I think is so cool that
Speaker 4:  these tools can do. And don don't know how to
Speaker 4:  evaluate a company telling me, I don't know how to make the connection between
Speaker 4:  the, the benchmarks are better and the capabilities are better.
Speaker 5:  I think it's because it's really, it's hard for them to do. So they're like,
Speaker 5:  okay, well I can lean on benchmarks because this is like something I can
Speaker 5:  actually say. I don't have to just be like, doesn't it feel nicer?
Speaker 5:  Which you get a lot of times with with gadgets. Yeah. They always are like,
Speaker 5:  gimme those, the subjective things. And largely with, with
Speaker 5:  ai it is largely subjective. Like, okay, yeah, it's cool that it can do
Speaker 5:  python and stuff better, but the the big stuff, the stuff that most people
Speaker 5:  are gonna be using it for is all that the subjective stuff. And you can't
Speaker 5:  test that. Like, it feels like you more have to do like a
Speaker 5:  research project. Like it's more like anthropology or something, I feel like.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Than it is like mathematics and, and computations.
Speaker 4:  Right. Do these models have different personalities? Right? Do they, are
Speaker 4:  they better at different things? 'cause their cultures are like, you do start
Speaker 4:  to get into some very deep questions about the nature of intelligence and
Speaker 4:  then you're like, someone asked it if I was handsome and I was like,
Speaker 4:  Hmm.
Speaker 4:  It like literally said like, beauty is in the eye of the holder. And I was
Speaker 4:  like, well you got a little bit of personality there. Whew.
Speaker 5:  All. right. I see how it is. Damn.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It's like his contributions are vast but I No, no.
Speaker 4:  So anyway, people should play with it. I'm curious what people think of it.
Speaker 4:  There is obviously the future of Google's business
Speaker 4:  is here, right? The future of the search business, which is the cash cow
Speaker 4:  for Google is sitting right in this product. And I still
Speaker 4:  don't know how that's gonna work. And I don't know if Google
Speaker 4:  yet knows how it's gonna work. How is it
Speaker 5:  Working in the Pixel? I haven't tried the Pixel version yet. And I'm just
Speaker 5:  curious like, so
Speaker 4:  The Pixel a pro is only, there's two things today. It's auto summarization
Speaker 4:  in the recorder app and smart reply in the keyboard. Keyboard are now Gemini
Speaker 4:  nano.
Speaker 5:  Okay. Yeah. I mean,
Speaker 4:  And you can really feel that 29th benchmark. Yeah. When you're using smart
Speaker 4:  reply in the Yeah. Pixel a keyboard. I mean, look, those are auto
Speaker 4:  reply, auto complete. That stuff is really important.
Speaker 5:  That's true. That is true. Like, but
Speaker 4:  The AI stuff they've been doing, the recorder app is neat. And like for,
Speaker 4:  you know, a lot
Speaker 5:  Of our reporters like it like, like a lot of our reporters are like, oh yeah,
Speaker 5:  I'll use a Pixel phone to just record because don don't have to worry about
Speaker 5:  all the variety, wide variety of transcription services
Speaker 5:  that cost a lot of money and also use ai. Yeah. So you can just do it that
Speaker 5:  way. That like, that's genuinely useful. But for a very small group of people,
Speaker 5:  I'd imagine
Speaker 4:  Google is always thinking about the, the, the journalists, hardworking journalists
Speaker 4:  of the world when they make the Pixel features. But if you're recording a
Speaker 4:  meeting and it summarizes the meaning for you and that gets meaningfully
Speaker 4:  better. That's fair. That's great. And, and if that happens locally and you're
Speaker 4:  not sending your enterprise work product off to a cloud
Speaker 4:  service that's good for you
Speaker 5:  Gonna do all my CES briefings this way. It's
Speaker 4:  Just like, throw the phone down, be like, talk to this robot, let's go. It'll
Speaker 4:  summarize what you have to say for me
Speaker 4:  anyway. But that, so that's the big news of the week. Like this is the future
Speaker 4:  of Google. You can just go play with Bard. It's neat.
Speaker 4:  There's other AI news this week. So Bing Dear your Suite
Speaker 4:  Bing announced something called Deep Search. So the
Speaker 4:  Bing has always, I can't believe I'm say this, we started out with Dex. I'm
Speaker 4:  going to go to Bing. There's always been one really fascinating part of the
Speaker 4:  Bing search product as it relates to s GPT four.
Speaker 5:  I just wanna sit with that sentence for a minute.
Speaker 4:  It's, they've been doing So I don't know if it has been good or it's worked
Speaker 4:  or it's taken one point of market share. But they've always been doing something
Speaker 4:  really interesting, which they call search orchestration.
Speaker 4:  Now what it's gonna do is take that one step farther. It's going to read
Speaker 4:  your search query. Microsoft's example is how do point systems work in Japan.
Speaker 4:  It's gonna figure out all the things that could mean, and it's gonna go search
Speaker 4:  for those things and lace them together. So you can figure out if you mean
Speaker 4:  credit card point system or weird social credit systems or whatever
Speaker 4:  it is. And it's gonna lace this here so it'll take more time. But it's actually
Speaker 4:  sort of like expanding your query for you. Yeah. And doing a
Speaker 4:  bigger, deeper search of the web web. I mean it's, it's, which I think is
Speaker 4:  fascinating. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I feel like, you know, looking at it and, and seeing what they did there.
Speaker 5:  I think that's a great example of the loyalty programs because it is something
Speaker 5:  huge. It is nebulous. And if you don't have like the card, the
Speaker 5:  points guy or whatever for, for your region, that is
Speaker 5:  genuinely useful. You want that, that summary and, and like
Speaker 5:  that's hard to do on your own. Yeah, you can, but it's obnoxious.
Speaker 4:  So what's really fascinating to me about this is that
Speaker 4:  if you'll remember when when Chat s GPT launched and Bing launched, there
Speaker 4:  was that explosion of interest in prompt engineering. Yeah. And we
Speaker 4:  had lots of conversations with people, lots of executives are on decoder
Speaker 4:  saying Prompt engineering is just a thing that's gonna happen in the middle.
Speaker 4:  There need to be other, well join
Speaker 5:  Just did that great piece on, on prompt engineering.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And everyone, there's this theory that that's like a local, that's
Speaker 4:  like a flash in the pan moment. Yes. And then you look at what Deep Search
Speaker 4:  is doing and it is mechanically taking your query
Speaker 4:  to the Bing search engine and rewriting it to be a longer prompt.
Speaker 4:  So it takes, how do point systems work in Japan and it
Speaker 4:  rewrites the prompt to Bing as provide an explanation for how various loyalty
Speaker 4:  card programs work in Japan, including the benefits requirements, limitations
Speaker 4:  each. And then it goes on, it's like a full paragraph long prompt. And you
Speaker 4:  see that Microsoft has learned that it, it should just automate
Speaker 4:  prompt engineering for you. And that's how it should constantly talk to the
Speaker 4:  LLMs. It's
Speaker 6:  A, it's another job claimed by AI
Speaker 5:  Created and claimed in the same year.
Speaker 4:  And you know, now that we know more about particularly how, how Bing
Speaker 4:  works, like the huge Meta prompt that it feeds into s
Speaker 4:  GPT is crazy. That's just that the one that killed Sydney
Speaker 4:  basically. Yeah. And killed the personality and puts the guide rails is just
Speaker 4:  a Meta prompt that is appended to your query. And
Speaker 4:  So don don't know if that's how Google is managing Bard. don don't know.
Speaker 4:  Like that's how they all work. But this is very much how Microsoft is starting
Speaker 4:  to manage Bing, which is fascinating. It's hysterical.
Speaker 4:  And this of this deep search tool just like kind of an extension of that.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Well, and I appreciate that. It's, it's pretty candid about it. I'm curious
Speaker 5:  like in practice how often it's gonna show you that whole search prompt so
Speaker 5:  that eventually you, you can figure that out and be like, okay, well So I,
Speaker 5:  just do a whole paragraph now instead of being like, tell me how to fix it.
Speaker 5:  Which is probably useful for people. Yeah. I mean I would do that. I don't
Speaker 5:  know. I'm sure most people would just be like, tell me how to fix it. 'cause
Speaker 5:  that's faster and easier. But yeah.
Speaker 4:  So, but The race to to, to your point Yeah. The race, to
Speaker 4:  just answer the question continues a pace. And I think for Google,
Speaker 4:  the Gemini stuff is exciting. It shows they're in the game. They're, they're
Speaker 4:  excited about it. Very obviously Sundar, you know, did a press tour, the
Speaker 4:  whole thing. But how they turn that into money is still a huge open question.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And I, I just dunno the answer. But if the end result is you ask the
Speaker 4:  LMA question, it just tells you the answer, whether it's going through this
Speaker 4:  like secondary prompt engineering exercise or not. Or it's passing the
Speaker 4:  hella swag test Yeah. Or whatever it's doing.
Speaker 4:  They gotta put ads in there somewhere. They gotta, they gotta make some money.
Speaker 4:  I have seen some people say they think that Gemini Ultra will be a
Speaker 4:  subscription product the way that s GPT four is a subscription product. s
Speaker 4:  GPT 3.5 is not, or hell
Speaker 5:  Grok is a subscription product.
Speaker 4:  Gr also launched this week. Yeah, don't, it's fine.
Speaker 4:  Last two little bits of AI news, lemme take a break. Apple also made some
Speaker 4:  AI news this week, which is the first time Apple has made any AI news
Speaker 4:  really?
Speaker 5:  Baby
Speaker 4:  Steps, baby steps. They released a new model framework called MLX
Speaker 4:  that allows you to run various kinds of models and various
Speaker 4:  coding languages like PyTorch on their chips using their
Speaker 4:  memory architecture ideas.
Speaker 5:  I bet that was an internal tool that they're like, it's good enough, we can
Speaker 5:  now make it public. Because they, that that's been a big deal at Apple is
Speaker 5:  they don't wanna actually use all the other AI tools, but they want their
Speaker 5:  own a to I tools. Yeah. So they've been having to like, how do we build our
Speaker 5:  own Bard and Gemini and
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Why are these names all well,
Speaker 4:  And Apple is also leaning more into the open source world. Yeah. So
Speaker 4:  if you are, if you, you know, you're open source researcher, you want to
Speaker 4:  use Meta's Llama, which is open source, you wanna run an Apple silicon, you
Speaker 4:  now have a framework to do that that Apple is providing and supporting. Will
Speaker 4:  that get you anywhere? Like, I, I don't know,
Speaker 5:  I'm curious to see how well the Silicon handles it because just how
Speaker 5:  different all the different architectures handle ai. And it's particularly
Speaker 5:  like that stuff is like the Apple silicon is
Speaker 5:  very specifically built for a specific type of processing and it's good at
Speaker 5:  the other stuff. We've seen how good it's with video. And I'm just really
Speaker 5:  curious if that translates as like GPU kind of translates. I
Speaker 4:  Think you're right. Like Apple has very particular GPU ideas. Yes. But they
Speaker 4:  also have very particular neural engine ideas. Yeah. And we, we've just never
Speaker 4:  seen anyone attack that part of their chip to go head head-to-head with like
Speaker 4:  an Nvidia. Yeah. Because
Speaker 5:  AI g Yeah. All they have to do is is say like, yeah, it it opens your phone
Speaker 5:  real fast. It's really good at it and it's super smart and it's like, cool.
Speaker 5:  I have no way to ever test any Apple product. That's why we do,
Speaker 4:  Here's what you do. You run shadow of the tune. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I was like, that's why we got shadows of the tomb reader. It's the only thing
Speaker 5:  that works, the only way to test an Apple product.
Speaker 4:  Okay. And then the last little piece of AI news, I will just remind everyone
Speaker 4:  again and again and again, these companies are running rampant with
Speaker 4:  copyrighted information to train their systems. No one knows if
Speaker 4:  it's legal. They're insistent that they are, but all of them, all
Speaker 4:  of this money coin flip fair use lawsuit could take it
Speaker 4:  all down. It is just true. It's, it's a total coin
Speaker 4:  flip. You might have some opinions. I have some opinions. Our company has
Speaker 4:  some opinions. Hai has some opinions. I know s Andela
Speaker 4:  has some opinion. I've asked all of them and they're like, yeah, the legal
Speaker 4:  process will have to pay out Getty's lawsuit, Getty
Speaker 4:  image's, lawsuit against Stability. AI is not going go into trial in the
Speaker 4:  UK. And they obviously have suit here too. The law in the UK different than
Speaker 4:  the in United States. This is just a gigantic time
Speaker 4:  bomb in the middle of the AI boom. Yeah. Is that no one knows that this training
Speaker 4:  data is very used. Again, I I have an opinion. I think it is
Speaker 4:  probably not. And I am not that person. That's not
Speaker 4:  how it came up at all. That's not that it's a surprising opinion
Speaker 4:  for me. But the idea that you can just take all of this stuff just to
Speaker 4:  hoover it up and somehow create billions of dollars of value for your
Speaker 4:  users out of it.
Speaker 5:  That seems wrong
Speaker 4:  Without any, any return just on its face.
Speaker 4:  It seems like you're gonna go to a court without argument and something there
Speaker 4:  is gonna happen that you cannot predict. Yeah. Weird. Just we, and so we'll
Speaker 4:  see. I don't know. don don't know. And the courts are not predictable.
Speaker 5:  You're, we're all gonna get like 50 cents for our tweets. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  That's what's gonna
Speaker 5:  Happen. Sorry. Here's your 50 cents. We used your tweets.
Speaker 4:  Google has to send you a penny Every time anybody uses Bar
Speaker 5:  Man. Those, those, those fanfic writers gonna make bank
Speaker 4:  And the lawsuits are just gonna keep happening because in particular in this
Speaker 4:  country, fair use is not a precedent setting decision.
Speaker 4:  Every single fair use case evaluated on its merits de novo, like
Speaker 4:  it's supposed to be case by case. It's in the law. So you can just keep filing
Speaker 4:  the lawsuits until something else happens. Could
Speaker 5:  Somebody just make a law at some point?
Speaker 4:  I one would hope I don Dunno if you've been paying attention to
Speaker 4:  the state of our government,
Speaker 5:  Just fix
Speaker 4:  It. Doesn't seem one day doesn't seem likely. One
Speaker 5:  Day
Speaker 4:  George Santos is on cameo. That's the state of our government.
Speaker 5:  He's not in the government anymore.
Speaker 4:  Well, he's on cameo. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Just good pivot.
Speaker 4:  All, right. We gotta take a break. I'm gonna sign up for Cameo. We'll be
Speaker 4:  right back.
Speaker 4:  All right? We're back. All, right? We're, we're off the AI Benchmark news.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, we're done. Now it's time for hacks. We're hacks
Speaker 6:  And
Speaker 4:  Snacks, hacks and freaks with a pH. Actually a pretty
Speaker 4:  important, what would you call it, Dan? A workaround.
Speaker 6:  Reverse engineering workaround. Yeah. Yeah. But there's like solution.
Speaker 6:  There's some spoofing happening there too, right?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Okay, Sonos, let's get into it. Sorry. So Beeper, which is a long
Speaker 4:  standing iMessage workaround that for
Speaker 4:  years basically until just recently involved you signing into
Speaker 4:  your iCloud account on a Mac Mini in the cloud as a relay service
Speaker 4:  now has reversed engineered iMessage and they say they can
Speaker 4:  do it natively. Dan, what's going on here? Yeah,
Speaker 6:  So it's a, it's a fascinating story as, as Neli
Speaker 6:  just said, you know, beeper's been around for a while, but over the
Speaker 6:  summer a developer posted proof of
Speaker 6:  concept to GitHub that they had reverse engineered the
Speaker 6:  iMessage protocol and was able to send messages directly from
Speaker 6:  basically any device Linux Windows, Android,
Speaker 6:  two Apple's iMessage servers without having to use a relay server.
Speaker 6:  And when Beeper found out about this Beeper, who is
Speaker 6:  headed by former Pebble, CEO, Eric Micki
Speaker 4:  Pebble, the smartwatch company,
Speaker 6:  Pebble the Smartwatch. Yes, you do have to clarify. There are like eight
Speaker 6:  failed Pebbles. Now don't name your future company Pebble. That's all
Speaker 6:  my, my advice to anyone. He reached out to this developer,
Speaker 6:  contracted with him, turns out it's a 16-year-old high school kid. Yes.
Speaker 6:  Hires him Part-time to develop this into
Speaker 6:  a full fledged app. So now what we have today is a new app
Speaker 6:  called, they're calling it Beeper. Mini for now it is an iMessage client
Speaker 6:  for Android. And it is exactly what that says. It is
Speaker 6:  you, you install it on your Android phone. You don't even have to sign in
Speaker 6:  with an Apple id. It talks to Apple servers, takes your phone number
Speaker 6:  and turns it into a blue bubble on IO iOS
Speaker 6:  devices or Mac, whoever you're messaging. And it does it all locally
Speaker 6:  without a server relay server involved. And the way that they kind of reverse
Speaker 6:  engineered it is a fascinating process. I strongly, strongly recommend going
Speaker 6:  to check out Snazzy Hugh's video on it because he explains step by step,
Speaker 6:  and frankly it's above my head how it all works. But they end up
Speaker 6:  spoofing serial numbers of real Apple devices, which
Speaker 6:  is a technique that's been around for a long time in the Macintosh world
Speaker 6:  and in other applications in order to get Apple software to run on things
Speaker 6:  that maybe Apple doesn't formally approve. Apple's kind of just
Speaker 6:  always ignored it and left it alone. But they're using this now
Speaker 6:  to basically spoof iMessage onto Android and allow you to
Speaker 6:  be having completely, you know, full, fully
Speaker 6:  supported, for the most part, bluebe conversations on an Android phone.
Speaker 6:  And it's, it's fascinating 'cause It works incredibly well. Yeah, because
Speaker 5:  You've used it Jake I know who wrote the piece Yeah. Has been using it and
Speaker 5:  you, you really like it.
Speaker 6:  I think it's great. Like I, I was, I, I switched my sim fully
Speaker 6:  from an iPhone to an Android phone and nobody noticed,
Speaker 6:  like nothing skipped a beat. Like I am still a blue bubble to all of the
Speaker 6:  iPhone contacts I've ever had. And now I can message with
Speaker 6:  RCS and Google Messages app to Android users and
Speaker 6:  I like don't get left outta group messages. I don't get missed
Speaker 6:  notifications on reactions. I, if I wanted to send voice
Speaker 6:  messages I could. Like all of those features are supported. It's just
Speaker 6:  fascinating
Speaker 5:  When somebody says congratulations. Do you also now get the balloons
Speaker 6:  So you don't get the iMessage reactions? I think that's called, you
Speaker 6:  don't hit that. I believe they said they were working on that. They're working
Speaker 6:  on actually integrating FaceTime somehow, which I don't know how
Speaker 6:  they're gonna do. And the one thing that they don't ever anticipate ever
Speaker 6:  being able to support are the iMessage apps and games which,
Speaker 5:  Oh no, sorry,
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Big loss.
Speaker 4:  Oh no, not iMessage Apps and games. The
Speaker 6:  IMessage experience that most people think about on their
Speaker 6:  iPhones is now fully replicated on Android.
Speaker 4:  What happens if you have a mixed group of some Android phones,
Speaker 4:  some Beeper Mini and some iPhones, you just fall back to
Speaker 6:  Sms. So the Beeper Mini is going to act as an iMessage in that and the iPhones
Speaker 6:  are gonna act as an iMessage in that and everything's just gonna fall back
Speaker 6:  to SMS. And so that would go through your SMS app, probably Google
Speaker 6:  messages on your Android phone. 'cause it's just gonna be an SMS conversation
Speaker 5:  When you text someone, are you getting the texts both to your Bieber app
Speaker 5:  and to the regular text app? No. Oh, that's
Speaker 6:  Cool. If you are iMessaging someone that see the app can like tell if
Speaker 6:  you're talking to an iMessage client and so it
Speaker 6:  just, your iMessage conversation stays entirely within Ber Mini. If someone
Speaker 6:  sends you a text message, it will come through your text
Speaker 6:  message number through Google Messages. So,
Speaker 5:  Well, I was, I was thinking like the, the, the, the, the example Neil I had
Speaker 5:  where he was like, okay, what happens if you've got a Beeper person and an
Speaker 5:  Android person and an i i iMessage person? Then where
Speaker 5:  does that message, like it goes to the Beeper app because
Speaker 4:  No, it goes to ssm it falls back to it.
Speaker 6:  It you in that scenario, you the Beeper Mini user are using
Speaker 6:  SMS. Yeah. And so the, the, like, the annoying part of this is that you
Speaker 6:  now have two apps for messaging. You have your iMessage app and you have
Speaker 6:  your Google Messages app. And beeper's plan is
Speaker 6:  to, the original Beeper app was like, kind of like an an all in one message
Speaker 6:  service. So all it integrated all of your message services. Beeper Mini is
Speaker 6:  strictly iMessage for now. Their plan is to integrate all of those other
Speaker 6:  plugins into the Mini app, eventually drop the Mini name
Speaker 6:  and Sunset. The old app is the, the ultimate plan. But for today you, you're
Speaker 6:  using two apps
Speaker 4:  And the claim here, which I think is important, we don't know if it's true,
Speaker 4:  but the claim is that Apple can't stop it without completely rebuilding the
Speaker 4:  iMessage protocol. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I'm I'm really curious. I think because I keep getting stuck on the spoofing
Speaker 5:  part of this, like with Hack Andt toss, I used to, I I built a lot of Hack
Speaker 5:  Andt tos when I was younger. I love it. It's a fairly small community. So
Speaker 5:  it was like, okay Apple, we, we were all like, well
Speaker 4:  Apple, the police are coming now. Yeah. We understand that Craig Gregory
Speaker 4:  just was listening to this. He just called the police. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  My poor dog's getting arrested as we speak at home.
Speaker 5:  But, but it was, it was super easy to do. It was a lot of fun. but it was
Speaker 5:  also understood that like, it's a very small community so it wasn't really
Speaker 5:  a big deal and it wasn't like a bunch of money was exchanging hands. You
Speaker 5:  weren't being like, build me a Macintosh. 'cause as soon as you did that,
Speaker 5:  apple came down. You own like
Speaker 6:  Well, so the difference there is with Hack andt tos, it's usually you have
Speaker 6:  to go acquire Apple's software and install it on a device
Speaker 6:  and there's no real legal way to get that software
Speaker 6:  if you're getting like OSS 10 leopard or whatever. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Without getting it from Apple. And Apple's not gonna give it to you if You
Speaker 6:  don't have a max. So you have to like basically torrent it. Well
Speaker 5:  That's why we all, like everybody I knew who did it had a Mac,
Speaker 5:  we just wanted to also have a tiny Dell latitude that
Speaker 4:  Can I, can I tell you a story from a youth?
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  So there was a company in Florida called S Star. Do you remember this? Yes,
Speaker 4:  I do. And it was like two kids and they figured out how to build Macintosh's
Speaker 4:  and they did in early like internet marketing
Speaker 4:  campaign where like, take down the man run OSS 10 on yours side star, we
Speaker 4:  can do it. And they had all these like I would call them
Speaker 4:  Reddit caliber legal theories Yes. About how it would be legal and how
Speaker 4:  they would defeat Apple in court and they would, you know, I had a s side
Speaker 4:  star review, a S star for End Gadget. It was just a pc. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  it was, I was like, I was like, what am I supposed to review here? Like it
Speaker 4:  was just a noisy ass tower PC that like sometimes
Speaker 4:  boots up into OSS 10. That's what
Speaker 5:  I used
Speaker 4:  To build and sometimes does nothing. It it
Speaker 4:  was exciting. But they had all these theories that like if you owned a copy
Speaker 4:  of the operating system, you weren't committing copyright
Speaker 4:  infringement or breaching the contract by
Speaker 5:  That's what we would all say in the, it was like Tony Mack 86 X
Speaker 5:  forum Yeah. Or whatever. We'd all be like, oh yeah, yeah, we're we're fine
Speaker 5:  because we already own it. Like, I went out and I had, I had the physical
Speaker 5:  copy of each DV cd Yeah. For the OSS that you could have until they stopped
Speaker 5:  distributing 'em. And we were like, we got this. But we also generally,
Speaker 5:  unlike S Star, weren't charging for it.
Speaker 4:  No S star is like charging money and got but this, this is like, like folk
Speaker 4:  copyright law. Yeah. Like you've convinced yourself that if you just
Speaker 4:  buy the CD you can make, you can send as many MP threes to your
Speaker 4:  friends as you want. Yeah. It is.
Speaker 5:  Same thing with torrents. They're always like, no, no, we're fine. We're
Speaker 4:  Fine. Yeah. And it, and it is all just like you're, you are concocting like
Speaker 4:  a moral argument that somewhere some money has
Speaker 4:  changed hands. So, I can do whatever think
Speaker 5:  Clarence Thomas will ignore. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  It's Who knows what's gonna happen man.
Speaker 4:  But, but my end of mys star story is they, they pitched themselves a bunch
Speaker 4:  and they, you know, they were compelling. They were like young kids. They
Speaker 4:  started a business, they were taking on the man. They gotten all this attention
Speaker 4:  and some like local Florida Alt Weekly
Speaker 4:  wrote this piece about how they were taken on Apple and who knew what happened.
Speaker 4:  Oh. And So I wrote it up in Eng Gadget. I was like, I can't believe they
Speaker 4:  conned. I called, I called it a puff piece. Yeah. I was likes a big puff
Speaker 4:  piece about side star like fun. Look at these guys. But they're doomed.
Speaker 4:  And the reporter and I I was like a baby blogger. Yeah. The
Speaker 4:  reporter wrote me just like the most hammer email,
Speaker 4:  like, how dare you, I would never write a puff piece. These are
Speaker 4:  valid issues. And I was like, I don know how to break this to you. Like this
Speaker 4:  company's not gonna make like five minutes. And sure enough, apple sued them.
Speaker 4:  Then it went away immediately. And I was like, that was crazy. but it
Speaker 4:  was, it was all based on this argument that like, if you did one right thing
Speaker 4:  once, then you could do the wrong thing as many times as you wanted. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And I think the difference with Beeper is they're not using any of Apple's
Speaker 4:  code. Right? They're not, they're just sending Apple a number.
Speaker 4:  Right. That happens to be a serial number.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. That's tough. And the, the reverse engineering is legal
Speaker 6:  and protected. Like that is like a, a valid thing to do. It's particular,
Speaker 6:  particularly when it comes to enabling interoperability, which is like the
Speaker 6:  whole hinging thing here, enables interoperability for
Speaker 6:  iMessage on Android devices.
Speaker 4:  There is another law that could get in their way.
Speaker 4:  It's just like, it's there, it's always lurking in the background. It's like
Speaker 4:  one of the worst laws in the books. It's a computer fraud and abuse act
Speaker 4:  that says if you wrongfully gain access to a system that is
Speaker 4:  a criminal penalty.
Speaker 5:  Well, this was how all the bios, they would reverse engineer the bios
Speaker 5:  back in the eighties and you're like, had to be in a different room from
Speaker 5:  the people reverse engineering it. Right.
Speaker 6:  This is Cranz, this is a plot point of halt and catch fire.
Speaker 5:  It is a plot point, but it's also true. It really happened. That's why it
Speaker 5:  was such a good plot point, one
Speaker 6:  Of the best shows ever made. but it is a, a whole plot line of it. It's very
Speaker 6:  cool. I
Speaker 5:  Remember being really excited. I was like, they're doing it, they're doing
Speaker 5:  Bios law.
Speaker 6:  But you know, again, it's a, the, the technical side of this is really
Speaker 6:  kind of above my head, but Quinn over at snazzy q in his
Speaker 6:  breakdown video, and he, like, he installs the open source
Speaker 6:  code on a Linux laptop and connects to the protocol and like
Speaker 6:  does the thing as It works to show what it's doing behind the
Speaker 6:  like polished app that you see on Android. And it's really quite fascinating.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. He makes a point that spoofing the serial numbers does have
Speaker 6:  a number of legitimate use cases and there's no way for Apple
Speaker 6:  to know whether this serial number that you are sending them
Speaker 6:  is the 2015 iMac 21.5
Speaker 6:  inch model that it was originally, or it's your Android phone. So course
Speaker 6:  Apple can't tell that. So if Apple were to like turn
Speaker 6:  that off, it would break a lot of things for legitimate users. So that's
Speaker 6:  kind of where the the rub is.
Speaker 4:  But because the code is public, because the activity is public, apple could
Speaker 4:  certainly sue Beeper and say you are improperly
Speaker 4:  accessing the iMessage servers that you are not supposed to have access to.
Speaker 4:  And there is a long line of cases, like everything in America
Speaker 4:  have total coin flip outcomes once you hit the Supreme court.
Speaker 4:  Right. Like at and t won a case and the characters involved in
Speaker 4:  the case are somewhat unsavory. But at and t won a case for someone who
Speaker 4:  was just hitting the at t website to do lookups over and over again.
Speaker 4:  And that was A-C-F-A-A case. LinkedIn just lost a case to
Speaker 4:  an analytics company called hiq that was scraping the
Speaker 4:  LinkedIn database. And it's like, well that seems wrong with an IQ one. The
Speaker 4:  Supreme court just took another case where a police officer improperly did
Speaker 4:  a lookup, like someone paid him money to use the police database to do a
Speaker 4:  lookup. I don know, but he had, he was authorized to use the database. He
Speaker 4:  just did it in an unapproved way. And like you just, like, if there's a server
Speaker 4:  on the internet and you talk to it and it tells you something, there's a
Speaker 4:  million different ways to parse out whether that is legal or not legal.
Speaker 5:  So does, how big is beeper's legal fund, I think is the real question we
Speaker 5:  need to be asking
Speaker 4:  The que here's, there's a couple questions right next to this. The EU decided
Speaker 4:  this week that Apple did not have to treat iMessage
Speaker 4:  as a, a platform that has to be interoperable. Like did Meta
Speaker 4:  with WhatsApp, did
Speaker 5:  They decide or they just leaned in that I thought they've just leaned in
Speaker 5:  that direction.
Speaker 4:  They've signaled
Speaker 5:  Signaled Yeah.
Speaker 4:  European politics. There's a lot of signaling posturing. Yeah. You rotate
Speaker 4:  a piece of cheese
Speaker 5:  And everybody's like, yes, thank you, thank you, thank you so much.
Speaker 4:  It's like, oh, debris has turned to the left. Thank you. I message will not
Speaker 4:  be a gatekeeper service. Like that's like, it seems like that's not gonna
Speaker 4:  happen. That is almost certainly because
Speaker 4:  Apple agreed to adopt RRCs. Right, right. Which was the gambit. And
Speaker 4:  and I think we all saw that as the trade. Like there's the threat of this
Speaker 4:  big interop regulation. Or they could do RRCs and say, look, it's interoperable
Speaker 4:  this way. Great. They did it. So that's sort of the background here.
Speaker 4:  Like Apple's gonna say, look, there's an interoperable way it's coming, we're
Speaker 4:  gonna use it. Maybe only four people ever use paper and the, or maybe
Speaker 4:  they just, Apple's pretty litigious. Maybe they just send a threat to this
Speaker 4:  company and say, stop it. But the need to stop it
Speaker 4:  or Apple's desire to stop it is going to cause problems. Yeah. Because
Speaker 4:  they don't actually have the RCS implementation yet. And so
Speaker 4:  to say we we're gonna keep people locked out of our service while we work
Speaker 4:  on this other thing. I think it's just gonna be, and it's an indie developer
Speaker 4:  that's really well liked. It got a lot of press because a lot of Android
Speaker 4:  people in this country really wanna send high messages and they're gonna
Speaker 4:  pay Beeper $2 a month or whatever it is to, to do it. They should have solved
Speaker 4:  this problem a million years ago. They should have found a way to do this
Speaker 4:  on their terms a million years ago because now they're doing it on the terms
Speaker 4:  of the European Union and somewhat improbably on the terms
Speaker 4:  Kowski and Beeper Mini. Which is just weird.
Speaker 5:  It's a delight.
Speaker 4:  And this is a 16-year-old kid who reverse engineering the protocol and is
Speaker 4:  like spare time. Like that's a weird place for the richest company
Speaker 4:  in the world to be Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Go after that 16-year-old kid.
Speaker 4:  This is the thing, you wanna file the CFA lawsuit against the 16-year-old
Speaker 4:  kid for a reverse engineering thing. Like you're the bad guy. That's just
Speaker 4:  straight up. You're the bad
Speaker 5:  Guy. Yeah. I mean that's what Sony did, right? With the, I think it was a
Speaker 5:  PSS three.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. This is the legend of Geo of George Hots.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Yeah. Like mm. Don't maybe don't do that.
Speaker 4:  Well, the George Hots did work, it did work in Twitter for five minutes.
Speaker 4:  All. right. So that's that other big piece of news we should talk about this
Speaker 4:  week. It seems like podcast industry is in turmoil. Spotify just had
Speaker 4:  layoffs. They're canceling really popular shows, including a show that won
Speaker 4:  a Pulitzer Prize. They canceled Heavyweight, the title laid off 10 percent
Speaker 4:  of its staff. It just seems like in general podcasts,
Speaker 4:  they had the big tech moment where all the money from the big tech companies
Speaker 4:  particularly Spotify, rushed in. Yes. And now the Tide has
Speaker 5:  Come back out. It's like Spotify rushed in with zero plan. And
Speaker 5:  then when the, the gravy train like did not continue the plan,
Speaker 5:  continue the plan was celebrities. The plan was own this
Speaker 5:  entire industry as quickly as possible, like grow so fast,
Speaker 5:  so big that nobody can stop us and we're a Tidal wave. And then like,
Speaker 5:  we'll be supported by all our ad dollars and the ad dollars are like, no,
Speaker 5:  we're not gonna support you that much. Right.
Speaker 4:  And they bought an ad tech company. Yeah. And they wanted to do dynamic insertion
Speaker 4:  of ads because they were
Speaker 5:  Trying to own the whole ad tech industry side of Spotify
Speaker 4:  Disclosure. Our ads are served by Spotify, sadd tech platform,
Speaker 4:  megaphone
Speaker 5:  Disclosure. We're a podcast,
Speaker 4:  I don't even know what I'm disclosing there. Like someone uploads this to
Speaker 4:  this thing and we use it. Yeah. It's great. Someone else runs the ads, but
Speaker 4:  it's true. There's a disclosure. The whole story to me is they thought
Speaker 4:  they could take a big, rich, open ecosystem and
Speaker 4:  turn it into a very closed one. Yes. You could turn Spotify in
Speaker 4:  the open podcasting ecosystem into something that looked a lot more like
Speaker 4:  YouTube. And I, I think it just didn't work.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I, I a hundred percent agree. I think they, they fail. Like, and we
Speaker 5:  all kind of knew this, remember Ashley came on, Ashley Carmen now at Bloomberg
Speaker 5:  broke a lot of this stuff about Spotify,
Speaker 4:  Nobel Trader Ashley Carmen, yeah.
Speaker 5:  Horrible trader. But came on this very podcast like what, two years ago talking
Speaker 5:  about this. And we were all like, Ooh, this doesn't sound like it's gonna
Speaker 5:  work for Spotify. It feels like they're just ignoring everything else
Speaker 5:  about this and why this is a bad idea. It feels like we were All right. High
Speaker 5:  five all of us two years ago. Yes.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I mean obviously they've held onto Joe Rogan. His deal is up
Speaker 4:  for renewal. We have been told. So we're tracking That
Speaker 5:  Did not hold onto Prince Harry and Meghan,
Speaker 4:  Meghan and Harry didn't make it. You know, there's something interesting
Speaker 4:  there. You know, the, the tech industry loves Talk about going direct. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Like, loves to talk about going direct. You don't need these journalists
Speaker 4:  or Pepsi. And it's like if you go direct and you have nothing to say,
Speaker 4:  no one will listen to you and you will have gone direct to no one. Which
Speaker 4:  is truly the Harry and Meghan story. Like
Speaker 4:  they're out of things to say.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. They, they did the book. We were all like, thank you. This is actually
Speaker 5:  all we wanted from you. Yeah. We just wanted the tea.
Speaker 4:  And I'm not even someone who, like, I'm Indian American. My people
Speaker 4:  have fled the British twice. Like we just get out and I,
Speaker 4:  I do not care about any of this, but it's like even the people I know who
Speaker 4:  do care, and we have them on our staff, Liz Lippa and Sarah Jog love
Speaker 4:  some royal family drama and they're like, whatever we're done with this.
Speaker 4:  And like that to me is you need some tension
Speaker 4:  to tell a good story. Yeah. And like that's, you buy a bunch of the celebrities
Speaker 4:  directly, you're not gonna have any tension. Every celebrity podcast is like
Speaker 4:  a celebrity and then someone else just needling them. Well,
Speaker 5:  Or there's there, the new trend now is it's the d-list
Speaker 5:  celebrities that were on the shows with the really big folks. They all get
Speaker 5:  together and then talk trash about the big folks. Yeah. And then sometimes
Speaker 5:  talk about like how they slept with the entire cast. And you're like a lot
Speaker 5:  of Disney channel
Speaker 5:  your face. We're like, why don't get into the podcast
Speaker 5:  scene guys. There's so many, like Disney channel
Speaker 4:  Tells we're ending this podcast before we, before we go that way.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. We're we're, we won't do that. It's wild though. That's the new trend
Speaker 5:  for celebrity podcasts. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  All of that seems like it didn't work. Just to be clear. Like Spotify burned
Speaker 4:  millions of dollars in this. They torched Gimlet, which was a darling,
Speaker 4:  it was failing as a company. And obviously they sold the Spotify for
Speaker 4:  tons and tons of money that they had no plan themselves to, to gain because
Speaker 4:  they were failing as a company. So good, good on them. but it also broke
Speaker 4:  Gimlet. It broke reply all, it broke the culture of that company
Speaker 4:  at, at some point. Like the mergers are just bad. The acquisitions are
Speaker 4:  just bad. And I think this feels like they bought Gimlet, they bought podcast,
Speaker 4:  they bought Anchor, they bought Megaphone, and they had no plan to munge
Speaker 4:  them all to They bought the ringer. Yep. And the plan to mu them all together
Speaker 4:  seems like it just failed.
Speaker 5:  Yes.
Speaker 4:  But the stock is up and they turn their first ever profit. And it's like,
Speaker 4:  is that all that matters?
Speaker 5:  Ooh. If you, if you like money. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I think we're, I think we're, I don't think podcasts are going anywhere.
Speaker 4:  You can see some of 'em are still growing. You can see money is flowing to
Speaker 4:  some categories in them, but it, it feels like we're returning
Speaker 4:  to a much more sustainable place to grow the podcast industry. Yes.
Speaker 5:  It was very unsustainable for a while. And now it's gonna be like, we are
Speaker 5:  only gonna support podcasts where people actually say something interesting
Speaker 4:  Maybe just,
Speaker 5:  And, and also Joe Rogan
Speaker 4:  And then other thing, Spotify and all the other big podcast players are doing
Speaker 4:  is they're, they're focusing on chat shows.
Speaker 4:  Influencer, you know, the, the, the solo podcast where the
Speaker 4:  influencers just ranted the screen, but it looks like a podcast. Yeah. A
Speaker 4:  deeply fast. Like that's a media PhD.
Speaker 5:  That's gonna be my spinoff. If
Speaker 4:  There are any media, PhD, any media studies students that are pursuing a
Speaker 4:  media studies PhD, I would read your dissertation on the,
Speaker 4:  the one person podcast where they just talk the whole time.
Speaker 5:  What do they do?
Speaker 4:  I just, I I like to talk. Yeah, I do that. I
Speaker 4:  love it mean that's same. That's it's my favorite.
Speaker 6:  That's the AM radio model, right? Like that was the Rush Limbaugh model.
Speaker 6:  It was the Alex Jones model. Just talk to the microphone for three hours
Speaker 6:  straight.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I'm just dying to know in podcasting to
Speaker 4:  do that on your own and then to like close your laptop
Speaker 4:  lid and be like,
Speaker 5:  I did it. Good
Speaker 4:  Job. There's, there's something in there about like that personality making
Speaker 4:  that kind of content with that kind of distribution that I promise you as
Speaker 4:  a PhD thesis.
Speaker 5:  I'd
Speaker 4:  Read it like there's some feedback loop in there that I just want to know
Speaker 4:  more about.
Speaker 5:  Just send it to Neela. Send it to all of us. Honestly. I wanna read that
Speaker 5:  too.
Speaker 4:  Well do it. Go get your PhD. That's what I'm telling you. That's a good use
Speaker 4:  of money. And then title, obviously, obviously laying Off Its staff. Again,
Speaker 4:  another Jack Dorsey brilliantly managed company. Yeah. We love
Speaker 5:  It. It had Beyonce for a
Speaker 4:  While. It did. And then last piece of little media news and we'll take a
Speaker 4:  break. Apple is munging together. It's iTunes movies and TV shows
Speaker 4:  app into the proper Apple tv, TV app.
Speaker 4:  So now we have to use it.
Speaker 5:  And it was already sort of done that way. Yeah. So it's just like,
Speaker 5:  they're just like cleaning up the crumbs. Like the people who haven't
Speaker 5:  really touched their workflow in 20 years are gonna be like, oh no, how am
Speaker 5:  I gonna like watch my old Aquaman episodes from 2006?
Speaker 5:  That sucks for them. But also the rest of us have been living now
Speaker 5:  where you just use the one app.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I'm judging people.
Speaker 4:  What I'm doing is serious. What you mean is Plex Alex's Plex app?
Speaker 5:  No, it's the Apple TV app. Sure.
Speaker 4:  By the way, there was a, a piece of news this week. Very distressing. Sony's
Speaker 4:  just deleting TV shows that people bought. Yeah. On PlayStation accounts.
Speaker 5:  We're gonna talk
Speaker 4:  About it later. We'll take a break. We'll get back, we'll talk about that.
Speaker 4:  All right? We're back sliding around time. Tell us about the Sony thing.
Speaker 4:  Earlier
Speaker 5:  This week, a lot of PlayStation users noticed that they were just getting
Speaker 5:  banned out of the blue. Like not a lot of people say, oh, I'm getting
Speaker 5:  banned. I don't know what happened. And you're like, no, you do. This
Speaker 5:  wasn't the case. They were just like totally outright band. They didn't know
Speaker 5:  what was happening. It was a whole lot of people, which was the other part
Speaker 5:  of this. And so j Peters and Tom Warren looked into it and, and
Speaker 5:  eventually Sony was like, oops, our bad. And just slowly has been giving
Speaker 5:  everybody their account access back. And it was all just an accident. It
Speaker 5:  was just like a a a bug and they, they, they screwed up. but it also just
Speaker 5:  immediately reminded everyone, particularly when paired with the fact that
Speaker 5:  Sony also recently said, okay, a lot of this content you purchased from
Speaker 5:  Discovery Plus you will not have access to it anymore. We've changed some
Speaker 5:  of our licensing. It's just like a big reminder that you
Speaker 5:  don't own anything you buy digitally. Yeah. You, you don't own any of it.
Speaker 5:  It's not yours. It's all licenses. It's all fake owner ownership.
Speaker 5:  And and Sony just accidentally reminded their entire
Speaker 5:  like customer's base. Yeah. Which is not what you wanna do when you are
Speaker 5:  highly dependent on all of, on all of them buying shit on your,
Speaker 5:  your stores.
Speaker 4:  They just radicalize a lot of people into buying that dis drive.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Which is
Speaker 4:  Maybe this is all a plot to get people to buy external dis drive. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  They're just trying to like move those disk drives. I'm like, All. right.
Speaker 4:  You're losing all, if someone opened a closet, they're like, we have a lot
Speaker 4:  of Blu-ray drives
Speaker 4:  way more than we thought You guys
Speaker 5:  All. right. Pull the disco plus stuff. Let's go. We got this
Speaker 4:  Dr. Pimple popper's outta here. We gotta move these drives.
Speaker 5:  But Jay wrote a really great piece just kind of lamenting it and and he's
Speaker 5:  absolutely right. Don't, like, if you really wanna own something
Speaker 5:  and you wanna own it for a long time, don't just buy the digital version.
Speaker 5:  And a lot of times you can just go buy a DVD or a Blu-ray and get the digital
Speaker 5:  version. Then you have both Yeah. For the same amount of money. And
Speaker 4:  Look, I'm building a new home theater right now in the new house. Ooh. I'm
Speaker 4:  really thinking about putting a Blu-ray player in it. I don't know why
Speaker 5:  Do it. I I've got one. Use it once a year. I you just,
Speaker 4:  I know you do.
Speaker 5:  I plug it into my, my computer.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Use it once a year to rip legal media to your
Speaker 4:  Plex server. You
Speaker 5:  Know, it's, it's folk folk copyright law. And we don't need to talk about
Speaker 5:  it too much here.
Speaker 4:  I've got a Blueray player that's been running Mac OSS nine for a decade.
Speaker 4:  It's great. All. right. Dan, what's your lightning round?
Speaker 6:  I got two. Okay. Ooh. Can I do both now or, yeah. All. right. The first one
Speaker 6:  is, Allison did a review of the Razr,
Speaker 6:  which is not to be confused with the Razr plus it is Motorola's
Speaker 6:  budget flip phone. Turns out it's not a very good phone. I'm just gonna start
Speaker 6:  off by saying that, but what's really fascinating to me about it is
Speaker 6:  this is priced at 700 bucks and because Motorola discounts things
Speaker 6:  a hundred percent of the time, all the time, you can buy for $500,
Speaker 6:  which means this is a flip phone with a folding screen
Speaker 6:  for $500. Which is kind of like a fascinating thing to me that we are already
Speaker 6:  at that point of affordability of these kind of flip devices.
Speaker 6:  The cameras aren't great. The processors can be a little slow. The outside
Speaker 6:  screen is not very useful. It's not a phone I would recommend anyone buy,
Speaker 6:  but it's pretty cool that like we've gone from, these are all a thousand
Speaker 6:  or $1,400 to $500 in just a couple
Speaker 6:  years. So that was my first one. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  It's true. And we, we, the second that first Galaxy Fold came out, we're
Speaker 4:  like, oh, the cost curve on this is gonna go oop. Yeah. What's interesting
Speaker 4:  is the technology curve has kind of stopped,
Speaker 4:  right? Like the screens are better, they're more durable. That was the big
Speaker 4:  thing. But they look largely the same. They're
Speaker 5:  Still lumpy.
Speaker 4:  Well, there's lumpy, but even just like the way the materials look
Speaker 4:  and feel.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. They still are soft kind of plastic. Yeah. It doesn't feel like hard
Speaker 6:  glass. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And that was the, there was some, there was a lot of talk about bendy
Speaker 4:  glass in the beginning. Do you remember this? Yes.
Speaker 6:  Ultra thin glass. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Where is it? I wanna
Speaker 6:  See it. Well, it's all in there. It just, well the, the way they work is
Speaker 6:  there's a layer of ultra thin glass and then on top of that is a soft plastic
Speaker 6:  screen protector. And that's what you touch. Yeah. And that's what provides
Speaker 6:  that kind of not so great tactile experience.
Speaker 4:  As with most things, technology kind of like make it better and keep the
Speaker 4:  cost the same. Or you can make, keep it the same. Keep bring the cost down.
Speaker 4:  And we are very much on the keep it the same, bring the cost down part of
Speaker 4:  the curve. There's not the step change into the part.
Speaker 6:  Particularly for the flip designs. The fold designs are
Speaker 6:  still very expensive. The one plus open
Speaker 6:  came out earlier this year and that is available for around $1,500.
Speaker 6:  That's kinda like the low price for these folding
Speaker 6:  phones. But the flip phones, and I think it's part of
Speaker 6:  who these are marketed to, folding phones are marketed to like Uber,
Speaker 6:  do everything nerds like me. And then the flip phones are marketed to people
Speaker 6:  who want something a little bit more fashionable, a little bit more compact,
Speaker 6:  discreet, don't wanna spend 10 to 12 hours a day staring at
Speaker 6:  their phone like I do. And, and wanna make it more of like an intentional
Speaker 6:  device. And so they don't need the fastest processor, they don't need the
Speaker 6:  highest end camera system. They don't need the bills and whistles to run
Speaker 6:  decks and things like that. even that, I think Motorola lets
Speaker 6:  you run its version of Dex, which is called ready for on its flip phones.
Speaker 6:  So, hey, that's the thing you could do, Eli.
Speaker 4:  Hey, I wanna see that next doc with a Motorola flip.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, let's do it. Yeah. Bad camera, slow processor.
Speaker 4:  Great. Okay. You all knew this was gonna be my lightning round.
Speaker 4:  You knew it. There was no choice except for this story to
Speaker 4:  be my lightning round item, which is the photo of the woman in the, in the
Speaker 4:  bridal gown. Like
Speaker 5:  I saw it and I, I, as soon as the news broke, what, earlier this week, I
Speaker 5:  was like, Hmm,
Speaker 4:  You know what? I'm coming. The news broke a couple weeks ago. Did you? A
Speaker 4:  couple weeks ago. And then OpenAI happened and we forgot about it. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  So this photo, there's a photo of a woman she's trying on a wedding dress.
Speaker 4:  She's in the bridal shots. one of those, there's mirrors all around her.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Like you do. So you can see yourself from all the angles and she's
Speaker 4:  making a different pose in all the mirrors. And then in person, she's a British
Speaker 4:  comedian. She posted her Instagram story. She said, this is crazy. I've
Speaker 4:  never had anything like this happen. The immediate
Speaker 4:  theorizing about AI photo composites
Speaker 4:  started happening. Smart HDR, she said she went to the Apple store. Someone,
Speaker 4:  some Apple store employee told her this was Apple beta testing a competitor,
Speaker 4:  a best take on Google, which makes no sense.
Speaker 4:  This is all true. This all happened. Right. This is all in her Instagram
Speaker 4:  stories and Instagram post. Yeah. Tom Warren, because she's in the UK. Tom
Speaker 4:  Warren reached out to her. I was like, we gotta get the actual photo we got.
Speaker 4:  And then he reached out to her, he got the photo, we were talking
Speaker 4:  about it. Then the opening eye news broke. Tom is our Microsoft
Speaker 4:  reporter. He and I got very distracted, very busy. We stopped
Speaker 4:  paying attention to the woman in her wedding dress for a minute. The, the
Speaker 4:  Post came back this week. People saw it
Speaker 4:  again, all the same amount of theorizing that happened, people calling it
Speaker 4:  fake, a publicity, not social media. And she said, and we had
Speaker 4:  the file and nothing about the file indicates that it's fake. Okay. Like
Speaker 4:  we were, Tom was sent the uncompressed un
Speaker 4:  seemingly unaltered original photo off the iPhone. And we were
Speaker 4:  looking at it, we were trying to figure out, we were like gone to ask Apple
Speaker 4:  because it is very odd Yeah. That she's making three
Speaker 4:  different poses in the mirrors. And so everyone's trying to like figure this
Speaker 4:  out. Again, a lot of people claiming that it's fake. It turns
Speaker 4:  out someone else had taken the photo and they had the camera
Speaker 4:  accidentally in Panorama mode. Oh yeah. So it actually did stitch together
Speaker 4:  several frames across to make it panorama. But if you
Speaker 4:  don't move the camera enough and You don't get a wide enough picture,
Speaker 4:  the iPhone does not append the Panorama label. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Oh. The only tell, and I, I, I think
Speaker 6:  there's a YouTuber, I Fondo, his name is Farouk. He's the one who kind of
Speaker 6:  like popularized or, or, or, or told the world about this
Speaker 6:  reasoning how it worked. But the only tell is that the resolution of the
Speaker 6:  final image is not the same as the resolution that is captured
Speaker 6:  by the sensor. And so the photos app does not
Speaker 6:  say Panorama because it's not a panoramic view. It's too
Speaker 6:  tall and narrow. It's a vertically composed shot, but the
Speaker 6:  pixels are different. And so that is like the tell there that is in panoramic
Speaker 6:  mode. Farouk was able to replicate this very quickly as soon as
Speaker 6:  he figured that out by putting his phone in panoramic mode and like doing
Speaker 6:  a very, like a, a another shot just that same way and was able to
Speaker 6:  replicate it in instantly. So it's, it's kind of fascinating. What's really
Speaker 6:  fascinating to me is like the stitching is like perfect. Which
Speaker 4:  Is like, because the cam 'cause the camera isn't moving. Yeah. I didn't
Speaker 5:  Know you could do that. I thought like you, because it always is like, move
Speaker 5:  the camera. That's what my phone sounds like to me. But it's, it's always
Speaker 5:  telling me to move the camera. So I'm always like, do I
Speaker 6:  Think it just tells that Alex that tells you how well people follow directions
Speaker 6:  on their devices when they're just
Speaker 5:  Mashing button. Can I just ignore that?
Speaker 6:  You could just ignore it. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  One Apple should just label all Panorama photos as panoramas. Yeah. That
Speaker 4:  seems like an easy fix to the solution. But two, the
Speaker 4:  expectation that AI is just gonna munge with reality
Speaker 4:  is everywhere now.
Speaker 5:  Well, I don't think the expectation is, the reality is like that, that that's
Speaker 5:  the reality of the situation. But like, I think people are still, because
Speaker 5:  that's why everybody thought it was a fake. 'cause everybody's like, you're
Speaker 5:  a liar. You did this on purpose, you used Photoshop or, or Panorama or
Speaker 5:  whatever. And it's like, no, she just accidentally did it. Yeah. Like,
Speaker 4:  But even if you, even if you think this is the world's greatest publicity
Speaker 4:  stunt Yeah. Targeted to a very small community, very
Speaker 5:  Small group.
Speaker 4:  It relies on an understanding that AI
Speaker 4:  exists Mm. And is doing photo stuff. Mm.
Speaker 5:  That's true. That's true.
Speaker 4:  Right? It's not like it's either ghosts in the building, like No, no. It's
Speaker 4:  like, oh, the, the iPhone cameras AI took this
Speaker 4:  completely unbelievable picture and it AI generated you. And
Speaker 4:  like people will believe that that's true. Yeah. And a lot of people believe
Speaker 4:  that it's true. Such that other people were debunking it like the whole thing.
Speaker 4:  And in the meantime it was a totally different lane Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Of photography. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  'cause because a lot of the theories were around it was doing that thing
Speaker 5:  where it chooses the best shot of you and it just happened to assume she
Speaker 5:  was three different people. Right.
Speaker 4:  It, the mirror had confused sort of like some sort of like best take. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  But Apple smarty share does not work like this at all. And even Google Best
Speaker 4:  Take does not work like this at all. Apple smarty share stacks seven frames
Speaker 4:  in like half a second. She would've had to move her hands so fast.
Speaker 5:  Just
Speaker 4:  Like, like totally insanely too fast. Like that's why I was like, we gotta
Speaker 4:  get the original file. There's no way that an iPhone just generate this.
Speaker 4:  'cause I was not thinking about Panorama mode. Yeah. So it's a Photoshop.
Speaker 4:  We, we might have been able to tell, but the thing that got me was she sent
Speaker 4:  it to Tom right away. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Tom
Speaker 4:  Reached it's weird. Reached out and she was like, here you go. And that,
Speaker 4:  that like, to me like you are a reporter long enough. Like, oh, there's some
Speaker 4:  things where if there's a hesitation there. Yeah. It's like you
Speaker 4:  only can get a compressed one then you're like, is
Speaker 5:  This off the
Speaker 4:  Record? And then you blame WhatsApp. Like there's all this stuff that usually
Speaker 4:  happens. Yeah. When you request an original and she was just like, here you
Speaker 4:  go. Okay. So I was like All. right. There's something here that don don't
Speaker 4:  understand and the, the panorama. What is interesting, the, the thing that's
Speaker 4:  truly fascinating to me is that the culture is ready to
Speaker 4:  receive AI fakery as an explanation for anything.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And like, I'm just telling the, the what is a photo apocalypse is like well
Speaker 4:  and truly here because you can tell anyone
Speaker 4:  that a photo has been AI faked and they, the chances of
Speaker 4:  them believing you are just steadily going up. Yeah. Even if it doesn't turn
Speaker 4:  out to be the case.
Speaker 5:  That's one of my, all my photos now are gonna be fakes. You don't know.
Speaker 4:  They already
Speaker 5:  Are. They already are. I haven't taken a real photo in 20 years. All. right.
Speaker 4:  I've got a couple other ones just to go through quickly.
Speaker 4:  One, this is maybe my favorite story of the year. Windows
Speaker 4:  has an issue that is just renaming printers to HP LaserJet across the board.
Speaker 5:  The only printer you need.
Speaker 4:  It's a very good, it's just
Speaker 5:  Advertising.
Speaker 4:  It's like, will AI kill us all? Or will the HP smart app
Speaker 4:  worm, its away under literally every computer on the planet and like begin
Speaker 4:  taking out centrifuges
Speaker 5:  And buying ink
Speaker 4:  And buying ink. Like the problem isn't paperclips, the problem is in cartridges.
Speaker 4:  So Microsoft says it's looking into it. It's Windows 10 11 printers being
Speaker 4:  randomly renamed to HP LaserJet. Some issues related to printer
Speaker 4:  configurations are being observed on Windows devices which have access to
Speaker 4:  the store. It's just very good.
Speaker 5:  It's so good.
Speaker 4:  Everyone just has the HP smart app. Now your printer isn an HP LaserJet and
Speaker 4:  that's, you're gonna like it.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. We, we do say buy a laser printer, but we usually say
Speaker 5:  brother, not not
Speaker 4:  Official statement. Most printers are being named as HP LaserJet M
Speaker 4:  1 0 1 dash M 1 0 6. The icons might also be changed.
Speaker 4:  It's
Speaker 5:  Oh, that's so
Speaker 4:  Good. It's very good. Then just real quickly,
Speaker 4:  we are gonna cover Epic VGO in much more detail on the Wednesday show. Sean
Speaker 4:  Hollister will be on the show. He's been in the courtroom, but this
Speaker 4:  is really important for this case. Google has gotten himself into an
Speaker 4:  enormous amount of trouble with this judge for deleting records throughout
Speaker 4:  this case.
Speaker 5:  Ooh. That's a no-no. Like an
Speaker 4:  Enormous amount of trouble. The judge is furious. Last Friday, he said he
Speaker 4:  would investigate Google personally for quote, intentionally and
Speaker 4:  systematically suppressing evidence. He called it a frontal assault
Speaker 4:  on the Fair Administration of justice. And he said, I'm gonna get to the
Speaker 4:  bottom of who is responsible on my own outside this trial. Yo
Speaker 4:  I, don Dunno what kind of,
Speaker 5:  I like, I I've been in, I've, I've been in enough companies that are, that
Speaker 5:  are like getting lawsuits and stuff. When you're told to retain all your
Speaker 5:  records that you just never think to not, you're just like,
Speaker 5:  yeah, and, and my mess is gonna be out there.
Speaker 4:  And Sundar was asking like, can I set this chat to auto delete? They were
Speaker 4:  deleting stuff left and right. They admitted in court that they were
Speaker 4:  just deleting stuff. At one point the judge called in Google's
Speaker 4:  general counsel and made him answer to why these policies were, he's furious
Speaker 4:  about this. That's great. I will investigate this on my own outside this
Speaker 4:  trial. It's a very funny threat. Like, he's gonna get a magnifying glass,
Speaker 4:  start walking his ropes off. He's he puts on a leather jacket. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Little fedora. And he's like,
Speaker 4:  Let's go. He's like a seventies bad cop. You know, it's gonna
Speaker 4:  Your
Speaker 5:  Driving his old ass car. Exactly.
Speaker 4:  He's like, he's got a muscle. He's got a GTO and a magnifying glass. He's
Speaker 4:  like, where are the records? don don't know what that will lead to. But
Speaker 4:  importantly, he has told the jury,
Speaker 4:  not that they have to, but they may infer
Speaker 4:  wrongdoing on the part of Google if there's a question that the missing records
Speaker 4:  would've answered.
Speaker 5:  Okay.
Speaker 4:  Right. So he's, and and that's like a pretty loaded suggestion.
Speaker 5:  I was like that. I mean it's like, well that's fair, but also, Ooh, that's
Speaker 5:  bad for Google.
Speaker 4:  Right. So the the idea here is that the, the jury is gonna consider, and
Speaker 4:  it really, it really seems like Google might lose this case.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. In a way that maybe at the end of Apple, you know, I I still think
Speaker 4:  Epic walked away with one important, just the way the legal
Speaker 4:  system works. They want a bunch of stuff and they want to appeal whatever.
Speaker 4:  But Apple is like, we just run our business and that's it. Google, there's
Speaker 4:  all this evidence and there's much deleted evidence. All this stuff. It
Speaker 4:  really seems like epic mounted a much stronger case with Google. Yeah. And
Speaker 4:  now the jury is being sent and they are allowed to
Speaker 4:  infer whatever Google was hiding was bad. Which is a
Speaker 4:  just a big deal. It might come to nothing. It might not come to nothing.
Speaker 4:  It's just worth noting the judge is furious. Like this is the
Speaker 4:  shadiest thing Google has done and the judge is furious about it and he has
Speaker 4:  told the jury about it
Speaker 5:  And it's gonna make all the, the appeals really messy to I 'cause I just
Speaker 5:  assumed they will all be appealed. Whatever the decision is.
Speaker 4:  Oh, whatever the decision is appealed. It, it all just, what you appeal is
Speaker 4:  the law. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Okay.
Speaker 4:  So the facts remain the facts. And so
Speaker 5:  Just, and this is why you don't delete your records. Right? Yeah.
Speaker 5:  'cause this will happen.
Speaker 4:  Right. But the, an appeals court does not to get, to go back and say,
Speaker 4:  the jury's finding a fact we wrong.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Right.
Speaker 4:  They get to say that the law is wrong and we should change the law or like
Speaker 4:  this other thing. Okay. So that's, that's a little, it's a little law schooly,
Speaker 5:  Technical All. right. I see it. I see the text.
Speaker 4:  But so here the inference of the jury was you might appeal, this was a wrong
Speaker 4:  inference to give the jury or whatever, but he didn't, he didn't
Speaker 4:  instruct them to think one way or another. He said they were just allowed
Speaker 4:  to, which is a very important instruction. Anyway. I would just say the Epic
Speaker 4:  v Google case, we're gonna talk about much more with Sean on Wednesday.
Speaker 4:  Get into it. But that was the one that stuck out to me this week is like,
Speaker 4:  oh, there's something there. All. right. And then the last one I just wanna
Speaker 4:  call out Alison Johnson, second call for her today has a
Speaker 4:  big piece as part of our infrastructure package about just 5G
Speaker 4:  and the fact that it hasn't paid off for anyone.
Speaker 4:  And she, she basically listened to all the big carriers earnings calls
Speaker 4:  and talk and how they're talking about their investments, what the investors
Speaker 4:  want. There's nothing there. Like, it's basically like they
Speaker 4:  might compete with fixed broadband. So you, instead of having
Speaker 4:  whatever ISP you have, you might get a 5G fixed wireless device. They
Speaker 4:  seem excited about that. They're excited about enterprise customers buying
Speaker 4:  fixed 5G networks, which is hard 'cause you gotta have an enterprise
Speaker 4:  sales team, which many of them don't. And then they can do what Verizon is
Speaker 4:  calling pricing actions. Hmm.
Speaker 5:  Which
Speaker 4:  Means one thing, I hate it. The action is turning the price
Speaker 4:  up. That's the action you can take.
Speaker 5:  You know what we can do? You got faster internet now you pay a hundred dollars
Speaker 5:  more. Enjoy.
Speaker 4:  I will remind everyone, we actually got a note this week about Project Jenna
Speaker 4:  Fivey, the ill faded attempt to turn Dish Network into a mobile
Speaker 4:  carrier. Still
Speaker 5:  Technically a,
Speaker 4:  They they have it. They've, I believe Allison points this
Speaker 4:  out. They've technically hit their coverage goals, but they've done it by
Speaker 4:  leasing space on at and t and T-Mobile's network. So they have not actually
Speaker 4:  built a nationwide wireless network.
Speaker 5:  It's just Mitchell.
Speaker 4:  It's just Mitchell. He's out there on the trail.
Speaker 4:  Our own wonderful Mitchell Clark, who we tried desperately to use Project
Speaker 4:  Gen five sis. We, this whole thing was a boondoggle. Yeah. It
Speaker 4:  cost a lot of money. It put all these carriers in debt. It consolidated us
Speaker 4:  down from four to three, well, three and project Gen five sis.
Speaker 4:  And now we're doing pricing actions. Like we should just see it for what
Speaker 4:  it is. You can read Allison's piece link to it. It is great. It is very
Speaker 4:  clear-eyed and direct about what has happened in a way that is not
Speaker 4:  just me ranting and raving and like makes the argument really well. It's
Speaker 4:  good. You should read it. Send it to all your friends
Speaker 5:  In Lena
Speaker 4:  Khan and then whatever carrier you have, switch to another one.
Speaker 4:  That's, that's my advice. That's my end of the year advice for our chat listeners.
Speaker 4:  Whatever you have, just switch to another one. Make 'em all Feel it. Be like,
Speaker 4:  why is this happening?
Speaker 5:  Oh, just do the churn. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Just turn 'em up.
Speaker 5:  Churn moment. It's a churn moment. Let's do it. Just
Speaker 4:  We I'm just saying we just gotta create the appearance of some competition.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I I really, I'm excited to go to at t
Speaker 5:  I'm not
Speaker 4:  No, it, I mean I'm, I'm just thinking about this advice that
Speaker 5:  Seems hard. You're like, no, don't actually do that. I don
Speaker 4:  Don't just do whatever feels right in your heart. That's The, Verge Chest,
Speaker 4:  everybody. That's my message this holiday season. Whatever's in your heart,
Speaker 4:  do it. Oh, speaking of the holidays by the way. Yeah. Holiday spectacular
Speaker 4:  coming up again. We've done HTMI,
Speaker 4:  we've done Bluetooth
Speaker 5:  Failed at Jeopardy.
Speaker 4:  We did not do a good job with Bluetooth jeopardy this year by
Speaker 4:  just popular demand, just wave of demand. The
Speaker 4:  Vergecast, holiday spectacular is USBC. Yes. We've got the
Speaker 4:  guests lined up. We got the ideas, we got the plug Fest
Speaker 4:  coming and we're gonna do another game show this year because Andrew
Speaker 4:  insists that we do a game show.
Speaker 4:  I believe it's the price is right. Are we allowed to say the
Speaker 4:  Yeah. We're allowed to say it's a game show. That is not,
Speaker 4:  it's not The price is right. If
Speaker 5:  Don don't have a a giant wheel,
Speaker 4:  We're gonna up the ante this year. All of us are gonna be playing for one
Speaker 4:  of you, a Vergecast listener and whoever wins, it's a big bag of swag.
Speaker 4:  So here's what we need from you call the hotline. Eight six six Verge. One
Speaker 4:  one. That's 8 6 6 8 3 7 4 3 1 1.
Speaker 4:  Tell us your name and your favorite USBC gadget. We'll
Speaker 4:  put all the names in a hat. We'll pick 'em out. We'll play we'll.
Speaker 4:  We'll, we'll do it. We're gonna
Speaker 5:  Compete for you.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I'll represent you. Alex will represent someone else. So I'm so sorry.
Speaker 4:  And then whoever wins gets a big bag of Verge merch.
Speaker 5:  I'm actually doing a lot of USB research right
Speaker 4:  Now. it actually, this just says some VERGE merch, so whoever, it's some
Speaker 4:  VERGE merch.
Speaker 5:  Could be a
Speaker 4:  Small bag.
Speaker 5:  Depends on how bad your person does. I've,
Speaker 6:  I've seen the merch. The merch is good. It's quality merch,
Speaker 6:  so it'll be a good price.
Speaker 5:  Are you prepping to to, to help your, your listener? Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I'm, I'm reading all up. I'm gonna know some specs. Oh boy. I'm gonna
Speaker 5:  know what OMS mean.
Speaker 4:  All right. She's got it.
Speaker 5:  I'm ready. Let's go. I got
Speaker 4:  You. Alex is gonna do some high school level electrical
Speaker 4:  research. It's gonna be amazing. No, that's it. That's come out the USBC
Speaker 4:  holiday spectacular. one of our silliest yearly traditions
Speaker 4:  back and forth. The USBC. Tell us your favorite USBC gadget.
Speaker 4:  8 6 6 of Virgin one. One. We'll pick some people, we'll play for them
Speaker 4:  The winner. Get some merch. Sounds pretty good. Call the number. That's it.
Speaker 4:  That's The Vergecast Rock and Roll.
Speaker 1:  And that's a wrap for Vergecast this week. Hey, we'd love to hear from you.
Speaker 1:  Give us a call at eight six six Verge one. One The Vergecast
Speaker 1:  is a production of The Verge and Vox Media Podcast Network. The show is
Speaker 1:  produced by Andrew Marino and Liam James. This episode was mixed and edited
Speaker 1:  by Xander Adams. And that's it. We'll see you next week.