# Transcript
ID: c6ca85ad-7743-4f0d-988f-543d7c3cfcc1
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Epic wins for Epic and Threads
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-7601938200899659870/-3255251823125914435/s93290-US-6257s-1702647337.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, David Pierce, and Alex Cranz discuss Apple responding to Beeper's iMessage for Android and the various other text-based platform news from this week.
Sean Hollister joins the show to discuss his time covering the Epic v Google trial, and what we learned from it all.
Speaker 4:  Hello and Welcome To The Vergecast, America's number one source of cyber
Speaker 4:  sruck wiper news. Breaking news on The Vergecast. Today, the cyber sruck
Speaker 4:  wiper is one blade. It will cost $79 to replace and the entire assembly,
Speaker 4:  I believe will cost 169 4 20.
Speaker 4:  I actually dunno the second one.
Speaker 5:  That sounds right though.
Speaker 1:  I fully believe that.
Speaker 5:  I was like, yeah, that's, that sounds like
Speaker 1:  Accurate. Oh God, what have we become?
Speaker 4:  I'm, I'm your friend. Neli. That's David. Pierce having an existential crisis.
Speaker 4:  Alex Cranz is here.
Speaker 5:  I I'm your friend that also believes that's the right price. That sounds
Speaker 5:  right.
Speaker 4:  I don't think you can price something at 420 cents. I don't think. I just
Speaker 4:  wanna, there's a tell in there.
Speaker 5:  You can you just like, you put an asterisk next to it.
Speaker 4:  All. right. Two things about the cyber track wiper. Before we begin the show,
Speaker 4:  there's a lot to talk about. There's a huge week for low stakes apple drama.
Speaker 4:  I will say
Speaker 4:  Threads officially launched ActivityPub support in minor ways. You can,
Speaker 4:  we should talk about that. That's a big deal. And then big news of
Speaker 4:  the week. Maybe the year, maybe the century. Google lost
Speaker 4:  the antitrust case with Epic. Epic won the antitrust case against
Speaker 4:  Google. Sean. Hollister was in the courtroom every day. He interviewed Tim
Speaker 4:  Sweeney at the end of it. He's gonna join the show. We're gonna talk all
Speaker 4:  about what happened there and what it means. And then of course we don't
Speaker 4:  have a lightning round. But let's begin with the cyber truck wiper, which
Speaker 4:  is why that's good. Do
Speaker 1:  The most important news at the top.
Speaker 4:  That's good. Which is why the people are here.
Speaker 4:  So many, many, many people sent me Jason ESSA's
Speaker 4:  video of the truck on launch day. I think I've mentioned ha
Speaker 4:  on the channel before. This is like a great YouTube channel. Jason's really
Speaker 4:  good. That video is very controversial. 'cause it is fawning, it is just
Speaker 4:  a fawning look at the cyber truck and you can, whatever.
Speaker 4:  You can have whatever feelings about that and, and in that video, in that
Speaker 4:  moment, sure. In that video he
Speaker 4:  waves around a cyber truck wiper on his lap. It shows
Speaker 4:  that it's one blade, but it's all fly. It's like I just didn't wanna, I couldn't
Speaker 4:  engage with it. You know what I mean? Did you
Speaker 6:  Just almost say the phrase floppy blade and decide to
Speaker 6:  run away from that?
Speaker 4:  Just do you see where, do you see where I'm at with it?
Speaker 5:  Yeah,
Speaker 4:  I do. So the evidence that it was one single blade was there
Speaker 4:  at the launch day when the videos from Marquez and Jason came out and, and
Speaker 4:  I think MotorTrend had one too. I just couldn't, I couldn't be
Speaker 4:  like, this is what solved the mystery. I just, I in my heart, do you know,
Speaker 4:  do, do you know? Do you know what I mean? A
Speaker 5:  Floppy blade can't solve a mystery. I, I understand. Yes, I understand.
Speaker 6:  After all this work, it's just a floppy blade.
Speaker 4:  So then this week and you know, people are sending it to me and I app, I
Speaker 4:  appreciate all of the cyber truck wiper detectives out there this week. The
Speaker 4:  parts manual for the cyber truck went online. Yeah. What's interesting about
Speaker 4:  it is some people can see prices in it and we cannot,
Speaker 4:  oh, so Umar Shaki and her staff has a Tesla model three logged in with his
Speaker 4:  account, can't see the prices on Twitter. People are going through it and
Speaker 4:  they can see the prices. Hmm. There's a discrepancy there. We're digging
Speaker 4:  into why. Well, if you know why, please email us at first cast@theriggers.com.
Speaker 4:  But in there, cyber shop wiper single blade seven $9, which
Speaker 4:  in the grand scheme of luxury vehicle wiper
Speaker 4:  blades is not that high. But I would just ask you to look into your heart,
Speaker 4:  imagine a triangle and decide if you think the cyber truck wiper
Speaker 4:  should cost as much as like A-B-M-W-M three wiper.
Speaker 4:  You just tell me don don't know the answer to that question.
Speaker 5:  I mean A BMW. Yes, it should. Wow. Same kind of person.
Speaker 4:  Rough. And that's very fast. Everybody. That's Alex Cranz. It's Alex.
Speaker 4:  Do Cranz The Verge dot com.
Speaker 5:  You all read Idiots and cars on Reddit. You
Speaker 5:  know what I'm saying?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. How much does the turn signal stock cost though, to be All? right.
Speaker 4:  I do read it. Anyway, that's the cyber truck wiper news, we believe based
Speaker 4:  on the available evidence. And it is a single floppy blade.
Speaker 4:  don don't know man. I just, I, you watch the video, there's a video of marque
Speaker 4:  driving it through the rain and his video's really good, but you should watch
Speaker 4:  'em all. It's fine. even that Jason one's really fun though. The production
Speaker 4:  value is very high.
Speaker 4:  He's, he's wiping and you can see it bending. Is it
Speaker 4:  wipes? And then you're like, if anything, if there's something
Speaker 4:  other than rain, for example, snow or ice
Speaker 4:  is the thing just gonna bend at the halfway point? don
Speaker 4:  don't know man. I don don't know. It's like a scoop. This, I don't wanna
Speaker 4:  review this truck at all. I understand there's four wheel steering under
Speaker 4:  it and it's 48 vol. I understand it's steer by wire. There's
Speaker 4:  technology. You can hit it with a hammer. Whatever you want. I just
Speaker 4:  want to use the wiper and if anybody can hook Alexis Hanian,
Speaker 4:  I'm talking to you bud. One, can I meet your wife two,
Speaker 4:  can I, can I try your cyber trucks? Right.
Speaker 6:  This is once again getting into Eli's forever vision
Speaker 6:  of reviewing cars without ever going anywhere in them. Like Neli just
Speaker 6:  wants to sit inside of a car that is not going anywhere and review it that
Speaker 6:  way.
Speaker 4:  Just push, push all the buttons sequentially. It will be great. All, right?
Speaker 4:  That's the cyber truck update for this week. Once again, The Verge is your
Speaker 4:  number one source of Cybert truck wiper news. And it's all thanks to listeners
Speaker 4:  like you Vergecast at The Verge dot com. All, right?
Speaker 4:  Big week for low stakes Twitter drama or yeah, big week for low stakes Apple
Speaker 4:  drama. Although I think if you're on Apple's security team,
Speaker 4:  maybe this isn't so low stakes for you, David, tell the people what is going
Speaker 4:  on with Beeper Mini and iMessage.
Speaker 6:  Okay, so last week you guys
Speaker 6:  were on the pod talking about this new app, Beeper Mini that came out from
Speaker 6:  this company Beeper, that if you listen to Vergecast, you've heard us talk
Speaker 6:  about a few times. It's like a universal messaging app. And they had come
Speaker 6:  out with a new app called BER Mini for Android that made you
Speaker 6:  completely, seamlessly a blue bubble on iOS.
Speaker 6:  Big Deal meant you could send native iMessages to iPhone users, it would
Speaker 6:  fix your group chats. Like huge win. Everybody got very excited.
Speaker 6:  Apple
Speaker 6:  didn't say anything when it came out. Has not really said anything over months
Speaker 6:  about these apps in general. Like beeper's been kind of making noise about
Speaker 6:  how it's hacking iMessage for a while. text.com is a thing that exists Sunbird
Speaker 6:  and nothing did that weird thing not that long ago. Apple really hasn't said
Speaker 6:  anything and I and others on our team have been pestering Apple for weeks
Speaker 6:  to say something about this like this it, if Apple is the
Speaker 6:  security focused company, it believes it is, it should have something to
Speaker 6:  say about whether these are a good idea or not. We didn't hear anything for
Speaker 6:  a long time. And then last
Speaker 6:  Friday, right after you guys published The Vergecast, because
Speaker 6:  the news is a fun and fickle thing, it started to become clear that
Speaker 6:  Beeper Mini was not working anymore. People couldn't send messages. And
Speaker 6:  the ongoing assumption was that Apple had found a way to shut it down. The
Speaker 6:  Beeper team starts like furiously try to fix it. Eric Midkowski, the
Speaker 6:  founder, is talking to pe everyone he can find who will listen to
Speaker 6:  him about why Apple should not shut this down, why it's good for the world,
Speaker 6:  why it's making things more secure, even for iPhone users. On and on and
Speaker 6:  on on Saturday as I'm sitting in the
Speaker 6:  HyperX eSports arena in Las Vegas waiting for the World
Speaker 6:  Excel championships, which is a thing I'm sure we will talk more about in
Speaker 6:  the future.
Speaker 6:  I get a, I get a note from Apple saying finally we have something to say.
Speaker 6:  And basically what Apple did was confirm that they took steps to shut
Speaker 6:  down Bieber Mini and kind of without saying in exactly those
Speaker 6:  words said they intend to keep doing so. And
Speaker 6:  that has sparked this whole fight where Beeper then spent the next few days
Speaker 6:  trying to get back up and running. Apple seems to have kind of taken
Speaker 6:  steps to shut it down again after it got up and running. Beeper got a version
Speaker 6:  of it that was still functional but less impressive where you still had to
Speaker 6:  use an Apple ID and you were only messaging from your email, not your phone
Speaker 6:  number. So it's kind of a half measure. And basically we're now in this like
Speaker 6:  cat and mouse game where Beeper is both like on principle and
Speaker 6:  for the sake of its product, deeply committed to the idea of getting
Speaker 6:  iMessage working. And Apple has made very clear that it is not going to allow
Speaker 6:  that to happen. And it's perfectly possible that
Speaker 6:  things will change eight more times between when I'm saying this and when
Speaker 6:  you hear this podcast. But as of right now, that's where we stand, like two
Speaker 6:  sides fundamentally at odds. And neither one really has even
Speaker 6:  a move to back down at this point.
Speaker 4:  Lemme just read this statement from Apple 'cause I think it's fascinating.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And again, this was sent to David while he was at the Excel World
Speaker 4:  Championships and he messaged me at what I believe was 9:00 PM
Speaker 4:  on a Friday night saying, can you edit this? I'm at, I'm in Las Vegas.
Speaker 4:  Just an incredible message. Teresa
Speaker 4:  All. right? Here's the whole statement from from Apple. At Apple we build
Speaker 4:  our products and services with industry leading privacy and security technologies
Speaker 4:  designed to give users control of their data and keep personal information
Speaker 4:  safe. We took steps to protect our users by blocking
Speaker 4:  techniques that exploit fake credentials in order to gain access to
Speaker 4:  iMessage. These techniques post significant risk to user security and
Speaker 4:  privacy, including the potential for metadata exposure and enabling
Speaker 4:  unwanted messages, spam and phishing attacks. We will continue
Speaker 4:  to make updates in the future to protect our user. So this
Speaker 4:  is a really interesting statement to me. One,
Speaker 4:  it exists.
Speaker 4:  That's, that's something, it's not nothing, right? Yeah.
Speaker 6:  We, people should know this is worth saying out loud. I'm sure we have said
Speaker 6:  this in the past, but like we ask Apple to comment on things that
Speaker 6:  happen in and around the Apple world all the time. And
Speaker 6:  the vast majority of the time we get absolutely nothing.
Speaker 6:  Occasionally we will get a, like we decline a comment and then you get that
Speaker 6:  like canned statement that Apple says every once in a while when they acquire
Speaker 6:  a company that's just like Apple acquires companies from time to time and
Speaker 6:  just not generally a comment on the murder of acquisitions. So yeah,
Speaker 6:  the very existence of a multiple sentence comment from Apple
Speaker 6:  is unbelievably
Speaker 4:  Unusual. Yeah. So that's just one thing. Like the amount the, the amount
Speaker 4:  of pure signal from this statement existing is very high. Yeah. Apple felt
Speaker 4:  like it needed to shut this down. It felt like it needed to explain why.
Speaker 4:  And you know, you, everyone knows about our background rules. We said put
Speaker 4:  a name on it and they put a name on it. Great.
Speaker 4:  Then it explains how they blocked it,
Speaker 4:  which is super interesting, right? There's a level of technical
Speaker 4:  detail in here. They block techniques that exploit fake credentials
Speaker 4:  in order to gain access to iMessage. I'll come back to that. Then it
Speaker 4:  explains why Beeper is dangerous in Apple's view.
Speaker 4:  They, they don't have to do that, right? There's something in there
Speaker 4:  where Apple felt like they have to say there are risks to security
Speaker 4:  and privacy and what those risks are. Metadata,
Speaker 4:  metadata exposure, enabling unwanted messages, spam and phishing attacks.
Speaker 4:  This is vastly more information than anyone actually needs.
Speaker 4:  Or that honestly that Apple is like these are their servers.
Speaker 4:  You can feel however you want to, but one
Speaker 4:  totally legitimate avenue for Apple to
Speaker 4:  take here is to say, we locked down access to our servers or our servers
Speaker 4:  go away. And Apple has done things like that
Speaker 4:  a million times. Yeah. Like we're having this conversation in
Speaker 4:  the context of Epic v Google, which was preceded by Epic v
Speaker 4:  Apple, you'll recall Apple responded to Epic
Speaker 4:  launching a in-app billing system on iOS by shutting
Speaker 4:  down access to Unreal Engine. Yep.
Speaker 5:  Like,
Speaker 4:  Like this is not a company that acts lightly when it acts. So. I wanna talk
Speaker 4:  about the why just really quickly and, and then I wanna go back to the how
Speaker 4:  because and how is important, especially with how Beeper vs is getting around
Speaker 4:  it. Now, the why here, I think they have to say why,
Speaker 4:  because there was demand for Beeper Mini.
Speaker 4:  There were people lots and lots and lots and lots of people were
Speaker 4:  excited about it. They want this product. So for Apple
Speaker 4:  to take it away from them, they had to provide some reasons
Speaker 4:  for why it, why it's being disallowed, why an
Speaker 4:  experience is being broken that people liked and people wanted. And
Speaker 4:  those reasons have to be good. And in general, when it comes
Speaker 4:  to large company ACE and their servers, the thing they turn to is security.
Speaker 4:  Yep. And the security argument might be valid. I'm just saying in general
Speaker 4:  when they're like, what's a morally unimpeachable reason for doing whatever
Speaker 4:  we want? The answer is always security and So don
Speaker 4:  don't know what the actual potential for metadata exposure is.
Speaker 4:  That's a weird one. Especially 'cause Apple right now is in a bit of a crisis
Speaker 4:  over the cops just asking for push notification data and getting it
Speaker 4:  without warrants. Yep. That's a, that's a real problem in iOS apple's plugging
Speaker 4:  that hole, changing some policy. But that was a real problem. Like if you're
Speaker 4:  worried about metadata exposure, there's, there are bigger fish to fry,
Speaker 4:  but it, this is really interesting, right? They're, they're laying out metadata
Speaker 4:  exposure, which is basically the cops asking for metadata from
Speaker 4:  companies that don't have the resources to fight back like Beeper and then
Speaker 4:  all this enabling on launch itself. So that's the why and you can,
Speaker 4:  you can evaluate the why on your own. But I, big companies often turn to
Speaker 4:  security. Apple turn to security. Then there's the how
Speaker 4:  we blocked techniques that exploit fake credentials. So Beeper was coming
Speaker 4:  up with what fake serial numbers of Apple.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. They were using like serial, they were spoofing serial numbers that
Speaker 5:  already existed for, for like Mac products Apple.
Speaker 4:  And this is the thing that enabled them to just register any phone number
Speaker 4:  time message. Right? Right. You did not need an Apple id.
Speaker 4:  So now you do need an Apple id and it's tied to an email address and
Speaker 4:  I truly wonder if there is still a fake credential
Speaker 4:  or an old serial number in the mix and whether Apple will be able to stop
Speaker 4:  it.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it's hard to know. 'cause I think
Speaker 6:  Eric and the Buer team have gotten maybe not surprisingly
Speaker 6:  less open about how all of this works. They were very
Speaker 6:  confident 10 days ago they put out a whole big like white paper
Speaker 6:  about how the tech worked. A lot of it was open source. They're like, this
Speaker 6:  is what we did and how we did it. And the assumption was we're only,
Speaker 6:  they're only being dishonest because there's nothing Apple can do about it.
Speaker 6:  Right. So that was like the line going around was if Apple wanted to stop
Speaker 6:  this, it would have to shut down a huge portion of iMessage. Turns out not
Speaker 6:  the case. So Beeper has definitely like locked down
Speaker 6:  some of its explanation, but what it used to do in the early days of
Speaker 6:  Beeper was just sign you into your Apple ID on a Mac mini in
Speaker 6:  a server rack somewhere that is in
Speaker 6:  every way you can think about it. Insecure. Right? Right. Like it meant,
Speaker 6:  it meant your messages and your Apple ID information was sitting on a computer
Speaker 6:  that you did not own, like straightforward insecurity. What Bieber says now
Speaker 6:  is that it's, it's figured out kind of a good middle ground how to take some
Speaker 6:  of that on device encryption and added security
Speaker 6:  in Bieber Mini and applied it back to, to
Speaker 6:  some extent the old way of doing things. It's not on a Mac mini anymore,
Speaker 6:  it's still in your device, but they're going it seems like through the same
Speaker 6:  old login through your Apple ID stuff as they used to. So they found kind
Speaker 6:  of a a half measure that seems to solve some problems, but
Speaker 6:  it, it screws up the main thing, which is it no longer works with your phone
Speaker 6:  number. Like Eric has been texting me this week from his Gmail account, which
Speaker 6:  is not the same as your phone number. It's just not. And so Bieber Mini
Speaker 6:  is like kind of a, a knee capped version of what it once was,
Speaker 6:  but it does seem to have at least if you believe Bieber and
Speaker 6:  that is kind of the open question. Is it, it it is
Speaker 6:  back in a lot of the right security practices here, which is good.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. The one thing that I think is fascinating about this entire ordeal
Speaker 4:  and then we should just move on because this is just gonna be a cat mask
Speaker 4:  game for a long time. Beeper is very confident in their technical solution.
Speaker 4:  Right? And that turned out to not to be the case. And now they're very confident
Speaker 4:  in this technical solution and maybe they'll get back to phone numbers and
Speaker 4:  whatever that is. The technical side of this, can Apple
Speaker 4:  defeat this exploit Maybe? it can Maybe, it can't Maybe, it will be cat mass
Speaker 4:  forever. It feels like it'll be Cat forever. There's a
Speaker 4:  gigantic legal problem here, right? Like Beeper users and I
Speaker 4:  just accessing Apple servers without permission and
Speaker 4:  Apple has lawyers. I don't know if anybody
Speaker 6:  Aware. It's like a lot
Speaker 4:  Of stuff. There's there's quite a few of them. Yeah. They are not shy. And
Speaker 4:  I think that this is probably, that's probably the last resort here again,
Speaker 4:  just the presence of this statement indicates to me
Speaker 4:  that Apple knows it has to explain its behavior in blocking this on a
Speaker 4:  technical level. If they can't do that and they have to
Speaker 4:  resort to a legal level or a contractual level,
Speaker 4:  right? To say, okay, if you use on Unreal Engine, if you are
Speaker 4:  using, if you're using our servers in an unapproved way,
Speaker 4:  we're just gonna turn off your Apple IDs.
Speaker 4:  You're done, you're out. That's just a contractual thing they can do. You
Speaker 4:  broke our terms of service, you're done. No more, no more access to your
Speaker 4:  photos. They could do it. Right. Other platforms do
Speaker 4:  stuff like that all the time.
Speaker 4:  Do do you want them to like I they don don't think they want to do that to
Speaker 4:  people. If they go ahead and sue Beeper for a violation of the
Speaker 4:  Computer Fraud and Abuse Act, which is a very controversial statute. Like
Speaker 4:  that's not like a, a cut and dry. You're morally correct when you
Speaker 4:  invoke the CFAA do, do you wanna have that fight? Do you wanna
Speaker 4:  go to court again? I I can send Sean to that courtroom too.
Speaker 4:  We, story streams are great. You know, I, I just think Apple would prefer
Speaker 4:  to defeat this on a technical level and I think people would prefer to fight
Speaker 4:  this on a technical level. There is a whole set of other levels that
Speaker 4:  is vastly more complicated that Apple has not touched yet. And I'm actually
Speaker 4:  kind of shocked they haven't even sent the letter to re yet. That's like
Speaker 4:  stop it.
Speaker 5:  I mean they
Speaker 4:  Like that to me is they
Speaker 5:  Could have, they just haven't told us.
Speaker 4:  I think, I think Eric would happily publish that letter.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I agree with that. That would be out there. Well I think on the one
Speaker 6:  hand, I think the reason Apple hasn't done that
Speaker 6:  yet is the thing that Beeper is holding onto, which is that
Speaker 6:  people want Beeper. Like I think it, if you just abstract all of this away
Speaker 6:  and it's like, okay, what should the world look like? Beeper's, right? Right.
Speaker 6:  Like the Yep. I want to live in a world where Beeper Mini exists. It is
Speaker 6:  better interoperable messaging is better. Cross-platform messaging is better.
Speaker 6:  The whole green bubble, blue bubble thing is stupid and we should do whatever
Speaker 6:  it takes to get rid of it. I believe all of those things. I also believe
Speaker 6:  Apple is absolutely within its right to shut it all down. Right? Like both
Speaker 6:  of those things are true. I think Apple
Speaker 6:  has started to pick a public fight here
Speaker 6:  that Beeper can make very ugly for it if it wants to. And Apple
Speaker 6:  will fight those fights if it comes to it. It will, it will pick a privacy
Speaker 6:  fight in the court of public opinion or in literal court when it comes
Speaker 6:  to it. But that's a pretty big battle. And
Speaker 6:  Eric and Bieber have proven they're willing to be very loud about this and
Speaker 6:  they're willing to be very principled in their argument for an open internet.
Speaker 6:  And that's just a hard fight to fight if you're Apple without looking like
Speaker 6:  the bad guy.
Speaker 5:  Well they have an obligation. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  'cause they kind of are the bad guy. They're allowed to be the bad guy. They're
Speaker 6:  well within their right to be the bad guy, but they will look like the bad
Speaker 6:  guy if they pick this. But the
Speaker 5:  Apple kind of has to pick it a little bit, right? Because it does have the
Speaker 5:  regulators in the eu it has regulators looking in the United States and one
Speaker 5:  of its big defenses for all of its really like kind of
Speaker 5:  bad practices is that it's security, security, security. So
Speaker 5:  anytime there is like these security moments, they they have to do it. Otherwise
Speaker 5:  that argument falls apart in all those other places. Right?
Speaker 6:  Right. But I think the, the more
Speaker 6:  aggressively and loudly Apple right
Speaker 6:  picks a fight with Beeper,
Speaker 6:  the worse it's gonna look doing so. Right. 'cause it's one thing to say we're
Speaker 6:  doing something to protect our users. It's another thing to say we are out
Speaker 6:  to destroy this startup full of people who just wanna make messaging better.
Speaker 5:  Well it's very similar to Jailbreaking where like
Speaker 5:  they, they weren't necessarily always going out and, and sending letters
Speaker 5:  to jail breakers. They were usually closing those holes quietly and then
Speaker 5:  people would get upset and then they would just slowly start taking
Speaker 5:  all of the good stuff from jailbreaking and put it into to Apple to the point
Speaker 5:  where like nobody really jailbreak phones as often anymore because you don't
Speaker 5:  have to like all, you don't get anything of real value for the
Speaker 5:  majority of people. And it feels like it's kind of the same thing here where
Speaker 5:  they can just like keep making like the, if the solution for Beeper
Speaker 5:  becomes like unwieldy enough, then Beeper goes away because
Speaker 5:  nobody wants to just be sending texts via their, their email and,
Speaker 5:  and Apple wins and kinda that similar jailbreak way of just like, well if
Speaker 5:  the other, if the option's crummy enough, do you really wanna do it? And
Speaker 5:  most Apple users are like, nah, I'll just go to Android. Totally.
Speaker 6:  And we're kind of headed down that road now, right? Like even the, the Beeper
Speaker 6:  team has been tweeting as this has all gone back and forth. Like, we understand
Speaker 6:  this is a pain, we're we're, we get it. If you wanna bail while we try to
Speaker 6:  figure this out, like we will figure this out. Like they're clearly feeling
Speaker 6:  the hit of how complicated Apple is making their lives. Yeah. But at
Speaker 6:  the same time Elizabeth Warren is out here tweeting about
Speaker 6:  Beeper and what is happening to green bubbles
Speaker 6:  and blue bubbles, which is like, it's
Speaker 5:  Hysterical.
Speaker 6:  This, this might be a fight coming for Apple
Speaker 6:  in a way that it doesn't want and is probably not likely to try and
Speaker 6:  look like the heavy on more than it has to don don't know. I don't think
Speaker 6:  this is anywhere near over. Yeah. I my guess would be Beeper Mini never gets
Speaker 6:  back to being what it was. But this fight gets louder and uglier
Speaker 6:  in other directions and I have no idea where it lands.
Speaker 5:  That feels right. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I I get the feeling that Apple
Speaker 4:  is gonna just end up leaning on RCS support to solve all these problems.
Speaker 4:  Right. This is why they're doing it. They, they basically made this horse
Speaker 4:  trade with European regulators. We're gonna support RCS and you're not gonna
Speaker 4:  make us open up iMessage in exactly the way that Beeper is trying to open
Speaker 4:  up iMessage. Right. And eventually they will kill Beeper. It just seems like
Speaker 4:  the question is whether they can do it on a technical level or whether they
Speaker 4:  have to resort to the more aggressive legal level. I I
Speaker 4:  I think the fact that they already c conceded the RRCs
Speaker 4:  question means that they're not gonna hesitate to
Speaker 4:  kill it. They're gonna maybe hesitate and how fast they kill it
Speaker 4:  and hope and probably assume that they will do it on a technical
Speaker 4:  level with what feels like an unimpeachable security
Speaker 4:  rationale rather than a legal level and what feels like a,
Speaker 4:  you know, much less fun business rationale. Yeah. This thing preserves our
Speaker 4:  lock-in, right? That's the answer. Yeah. Like we have the emails from Eddie
Speaker 4:  Q to Phil Schiller where Eddie Q is like, we should open up iMessage to Android
Speaker 4:  and Phil Schiller's, I believe it was Phil Schiller,
Speaker 4:  it was filler. Craig writes back, this is the thing that
Speaker 4:  parents hand down their iPhones to their kids for. Yep. So
Speaker 4:  no, and that's just as dead on as it gets.
Speaker 4:  And I, a lawsuit based on that seems way less fun than a bunch
Speaker 4:  of engineers fighting Alex by the way, to your point about jail breaking
Speaker 4:  a huge number of members of the jail, a huge number of the
Speaker 4:  jailbreak community was Apple engineers. Oh really? And I think there's
Speaker 4:  a, I think, I think there, I think Apple knew this.
Speaker 4:  There there was, there was a lot of, yeah there are some, there
Speaker 4:  are some stories in the end as you guys, but we'll set those aside.
Speaker 4:  That's what I'll say. I don't remember how off the record stories are.
Speaker 4:  That's what I'm trying to tell you. That's fair. I think that's good enough.
Speaker 4:  They're so long ago that I don't remember if they were secrets or not, but
Speaker 4:  it is true just on its face. You go back and dig through it.
Speaker 4:  A substantial amount of the Joeb Break community was reliant on Apple Engineers,
Speaker 4:  which is fascinating. So Beeper that's, that's your answer. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Jailbreak. The iPhone. That's your answer All. right. Let's talk about
Speaker 4:  other messaging news which is much more exciting but also about
Speaker 4:  interoperability, which is ActivityPub had a big moment
Speaker 4:  today. Yeah. Masks on had a big moment today. Threads had a big moment today.
Speaker 4:  Today. But what's going on there?
Speaker 6:  So the biggest thing that, well two big things happened to
Speaker 6:  Threads this week. One is that it's now available in the eu. So
Speaker 6:  to everyone who has gotten a bunch of new followers putting
Speaker 6:  u's where there should just be os that's why there's tons of those people.
Speaker 6:  And the other thing is Mark Zuckerberg kind of out of nowhere posted
Speaker 6:  on Threads, that Threads is now starting to
Speaker 6:  integrate with ActivityPub in a very small way. Basically
Speaker 6:  you can now read Threads posts from a couple of
Speaker 6:  accounts. It's like Adam Mosseri and a couple of other Meta people right
Speaker 6:  now. But ultimately it'll be everybody who's on Threads. You can read their
Speaker 6:  posts on Mastodon or in any other
Speaker 6:  ActivityPub app like that. So this is, this is the first real step
Speaker 6:  in Federating Threads with the rest of the
Speaker 6:  ActivityPub universe. And for months there's been this debate, is Threads
Speaker 6:  ever gonna do this? Now that they see it's such a big potential business
Speaker 6:  and it's so successful, maybe they'll walk away and they have said over and
Speaker 6:  over and over like no, we plan to do this for real. And it appears that work
Speaker 6:  is like very seriously underway. People are starting to see Adam
Speaker 6:  ER's Threads posts in their Mastodon clients, which is kind of mind bending
Speaker 6:  in the coolest way. Yeah. Like it's happening. It's the best.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. He's at Macary at thread sut net. I signed, I followed him from my
Speaker 4:  Mastodon social account using the Mammoth app and then I opened my regular
Speaker 4:  MAs on client and looked at my account and it was there and I was like, oh
Speaker 4:  this is the future.
Speaker 6:  Yep. That's it. That's the stuff
Speaker 4:  Like I, I'm using multiple clients to access one account and
Speaker 4:  content from another server entirely that is owned by Meta showing up here
Speaker 4:  and including a video. Right. He, the first thing he posted was a video.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And then a bunch of other Threads folks, including their
Speaker 4:  engineers are, are posting like little jokes like it went from 4 0 4 to 200
Speaker 4:  and you can tell they're just like playing with it now. The the cool stuff
Speaker 4:  is not there yet, right. Like this has been enabled on the level of
Speaker 4:  what you might think of as RSS right now. Yeah, that's right. So they published
Speaker 4:  something on the thread server, another server can pull it in.
Speaker 4:  There's no interactivity, there's no true interoperability. Right. You're
Speaker 4:  just kind of pulling some content down. Right. That's still a big deal. Right.
Speaker 4:  And for a company like Meta to be like, we will publish a a syndicated
Speaker 4:  feed of content from our platforms, our social
Speaker 4:  platforms still like a big deal. Right. But it's not the thing.
Speaker 6:  Well and the beauty of it is this is the part that Meta has the least
Speaker 6:  incentive to do, right? Yeah. Like all of the rest of it is
Speaker 6:  better for Meta. Like the thing where in theory, like you described Neela,
Speaker 6:  you can read Adam's posts on Threads in your ma on app that is
Speaker 6:  a third party app. What Meta wants and what's ultimately good for
Speaker 6:  Meta's business is when you can like or reply to that stuff and it funnels
Speaker 6:  all the way back through that whole stack to Threads. Yeah. Right. So Adam
Speaker 6:  can be in Threads and you can be in Mammoth and you can have a conversation
Speaker 6:  with each other. That's where all of this wins. So you wouldn't do the thing
Speaker 6:  where you just let your content go other places without
Speaker 6:  real commitment to building all the stuff that brings it back and all the
Speaker 6:  account sharing stuff they're gonna want to do because it'll bring people
Speaker 6:  to Threads because Threads is the best platform for it. Like this is
Speaker 6:  not the one part of it you would do if you weren't committed to doing the
Speaker 6:  rest of it.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, and I agree with you. I think what I had point out is the other part's
Speaker 4:  way harder. Like building an RSS feed is like pretty easy, right? Way harder.
Speaker 4:  The part, the part where you're like, okay, someone hit like in
Speaker 4:  Mammoth or Ivory or whatever it on client
Speaker 4:  that like funneled to their server, which then talked back to our server
Speaker 4:  and that like showed up on the Threads app for somebody
Speaker 4:  that's very complicated. There are real security challenges there. There
Speaker 4:  are real content moderation challenges there. It's not just likes, it's also
Speaker 4:  comments and replies, reposts, like all that stuff
Speaker 4:  as you bring it back onto your server, you have to, you have to moderate
Speaker 4:  it, you have to care about it all, whatever. And I think that's the stuff
Speaker 4:  that's yet to build. But you are correct that that is the stuff that accrues
Speaker 4:  value back to Meta. 'cause it makes their community ultimately more vibrant.
Speaker 4:  And I think what Meta thinks it's gonna sell is better product design, better
Speaker 4:  user experience, better advertising, all this stuff. Which, you know,
Speaker 4:  it's a, it's if you're Meta it's a pretty good bet to make that you will
Speaker 4:  outdo a handful of massive on server admins on things like
Speaker 4:  content moderation and and advertising integration. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  It was really interesting. I went back and when I was writing the post about
Speaker 6:  this was just pulling some of meta's old quotes about this stuff from
Speaker 6:  the last six months or so as they've been talking about this. And they've
Speaker 6:  been surprisingly consistent in a way I didn't even realize. Like Mark Zuckerberg
Speaker 6:  in particular has talked about this as a creator play.
Speaker 6:  The idea is that this network of open systems
Speaker 6:  is what creators are going to want because they've understood too many times
Speaker 6:  that if you build an audience in one place that is captive to that one place,
Speaker 6:  people will eventually leave or that place will fall apart or whatever. And
Speaker 6:  then you have to start from nothing and nobody wants that. And so what Mark
Speaker 6:  and Adam Mosseri have continued to say is the future is
Speaker 6:  these more portable, more interconnected systems. And what Meta is
Speaker 6:  betting is that it can build creator tools, right? It can build the best
Speaker 6:  stuff to use to post it can build the best AI things.
Speaker 6:  It can like bring Tom Brady into your life in a weird AI way. It
Speaker 6:  can monetize you better. Like Meta is actually sort of
Speaker 6:  divorcing the idea of social networking is a good business. Which it turns
Speaker 6:  out it's not everybody has figured this out and leaning into we're gonna
Speaker 6:  outsource all of the like hanging out with your friends bits of this and
Speaker 6:  we're just going to win at how people make money on these platforms. And
Speaker 6:  I actually think if I'm Meta, that's a pretty good bet because Meta has proven
Speaker 6:  over and over it's better at that than everybody.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And I, I think it also creates opportunities
Speaker 4:  for those creators or media companies in different ways. Like everyone
Speaker 4:  knows what I, we're gonna do it somehow. don don't know how we're gonna do
Speaker 4:  it, but if
Speaker 6:  You keep saying it, it'll eventually happen. It's,
Speaker 4:  I'm just gonna horsepower this thing into his existence. Look, we had, I'll,
Speaker 4:  I'll just give you some inside baseball. Our company had an all hands today
Speaker 4:  just before we're recording and our CEO said the word fedi verse during the
Speaker 4:  all hands. And I was like, I did it. You cheer.
Speaker 6:  He did kind of say it like it was written on a piece of paper in front of
Speaker 6:  him, but he'd never seen it before. Like I was
Speaker 4:  Standing behind the curtain with a knife. You know, say it,
Speaker 6:  That
Speaker 4:  Just means I've said it enough that other people think they should say, which
Speaker 4:  is victory one. But I'll just use another example.
Speaker 4:  Threads lately has been very thirsty for Sports Threads. Yeah. I don Dunno
Speaker 4:  if you know this, they, they start out, they are a bunch of F1 fans over
Speaker 4:  there. So they even in Myer's video about launching in Europe today, he's
Speaker 4:  like, we want to bring sports communities that are deeply rooted in Europe.
Speaker 4:  Like F1. Yep. Which is an amazing way to say F1 is kind of fussy.
Speaker 6:  They did a whole thing with the NBA at the end season tournament. The other
Speaker 6:  thing that was happening in Vegas. Yes. While I was there, they were like,
Speaker 6:  they were a big sponsor. They brought in all the ESPN peoples ESPN's having
Speaker 6:  this fight with, with Elon Musk and and Twitter. So they're all coming like
Speaker 6:  it's, it's a, it's a thing that's happening.
Speaker 4:  So if I was running ESPN today, I would not be like, you
Speaker 4:  can have my reporters for free. Right? Yeah. You
Speaker 4:  woe is not gonna tweet scoops for free on Threads the way that he's been
Speaker 4:  doing for Twitter. I'm setting up a Mastodon server
Speaker 4:  and you can federate with us if you pay us the money for
Speaker 4:  access to the the people. And that is just a new way of thinking
Speaker 4:  about these businesses that it, I I, you know,
Speaker 4:  a bunch of media executives like don't like thinking new ways. They're like,
Speaker 4:  what if we make YouTube videos? Like that's like how they all think,
Speaker 4:  have you heard of this platform? It's called TikTok. Like these are the dinners
Speaker 4:  I go to. But they are all starting to think now, okay, well how
Speaker 4:  do we actually get paid for the stuff beyond just being like, we can make
Speaker 4:  it go viral better than anybody else. And so there's just new
Speaker 4:  opportunities for companies for creators to stand
Speaker 4:  up their own services and say, look, if you want access to us, like we need
Speaker 4:  some revenue sharing terms or you need to let us put advertising into our
Speaker 4:  feeds the same way that you let Instagram creators put advertising into their
Speaker 4:  feeds. And I, I just, I dunno if any of that's gonna work. I truly
Speaker 4:  do not know if any of that's gonna work. I know that it's new and
Speaker 4:  no one has actually, like, I can't point to anything else that has ever worked
Speaker 4:  like that and I can't point to anything else that could work like that. And
Speaker 4:  so like new things are just like fundamentally exciting to me. 'cause I think
Speaker 4:  the way it shakes out will be different or potentially better
Speaker 4:  or potentially way worse. But it's new, right? Like I'm just on the
Speaker 4:  hunt for new, like we've been doing it the, we've been doing it the platform
Speaker 4:  way for like 10 years. We just ran our big package on Twitter being
Speaker 4:  dead, which don don't know if people call it like Twitter is dead.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It's not that we called it dead. Elon Musk killed the
Speaker 4:  company and he renamed it X Linda Yao was on our
Speaker 4:  stage at code and she's like, Twitter is dead, it's called X now.
Speaker 4:  Okay, Twitter's dead, this is it, whatever. But inside of that I wrote a
Speaker 4:  big piece, but it's just like what the platform era of media did to all of
Speaker 4:  us. And it just, Ezra Klein is in that, and we talked about it on the Wednesday
Speaker 4:  show, but I just repeat this. He's like, Twitter increased the
Speaker 4:  scale of our communication and it reduced our ability to communicate.
Speaker 4:  And what if we just like did some other stuff and I, I promise you this ActivityPub
Speaker 4:  stuff, it's at least the thing that creates the opportunity
Speaker 4:  for people to think in new in different ways. It might not be the thing,
Speaker 4:  it might not work, but I just, I just have not seen so many people
Speaker 4:  having new ideas about the internet in a long time.
Speaker 5:  What about social media in particular? But I kind
Speaker 5:  of, one big question about this whole integration. What happens for people
Speaker 5:  who have like a lot of followers on Mastodon and also have a
Speaker 5:  Threads account, what do they do?
Speaker 6:  So this is, I would argue one of the most fun
Speaker 6:  conversations about this right now because no one knows the answer to that
Speaker 6:  question because there, there is a way of thinking about it that is like,
Speaker 6:  I have one omnibus fedi verse account, right? Yeah. That
Speaker 6:  it is, it is my, it would be the equivalent of having one account that worked
Speaker 6:  across Twitter, Facebook, Instagram, TikTok and everywhere else, right?
Speaker 6:  Your single account, you can actually make a really good case that that doesn't
Speaker 6:  make any sense. That actually what you're gonna want is a couple of different
Speaker 6:  accounts in different places and that the upside is that
Speaker 6:  you choose where you post and to what. And so like you could use
Speaker 6:  your Mastodon account for just like tweeting about the cool new glasses that
Speaker 6:  you got and your Threads account could be your work account and that maybe
Speaker 6:  those things being separate is useful. But the upside of it is
Speaker 6:  that if I wanna read your work account where I have my personal account,
Speaker 6:  I can, right? So it's all sort of platform agnostic. but there might be a
Speaker 6:  world in which people want lots of different accounts for different
Speaker 6:  uses but that just gets bonkers.
Speaker 6:  Like, oh I have 10 accounts for 10 different things. But you can
Speaker 6:  access any of them from anywhere is like the, the UI of that totally
Speaker 6:  falls apart if we don't do it correctly. So I don't know. My guess would
Speaker 6:  be, if I had to bet on something, I would guess that a lot of people will
Speaker 6:  get Threads accounts because Threads is gonna be, it's gonna be the Gmail
Speaker 6:  of this space for a while and then it'll just be sort of the
Speaker 6:  default one to have and then we'll get to see how it
Speaker 6:  plays out in lots of different directions. But right now, like I think a
Speaker 6:  lot of us, we've talked about this on the show, we sort of bet on Threads
Speaker 6:  betting A, that it would eventually integrate with ActivityPub and B, that
Speaker 6:  it was probably gonna be the biggest platform for a while. And there are
Speaker 6:  real values to being on the biggest platform. So like I've spent more time
Speaker 6:  on Threads than Mastodon. So when it comes to it, I will probably end up
Speaker 6:  investing more in my Threads account over time than my Mastodon account.
Speaker 6:  But will I keep the MAs don? Don't know. This is also weird and this is why
Speaker 6:  it's fun. Like to NE's point, like this is a new thing we've never actually
Speaker 6:  had to figure out before.
Speaker 5:  I've, I've been talking with other friends about this too because like I,
Speaker 5:  I don't, I never really used Mastodon. I've got like an account there, but
Speaker 5:  it just is like a placeholder of more than anything else. But I know people
Speaker 5:  who are like very, very active on Mastodon and as they started seeing Threads
Speaker 5:  getting bigger, they're like, okay, well we'll go start an account there.
Speaker 5:  And so now they're active on both and one, how do you have the energy? Yeah,
Speaker 5:  I understand but two like I was like well what's the calculus then? Like
Speaker 5:  when, when, when this all interacts, do you maintain both accounts? You
Speaker 5:  kill it and they're like I genuinely don't know. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  I don't think anybody does. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  NO
Speaker 4:  Yeah I I think there's some real value
Speaker 4:  to having different places for different things.
Speaker 5:  A hundred percent
Speaker 4:  These were all people. I do not know how people are like being
Speaker 4:  goblins on Blue Sky and then being whatever LinkedIn version of themselves
Speaker 4:  they're on
Speaker 6:  Threads also goblins, different kind of goblin but still pretty goblin engage
Speaker 6:  there.
Speaker 5:  Were in Go, were wearing a little tie on on Threads
Speaker 4:  But like I can see a world again I don dunno if any of this will work. I
Speaker 4:  don Dunno if this is a good idea. I don Dunno if, you know if we can build
Speaker 4:  any of this, but I can just see a world where my work
Speaker 4:  personality tweeting about tech and silliness
Speaker 4:  happens at, you know, neli at The Verge dot com
Speaker 4:  and you can follow that on Threads and that shows up in our homepage and
Speaker 4:  those are quick posts and those get federated and you can you just follow
Speaker 4:  me where you are and then tweeting about Aaron Rogers
Speaker 4:  happens somewhere else. Right? Right. And that just
Speaker 4:  seems better and maybe, maybe you want to, to
Speaker 4:  slam all that stuff together. Maybe some people will, but it just feels like
Speaker 4:  for too long we have just slammed too many things
Speaker 4:  together. Right. And actually being like, okay I've built one distribution
Speaker 4:  channel for one kind of audience that I can cultivate and grow
Speaker 4:  and I can build another distribution channel for my friends or my family
Speaker 4:  that isn't like a wholesale platform shift.
Speaker 4:  Like I'm this person on Instagram in the format of short videos.
Speaker 4:  I'm this person on Twitter in the format of deeply
Speaker 4:  snarky text posts, right? Like I'm the most nihilistic version of myself
Speaker 4:  on Twitter and I'm this person on threat. Like that having
Speaker 4:  the format dictate what kind of thing you're doing I think
Speaker 4:  has forced just, it just caused a lot of weird shit to happen.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And I think saying, okay, yeah we can have lots of different feeds,
Speaker 4:  we lots different accounts and you can act, you're kind of format independent
Speaker 4:  but you're chasing different things. Again new, I don't have any of that's
Speaker 4:  gonna work. Yeah, well I
Speaker 5:  I think, I think that it, that trips me up there is is you know, this kind
Speaker 5:  of stuff. We've been doing more than one account for a while now, right?
Speaker 5:  Like Finsta accounts and stuff like that. But what
Speaker 5:  happens is people inevitably go and have that one account because that's
Speaker 5:  where they have the most interaction. Yeah. And so like are you really gonna
Speaker 5:  wanna take your
Speaker 5:  reckless at Green Bay Packers social
Speaker 5:  account and and only use that when you have like 50
Speaker 5:  followers Who there who also have the same feelings about Aaron Rogers? I
Speaker 5:  assume more than 50 people have those feelings. They do. But like is, you
Speaker 5:  know, are you gonna wanna do that? And then when you have this much bigger
Speaker 5:  mouthpiece over here and I'm just really curious how people are gonna do
Speaker 5:  feel about that.
Speaker 4:  I feel, I just want to say this now and this is, I
Speaker 5:  Apologize. This is about Aaron Rogers.
Speaker 4:  I've, I've given him even more attention. Let's talk about Jordan Love
Speaker 4:  or I call him Flag Hart. He's great. I need an account just for that just
Speaker 4:  to make Flag Hartt social. It's when you, when you type
Speaker 4:  Jordan love's name into the iPhone to text your, your group chat about
Speaker 4:  it, it replaces it with a Jordanian flag and a heart icons.
Speaker 4:  Now we just call 'em flag heart. It's very good. We can make this happen
Speaker 4:  together.
Speaker 4:  Jordan, if you're listening and I know that you are,
Speaker 4:  can I meet your wife and Jordan Love and drive your truck?
Speaker 4:  That's a road trip I would enjoy. I would go on that trip in a heartbeat.
Speaker 4:  Just the weirdest four people in a cyber truck.
Speaker 7:  So get quiet.
Speaker 4:  So two of you are world class athletes.
Speaker 4:  Yes. How's it go? Both of us were very active on Reddit
Speaker 4:  when we were younger.
Speaker 7:  Oh boy.
Speaker 4:  Anyway, I'm excited about it. I think it's really fun if you have a master
Speaker 4:  account, just like do it do the thing. Follow Myer's already
Speaker 4:  the third most followed person in the Fed verse by by one chart that I saw.
Speaker 4:  Which is wild. Yeah. Follow some people on Threads. Like just try
Speaker 4:  it out like it will change your brain a little bit. Right? It's like
Speaker 4:  a follow button that you just don't expect to exist and you're like oh this
Speaker 4:  is better. Like there's just something better about it being like, oh
Speaker 4:  I'm in much more control of this situation.
Speaker 4:  I don. I think, I think it's gonna be I don Dunno about great but it's gonna
Speaker 4:  be different And I'm definitely in the market for different Yeah
Speaker 5:  Agreed.
Speaker 4:  Same All right? We gotta take a break. We're gonna come back. Sean Hollister's
Speaker 4:  gonna tell us all about Epic versus Cooper. We'll be right back.
Speaker 4:  We're back. Sean, Hollister Welcome To, the rich cast.
Speaker 9:  Thank you for having me yet again.
Speaker 4:  I'm very excited to talk to you. You spent every single day in the courtroom
Speaker 4:  for the Epic v Google trial. You were there when the verdict came in, which
Speaker 4:  was very fast.
Speaker 1:  Was it like a month was the whole thing Sean? How long? How long has
Speaker 9:  It been? I spent a Fortnite in Fortnite court because it was, it was
Speaker 9:  14 actual days of bigot court. I know a Fortnite includes nights too,
Speaker 9:  whatever. But yes, the trial lasted like four weeks plus
Speaker 9:  like one day we had Fridays off,
Speaker 9:  but I spent 14 actual days in the courtroom. And on
Speaker 9:  this last day we expected the verdict
Speaker 9:  might come in quickly for Google and
Speaker 9:  it came in quickly for Epic. And none of me, none, not
Speaker 9:  myself, not any of the other courtroom reporters expected that. That was
Speaker 9:  a huge surprise.
Speaker 4:  So I just wanna congratulate Sean here inside baseball. Sean beat
Speaker 4:  everyone by minutes if not hours to publishing
Speaker 4:  the story of the verdict. So congratulations Sean. Well well played the
Speaker 9:  Power of a pre-written stub.
Speaker 4:  Don't tell the people how we do it.
Speaker 6:  Sean wrote 65 stories for every possible outcome. Sean
Speaker 4:  Hollister in the multiverse
Speaker 9:  It was, it was four a pre-route. Four stories.
Speaker 4:  That's
Speaker 6:  Ridiculous. So there's a version where Google wins one, where Epic wins one
Speaker 6:  where like the courtroom explodes. Yeah. And then one where the judge is
Speaker 6:  just like, nevermind. Get outta here. All
Speaker 4:  Of you by iPhones get out of my face.
Speaker 9:  Exactly.
Speaker 4:  So Epic won. It was a runaway victory
Speaker 4:  that Google found for it on every claim. That's the
Speaker 4:  headline. Let's back up here. A lot of people are very familiar
Speaker 4:  with Apple, the Epic in which Apple won on virtually every claim.
Speaker 4:  There are some key differences in the trial. What were
Speaker 4:  these cases about and what were those differences?
Speaker 9:  Oh my gosh, So I actually have an
Speaker 9:  outline of the differences. 'cause this is the question on everybody's mind.
Speaker 9:  How could Google possibly have lost this case
Speaker 9:  when Apple one isn't Apple? The obvious
Speaker 9:  monopolist with the walled garden and everything like that. But a
Speaker 9:  whole bunch of things that I'd, I'd heard and and read told me that
Speaker 9:  these were very different. First off, the lawyers for both sides were telling
Speaker 9:  me before we began, these are logistically different cases with different
Speaker 9:  evidences, different judges. The apple verdict doesn't carry any weight
Speaker 9:  here. And not only that, they were not able to bring up the
Speaker 9:  application in the courtroom. The judge said, you don't talk about this.
Speaker 9:  So carries no weight at all. The next big thing
Speaker 9:  of course is that Google controls its ecosystem with all
Speaker 9:  these third party business deals. Whereas Apple's its own OEM,
Speaker 9:  there are more unfair looking documents in more hands
Speaker 9:  because Google had to like hand out all these contracts to these
Speaker 9:  different companies.
Speaker 6:  Google just has to like send more emails with more attachments. Like literally
Speaker 6:  it feels like that was a big part of this. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  Emails. Yeah,
Speaker 9:  Absolutely Emails.
Speaker 4:  I'm just telling you it's a one word that means everything. And you can buy
Speaker 4:  a shirt and
Speaker 9:  We've known this for like ages now. We wrote a piece in what,
Speaker 9:  20 11, 20 12. one of the first years of The Verge about the
Speaker 9:  Sky Hook case where we saw how Google tries to control the ecosystem
Speaker 9:  through all these contracts. But so many of them came out in this moment
Speaker 9:  and so many of 'em looked unfair. And I don't know if like
Speaker 9:  unfair would've swayed a judge, but I think it may have swayed a
Speaker 9:  jury who looked at these like blatantly unfair, Spotify
Speaker 9:  gets to pay, you know, nothing to Google to be in the Google Play store while
Speaker 9:  other companies have to pay 26 or 30%. Like that seems
Speaker 9:  blatantly unfair. The jury saw that, they saw Google trying to
Speaker 9:  keep it secret and they didn't like that jury in front of a bench.
Speaker 9:  That's one of the big things here. They saw that Google had a lot
Speaker 9:  of things to hide, especially
Speaker 9:  all of these chats between various executives that were being auto
Speaker 9:  deleted by the corporate policy at the time for
Speaker 9:  for, for, for document retention. The judge is like, what the fuck
Speaker 9:  Google, you're supposed to keep the documents
Speaker 9:  for us so that we can look at them in the courtroom. And Google was like,
Speaker 9:  nah, we never change any of that stuff. Ooh.
Speaker 6:  So wait, can I just say one thing about this actually? 'cause I was, I was
Speaker 6:  in court for USV Google when Sundar Pcha was
Speaker 6:  testifying and they brought this up to him too and he absolutely
Speaker 6:  won that interaction, which was so fascinating to
Speaker 6:  me because the case that he made essentially was there was this one thread
Speaker 6:  that they brought up with him in which the last thing you see is him saying,
Speaker 6:  can you turn off history please? And so they turn off history and that's
Speaker 6:  obviously the end of the thing 'cause they stop storing it. So they bring
Speaker 6:  this up and they give s this whole long spiel about, you know, you're destroying
Speaker 6:  evidence, this is a disaster. And, and his response is essentially, well,
Speaker 6:  did you find any more versions of that happening? And they were like, how
Speaker 6:  would we know you deleted it? And he was like, well you found this one because
Speaker 6:  I asked them to turn off history. Did you find any other times where to turn
Speaker 6:  off history? And and the lawyer goes, no, and that's the end. And Sunar just
Speaker 6:  like victorious sits back and it, that immediately went away
Speaker 6:  in USV Google and it was such a non-issue, but in this one it just
Speaker 6:  kept being part of
Speaker 4:  The trial. Can I, can I want Sean to, to get into this, I just wanna point
Speaker 4:  something out that I think is often forgotten when we cover the legal
Speaker 4:  system. One, we have an audience of tech people and people believe the legal
Speaker 4:  system is deterministic. Like it's an algorithm, like you put in
Speaker 4:  some inputs and you get an output and you can predict the output. Not true.
Speaker 4:  I, I think this we are, we've learned over and over again in America
Speaker 4:  over the past couple, not true, almost completely random, especially when
Speaker 4:  there's a jury involved and then I'm a lawyer and
Speaker 4:  I'm married to a lawyer and I have a lot of friends who are lawyers. So I'm
Speaker 4:  just gonna say this and we can all just react to it however you want. Some
Speaker 4:  lawyers are better than other lawyers
Speaker 4:  and if you're Epic, you can afford really good lawyers,
Speaker 4:  and if you are the United States government
Speaker 5:  Hire better.
Speaker 4:  It's just right, like prosecutors
Speaker 4:  like
Speaker 4:  you, you just see it. I, I, you know, it's like, I'm just like, you could
Speaker 4:  just react to that however you want, but you can just see that
Speaker 4:  some lawyers are better than other lawyers. And there's, that's a real
Speaker 4:  difference in these cases for sure.
Speaker 9:  Epic afforded some really good lawyers here. Yeah, I I, I was very impressed
Speaker 9:  with how, just how much and how often
Speaker 9:  they put the witnesses on edge and, and turned Google's
Speaker 9:  witnesses against Google and all the, all these things. I was surprised that
Speaker 9:  Google's lawyers didn't have a better defense, but they
Speaker 9:  were in a very difficult position here because Epic spun this
Speaker 9:  whole thing as this tale of good and evil with all of these
Speaker 9:  unfair documents on the table. And Google was left to explain
Speaker 9:  away all these complicated business deals, which might make
Speaker 9:  sense and might might've even convinced a judge, Hey, this is just normal
Speaker 9:  business practices. You've seen this in your courtroom a thousand times,
Speaker 9:  but the jury hasn't. The jury hasn't seen all these unfair deals
Speaker 9:  and Epic constantly. Every Google executive
Speaker 9:  that came under the stand, every Google witness that was there
Speaker 9:  got grilled hard about their emails and about these
Speaker 9:  deleted chats, you know? Oh, I love it. How, how will we ever know what's
Speaker 9:  in your, what's in your chats? You'll never know. So Sundar though, the
Speaker 9:  judge was willing to let Sundar pass the buck Epic's lawyer
Speaker 9:  was all like, you know, you're res you, you agree that you're responsible
Speaker 9:  for everything that goes on at Google. Right? But after the jury filed
Speaker 9:  out of the courtroom, judge Donato was, you know, okay, okay, Sundar,
Speaker 9:  I, I, I, I accept that you got bat advice from your lawyers,
Speaker 9:  maybe, but I want the buck to stop with somebody.
Speaker 9:  Bring your chief legal officer into court. So the judge hauled in
Speaker 9:  Google's chief legal officer for over, I wanna
Speaker 9:  say over an hour of questioning about how the heck got this happened.
Speaker 9:  And he did not look good on the stand. Google CLO
Speaker 9:  Judge was not buying it. Kent,
Speaker 4:  His name is Kent Walker, by
Speaker 9:  The way. Kent Walker, yes. Kent Walker.
Speaker 9:  Google's Google's attorney who's, who's, sorry, Epic's attorney whose name's
Speaker 9:  escaping me right now. But she was amazing. And, and,
Speaker 9:  and she just, just completely threw him off balance. The
Speaker 9:  judge double teamed Kent Walker with this, with this, this,
Speaker 9:  with this attorney. And like, you know, I don't understand this either. Can
Speaker 9:  you, can you explain those things you just said to me again, Mr. Walker,
Speaker 9:  and, and he wasn't having any of it and he ended the, the judge, judge
Speaker 9:  almost one of the penultimate things that Judge Dondo did in the case is
Speaker 9:  he said he's going to personally investigate Google Wow.
Speaker 9:  For deleting all these chats and for, for abusing. What, what
Speaker 9:  1, 1 1 Google Lawyer internally called fake legal
Speaker 9:  privilege. We, we saw a whole bunch of documents during the case
Speaker 9:  that were marked, you know, confidential and privileged. And Google
Speaker 9:  executives, including Sundar Phai, agreed
Speaker 9:  that the only reason some of these things were marked confidential and privileged
Speaker 9:  was so that they wouldn't be forwarded around the company internally and
Speaker 9:  potentially fall into other hands.
Speaker 4:  It's not a good sign when the judge vows to personally
Speaker 4:  investigate your company after the trial is over. Feels bad. So here's what
Speaker 4:  I wanna know, Sean, and then we can, we can dive into some of the merits
Speaker 4:  of the case. This was happening. The judge is furious
Speaker 4:  about this. We, we talked about this a couple weeks ago. We're seeing all
Speaker 4:  these documents. You up wrote a great recap of all the documents, all the
Speaker 4:  deals the judge instructs the jury. Like
Speaker 4:  you can interpret the lack of documentation and the hiding any way you
Speaker 4:  want, which is a big wink wink on how to interpret
Speaker 4:  them. And yet everyone thought Google would win.
Speaker 4:  Why? Like, that's the part that does. Why, why was the vibe in the courtroom
Speaker 4:  that Google would win quickly here?
Speaker 9:  I think the vibe in the courtroom was that Google would win because
Speaker 9:  of the key question that we always ask in an
Speaker 9:  antitrust trial market definition.
Speaker 9:  Google's been arguing since the very beginning of the case that whatever
Speaker 9:  it did, it was justified because it does all these
Speaker 9:  things to so that Android can compete with the iPhone. And if
Speaker 9:  you say the market definition here is iPhone
Speaker 9:  versus Android, Android is competing with iPhone, consumers are choosing
Speaker 9:  to buy an iPhone versus an Android phone.
Speaker 9:  How is Epic going to say, Hey Google, you have a
Speaker 9:  monopoly on phones. Hey Google, you have a monopoly on apps. Epic
Speaker 9:  wanted everybody to think that Google has a monopoly on Android app
Speaker 9:  distribution very specifically and on Android in app payments where
Speaker 9:  it kind of does, I mean, yes there's a Samsung app store, but
Speaker 9:  Epic convincingly showed that Samsung's app store accounts for barely
Speaker 9:  any download compared to Googles, you know, everybody wants to use Google.
Speaker 9:  Well, and
Speaker 6:  That it's all of that is because of Google's abuse
Speaker 6:  of the system, right? That, that Google has done the work to ensure
Speaker 6:  that Samsung and
Speaker 4:  Others, others can't play nicely. I wanna come, that's the substance of it.
Speaker 4:  I just, for one second, I just wanna sit on why everyone thought Google would
Speaker 4:  win. So I read that, right? Okay. It's market definition.
Speaker 4:  Apple just won. Android is technically more open
Speaker 4:  than the iPhone. Even if contractually it is not more open, as we've
Speaker 4:  learned, of course the Google's gonna win, right? The phone's more, more
Speaker 4:  open on its face
Speaker 9:  And in so many ways too. I mean it's, it's, yes you can have your other app
Speaker 9:  store on the phone, but you can also side load apps. Since the very beginning
Speaker 9:  of Android, I was holding up my T-Mobile G one phone and I would download
Speaker 9:  an a PK off the internet and I would put it on there. I don't if any of us
Speaker 9:  immediate get room do that these days. Exactly. I don't know if anybody,
Speaker 9:  any of us do it these days. 'cause so many things are on the play store already
Speaker 9:  and why wouldn't you go there? But like the idea that
Speaker 9:  you can put an app on an on Android phone, so many different ways. You can't
Speaker 9:  put it on the iPhone. How could Google have a monopoly on Android app
Speaker 9:  distribution?
Speaker 4:  The other thing that I think is just sort of reverberating here, and I think
Speaker 4:  we, we all noticed it was the lack of interest in the Google case compared
Speaker 4:  to the Apple case. Like the Apple case was like a star studded, you know,
Speaker 4:  our, our traffic charts are off the charts every single day. Google Verbaled
Speaker 4:  along and Sean, you did a great, like a lot of people covered the Google
Speaker 4:  trial by just following Sean in the story stream. Yep. Which is, you know,
Speaker 4:  great, that's the service we provide. But we could see there was a different
Speaker 4:  level of interest. And the thing that I'm honing in on
Speaker 4:  is one, I think everyone assumes that big companies will always win their
Speaker 4:  antitrust cases, which is wrong. And then two,
Speaker 4:  I think people thought it was boring and it appears that the jury did not
Speaker 4:  think it was boring, right? This is like the key thing that everyone missed
Speaker 4:  is the jury was like, oh, this is pretty exciting and interesting and
Speaker 4:  dramatic actually.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. Not only was the jury paying attention
Speaker 9:  throughout almost the entire trial, we saw some yawns and
Speaker 9:  like a, when a couple of the expert economists came in and spent a while
Speaker 9:  explaining, you know, basic market theories, there were a few
Speaker 9:  yas, but most of the time they were extremely attentive. They were looking
Speaker 9:  over at the person asking the questions, they were looking over at the witness
Speaker 9:  to see what the answers were. They were looking at the judge, they were looking
Speaker 9:  down at their monitors, looking at all the documents, trying to follow along
Speaker 9:  with some of the slide decks. And they asked
Speaker 9:  questions. Literally today we got to see a few of the
Speaker 9:  questions that the jurors asked during the case. They
Speaker 9:  wrote notes to the judge and said, Hey, can you ask Google
Speaker 9:  how many of the devices are in the RSA 3.0 Premier Tier? Which by
Speaker 9:  the way, is the contract that decides whether A OEM
Speaker 9:  can preload another app store or not onto a phone. So they're like, oh
Speaker 9:  yeah, did, did Google actually keep anybody from doing that? They cared.
Speaker 4:  So now let's get to the substance of it, which is the market.
Speaker 4:  I think everybody thinks the market is iOS versus Android, but here
Speaker 4:  I think what we are really talking about is Google runs Android,
Speaker 4:  it's a platform, it's open, anyone can use it. And there actually
Speaker 4:  is a market for Android app distribution. There are other
Speaker 4:  stores, there are other ways to get Android apps on Android
Speaker 4:  phones. There is not a market for
Speaker 4:  iOS app distribution, which I think was a real problem for Epic. They couldn't
Speaker 4:  argue that Apple was unfairly dominated market 'cause no market existed.
Speaker 6:  Well that's why that one became all about payments, right? That was fundamentally
Speaker 6:  the thing. And like the win that Epic got was the anti steering stuff where
Speaker 6:  you could start to tell Apple users that other ways to pay for things exist.
Speaker 6:  But yeah, in that case, I went back and read a bunch of this and there's
Speaker 6:  so much of it that it's like Apple was able to get away with so much because
Speaker 6:  specifically it is so incredibly locked down and Google,
Speaker 6:  we, we thought Google's relative openness was gonna be a reason. It was harder
Speaker 6:  for Epic to win. And I think it actually went the other way and gave Epic
Speaker 6:  like a chance to make a case against Google that you just
Speaker 6:  can't do. 'cause you have to pry open Apple as a company to do it. And that's
Speaker 6:  not gonna work.
Speaker 9:  I think that's absolutely right.
Speaker 5:  We talked about this with the, with the Beeper vs. Stuff in the first segment
Speaker 5:  where, where like Apple kind of has an obligation, their whole brand is we
Speaker 5:  shut everything down, we lock it down, and it wins them trial after trial.
Speaker 5:  Like if you look at this and say, oh yeah, if the minute
Speaker 5:  Google started saying, well sure we have a monopoly here, but it's
Speaker 5:  Android and we're competing against iPhone, Google was kind of in trouble
Speaker 5:  because that was never the argument the other side made. And they just kind
Speaker 5:  of like, it felt like almost they ignored the argument that Epic
Speaker 5:  was making to be like, no, no, but see we're competing against Apple. And
Speaker 5:  it's like, well why would you make that argument when you really can't bring
Speaker 5:  up Apple that much here? And two, that's not
Speaker 5:  what the people suing you are complaining about.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. So, so, so when I was reporting on this case
Speaker 9:  in the courtroom, what I did not understand until the very
Speaker 9:  end, and I don't know if it's always this way, but what I didn't understand
Speaker 9:  until the very end was who is going to decide
Speaker 9:  the market definition and how in a
Speaker 9:  jury trial in the Apple case, the judge said, well, you know,
Speaker 9:  Epic, we don't, we don't think it's, it's about, you know,
Speaker 9:  iPhone versus Android. It's gonna be about mobile game transactions because
Speaker 9:  that's what you're actually suing over, right? Vbu and whether
Speaker 9:  where people can buy them and how, and that meant that
Speaker 9:  Epic had to be competing there with other game
Speaker 9:  stores like Nintendo and Sony and Microsoft where it already
Speaker 9:  pays the 30%. So why shouldn't you pay 30% here on Apple too?
Speaker 9:  But in this case, the people who got to decide the market
Speaker 9:  definition were the jurors. They got to write it in on the verdict
Speaker 9:  form themselves, and they were steered by the
Speaker 9:  jury instructions and by a lot of the case towards the idea that
Speaker 9:  it would be Epic's chosen market definition of
Speaker 9:  Android app distribution and in-app
Speaker 9:  transactions in-app, mobile payment systems. I mean, and so
Speaker 9:  when they were confronted with that and, and, and the judge was very skeptical
Speaker 9:  of any other theories like Google, sorry, really wanted you to
Speaker 9:  think that this was not only just about Apple versus Android, but also
Speaker 9:  they had one of their expert economists come under the, under the stand and
Speaker 9:  suggest it was going to be about the facilitation of mobile transactions.
Speaker 9:  And the judge was not having that. God, the judge was like,
Speaker 9:  isn't what you're saying, doesn't that apply to any transaction on the internet?
Speaker 9:  How does any of that have to do with mobile apps? Specifically?
Speaker 4:  How do you get a job as an expert economist, you get paid so much money,
Speaker 4:  just be like, look at this chart. It means whatever who's paying me wants
Speaker 4:  it to mean
Speaker 4:  Like, it just seems like such a good and lucrative gig, right? It's like,
Speaker 4:  yeah, we, we
Speaker 9:  Heard like $1,600 an hour for this person to be on to be
Speaker 9:  delivering their, their statements in court. $1,200 an hour Wow. For this
Speaker 9:  person. And it was funny that the
Speaker 4:  Chart is all used
Speaker 9:  World every time it was this back and forth between Epic and Google. Hmm.
Speaker 9:  I wonder if we can point out how much their expert is making, but let's point
Speaker 9:  out that they're biased. Bit of a double-edged sword there.
Speaker 4:  But but just to be clear, the market on
Speaker 4:  its face because it exists is Android app distribution. It is.
Speaker 4:  There could have been a better and richer Samsung app store, but Google
Speaker 4:  paid some money. There was this idea that, what was it?
Speaker 4:  Epic and Valve and a bunch of other companies, Activision,
Speaker 4:  BL Activision Blizzard would start app stores and
Speaker 4:  compete against Google. Yeah.
Speaker 9:  They wanted to build the steam of mobile was to compete against
Speaker 9:  Valve, but a Epic, Activision Blizzard, I think it was Supercell
Speaker 9:  was gonna be part of that. They were gonna build a steam of mobile, they
Speaker 9:  claimed and, and, and put that on Android. And then, you know, you'd,
Speaker 9:  you'd buy your games there maybe.
Speaker 4:  And then Google, Google responded this with something called Project Hug,
Speaker 4:  where it just went and hugged people with money to make them not do it.
Speaker 4:  That's a smooth move. That's what you want to do. It's a hug. And you're
Speaker 4:  like, is that getting a be Is it a weird little, oh no, it's just cash.
Speaker 9:  Well, they hugged him and then Pocket maybe the jury would, would, would,
Speaker 9:  would get that. It wasn't exactly a bribe because it's, it's, it's all like
Speaker 9:  these co-marketing arrangements here. We'll give you some Google ad credits
Speaker 9:  and here here's some revenue sharing over here. And here's, you know, the
Speaker 9:  only, the only company that I think Google directly paid it was
Speaker 9:  like, here's money for doing the thing. It's just a bribe is Motorola and
Speaker 9:  lg. But yes, I mean it all comes down to it's harder for anybody else
Speaker 9:  to build the thing because Google is paying someone. It's a bad bribe. but
Speaker 9:  it
Speaker 6:  Does come back. And this is why I think the, the fact that it's a jury trial
Speaker 6:  is so fascinating because it's like, there's a series of things in here,
Speaker 6:  right? And I think Project Hug, which you just described, and then the Spotify
Speaker 6:  deal that Google gave Spotify where it essentially doesn't,
Speaker 6:  actually, can you just explain that really fast? 'cause I, I confess, I got
Speaker 6:  hung up on like what the numbers are about here, but essentially Spotify
Speaker 6:  got a sneaky deal from Google where it essentially didn't have to pay anything
Speaker 6:  to be in the Play store. Right?
Speaker 9:  That's, that's it. I mean, okay, Spotify, okay. Normally
Speaker 9:  an app developer pays what, 30% to be on the play store.
Speaker 9:  They pay 15% for their first year or something like that.
Speaker 9:  If it's, and then it's, and then there's a 15% for subscriptions. There's
Speaker 9:  a bunch of ways that Google discounts the rate, but some app developers said,
Speaker 9:  we wanna have our own payment system. And Google first said, no,
Speaker 9:  you're not gonna have your own payment system. And then they said, well maybe
Speaker 9:  we'll do this experimental trial thing where some companies get their own
Speaker 9:  payment system and we'll give you a 4% discount. And
Speaker 9:  they called it something Choice billing. So if
Speaker 9:  you, if you were on the choice billing, you'd have, Spotify would theoretically
Speaker 9:  have one system where it pays its 15% to Google
Speaker 9:  for subscriptions, or it's 30% for one time purchases, if that's
Speaker 9:  a thing on Spotify anymore. And then on the on, on, if it
Speaker 9:  wants, if Spotify wants to use its own payment system, we get a 4% discount
Speaker 9:  on that. So 11%, which
Speaker 6:  Is nothing. And like this came up a bunch, right, that like by the time you
Speaker 6:  pay another payment processor, you're gonna be back at 15%. So you might
Speaker 6:  as well just give Google because it's simpler. So like that's not a deal
Speaker 6:  at over 50
Speaker 9:  Google calculated, you'd be paying more than that 4%. Yeah. Okay. To get
Speaker 9:  your own payment system, they thought it wasn't even gonna be a choice. So
Speaker 9:  it's,
Speaker 6:  It's a fake deal.
Speaker 9:  Money that completely fake. Okay. But what we learned is Google SE
Speaker 9:  or Spotify secretly had an arrangement to pay not
Speaker 9:  11%, but 0% when it used its own
Speaker 6:  Bill, which is a deal.
Speaker 9:  And that's, that's quite a deal. But, but Google isn't offering that to anyone
Speaker 9:  else that we're aware of. Google also said, Hey Netflix,
Speaker 9:  you don't wanna pay 30% anymore or 15% anymore. You can pay 10%, you wanna
Speaker 9:  pay 10%. Netflix said no. Yeah, we're gonna just bypass the
Speaker 9:  store. We're not gonna let you buy thing, buy your subscription to Netflix
Speaker 9:  through Android, you'll go buy it on the web, you'll buy it somewhere else.
Speaker 9:  We know you'll find it elsewhere. That's
Speaker 4:  Like when one monopoly hits another monopoly, like Netflix is like,
Speaker 4:  what are you gonna do? Not have Netflix? Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Like, hey, we don't, we're not paying you money to sign up for Netflix.
Speaker 4:  No, you'll just have it at birth. I
Speaker 9:  Love that's Netflix's approach constantly. Here's my question. That is also
Speaker 9:  what Spotify said. What are you gonna do? Just not have Spotify? Yeah. And
Speaker 9:  Google said, okay, you can pay nothing. And at what point,
Speaker 9:  at what point Google said they were gonna do this to us if we didn't give
Speaker 9:  'em a deal, I didn't realize at that point that it was a 0% deal. I thought
Speaker 9:  it was, you know, maybe they get 6% or something, 0%. What do
Speaker 9:  you do at that point? If you're Google, do you say,
Speaker 9:  okay, you get the special deal. Do you say let's treat
Speaker 9:  everybody fairly like we, we pretend we're gonna do and and and you know,
Speaker 9:  make that real and just give everybody the 0%. What do you
Speaker 4:  Think? So Google has to make the deal because there's the other, there's
Speaker 4:  the out right? Apple just says we're gonna not have
Speaker 4:  Netflix, which is fascinating, like
Speaker 4:  their view. And it is played out in different ways for Apple in different
Speaker 4:  platforms. So on the iPhone they're like, we just wanna have Netflix and
Speaker 4:  everybody caves. Like the idea of not having your app on the iPhone
Speaker 4:  completely outta bounds. Apple tries to pull the stuff with
Speaker 4:  the TV app on the Apple TV and Netflix is like, no,
Speaker 4:  we're just, we're no, what are you gonna do? Not have Netflix. But at the
Speaker 4:  same time, and Apple's like, okay, you don't have to put your Apple tv,
Speaker 6:  Can you sign up on Netflix through in-app purchases? I don't think so. Netflix,
Speaker 6:  Netflix has held pretty fast on that stuff. Yeah. And, and there's, but the
Speaker 6:  thing is, there's only a handful of companies that can get away with that,
Speaker 6:  right? Like I'm actually surprised, yeah, Spotify rises to that level
Speaker 6:  for Google or anybody. But like I think if I'm Google my worry is like, okay,
Speaker 6:  Spotify's not in the play store. Spotify's gonna be in the Galaxy store.
Speaker 6:  And you know what, like a hell of a lot of people might do to get Spotify
Speaker 6:  on their phones is open the Galaxy store.
Speaker 4:  That's what I mean, there's a market there, right? They have an out, they
Speaker 4:  can go and say open this other app store, right? We we're gonna partner with
Speaker 4:  Samsung directly and preload Netflix on the phone in
Speaker 4:  a way that Apple's just like, no, no other choices shall exist. And
Speaker 4:  Sean you interviewed Tim Sweeney right after the trial and I thought this
Speaker 4:  was the most important thing that he said. He said, I
Speaker 4:  wish Apple wasn't so like clear cut on what you can't
Speaker 4:  do. And I think the exact words he used were Thou shalt not have another
Speaker 4:  app store. Yeah. And it's like, oh that's the, that's why you lost
Speaker 4:  against Apple because there wasn't even the possibility
Speaker 4:  for Apple to unfairly foreclose, right? Like
Speaker 4:  Google's like, oh, there's all these outs they can take. It might result
Speaker 4:  in some fragmentation. You can assign noble intentions to Google here, by
Speaker 4:  the way, you can say Android had a big fragmentation problem. You
Speaker 4:  don't want all these different ways to get apps, especially the big apps.
Speaker 4:  Like if you go get a new phone and to get Spotify and
Speaker 4:  Netflix and TikTok, you need to download three different app stores.
Speaker 4:  This is a bad outcome. Yes. For Google, it's a bad outcome for users. I think
Speaker 9:  It's important to remember that we at The Verge spent several years
Speaker 9:  writing reviews of Android phones where we were like, I wish this just had
Speaker 9:  pure stock Android on it. Instead of layers of blood
Speaker 4:  Bone stock, I believe bone
Speaker 9:  Stock. That's right, that's right. Like, I want that from my phone.
Speaker 9:  Motorola testified on the stand that it helped them cell phones.
Speaker 9:  Like I get why Google wants to crack down in fragmentation. We've written
Speaker 9:  the editorial eight times here at The Verge and these contracts
Speaker 9:  are how it does that. But these contracts have also helped them make
Speaker 9:  the Google Play Store a profit center for the entire company that makes
Speaker 9:  ridiculous billions in revenue would be a Fortune 100
Speaker 9:  company all by itself and has a 72% or something like that
Speaker 9:  profit March.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And one by the way, one way you could cut down in fragmentation is
Speaker 4:  by being more competitive, right? Like, this is actually like really
Speaker 6:  Interesting. Make better phones. Google
Speaker 4:  You, right? You could make a better phone. You could, you could make the
Speaker 4:  Pixel really competitive. Like there's a million ways to do it. And Google
Speaker 4:  chose to do it by taking a bunch of money, firing it into the market
Speaker 4:  and making sure that no other competitors existed. Which by the way, David
Speaker 4:  did come back to DOJ versus Google is exactly what they do in the
Speaker 4:  search market. And I don know how that case is gonna go. But the parallels
Speaker 4:  are right there. The
Speaker 6:  Parallels are right there. And I think the difference, like back to the thou
Speaker 6:  shalt not thing like you, you can accuse Apple of many things, but you cannot
Speaker 6:  accuse Apple of being inconsistent, right? Like, it, it is,
Speaker 6:  it, it has been what it has been for a very long time and you can dislike
Speaker 6:  it, but I think one of the reasons Apple keeps winning is because it just
Speaker 6:  keeps saying the same thing and it's not unclear about what you are signing
Speaker 6:  up for when you buy an iPhone. And when that
Speaker 6:  happens, it might be different. Google on the other hand, I think
Speaker 6:  the sketchiness of all of these deals I think really worked against Google,
Speaker 6:  especially in a jury case where like you can, you can sort of
Speaker 6:  talk yourself into some of these being like reasonable things that
Speaker 6:  reasonable businesses do, but like there's no question that they just feel
Speaker 6:  gross. And I think to, to a jury especially over time, and I
Speaker 6:  wonder how it felt even just sitting in the courtroom, like my sense was
Speaker 6:  even just like following your stuff in the story stream Sean, like you kind
Speaker 6:  of got more and more of like an ick over the course of
Speaker 6:  the trial watching all of this go down and you just go from thinking like,
Speaker 6:  oh, Google is a company that makes deals to insured to just being like, this
Speaker 6:  just sucks. And I think, like I get the sense everybody sort of felt that
Speaker 6:  over the course of four weeks.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. I think I maybe I, maybe I was a bit of a proxy for, for helping
Speaker 9:  our readers live vicariously in the, in the position of the jurors so they
Speaker 9:  could see it kind of like that. If you were in the courtroom, would you feel
Speaker 9:  the same way if you were one of the people on the nine jurors making
Speaker 9:  these decisions? I do wanna challenge what you said earlier about Apple being
Speaker 9:  consistent. It has been compared to Google incredibly
Speaker 9:  consistent.
Speaker 4:  Sure.
Speaker 9:  But Apple made sweetheart deals over private email too. I mean
Speaker 9:  that fair. Netflix had a unique relationship with Apple to do a 15%
Speaker 9:  revenue share, which was not enough for Netflix. And Netflix eventually did
Speaker 9:  go its own way, but they did try and
Speaker 9:  broker that similar kind of arrangement. Yeah, that's true. There were a
Speaker 9:  number of things like that that we saw back in the day,
Speaker 5:  But not at this trial. Because you weren't allowed to talk about Apple at
Speaker 5:  the trial for the most part.
Speaker 9:  Exactly. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  We had another trial. Alex you're gonna say something? No,
Speaker 5:  No, I think mine was just an anecdote because when, when I was, I was
Speaker 5:  like reading all of your coverage Sean and a, a friend of the family is a
Speaker 5:  former judge, and I'd be like, okay, I have a question for you as a former
Speaker 5:  judge, if someone has been going out of their way
Speaker 5:  to like hide a lot of documents and stuff to the point that it keeps
Speaker 5:  coming up in trial,
Speaker 5:  how would that case probably go for them? And, and that friend was like,
Speaker 5:  not, well, just as a judge,
Speaker 5:  Don't do that. And then I was like, and then there was also a bunch of proof
Speaker 5:  that they were doing these sweetheart deals and like other people do it,
Speaker 5:  but they were doing it and they're like, no, you're kind of boned in that
Speaker 5:  respect. They used more polite terminology there, but they were very much
Speaker 5:  like, oh, like, like it was, I think for anybody who wasn't
Speaker 5:  kind of in that tech space and had seen the Apple case, but it has like any
Speaker 5:  kind of grasp of this stuff. It was just like, oh no, you Google was, was
Speaker 5:  gonna get wrecked. Like yeah, you can't piss the judge off that much and
Speaker 5:  expect to, to win generally.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Where, where the judge is like, I will personally investigate you.
Speaker 4:  That was a long night for Google's lawyers. Like they, a lot of Macallan
Speaker 4:  was consumed. That's what I, that's what I think Google's lawyer strength.
Speaker 4:  Two things that I want to bring up. One Alex, to your point, I think having
Speaker 4:  the jury, you know, there's that phrase like you don't wanna know how the
Speaker 4:  sausage is made. And I think a lot of judges are like, oh, that's some sausage.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And the jury is like, this is gross. Like I'm never eating a hot
Speaker 4:  dog again. Right? Like I think there's just that element of it. And then
Speaker 4:  I think, and this Shauna, I kind of want to bring this
Speaker 4:  together and, and wrap this up a little bit. There's just
Speaker 4:  the element that all business works like this.
Speaker 4:  And if you just like see how it happens, like maybe that's bad,
Speaker 4:  right? Like Google's an advertising company in a
Speaker 4:  do a lot of deals and they're really good at making sharky deals. And
Speaker 4:  that version of Google is very different than the version of Google. That's
Speaker 4:  like the new Google doodle is in different colors today, right? Like they,
Speaker 4:  they maintain that quirky silly image and then the back end of
Speaker 4:  Google is a Sharky advertising company. And
Speaker 4:  when you see it, it's like really bad. And there was one moment
Speaker 4:  that I still think is the most fascinating where Tim Sweeney and
Speaker 4:  Sun re met for settlement and they couldn't get there. And you
Speaker 4:  talked to Tim about it and he wouldn't tell you about it with the, about
Speaker 4:  the specifics, but it seemed like Google tried to make another
Speaker 4:  deal at the last minute. And Tim said, no,
Speaker 9:  That's what, that's certainly what Tim Sweeney was
Speaker 9:  implying. He, he certainly implied that Sundar tried to
Speaker 9:  offer me personally something again, and, and frankly to, to
Speaker 9:  your point about like maybe this is just how the sausage is made, business
Speaker 9:  deals happen like this. The judge also
Speaker 9:  thought that Epic might take its own deal in the
Speaker 9:  courtroom after the jury had gone home for the day. Judge
Speaker 9:  Donato was like, Hey Epic, Google,
Speaker 9:  have you tried settling yet? And when Epic's attorney, lead attorney
Speaker 9:  said, no, we haven't actually really tried that yet. And
Speaker 9:  he was like, what are you asking for? And Epic went off on some
Speaker 9:  like, we want this for us and all developers. And the judge came back with,
Speaker 9:  well, Spotify got this special deal for itself. I'm sure you could get
Speaker 9:  that special deal for yourselves too. Go talk about it. And so
Speaker 9:  the judge was under the implication by wait, that this wasn't gonna be a
Speaker 9:  blank thing for all developers. Maybe Epic should go get a special deal for
Speaker 9:  itself.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. By the way, most cases settle, this is a thing we should note, like
Speaker 4:  70 or 80% of cases settle and judges want the cases to settle,
Speaker 4:  right? The idea is that the American legal system should not resolve conflicts
Speaker 4:  between two rap priorities themselves. You should go work it out and that's
Speaker 4:  fine. So, I, I think the judge has to say that, but like the
Speaker 4:  idea that he asked Epic, what do you want? And Epic responded with some
Speaker 4:  potentially self-serving I but yet very idealistic creed perfectly
Speaker 4:  in character for Epic.
Speaker 6:  Well, and that's
Speaker 4:  Actually totally in character.
Speaker 6:  That was the other thing I was wondering, Sean is for what,
Speaker 6:  three years now? Tim Sweeney has been trying to kind of white knight his
Speaker 6:  way through all of these processes. Like he really
Speaker 6:  wants to be seen and have Epic be seen as the good
Speaker 6:  guy here, right? And he even said to you, he's like, we would never take
Speaker 6:  a deal. We're doing this for all developers. We've always done this for all
Speaker 6:  developers. Even when Google offered us a deal, we said, no, we wanna do
Speaker 6:  it for all developers. He like dug up an email that they offered the deal
Speaker 6:  that he didn't want. Like, but then he sits on
Speaker 6:  the stand and is like, yes, if this happens, we're probably gonna make billions
Speaker 6:  of dollars.
Speaker 9:  Okay. So little story about that, little story about that.
Speaker 9:  I thought, I thought that maybe Tim Sweeney is
Speaker 9:  just that kind of personality where
Speaker 9:  he walks up there and he doesn't necessarily know what he's saying
Speaker 9:  is, is truthful, but maybe not the best thing
Speaker 9:  to be seen publicly saying maybe, maybe this just kind of
Speaker 9:  came out of him. But then after
Speaker 6:  He's testifying on vibes,
Speaker 9:  Maybe Maybe it just came out of him that he's laughing about how he could
Speaker 9:  make billions of dollars by paying Google nothing. But No,
Speaker 9:  but no, I, I ran into him later in the hallway. I think it was the next day.
Speaker 9:  'cause by the way, he's been there every single day of the trail. Save one.
Speaker 9:  I ran him to the next day and he, and he, and he walks up to me and he says,
Speaker 9:  you got the number of exclamation points, right? Oh,
Speaker 9:  and he's referring to this post where he's laughing about making billions
Speaker 9:  of dollars off of Google.
Speaker 6:  Interesting.
Speaker 4:  How many exclamation points was it?
Speaker 9:  Just one actually, but one, one for that phrase. Well, there was
Speaker 6:  Another one,
Speaker 9:  Another sentence. Awesome. It's awesome that he could avoid paying Google
Speaker 9:  anything. So one, one there and then one for the, the billions of dollars,
Speaker 9:  two exclamation points total.
Speaker 6:  So is is Tim Sweeney still the white Knight for all developers everywhere?
Speaker 6:  Like as at the end of this, if as they appear to be winning this fight, which
Speaker 6:  will get appealed and God only knows, but like, does he still seem like the
Speaker 6:  champion of all developers or did he just like lie in his pockets and laugh
Speaker 6:  all the way to the bank?
Speaker 9:  God don don't know. I I I feel like a question in
Speaker 9:  the back of my mind for, for the three years now has been,
Speaker 9:  does he actually think he'll ever win any of these lawsuits
Speaker 9:  all the way through appeal? Or is he doing this to grossly
Speaker 9:  embarrass Google and Apple because all of these
Speaker 9:  documents and contracts are coming out and because he's decided he wants
Speaker 9:  to personally make his company's wealth go towards this,
Speaker 9:  this effort,
Speaker 6:  Which by all accounts would not be out of character for Tim Sweeney. Like
Speaker 6:  I've, I've never met the man, but everything people who know him say makes
Speaker 6:  that seem like a perfectly plausible explanation.
Speaker 9:  Absolutely.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Like a very funny Tim Sweeney fact is a,
Speaker 4:  you know, we, we have like lots of ideas, but on the record and off the record
Speaker 4:  and background, Tim Sweeney only talks on the record. That's just
Speaker 4:  the thing. He just like won't, he won't even entertain the idea that he should
Speaker 4:  talk to you in the background. That's him coming to us. That's usually the
Speaker 4:  other way around. And I know people have like lots of issues with him as
Speaker 4:  a personality and like what Steam does and whether not Steam. I know people
Speaker 4:  have like a lot of issues with Epic and what Epic does and whether Epic is
Speaker 4:  ruthless on the PC and they're buying exclusives from the Steam, like whatever.
Speaker 4:  But I, I do think there's an idealism there. Like it's, it's actually like
Speaker 4:  a really interesting thing for a company of, of Epic
Speaker 4:  size to be idealistic or to have a CEO who's idealistic. Like
Speaker 4:  most CEOs are like, soon Reper try offered me billions of dollars to
Speaker 9:  Go. He even tried to be idealistic about the billions of dollars thing.
Speaker 9:  I mean the very next thing that happened was in that
Speaker 9:  moment he said, I think it would be billions of dollars. It'd be awesome
Speaker 9:  if I could avoid paying Google anything. Google was very satisfied with
Speaker 9:  that. And they said pass the witness. Epic came
Speaker 9:  back on and Epic said, you know, so why do you want, you know,
Speaker 9:  why, why, where do you think you get this same kind of deal where you avoid
Speaker 9:  paying anybody else anything? And he said, that's how, how it's been on the
Speaker 9:  PC with Windows. That's how it is on the Mac. You
Speaker 9:  can put apps on there and not pay somebody to put your apps on there.
Speaker 9:  So he may believe that this is part of the idealistic thing that he's trying
Speaker 9:  to do. And I think that he has supporters who also believe that.
Speaker 9:  I'm not quite sure which side I'm on of that.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I think that's an open question especially 'cause what's gonna happen
Speaker 4:  next is both of these cases are on appeal.
Speaker 4:  And I, I don't know if this is true, this is just my interpretation of the
Speaker 4:  Apple case. I think the judge ruled the way she did in the Apple case to
Speaker 4:  set up an appeal, right? There's a reason that
Speaker 4:  the judge in California felt very comfortable saying,
Speaker 4:  the state law in California allows me to do a prohibition on anti
Speaker 4:  steering, but the federal antitrust law does.
Speaker 4:  I'm not gonna, I'm not gonna run into that fight. I'm gonna let a higher,
Speaker 4:  I'm a trial court judge. I'm not gonna reinterpret
Speaker 4:  the antitrust law of the United States. I'm gonna kick that upstairs 'cause
Speaker 4:  she knows this appeal is coming. So that has always been my read of that.
Speaker 4:  I think she's a very savvy judge. She developed a trial record, she kicked
Speaker 4:  it upstairs. This judge had a jury. The jury doesn't give a shit about being
Speaker 4:  overturned on appeal. You know, like it's a, it's a different case.
Speaker 4:  Diff facts are different. The markets are different. Both cases are gonna
Speaker 4:  get appealed. Sean, based on your talk with Tim, you're
Speaker 4:  covering the trial. What, what do you think Epic is doing next here?
Speaker 9:  I think Epic is still gonna wait, quote unquote a little bit because
Speaker 9:  we have until the second week of January before Epic's lawyers
Speaker 9:  and Google's lawyers come back together and say, Hey judge, what is actually
Speaker 9:  going to happen now that Epic is won? Because we don't know what the judge
Speaker 9:  can or will actually grant Epic now that the
Speaker 9:  jury has said yes, there is, you know, this is an illegal monopoly as far
Speaker 9:  as we're concerned. So there's that Tim was like, oh yes,
Speaker 9:  we'll keep fighting everywhere. We've got all these other cases going on
Speaker 9:  around the world. They're waiting there. I I think there were a couple of
Speaker 9:  Australia cases that were kind of on hold because
Speaker 9:  they wanted to see what was going to happen in the US before Australia weighed
Speaker 9:  in classic
Speaker 4:  Australia.
Speaker 9:  And, and of course the Apple one is being appealed. They're, they were both
Speaker 9:  sides. Both Apple and Google are hoping the Supreme Court will take up the
Speaker 9:  Apple decision, which has already been through the appeals appellate level.
Speaker 4:  We'll see All, right? We have a, we have another year of sending Sean to
Speaker 4:  courtrooms. I'm so sorry, Sean, potentially in Australia.
Speaker 9:  I, I, I have wanted to visit Australia for a while.
Speaker 1:  He's
Speaker 4:  Beautiful.
Speaker 4:  All, right? We gotta take a break. We're gonna do a lightning round. We'll
Speaker 4:  grab on
Speaker 4:  All, right? We're back. Sean's sticking with us for the lightning round.
Speaker 4:  Sean, you're the guest of honor even cooped up for a Fortnite in Fortnite
Speaker 4:  court with Tim Sweeney. one of the
Speaker 6:  Best headlines we've run in a while, by the way, a Fortnite in Fortnite
Speaker 4:  Court, but people got mad at us. They're like, you're too gleeful about Epic
Speaker 4:  women. I'm like, the company's name is Epic. Yeah. What, what
Speaker 6:  Are we supposed
Speaker 4:  To do here? There's not a journalist in the country or world that can stay
Speaker 4:  away from Epic victory in this moment. What are you talking about?
Speaker 4:  Epic
Speaker 9:  Win Epic victory for a while. Whether they read the Apple case. It's
Speaker 4:  The name of the company. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  It's not even like anyone who's reading that as an adjective is wrong.
Speaker 6:  Epic Epic win. It's, it's a fact.
Speaker 10:  Can you imagine the other way? Google win. Google
Speaker 4:  Victory read. It's like people just start searching. What did they win?
Speaker 4:  Bard's like, I don't know. Yeah.
Speaker 9:  Can't tell that. During, during the Apple case we called the Judge Epic Judge
Speaker 9:  fairly often. That was fun. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. That's very good. All, right? Sean, you're the guest of honor. You
Speaker 4:  get to go first. What's your lightning round item?
Speaker 9:  Opera's gamer browser now has a panic button for when you're caught in the
Speaker 9:  act. Oh boy.
Speaker 4:  I knew you
Speaker 9:  Were gonna pick. Oh boy. And I
Speaker 9:  I don, I don't don don't wanna talk about the panic button. I wanna talk
Speaker 9:  about how Opera has a browser that has to
Speaker 9:  go to these incredible ridiculous gamer centric
Speaker 9:  extremes in order to differentiate from Chrome the
Speaker 9:  dominant browser because nobody else can compete. And we've just
Speaker 9:  been talking about Google competing with things like
Speaker 4:  No, this is, but this is the competition. This is, you need a browser
Speaker 4:  that can set limits on CPU and GPU usage. So you can keep gaming
Speaker 4:  at your full frame rates and that has a panic button. So if someone
Speaker 4:  walks in while you're gaming Mm. It's
Speaker 5:  Very resource intensive.
Speaker 9:  And there's a, there's a little known feature in Opera GX where if you die,
Speaker 9:  hopefully you press the button that told it to delete all your history so
Speaker 9:  that they won't see the things that you were looking at when you press
Speaker 6:  The panic button. If you, I just, my favorite thing about this is that it
Speaker 6:  it, when you press F 12, which jumps you out of whatever you're doing into
Speaker 6:  a quote unquote safe tab, one of the options they give you is to go to Twitch.
Speaker 6:  Which is like, is that better?
Speaker 4:  Oh, I'm playing a video game.
Speaker 6:  I don't want my boss to see me. Lemme go to Twitch.
Speaker 5:  Does it auto mute too?
Speaker 6:  I have not. Does
Speaker 5:  The tab auto mute? It should. I was gonna say Alex ask
Speaker 6:  Hard questions.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I'll, if you, I, you know what? I don't want to linger on this for
Speaker 4:  one second. Longer.
Speaker 5:  Rest of
Speaker 4:  Around. If you're in a situation where you need a panic button in your browser,
Speaker 4:  fucking volume should be off.
Speaker 6:  Headphones. People headphones.
Speaker 5:  Freshman in college get this browser you share in a dorm room,
Speaker 5:  you get this browser.
Speaker 4:  Oh
Speaker 9:  My God. Can't wait to see their market show.
Speaker 6:  Boy,
Speaker 4:  Thank you Sean.
Speaker 4:  Why? Why did I do this? All, right?
Speaker 4:  Pierce, can you just, just clean, clean us up somehow?
Speaker 6:  Mine is the Apple TV app, which has a new panic button where
Speaker 6:  when you're
Speaker 5:  Takes you to HBO max.
Speaker 4:  So
Speaker 6:  Apple,
Speaker 4:  The dark recesses of HBO Max,
Speaker 6:  You hit a button and you go to HGCV just like that. It's like, no problem.
Speaker 6:  Whatever you were watching. No, the Apple
Speaker 4:  Somewhere. David's ZZ was like, ship a panic button.
Speaker 4:  This is how we win.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, you can have that for free too.
Speaker 5:  No one can know. You watch Gilded
Speaker 6:  Age. The Apple TV app just got a redesign on the Apple tv.
Speaker 6:  Apple has had this like don don't know, 15 year long obsession
Speaker 6:  with like trying to solve the interface of television. And I think it's like
Speaker 6:  the most quixotic thing Apple is trying to do. It's either that or build
Speaker 6:  a car. Like one two equally impossible. Yeah. Goals.
Speaker 6:  But the new TV app actually looks really nice. They've redesigned it. It
Speaker 6:  has easier ways to get to some of the channels you can get at through Apple
Speaker 6:  tv. It has some easy ways to get to like buying stuff from much
Speaker 6:  different platforms. Apple's big idea is to be like the TV guide for all
Speaker 6:  your streaming stuff. So it pulls all the stuff you're watching, all the
Speaker 6:  recommendations, all this stuff into one place. It notably does not have
Speaker 6:  Netflix, which like immediately destroys its utility for a large number of
Speaker 6:  users. Because
Speaker 4:  This is what I'm saying about net, like when when one monopoly hits another
Speaker 4:  one. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It's also bad at a lot of other ones too.
Speaker 6:  It is. Apple. Apple I like, I think is on the right path here. I just
Speaker 6:  think it's impossible to do what it's trying to do. But I admire Apple for
Speaker 6:  just continuing to believe that it is Apple. And so it can eventually bully
Speaker 6:  every other company into being part of this. But the new app is very nice.
Speaker 6:  I suspect we'll get a lot of this stuff on other platforms as well. And like
Speaker 6:  the streaming interface that we have sucks and somebody should
Speaker 6:  fix it. And like, I don't care if it's Apple, I don't care if it's like,
Speaker 6:  just watch, like pick a company. don don't. I don't care if it's Plex. No
Speaker 6:  one cant. I should want it to be Plex. I would like for it to be Plex. Plex.
Speaker 6:  Could you please
Speaker 9:  See this? I just wanna say that Steve Jobs did not tell Walter Isaacson
Speaker 9:  on's deathbed that he wanted to build a car. He said he'd cracked the TV
Speaker 9:  and it's about the time they cracked it. It's
Speaker 6:  Exactly right. That's exactly right.
Speaker 4:  Really the whole company chased this like deathbed comment for
Speaker 4:  too long. Do you
Speaker 6:  Think Steve just meant like his, he, he cracked his tv. He like threw something
Speaker 6:  at his television and cracked it and Walter just like, he threw
Speaker 4:  A remote.
Speaker 4:  So we bought a new house. We're like, I'm building a home theater down there.
Speaker 4:  It's like a whole thing. There's speaker wire everywhere. The poor electrician
Speaker 4:  just keeps looking at me like I'm crazy. It's great.
Speaker 4:  So two, two things. One, in the meantime we have a Samsung Frame tv, which
Speaker 4:  will eventually be the bedroom tv
Speaker 4:  and I have used ties in now. Mm. I'm just
Speaker 5:  A moment of silence for Neli
Speaker 4:  Ties, Tieszen Support Club more for you. Please help me.
Speaker 4:  But Samsung does one very smart thing with Tieszen on this TV in the builtin
Speaker 4:  software. When you're watching YouTube TV and you click out of it and you
Speaker 4:  sound like go back to any other place where there should be media playing,
Speaker 4:  it just starts playing it again as though you are just watching tv.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, it's, it is just very, it's just very clever. It just
Speaker 4:  restarts your streaming app and it just has media playing where you're like
Speaker 4:  goofing around in the menus or whatever. It makes it feel like a TV and not
Speaker 4:  like the Apple tv, which very much feels like a tiny iOS device
Speaker 4:  that is very upset that you are not watching Apple TV plus.
Speaker 6:  Or like all the fire TVs now, which are like, oh, you turn on your TVs, here's
Speaker 6:  some ads. Do you wanna watch some ads? How about some ads as soon as
Speaker 5:  You turn it on.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. So there, there's something there which I think is just really clever
Speaker 4:  and smart. Yep. In Python. But it's part of the turn you're talking about
Speaker 4:  these interfaces suck because they're all trying to get
Speaker 4:  you to do something you don't want to do. Or they're all trying to keep you
Speaker 4:  away from watching TV or they wanna show you ads. Particularly like
Speaker 4:  Alex writes about Fast all the time, right? Like free ad supporting TV is
Speaker 4:  a big thing, which means they're desperately trying to get you to watch free
Speaker 4:  ad supported tv. That's weird. The second thing,
Speaker 4:  I've been thinking about this a lot with just Apple TV and like what will
Speaker 4:  be my primary device and here's what I've settled on. I'm gonna buy a Sony
Speaker 4:  a 95 L. Okay. They're not in stock anywhere. And I'm just gonna watch
Speaker 4:  Bravia core Sony's proprietary streaming service that has the highest bit
Speaker 4:  rates in the entire industry.
Speaker 6:  Oh boy.
Speaker 4:  In that Spiderman
Speaker 5:  Spider's gonna look so good on that tv. It's gonna be the red suit. It has
Speaker 4:  Like four movies. It's Yeah. Yeah. Look it has, I
Speaker 4:  think it has 4, 4 4
Speaker 5:  Reds. See? See you're gonna, you that's, they love to be like, look how good
Speaker 5:  Spider-Man looks with our high bit rate. Red
Speaker 4:  Is red, red is famously the hardest color to compress and
Speaker 4:  Spider-Man's a great demo. Yep. I'm gonna watch the hell outta
Speaker 4:  Spider-Man.
Speaker 5:  That and Red Buses in England. They're like, look at it, it's
Speaker 5:  beautiful. You're like, it's fine.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, don don't know it just like all of my stuff, I, I bought
Speaker 4:  a lot of movies in Apple and now it's like this thing does not want me to,
Speaker 4:  they shut down the movies app and the TV app, which I never ever used, but
Speaker 4:  they shut down the movies app and it's like, oh, I just wanted to see what
Speaker 4:  was out and like watch a movie and now it's like I have to contend with the
Speaker 4:  morning show. Like, here it is, here's just, do you want
Speaker 4:  the morning pay for this? Yeah. Watch it. And I'm like, I just wanna see
Speaker 4:  what movies are out. don don't know. Are
Speaker 9:  Any of us holding onto to discs?
Speaker 5:  I just bought a
Speaker 9:  Bunch. I've still got my 4K discs. They go in my PSS five. They just bought
Speaker 9:  a bunch. That's how I watch my, my good looking movies.
Speaker 4:  I I was gonna do that. But Bravia core dog,
Speaker 6:  Sean, I will say history is increasingly proving you, right? Yeah. I
Speaker 6:  was not here last week to be furious at what Sony did, removing all
Speaker 6:  the stuff that people had bought on on their PlayStations. But that shit
Speaker 6:  sucks. Yeah. And we are rapidly nearing a point where legitimately, if you
Speaker 6:  wanna make sure you can watch something, you're gonna have to buy it on disc,
Speaker 6:  which is like a dumb place to end up. but it feels
Speaker 5:  Like we're it's beautiful headed. No, it's, I've now got Michael Doffs, American
Speaker 5:  Ninja from the eighties on DVD and like
Speaker 5:  can't find that on streaming
Speaker 6:  All. right? Well there's Alex's like, whatcha gonna
Speaker 5:  Do you wanna watch that horror show? m like only one
Speaker 5:  way to watch it. Oh my God. If my sister's listening, I'm sorry. You now
Speaker 5:  know what you're,
Speaker 6:  It's too many
Speaker 4:  All. right. I'll do mine and then we'll end with Cranz. Mine is
Speaker 4:  a weird week for electric cars just around the board, but
Speaker 4:  Cadillac announced the Cadillac of Tik,
Speaker 4:  which is their next electric SUV. It looks pretty
Speaker 4:  good. It looks like a little baby Escalade Cadillac. I just wanna point out
Speaker 4:  Cadillac's prices for EVs are completely out of control. So this
Speaker 4:  one is going to cost $90,000. And I will remind you
Speaker 4:  it is called the Tik within IQ because I was
Speaker 6:  Cadillac. What what does Cadillac do? There's like the, the
Speaker 6:  lyric, which I assume is now pronounced
Speaker 4:  Lyric
Speaker 6:  And the, the que and the, there was like the Cinque and the
Speaker 6:  Celeste, like who at Cadillac keeps being like, you know what's dope is our
Speaker 6:  q names that are unpronounceable, like stop it.
Speaker 4:  So yeah, they, they start with a lyric, which sort of makes sense.
Speaker 6:  It's actually pronounced Ric. Sorry don don't know if I just wanna,
Speaker 4:  The, the Ric is actually kind of reasonably
Speaker 4:  priced. It's like you can get one in the sixties, which for a Cadillac is
Speaker 4:  like in the zone. They have, they have a cheaper one that
Speaker 4:  that's coming out. And then they have the
Speaker 4:  Escalade, which starts at 120,000.
Speaker 5:  Is there a Q level trim
Speaker 4:  And then they, the Celeste is 340,000.
Speaker 6:  It's Escalade with a Q. Sorry, sorry.
Speaker 4:  Always Q you know the Escal? It's the Escalade iq. They could not figure
Speaker 4:  out how to jam the e tack it on on the Escalade. So like whatever. It's
Speaker 4:  the Escalade iq. Like we just, here's an E you
Speaker 4:  can have it $120,000 please.
Speaker 6:  I say that these cars are hot. Like I'm, I'm very into the styling they have
Speaker 6:  for these.
Speaker 4:  I have, I don't, I don't need a car. I moved back
Speaker 4:  to Civilization. I don't live in the woods anymore. I live in a very walkable
Speaker 4:  place. I'm like, I should buy a lyric all the time. I'm like, I should buy
Speaker 4:  a lyric. And I'm like, why? I would never. So you can say Lyric,
Speaker 4:  we have a hybrid with 25 miles of electric range. I haven't bought gas in
Speaker 4:  three months. 'cause that's all we need. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  How's the pickup truck
Speaker 4:  Pickup's going?
Speaker 4:  I love it so much and I need to get rid of it. And I
Speaker 4:  come on
Speaker 9:  Still waiting for the Iion, which is a Hyundai vehicle
Speaker 9:  to get some NACS charging.
Speaker 4:  Who decided? Huge. Also, I shouldn't buy any of this stuff. The future, what
Speaker 4:  are doing Until they, until they have the Chargers.
Speaker 9:  We need the Chargers
Speaker 5:  One day
Speaker 4:  All. right. I'm gonna buy a Cadillac All. right.
Speaker 4:  It does look pretty good. All, right?
Speaker 5:  This one, this one's a little sad. Take sound. I've been
Speaker 5:  2003. I was in college and I met a guy
Speaker 5:  and he said, he said panic button.
Speaker 4:  Panic button.
Speaker 5:  He said, Hey, my uncle's a producer at like Today show
Speaker 5:  or something. He's going to E three. Do you want to go? And I
Speaker 5:  went in college to E three and then I went for the next 10
Speaker 5:  years. Wow.
Speaker 5:  Not always with with hi his, his family and,
Speaker 5:  and the, the hosts of the Today Show or whatever was great.
Speaker 5:  And, and then I never went again 'cause it got really bad and it continued
Speaker 5:  to get bad. And E three just got less and less and less
Speaker 5:  useful. And that is why this year E three is officially
Speaker 5:  dead. It was the trade show for video games like Sean.
Speaker 5:  Did you ever go to E three? Yeah. I feel like you went to E three.
Speaker 5:  It was like, like it was kind of fun.
Speaker 9:  Should I tell the story?
Speaker 4:  Sean's like, I was born in the dark. It was fun.
Speaker 5:  You was, you saw cool stuff. Oh good. You know, I went, I went the year that
Speaker 5:  they, they moved it all to Santa Monica and you had to see all the video
Speaker 5:  games in an airplane hangar and otherwise you just had to know a lot of people.
Speaker 5:  And I did not So I spent a lot of time on the beach. That E three, it was
Speaker 5:  great, but
Speaker 5:  that's what I should have done. It's really, really nice.
Speaker 6:  Sean what's your weirdest e three story? I feel like there I can just see
Speaker 6:  on your face. Yeah. You have a weird E three story that You don't wanna tell.
Speaker 6:  You have to tell. I would like you to tell it
Speaker 9:  A weird e three story. I don't want to tell. Or do you or do you want, or
Speaker 9:  do you want the good one? The one about the good one? The one I told one.
Speaker 9:  Give us a good one. I love a good All, right? I'll,
Speaker 4:  I gotta a good one. Okay.
Speaker 9:  I'm just gonna read from my CNET article because, because I haven't
Speaker 9:  rewritten this and I, I'll just do my voice. It'll be great.
Speaker 9:  I was playing Warhawk. The first game for Sony's just announced PSS three
Speaker 9:  motion controller where you could fly a heavily armored war plane just by
Speaker 9:  tilting a game pad. Believe it or not, those simple motion controls were
Speaker 9:  revolutionary at the time. This was before the iPhone was announced. Before
Speaker 9:  Twitter existed and even before the Nintendo, we and PS three were released.
Speaker 9:  To give you some context yet on the show floor, there wasn't much of a line.
Speaker 9:  We only had to wait a few minutes before I got to try this potentially groundbreaking
Speaker 9:  title. The longer I played, the more people crowded around me.
Speaker 9:  Soon I felt like a star. I was on fire playing war, like, like a champ
Speaker 9:  in front of my very old audience. The more people watched, the better I played
Speaker 9:  flying that deadly war plane with precision. Then it was over. I turned
Speaker 9:  around and handed the controller two. She guru me a mode.
Speaker 4:  This is a dream you had, right? This is not an story.
Speaker 9:  Father of Barrio Zelda was behind me the whole time. The crowd
Speaker 9:  had been there for him
Speaker 9:  because they were watching the man who developed the We Motion
Speaker 9:  controller, try his competitor's product for the first time. And
Speaker 9:  you're just like, wow. And So I just stood there dumbfounded. He's playing,
Speaker 9:  watching Bebo to play this game and his face had no expression on it.
Speaker 9:  None. Yeah. Stone cold.
Speaker 5:  He was not as impressed with your playing. Fantastic. Was he?
Speaker 5:  Oh, I just saw like,
Speaker 4:  Well, Sean didn't know he wasn't paying attention. He was locked in the
Speaker 9:  War game. Blame for my
Speaker 5:  Audience. Saw Paris Hilton and like those, those TV or the, the
Speaker 5:  T-shirt cannons. He had t-shirt cannons of
Speaker 9:  Everything.
Speaker 4:  I never went to, I've never been once some weird stuff. Every instinct I
Speaker 4:  ever had was to stay away. It's good and, and I, I feel like it collapsed
Speaker 4:  on itself, right? Like it was a trade show that three big companies
Speaker 4:  were there. I think in Covid, sort like Microsoft pulled out. Then Sony pulled
Speaker 4:  out and there was like a question of whether it'll come back. And I think
Speaker 4:  those companies all, were like, wait, this sucked. Like we
Speaker 4:  can just do our own events, which is what all the tech companies have realized
Speaker 4:  over time. And there was no, there was no chance it was ever coming back
Speaker 9:  For years. I heard people say, oh, e three's gonna die this next year.
Speaker 9:  We don't need it. Particularly after that Santa Monica show where it got
Speaker 9:  like really tiny, they were like, oh, we don't need E three. But what I kept
Speaker 9:  hearing smart people in the room say was that
Speaker 9:  the executives at the video game companies would always need a
Speaker 9:  stage so that they could go glad hand each other and they
Speaker 9:  needed to have like some place where the meetings would happen. And now
Speaker 9:  we have Jeff Keeley with the Summer Game Fest and all those things,
Speaker 9:  and he'll gladly let people, executives, gland, hand each other on stage
Speaker 9:  even if they have nothing to show. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I mean that, that's, that's exactly what happened. Like that 2008 Santa Monica
Speaker 5:  show was, it had gotten too big, right? Like 2007 was enormous. It
Speaker 5:  was really, really unwieldy. It was not a great time. And so they said, okay,
Speaker 5:  we're gonna shrink it down. And then they reopened it and
Speaker 5:  they were like, well, we need more people, so we're gonna let anybody come.
Speaker 5:  And that just made it like not a trade show anymore, but this weird
Speaker 5:  hybrid that didn't make anybody happy. And then finally,
Speaker 5:  COVID came and like, like Covid Covid effectively,
Speaker 5:  like they realized Oh, all, yeah. Everybody realized, oh wait, don don't
Speaker 5:  need this. I don't actually need the Glad hand here. Jeff Cleve. Jeff,
Speaker 5:  Jeff Keeley, and you know, a web
Speaker 5:  broadcast is enough for me.
Speaker 4:  All, right. Well that's the Vergecast. We'll back next week. Cs,
Speaker 5:  The vibes are different for CES. People are
Speaker 11:  Pumped speaking such a downer. People are
Speaker 4:  Pumped. Are they?
Speaker 4:  Well we things, things that did not stop at
Speaker 6:  The pandemic
Speaker 4:  Back with a vengeance. Cs. No, that's it. Sean, thank you
Speaker 4:  so much for coming. This has been really fun. Oh, thank you.
Speaker 6:  Wait, can I just say one more thing before you, before you take us out? I
Speaker 6:  just, I just wanna shout out a, a person on Threads named Mark
Speaker 6:  Pono who decided that what he would do is post at me every single day
Speaker 6:  until I mentioned him on a Vergecast episode, which I had no intention of
Speaker 6:  ever doing. And then he did it for two weeks to the point where Threads
Speaker 6:  throttled him and wouldn't let him post for a whole day because they thought,
Speaker 6:  oh no, Threads thought he was harassing me. Aw. Oh no, he's allowed to post
Speaker 6:  again. But I just wanna say I hear you and thank you. And also please, no
Speaker 6:  one ever do that to me. Aw,
Speaker 4:  Very good. Very good site. Look great this week
Speaker 4:  you go read Sean's coverage of the trial, all sorts of other good stuff.
Speaker 6:  The Twitter package is amazing. Like truly Twitter package is amazing. If
Speaker 6:  you haven't been on the scroll back of Alexandria, I spent 90
Speaker 6:  full minutes just scrolling reading tweets and it is gig it the
Speaker 6:  single best way to kill time on the internet right now.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, that's it. That's for Chest
Speaker 1:  And that's a wrap for Vergecast this week. Hey, we'd love to hear from you.
Speaker 1:  Give us a call at eight six six VERGE one. One The Vergecast
Speaker 1:  is a production of The, Verge and Vox Media Podcast Network. The show is
Speaker 1:  produced by Andrew Marino and Liam James. This episode was mixed and edited
Speaker 1:  by Xander Adams. And that's it. We'll see you next week.