# Transcript
ID: 2ca2c6d1-d36b-47a9-825a-eb3704136447
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: The poster’s guide to the new internet
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/1408347795112102621/2152294294302122897/s93290-US-1812s-1698058293.mp3
Description: In episode three of our connectivity mini series, The Verge's David Pierce explores the idea of POSSE and PESOS, two syndication models for posting on the internet that don't rely on a single platform.
Buckle in, it gets nerdy.
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we love hearing from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Disabled
Speaker 1:  Support for this episode comes from Amazon Web Services. The
Speaker 1:  strength of your organization has everything to do with your applications,
Speaker 1:  from your back office operations to the applications that connect you to
Speaker 1:  your customers and partners. A W Ss continually innovates their
Speaker 1:  infrastructure and services so you can build, run and scale
Speaker 1:  applications in the cloud on premises and at the edge. That's
Speaker 1:  why millions of organizations trust a W Ss for every
Speaker 1:  application, wanna develop and deploy secure applications faster
Speaker 1:  so you can optimize costs and free up time to innovate for your customers.
Speaker 1:  Choose a W Ss and Power virtually any application
Speaker 1:  you can imagine.
Speaker 3:  Welcome, To, The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of really simple syndication.
Speaker 3:  I'm your friend David Pierce and this is the third episode in our series
Speaker 3:  all about connectivity. If you miss the first two episodes, we talked about
Speaker 3:  telly and how we connect to content and beeper and how we connect
Speaker 3:  to each other. They're both super fun episodes. You should listen to both.
Speaker 3:  Today I wanna talk about something a little different. I wanna talk about
Speaker 3:  posting and when I say posting, I mean it in the broadest possible
Speaker 3:  way. Like if messaging is how we talk to directly to each other,
Speaker 3:  posting is how we talk to the internet. An audience, the
Speaker 3:  whole world, whatever you want to think about posting the threads or X or
Speaker 3:  Instagram that's posting, uploading to YouTube or TikTok.
Speaker 3:  Also posting. Posting is how a lot of creators have made
Speaker 3:  careers. It's how a lot of people and companies and even governments
Speaker 3:  share and consume information. A huge portion of the internet
Speaker 3:  is just places for posting and for reading other people's posts. One
Speaker 3:  thing we've been talking a lot about on this show over the last year is the
Speaker 3:  way that these posting networks, these social networks are changing.
Speaker 3:  I really think we're at the end of what you might call the great platform
Speaker 3:  age where a handful of big companies and products like Facebook and Twitter
Speaker 3:  and Reddit and really not that many others, own all of the posting
Speaker 3:  systems. Recently we have things like Mastodon and Blue Sky,
Speaker 3:  which are big new ideas about how this all works. There are
Speaker 3:  more open, more interconnected, more like the web itself than
Speaker 3:  just a specific platform. We've talked a lot about Activity Pub on this
Speaker 3:  show in the last nine months or so. We're not gonna do too much of that
Speaker 3:  today. Activity Pub is the protocol that underlies a lot of the change that's
Speaker 3:  going on, but again, we're not gonna do too much of it. Just a, a tiny bit
Speaker 3:  of, lemme just play you this clip from Flipboard, C E o, Mike
Speaker 3:  McHugh from when he was on The Vergecast back in April.
Speaker 2:  Activity Pub You know, when I think about it, I think there are two things
Speaker 2:  that it does and one of them is to create an open social graph that
Speaker 2:  becomes a part of the web, which in and of itself is a very big
Speaker 2:  deal. The other thing it does is it creates a common
Speaker 2:  two-way streaming platform or or architecture that allows
Speaker 2:  services to be interoperable. So what this means is that
Speaker 2:  as we've seen all these social media platforms basically just
Speaker 2:  become other versions of themselves. They You know they all have vertical
Speaker 2:  video now. They're all copying each other. They all build everything into
Speaker 2:  this vertical stack that's totally proprietary. And if you leave and you
Speaker 2:  try to do a new one, you've gotta rebuild your social graph. As a creator,
Speaker 2:  that's a big issue. As a brand, as a publisher, that's a big problem.
Speaker 2:  So what this reminds me of is the days of a O l before the web
Speaker 2:  really happened, everything is built vertically. If you wanna do a You know,
Speaker 2:  put something up online, you have to go do a business development deal with
Speaker 2:  a O l and all of the innovation is locked in by
Speaker 2:  one company. So they're only doing as much as that one company can do.
Speaker 2:  And with this activity Pub Breakthrough And, what it really
Speaker 2:  allows is the web to flourish again and to You know
Speaker 2:  kind of reopen up all of that innovation that currently is really
Speaker 2:  controlled by just You know a handful of social media platforms
Speaker 2:  today.
Speaker 3:  Like I said, we're not going to spend today talking about Activity Pub. I
Speaker 3:  think it's important to understand, but that's not what we're here to do
Speaker 3:  today. We are going to talk about an acronym, sorry, not an acronym.
Speaker 3:  I always get that wrong. It's an initialism, two of them actually very similar
Speaker 3:  but also very different in some important ways. The first one is
Speaker 3:  POSSE P POSSE POSSE. It stands for post own site
Speaker 3:  syndicate everywhere. You don't have to remember that. I'll come back to
Speaker 3:  it. The other one is PESOS Similar but different
Speaker 3:  PESOS. It stands for Post Everywhere syndicate own site.
Speaker 3:  These are two ideas and really one idea in two parts about how
Speaker 3:  Post should work, but they're really not all that different from one another.
Speaker 3:  And I think that if you want to understand the future of posting, POSSE and
Speaker 3:  PESOS are the key. So the story of POSSE and PESOS starts in about
Speaker 3:  2012. It came out of a group called Indie Web, particularly
Speaker 3:  a guy named EC Celek. This is how Totec described the reason behind
Speaker 3:  the idea at a Google developers event. He was at all the way back in
Speaker 3:  2013,
Speaker 4:  Because I wanna own my own content, I wanna control it, but yet I still wanna
Speaker 4:  stay in touch with my friends. And that's really where POSSE came from was
Speaker 4:  this like diligent desire to own your own content. But then like, hey, my
Speaker 4:  friends are reading on Twitter or my friends are reading on Facebook, or
Speaker 4:  my friends are reading on Google Reader. Wherever they're reading, you're
Speaker 4:  like, okay, I have to have a feed, right? If someone's using a feed reader
Speaker 4:  or if someone's just using Twitter, I need to post copies of my content to
Speaker 4:  Twitter or Facebook. But in all those cases, one thing we've we've tried
Speaker 4:  to do is like make sure that there's always links or or some identifier pointing
Speaker 4:  back to the original. And that's important because when you start kind of
Speaker 4:  forking these conversations in these different forums, you may want to actually
Speaker 4:  integrate them back right in your own site and somebody might wanna see like
Speaker 4:  the whole story of what's going on. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  The idea behind POSSE is basically this, instead of posting by logging
Speaker 3:  into some platform and posting only for that platform and the people on it,
Speaker 3:  then logging into another platform and posting different stuff for that platform
Speaker 3:  and those people, the place you post should be your own website,
Speaker 3:  a blog, social feed, a gallery, whatever it should be, your
Speaker 3:  website. And that link back part that EC was talking about is
Speaker 3:  also really important. You see some POSSE believers around the internet,
Speaker 3:  they use full links to their post at the end of every post that they share.
Speaker 3:  Others will add like a six digit ID that you can add to their
Speaker 3:  website U R L and find it that way. Either way, the goal is to have your
Speaker 3:  stuff be everywhere, but to always be bringing people back toward
Speaker 3:  your own site. The idea is that a thing is yours that you publish
Speaker 3:  on and that's where everything starts. The way I think about it is like who
Speaker 3:  owns the publish button right now the platforms do you post on X
Speaker 3:  by typing in a text box on X, you post on Instagram by
Speaker 3:  using Instagram's upload feature. But in a POSSE world, the publish button
Speaker 3:  lives on your website, your blog, whatever thing you've created,
Speaker 3:  you post there and whatever you post gets disseminated to all the places
Speaker 3:  that your audience is. I really like this approach. This approach has a bunch
Speaker 3:  of benefits too, starting with the fact that it's just easier, right? Right
Speaker 3:  now, even if you wanna post the exact same thing to X and
Speaker 3:  Threads and Mastodon, you have to log into three services. You do a bunch
Speaker 3:  of copying and pasting, you post in each one individually. You have kind
Speaker 3:  of three different conversations on three different platforms. It's just
Speaker 3:  disconnected in a way that it shouldn't be. If you've ever used a tool like
Speaker 3:  Hootsuite or Sprinkler or one of those apps that brands use to post their
Speaker 3:  stuff around the web, You know how useful. Just a simple better posting tool
Speaker 3:  can actually be. POSSE would give those tools to everybody.
Speaker 3:  PESOS by the way, is kind of the exact inverse. In a PESOS world,
Speaker 3:  you can publish from anywhere using any tools on any platform and everything
Speaker 3:  you publish gets sent back to your site. So you post on Instagram
Speaker 3:  with Instagram's tools, you post on X with X's tools, but all of it gets
Speaker 3:  pulled back to your website, your blog, whatever. It's in that world.
Speaker 3:  Your website becomes more like an archive of your stuff published
Speaker 3:  elsewhere, whereas POSSE sees it as the place for the best version of your
Speaker 3:  posts. That's where people should go to interact with you. The difference
Speaker 3:  is subtle but important, but generally I think both sides really see the
Speaker 3:  world the same way and think that in general, this platform specificity
Speaker 3:  is a bad idea. That's really the bigger picture here. POSSE
Speaker 3:  and PESOS both want to totally upend the way we think about our content and
Speaker 3:  social networks right now. These social platforms say that you own your
Speaker 3:  content but you don't really, if a social platform goes away, your stuff
Speaker 3:  is just gone. If a platform decides you violated the rules and deletes
Speaker 3:  your stuff also gone in the same way that Activity Pub makes your
Speaker 3:  social graph portable between networks, POSSE turns the social networks
Speaker 3:  into destinations for your content but not the place you create
Speaker 3:  anything. I think that difference is really important and the more I've learned
Speaker 3:  about POSSE, the more I've come to see it as a potentially powerful new way
Speaker 3:  to think about posting and building content in general. But it also does
Speaker 3:  raise some really complicated questions. The way we think about posting now
Speaker 3:  posting is really only half the equation. So what's Posse's
Speaker 3:  plan for likes and reposts and comments and replies and all the rest of the
Speaker 3:  engagement that comes on these platforms. And if Posse's idea is
Speaker 3:  to just post the same thing on a hundred different platforms, is that actually
Speaker 3:  what we want? And just from a pure aesthetic perspective,
Speaker 3:  how does all of that work on one website? How do I make the
Speaker 3:  whole internet of posting and content make sense on my
Speaker 3:  domain? I asked Cory Dro, the author and activist in one of the Internet's
Speaker 3:  most kind of tenured bloggers, what he thought about all of this. He said
Speaker 3:  that when he set up his new blog pluralistic about two years ago, he tried
Speaker 3:  to adhere to the POSSE way of life and then he explained how his
Speaker 3:  system works. I'm gonna play you his entire answer, which is very
Speaker 3:  long and very technical because I think it's useful to understand what
Speaker 3:  it takes right now to really make this work.
Speaker 5:  I wanted to find a way to stand up a new platform in this moment
Speaker 5:  where everyone gets their news and their You know does their reading
Speaker 5:  through these silos that then hold you to ransom.
Speaker 5:  And I wanted to use those silos to bring in readers and to
Speaker 5:  attract and engage with an audience, but I didn't wanna become beholden to
Speaker 5:  them. And So I made my own POSSE thing. And so as when I started,
Speaker 5:  I literally had an H T M L template in the default Linux editor,
Speaker 5:  which is called Get It, which I've got like emax key bindings on. And I just
Speaker 5:  literally would open that file and re-save it with a different file name,
Speaker 5:  like I had a pen the day's date to it, and then write a bunch of blog posts
Speaker 5:  in this template. And then I would copy and paste those
Speaker 5:  into Twitter's threading tool and mask it on and
Speaker 5:  Tumblr and Medium like one at a time,
Speaker 5:  individually editing as I went. And then I would turn it into a
Speaker 5:  text file that I would paste into an email that I would send to a mailman
Speaker 5:  instance where I was hosting a newsletter and then I had full
Speaker 5:  text r s s as well and Discourse for Comments, which has its own
Speaker 5:  syndication for people to follow you on discourse. That was a lot of manual
Speaker 5:  work and I made a lot of mistakes. And a guy, Lauren
Speaker 5:  Kornfield, who's a like legendary cryptographer who was following it,
Speaker 5:  took notice of how many manual errors I was making and said
Speaker 5:  like, do you need me to write you some Python scripts? And so he did. He
Speaker 5:  wrote me a little Python script that automates about three
Speaker 5:  quarters of that work, which still leaves me with substantial
Speaker 5:  work to do. So I'm, I have a text editor tab open that
Speaker 5:  has one of the two posts I'm gonna post today in it already
Speaker 5:  and the other one just as a skeleton. And then I
Speaker 5:  have a template file that has all the things that change from
Speaker 5:  day-to-day, like a recap of yesterday's posts, my
Speaker 5:  overview of my blog posts from 20 years, 15 years, 10 years,
Speaker 5:  five years, and one year ago my upcoming talks and
Speaker 5:  promotional messages. I'm, I'm running a Kickstarter for my next novel. If
Speaker 5:  I can plug that it's at lost-caused.org and
Speaker 5:  So. I've got that open. I've got a template open for social media from
Speaker 5:  Mastodon and Twitter that has a slightly different version of those same
Speaker 5:  things that I manually maintain. I have a file called Twitter two and a file
Speaker 5:  called Mastodon two, which have captures of that second post
Speaker 5:  that I'm gonna publish today, but not the first one. There's an empty file
Speaker 5:  called Twitter and Mastodon that are still on my, on my desk. And then
Speaker 5:  in one Firefox window I have probably about 10
Speaker 5:  tabs. Three are for medium, one is for WordPress, three or for Tumblr, three
Speaker 5:  or four Twitter and three or for Mastodon that are just kind of the templates
Speaker 5:  for these things. And then in another window I have
Speaker 5:  1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10 different tabs
Speaker 5:  for articles that I'm going to refer to in today's blog post.
Speaker 5:  And So I will then compose that in the text editor, run the Python
Speaker 5:  scripts on them. That takes as long as it takes to write a blog post.
Speaker 5:  But then I will spend probably another hour getting
Speaker 5:  everything into all of those feeds.
Speaker 3:  Okay, you get the idea right? The process is rough. Corey finished his thought
Speaker 3:  here by being very annoyed at how hard it is to post long threads on X
Speaker 3:  these days. And he's right. And here's the problem. The existing
Speaker 3:  platforms X and all the rest have no incentive at all to make it easy
Speaker 3:  for you to bring stuff in or get stuff out. They want to keep you using
Speaker 3:  their tools on their platform as much as possible. But not
Speaker 3:  only are platforms like Blue Sky and Mastodon and Pixel Fed inventing new
Speaker 3:  more open tools for posting and reading, there are new apps
Speaker 3:  out there trying to passify the internet as we know it. Now
Speaker 3:  we're gonna take a quick break and then we're gonna talk to the creator of
Speaker 3:  one of them. We'll be right back.
Speaker 1:  Thank you to Amazon Web Services for sponsoring Vergecast
Speaker 1:  A w s has been innovating infrastructure for over 15 years
Speaker 1:  so you can build and run secure performance applications faster and
Speaker 1:  more economically. That's why a w s pioneered serverless technology
Speaker 1:  in 2014 with the launch of a w s Lambda.
Speaker 7:  Lambda allows developers to supply snippets of code in various
Speaker 7:  languages like Java or Python or otherwise, and we run it on
Speaker 7:  their behalf using a S'S power of infrastructure.
Speaker 1:  AJ NIR is Lambda's general manager with a W Ss Serverless Services.
Speaker 1:  Customers can offload most operational responsibilities to a w s
Speaker 1:  and get built-in high availability, scalability and security best
Speaker 1:  practices by default
Speaker 7:  And, what that means is they can get a, what we would call a production grade
Speaker 7:  application up and running in factors of time that are three to five times
Speaker 7:  shorter than it used to be in the past.
Speaker 1:  AJ will be back later in the show to tell you more about how a w s
Speaker 1:  serverless technologies make it easy to scale and manage cloud applications.
Speaker 1:  Reimagine your applications with a w s
Speaker 3:  All, right? We're back. I think POSSE, as I've been saying, is a really good
Speaker 3:  idea. I really believe in the idea of having your own space and owning your
Speaker 3:  own content online. I'm just not at all sure how it's supposed to like
Speaker 3:  work and how it's gonna be easier and more doable than just signing up
Speaker 3:  for a Facebook account. So I called up Manton Reese, who's the founder of
Speaker 3:  a service called Micro Blog to see how he thinks about it. Micro Blog
Speaker 3:  has been around since 2017. It didn't necessarily start as a
Speaker 3:  POSSE tool or a way to do activity pub posting. It just started because
Speaker 3:  Manton thought well before Elon Musk showed up that we needed a Twitter
Speaker 3:  that wasn't owned and operated by one single company.
Speaker 8:  One of the original premises was just could we rebuild a Twitter
Speaker 8:  like user experience but base it on blogs? So the
Speaker 8:  timeline in Micro Blog is just posts from lots of feeds, lots of R S Ss feeds,
Speaker 8:  whether they're hosted a Microsoft blog or they're hosted somewhere else,
Speaker 8:  so, so how do we merge those together so you don't just have like a few
Speaker 8:  tabs open with your favorite websites and you're typing in the domain name
Speaker 8:  that it's more of a newsfeed timeline experience and
Speaker 8:  that's what people want. But if the foundation of that, if the protocols
Speaker 8:  can be open, it allows us to just build so many interesting apps,
Speaker 8:  so many different types of experiences, it'll just be way, way
Speaker 8:  better.
Speaker 3:  That philosophy, the stuff he's talking about there became a lot more real
Speaker 3:  for him and I think for a lot of people on the internet over the last year,
Speaker 3:  frankly whatever you think about how Elon Musk is doing at X, the
Speaker 3:  whole saga has made really clear that the services we care about and
Speaker 3:  post on are Fragile Micro blog now lets you keep a
Speaker 3:  simple blog, which kind of looks like Tumblr I guess, and you can post photos
Speaker 3:  or texts or links or whatever. And when you post to Micro Blog,
Speaker 3:  you can also automatically post to Mastodon, Tumblr, blue Sky, medium,
Speaker 3:  LinkedIn, pixeled, no Stir and Flicker. It's a lot of services.
Speaker 3:  One of the big criticisms that I've heard of the POSSE approach and of tools
Speaker 3:  like Micro Blog is that actually posting the same content to
Speaker 3:  all of those different networks is a terrible idea. Networks have
Speaker 3:  different audiences, different people, different norms, different ways of
Speaker 3:  engaging with the system. At some point, if you're just posting to a bunch
Speaker 3:  of places all at once, aren't you basically spam? When I put that
Speaker 3:  question to Manton, he said he doesn't really see it that way.
Speaker 8:  I think it really depends on the person, like what you're trying to get out
Speaker 8:  of posting. If you are a quote unquote like social media
Speaker 8:  presence and you are an influencer and you are really needing to target
Speaker 8:  different groups, sure, but if you are posting first
Speaker 8:  for yourself, like I want, I'm doing something, I'm thinking about something,
Speaker 8:  I wanna share this with the world, then it's really a secondary
Speaker 8:  decision about how people receive it. Like so for me, I like to post
Speaker 8:  to my blog, I like everything to be there and if I post a photo to my blog,
Speaker 8:  it would be great if everybody on different networks could see it.
Speaker 3:  Manden did agree though that the user interface for all of this is bad
Speaker 3:  starting at the very beginning, which is that you have to register your own
Speaker 3:  domain. That is already too much work and expense for a lot of people.
Speaker 3:  I mean, who wants to manage d n s records? Who even wants to know what d
Speaker 3:  n s records are? Micro Blog does push you to register your own
Speaker 3:  domain during the setup process, but Manson actually said it probably doesn't
Speaker 3:  push hard enough and make it easy enough. And in general, he said
Speaker 3:  the real bar for websites and for POSSE in general is that you have to be
Speaker 3:  easier than creating a social account. And the thing is, it's really,
Speaker 3:  really easy to create a social account. That's a hard, hard bar to
Speaker 3:  clear. Okay, we've gotta take one more quick break and then I have one more
Speaker 3:  person I wanna talk to about all of this. One of the people in charge of
Speaker 3:  the Internet's biggest posting platform and someone who thinks about this
Speaker 3:  stuff way more than most, we'll be right back,
Speaker 7:  Fox Creative.
Speaker 1:  This is advertiser content brought to you by Amazon Web Services.
Speaker 1:  AJ NA from a w s says there's an easy way to understand the
Speaker 1:  benefits of serverless app development.
Speaker 7:  So, I. Think about serverless closer to the concept of wireless,
Speaker 7:  meaning
Speaker 1:  The servers are there, you just don't have to think about it.
Speaker 7:  They become our problem to worry about.
Speaker 1:  That means no infrastructure to provision or manage no operating systems
Speaker 1:  to install, upgrade or patch a w s takes care of it all for you.
Speaker 7:  A lot of the innovation we see in the market today I don't believe would
Speaker 7:  have been possible if something like cloud services did not exist as the
Speaker 7:  accelerant. That's
Speaker 1:  Because serverless technologies from Amazon help customers across
Speaker 1:  industries do two very important things. First, serverless
Speaker 1:  technologies eliminate operational overhead so your teams can release
Speaker 1:  quickly, get feedback and iterate to get to market faster.
Speaker 7:  The customer is always gonna pick the one who meets their needs faster. Second,
Speaker 1:  A w s serverless solutions reduce total cost of ownership
Speaker 1:  with a pay for value billing model. So you never pay for resources, you
Speaker 1:  don't need
Speaker 7:  The total cost of ownership and infrastructure costs are lower than what
Speaker 7:  they would do if they were building on their own. I continue to marvel that
Speaker 7:  when we see companies that are built by one and two people that are serving
Speaker 7:  millions of customers and helping millions of people around the world do
Speaker 7:  things better. And those are the kind of accelerations that happen when customers
Speaker 7:  use cloud services.
Speaker 1:  Learn how a Wix serverless technologies can help you
Speaker 1:  accelerate innovation and lower TCO for your
Speaker 1:  applications@go.aws slash every app.
Speaker 3:  All, right? We're back. I've become obsessed in recent months with this question
Speaker 3:  of how a POSSE system can work. How I as a poster
Speaker 3:  can control where all my stuff is, where things go, I can engage with people
Speaker 3:  but do it all through a place that is mine. It's a really complicated system.
Speaker 3:  It's kind of a rewiring of the entire internet in a certain way and I
Speaker 3:  think it's gonna take everything from domain registrars to R ss s
Speaker 3:  readers to social platforms to think totally differently about how they operate
Speaker 3:  if we're gonna make this work. And frankly I've wondered a lot if this is
Speaker 3:  just an impossible dream, a cool idea about the internet of 20
Speaker 3:  years ago that just can't exist anymore. Like is the toothpaste just out
Speaker 3:  of the tube on this stuff Now to help me sort through it, I called up Matt
Speaker 3:  Mullenweg, the c e O of Automatic and one of the most important people working
Speaker 3:  on WordPress, which is the software that powers basically half the internet.
Speaker 3:  Matt has been a blogger for two decades and has been working on posting
Speaker 3:  software for pretty much just as long So I figured he might have some thoughts
Speaker 3:  and surprise, surprise, he had some thoughts. The first thing I asked him
Speaker 3:  was if he was familiar with the POSSE and PESOS ideas. He said yes
Speaker 3:  he was. And that he actually liked the theory of it quite a bit.
Speaker 9:  As someone publishing, I want as much interaction as possible,
Speaker 9:  so why are you making me choose which network it goes to? I should post it
Speaker 9:  once ideally to my domain and then it goes to x
Speaker 9:  slash Twitter and Threads and Tumblr and all the other networks that have,
Speaker 9:  can have their own interfaces and network effects and everything like that.
Speaker 9:  But my thoughts should go to all those places. They should
Speaker 9:  all have APIs where whatever interactions are happening on those platforms,
Speaker 9:  I should be able to bring them in. There's actually some really cool plugins
Speaker 9:  for WordPress that'll bring in like Twitter replies to tweets, which I think
Speaker 9:  is kind of interesting. And then as well, if I'm interacting with someone
Speaker 9:  else with their own domain, their own open web thing, like there should be
Speaker 9:  a way for our sites to talk to each other in a way that yeah, that has the
Speaker 9:  same effect as what's sort of simple to do in these monolithic
Speaker 9:  domain architectures.
Speaker 3:  This is where I'm really curious how you think about it as not somebody who
Speaker 3:  runs one of these companies but who has like been a blogger on the internet
Speaker 3:  for a really long time. 'cause I think the counter that I've heard to the
Speaker 3:  POSSE idea is that it's just not true that you can
Speaker 3:  post one thing and syndicated it everywhere and it will work that fundamentally
Speaker 3:  even all, all the networks are just text boxes or vertical video, but they
Speaker 3:  want different things, they have different norms and you actually have to
Speaker 3:  kind of be different things in different places because that's just how these
Speaker 3:  systems work. Is that a surmountable thing in the kind of
Speaker 3:  POSSE era? What do you make of that criticism of the The thesis? Yeah,
Speaker 9:  I mean there's nuance to each one of course, and there's like
Speaker 9:  public companies like Sprinkler or Sprout that that all they do is like
Speaker 9:  allow folks who want to post to all these places like manage that. We've
Speaker 9:  been thinking in our Jetpack plugin as well, we've been thinking a lot about
Speaker 9:  what's the right UI for this. I think there might be something like the first
Speaker 9:  step is posting to my blog and the second step is I kind of get some
Speaker 9:  opportunities to customize it for each network versus I think where we messed
Speaker 9:  up a little bit is by trying to make this all automated, which by
Speaker 9:  definition maybe loses some of the nuance of like
Speaker 9:  cropping the image a certain way or, or maybe even not having a
Speaker 9:  link, maybe you don't You know link back to your post, which you just sort
Speaker 9:  of associate the ID of a tweet with a canonical
Speaker 9:  post on your side and then you kind of figure it out on your side versus
Speaker 9:  trying to have them link back to you So I think there's, this is
Speaker 9:  actually more of a a user interface and user flow issue than it is
Speaker 9:  necessarily a technical one. I'm really into this kind of two or three step
Speaker 9:  publishing process as as part of this, as a way to get around this.
Speaker 9:  The other nice thing is that like you want to aggregate as well, So I,
Speaker 9:  I don't want to have to go to all these places necessarily to find the people
Speaker 9:  who I really care about following. Like maybe I'll open an app to see what
Speaker 9:  their flavor of algorithm is and if it surfaces anything interesting for
Speaker 9:  me, but for people I truly wanna follow. I kind of want something that brings
Speaker 9:  that all together in a way that, again, as someone who runs
Speaker 9:  a network like Tumblr, like I know this is like a trade off 'cause I want
Speaker 9:  people obviously to come to my thing. So I can show 'em ads and support the
Speaker 9:  service and everything, but as a user I, I really want everything together
Speaker 9:  in one. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  I think that's right. I think part of why I'm so excited about this whole
Speaker 3:  next phase is that like the creating the platform
Speaker 3:  and the consumption can all be different things. They can all be the same
Speaker 3:  thing in the same place, but they can also be all different things in different
Speaker 3:  places. And if there's just a whole bunch of like fascinating products that
Speaker 3:  are gonna appear when you can just be a reading app. Like
Speaker 3:  the folks at Flipboard I know are thinking a lot about this stuff. They're
Speaker 3:  like, how do we make the best reading experience for the Fedi verse? We don't
Speaker 3:  even have to worry about the text box to post in. We just want figure out
Speaker 3:  consumption. And I think splitting up that stuff is so interesting because
Speaker 9:  A few jobs to be done when you think about it like, and the apps bundle them
Speaker 9:  into one thing. 'cause paper used to bundle like classified and
Speaker 9:  obituaries and news and journalism and like lifestyle
Speaker 9:  stuff. Like what they do is they bundle like, I'm bored and I
Speaker 9:  wanna see something from people I follow. I'm bored and I wanna see things
Speaker 9:  that maybe, I don't know I, I want You know, which is actually where they've
Speaker 9:  scaled a lot. I want to publish something. And then finally like I
Speaker 9:  wanna see how people are interacting with the thing. I published, I guess
Speaker 9:  maybe a fifth, I wanna reply to things that people have published or share
Speaker 9:  things that people published. That's a really lovely loop. And actually one
Speaker 9:  of the things I I miss most about Kind the Reader days is like
Speaker 9:  how much it would get me to blog. Hmm. Because when I was kind of one click
Speaker 9:  or I used the WordPress Bookmarklet You know I could be on indie site
Speaker 9:  reading any article and it was just one click to kinda share that to my blog.
Speaker 9:  But at some point, I think especially with WordPress making the title so
Speaker 9:  prominent, like we, we made it a little too heavy to do a post and I
Speaker 9:  want something a little bit more like a Cott Key or Daring Fireball
Speaker 9:  or like some of these longstanding blogs and I've, how I've been trying to
Speaker 9:  redesign my blog Ma tt is to also have these titleless posts
Speaker 9:  which are a little just lower You know the big title and the big image really
Speaker 9:  makes you feel like you gotta write like an essay, gotta do something like,
Speaker 9:  like you post where it's like really thought through and has lots of, but
Speaker 9:  sometimes I just wanna shoot something off a little shorter. It's not really
Speaker 9:  a tweet 'cause I wanna have links and like I want it to be rich, but it's,
Speaker 9:  it's not like a essay either. It's not You know one of these Magnum opuses
Speaker 9:  that Mark Andre or Paul Graham post.
Speaker 3:  I've been researching this stuff and talking to people about it for months
Speaker 3:  now and here's what I think. I think this is the way, I think
Speaker 3:  it's a shame that we've all gotten used to giving away all of our posts and
Speaker 3:  all of our content just to get the engagement and connection that we get
Speaker 3:  from these platforms. I think it is possible to have it both ways and I think
Speaker 3:  a POSSE style system is a really cool way to get there.
Speaker 3:  Just as I'm hopeful that Activity Pub is gonna win and open up social to
Speaker 3:  many more platforms and systems and ways of thinking about the world.
Speaker 3:  I'm hopeful that POSSE can win too because I think we shouldn't be stuck
Speaker 3:  on platforms and more of the internet should belong to us and not companies.
Speaker 3:  And there are some really exciting signs here. I think the thing Blue Sky
Speaker 3:  is doing where you can use your domain name as your username is awesome.
Speaker 3:  A bunch of people I talk to mention that to me as one sign of doing
Speaker 3:  this exactly the right way. I also think tools like Micro Blog are a big
Speaker 3:  deal and I think the growth of these new platforms like Blue Sky and Macedon
Speaker 3:  can also bring new growth not just in how we post, but in how we consume
Speaker 3:  posts and how we sort them and how we organize them. All of this is being
Speaker 3:  broken into pieces in really interesting ways. I also think it might
Speaker 3:  just be impossible to pull all of this off. The truth is we do live
Speaker 3:  in an era of walled gardens where the biggest businesses in the world have
Speaker 3:  figured out how to keep us and our posts glued to their feed and
Speaker 3:  addicted to their published buttons. For POSSE to Work, we'll basically take
Speaker 3:  a complete reinvention of the internet from the blogging software to
Speaker 3:  the social networks to like literally the GoDaddy interface. All of it
Speaker 3:  is gonna have to change in order for this to work in big, meaningful
Speaker 3:  internet shaping ways. If all of that does happen, and again, I'm hopeful
Speaker 3:  but skeptical that it will happen, it won't happen fast or soon. Even
Speaker 3:  in 2012 when the indie web community was first talking about
Speaker 3:  POSSE, the web was a more open and less commercialized place than it is
Speaker 3:  now. Now, I mean, You know what it's like to be online, it's just commerce
Speaker 3:  everywhere. So stay tuned on POSSE and PESOS. But here
Speaker 3:  is my one piece of very specific advice for right now, buy a
Speaker 3:  domain name. If you don't already have one, buy one that feels like it could
Speaker 3:  be your internet home, your username, your blog, your archive, your
Speaker 3:  publish button, your everything. Personally, I bought David Pierce
Speaker 3:  XYZ a while ago for this exact purpose, but I'm looking at it now and I could
Speaker 3:  be David Pierce dot social, david Pierce dot guitars, david Pierce dot bingo,
Speaker 3:  which actually rules David Pierce dot golf, David Pierce dot apartments,
Speaker 3:  and so many other things. Get a domain and get ready for the future when
Speaker 3:  that domain is like your phone number or your email address or your
Speaker 3:  username, that it is the signal of the part of the internet that actually
Speaker 3:  belongs to you. I don't know how long it's gonna take for it to be like that,
Speaker 3:  but I think it's gonna be great.
Speaker 3:  All, right? That's it for The Vergecast today. Thank you so much to everyone
Speaker 3:  who is on the show, and thank you as always for listening. This show is produced
Speaker 3:  by Andrew Moreno and Liam James The. Vergecast is Verge production and part
Speaker 3:  of the Vox Media podcast network. We'll be back with episodes on Wednesday
Speaker 3:  and Friday. There's still tons of news to cover this week from yet another
Speaker 3:  Netflix price hike to cyber truck ship dates, to Mario Games and
Speaker 3:  lots more. And then we'll be back next Monday with the fourth and final episode
Speaker 3:  in our connectivity series. See you then. Rock and roll.
Speaker 1:  Thank you to Amazon Web Services for supporting Vergecast.
Speaker 1:  According to Deloitte, customers who choose a w s serverless
Speaker 1:  services can reduce their total cost of ownership by up to
Speaker 1:  57% and reduce their development time by
Speaker 1:  68%. The
Speaker 7:  More you can leverage the capabilities that are already out there, the faster
Speaker 7:  you're gonna be able to innovate on behalf of customers and absorb all the
Speaker 7:  great trends that are happening in the market today. And that's where a lot
Speaker 7:  of the million plus customers we have on Lambda today see the value and continue
Speaker 7:  to users us today.
Speaker 1:  A Wix serverless can help you get your applications to market faster
Speaker 1:  while reducing your total cost of ownership. Learn more at
Speaker 1:  go.aws/aws. Four EA.