# Transcript
ID: b603e971-b518-4efc-b4c7-19e9e6010b8b
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Can AI make a hit song?
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-437098082491250407/-4712198776586149341/s93290-US-3600s-1695031564.mp3
Description: In episode two of The Vergecast's AI mini series, David Pierce sits down with Switched on Pop's Charlie Harding and music producer Ian Kimmel to share how they made an entire song from scratch using a bunch of AI tools.
Later, Nilay Patel joins the discussion to talk about the future of AI in the music industry.
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we'd love to hear from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (3 ads detected)
Speaker 3:  Welcome to The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of procedurally generated
Speaker 3:  four on the floor. I'm your friend, David Pierce, and this is the second
Speaker 3:  episode in our three-part series about ai. What we're trying to do in these
Speaker 3:  episodes is not just talk about AI as a theory or
Speaker 3:  fast forward a dozen or a hundred years to when AI takes over the world
Speaker 3:  and kills us all, but actually look at what AI is really doing
Speaker 3:  in our lives right now. This week we're gonna talk about how AI is
Speaker 3:  changing music, and we actually got started down this
Speaker 3:  particular rabbit hole while we were making last week's episode about cloning
Speaker 3:  your voice because in the making of that episode, we discovered this tool
Speaker 3:  called sify.ai that claims to be able to train a model to
Speaker 3:  sound not like your speaking voice, but your singing voice.
Speaker 3:  As far as I can tell, SIFY isn't really a production
Speaker 3:  tool so much as it is sort of a silly tool to let you make songs using
Speaker 3:  voices like, I don't know, SpongeBob Squarepants,
Speaker 3:  Michael Jackson.
Speaker 1:  But
Speaker 3:  You can also train it with your own. So obviously I had to test that.
Speaker 3:  So I got out my mic, put on some headphones, and I spent about an hour
Speaker 3:  singing a few of my favorite songs into a recorder. I'm not going to play
Speaker 3:  those recordings for reasons of my own embarrassment, but also because trust
Speaker 3:  me, literally no one needs to hear that. But the thing is,
Speaker 3:  you're kind of about to hear my voice anyway,
Speaker 3:  or@leastwhatsify.ai thinks. I sound like
Speaker 3:  The process is kind of weird. You upload a bunch of stuff, it processes your
Speaker 3:  voice, and then you just plug in a YouTube U R l, it tries
Speaker 3:  to extract the vocals, then sort of paste yours back in
Speaker 3:  and then rewrite the song using your voice. It's wonky, but it's
Speaker 3:  super fun and pretty quick. So without further ado, please welcome
Speaker 3:  to the stage AI David Pierce singing. I Wanna Hold Your Hand by the
Speaker 3:  Beatles.
Speaker 3:  It's actually not
Speaker 5:  Bad.
Speaker 1:  Like
Speaker 3:  I cannot stand the sound of my own singing voice, but that does kind of
Speaker 3:  sound like me, I think at least until you get a little further into the
Speaker 3:  song and then it all just completely falls apart
Speaker 5:  And when,
Speaker 3:  Okay, I feel happy. Okay, I could do this forever. We made a lot of songs,
Speaker 3:  but I'll only do one more here. This is Suspicious Minds by Elvis
Speaker 3:  Presley, by ai. David Pierce.
Speaker 5:  We,
Speaker 5:  I can walk out.
Speaker 1:  Oh, Lori.
Speaker 3:  Okay. Let's just move on. Before this goes any further off the rails, or
Speaker 3:  everyone stops listening because of my voice, let's bring in a couple of
Speaker 3:  actual musicians to talk about how AI is changing the way we make
Speaker 3:  music. My guests today are Charlie Harding, a songwriter and the co-host
Speaker 3:  of the wonderful podcast Switched on Pop, who has been on this show before.
Speaker 3:  He is responsible for Laser Bong
Speaker 6:  It
Speaker 3:  And Ian Kimmel, a producer and songwriter who has worked with everyone from
Speaker 3:  B T S to Mary j Blige to Netflix. And the N B A Ian also
Speaker 3:  runs a company called Biscuit Head Collective, which works with artists of
Speaker 3:  all sizes to make songs. So you could say AI is very important
Speaker 3:  to both of these people and their livelihood going forward, and I wanna
Speaker 3:  know how they're thinking about it right now and how it fits in
Speaker 3:  Charlie. Harding, welcome back to The Vergecast. Thank you for having me.
Speaker 3:  This is, it's just delightful having you back. It always gets weird when
Speaker 3:  you're here, which is my favorite thing about having you here. It's gonna
Speaker 7:  Get weird today.
Speaker 3:  Ian Kibble, welcome to the show. Thanks for,
Speaker 5:  Thank you so much for having me as well.
Speaker 3:  Okay. So I wanna do this episode in two parts. Sure. Talking about AI is
Speaker 3:  very complicated because you end up having to talk about like the cool things
Speaker 3:  it can be and then the terrifying things about it. And then we're all gonna
Speaker 3:  die and it's illegal all at the same time. So we're just gonna split those
Speaker 3:  things apart. Yeah. So for the first half of the show, I want to talk like
Speaker 3:  super practical, how this stuff actually works, what you can do with it.
Speaker 3:  You're both professional musicians. I wanna talk about like how this actually
Speaker 3:  works like in the world. And then we're going to take a break, we're gonna
Speaker 3:  collect ourselves, and then we're gonna talk about our feelings. Yeah. Does
Speaker 3:  that sound good? Sounds great. Go. You guys good with that? Yeah. Okay. So
Speaker 3:  I gave you guys some homework and we're gonna get to it in a minute and it's
Speaker 3:  very exciting. But I think the first place I wanna start is like, if you're
Speaker 3:  a working musician today in September of 2023,
Speaker 3:  are you thinking about AI in your day-to-day, like at all? Right now,
Speaker 7:  I am as a music reporter. Sure. But in terms of making music,
Speaker 7:  I think we probably share this. The only tool I've really used to assist
Speaker 7:  in any part of the creative process, it's been chat pt. But even that is
Speaker 7:  quite limited.
Speaker 3:  Interesting. That's not at all what I would've guessed. Oh yeah. So how are
Speaker 3:  you using it right now? Like where would chat g p t fit in? You
Speaker 7:  Can use it as a rhyming dictionary. Ooh, okay. But it hasn't come into my
Speaker 7:  life very much. I mean, I, I wanted to bring Ian into this conversation because
Speaker 7:  I feel like he kind of has of has, I think he has the most skin in the game.
Speaker 7:  Sure. Because on top of being a record producer, he's got
Speaker 7:  You know Platinum Records, Grammy nominations. He also runs a
Speaker 7:  business where he will help you take your indie track and make it a like
Speaker 7:  top 40 professional style song. So if there's anyone who probably cares
Speaker 7:  about the world of AI replacing musical things, like, I mean, he's
Speaker 7:  directly invested in it. So I'm curious. Yeah. Has, how has AI been in your
Speaker 7:  life?
Speaker 8:  I mean, the number one thing to think about, at least when I'm jumping into
Speaker 8:  it is generally You know we we, we go back a couple decades
Speaker 8:  and we're looking at people like going to tape and that kind of thing. And
Speaker 8:  Then, we have things like vsts, the plugins, replacing all that.
Speaker 8:  So now we're getting into this new era of AI and like all these
Speaker 8:  new technologies coming out that the number one thing I'm paying attention
Speaker 8:  to is just trying to be current. I'm young, I'm in my twenties. But at the
Speaker 8:  same time, with all this technology we have to do, like it has to, we always
Speaker 8:  have to keep up with the times, otherwise we're gonna get left behind. But
Speaker 8:  there is so many amazing functions going on inside of it. And
Speaker 8:  me being a music professional who is a musician that can play multiple
Speaker 8:  instruments and program drums and all that kind of stuff, it doesn't come
Speaker 8:  into my world as often as like a new music producer would. Okay. Just
Speaker 8:  because there's so many season. So you think
Speaker 3:  If you were starting fresh right now trying to get in the game, you think
Speaker 3:  you would be maybe more invested in figuring out some of the AI stuff?
Speaker 8:  Definitely. Yeah. Interesting. If I didn't know how to program drums, there's,
Speaker 8:  you can just pull up this one V S T that allows you to program
Speaker 8:  drums with a hit of a button. It automatically reads your tempo. You can
Speaker 8:  set the vibe that you want and then you got drums and then you click the
Speaker 8:  button again and then you have a variation of that. And it just, there's
Speaker 8:  so many tools that it's creating to really save time. And also
Speaker 8:  in the learning process, it's a bigger jump, it's a lot quicker. So it's
Speaker 8:  allowing new music producers to be able to jump on way quicker. But that
Speaker 8:  being said, the thing I only really use in my professional life would be
Speaker 8:  chat G P T
Speaker 3:  For the same reasoning, dictionaries, all that stuff.
Speaker 8:  Not as much for me. Sometimes lyric editing. Okay. To see if
Speaker 8:  I can like pull something better out of it. Not as often, but the most
Speaker 8:  I'm actually using it for is writing well converting business emails.
Speaker 3:  Like
Speaker 8:  That's the top thing I've using Chat for.
Speaker 3:  That's your, your hit album. Well, converting business emails, right?
Speaker 8:  Yeah, exactly. Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 7:  Sounds like a great vapor wave album. Let's make that.
Speaker 8:  But yeah, that's the top thing I've using it for as this time. It's You know,
Speaker 8:  it's the sidebar of the music industry is the business of the music industry.
Speaker 8:  But it's something that's very important for somebody like me who's trying
Speaker 8:  to afford to live in New York, You know. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  For sure. So is there, is there anything that feels like you
Speaker 3:  would love to offload part of the process to ai? Where I feel
Speaker 3:  like You know everybody in who does sort of normal desk jobs is
Speaker 3:  like loves AI because it can write their emails, right? Yeah. And that feels
Speaker 3:  like the kind of thing that it's like, this isn't really my job, but it's
Speaker 3:  a thing I have to do as part of my job. So like terrific. If I can offload
Speaker 3:  that. Amazing. I mean we were,
Speaker 7:  We were talking about this just yesterday. I'm very jealous of Ian because
Speaker 7:  he has a team of people that work with him to help him do all the prep
Speaker 7:  work, which is really boring. Mm. Sloppy. So prepping a mix session takes
Speaker 7:  forever. You have to cut out all the silences, you have to get everything
Speaker 7:  in the right order, you have to color the tracks, tuning vocals,
Speaker 7:  aligning things. A lot of things do have creative choices that happen in
Speaker 7:  them, but there can be just dozens of hours a week of prep work
Speaker 7:  that usually is handled by an assistant or an engineer. And
Speaker 7:  I don't finish songs often because I'm like, I don't wanna spend my entire
Speaker 7:  day doing all this prep work, which not only slows me down, but
Speaker 7:  it also, it drags me down as well. Like it puts me in a creative
Speaker 7:  hole where what I need to do is just like get right into my creative
Speaker 7:  state, but I have to do that five hours into staring at my computer. So there's
Speaker 7:  a lot of things that I would love for it to automate.
Speaker 8:  And at this point, it's not replacing anything I'm doing or my assistants
Speaker 8:  are doing, but there is technology now coming out that is helping with it.
Speaker 8:  But I think we're just on The Verge of that. I saw one last week that
Speaker 8:  So, we talk about the stems of a song, all the different instruments and
Speaker 8:  vocals and everything. And if someone You know, a lot of times will get it
Speaker 8:  from the producer or the artist and nothing will be labeled So. we have to
Speaker 8:  go through and listen to every single one. Right. And now there's a new technology
Speaker 8:  where you can enter in your stems and it can name exactly what they are and
Speaker 8:  you can choose how they're named and everything like that. So at this point
Speaker 8:  there is new technology coming up that can really save us a lot of time.
Speaker 8:  Save my assistants in particular a lot of time. But it we're just on The
Speaker 8:  Verge of that, which is personally really exciting for me. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  And, and it's important because like if you were to mix the artist, Jacob Collier,
Speaker 7:  who's Grammy winning artist, what is a, a small session of his like 400,
Speaker 7:  500 tracks definitely good Ford. Right? So if those haven't been labeled,
Speaker 7:  you got 400 to 500 tracks, I, apple literally expanded the number of
Speaker 7:  tracks that their d a w logic can have because he was feeling like he
Speaker 7:  was hamstrung by the number of tracks they could have. Yep. So you can have
Speaker 7:  these huge sessions if things are unlabeled. I mean, it could take an entire
Speaker 7:  day just to get things set up properly so you can make it. That
Speaker 8:  Makes time. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, that's a really good example. I mean it's, it is kind of the, the like
Speaker 3:  the work about the work and that's so much of ai. Like we talk about this
Speaker 3:  even with like what Google and Microsoft are doing, where it's like you can't
Speaker 3:  do your actual sort of meaningful work better, but you
Speaker 3:  can turn an Excel spreadsheet into a PowerPoint deck more quickly.
Speaker 3:  And that's where we are with AI in a lot of places, I think. And that's,
Speaker 3:  that's fine and good. But yeah, it does feel like there's a, there's a leap
Speaker 3:  away before it starts being more than that. Like do you feel like you're
Speaker 3:  in a moment of existential business questions about like, how do I
Speaker 3:  do this job? We're gonna get to much more of that later
Speaker 8:  For sure. Preview it for us now. No, the toes in the water. Yeah. No, it's
Speaker 8:  definitely, I'm, I am not worried at all, nor
Speaker 8:  should anybody in my company be worried about like You know for,
Speaker 8:  it's just minuscule tasks at this point. There is You know, there's things
Speaker 8:  rolling through my head like, okay, we have this STEM technology to read
Speaker 8:  the stems, so that means You know that AI can't hear
Speaker 8:  critically, but it can like read waves and all that kind of stuff to really
Speaker 8:  understand what's going on. So it can tell what different elements are.
Speaker 8:  You can reference things that sound good and then it could like mix your
Speaker 8:  song in a way that sounds good. And You know it's, that is not at a point
Speaker 8:  we are at right now, that technology hasn't been made. But I see it in the
Speaker 8:  future for possibly being able to automate some of the bigger jobs that we
Speaker 8:  have. But just the data set that you would need in order to create that would
Speaker 8:  be incredible. You know. Totally. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  So I mean, music is music creation though. A big business is often
Speaker 7:  a lot of, a lot of the companies that serve the music professionals,
Speaker 7:  they're small businesses. I mean, some of them are multimillion dollar businesses,
Speaker 7:  but You know, if you look at like the synthesizer companies, they're like
Speaker 7:  a dozen people. They're using really old technology from the seventies. Often.
Speaker 7:  There are a handful of You know, certainly music technology companies that
Speaker 7:  are working in ai, but they don't have the resources of Google. Right. In
Speaker 7:  fact, some of the tools that we've used for fun have been created by Google
Speaker 7:  as sort of like side throwaway projects. And so one of the big problems I
Speaker 7:  think in servicing music professionals is large
Speaker 7:  good data sets that might exist for You know, helping us
Speaker 7:  make PowerPoints 'cause how many PowerPoints exist. Totally. But getting
Speaker 7:  access to good data. I mean, I remember The Verge had an amazing article
Speaker 7:  written by a You, know a former journalist here at Danny Deal who talked
Speaker 7:  about the metadata problem within music. And just like people don't submit
Speaker 7:  the metadata to the streaming services for you
Speaker 7:  to then know how to get paid. So there's just like, the data problem
Speaker 7:  is already such a significant problem throughout the music industry. More
Speaker 7:  broadly making tools that are built off of that training data
Speaker 7:  for our subset, fairly niche industry, I'm You know,
Speaker 7:  skeptical and expect the best tools probably being things that are
Speaker 7:  appropriated from the larger tech companies.
Speaker 3:  Got it. Okay. Alright. So the, the super primitive nature of all of this
Speaker 3:  makes me very excited for what's about to happen, which is
Speaker 3:  that I basically told you I wanted to talk about some of the specific tools
Speaker 3:  that are out there and how they're using 'em. And the two of you went like
Speaker 3:  several orders of magnitude beyond that. And you just made AI music
Speaker 3:  is essentially my understanding of what happened here.
Speaker 7:  We made music, you made using only AI tools.
Speaker 8:  Okay.
Speaker 3:  I wanna walk through this whole process. I wanna hear the thing that you
Speaker 3:  made. I have not heard any of this. I'm very excited. But before you get
Speaker 3:  into it, how was this process? You did this with like very little notice
Speaker 3:  or time. Has this, was this like, was this fun? Was this awful?
Speaker 3:  Was this, did you make the worst thing you've ever made in your lives and
Speaker 3:  you hate it forever? Like how did it feel?
Speaker 7:  I feel like Ian, you make stuff just every single day. How is this different
Speaker 7:  for you? I'm curious. I'm
Speaker 8:  So happy I was doing it with him, first of all, like a lot of other people,
Speaker 8:  this would've been so frustrating, but I felt like I had a broken leg the
Speaker 8:  whole time. It slowed down the process and it's not just like figuring
Speaker 8:  out these tools and how to use them, it's how to, like, we had to restart
Speaker 8:  and manipulate audio in a way after using the AI to
Speaker 8:  actually get it to fit in correctly, which was You know. So time
Speaker 8:  consuming when it's like, one of the tools we used was just to create a simple
Speaker 8:  base, which was just a sine wave. And I could have pulled up a plugin
Speaker 8:  and done it in 30 seconds, but in order to try and create
Speaker 8:  a sine wave using some of these things, it took us 10 minutes. You know.
Speaker 8:  So it was just a slow process just going through the entire
Speaker 8:  thing. And You know, it's really fun getting starter ideas and little things
Speaker 8:  that I personally wouldn't think of and pulling those in, but using it
Speaker 8:  for the entire process was very inhibiting.
Speaker 7:  I believe that. Yeah, I mean, learning any new tool is always gonna slow
Speaker 7:  you down, like with any studio tool as well. Like if you get new equipment
Speaker 7:  in the studio, you gotta kind of spend an hour learning it. So there definitely,
Speaker 7:  we, we were held back by using new things while trying to be
Speaker 7:  creative at the same time. That said, most of the material that we put together
Speaker 7:  would've been a lot easier if we could have just used the existing tool sets
Speaker 7:  that we already have. So it was a fun exercise, a set of
Speaker 7:  constraints and a fun excuse to hang out and make a song together. Love it.
Speaker 8:  Let's, so
Speaker 3:  Let's, let's do it. Walk me through like, okay, you, you sit down to do this.
Speaker 3:  Where do you even, where do you start?
Speaker 7:  Well, I had done a little bit of research the night before to make sure and
Speaker 7:  You know, I I, I cover music. And so I had a list of things I
Speaker 7:  was curious about exploring and we thought that we should probably begin
Speaker 7:  with an idea, right? Like typically a good song is gonna
Speaker 7:  have some kind of hook, some kind of core idea that's gonna guide it so that
Speaker 7:  we'd know which direction to go in. And we figured we could
Speaker 7:  use chat G P T, which is the You, know that that would be the top of the
Speaker 7:  funnel. Everyone knows it. Let's see if we can love it. Use that for some
Speaker 7:  sort of creative purpose. And so I came into the room and I had been talking
Speaker 7:  about, I've just started a, a teaching position, which I is really fun for
Speaker 7:  me, I'm teaching a, a, a music school and I actually didn't finish my music
Speaker 7:  major. So there's kind of this like imposter syndrome that I have of going
Speaker 7:  into class every day and teaching something where I, I kind of dropped that
Speaker 7:  major. And so I thought, well let's, let's go with that idea. And then I
Speaker 7:  think you went a little further and like, how about, let's, let's take it
Speaker 7:  to like a, just the feeling of like not belonging. And so you
Speaker 7:  made an amma, you have a way of prompting chat, g p t Ian that is
Speaker 7:  sophisticated and re results in some lyrics. I don't
Speaker 8:  Find it sophisticated, but thank you. Yeah. So essentially he had the
Speaker 8:  imposter syndrome idea and I was thinking like, okay, what can we make this
Speaker 8:  more standard song core lyrical content
Speaker 8:  wise? And so what we, what I thought it was like, okay, I have
Speaker 8:  imposter syndrome, but imposter syndrome was somebody else. It'd be really
Speaker 8:  easy to jump into a relationship. So I prompted a little bit of relationship
Speaker 8:  and then I also prompted it with, I have imposter syndrome being in
Speaker 8:  this musical or in any world with ai also there I feel like
Speaker 8:  it's better than me. I feel like it can do better than me. So a lot of You
Speaker 8:  know the nouns and things like that that we're verbs and everything were
Speaker 8:  like electrical techie, stuff like that, which is really
Speaker 7:  Interesting. Ian basically writes like a multi-paragraph long prompt that
Speaker 7:  is just like, you have this way of just kind of like it's stream vomiting,
Speaker 7:  word consciousness, stream of consciousness. Like maybe that will prompt
Speaker 7:  interesting and creative things. And, and we, we, I think we came to the
Speaker 7:  idea that like, we would like this song to be maybe from the perspective
Speaker 7:  of an AI that has imposter syndrome trying to exist in the world. Ian
Speaker 7:  has this amazing studio in midtown that, that has the, they're on the
Speaker 7:  eighth floor with this giant window that overlooks the Empire State Building.
Speaker 7:  So, we had to make it also set in New York. Sure. So, we sent that prompt
Speaker 7:  in and we got back garbage. Yep.
Speaker 7:  He used chat G P T 3.5. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  He used four. Okay.
Speaker 7:  I used four. I think four is supposed to be the more creative. Yeah. And
Speaker 7:  so this is what we got from our just first verse. After this big prompt
Speaker 7:  woke up today in a world so bright but shadows formed beneath the city lights,
Speaker 7:  you're soaring high. While I remain tied to the ground by invisible
Speaker 7:  chains, starting a song with woke up today has got to be the most
Speaker 7:  cliche way of beginning a song.
Speaker 8:  It's like an off, off, off Broadway show. That,
Speaker 7:  And so the real challenge here is it does write Yeah.
Speaker 7:  The most cliche kind of lyrics, very obvious end rhymes,
Speaker 7:  bright lights, remain chains. Oh, that's kind of nice. It
Speaker 7:  actually made a slant rhyme. Sure. But it's, it's really bad at like multi
Speaker 7:  syllabic rhymes, which is what makes You know a great verse, strange
Speaker 7:  rhyme schemes and things like that. We were also upset that it was kind of
Speaker 7:  vague. Good songs are gonna have some specifics. Like you want the Red scarf
Speaker 7:  and a Taylor Swift song. Sure. That's gonna guide you through the entire
Speaker 7:  narrative. And So, we, we tried a different approach. I I borrowed
Speaker 7:  this songwriting tool from Jeff Tweedy of Wilco
Speaker 7:  and he's got this idea where you wanna hack your brain and put together
Speaker 7:  unlikely pairings of words are often where you find interesting new meaning.
Speaker 7:  So I said, give me, this is one of his exercises. Give me
Speaker 7:  10 verbs that are about imposter syndrome and then
Speaker 7:  give me 10 nouns that are objects in New York City. And it
Speaker 7:  started giving me more interesting Okay. Poetic things, including intruding
Speaker 7:  skyscrapers, shattering street lamps, looting
Speaker 7:  newsstands, tampering, taxis. I said, okay, well take some of those
Speaker 7:  and try to write some lyrics. So it gave me this verse,
Speaker 7:  intruding skyscrapers piercing the night in their looming shadows. We tried
Speaker 7:  to find the light Sneaking subways silent cries. They echo
Speaker 7:  We're in different lanes waiting for the metro. Now
Speaker 8:  Better, not better. Better.
Speaker 7:  We liked Metro, although clearly nobody in New York City calls
Speaker 7:  the subway, the metro
Speaker 8:  Sneaking subways kind of works for me. Yeah. I
Speaker 7:  Like sneaking subways. And then, so then I was like, wait, we need more specific
Speaker 7:  things. So I then prompted it further and was like, but can you give me some
Speaker 7:  specific places in New York City now
Speaker 8:  We go down the rabbit hole and,
Speaker 7:  And, and it updated it to intruding skyscrapers. The empires might by the
Speaker 7:  Flat Iron building. We first saw the light Sneaking Subways beneath the Central
Speaker 7:  Park by the Bethesda Terrace. We lost our spark. And you immediately start
Speaker 7:  singing. Do you
Speaker 8:  Remember No, no.
Speaker 7:  The the Alicia Keys song.
Speaker 8:  Oh yeah. In New York. It was just so like
Speaker 8:  incredibly specific or like gave You know I i I
Speaker 8:  love an actual place, something tangible. Sure. You know. Like I put the
Speaker 8:  word Bowery in so many of my songs. It's ridiculous. But
Speaker 8:  not every line. Yeah. It's, it's, yeah. So we kept
Speaker 7:  Prompting and kept prompting and trying to get better material out of it
Speaker 7:  and it just wasn't working. And So, we decided to go with sort of the, the,
Speaker 7:  I think what was the second prompt? The one that used that sort of noun verb
Speaker 7:  exercise. Sure. And Ian is really good at reducing
Speaker 7:  bad lyrics that's been submitted to him and make them You know more Singable
Speaker 7:  So. we knew we had something he could work with. I think my favorite
Speaker 7:  AI tool actually that we used the entire time, I'm assuming it's ai, I don't
Speaker 7:  know, was he took a picture of my computer screen
Speaker 7:  with the lyrics on it and Apple automatically can
Speaker 7:  identify the text. Oh sure. And he can copy and paste the text from the picture
Speaker 7:  into an Apple note and edit it. I think most of,
Speaker 3:  I love that that's the best ai
Speaker 7:  That was, that was the best thing that
Speaker 3:  We used. That is so telling
Speaker 7:  And I, I think Mo, the tools that I had the most fun with are the things
Speaker 7:  that often market their AI the least. Interesting.
Speaker 7:  So I don't know if there's some sort of You know machine learning in, in
Speaker 7:  that tool. Yeah, no,
Speaker 3:  That counts. I'm, that's ai. Okay. Yeah, we're good.
Speaker 7:  Okay, great. Great, great. Alright, we got an idea. We've got some rough
Speaker 7:  lyrics. We need a vibe and So, we went hunting for sounds and
Speaker 7:  the first place we went was a, a website called Suno. Suno is kind of like
Speaker 7:  the mid journey for music. They have a Discord server
Speaker 7:  where you can enter a prompt and it's gonna spit out rather than a picture
Speaker 7:  like mid journey. It's gonna, it's gonna spit out music and it's, I believe
Speaker 7:  fully synthesized music including lyrics and and vocals.
Speaker 7:  So can I play you what we got please? Okay. We're just gonna do a smattering
Speaker 7:  of sounds for now. We entered the first verse that intruding skyscrapers
Speaker 7:  verse, and this is what it gave us.
Speaker 9:  Intruding skyscrapers.
Speaker 9:  Try to find the light.
Speaker 7:  I was like, okay, I like the Nokia ringtone. Yep. We're gonna use that. Yep.
Speaker 7:  And we've got some vocals like,
Speaker 3:  So all of that was synthesized. That was also because you fed a text and
Speaker 3:  it came back with that. That's right.
Speaker 8:  Also, this is the full audio quality, like to be told to
Speaker 7:  Oh yeah. It's like
Speaker 8:  A this, this isn't being degraded at all through the listening process here.
Speaker 8:  This is the full auto audio qualities
Speaker 3:  It came out. It's basically Nokia ringtone quality. Yeah,
Speaker 7:  Yeah, exactly. Okay. And then actually just like mid journey, it will give
Speaker 7:  you alternatives. So it gave us this other track as well.
Speaker 7:  And this one we thought was kind of trash, but it has this Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Getting like bad country song vibes from this.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, yeah. But we like this little sort of piano we syn thing.
Speaker 7:  Now we have the problem that we want these individual pieces of material
Speaker 7:  to play with So. we go to a website called Audio
Speaker 7:  shake.ai and they will stem your
Speaker 7:  pre-existing music for you. Right. So, we need it all separated. Audios shape
Speaker 7:  will take that track and it gives us the vocals, the little
Speaker 7:  piano riff we liked from the first one and, and some of like other stuff.
Speaker 7:  And then you can You know, listen to 'em individually. So
Speaker 3:  This seems like the kind of thing that I could see being useful for lots
Speaker 3:  of things in the world, but not really in the music making process. Like
Speaker 3:  are you often pulling stems out of existing things when you're making music?
Speaker 3:  Well, I
Speaker 8:  Mean generally that's against copyright So we can't, well,
Speaker 3:  Yeah, exactly. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  People use it for remixing so, sure. So especially when, when like it's a
Speaker 7:  really old song and so you do have the rights for it. Big name artists
Speaker 7:  actually using this tool to be able to get the stem spiel to remix. Right.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. You also see it all over TikTok and stuff. They're using it to like
Speaker 3:  isolate the vocals and stuff like that. For
Speaker 7:  Sure. Kinda stuff. Yeah. Yeah. Right. Okay. So isolating vocals, shooting
Speaker 9:  Scrapers.
Speaker 7:  We now have isolated vocals. Okay. Right. And we have a little fun riff,
Speaker 7:  this little senty thing.
Speaker 7:  I do like that my, my my noke, my Nokia ringtone. The ringtone is nice. Okay.
Speaker 7:  So that's the first sound we assemble. We've got Suno, we also
Speaker 7:  pulled
Speaker 3:  Piano riffs. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  That thing from the Bad Country song. Yeah, we got that as well. Alright.
Speaker 7:  So, we got those sounds. I then just went to like a ton of other,
Speaker 7:  we will make music for you AI sites thinking maybe I can just keep stemming
Speaker 7:  stuff. And a lot of them are really bad. The quality of music that we
Speaker 7:  were getting back would not fit like top 40 pop
Speaker 7:  kind of vibe. They're much more like background advertisement,
Speaker 7:  sort of mood music. But we figured maybe we could You know Get
Speaker 7:  Inspired by One. And So, we went to a place called Sound Full and heard this
Speaker 7:  music, which I think sounds like a pharma ad
Speaker 3:  Side effects include try out. Yeah, yeah,
Speaker 7:  Exactly. And we're like, okay, So, we, we took this to Audio
Speaker 7:  Shake and we got the piano,
Speaker 3:  Which okay,
Speaker 7:  The quality is not great, but
Speaker 7:  this guy's a wizard. I, we knew he could do something with it. When we play
Speaker 7:  with it, we got a few more sounds. We went to
Speaker 7:  Splice is one of the biggest libraries of samples
Speaker 7:  and they have a new tool that will automatically pair different samples together
Speaker 7:  for you as sort of like a starter. Okay. And we went to their
Speaker 7:  beta AI tool and they made this sound for us.
Speaker 1:  These
Speaker 7:  Are four different samples that splice just kind of randomly put together.
Speaker 7:  And we thought sounded kind of like a really bad phone call again.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Like you're on waiting. It's like, but we liked the kick drum So.
Speaker 7:  we, we, we got the kick drum. Okay. Full
Speaker 8:  Drums. Yeah. The snare too. You
Speaker 7:  Had a sample of your own. Ian has has a You know
Speaker 7:  professional producer has a bunch of starter sounds that he can bring to
Speaker 7:  any session and just like get things going creatively. But we had to figure
Speaker 7:  out how to process something he'd already made through ai. Sure. And so there
Speaker 7:  was a tool by a company called Output called Arcade that will automatically
Speaker 7:  take your sample and play it back to you with some kind of AI tool
Speaker 7:  that will make some creative choices with that
Speaker 8:  Sample. It's essentially the listening and chopping arcade also does a creative
Speaker 8:  function where you can set the key and it looks at the tempo. Okay. And then
Speaker 8:  it will give you sounds that could work. It's not using any kind of learning
Speaker 8:  technology in this case, but they have a new portion where you can input
Speaker 8:  a sample. It learns that sample, figures out where to chop it and then
Speaker 8:  plays it back to you in creative chops. I see.
Speaker 7:  Okay. So here's the chops that it gave us
Speaker 7:  all. Now we have a selection of sounds like basically we have lyrics, we
Speaker 7:  have collected our paints, we gotta now put something together. Right. And
Speaker 8:  All in different keys, all in different tempos.
Speaker 7:  I think that whole process took us like two and a half hours of getting all
Speaker 7:  that material and just like getting something to work with. And we have
Speaker 3:  A lot of piano tracks, a
Speaker 7:  Lot of piano tracks that we're
Speaker 3:  Keeping track. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  I'm
Speaker 3:  Feeling this is gonna be a very moody song.
Speaker 7:  We were thinking moody. Yeah. I mean like, because we actually made a, I
Speaker 7:  didn't say we did make a little reference playlist of, of artists that maybe
Speaker 7:  could inspire the vibe. We, we definitely wanted Moody Piano was on there.
Speaker 7:  We wanted a sort of mid tempo, happy, sad
Speaker 7:  walking through New York in the rain kind of thing at night. Yeah. But it's
Speaker 7:  like neon all around. All right. So that's, that's the vibe. Yeah. And with
Speaker 7:  all of that prompt, we probably could have written a song war two in the
Speaker 7:  amount of time that it took us to collect these sounds, which are very sure
Speaker 7:  lo-fi and need a lot of processes make sound good. So Ian
Speaker 7:  takes first the piano and gives us
Speaker 7:  this riff. The, the piano from Suno,
Speaker 7:  the piano from Sound, actually,
Speaker 7:  which You know sounds a whole lot better than
Speaker 1:  Oof.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. That's where we started. Yeah. So that's
Speaker 7:  Where we start. And then I think we had these like interesting, we, we had
Speaker 7:  those like sparkly sound effects
Speaker 8:  That's no. Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 7:  We piled 'em together
Speaker 7:  and Then, we had that kick drum.
Speaker 7:  It took us probably half hour to process the sounds to actually sound better
Speaker 7:  than they initially did. We thought, okay, that's sort of like a
Speaker 7:  pre chorus chorus. Now let's use some of our other sounds. Let's make a verse.
Speaker 7:  And one of the issues is we didn't have a base and we were trying to
Speaker 7:  limit ourselves to only the sounds that we had at our disposal. So. we
Speaker 7:  took this tiny little sample from Suno
Speaker 7:  again, SUNO the sort of mid journey like right app
Speaker 7:  that
Speaker 3:  Just that Okay.
Speaker 7:  That and I turned that into a bass sound
Speaker 3:  That's like a space base space. Okay. By like
Speaker 7:  Staring and fiddling a basically I put that into a sampler. I process it,
Speaker 7:  I do a bunch of different things to it to give us some kind of base something.
Speaker 7:  And I think it, I used the same sample. And to make this as well,
Speaker 8:  It just took so long to long get from that one to another one. We just had
Speaker 8:  to run it through like three plugins and yeah, it was, okay.
Speaker 7:  So, and we have one more sound, which was this,
Speaker 7:  I can't even remember which one this came from. That
Speaker 8:  Was from my loop.
Speaker 7:  That was your, this is your
Speaker 8:  Loop from the arcade. Yeah. Got it. This is the
Speaker 7:  Arcade loop. Okay. And so kind of all those things together, give us a verse
Speaker 7:  vibe.
Speaker 7:  And then I think there's just other little chirpy sound
Speaker 10:  As the piano
Speaker 7:  And the sounds are like, they're a little, they're they're, they've got a
Speaker 7:  lot of texture we'll say. I think they sound kind of like the Nokia ringtone
Speaker 7:  is probably the best metaphor, but for me it's like those really bad MP
Speaker 7:  threes that you definitely didn't download off of Kaza or Napster You know
Speaker 7:  20 years ago. That's kind of the quality that they came in. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. There's that one that it kind of makes you wanna like peel your headphone
Speaker 3:  off just to make sure it's like not you didn't blow your speakers. Yep. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  So the next thing is, okay, we have, now we have a vibe, we have some lyrics.
Speaker 7:  We've got to put together some kind of, we'll call top line. We need a melody
Speaker 7:  that's gonna go on top. This is where I think we gave up on
Speaker 7:  trying to use an AI to write a melody. I was just like, Ian get in the booth.
Speaker 7:  Sure.
Speaker 3:  I, I just start riffing and see what
Speaker 7:  Work. And he puts on some autotune. Here's what he gives us
Speaker 11:  Skyscrapers here through the night
Speaker 11:  shadows under the city lights.
Speaker 7:  Now Betty, he, he kind of has massaged the lyrics.
Speaker 7:  I will say that I think intruding skyscrapers is a terrible opener to a song.
Speaker 7:  It's very wordy. Yeah. Intruding skyscrapers.
Speaker 3:  It's a lot of syllables to say at the very beginning. Yeah. Doesn't,
Speaker 7:  Doesn't roll off easily. No. So, we build a whole bunch of melodic ideas,
Speaker 7:  pair them with these lyrics. Ian puts down a whole set of vocals to the entire
Speaker 7:  song. The more interesting thing though is we can't use his voice. We have
Speaker 7:  to use someone else's voice. So, we send this through voice
Speaker 7:  swap.ai. If you wanna release a track with them, they
Speaker 7:  will actually allow you to license their professional singers. This is one
Speaker 7:  of the few tools that has actually made pretty high quality tools specifically
Speaker 7:  for musicians. So
Speaker 3:  They're actually generating models like with specific musicians. That's right.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. And then you can plug your own stuff in and get their generated stuff
Speaker 3:  out.
Speaker 7:  I i if you license it for a couple hundred dollars basically. So this is
Speaker 7:  for journalistic demo purposes only. Of course we're not releasing this
Speaker 7:  song. And So, we, we've
Speaker 3:  Been named for this song, by the way, have we titled it yet at this point
Speaker 3:  in the process? Absolute. I
Speaker 7:  Don't belong probably. Yeah. Okay. You haven't heard the chorus yet? Oh,
Speaker 3:  You're right. I apologize. All right. I don't belong. Parentheses, intruding
Speaker 3:  skyscrapers. Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 7:  That's it. Perfect. Alright. So, we send his
Speaker 7:  voice through the voice model
Speaker 12:  Intruding skyscraper.
Speaker 7:  Now it sounds very process and affected because we intentionally took
Speaker 7:  his auto-tune vocal and sent it through the, the, the, the model. We want
Speaker 7:  this to sound like it might be an AI singing to us, say So.
Speaker 3:  We did not, it sounds more robotic in a good way. Yeah. We
Speaker 7:  Didn't want it to sound natural. That was the goal. I probably voice swap
Speaker 7:  is supposedly the best at doing this. But we tried to hack their thing to
Speaker 7:  give us bad quality Sure. Material back. There were a few other small tools
Speaker 7:  we used at this point. I mentioned that Google Law has a handful of
Speaker 7:  projects, one called Magenta where they will edit midi data.
Speaker 7:  That's basically You know the programming language that musicians use to
Speaker 7:  input music into their, their software. And we had
Speaker 7:  made this little rhythm on our own.
Speaker 7:  Just that. And what Magenta would do is it will give
Speaker 7:  you variations on your rhythm. So it gave us this.
Speaker 3:  Okay.
Speaker 7:  I mean one of us could have done this, but we just figured all right that
Speaker 7:  there's one nice it ation, it
Speaker 3:  Seems like how many of these tools are doing kind of roughly the same thing
Speaker 3:  where you, it's like, I mean, they're basically all chat g p T, right? Like
Speaker 3:  you say like, here's a thing, give me other versions of this thing. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  And it's, it's able to do that with sort of some level of competence. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  But there's so many moments in this process it seems like, where you've said
Speaker 3:  like, okay, we need to put all these pieces together or we need to
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Start from scratch and get somewhere. And these tools are just, they
Speaker 3:  have nothing to Yeah. I
Speaker 7:  Mean, 'cause like I, like I just need one little percussion idea and I honestly
Speaker 7:  don't, there's probably some tool somewhere, but if you ask me, can you like
Speaker 7:  go interpolate and make me an interesting little top percussion moment,
Speaker 7:  like it would've been faster to program. But anyways, I used Magenta to make
Speaker 7:  this little,
Speaker 7:  It's intentionally buried in the back of the track and there's a
Speaker 7:  artificial tape plugin to sound like, like a tape machine. Sure. That's trained
Speaker 7:  off of a neural net that we put in here to, to process made by baby audio.
Speaker 7:  Finally, I'm gonna play the whole thing in just a second. Love it. We put
Speaker 7:  the whole song together and there's a company called Isotope that
Speaker 7:  has a mix and master assistant tool.
Speaker 7:  Their mixing tool is called Neutron. And that will go on every single track
Speaker 7:  and you can basically say, Hey, mix this track for me. And at the end on,
Speaker 7:  on the the the full master track, you put ozone. And
Speaker 7:  same thing, rather than mixing and mastering the song ourselves, we just
Speaker 7:  hit the master assist with a license that Ozone gave, that isotope gave
Speaker 7:  us for to make this song. And
Speaker 3:  Isotope specifically is pretty widely used. Right? I don't know how much
Speaker 3:  the AI stuff is, but the isotope thing
Speaker 7:  Is, is pretty well actually, and this is a great example of like the AI marketing
Speaker 7:  around isotope and ozone is just like a tiny little slice of what that's
Speaker 7:  for sure. Being used for. I think, I
Speaker 8:  Think they're mostly chasing after the people who are doing the top of the
Speaker 8:  top work and know the sounds so well and just wanna make a really big help
Speaker 8:  tool in order to jump on. They don't want to necessarily necessarily take
Speaker 8:  someone from like 0% to 10%. It's more for sure. Yeah. Yeah, that makes
Speaker 7:  Sense. So anyway, do wanna hear the track? Yeah. Here's what we got.
Speaker 3:  This is I don't belong parentheses, intruding skyscrapers.
Speaker 12:  Intruding skyscrapers, Pierce through night
Speaker 12:  ing, shadows under the city lights
Speaker 12:  sneaking through the silent.
Speaker 12:  We're in different lanes for
Speaker 12:  dreams.
Speaker 12:  Intertwine t escapes
Speaker 12:  trying to make you mind, but with,
Speaker 3:  All right, we're gonna take a quick break and then we're gonna come back
Speaker 3:  and talk more about this. But we're gonna let this play us out.
Speaker 3:  All right, we're back. We brought in Eli Patel. Hi Eli. Hey, what's up? It's
Speaker 3:  time to talk about our feelings, but first I wanna know, you were sitting
Speaker 3:  in the control room listening to the song. What do you think? Is it a song?
Speaker 3:  Do we have a banger on our hands?
Speaker 14:  I think someone needs to go in and move those drums into the pocket.
Speaker 14:  They're, they're early. The snare was early. That's like, I can't hear anything
Speaker 14:  beyond that. And that's just, that's just me. Okay. That's
Speaker 3:  The first thing I listen
Speaker 8:  To. You should have so many more critiques.
Speaker 14:  I I'm confident there are more critiques to be had.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. It it, it's really hard for like my musical representation on this
Speaker 8:  show to be.
Speaker 3:  Sorry.
Speaker 8:  It's very difficult for
Speaker 3:  Me. So do you, do you listen to that and think, like, is there anything in
Speaker 3:  that that's interesting to you as a musician?
Speaker 8:  So the, the, the more I've done this, the more I produce music for like so
Speaker 8:  many different people, the more I've realized that I do make bad music and
Speaker 8:  that's okay. And that's gonna go right into the trashcan and that is just
Speaker 8:  fine. I'll make a better one tomorrow. And You know is really fun using
Speaker 8:  all of these tools, but it would take me more time to go into this and try
Speaker 8:  and save stuff from it than it would just be to make a new song.
Speaker 14:  Yeah. Yeah. That's fair. My my old feeling about AI in general is it is
Speaker 14:  a canon of c plus content. Yeah. And if you point a canon of
Speaker 14:  c plus content Yeah. At any business model, something happens. And
Speaker 14:  that song, like it's a, that song is like a canon blast of
Speaker 14:  c plus content. Right.
Speaker 8:  I I I think the biggest problem
Speaker 7:  Was that we used that piano, which came from what sounded like a pharma
Speaker 7:  ad. Yeah. And So, we, we started it from a terrible source material.
Speaker 7:  I remember when we were, when you were working with it, we're like, we're
Speaker 7:  not going in the right direction. What are we gonna do? And I was like, we
Speaker 7:  gotta make the, the verses gotta be minor because it's too happy. And it
Speaker 7:  just like, we ended up making like slightly better remixed pharma music.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. So, I don't know. I mean, look, have you
Speaker 3:  Listened to the radio lately? It's, it's not, not what the kids are
Speaker 3:  listening to.
Speaker 3:  Okay. So the piece of this that I think is left to talk about is the, like
Speaker 3:  what this means, like the capital F feelings about
Speaker 3:  all of this. Right. And I think Neli, I, we've spent a lot of time in the
Speaker 3:  show talking about like what AI does to these industries and how we use them.
Speaker 3:  But I'm especially curious like, and we talked a little bit about this at
Speaker 3:  the beginning, but like as people who make PU music professionally, we're
Speaker 3:  in this moment where I think most of these tools are not very good. Many
Speaker 3:  of these tools are useless as we were talking about at the beginning. But
Speaker 3:  like there are a lot of people who would tell you, we are on the road to
Speaker 3:  this stuff becoming a part of life. Right. And I guess the first thing
Speaker 3:  I wonder is like the story of technology helping us make music goes back
Speaker 3:  forever, right? And there's like, there have been these sort of moral panics
Speaker 3:  about autotune and the idea that you can make drums on your computer instead
Speaker 3:  of having to play drums and everybody gets up in arms about that. Like, is
Speaker 3:  AI different from those things or is it just kind of another
Speaker 3:  technology on the spectrum of how we make music, which is a forever changing
Speaker 3:  thing?
Speaker 8:  I don't think this is any bigger of a step than we've had in the past just
Speaker 8:  because a lot of the AI technology that we have is just doing
Speaker 8:  little steps. If you really look into it, So, we have like splice that has
Speaker 8:  every loop under the sun that I can just drop into my song and it can
Speaker 8:  or cannot work. But I instantly have a great quality, let's say drum recording.
Speaker 8:  And then you have programs like Drummon, which uses ai.
Speaker 8:  I'm not actually sure how, because I'm pretty sure it just reads
Speaker 8:  the b p m of the song, which is incredibly easy to do. And then you choose
Speaker 8:  the genre you want and then you hit generate and it gives you a drum
Speaker 8:  sample pattern and you can hit generate again. It'll give you a different
Speaker 8:  drum sample pattern. And to me that's kind of no different than going on
Speaker 8:  splice and going through those sounds and picking one from there. It's automatically
Speaker 8:  syncing up right away so you can hear it quicker. But there isn't a giant
Speaker 8:  step anywhere in music that I have seen at least.
Speaker 7:  I think a great analogy would be like the re release of drum machines in
Speaker 7:  the 1980s. Like originally these things were made to be like demo devices,
Speaker 7:  maybe replace a drummer. And a lot of them were completely not, they were
Speaker 7:  failures. The most important sound in contemporary popular
Speaker 7:  music is probably Roland's T R 8 0 8. The drum machine. That was a failure
Speaker 7:  ended up in pawn shops and early hip hop producers start thinking, well
Speaker 7:  that's a cool sound if I, if I misappropriate it and used in these different
Speaker 7:  ways and I mix it in interesting ways. This thing, which sounds kind of like
Speaker 7:  a toy actually sounds amazing. And it took
Speaker 7:  decades for these You know rejected devices then to
Speaker 7:  become the mainstream sound. I think what will be most interesting are the
Speaker 7:  weird sounds that you can get out of these tools. Kids in their basements,
Speaker 7:  figuring out how to misuse them, at least at the state we are today
Speaker 7:  to create new interesting creative material. But this was mostly a really
Speaker 7:  challenging exercise with the exception of isotopes. Tools were very usable,
Speaker 7:  very useful. I mean we use those everyday professionally. Anyways, Apple's
Speaker 7:  iPhone was very useful and chat Chachi PT was mildly useful.
Speaker 14:  You know you brought up autotune and the panic over autotune.
Speaker 14:  It's important to just remember when autotune first hit as an effect,
Speaker 14:  they lied about it because the stigma was so incredible.
Speaker 14:  So believe by Cher, they overdid the autotune.
Speaker 14:  And there are articles upon articles where the producers of that song
Speaker 14:  just invented other lies to claim that they had
Speaker 14:  done something that was not used. Autotune, unshare because they were so
Speaker 14:  worried about the stigma of having used the software. And now it's like
Speaker 14:  everyone sees it all the time. And I, I think we're in that moment with
Speaker 14:  AI just like across the board creatively where no one wants to cop to it.
Speaker 14:  But it's just gonna be in the background of all these tools that we're using
Speaker 14:  all the time. And the question is, can you make something that sounds different
Speaker 14:  or great? And I think the worry is that you're gonna type in pop
Speaker 14:  song and get that and that will be all of music. Yep.
Speaker 7:  Okay. Eli, I feel slightly insulted, just to be clear, we didn't
Speaker 7:  'cause you, we didn't prompt that. We actually, we actually worked to make
Speaker 7:  something over about two hours that that was song ish.
Speaker 14:  Song ish. Yeah, yeah. You know
Speaker 7:  And using only AI tools and yeah, it was, it was very challenging to make
Speaker 7:  anything. It just led us in strange directions. But
Speaker 14:  Look, I think that's as big of a hit as believe.
Speaker 7:  Oh my God,
Speaker 14:  Let's get out there.
Speaker 8:  All right, y'all have a good day. How out?
Speaker 14:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  So Ian, if somebody walks into your studio and is like, I have the beginnings
Speaker 3:  of something, I made it entirely with ai. Are you gonna like roll your
Speaker 3:  eyes and kick them outta the studio?
Speaker 8:  Oh, not at all. No. I take demos from artists all the time. So a lot of times
Speaker 8:  we'll do stuff from scratch, but generally I'm working with stuff who, like
Speaker 8:  they've already had the guitar part and the vocal and that kind of thing.
Speaker 8:  And yeah, there's no stigma behind any of it. You know. There's a bigger
Speaker 8:  stigma I think right now with using full samples
Speaker 8:  than there is using any kind of AI tool where
Speaker 8:  if all of my drums are from one like drum sample loop, people are
Speaker 8:  like, oh, you could have been more creative than just go on splice and drag
Speaker 8:  that in. That's more of a stigma than like using an AI tool at this pointing.
Speaker 3:  That's really interesting. Yeah. So, and what about the, like I was just
Speaker 3:  thinking, listening to that vocal, that has gotta feel weird for you having
Speaker 3:  uploaded your voice to a piece of software that spit back your
Speaker 3:  singing in somebody else's voice. And I feel like I, I wonder about that
Speaker 3:  creatively with all of this stuff, right? Obviously there's big copyright
Speaker 3:  questions about who owns a voice and can you make a song with fake Drake
Speaker 3:  that counts. But I wonder, like it's gotta feel weird to hear
Speaker 3:  that out in the world, whether you're Drake or you like
Speaker 3:  listening to someone else sing your song that was just your
Speaker 3:  voice 30 seconds ago. Yeah. What does that feel like?
Speaker 8:  I mean, for me, I like my voice. So I would rather just stick with my voice.
Speaker 8:  But coming from, I work with so many vocal producers or
Speaker 8:  producers in general top line writers that do not like their own voice at
Speaker 8:  all. And they have to manipulate it and tune it a lot to get it to the point
Speaker 8:  they would like to get it to. So if you're not a fan of your vocal tone,
Speaker 8:  but you can get your point across in a recording, then you can change out
Speaker 8:  your voice with something like this. And a lot of the work I do is I'll create
Speaker 8:  a full beat, I'll put on the top line myself, the lyrics and melody and everything
Speaker 8:  and then I'll send it to an artist. It's a pitch. And if they like the song,
Speaker 8:  they'll remove my top line and put theirs on and keep everything else. So
Speaker 8:  essentially You know you don't have to keep the AI generated voice, but it
Speaker 8:  gives a reference for a pitch situation. Interesting.
Speaker 7:  This is also just like an age old issue. People feel uncomfortable with their
Speaker 7:  voice and there have been hacks that we've used for decades,
Speaker 7:  whether that's reverb and compression or oftentimes, in fact, when you went
Speaker 7:  in the booth, the very common thing to do when you're trying to improvise
Speaker 7:  melodies and top line over a beat is you just put on autotune
Speaker 7:  almost to Max and it lets you be looser and freer.
Speaker 7:  And so I think there's actually something very, yeah there, there's something
Speaker 7:  liberating about being like, ah, I don't feel good about my voice, but I
Speaker 7:  know I can make a song and I can make it sound better if I just You know
Speaker 7:  work. Massage it with these tools. Neil, how
Speaker 14:  Do you feel
Speaker 8:  About your singing voice?
Speaker 14:  Yeah.
Speaker 8:  2, 3, 4
Speaker 14:  You know, when I was in the punk band in college, I sang with a British
Speaker 14:  accent.
Speaker 8:  That's AI right there.
Speaker 14:  That's just some straight Al Jorgenson did it in ministry and I'm gonna
Speaker 14:  do it too. And that's, that was the road I was in. You know you said there's
Speaker 14:  copyright issues. There aren't though. That's, that's actually the thing,
Speaker 14:  right? That your voice is not protected in that way. There's like a handful
Speaker 14:  of laws at the state level that might protect it, but no, none of has ever
Speaker 14:  been tested. And the real question is not can I sing into
Speaker 14:  a computer and have it sound like whoever so I can send it to someone else
Speaker 14:  and they can, it's can I distribute that and tell
Speaker 14:  everyone it was Drake? Right. Or tell everyone that it, it sounded
Speaker 14:  alike to Drake.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, I mean I'm pretty sure we can't release any part of what we've made
Speaker 7:  more because of licensing issues rather than copyright issues. Because some
Speaker 7:  of these tools we've used probably have some kind of license that needs purchased
Speaker 7:  to be able to then You know, use some of their sounds. And we did not do
Speaker 7:  all of that perfectly.
Speaker 14:  I promised David that I would bring up the thong song on today's episode
Speaker 14:  of The Verge House. Well, what's fascinating about the music industry right
Speaker 14:  now, and Charla and I have talked about this lots of times, is that the
Speaker 14:  norms inside the music industry about sample usage, about interpolation,
Speaker 14:  about all this stuff have almost nothing to do anymore with
Speaker 14:  copyright law. So I know this fact about the thong song
Speaker 14:  now, and I will come back to it over and over again. Cisco does not own
Speaker 14:  the publishing to the thong song because he said live in La Vita Loca
Speaker 14:  in that song one time. Oh wow.
Speaker 7:  No way. In
Speaker 14:  The chorus. And Ricky Martin's songwriter came and took it and makes all
Speaker 14:  the money every time that song is played. Wow. That's ridiculous to me.
Speaker 14:  T-Pain, I think that just this week revealed that he owns almost none of
Speaker 14:  the publishing to bayou a drink. 'cause there's all these little quotes
Speaker 14:  in it and all those people came for him and they took his publishing away.
Speaker 14:  Right. Wow. And that's like, they didn't go to court. The norms, they're
Speaker 14:  just lawyering up and Yeah, norms pressuring people, the norm in the music
Speaker 14:  industry are just like, we're gonna, we've built this other system.
Speaker 14:  And it, if you just described that to you, it's like if you just whisper
Speaker 14:  the phrase live in La Vita loca like Ricky Martin appears and like takes
Speaker 14:  your money away is, that's not right. Like it doesn't, it doesn't sit right
Speaker 14:  with me anyway. And I think this AI stuff is gonna lead to like
Speaker 14:  a supercharged version of that where like the
Speaker 14:  computer is automatically giving Ricky Martin money because it's
Speaker 14:  been trained on his, like that seems like it will fall apart.
Speaker 3:  Well it seems, it seems to me like it goes one of two ways where either those
Speaker 3:  norms become really, really, really aggressive and
Speaker 3:  careful and everybody becomes very litigious about everything like you're
Speaker 3:  talking about. Or it goes the other way and we end up in this place where
Speaker 3:  it sort of, nobody owns anything. It's just like pure anarchy and chaos.
Speaker 3:  That's, that's not right. 'cause you don't know. But we're gonna get to this
Speaker 3:  point now where, I don't
Speaker 14:  Dunno if the music industry, I mean everybody's
Speaker 3:  Gonna get real litigious at the beginning, but like what we're
Speaker 14:  Going through once described as a cruel and shallow money trench,
Speaker 3:  But like we're going through this with chat G P T right now, right? Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Where it's like, they're like, oh, well this sounds like the book that I
Speaker 3:  read or that I wrote and open ai. It's just like, who's to say? And
Speaker 3:  it's just we're we're just like, we're putting so many black boxes between
Speaker 3:  I made something and something else exists that is kind of similar to the
Speaker 3:  thing that I made that I wonder if it's just gonna get harder and harder
Speaker 3:  to understand provenance and where all this stuff came from
Speaker 3:  and what counts as a sample and who's responsible and where, and it's just
Speaker 3:  like, I, I suspect,
Speaker 14:  But this, when you say, how do you about side of this, this is the thing
Speaker 14:  that I, that gives me the most uncomfortable feeling because they're not
Speaker 14:  gonna not try. Right. And they're gonna, they're already trying really hard.
Speaker 14:  Like YouTube has a deal with Universal, which seems very terrifying to me.
Speaker 14:  And they've already built this bizarre system
Speaker 14:  where Charlie came out and we talked about Olivia Rodrigo's public handing
Speaker 14:  out publishing credits on an episode of Decoder, where Olivia Rodrigo's
Speaker 14:  like, fine, Paramore can have a credit, even though probably shouldn't.
Speaker 14:  Right. Or like, they, the Taylor Swift ones are Swift, the Taylor Swift
Speaker 14:  ones even more really shaky. Right. And it's like the industry has decided
Speaker 14:  they don't, inside the family, they're not gonna fight. Right. And the famous
Speaker 14:  people will just like, collect some money from new artists, and you just
Speaker 14:  keep spinning that up with AI and you're like, oh, eventually the rich are
Speaker 14:  just gonna get richer here. And like, ways that I think
Speaker 14:  disincentivizes anyone from trying to make anything new, like you might
Speaker 14:  as well in that case then just try to flip samples as creatively as possible
Speaker 14:  and hand the money back out. Right. And that, that's the feeling
Speaker 14:  here, that it's like the music industry's response to AI
Speaker 14:  is to become even more corporate in, in a way
Speaker 14:  that just makes me like, like I'm an old punk rocker. Like, that seems like
Speaker 14:  not what you should do, You know. Like, yeah, you should, like,
Speaker 14:  the kids should revolt against all of that. And like, Olivia Rod
Speaker 14:  should be like, I'm, I'm definitely not paying you.
Speaker 8:  But in the same way, the industry, as I've noticed,
Speaker 3:  Is getting a lot polite in
Speaker 8:  Some ways. And I realize when we think about that, it, it might not look
Speaker 8:  that way, but You know when I have writing sessions with people now that
Speaker 8:  there'll be four people in a room, and let's say three of us do 90%, not
Speaker 8:  99% of the work, and the other person lays one base note down,
Speaker 8:  that's four equal splits on publishing. Yeah. And I, I kind of see it the
Speaker 8:  same way with You know you're anticipating the lawsuit and there's gonna
Speaker 8:  have to be a payout regardless and like all this stuff just to make it go
Speaker 8:  away. Like there's definitely that side of it, that's why you add the credits
Speaker 8:  initially. But it's more so just like a, I don't know, a peace
Speaker 8:  offering of kindness to be like, here, take this. And it is cool seeing people
Speaker 8:  like You know a higher up artists that are handing out
Speaker 8:  to like lower level artists, these publishing credits and that kind of thing
Speaker 8:  too. So I don't know. The way I think about it's, it is getting polite, but
Speaker 8:  yeah, when we thinking about AI in the industry, it's, it's
Speaker 8:  corporations Yeah.
Speaker 14:  Which is scary. And, and then it's automated. That's the thing that gets
Speaker 14:  me. It's like, okay, some artists are handing out some credits
Speaker 14:  as they go through a writing session. Okay. Like I, I don't know how
Speaker 14:  you feel about Ricky Martin, but like, yes or no that happened Right? On
Speaker 14:  the flip side, it's like, okay, I made a song using ai, uploaded it to YouTube.
Speaker 14:  YouTube is like, Drake gets a piece of this. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  I mean, I don't make switch dot pop video versions for YouTube
Speaker 7:  because the content ID system is such a pain. Yeah. That I don't wanna deal
Speaker 7:  with it because it will demonetize everything. You have to fight everything.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Even for journalistic purposes, if you use any copyright material,
Speaker 7:  which is absolutely fair use YouTube just is its own government,
Speaker 7:  right? Yeah. With its own set of id. It's, it's not actually a copyright
Speaker 7:  issue. It is a set of private contracts between copyright holders with
Speaker 7:  YouTube that has a system that you have to go through that is its own court.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. And it's just such a pain that I don't deal with it and I'd rather
Speaker 7:  just make a podcast.
Speaker 8:  Right.
Speaker 3:  Charlie, you were mentioning before, like you didn't do this process of
Speaker 3:  making all this stuff in the most sort of like upstanding pay everybody who
Speaker 3:  should weigh, but like you left a trail that every one of these services
Speaker 3:  knows about. Right. And and to your point, as they get better at doing things
Speaker 3:  like having deals with record labels and stuff, like, it may be true
Speaker 3:  that that money just like slowly starts to disappear every time you open
Speaker 3:  a new app. Yeah. And right now this stuff is happening like in Discords and
Speaker 3:  like one of the most popular things is like a, it's in a Google drive and
Speaker 3:  you just upload your file to a Google Drive and then download it from a different
Speaker 3:  Google Drive. And it's like, that is fine and gonna be hard
Speaker 3:  for anyone to figure out how to make money off of. Right. But eventually,
Speaker 3:  if this stuff gets better as quickly as people think it's going to, it's
Speaker 3:  going to get corporatized too. They're gonna make these same deals and then
Speaker 3:  all of a sudden as you make music, you're just gonna leave these like
Speaker 3:  bread crumbs,
Speaker 7:  A number of these services claim to have watermarks within them so that they
Speaker 7:  could identify automatically with, with systems if you haven't properly licensed.
Speaker 14:  Do you believe them? Mm. You know how like the B B C used to drive around
Speaker 14:  London with a truck that could detect TV antennas if you didn't pay the
Speaker 14:  fee.
Speaker 14:  I'm just saying, man,
Speaker 7:  I think the question is how good do AIS get at tracking those things down
Speaker 7:  for them? Because it's a pain to to to, yeah. To, to enforce. But
Speaker 7:  I think enforcement of copyright will get significantly easier. I mean, there
Speaker 7:  are people making very effective d r M tools that can basically track every
Speaker 7:  misuse of copyright on Instagram. People just, 'cause Instagram is basically
Speaker 7:  a one giant copyright cluster, right? Yeah. People are taking people's intellectual
Speaker 7:  property all the time and reposting it without permission and no one's really
Speaker 7:  enforcing it. 'cause it's difficult. But there are companies that can help
Speaker 7:  you do so if you want to. But
Speaker 8:  It's also mind numbing because, so I, I put out a song that was a hundred
Speaker 8:  percent, or I wrote it, I did everything on it. I had a hundred percent of
Speaker 8:  the master, a hundred percent of the publishing. I put a TikTok video out
Speaker 8:  using that audio, and the audio got removed for copyright. No.
Speaker 7:  Wait, what?
Speaker 8:  I own it. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 14:  But this is so like all these automated systems have some error rate. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  Right. A hundred percent
Speaker 14:  I can post my own song will just take
Speaker 7:  Did you have any, did they tell you like, what, what did you do wrong?
Speaker 14:  You literally violated your own copyright. Exactly. The estate of Marvin
Speaker 14:  Gaye I to
Speaker 8:  Shame myself, this
Speaker 7:  Is, this is why I actually, when need the, I music was mad. We can't make
Speaker 7:  music anymore because it's so attention
Speaker 14:  Is what I'm, this is what I'm saying. You build these systems with this
Speaker 14:  weird understanding of who gets paid and why inside of it.
Speaker 14:  And the answer is because you exist and you might sue us.
Speaker 14:  And then the error rate in the system makes it so new artists
Speaker 14:  can't upload their own music. And it's like, well, that's not the, that's
Speaker 14:  just definitely the, the wrong outcome you make, I'll give you the,
Speaker 14:  the blurred lines example. Like you open an AI drum program and
Speaker 14:  you're like, give me a Marvin Gaye beat. Yeah. And the state of Marvin Gaye
Speaker 14:  is like, that sounds too much like any song. We're
Speaker 8:  You down? Can you not Where you could prove that AI made it and that you
Speaker 8:  could like, like counter Sue and
Speaker 14:  Yeah, I just think like that's the thing. Like that's the feeling I
Speaker 14:  get with all this stuff is once you just add this much software to the creative
Speaker 14:  process and the pressure on the software is to do automated
Speaker 14:  enforcement or automated credits or to not do things
Speaker 14:  to protect you, it's like, oh, we've just pushed creativity into
Speaker 14:  one tiny little box.
Speaker 7:  I I honestly, throughout this whole conversation, I'm still wondering like,
Speaker 7:  what is even the point of using any of these tools? Because in music at this
Speaker 7:  point, there's just no scarcity. If you want a sound, it exists. You can
Speaker 7:  get it for free or cheap. If you want professional level tools, you can use
Speaker 7:  them with a decent computer. There are free tools available to make
Speaker 7:  very high quality music. Like if you asked us to go do this process again
Speaker 7:  using only a hundred dollars guitar and plugins that were free off the internet,
Speaker 7:  we would make a much better song.
Speaker 8:  No, just band Lab. So Band Lab. Oh, band Lab. Yeah. Band lab.com entirely
Speaker 8:  free. And anyone can use it. I guarantee you, you just, you just pick
Speaker 8:  loops and you drop 'em in and it manipulates them and makes 'em all fit together.
Speaker 8:  I've taught band lab to eight year old children and they had it like that.
Speaker 8:  Wow. And it's so, so easy to use. So, and it's free and everything is
Speaker 8:  yours. It's entirely royalty Freeda.
Speaker 7:  Why? But we don't need these tools to make music for us unless there's there,
Speaker 7:  there's definitely like the amateur who's trying to learn or wants to express
Speaker 7:  something, I think is certainly interesting. But as, as You know, working
Speaker 7:  professional, it's kinda like if you want the high quality sound,
Speaker 7:  you're not getting it from these things. So why even like, deal with the
Speaker 7:  future headache that Neli is discussing. You put yourself in that world.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 14:  But our, this is just at the bottom of the curve though. I mean, that's
Speaker 14:  kind of Right. This is the, the 8 0 8 example. Like it didn't work for that
Speaker 14:  workflow, and then the stuff got discarded and then people who were not
Speaker 14:  part of the gate cap system were like, we're gonna use it for our own thing.
Speaker 14:  And that became a dominant sound like, right. That's the pro case
Speaker 14:  here.
Speaker 7:  There's also the, like this idea that culture radically shifts and that
Speaker 7:  all we want is completely individualized art, which doesn't seem very
Speaker 7:  human. Yeah. But perhaps that happens. And then like, yeah, we all make our
Speaker 7:  own songs that are in our own perfect little world. The thing is right now,
Speaker 7:  like already there is so much high quality library music,
Speaker 7:  You know, like, like better pharma sounding music that you could go
Speaker 7:  listen to, which is like your own special personalized playlist. And I actually
Speaker 7:  just, that's not what people usually want. They wanna like be in conversation
Speaker 7:  with culture, what other people are doing. And so that, that world doesn't
Speaker 7:  really make sense to
Speaker 3:  Me. Yeah. And it goes back to something you were saying at the very beginning,
Speaker 3:  which is like, if you, if what you want is an easier way to make
Speaker 3:  like a music bed for your YouTube video Yeah. Tools
Speaker 3:  abound and they're getting better very quickly. If you want something that
Speaker 3:  is like good and high quality and will make you feel things and care about
Speaker 3:  things and like be on the radio, we're kind of nowhere
Speaker 3:  still.
Speaker 7:  And I, I still think these tools kind of, they're pretty janky most of the
Speaker 7:  time. Like, like I just, we just did an episode, You know with Jimmy Buffet
Speaker 7:  recently died and So, we did a little tribute episode to him on Switch on
Speaker 7:  Pop. And I had to make a promo for that episode and I was like, can I
Speaker 7:  just find Jimmy Buffet esque music? And I couldn't find anything good
Speaker 7:  on Splice and I went to some AI tools and was like, make me a Jimmy Buffett
Speaker 7:  song. And I was just like, screw it. This is so annoying. I brought out my
Speaker 7:  acoustic guitar and I just strum some chords and it sounded way better than
Speaker 7:  anything asking to generate.
Speaker 3:  Well, when Jimmy buffett.ai launches we're having you all back and Oh wow.
Speaker 3:  But until then, thank you all for being here. This was unbelievably fun.
Speaker 3:  I really appreciate it. Charlie, will you play us out? Yeah. Run
Speaker 14:  It back.
Speaker 3:  All right. That's it for the show. Thanks to Charlie, Ian and Neli for being
Speaker 3:  here. And thank you as always for listening. Ai. David, do you want to hit
Speaker 3:  the credits again? If you have Thoughts, questions, feelings, or other
Speaker 3:  songs you'd like to hear AI David Sing, you can always email
Speaker 3:  us at Vergecast at The Verge dot com or keep calling the
Speaker 3:  hotline. 8 6 6 Verge one one. We love hearing from you
Speaker 3:  and the Meta Vergecast episode is coming soon. So if you have questions about
Speaker 3:  The Verge or The Vergecast, send them in quickly. This show is produced by
Speaker 3:  Andrew Marino and Liam James. Brooke Miners is our editorial director of
Speaker 3:  Audio The Vergecast is a Verge production and part of the Vox Media
Speaker 3:  Podcast network. We'll be back on Wednesday with some more Apple talk
Speaker 3:  and with plenty of new news on Friday. See you then. Rock and roll