# Transcript
ID: d277bfe0-9ccf-11ed-a920-cdf17783cba6
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: The Last of Us recap, lessons learned from Silicon Valley, and Vergecast Hotline
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-7046626851643436486/6985195536370191970/s93290-US-4281s-1674665189.mp3
Description: Today on the flagship podcast of zombie kisses:
02:02 - The Verge’s managing editor Alex Cranz chats with film & TV reporter Charles Pulliam-Moore about HBO’s The Last of Us and how it handles the video game adaptation. [Spoilers for episode 1 + 2]
22:40 - Historian and author of the book The Code: Silicon Valley and the Remaking of America Margaret O'Mara talks about how the lack of non-compete clauses shaped Silicon Valley.
38:30 - We answer your questions left on our Vergecast Hotline! Thunderbolt docks, end-to-end encryption, and smart assistants.
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we'd love to hear from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Disabled
Speaker 2:  Hello, and you're listening to The Verge, the flagship podcast
Speaker 2:  of Zombie Kisses. I'm your friend Alex Kranz, and we've got a big
Speaker 2:  show Today, obviously we're gonna be talking about the last of us with Charles
Speaker 2:  Pullum Moore. It's gonna be really, really exciting. And we're gonna be talking
Speaker 2:  about the zombie kisses. So if you haven't seen the latest episode of The
Speaker 2:  Last of Us, probably should go ahead and skip that part. Right now though,
Speaker 2:  I'm making cocktails. I'm making something called a Jet pilot, which involves
Speaker 2:  a lot of booze, a lot of juices, a little ice
Speaker 2:  in a blender. And it wouldn't exist if
Speaker 2:  non-competes had existed in the bartending world in the thirties because
Speaker 2:  it's based on something called the Zombie. The bartenders took the idea
Speaker 2:  for it, went to another hotel, made it. It's delicious. And it also makes
Speaker 2:  sense because I'm gonna be talking about non-competes on the show today.
Speaker 2:  I've got Margaret O'Mara coming on. She's a professor. She's written this
Speaker 2:  incredible book called The Code, all about the creation of Silicon Valley.
Speaker 2:  She makes a really smart case that the Silicone Valley we know today
Speaker 2:  might not be the same if non-competes had been
Speaker 2:  enforced in California in the fifties and sixties. It's gonna be really,
Speaker 2:  really fun. I'm super excited for you guys to hear it. We've also gonna be
Speaker 2:  doing the hotline today, so we've got a lot of your questions in and we're
Speaker 2:  gonna go ahead and answer them. It's gonna be a great time. But first I'm
Speaker 2:  gonna get back to Megan, this cocktail and a blender. See you on the other
Speaker 2:  side.
Speaker 3:  Hey y'all, this is Josh Mucci, host of the Pitch, a
Speaker 3:  Vox Media podcast where real entrepreneurs pitch real tech
Speaker 3:  investors for real money. In this season, we're letting listeners
Speaker 3:  like you invest in the startups on our show, hear
Speaker 3:  the next billion dollar idea way before anyone else.
Speaker 3:  That's kind of sexy. Go make the money, honey. Follow the pitch
Speaker 3:  for our best season yet, new episodes start dropping weekly
Speaker 3:  on February 8th.
Speaker 4:  Dating apps, whether you're single in a relationship or summer in
Speaker 4:  between, you can't get away from them, but what happens when your romantic
Speaker 4:  life is part of a company's bottom line? How did dating
Speaker 4:  become a multi-billion dollar business? I'm Lakshmi
Speaker 4:  Renn.
Speaker 5:  And I'm San Tosin Kurtz. We are hosting Land of the Giants,
Speaker 5:  a podcast about the biggest tech companies of our time.
Speaker 4:  This season we're exploring how apps like Tinder, hinge and
Speaker 4:  Bumble impact our search for love
Speaker 5:  Land of the Giants dating games from the Verge, the Cut,
Speaker 5:  and the Vox Media podcast network. Subscribe for free wherever
Speaker 5:  you listen.
Speaker 3:  And we're
Speaker 2:  Back. Okay, so as I already noted, we're talking the last of us with Charles
Speaker 2:  Pullum Moore today. So if you haven't watched and don't wanna be spoiled,
Speaker 2:  go ahead and skip this segment. No, really, I'm waiting.
Speaker 2:  Okay, great. Welcome everybody else. Look, the Last of us
Speaker 2:  is a bonafide hit and it's also one of the most successful adaptations of
Speaker 2:  a video game we've seen since like, like Angelina Jolie's, tomb Raider.
Speaker 2:  So Charles and I are gonna talk about the first two episodes, the state of
Speaker 2:  video game adaptations, and the hurdles still facing the last of us.
Speaker 2:  Hello Charles, how are you doing today?
Speaker 6:  I'm good crayons. How are you?
Speaker 2:  I'm good. I'm excited to talk with you about the last of us because we have
Speaker 2:  some different opinions and some similar opinions on this. And I think what
Speaker 2:  we first wanna probably talk about is this is kind of a big deal for
Speaker 2:  hbo, right? Like it's been super successful so
Speaker 6:  Far. Yeah. To listen to the way that HBO O is talking about this
Speaker 6:  show. It is the second coming more, more
Speaker 6:  specifically it is their second highest
Speaker 6:  rated show after House of the Dragon, sort of like since
Speaker 6:  2010, which is the, that's sort of like, that's sort of the starting point
Speaker 6:  that we're using as the beginning of like when streaming got serious and
Speaker 6:  it's like hbo, you existed before then and HBO's like, don't think about,
Speaker 6:  don't
Speaker 2:  Think about that. Don't think about it. Yeah, don't worry about it. But
Speaker 6:  It is, you know, it is sort of impressive that, aside from the
Speaker 6:  follow up to one of HBO's most successful shows, which you know has
Speaker 6:  eclipsed its predecessor in terms of its popularity rather in terms of its
Speaker 6:  premier's popularity. This new endeavor from the network has also
Speaker 6:  shown the early signs of being what the kids like to
Speaker 6:  call a hit. Yeah. You know, 4.7 million, you know,
Speaker 6:  4.7 million viewers for Premier is nothing to sneeze at.
Speaker 6:  And while HBO as an entity is
Speaker 6:  not new to this game, right, hbo, this is what
Speaker 6:  they do, they put out hits, right? Yeah. What is sort of, you know, special
Speaker 6:  and momentous about the last of us as you know, if you're listening to this,
Speaker 6:  you know, the last of us based on a video game, video games
Speaker 6:  have a reputation for not being, not lending themselves to the most
Speaker 6:  interesting or compelling adaptations.
Speaker 2:  I mean, I loved Super Mario Brothers the movie, was
Speaker 2:  it a good movie? No.
Speaker 6:  I mean like we, we are of an age, like we are of that age where we have gone
Speaker 6:  through enough waves of things both from like the
Speaker 6:  first party creators. Like we've just seen a number of different Marios Yeah.
Speaker 6:  That now at our big ages we can appreciate what the movie was trying to do.
Speaker 6:  Right. Whereas when you're, when you're young and impressionable, it's like,
Speaker 6:  it's not the thing that I thought it was gonna be. It's terrible. Yeah. Whereas
Speaker 6:  now it's sort of like in this era of her
Speaker 6:  medically sealed and calculated for success adaptations. You look at
Speaker 6:  something like that Mario movie and go, wow. Like the studios really would
Speaker 6:  not try to be like that bold. I was actually just
Speaker 6:  having a conversation about the last of us and the upcoming Mario movie and
Speaker 6:  it's like, yo, like looking back on that Mario, on the live action Mario
Speaker 6:  film, like the idea of a New York City encased in like wet
Speaker 6:  fungus that's colonized at everything is very much what the last of us is
Speaker 6:  trying to go for. Who's to say, who knows? Like maybe if Baba
Speaker 6:  Hoskins, our IP was popping up as Mario now we'd all be like, yo,
Speaker 6:  that right there, that's something I really wanna dig into.
Speaker 2:  I know, I, I, I feel like nobody understood how video game
Speaker 2:  adaptation should work then. And you look back on it and you're like, yeah,
Speaker 2:  it would've been stupid to do a live action like adaptation of the actual
Speaker 2:  Mario game. That would've been dumb.
Speaker 6:  It could have been dumb. It's one of those things where it's, it's, you know,
Speaker 6:  in order for video game adaptations to be successful, there is no one,
Speaker 6:  there is no one way to do it. Right? You can go for
Speaker 6:  accuracy and authenticity, quote unquote,
Speaker 2:  Which is what the last of us is doing, which
Speaker 6:  Is a lot of what the last of us is doing and that's what we're gonna talk
Speaker 6:  about. But there's also something to be said for taking risks and spending
Speaker 6:  money on the production to make it look good and interesting and really selling
Speaker 6:  people on the concept. I think that oftentimes when the shorthand
Speaker 6:  is sort of like, oh, this video game adaptation is bad, what people
Speaker 6:  are really speaking to is the different ways in which the
Speaker 6:  adaptations maybe didn't quite work hard enough
Speaker 6:  to get people on board with their idea of what the adaptation was going
Speaker 6:  to be. And it's kind of like, look, you know this thing and you recognize
Speaker 6:  that this thing is gonna be something different. How about you come on this
Speaker 6:  journey with us? And oftentimes when a film goes out
Speaker 6:  of its way to sort of make that jump from one medium to another easy for
Speaker 6:  you, you kind of find yourself having a good time. Like that's kind of, that
Speaker 6:  was, we're not even talking about the last twist yet, but like that was,
Speaker 6:  that's, that's often how I think about Detective Pikachu, which is a solid
Speaker 6:  film that people don't recognize as being like pretty close to a game. One
Speaker 6:  because a lot of people didn't play the game, but two, because the movie
Speaker 6:  really does go out of its way to sell you on,
Speaker 6:  Hey, what if there was a city filled with 12 species
Speaker 6:  of Pokemon no more, no less? You know?
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I I think like, I think we're, we can talk about the last of us when
Speaker 2:  we talk about this because Detective Pikachu told a really good
Speaker 2:  story first, right? Like, like the reason that people like that movie, the
Speaker 2:  reason people still like that movie is because it was out to tell a good
Speaker 2:  story. And if it hadn't been Pikachu, if it'd just been some other adorable
Speaker 2:  tiny, fluffy creature and a whole bunch of other adorable tiny fluffy creatures
Speaker 2:  probably wouldn't have done as well. Cuz you wouldn't have had that emotional
Speaker 2:  resonance, but it still would've like, worked as a film.
Speaker 6:  It would've worked. And I was gonna say, well, like would about Detective
Speaker 6:  Meow that wouldn't have worked. But then I was thinking to myself like, I
Speaker 6:  totally would've seen a live action team Rocket movie. But the, the thing
Speaker 6:  is like the, the magic of Detective Pikachu really
Speaker 6:  was sort of like, let's create a world that feels rooted
Speaker 6:  in the Pokemon world. Which is to say, you know, you've got my chances guiding
Speaker 6:  traffic, but we are going to make it read as realistic
Speaker 6:  enough for you adult Pokemon fans because we all know who these movies are
Speaker 6:  for. Right. To be able to and want to project yourself
Speaker 6:  into this space so that you can still get that, you know, little nostalgia
Speaker 6:  kick and be able to appreciate the story being told about how Me
Speaker 6:  Too is plotting to take over the world by swapping every,
Speaker 6:  it's very, it's, it's, it's, it's
Speaker 2:  It's a lot. It's a lot. Everybody go watch Detective Pikachu. It's a fun
Speaker 2:  movie. But I think that's interesting to talk about that when we talk
Speaker 2:  about the last of us, because the last of us didn't have as many
Speaker 2:  hurdles to, to jump over, right? Like Naughty Dog has historically done video
Speaker 2:  games that are, everybody calls 'em movies, everybody's like, oh, uncharted
Speaker 2:  is a movie. The Last of Us is a movie. So it kind of like, it already had
Speaker 2:  a lot of the big beats that you seal. It felt like easy mode as adaptations
Speaker 2:  go.
Speaker 6:  It is the truth. It's, it's one of those truths that when you say it out
Speaker 6:  loud, fans get upset with you. And it's like, well, you know, let's just
Speaker 6:  call it it. Like let's just call the thing what it is when you're playing
Speaker 6:  through the last of us. While it is this really dramatic story about
Speaker 6:  a man and his charge trying to survive through the apocalypse,
Speaker 6:  that feels rather specific and unique in the moment when you're
Speaker 6:  like ensconced in it. The moment that you take a step back from the last
Speaker 6:  of us and you know, you look to the left and the right and
Speaker 6:  see things like The Walking Dead, you know, in, in all of its fullness, you
Speaker 6:  recognize that it's just, it's, and I don't say this disparagingly, it's
Speaker 6:  another one of these stories, right? Yeah. This one is right down the middle
Speaker 6:  you've got a grizzled, middle-ish aged man who's got
Speaker 6:  regrets and a lot of you know, guilt and he's, he wears it on his
Speaker 6:  face and he carries it, he carries it in his gait and he's really just living
Speaker 6:  for this little girl who isn't his daughter, but she's just like his and
Speaker 6:  it's like, where have I heard this story before? And the answer is everywhere,
Speaker 6:  right? That it, yeah. It is one of those, you know, quote unquote
Speaker 6:  universal stories whose universality comes from the fact that it is told
Speaker 6:  over and over and over again.
Speaker 2:  I mean that's like Pedro Pascal's career the last couple of years
Speaker 2:  has been telling this story.
Speaker 6:  I don't know if anyone's seen the Mandalorian, but I mean to say that like
Speaker 6:  Ellie and Grok are essentially the same figure. It's not like
Speaker 6:  they got a lot in common. Right? I feel like, I feel like the two of them
Speaker 6:  would get along very, very well. But with the last of us as video game, what
Speaker 6:  really sort of set it apart and what really solidified it in a lot of fans
Speaker 6:  minds is being, you know, best video game story ever
Speaker 6:  has a lot to do with the fact that the game brought together a lot of
Speaker 6:  the components of, I don't wanna call 'em prestige, but you know,
Speaker 6:  serious and well-crafted apocalyptic stories. It brought all of those together
Speaker 6:  and packaged them into a video game that played a lot
Speaker 6:  like a cinematic story that gave you the ability, because it's
Speaker 6:  a third person game to just sort of shift around the scene as it was unfolding.
Speaker 6:  There are action elements, there are stealth elements, but you are supposed
Speaker 6:  to really develop a relationship. You are supposed to develop an
Speaker 6:  affinity for Ellie in all of her foul mouthiness and sort of the
Speaker 6:  way that she balks at the way that Joel is. And you're
Speaker 6:  supposed to sort of almost feel like the unseen third
Speaker 6:  companion who's like following along with them and
Speaker 6:  for people for whom this was their first exposure to that kind
Speaker 6:  of story, that kind of game. I, it's, it's not hard to understand why
Speaker 6:  this caught on for so many people, why this sort of became such a big, such
Speaker 6:  a big kick because, and again, this is not to disparage oftentimes, you know,
Speaker 6:  video game stories, they're not always great, right? Yeah. They're not always,
Speaker 6:  sometimes it is like, hey you are here to power these
Speaker 6:  guns up and mow through these masses of
Speaker 6:  undead people and that's it and that's it. Don't worry about the story. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And the last of us really did sort of prioritize you internalizing the
Speaker 6:  story and your feelings about those characters. There were rumblings for
Speaker 6:  a very long time that there was going to be Last of Us film. It's also easy
Speaker 6:  to understand why because this does ape the shape and the
Speaker 6:  movements of not just to zombie movie, but there are also
Speaker 6:  traces of things like children of men in this. There
Speaker 6:  are shades of the road in this for the cor mc McCarthy fans,
Speaker 6:  right. It's, it's obvious, it's easy to see why the studios saw to themselves,
Speaker 6:  oh this has to be on the big screen. Yeah. But is often the case with
Speaker 6:  video game projects, you know, they get stuck in development. Hell, it
Speaker 2:  Was messy
Speaker 6:  And ultimately, you know, it finds its home. The project finds its
Speaker 6:  home on H B O as a series, which,
Speaker 6:  you know, the general understanding is that the adaptation curse is not specific
Speaker 6:  to movies. It's like, no, no, no. Once you try to turn a video game into
Speaker 6:  anything that's not a video game, it just be instantly becomes bad. But again,
Speaker 6:  because the last of us at its core was always crafted with such
Speaker 6:  a cinematic style of storytelling in mind, what we've
Speaker 6:  seen, what you and I have seen people who are listening, being to watch the
Speaker 6:  show we're seeing is a lot of the show is like a pretty faithful,
Speaker 6:  you know, there are, yeah, let's say maybe 60% faithful
Speaker 6:  recreations and there are other 40% or things that are different, but it's
Speaker 6:  like, oh, this is just what I didn't see on camera. Cuz I didn't,
Speaker 6:  I wasn't facing in that direction while I was playing.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I think that's, that's really, that's one of the things I've kind of
Speaker 2:  liked about it is because I played the game and I hate zombies. They terrify
Speaker 2:  me. And so like, playing the game was the worst experience in the world.
Speaker 2:  Cause like I'll play it. Everybody loves it, I gotta play it. My brother
Speaker 2:  would come over and do his laundry and I'd be like, can you beat this part
Speaker 2:  cuz I'm too scared like a grown ass woman asking my brother to do
Speaker 2:  this. But that's why I liked the, the movie is I was like, oh, I can just
Speaker 2:  skip to the cut scenes. I don't have to worry about mowing down all these
Speaker 2:  guys or sneaking past all of these, these zombies. I can just get to
Speaker 2:  the good parts, the reason that I played the game and, and have historically
Speaker 2:  played naughty dog games. But there were, there were definitely some, some
Speaker 2:  changes here. And I wanna talk about some of those. The first one we're gonna
Speaker 2:  talk about is the death of Tess. Presumably everybody's
Speaker 2:  listening to this very different from the game cuz the game, her death happens
Speaker 2:  off camera and it's by humans. And in this she
Speaker 2:  frenches a zombie.
Speaker 6:  It's a, it's a heroic noble sacrifice. And she's like, Joel,
Speaker 6:  they got me,
Speaker 2:  They
Speaker 6:  Got me. They got me. Joel, and I'm glad we're talking about this because
Speaker 6:  in this first episode, Tess has sort of been won over on the idea
Speaker 6:  of Ellie being potentially like the savior Yeah. Of humanity.
Speaker 6:  And that's also something that, that is not unlike the show or rather unlike
Speaker 6:  the game, but the show puts a lot more emphasis on it subtly, right?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. It's not, it's not exactly the most, like they're not beating you over
Speaker 6:  the head with it, but there are more people who are sort of aware of Ellie's
Speaker 6:  specialness and it sort of inspires them to
Speaker 6:  rise to do heroic things in order to make sure that she and Joel are
Speaker 6:  able to, to like make it away. And the first, one of the first big examples
Speaker 6:  of this is us seeing Tess, you know, decide to,
Speaker 6:  she blows the thing up. There's a bunch of cor decept zombies coming in
Speaker 6:  and they swarm her and, and
Speaker 2:  She's trying to light the the lighter.
Speaker 6:  Can I tell you that's one of my least favorite tropes. I've never had a lighter
Speaker 6:  just like stay lit also when I like let it go. So this whole like, I'm gonna
Speaker 6:  throw it dramatically,
Speaker 2:  Zippos will do it, but zippos also light easy and I was just like,
Speaker 2:  I know you're dying. I know you're scared but can you like,
Speaker 2:  can you focus for half a second,
Speaker 6:  Do it with some intentionality and then just set it down.
Speaker 2:  When I saw that moment where it's a really violent, really, really
Speaker 2:  kind of gross moment, her death in this versus the game, the game is like
Speaker 2:  happens off camera and yes you can technically go back and look at her body
Speaker 2:  and be like  That was my jewel impression by the way.
Speaker 2:  You can technically do that. But in this it's like, no, she's gonna have
Speaker 2:  a very graphic death and you are gonna know she's dead. And it felt
Speaker 2:  really kind of cruel to me. I was like okay,
Speaker 2:  I didn't need that. Like one Anna to is doing a great job of getting
Speaker 2:  us to care about this character. She's doing a great job of developing relationships
Speaker 2:  with these other characters. So like we feel her relationship
Speaker 2:  and her commitment to Ellie in a way that didn't always necessarily
Speaker 2:  translate in the game. And we feel that relationship with her and Joel in
Speaker 2:  a way that didn't translate in the game. And then to be like, no, now
Speaker 2:  she's gonna like make out with a zombie.
Speaker 6:  My reading The Zombie made out with her, the zombie was very much like, come
Speaker 6:  on, come on. And she was like, look, where else am I gonna go? I know what
Speaker 6:  you mean as you alluded to earlier. I'm neutral on the show. I think
Speaker 6:  it's fine. Right. Yeah, I think it is definitely, it's one of the better
Speaker 6:  apocalyptic zombie shows out in the past 10
Speaker 6:  years let's say, in that I just like that it moves. There
Speaker 6:  are other series like The Walking Dead that really do meander and spend too
Speaker 6:  much time focusing on petty human things that I understand. That's, I can
Speaker 6:  understand that that's, that's where the comics exist. That's where, you
Speaker 6:  know, they are sort of most comfortable. But after a while it's like, I don't
Speaker 6:  care about cannibals doing, doing silly things that, you know,
Speaker 6:  hurt people.
Speaker 2:  I'm focused on these two characters. Let's move along. Let's get 'em to
Speaker 2:  Colorado. That
Speaker 6:  Being said, something that I, I came to feel about this show as I watched
Speaker 6:  all nine episodes is because, so it is a very, it is a really
Speaker 6:  faithful adaptation of the game, but because it is a television show, there
Speaker 6:  are some things that are structurally different about it and in a way that
Speaker 6:  like when you play through a video game as you're progressing through, we
Speaker 6:  don't really think about games as levels anymore, but they're just sort of
Speaker 6:  vignettes that you sort of play through. When I'm sitting down to play a
Speaker 6:  video game, it's almost kind of like interactive theater for me.
Speaker 6:  There is a certain degree to which I do not
Speaker 6:  think or worry too much about the logistics
Speaker 6:  of how people move around the world. I I don't think I'm unique in that
Speaker 6:  and there is some of that here in the game or rather here in the show.
Speaker 6:  But one of the things that I came away feeling because of the show's structure
Speaker 6:  it all, it has a way of creating this kind of like character of the week
Speaker 6:  kind of scenario. Yeah. Where just as a
Speaker 6:  character has had a chance to exist on screen and really
Speaker 6:  sell you on them as a person and how they fit into this world, they end up
Speaker 6:  dying. Which again is not unique, especially in
Speaker 6:  an apocalyptic show, but they always end up
Speaker 6:  dying in a way that to me felt as if it was meant to sort of
Speaker 6:  make you go, oh wow. Damn, that's sad. And
Speaker 6:  while I, I totally appreciate that being the intended
Speaker 6:  response, there comes a point at which the
Speaker 6:  mm I don't wanna say manufactured this, but sort of the intentional working
Speaker 6:  towards that feeling kind of started to feel hollow for
Speaker 6:  me.
Speaker 2:  I get that. I think you can, you can see the structure of this show
Speaker 2:  really clearly in a way that you don't always. And so like on the last of
Speaker 2:  us, I don't think this is a spoiler, those odd number episodes tend to be
Speaker 2:  like flashbacks. We're gonna stop and we're gonna sit with a character and
Speaker 2:  we're gonna really think about them. Even number episodes are like, we gonna
Speaker 2:  move through the plot today, Let's get through it. You know, what's coming?
Speaker 2:  Let's go. And so I started to like brace
Speaker 2:  myself cuz especially cuz being aware of these characters and being aware
Speaker 2:  of, of their stories in the game, I was like, okay, I
Speaker 2:  know what's coming next. I know next week is gonna be, we're gonna go deep
Speaker 2:  dive with these two characters and I know what's gonna happen to them probably
Speaker 2:  in that episode or the episode right after. And so I get like, you do
Speaker 2:  feel that kind of manufactured way where you're like, do I actually like
Speaker 2:  this? Is this actually good or am I just like enjoying it because
Speaker 2:  it's an adaptation of something I've enjoyed and I like seeing a new version
Speaker 2:  of it,
Speaker 6:  But also because the shape of everyone's arcs, the the
Speaker 6:  specific details when you zoom in are very different. But after a
Speaker 6:  while the pattern does become, here's a new character for you to develop
Speaker 6:  an affinity for, get ready for them to die and for us to return to Eli and
Speaker 6:  Joel. And that's all supposed to serve to rather to reinforce upon
Speaker 6:  you like these are the situations this, these are the circumstances that
Speaker 6:  El and Joel exist in. And I can appreciate that without Yeah. You know, I
Speaker 6:  don't, I don't always need to see, you know, the happy couple
Speaker 6:  who finds love in the apocalypse suddenly die. Oh my God. Aren't you
Speaker 6:  sad? Cuz that happens a couple that happens a couple of times in this show
Speaker 6:  and it's like, alright, alright, I get it, I get it, I
Speaker 6:  get it. But these zo I I, it's, it's funny, I like you
Speaker 6:  am a big old scared cat. Yeah. When it comes to zombies, Zach Snyder's, Don
Speaker 6:  of the Dead truly ruined me for a few years. Right. Just really,
Speaker 6:  I, we can talk about that at another time. But with the last
Speaker 6:  of us, I being the weirdo that I am,
Speaker 6:  this being both the gay and the show, putting so much
Speaker 6:  focus on the fungal aspect of the
Speaker 6:  infection. I came into the show really excited
Speaker 6:  to see not just the clickers, I wanna see all of it, right? Yeah. I, I wanna
Speaker 6:  see every stage of the infection. And I get that the show doesn't
Speaker 6:  necessarily start off in a place where we're going to be seeing
Speaker 6:  all of them out and about hunting. But one of the things that I,
Speaker 6:  especially at this point where we are in this series now personally,
Speaker 6:  I want to see more, I wanna see more than just can we kiss
Speaker 6:  and I gave you my fungal infection. I wanna see more, I wanna see more
Speaker 6:  fungal armor.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Well the show, the show is continuing on. We don't wanna spoil
Speaker 2:  the rest of it for, for our audience. I assume a lot of you who are listening
Speaker 2:  to this are watching the show. I love it. If you're listening to this and
Speaker 2:  you haven't been watching the show, sorry for the spoilers, I'm sorry.
Speaker 2:  You're gonna have to go Google like Tess make out Zombie
Speaker 6:  Do that Halloween costume. Like that's, start thinking about
Speaker 2:  That now. That's a good costume. I think we, we, you know, we might come
Speaker 2:  back to this. This is, this is still gonna be a really big adaptation. Do
Speaker 2:  you think this is gonna be a sea change for video adaptations? Do you think
Speaker 2:  people are gonna stop hand ringing about it? Especially as games themselves
Speaker 2:  have often gotten more cinematic?
Speaker 6:  I think the more interesting thing to pay attention to is if and how
Speaker 6:  games really start posturing themselves to lend themselves to adaptations
Speaker 6:  better. And I don't think that's necessarily going to mean everything is
Speaker 6:  going to be third person. Every game is just gonna give all of its
Speaker 6:  NPCs like, you know, wiki in trees that you can just click through and it's
Speaker 6:  like, ooh, I know who's gonna play this person. It's not necessarily gonna
Speaker 6:  be that, but I think it is gonna be interesting to see if more developers
Speaker 6:  try to start positioning their games for this kind
Speaker 6:  of thing.
Speaker 2:  Kinda like comics have been doing the last like 10, 15 years
Speaker 2:  where they're like, this is actually just like our pitch for the movie you
Speaker 2:  should make instead. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  Yeah,
Speaker 2:  Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. That's why Captain Marvel exists.
Speaker 2:  Sorry, love Captain Marvel. Great movie, but it
Speaker 2:  exists because they wanted to make a movie. The comic does. Well, thank you
Speaker 2:  Charles. This has been a wonderful conversation. Of course. You're gonna
Speaker 2:  have to come on again. We'll do, let's do like a two hour episode on Super
Speaker 2:  Mario Brothers the movie. And Wyatt's arguably one of the most
Speaker 2:  interesting film adaptations of a game.
Speaker 6:  This is something that we can a hundred percent agree on. So yes.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, we're gonna do it. Get excited, we'll do that and we'll be like, oh
Speaker 2:  yeah. And then also there's this other supermarket movie. It's great. But
Speaker 2:  thank you so much Charles,
Speaker 6:  This is great.
Speaker 2:  We're gonna take a break and when we get back we're gonna be talking with
Speaker 2:  Margaret all about non-competes
Speaker 2:  Support for today's show comes from Deloitte. What does the future look
Speaker 2:  like? It's a question that drives progress, but more importantly, how do
Speaker 2:  you get there? It's curiosity, resourcefulness and bold
Speaker 2:  ideas that can drive us even further than new technology. Because
Speaker 2:  while technology can take you far human exploration could take you even
Speaker 2:  farther. Deloitte helps businesses build the future only they can imagine
Speaker 2:  by melding deep business acumen and innovative technology with a
Speaker 2:  vast team of tech savvy professionals. Unlock technology as powerful as
Speaker 2:  your vision and push the boundaries of the possible so that you can stay
Speaker 2:  a step ahead with the thinking to help you transform what's next into
Speaker 2:  what's now helping you see the extraordinary potential in the seemingly ordinary
Speaker 2:  while blending the possible with the practical is what Deloitte does.
Speaker 2:  See how you can engineer advantage with Deloitte at
Speaker 2:  deloitte.com/us/engineering advantage.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. So a few weeks ago and after months of
Speaker 2:  investigation, the FTC announced its plan to get rid of the non-compete in
Speaker 2:  the United States. The
Speaker 7:  Rule would make it illegal for a company to enter into a new non-compete
Speaker 7:  agreement with a worker or maintain an existing non-compete. And
Speaker 7:  companies would mostly not be allowed to tell workers they're subject to
Speaker 7:  non-compete clauses.
Speaker 2:  A lot of people have had feelings about that and there's a lot of concern
Speaker 2:  that without non-competes innovation and companies is just gonna like falter.
Speaker 2:  But I personally don't think that's true. California has basically never
Speaker 2:  permitted the enforcement of non-competes. And Silicon Valley, which is like
Speaker 2:  hugely innovative, has thrived partially because of that.
Speaker 2:  But you shouldn't just believe me and that's why I'm talking to Margaret
Speaker 2:  O'Mara, she's a historian at the University of Washington, an author of several
Speaker 2:  books including the Code, which is all about the creation of Silicon Valley
Speaker 2:  as we know it.
Speaker 2:  So Margaret, thank you for joining us today.
Speaker 8:  It's great to be here. Thanks for having me.
Speaker 2:  I was really excited to talk to you because obviously there's been a lot
Speaker 2:  of discussion about non-competes lately. A lot of hand ringing from
Speaker 2:  certain parts of the world, a lot of like finally
Speaker 2:  from other parts of the world. And what I thought was really interesting
Speaker 2:  was reading your book, the code, you kind of talk about this
Speaker 2:  myth that we've known about, about Silicon Valley for a long time. That
Speaker 2:  the non-compete or the lack of non-competes built Silicon Valley.
Speaker 2:  Would you say that's true?
Speaker 8:  I think it's one factor. You know, it's, it's one of these things that historians
Speaker 8:  love. It's this totally serendipitous accidental,
Speaker 8:  it's an accident of history. It's, yeah, there was, the reason
Speaker 8:  that Silicon Valley has been advantaged in this particular way
Speaker 8:  has to do with the California state Constitution of, you know,
Speaker 8:  formulated in the late 19th century, which was just trying to kind of, it
Speaker 8:  was this hodgepodge of lots of different legal traditions, you know, Spanish,
Speaker 8:  Anglo-American, and long story short just ended up with this provision
Speaker 8:  that you could not enforce the non-compete agreement and the way that it
Speaker 8:  worked in practice, particularly in early Silicon Valley, meaning in
Speaker 8:  the 1960s when the chip industry is starting, the
Speaker 8:  silicon semiconductor makers that put the silicon in the valley,
Speaker 8:  that people could easily hop from one company to another.
Speaker 8:  And, and certainly employers kind of tried to prevent
Speaker 8:  IP from, from traveling with them, right. But they really,
Speaker 8:  they really couldn't. And so it was incredibly generative and allowed
Speaker 8:  tacit knowledge and experience and technical knowledge to go from
Speaker 8:  one place to another quite easily
Speaker 2:  Because there was only a couple of, of these, these chip makers
Speaker 2:  there. And then suddenly there was a ton and you look and you're like, wait,
Speaker 2:  you all seem to start at like Fairchild and you all just kinda
Speaker 2:  left. And then like Intel, Intel was started by two guys from Fairchild,
Speaker 2:  right? Yeah. Would Intel exist now? I mean obviously
Speaker 2:  it might exist now, but yeah. If non-competes had been enforceable in
Speaker 2:  California, would Intel have grown as as much as it did then?
Speaker 8:  Gosh, I don't know. I mean there's, yeah, I mean, I think just broadly the
Speaker 8:  incredibly generative nature of lots of small firms kind of networked
Speaker 8:  small firms was really enabled by this kind of fluidity
Speaker 8:  in the marketplace. And you know, part of it was kind of a, we're
Speaker 8:  making this up as we go along element to it. I, I
Speaker 8:  like to think about the early Valley as kind of like the Galapagos Islands
Speaker 8:  where you are removed from other
Speaker 8:  inputs. You're kind of in this very isolated space. I mean, keep in mind
Speaker 8:  the only other thing going on there was growing apricots
Speaker 8:  and fruit orchard. You know, there's just not, this wasn't an
Speaker 8:  industrial area like say Boston
Speaker 8:  or you know, New York or other places that the electronics industry
Speaker 8:  and the computer industry was growing at that time. And so, and these were
Speaker 8:  young, younger people. The the guys who ended up out there
Speaker 8:  were there in part because they didn't have connections and money.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. And, and they didn't have a lot of managerial experience
Speaker 8:  or a lot of, you know, being non, non-hierarchical and having
Speaker 8:  kind of flat management structures was also something really highly valued
Speaker 8:  in the early valley.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And you talk about in, in the book that some of these initial companies,
Speaker 2:  the managers were just bad. Like, you'd go and you'd work for a guy and he'd
Speaker 2:  be a genius, but he'd be terrible to work with. And so these guys would go,
Speaker 2:  wait a minute, I can take a lot of the ideas I have here and just go start
Speaker 2:  my own company and not work for this jackass.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. Turns out being a Nobel Prize winner does not
Speaker 8:  necessarily mean you're gonna be a great boss. The most
Speaker 8:  notoriously bad boss that really kind of gets this flywheel going
Speaker 8:  is William Shockley the go inventor of the transistor. He's the person who
Speaker 8:  brings out these super talented young engineers to work for
Speaker 8:  him at his, his newly created Shockly Semiconductor,
Speaker 8:  which is the very first semiconductor startup in the valley in the mid fifties.
Speaker 8:  He's impossible to work for. He has a lot of other not very great
Speaker 8:  character traits and eight of them band
Speaker 8:  together find someone who's going to help them
Speaker 8:  find financing and start their own company. And
Speaker 8:  yeah, there was no, you know, the long arm of California law
Speaker 8:  couldn't come in and say, no, you can't do that. And then in turn, when
Speaker 8:  the Fairchild semiconductor, which was that new company when that got
Speaker 8:  to be the, you know, know the people who had financed that were being
Speaker 8:  a little bit obstinate about allowing the, the people who work
Speaker 8:  there to do what they wanted to do. Shocking. Yeah. They left and went on
Speaker 8:  to start their own companies or go to other companies and see these ideas.
Speaker 8:  So yeah, there's this ability to just jump ship and, and go that is,
Speaker 8:  it's, you know, contributing to it. I mean one of the really cool things
Speaker 8:  about all of this is that, you know, we all wanna kind of point to here's
Speaker 8:  this one thing that made everything happen. Yes. And actually it's a lot
Speaker 8:  of things working together, but the non-competes is this sort of wonderful
Speaker 8:  oddball circumstance that underscores how,
Speaker 8:  you know, sometimes you can't, things you don't expect will be
Speaker 8:  really consequential. And also these like distinctions of
Speaker 8:  geography actually really do matter. The, the kind of state what state law
Speaker 8:  is like has a is consequential.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I think a lot of times my kind of go-to on non-competes is Mark
Speaker 2:  Papermaster in the, the mid two thousands he was at I B M,
Speaker 2:  he was overseeing a lot of their chip business there. Tony
Speaker 2:  Fidel leaves Apple, he was the creator of the iPod. He leaves and
Speaker 2:  they say, okay, we're gonna bring in Mark Papermaster. And they bring him
Speaker 2:  in and IBM's like, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa. And because he'd signed
Speaker 2:  his contract in New York and not in California, he went to court
Speaker 2:  and he, he ended up settling and couldn't work for six months, was
Speaker 2:  unemployed by Apple for six months, worked there for a year and then left
Speaker 2:  like just ruined kind of his career. And that wouldn't have happened
Speaker 2:  in California necessarily if he'd signed all those contracts additionally.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. And look, you know, the, you know, part of this story, this California
Speaker 8:  noncompete story is also, you know, the early days, of course these companies
Speaker 8:  are incorporated in California, they're just in California. Yeah. Now we
Speaker 8:  have tech companies that have, you know, they may be headquartered in California,
Speaker 8:  but they're all over the world. So, you know, the stories could become a
Speaker 8:  little more murky too. Right, right. We do have instances in which very
Speaker 8:  valuable talent and ideas try to move and the
Speaker 8:  the, the companies try to claw that back. So the big look, the big Silicon
Speaker 8:  Valley based companies are not immune from that either.
Speaker 8:  But I think there's a real value in recognizing
Speaker 8:  innovation rarely happens kind of vertically within the silo of
Speaker 8:  one company. Yeah. It usually happens with a lot of different places.
Speaker 8:  Inputs, you know, this is the real contrast drawn between
Speaker 8:  the early Valley and Boston's Route 1 28, which was
Speaker 8:  a lot of big companies where things were within. And the east coast more
Speaker 8:  generally was a lot of big companies like, like at and t and Bell
Speaker 8:  Labs, which is where Shockley started and the ability
Speaker 8:  to kind of, you know, have these smaller firms, multiple
Speaker 8:  smaller firms rather than one single one seems to have been, you know,
Speaker 8:  you can track, there's just more ideas being generated and new things
Speaker 8:  happening.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Let's, let's talk a little bit more about the east coast side of things
Speaker 2:  because pre shockly, pre Fairchild, it was the east coast where
Speaker 2:  most of the development was happening. That was where a lot of the universities
Speaker 2:  were. That was where a lot of the, the, the big companies were. And then
Speaker 2:  it slowly moved to Silicon Valley and part of that was was because of the
Speaker 2:  non-competes because Boston and, and New York, yeah. They'd enforce them.
Speaker 2:  They'd keep these guys from it.
Speaker 8:  Right. Yeah. And well, and it was that sort of enforcement I think is one
Speaker 8:  piece of kind of a broader story
Speaker 2:  Of yeah, maybe
Speaker 8:  Let's call it more conservative business culture or you know, this is
Speaker 8:  the way we do things. You know, keep in mind that in the
Speaker 8:  middle part of the 20th century, a lot of this advanced electronics,
Speaker 8:  particularly miniature electronics, was really state of the art.
Speaker 8:  Not, you know, it was risky business. Like, oh, there's not a, you know,
Speaker 8:  what's the use case? The thing that was, you know, the flywheel that was
Speaker 8:  really creating a market in large part was the Cold
Speaker 8:  War and military spending and the US government was ordering up these
Speaker 8:  esoteric high-tech things, but more broadly in the commercial
Speaker 8:  side. Yeah. There was a commercial computer industry in the fifties and sixties,
Speaker 8:  a huge one. It was almost entirely had ordered on the east coast. And that's
Speaker 8:  another thing that's kind of gets lost in the story. Yeah. You
Speaker 8:  have these really early super important milestones of
Speaker 8:  computing that are happening on the east coast. I mean, a really important
Speaker 8:  part of this whole history is the very first all digital pro
Speaker 8:  programmable computer is the Neac, which is developed at the
Speaker 8:  University of Pennsylvania. Penn in Philly in comes out in
Speaker 8:  1946. The inventors of that try to
Speaker 8:  commercialize it. Penn makes it super, super
Speaker 8:  difficult for them to do so. And
Speaker 8:  ultimately they kind of leave their jobs at the university and they
Speaker 8:  don't have kind of financing. They, you know, look the university, other
Speaker 8:  kind of financiers there were not that interested in investing. They
Speaker 8:  commercialize as this startup called univac, which creates a
Speaker 8:  commercial version of this. This is really the first, you know, in the very
Speaker 8:  early days of computing, UNIVAC kind of was synonymous with computer in the
Speaker 8:  way that Kleenex is with facial tissue and Google is with
Speaker 8:  search, right? Yeah. Just for a brief period. But they had to kind of go
Speaker 8:  on their own. And you know, it's a really
Speaker 8:  good example of this, well we don't wanna, you know, we don't wanna
Speaker 8:  invest in this new thing. Like what are you gonna do with that? How are you
Speaker 8:  gonna make money? And, and whereas on the west coast there was,
Speaker 8:  you know, a different, you know, it was less, there were fewer
Speaker 8:  established institutions that were ready to stay. No.
Speaker 8:  And there was now this big stream of money coming in,
Speaker 8:  particularly in places like California that had to do with military
Speaker 8:  spending. And so that's a, a wave that these small firms got to ride.
Speaker 8:  Yeah,
Speaker 2:  No, that's cool that they, they kind of, they wrote it and then they created
Speaker 2:  Silicon Valley and like Yeah, now everything's there. Now it's California's
Speaker 2:  what the fifth largest economy in the world or something incredible like
Speaker 2:  that.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. It's enormous. You know, it's, it also points to like, we can also
Speaker 8:  look and see kind of what matters and what doesn't. Right. So,
Speaker 8:  you know, Silicon Valley entrepreneurs and business leaders have,
Speaker 8:  you know, forever been complaining about California taxes and they are
Speaker 8:  high for sure. And certainly here in my state of
Speaker 8:  Washington, there's, it's definitely been a regional advantage that there's
Speaker 8:  no state income tax and other things that kind of tech firms have used
Speaker 8:  to leverage to recruit people and to grow. But look, if we
Speaker 8:  really look at the sort of, what is the thing, if Thai taxes
Speaker 8:  were deterrent to a high-tech cluster growing and
Speaker 8:  innovation happening, then California would've been, wouldn't have start
Speaker 8:  begun in the first place. You know, there are kind of other things. So this,
Speaker 8:  this non-compete story is a great example of, there are other things, a
Speaker 8:  state conditions that a state law can create
Speaker 8:  or local business climate that are actually more important
Speaker 8:  Yeah. Than whether it's a high tax or a low tax place.
Speaker 8:  And of course if you're a really low tax region, then you know, I mean taxes
Speaker 8:  pay for public amenities. So one of the things that grew California, certainly
Speaker 8:  in the middle part of the 20th century was, yes, it was high taxes, but they
Speaker 8:  were spending a lot on building roads and schools and infrastructure and
Speaker 8:  all these things that were making it pretty easy and
Speaker 8:  interest. You know, people were drawn to migrate to California because of
Speaker 8:  that.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I know. And they did not go to Texas. Well we had ti
Speaker 2:  we had ti at Tandy.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. I mean a lot. Look, a lot of people went to Texas. It's great. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  Another reminder too is like, you know, people are like, oh, Texas is the
Speaker 8:  new high-tech capital. And you're like, well actually they've been doing
Speaker 8:  that stuff for a long time. Yeah, yeah. Like this is, you know,
Speaker 8:  nothing's as new as you think. That's the other thing. History professors
Speaker 8:  always like to chime in, be like, this isn't new. We've been doing this for
Speaker 8:  a while.
Speaker 2:  It's true though. Yeah. I think a lot of people in California are like, oh,
Speaker 2:  you're making non-competes out, getting rid of non-competes. That's not new.
Speaker 2:  We've been doing that for decades. Yeah. Since, since the beginning,
Speaker 8:  Since 1870.
Speaker 2:  Well do so, so it sounds like non-competes are, are just kind of one
Speaker 2:  part of this big puzzle for, for the development of Silicon Valley, but they
Speaker 2:  really did enable a lot of these firms to be much more creative, to
Speaker 2:  let people bounce around to to, to create that kind of ingenuity
Speaker 2:  that we think of as like a hallmark of the region.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, I think that's right. And I think, you know, what it underscores,
Speaker 8:  I think for wherever you are is that the tech
Speaker 8:  industry, it's, it's not about necessarily the tech, it's about the
Speaker 8:  people, right. The people who, who create the ideas
Speaker 8:  and that, you know, the, the moving back and forth and the
Speaker 8:  willingness to, you know, I think what it also does is, it's not to say
Speaker 8:  that Silicon Valley has not always been an extremely competitive place.
Speaker 8:  These, all these little chip makers in the sixties, you would not, I mean
Speaker 8:  the elbows were sharp. Yeah, yeah. They were, they were hustling
Speaker 8:  hard to out to outrun one another. But you do create
Speaker 8:  kind of this collaborative ecosystem
Speaker 8:  of people, you know, just a lot of connective tissue
Speaker 8:  across firms. And that over time is really
Speaker 8:  generative. If you actually look at the, I love Steve Jobs once,
Speaker 8:  the metaphor that he used, which I really love is talk, he talks about passing
Speaker 8:  the baton. Yeah. Which is one generation kind of
Speaker 8:  passes the baton to the next in tech. And so that's the other thing. There's
Speaker 8:  kind of this lateral movement at during a certain tech generation
Speaker 8:  and then it also turns over to, you know, this, the people making
Speaker 8:  microchips are the mentors and the investors of
Speaker 8:  the people making desktop computers. And then those people
Speaker 8:  are the ones investing and mentoring the early.com
Speaker 8:  companies and on and on. And so that kind of
Speaker 8:  collaboration across entities and across time is
Speaker 8:  a real secret of Silicon Valley that sometimes gets lost in the
Speaker 8:  shuffle. Cuz we think present tense and future tense is what it, what
Speaker 8:  matters. But actually time and the time
Speaker 8:  it has taken to create this very distinctive community that
Speaker 8:  non-competes helped foster that. Yeah. In the
Speaker 8:  very beginning. That's really what makes it go
Speaker 2:  Well. Thank you Margaret. This was super, super informative. I appreciate
Speaker 2:  it you taking the time to come chat.
Speaker 8:  Well delighted to join you. Thanks.
Speaker 2:  We're gonna take another break and when we're back, we're gonna be doing
Speaker 2:  the hotline. Stay tuned.
Speaker 2:  Okay. Welcome back. It's time to hear what our listeners are thinking about
Speaker 2:  in the tech world. Our VIR hotline is open 24 7 where you can
Speaker 2:  leave us messages and ask all of your Burning Tech questions. We selected
Speaker 2:  a few to run today, but keep calling, I swear we listen, we
Speaker 2:  wanna hear from you. Our first question comes from Jay in Ann Arbor, Michigan.
Speaker 2:  Let's go right to it.
Speaker 9:  Hi, this is Jay from Ann Arbor, Michigan and like
Speaker 9:  many of the cast hosts, I am excited
Speaker 9:  about U S BBC and as more things use
Speaker 9:  US BBC connectors, the problem I'm starting to face
Speaker 9:  is that I don't have enough ports to plug everything in.
Speaker 9:  And it doesn't seem like there are as many hubs
Speaker 9:  available as there are for U S B A connectors. I've
Speaker 9:  read that some of that has to do with the chips that are required
Speaker 9:  to make that happen. But I was wondering what your take was.
Speaker 9:  Thanks a lot
Speaker 2:  Jay. We're gonna go ahead and talk to Sean Hollister, who I like
Speaker 2:  to think is the verges u S BBC expert. Sean,
Speaker 2:  what's happening with u s bbc?
Speaker 10:  Hi Jay. You're absolutely right. It does have something to do with the
Speaker 10:  chips. You see there are a lot of companies who want to
Speaker 10:  make u s BBC hubs who want to make U s BBC docking stations,
Speaker 10:  but all of them or very very many of them rely on chips from
Speaker 10:  a smaller number of suppliers. And so these chip companies are like,
Speaker 10:  well what do people want out of a USS BBC dock? And most of them
Speaker 10:  say they want a single cable that lets their laptop plug into legacy
Speaker 10:  peripherals. And so U S B A continues to be hugely
Speaker 10:  popular. Ethernet doesn't have a replacement yet. Cameras
Speaker 10:  have not really switched from big SD cards to micro SD cards.
Speaker 10:  And so all of those things are competing for space
Speaker 10:  and for capabilities in the chips and
Speaker 10:  docks that are made. And so like if I
Speaker 10:  want to get us BBC ports right now I'm kind of limited to
Speaker 10:  Thunderbolt four docks. If you want to pay 300, $400,
Speaker 10:  maybe 200 if you're lucky for a Thunderbolt four
Speaker 10:  docking station, they're out there, cow digit pluggable, even
Speaker 10:  anchor mix, some of them, each one of them is gonna make you make some kind
Speaker 10:  of trade-offs. Either you're gonna pay a lot of money if you want something
Speaker 10:  that gives you like three downstream usb, four Thunderbolt four
Speaker 10:  ports, or you're going to pay for a lot less capability. I
Speaker 10:  saw one in an anchor that'll give you like two additional U S
Speaker 10:  BBC ports outta your laptop. Ah, but even that costs 200 bucks. It's a
Speaker 10:  lot of money.
Speaker 2:  Two, only two extra ports. A hundred dollars a port.
Speaker 10:  Yeah. Because when you're talking about Thunderbolt four people assume,
Speaker 10:  oh yeah, this person's gonna plug in a bunch of high speed like external
Speaker 10:  GPUs and heavy duty storage. It's gonna be rate arrays.
Speaker 10:  But then they're also going to have to go to Intel generally and get some
Speaker 10:  fancy chips to do that. Each one of those chips
Speaker 10:  generally gives you two ports on a docking station.
Speaker 10:  So there'll be one port that'll be the one that goes into your laptop and
Speaker 10:  then you get one downstream port out of that. And then your second chip
Speaker 10:  will probably get you your other two downstream ports. So you'll have your,
Speaker 10:  maybe your monitor will come out of that and you'll have your rate array
Speaker 10:  and then you'll have maybe your a second monitor or, or some other
Speaker 10:  fancy U S BBC device on the other end, but you don't get a lot.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, yeah. That sounds like nothing. So if, if Jay or
Speaker 2:  myself wants to add like four or five U s BBC
Speaker 2:  ports, we basically just need to go spend $300
Speaker 2:  on a Thunderbolt for Doc in Hope.
Speaker 10:  I really wish it was different. That's kind of the case right now. If you
Speaker 10:  go to Amazon, you search for a U US BBC hub, most of them
Speaker 10:  are just gonna have a single u SB connector that plugs into your laptop.
Speaker 10:  And then if there's a second U S BBC on it, it might not even be for
Speaker 10:  data, it'll just be a power input. Ugh. So they figure you're gonna
Speaker 10:  plug your laptops CPC power adapter into the hub and then
Speaker 10:  you can get the pass through to your laptop. That way you get that glorious,
Speaker 10:  oh yeah, I can plug this single cable in my laptop. I get my power, it's
Speaker 10:  charging, it's gonna, I can plug my old flash drive in, I can plug my hd,
Speaker 10:  my monitor in, I can plug my ethernet in for Wired internet. They
Speaker 10:  don't expect that you're gonna have all this high speed additional peripherals
Speaker 10:  and that if you do, you're gonna be willing to spend those extra, you know,
Speaker 10:  a hundred, 200, $300 for the Thunderbolt four
Speaker 2:  Episode. Is there any hope? Like is there something, did something
Speaker 2:  get announced that ces were there there rumors? Are we, are we gonna get
Speaker 2:  any relief?
Speaker 10:  I wish. I think what it's going to take, I think what it's really going
Speaker 10:  to take is when we have
Speaker 10:  passed by some of these old legacy peripherals, when people have accepted
Speaker 10:  you don't really need ethernet anymore, you're gonna be fine with wifi,
Speaker 10:  we're getting to the point where WiFi's getting a little more, more reliable.
Speaker 10:  You can get back channel three, you know, your 60 gigahertz band
Speaker 10:  so that you have that dedicated high speed short range connection to
Speaker 10:  your router, right? Or to your VR headset or something. Maybe you don't
Speaker 10:  need that port anymore in the future. Maybe micro SD
Speaker 10:  becomes more reliable. You don't need that. But right now, if you are a
Speaker 10:  cheap hub manufacturer in Shenzhen that's trying to put out a
Speaker 10:  whole bunch of hubs for all of these alphabet
Speaker 10:  soup brands and even some of the brands you know about, you are probably
Speaker 10:  going to be buying that chip from a supplier that wants to supply all of
Speaker 10:  those legacy those, you know, those, those peripherals
Speaker 10:  that people wanna plug in that are a little bit more old school.
Speaker 2:  Okay. So people like Jay, myself, I am almost completely out of u s
Speaker 2:  BBC ports on my Max Studio at this point. We, we just need to like
Speaker 2:  hope that these suppliers start to recognize that there's more of us
Speaker 2:  and we're a market too.
Speaker 10:  I think there's that. I also think laptops will pro and desktops will probably
Speaker 10:  just have more of these ports in the future. What frustrates me to No End
Speaker 10:  is the USS BBC state on Desktop PCs
Speaker 10:  where yeah, you know, if you're getting a desktop you wanna plug a lot of
Speaker 10:  things into it. But the last two motherboards I bought
Speaker 10:  with USS BBC ports on them, they would only have a single port
Speaker 10:  on the back of the machine. And what frustrates the heck outta me is you
Speaker 10:  know how there's like an IO panel, you need to stick into the back of your
Speaker 10:  PC case to like hold all those ports and keep them from like just
Speaker 10:  electrically touching the sides of your case. Those things are generally
Speaker 10:  springy enough that when I stick a U s BBC cable into the back, it just
Speaker 10:  pushes it right back out again. It like bounces right out. It frustrates
Speaker 10:  the heck outta me if you really just do need more u s BBC ports and you
Speaker 10:  don't care about how fast they are. I have seen a bunch of one
Speaker 10:  port to four port USBC hubs on the internet that it is one
Speaker 10:  thing that the chips are being made for. Just know that they can
Speaker 10:  be really slow. Some of them are just five gigabits per second. That's USB
Speaker 10:  3.0 speeds out of your US BBC ports.
Speaker 2:  I hate that. Well, thank you Sean. Jay, I wish the news was
Speaker 2:  better. Sorry.
Speaker 2:  Okay, we're gonna kick it to this next question, which I've got Dan
Speaker 2:  Seifert here to answer. Hello roll the tape. Andrew.
Speaker 9:  Hey Verge cast hotline. My name is Frank from North Carolina.
Speaker 9:  I have two laptops, one work and one personal, and they both use
Speaker 9:  Thunderbolt four. What is a good option
Speaker 9:  to easily switch between the two of them seamlessly without paying for one
Speaker 9:  of those ridiculously expensive KVMs that support
Speaker 9:  Thunderbolt for? Is there a quick and easy solution to this? All right,
Speaker 9:  thanks. Bye.
Speaker 2:  All right, Dan, can you help Frank out?
Speaker 11:  Frank, thank you for this question. I love this question. It is a problem
Speaker 11:  that's near and dear to my heart, so I relate very well to it. I will say,
Speaker 11:  I don't know exactly your setup here, so I'm not sure if you wanna use
Speaker 11:  the both of these laptops with the same monitor, mouse and keyboard or
Speaker 11:  if you just want to be able to switch between inputs on them. So we're gonna
Speaker 11:  explore multiple options for you and hopefully you can find
Speaker 11:  something that works for you. So for starters, you mentioned a Thunderbolt
Speaker 11:  four dock. If there's a Thunderbolt four dock that has a built-in KVM switch
Speaker 11:  into it, I don't know of it. All of those expensive fancy docks that you
Speaker 11:  see on the market with lots of ports and they cost about three to $400 or
Speaker 11:  so. You can't actually switch between inputs on those.
Speaker 11:  You can output to multiple displays, but you really can only connect one
Speaker 11:  computer at a time to them. So that's not really the solution. There is
Speaker 11:  a few hardware options for you. There's a basic KVM
Speaker 11:  switch. KVM stands for keyboard video and mouse. They've been around for
Speaker 11:  eons. The modern ones these days use H D M I inputs
Speaker 11:  and USB ports. And so you would just kind of, if your laptops have
Speaker 11:  just u s BBC on them, you would have to do u s BBC to H D M I and get a
Speaker 11:  converter cable, which is not too hard to do. But basically you plug both
Speaker 11:  laptops into those. You plug your one mouse and your one keyboard into it
Speaker 11:  and you plug your one display into it and then you have a little switch
Speaker 11:  on the switch itself to switch between them. So you use one at a time
Speaker 11:  and you just kind of switch between 'em. So that's a very simple hardware
Speaker 11:  solution for you. There is one silly
Speaker 11:  u s BBC four switch U SB four
Speaker 11:  switch that uses u s BBC ports. It's a thousand dollars dev board.
Speaker 11:  It takes two u s BBC inputs and it outputs to one u s BBC
Speaker 11:  plug and then you can switch between them. That's an option. I'm just saying
Speaker 11:  I'm laying out all the options here. It's not maybe one I'd recommend, but
Speaker 11:  it's an option. And then the last hardware solution for you
Speaker 11:  is a lot of big monitors have the ability
Speaker 11:  to accept multiple inputs, whether that's multiple display
Speaker 11:  inputs from two different computers, or also you can
Speaker 11:  connect your keyboard and mouse directly to the monitor and they have built
Speaker 11:  in KVM switches on them. And so if your screen is big enough,
Speaker 11:  you can split the screen. You usually see this with like the ultra wide
Speaker 11:  screens. And so one side can be your one, your personal laptop. The
Speaker 11:  other side can be your work laptop and there's a KVM switch built into the
Speaker 11:  monitor itself so that you can use the same mouse and keyboard to switch
Speaker 11:  between them. So that's another hardware option for you. But if you already
Speaker 11:  have a display already, you don't wanna buy a new one or anything like that.
Speaker 11:  There are some software options. Yeah, software,
Speaker 11:  yes, software. The first one is Universal control on a Mac. It
Speaker 11:  only works between two Mac and they have to share an iCloud account. I'm
Speaker 11:  gonna guess that you don't have two Macs here. Just most people who have
Speaker 11:  a work laptop and a personal laptop don't have two Macs in the same scenario.
Speaker 11:  Maybe you do, but if you don't or if you, you do also have to have them
Speaker 11:  both on the same iCloud account, which might be precluded by one of them
Speaker 11:  being work option. So, so Universal Control works really cool, but it's
Speaker 11:  probably not a practical option here. Another software option is called
Speaker 11:  Logitech Flow. If you happen to have a modern keyboard or mouse
Speaker 11:  from Logitech, there's an app that you can download on both computers. It
Speaker 11:  works cross Windows and Mac that will let you do the universal
Speaker 11:  control thing. Basically you just move your cursor over to the edge of the
Speaker 11:  screen and it passes it over to the next one and then you click on it and
Speaker 11:  your keyboard will work over on that computer and you can move your mouse
Speaker 11:  back over to the other side. So if you have the right Logitech stuff,
Speaker 11:  you can do that. There's a couple of apps I found that don't require
Speaker 11:  specific hardware. They're called Share Mouse and Synergy and they both
Speaker 11:  appear to do the same kind of thing. I've
Speaker 2:  Used Synergy. Yeah,
Speaker 11:  It's if you have your computer like open and on and plugged
Speaker 11:  into separate displays, you can use the same mouse and keyboard
Speaker 11:  and just move it between them. With these apps installed, share
Speaker 11:  Mouse is about $81. It does have a free trial that you can try out to see
Speaker 11:  if it works. Synergy is a little bit cheaper. It's about $30. I haven't
Speaker 11:  personally used either of them. Alex has used Synergy. Apparently.
Speaker 2:  I've used Synergy. It was, it was years ago. It
Speaker 2:  technically gets the job done. Is it
Speaker 2:  the prettiest? No, but it it, it works.
Speaker 11:  Yeah. I mean it, it'll work if we're trying to do this on a shoestring budget,
Speaker 11:  30 bucks is not bad to spend.
Speaker 2:  It just doesn't ever feel as natural as using like the Monitor
Speaker 2:  solution you you offered or those hardware solutions.
Speaker 11:  Yeah, hardware solutions are probably the way to go. I'm gonna recommend
Speaker 11:  the easiest setup and I'm gonna assume that you got some space on your
Speaker 11:  desk. I think the easiest setup is to use an external display with your
Speaker 11:  main laptop, which would be like probably your work laptop, right? The one
Speaker 11:  that you're, you're spending the most time on. You install one of the apps
Speaker 11:  like Synergy onto both computers so you can share your mouse
Speaker 11:  and your keyboard and then you just leave your personal laptop open on the
Speaker 11:  side of your desk and when you wanna like move over to your personal laptop
Speaker 11:  to send a Discord message or an iMessage or whatever it is you're doing
Speaker 11:  over there, you just move your cursor over, you do it and then you move
Speaker 11:  back to your work one that's on your big display. I think that's probably
Speaker 11:  the most practical, easiest setup, an alternate option for you
Speaker 11:  if you're not wanting to use your work laptop and your personal laptop at
Speaker 11:  the same time. Like this is kind of like you're like, I've got a work laptop
Speaker 11:  that I do work on, but then I've got a gaming laptop that I only play games
Speaker 11:  on. You're probably not like having those active at the same time, but
Speaker 11:  what you do there is then you buy a, either a Thunderbolt or u
Speaker 11:  s BBC doc that's got a lot of ports on it. You plug your display and all
Speaker 11:  your peripherals into it, you plug your mouse, your keyboard, ethernet,
Speaker 11:  whatever, your speakers, everything goes into that dock. And then to switch
Speaker 11:  between the computers, you just unplug one cable outta the one and plug
Speaker 11:  it into the other when it's time to play games or something like that. That's
Speaker 11:  what I personally do. I don't usually use two laptops at the same time.
Speaker 11:  When I'm working, I got my work one setup. If I do wanna play games, I pull
Speaker 11:  out the gaming laptop and I just switch the cable over from the dock. So
Speaker 11:  those are my solutions. I don't think any of them are super elegant.
Speaker 2:  I will say Synergy has gotten prettier than the last time I used
Speaker 2:  it circa like 2013.
Speaker 11:  It, it also looks prettier than share mouse. Share Mouse looks pretty
Speaker 11:  basic.
Speaker 2:  You can sometimes find, I think there might be an open source one
Speaker 2:  as well out there, but most of them tend to be a
Speaker 2:  little buggy and it usually requires you to like run a server
Speaker 2:  essentially.
Speaker 11:  Yeah, you do. The way those work is over basically over ad
Speaker 11:  hoc wifi. So you kind of have to have like a, there's, there is
Speaker 11:  some kind of like internet like communication and
Speaker 2:  You have to install the software on that, that work computer, which
Speaker 2:  depending on how tight you are with your IT department Yeah, could
Speaker 2:  be a problem.
Speaker 11:  Exactly. Yeah there there's definitely lots of caveats here in terms of
Speaker 11:  like what your specific setup is and like what you'll be allowed to do.
Speaker 11:  I don't think your IT department can get in the way of you using a basic
Speaker 11:  hardware KVM switch like that cuz that's just a matter of plugging things
Speaker 11:  in and it's got a hardware switch on it that you just click the button to
Speaker 11:  switch between them. So that might be the most practical solution for you.
Speaker 2:  All right, well Frank, please let us know how the KVM hunt goes.
Speaker 2:  Dan, thank you so much.
Speaker 11:  Good luck and somebody please make a Thunderbolt for KVM doc
Speaker 11:  switch. I will buy it. Somebody do it please.
Speaker 2:  Okay, so our next question is from Mark. Let's give it a listen.
Speaker 12:  Hey Verge Travis Mark, I am in soho in
Speaker 12:  New York City and I see this ad going up by meta. It says set up a new era
Speaker 12:  of personal privacy with automatic end-to-end encryption
Speaker 12:  from WhatsApp. And I just wanna know what's the difference between that
Speaker 12:  end-to-end encryption and all the other ones. Is it real? Am I gonna get
Speaker 12:  screwed? Is it good? Please help. Thanks.
Speaker 2:  Okay, so to answer this question we had to go to somebody who's been writing
Speaker 2:  about a bunch. Mitchell Clark, is WhatsApp real?
Speaker 13:  Yeah, so the T R D R is kind of interesting. End-to-end
Speaker 13:  encryption is actually good and it will almost certainly
Speaker 13:  not screw you over. That's not the same thing as saying that
Speaker 13:  it's immune to surveillance if that's what you're worried about about cuz
Speaker 13:  that's kind of like an entirely different thing. So to go a bit
Speaker 13:  deeper into that, you asked how its encryption is different from the other
Speaker 13:  apps and the, the kind of interesting thing that I've found is that it is
Speaker 13:  not, at least when it comes to Signal, which
Speaker 13:  is kind of like the gold standard for private messaging apps, it uses
Speaker 13:  the literally the same protocol as Signal. So in
Speaker 13:  terms of whether Meta or the government would be able to read your messages,
Speaker 13:  you should be totally fine using WhatsApp. Now the
Speaker 13:  thing that the ad doesn't tell you is that in terms of privacy there
Speaker 13:  are 100% better options out there. That's because WhatsApp can
Speaker 13:  and almost certainly does collect metadata on your conversations.
Speaker 13:  So while it doesn't know what you are saying, it does have a record of who
Speaker 13:  you were talking with when you were talking with them. You know, if y'all
Speaker 13:  exchange pictures or whatever like that stuff, it can tell
Speaker 2:  That seems not great for people who want end to encryption.
Speaker 13:  I'm not saying that it's like lying by a mission, it is
Speaker 13:  technically private, it does have end-to-end encryption for
Speaker 13:  your messages and those contents, but the metadata it can
Speaker 13:  see and it also collects things like your location information, device
Speaker 13:  information, stuff like that. And that data is super
Speaker 13:  valuable. Governments can and have asked Meta to hand it over before.
Speaker 13:  And so if you are the type of person who's concerned
Speaker 13:  about data collection and overall privacy, then that's
Speaker 13:  something you really wanna consider. Not just with WhatsApp but with a bunch
Speaker 13:  of different apps that say that they support end-to-end encryption because
Speaker 13:  they can, but there's more to that story. So iMessage in
Speaker 13:  ocs, it's kind of the same deal with those. The one app that doesn't do
Speaker 13:  that is Signal. So there's a feature in it that
Speaker 13:  makes it so that even the company running the app can't tell who you're
Speaker 13:  messaging, which is pretty solid. So like in terms of real word
Speaker 13:  stuff, meta can read what's on the outside of your envelope that
Speaker 13:  you're mailing to someone, your, your thank you cards for Christmas
Speaker 13:  presents, which you should be sending right now. Meta can read the address,
Speaker 13:  your address, who, who you're sending it to. And so can a bunch of other
Speaker 13:  people who make end-to-end encrypted messaging apps Signal cannot.
Speaker 13:  Okay. Neither of them can see what's in that envelope, but there's a difference
Speaker 13:  between how much data they are collecting.
Speaker 2:  So like WhatsApp, iMessage, that's gonna make sense for people
Speaker 2:  who are talking with their family and friends and maybe just don't want the
Speaker 2:  world to know what all salacious things they get up to in their chats.
Speaker 2:  And then Signal is like, no, I don't want you to know anything.
Speaker 13:  Right. If you are, I don't, I was gonna
Speaker 13:  try to come up with an example. I don't want the FBI to burst into my house,
Speaker 13:  so I'm I'm I'm gonna, I'm gonna leave it very vague, but like the, the
Speaker 13:  one rub of this is that if you have friends and family using a messaging
Speaker 13:  app that's probably WhatsApp, like the network effect with these
Speaker 13:  messaging apps is really, really strong. So you're not,
Speaker 13:  even if you did want to, you know, convince your mom to use Signal,
Speaker 13:  you're probably not gonna have a whole lot of luck with that. It's usually
Speaker 13:  a losing battle trying to get people to adopt new messaging apps. So
Speaker 13:  if, if you are wondering, I have people wanting me to use WhatsApp,
Speaker 13:  does it have this bare minimum level of safety? The answer is yes
Speaker 13:  and it should be totally fine if you're not trying
Speaker 13:  to blow the whistle on illegal government actions
Speaker 13:  or corporate espionage, like for that maybe, maybe choose something
Speaker 13:  different.
Speaker 2:  I love that. All right, thank you Mitchell. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Okay, here's the final question for today.
Speaker 14:  So number one, David Pierce, you know my friend, you didn't invite me to
Speaker 14:  your Christmas party, so let's get through that. Wait, am I supposed to
Speaker 14:  say my name? Alright. Anyways, but number two voice assistants,
Speaker 14:  like what's going on with voice assistants? It seems like nobody's
Speaker 14:  doing anything interesting with them anymore. Is it because they can't be
Speaker 14:  monetized? Can you please fix theory please.
Speaker 2:  All right, well David is not here to invite you to use Christmas party
Speaker 2:  or answer the question, but I've got Jen Tui here.
Speaker 15:  Hi.
Speaker 2:  Hi Jen. Like what's going on is, are things
Speaker 2:  happening in voice assistant land?
Speaker 15:  Well, it's an interesting question there, multi-part, honestly.
Speaker 15:  You know, I think voice assistants are really quite good right now.
Speaker 15:  I think we've kind of come to expect a lot from them because our other personal
Speaker 15:  devices are so, you know, intuitive and responsive to us. But
Speaker 15:  voice assistants, especially in the smart home, kind of have a harder job
Speaker 15:  than say like your smartphone or your computer where, you know, we've become
Speaker 15:  used to such easy interaction because voice assistants
Speaker 15:  generally lack the context that say a smartphone does. And the
Speaker 15:  attempts that companies have made to sort of personalize the various voice
Speaker 15:  assistants who, NA, whose names, I'll try not to say too many times. So
Speaker 15:  not to activate everyone's devices, but those attempts to sort of
Speaker 15:  personalize them have been, have, haven't worked that well, especially in
Speaker 15:  multi people households. So you may say something
Speaker 15:  to your voice assistant, like, you know, play my playlist and it, it doesn't
Speaker 15:  know who you are. Yeah. And so those things, that's been a bit tricky.
Speaker 15:  Each company has tried to address that, but more often than not it
Speaker 15:  ends up just being frustrating for the user. And generally I would say
Speaker 15:  of the three main voice assistants, each kind of has its pluses
Speaker 15:  and minuses. You know, like Amazon's has a very wide
Speaker 15:  range of capabilities, but that can get hard
Speaker 15:  because it's not specific enough. You know, you might, I've had
Speaker 15:  examples where I've asked the assistant to, you know, turn on a light
Speaker 15:  switch or do some smart home thing and it'll end up sort of
Speaker 15:  telling me the latest news headlines because it, it gets confused.
Speaker 15:  So you know that and that's frustrating and because we're so used to things,
Speaker 15:  you know, technology has become so advanced. We're used to things doing
Speaker 15:  exactly what we expect and voice assistants are la have lagged behind
Speaker 15:  there. You know, like Google is really good for general knowledge, you
Speaker 15:  know, things like directions, traffic, weather. And then
Speaker 15:  Apple's assistant is so well integrated into the Apple ecosystem,
Speaker 15:  you know, they've just launched some new capabilities like with the HomePod
Speaker 15:  that we just wrote about this week. You know, you can ask your HomePod
Speaker 15:  mini to find your husband if he's gone missing. So it will,
Speaker 15:  you know, like find my on your iPhone now instead of having to pull out
Speaker 15:  the iPhone you can just say, Hey s where's my husband?
Speaker 15:  And it will give you direct, you know, give you even directions to go
Speaker 15:  find him. Oh wow. And you know, they are adding new features but in general
Speaker 15:  the problem is no one voice assistant does all of these
Speaker 15:  things. Well, you know? Yeah. You kind of have to pick or choose and, and
Speaker 15:  this, the caller did say specifically, please fix Siri.
Speaker 15:  And that's a leading question. You know, I'd love to know what specifically
Speaker 15:  he, his problem is with Siri personally, as I've written about,
Speaker 15:  I do find Siri to sort of actually be one of the better voice assistants
Speaker 15:  for smart home control. But anything else or largely anything. Anything
Speaker 15:  else. And it does kind of spin its wheels a lot and I think a lot of them
Speaker 15:  have this problem where you are waiting on them to do what you've asked
Speaker 15:  because they're often relying on a cloud connection and
Speaker 15:  that, you know, gets frustrating for you sitting there waiting for it to
Speaker 15:  turn the lights on or off or read you the news headlines
Speaker 15:  because you know, one of the issues is in the smart
Speaker 15:  home is if you rely too much on the cloud, the voice assistant has to
Speaker 15:  send the command and then the get the data and bring it back and then do
Speaker 15:  its thing. And you know, in my mind I think voice control works
Speaker 15:  best when it's local, when the connection, everything it it's
Speaker 15:  working on is local. And that's also sometimes where you'll find using the
Speaker 15:  voice assistant on a phone, the ones that work well on a phone
Speaker 15:  is quicker than using it with smart home speakers. And this is
Speaker 15:  actually something and you know, you can't have me on the ver without me
Speaker 15:  mentioning the word matter.
Speaker 15:  It's, this is something for the smart home I think Matter may actually
Speaker 15:  help with because it will help bring all our
Speaker 15:  control of smart home devices locally. Devices will be able to
Speaker 15:  talk directly to each other rather than having to go to the cloud and talk
Speaker 15:  directly to voice assistance. So, you know, that may be an area
Speaker 15:  we're gonna see some improvement. It's gonna take a while though. I think
Speaker 15:  voice assistance often get the blame because they're the control point.
Speaker 15:  Like you get mad at your smartphone when you know a website's not working
Speaker 15:  or an app's not working when in fact it's quite likely that
Speaker 15:  it's like a device network issue or some connectivity
Speaker 15:  that's sort of broken in the background and it's not actually their fault,
Speaker 15:  but that's why you get shoot the messenger.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I used s and S sometimes doesn't wanna connect
Speaker 2:  to the internet and it's unclear why and it just likes to return. I can't
Speaker 2:  do that right now. And I'm like, but you can. I know you can
Speaker 15:  And you just did it like 20 minutes ago, why can't you do it now?
Speaker 2:  Now? And it's so frustrating and I know intellectually something's
Speaker 2:  going on here, I need to troubleshoot the wifi, but no, I'm still mad
Speaker 2:  at this little tiny speaker in my kitchen and I want to throw it against
Speaker 2:  out the window.
Speaker 2:  Do you think we're gonna see more use of
Speaker 2:  these conversational ais that we've seen like chat G B T, do you think those
Speaker 2:  are gonna become more involved in these voice assistants or are they gonna
Speaker 2:  continue to be this place where we ask very specific kind of
Speaker 2:  robotic questions to them and they give us those very kit tined
Speaker 2:  answers?
Speaker 15:  Yeah, and so that's another area I think people get frustrated is you
Speaker 15:  have to use for the most part very specific nomenclature. And you know,
Speaker 15:  if you just vary it instead of saying like every day you say every
Speaker 15:  night and it doesn't know what you're talking about, it is tricky. It's
Speaker 15:  also makes it hard for people in your home who aren't used to using voice
Speaker 15:  assistants to control things because they may say, you know, turn on the
Speaker 15:  lamp instead of turn on the light and the the voice assistant doesn't
Speaker 15:  know the answer. And these kind of new innovations around
Speaker 15:  AI is very interesting and I, you know, we had a great piece on
Speaker 15:  the, on the site this week sort of looking, I think someone ki created
Speaker 15:  a really cool voice assistant. Yeah. Using yes.
Speaker 15:  And that was that, that was amazing. And it looked and it was like, yeah
Speaker 15:  this could be the sort of sort of nirvana for voice assistants. But I think
Speaker 15:  people rightly pointed out, when you don't have a tightly
Speaker 15:  controlled ecosystem for a voice assistant, it could get messy and scary
Speaker 15:  very quickly. Especially like, you know, I
Speaker 15:  I, I posted this question on, on Twitter a little while ago, like what is
Speaker 15:  it that annoys you most about your voice assistant? And an old colleague
Speaker 15:  of mine said, well when it plays non toddler friendly versions of old
Speaker 15:  and it's like, you know, you don't, there are times when you want control,
Speaker 15:  you just don't want the whole world wide world of artificial intelligence
Speaker 15:  streaming through your smart speaker and into the ears of your, through
Speaker 15:  your old toddler. So you know, we kind of need this
Speaker 15:  control mechanism and you know, we need these companies to sort of be able
Speaker 15:  to provide the exact information we want and not go off onto weird
Speaker 15:  tangents. But you know, it's a hard problem to solve. I'm not an
Speaker 15:  AI expert but I'm sure our colleague James Vincent would be able to, would
Speaker 15:  agree with me that, you know, this type of natural
Speaker 15:  language processing, this type of, you know, being able to adapt to the
Speaker 15:  way we speak to a voice assistant, nailing that down and getting that right
Speaker 15:  is incredibly hard. You know, the simplest things in life are
Speaker 15:  a lot harder to do in technology than it than you would think on the
Speaker 15:  monetization front, which is the other part of his question. You know, there's
Speaker 15:  one of the three that's sort of the prime target here. Amazon's
Speaker 15:  assistant is constantly trying to sell us things. Yes,
Speaker 15:  it's a tricky world. I don't, when you think about what we are getting
Speaker 15:  from a voice assistant, it is kind of surprising that we're not having to
Speaker 15:  pay for it. I mean the functionality that you are getting, you know, it's
Speaker 15:  like, you know, the older dash, I dunno if it's old, but in the tech world,
Speaker 15:  you know, if you are not paying for it then you are the product. So
Speaker 15:  that's something with Siri and Google assistant,
Speaker 15:  you know, it's a feature of their hardware so it's a feature of the smartphone
Speaker 15:  or the smart speaker and those companies are monetizing in
Speaker 15:  different ways. But with Amazon's, you know, their main monetization
Speaker 15:  strategy is byproducts from us. So we are gonna see more of
Speaker 15:  that. I'm very sure in the future with the voice assistant in
Speaker 15:  your home. So just be aware when you're picking which one, which one you
Speaker 15:  wanna bring into your home, that that one is the one that's most likely
Speaker 15:  to see more monetization in the future, which already does. So
Speaker 15:  start
Speaker 2:  Trying to sell you stuff. Yep. Well that's one of the reasons I went with
Speaker 2:  Siri honestly is, is is I knew there was a little bit more mindfulness
Speaker 2:  of privacy and unlikely for me to be
Speaker 2:  monetized in my data to necessarily be monetized. Yeah. Or at least in ways
Speaker 2:  that are very visible to me.
Speaker 15:  And then on the flip side though, Siri doesn't do as much as
Speaker 15:  Amazon's or Google's does and that's why Yeah because it doesn't know
Speaker 15:  as much about you because you've chosen that for that reason. So you know,
Speaker 15:  as I said the beginning, the three do things very differently and in different
Speaker 15:  ways and in a way that's good cuz you can choose which one and the
Speaker 15:  ultimate, you know, in the ideal world will all it, there'll be one that
Speaker 15:  can do it all. And you know, it was interesting that ces this year
Speaker 15:  Amazon was showing off some integrations using its voice
Speaker 15:  assistant in different places. So it's now you can
Speaker 15:  actually get, or you will be able to have both Amazon's assistant and Apple's
Speaker 15:  as assistant in vehicle infotainment system.
Speaker 15:  So you can choose which one you talk to. And then they also partnered
Speaker 15:  with Josh ai, which is a really interesting,
Speaker 15:  entirely local based home voice control system. Oh cool.
Speaker 15:  So that's kind of an interesting partnership because you're getting the
Speaker 15:  local control but then when you want to, you can, you know, reach out to
Speaker 15:  the cloud and you know, get the latest Buffalo Bills sports score or whatever
Speaker 15:  it is that you want, but
Speaker 2:  It runs like natively on your, your home hardware. You don't have
Speaker 2:  to,
Speaker 15:  That's what they were saying. Yeah. So Josh AI has its own little
Speaker 15:  speakers that you kind of can put around your home. And to be clear, Josh
Speaker 15:  AI is, is a very high end, quite an expensive Okay.
Speaker 15:  System that you would add to a high end. I
Speaker 2:  Got all excited.
Speaker 15:  It may become a little more accessible at some point, but yeah, it, so they
Speaker 15:  have these, I think they're called nano microphones and you can just kind
Speaker 15:  of put them around your home from my understanding was, and I, this
Speaker 15:  isn't out yet, but this is, they were announcing the partnership, my understanding
Speaker 15:  is that there will be integration. So you can ask the same device
Speaker 15:  for either Josh AI or Amazon's assistant and depending on
Speaker 15:  what you want to, what kind of information you want or what actions you
Speaker 15:  want to take. So there's, there are developments and movements in voice
Speaker 15:  assistance and I think they'll continue to grow and get more
Speaker 15:  useful, but probably also still be something you want to yell at every now
Speaker 15:  and then.
Speaker 15:  And I have been told by engineers at Amazon that they do pay attention
Speaker 15:  when you swear at it.
Speaker 2:  Oh no, that's very bad for
Speaker 15:  Me. It's registered as a negative customer feedback.
Speaker 2:  Oh boy. Well I am gonna have to go apologize
Speaker 2:  to all my voice assistants now, so thank you
Speaker 2:  Jen. I appreciate you coming on. You're
Speaker 15:  Welcome.
Speaker 2:  And that's it for the vercast today. Thank you for listening. As
Speaker 2:  always. There's a ton more coverage on everything we talked about@theverge.com.
Speaker 2:  If you have thoughts, feedback, feelings, book recommendations, you can always
Speaker 2:  email the vergecast vergecast the verge.com and of
Speaker 2:  course if you have questions, please call the hotline. It's eight sixty six
Speaker 2:  Verge 11. Again, that's 8 66 Verge 11.
Speaker 2:  The show is produced by Andrew Marino and Liam James Nori Donovan is our
Speaker 2:  executive producer and Brooke Mentors is our editorial director of audio.
Speaker 2:  The VER is the Verge production and part of the Vox Media podcast network
Speaker 2:  will be back on Friday to chat with more of the Verge crew about whatever
Speaker 2:  is happening this week. So see you then.