# Transcript
ID: 4b867266-ce54-486c-92c3-7469d16a53fa
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Meta and Reddit prove the social web is over
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-8091924036318599526/3940564298388151329/s93290-US-5330s-1694808088.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, Alex Cranz, and David Pierce discuss the vibe shift that is happening on social media and the communal internet.
Speaker 2:  Support for this show comes from a w s. Innovations in
Speaker 2:  machine learning and AI have completely changed the game. But
Speaker 2:  as with any cutting edge technology, it's important to stay ahead of the
Speaker 2:  curve or you risk getting left behind. Amazon Web Services
Speaker 2:  can help your small business stay ahead of the competition. A W
Speaker 2:  Ss provides a framework for businesses to navigate the fast changing landscape
Speaker 2:  and helps businesses harness the emerging capabilities of AI and
Speaker 2:  machine learning. It's time to imagine how a w s can
Speaker 2:  transform your business. Go to a SS is how.com
Speaker 2:  to learn more.
Speaker 3:  Support for this show comes from American, Express Business If. you are
Speaker 3:  a small business owner. you wanna partner with someone that can help make
Speaker 3:  your day to day a rewarding experience. That's where American Express can
Speaker 3:  come in. American Express business cards are built for your
Speaker 3:  business with features and benefits like the ability to earn membership rewards,
Speaker 3:  points on select cards, the power to pay for big business purchases.
Speaker 3:  And 24 7 support from a business specialist built for
Speaker 3:  your business. Amex business terms apply. learn more
Speaker 3:  at American Express dot com slash business cards.
Speaker 4:  Hello and Welcome to The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of Mark
Speaker 4:  Zuckerberg and Elon Musk fighting in a cage.
Speaker 5:  The exclusive team covering it.
Speaker 4:  Alex Heath broke this story. Yeah, that's fine. I'm proud of him. He's
Speaker 4:  a great reporter. Not
Speaker 6:  Only did Alex Heath break this story, I think Alex Heath like wielded into
Speaker 6:  existence.
Speaker 4:  That's the problem really, is that Alex is
Speaker 4:  goading it into reality. And that's and that's fine. And it, it appear, we
Speaker 4:  can talk about it. It appears Mark Zuckerberg really wants to do this. He
Speaker 4:  should and I feel that we should be very proud of ourselves as The
Speaker 4:  Verge as the journalistic institution that we have become. And
Speaker 4:  also deeply extremely ashamed that this is
Speaker 4:  happening on our watch.
Speaker 6:  That feels right.
Speaker 4:  Here's this story. I'm your friend Neli Alex. Cranz is here.
Speaker 5:  I'm your friend who could take Musk in a fight but probably couldn't take
Speaker 5:  Zuck in a fight.
Speaker 4:  I'm gonna let that sit. David Pierce is here.
Speaker 6:  Hi. I have already called Dibs Own being the sideline reporter who interviews
Speaker 6:  the fighters between rounds. It's gonna be unbelievable. We
Speaker 4:  Run a gigantic sports website, ESP Nation's right there. They have a giant
Speaker 4:  combat sports operation. Ariel Ani is a part of the Vox Media.
Speaker 4:  Fa Wait, we we can do it. No,
Speaker 5:  We're gonna do it. This
Speaker 6:  Is the corporate synergy we've been waiting for.
Speaker 4:  It's DraftKings Nation. The ESP Nation
Speaker 4:  partnership with DraftKings is already like running odds on this fight. It's
Speaker 4:  a lot. There's a lot going on here. Here's what I will tell. We have nothing
Speaker 4:  to do with it by the way. They're just like doing their thing. It's just
Speaker 4:  very funny. Here's the story as we know it today,
Speaker 4:  Instagram is going to launch some competitor to Twitter.
Speaker 4:  It's called Threads. We've seen screenshots of it from presentations that
Speaker 4:  were given inside of Meta. Their position, and this is what they said at
Speaker 4:  the all hands that Alex Heath reported on was people want to competitor to
Speaker 4:  Twitter. That is Sanely run. That's what they said. The
Speaker 4:  audience of Meta employees like clap to this. Which is also very funny given
Speaker 4:  that Meta does not have like a sparkling content moderation
Speaker 4:  track record, but whatever Meta is the company that like
Speaker 4:  set up the fake supreme court of content moderation. They're doing it a different
Speaker 4:  way. Elon is, I would say not
Speaker 4:  doing it that way. He's running Twitter in a different way.
Speaker 4:  That's
Speaker 5:  That. That feels correct.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I would say interest.
Speaker 5:  That's a very political way to say it. I like that. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  One is a train and the other one is like an out of control haunted
Speaker 4:  car from a horror movie. There are different ways
Speaker 4:  of running a business. You know. Yeah. Every now and again someone on decoder
Speaker 4:  is like, I don't know how I make decisions. I get drunk and flip coins until
Speaker 4:  I fall down. And that's one way to run a business. Okay, fine.
Speaker 4:  So now Elon has been like tweeting about Zuck, like taunts
Speaker 4:  about this Instagram competitor, this Instagram editor we're gonna talk about
Speaker 4:  in much more detail in just a second because it is causing a lot of drama
Speaker 4:  on the sort of federated social networks of the internet. However,
Speaker 4:  someone goaded Elon into tweeting, he would like to cage fight
Speaker 4:  Zuck. Wait,
Speaker 6:  Can I just, can I just interrupt real fast? Yeah. Not only someone, I'm just,
Speaker 6:  I'm looking at this tweet thread right now and it is like the most beautifully
Speaker 6:  Twitter thing of all time. So Mario Nal I think is how you
Speaker 6:  pronounce it. Tweets, it has lots of followers is like a thing. Elon Musk
Speaker 6:  would potentially have seen. Elon responds to a tweet about
Speaker 6:  Instagram threads being a thing. He responds, I'm sure Earth can't wait to
Speaker 6:  be exclusively under zucks thumb with no other options. At least it will
Speaker 6:  be sane. Was worried there for a moment. Laugh, crying emoji. And then
Speaker 6:  a person on Twitter who has 68 followers.
Speaker 4:  68 and a blue check one assumes and a blue check. No blue
Speaker 6:  Check's
Speaker 4:  Blue check.
Speaker 6:  This is very surprising. Elon Musk checkin his unverified replies. That's
Speaker 5:  Love that for us. Whose
Speaker 6:  Username is KW Markoff? 2, 6, 6 5 6. And whose
Speaker 6:  username is kw markoff@aol.com. It's very good.
Speaker 6:  Yes. Responds better be careful at Elon Musk. I heard he does the
Speaker 6:  juujitsu now and then nine different laughing
Speaker 6:  emojis. And then to that Elon Musk responds, I'm
Speaker 6:  up for a cage match if he is l o l. Right. And that's how this all began.
Speaker 4:  68 followers, haunted car. That's all I'm
Speaker 4:  saying.
Speaker 5:  A legend
Speaker 4:  Zuck responds to this by screenshotting Elon's tweet. There's
Speaker 4:  apparently a, this is a reference to some famous m m a fighter and he just
Speaker 4:  puts block text over it that says Send me location. You would
Speaker 4:  think that this story has now reached its cringes point.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. That's like the cringe level there is
Speaker 4:  And, and here's where our friend Alex pours gasoline on the fire. He reaches
Speaker 4:  out to Meta and says, is this real? Does he actually wanna fight
Speaker 4:  Musk? Which is I would say just a very funny
Speaker 4:  thing for a reporter to ask, does your billionaire c e o
Speaker 4:  wish to fight the other billionaire c e o for real? Or is he just
Speaker 4:  taunting him with references to fighting like in the
Speaker 4:  annals of journalism? That's chapter one. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And there's like, for most people we assume it's just a taunt because
Speaker 5:  they're very rich, very pasty billionaires.
Speaker 4:  But it is true that Mark Zuckerberg has been training in, he has martial
Speaker 4:  arts, he did like a fight with Rogan and he had made a video of himself
Speaker 4:  training. This is like a whole thing he did. He has competed in tournaments.
Speaker 4:  So Meta PR is like, it speaks for himself. He wants to fight him. And now
Speaker 4:  everything we have heard is that Zuck is actually serious about this. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  That he's pushing for luminaries of the fight world to somehow get involved.
Speaker 4:  Jake Paul is like, I wanna run it on ESPN Plus, which is
Speaker 4:  just very funny. She's
Speaker 5:  Like a fighter too now.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. There's no money being an influencer as we, we will talk about the
Speaker 4:  den truck interview later, but like you can be a famous influencer and then
Speaker 4:  your immediate move is to find something that will make you money. And
Speaker 6:  And the and the next turn of that is social media CEOs pivoting to combat
Speaker 6:  sports.
Speaker 4:  Right. It's like, it's the same thing. It's like there's not a lot of money
Speaker 4:  in social media. Get that paper review money, you pivot to fighting,
Speaker 4:  you need to collect some actual dollars. Yeah. Anyway, it has,
Speaker 4:  this story has gone from funny Alex Heath joke on the website
Speaker 4:  to what I would describe is an inescapable
Speaker 4:  and exhausting worldwide phenomenon. We are like, people are taking action
Speaker 4:  on this fight that hasn't happened and should not happen.
Speaker 5:  Do you guys remember in 2006 there was this director
Speaker 5:  named Uey Bowl who was known for doing like horrible garbage video
Speaker 5:  game, adapt adaptions and critics hated him and he was like, I'm
Speaker 5:  going to fight my critics. And so he invited them all
Speaker 5:  to fight, including like low tax the founder of something awful.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And proceeded to beat every single one of them.
Speaker 5:  Like destroy them. It was the saddest thing in the world. I knew one of the
Speaker 5:  guys and he's like, yeah, I'm gonna fight him. And you're like, oh. And that's
Speaker 5:  kind of, I'm kind of worried for Elon for that very reason
Speaker 5:  'cause these guys are all like, well whatever he is a film director, I can
Speaker 5:  fight him. And like no, he's like, he's like Zuck. He's like getting a little
Speaker 5:  Was J Jacked was like ready?
Speaker 4:  Well put the link to Zuck fighting a guy in the show notes. There's a YouTube
Speaker 4:  video. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I don't think it's gonna be, it's gonna be an interesting fight.
Speaker 4:  I want to make it very clear, my position is that these
Speaker 4:  men should not fight each other. That's fair. I fair. Don't think
Speaker 4:  that would be good for the world.
Speaker 5:  No. It would be like the most excruciating thing to
Speaker 5:  watch and just, I think I'd feel like
Speaker 5:  we'd reached the point where we just Yeah. Shut
Speaker 4:  It down. When I say that as my position nominally,
Speaker 4:  that would be the editorial position of The Verge. But I suspect
Speaker 4:  very strongly that in a sort of mutiny type
Speaker 4:  situation, the editorial position of The Verge as composed
Speaker 4:  by its staff is let them fight. Yeah. and I'm a little worried
Speaker 4:  about that, but we're just gonna let it happen.
Speaker 5:  Let them fight. The
Speaker 6:  Only thing I can say with absolute certainty is that there has already been
Speaker 6:  a meeting at the WWE e about how to get Elon Musk and Mark Zuckerberg
Speaker 6:  into a ring together. Yeah. And if it hasn't, please invite me to that meeting.
Speaker 4:  The last thing I'll say about this and Then, we should actually talk about
Speaker 4:  the, the real drama with Instagram threads. The last thing I'll say is
Speaker 4:  Elon is the WWE E and Zuck is the U F C. And those things are not
Speaker 4:  necessarily compatible, right? Like that's actually the
Speaker 4:  split here. Yeah. Is Elon I think would definitely do the WWE thing. I
Speaker 4:  think Zuck wants to actually punch him in the face.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, that's fair.
Speaker 5:  That feels right.
Speaker 4:  All right, let's talk about the actual, we'll see, I'm sorry.
Speaker 4:  I dunno. We
Speaker 5:  Do not condone violence.
Speaker 4:  How do you explain like an apologetic curiosity?
Speaker 5:  I think that's right. Like you're just like You know What if that flits across
Speaker 5:  my eyeballs on a TikTok? That's, I'll wait
Speaker 5:  a second before I swipe up. What's
Speaker 4:  Pre guilt? That's the, that's the word I'm looking for. Type find
Speaker 4:  your chat GPTs and be like what's the word for pre guilt? Send it to me.
Speaker 4:  Okay. We should talk about the real drama with Instagram threads, which
Speaker 4:  I think is like drama. The Verge is designed
Speaker 4:  to cover. So if you like me think that we're reaching
Speaker 4:  a moment for the social web, it appear, it appears to be
Speaker 4:  tearing itself apart. It just is like we're gonna talk about Reddit in the
Speaker 4:  next section. Reddit has come to one sort of conclusion. Twitter has come
Speaker 4:  to a very different sort of conclusion. Facebook isn't sending anybody traffic
Speaker 4:  anymore. Like that thing the web of the sort of mid
Speaker 4:  2010s is like run its course good.
Speaker 4:  Yep. Sure. No one's getting any like animal traffic anymore.
Speaker 4:  You know. Like it's not, it's not if we're not doing it, no
Speaker 5:  Cute pet traffic.
Speaker 4:  Right? And then you see what's happening in the media like Buzzfeed news
Speaker 4:  is shut down and Buzzfeed is pivoting towards like that web, that particular
Speaker 4:  web is coming to a close. Something else is gonna happen. We have
Speaker 4:  talked on The Vergecast and on The Verge a lot about ActivityPub, about Blue
Speaker 4:  Sky, about these federated social networks. And now the first
Speaker 4:  big entrant is it seems Imminent Instagram threads,
Speaker 4:  which we think is compatible with ActivityPub or
Speaker 4:  evidence for this is some good reporting and a little bit of a mention on
Speaker 4:  one slide, but they haven't like launched it. We don't know
Speaker 4:  the existing Federated social network Mastodon and The Fediverse
Speaker 4:  at large, which are run on ActivityPub. I would say David are reacting
Speaker 4:  to this very poorly.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I think that's right. So one of the weird quirks
Speaker 6:  of The Fediverse and Mastodon in particular is that it is
Speaker 6:  very proud of itself and sort of insular. It is not
Speaker 6:  famous for being an open group of people excited to welcome
Speaker 6:  new people in from wherever they're coming. There are norms, we've talked
Speaker 6:  about this on the show, there are norms like everybody calls it the bird
Speaker 6:  site and not Twitter. And if you call it Twitter on Mastodon, you're like
Speaker 6:  shamed for it. It's just a strange place with a very sort of specific set
Speaker 6:  of like in crowdy rules. And the assumption is,
Speaker 6:  and I think correctly. So that if and when Instagram launches
Speaker 6:  threads, this competitor, the code name we've heard is Project
Speaker 6:  92. That it will instantly be by far the biggest thing on The Fediverse,
Speaker 6:  right? Like it, it stands to reason. Instagram is enormous. You'll be able
Speaker 6:  to take your Instagram handle and turn it into your Fediverse handle
Speaker 6:  in this app that will be compatible with ActivityPub. So in
Speaker 6:  that moment, the The Fediverse, this open social web that's
Speaker 6:  powered by ActivityPub goes from a lot of little pieces
Speaker 6:  with Mastodon being kind of the largest little piece to Instagram
Speaker 6:  and then everybody else. And there are a lot of people who
Speaker 6:  on principle do not want Meta to be part of this thing. There's, there is
Speaker 6:  just a, a belief among some people that this would be a bad
Speaker 6:  thing. Meta is a bad company run by bad people who will do bad things for
Speaker 6:  The Fediverse. They will destroy the open standards. They will ruin everything
Speaker 6:  and they are fighting absolute tooth and nail
Speaker 6:  to convince everyone to not even basically allow Meta
Speaker 6:  into this world.
Speaker 5:  I like what's the point of
Speaker 5:  having something be open source and then actively reject
Speaker 5:  when you have new participants.
Speaker 6:  So technically me Meta can do this without asking permission.
Speaker 6:  Right? Right. Like it, it can build a thing on ActivityPub. Terrific. But
Speaker 6:  what is true is if you run, and this is part of the beauty of these systems
Speaker 6:  actually like when it works, what this allows admins to do is say okay,
Speaker 6:  my version of my sort of little corner of The Fediverse is
Speaker 6:  compatible with lots of things, but I get to choose the folks who can't even
Speaker 6:  come into the room, right? Like we're all using the same standard, but I'm
Speaker 6:  not gonna allow these people over here to be part of my club because
Speaker 6:  You know whatever they suck, they're Nazis, they're mean teenage boys.
Speaker 6:  They send nudes whatever. I just don't want them to be part of it. So you
Speaker 6:  have these tools by which everybody is sort of on the same playing field,
Speaker 6:  but you get to like have your own space if that's a thing that you want.
Speaker 6:  And by and large, I think that's a good thing, right? And as this has been
Speaker 6:  small, it has basically been like, okay, if you're gonna be a good actor
Speaker 6:  operating in good faith, we're all gonna be open to each other. And
Speaker 6:  what is now happening is that the largest player by far is
Speaker 6:  perceived by some of these people to not be a good actor acting in good faith.
Speaker 6:  And so what's gonna happen if this boils up into anything and we should talk
Speaker 6:  about whether it's going to, because I'm suspicious that this is actually
Speaker 6:  anything, it's just gonna divide, right? Like there's gonna be two different
Speaker 6:  things powered by the same thing. And it would be like Gmail users not being
Speaker 6:  able to email Outlook users and that's, that's where this would land if Meta
Speaker 6:  and the rest of The Fediverse like really part ways from each other. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  So I think two
Speaker 4:  Things of note here. One, lots of good reasons
Speaker 4:  to not trust Meta
Speaker 5:  A hundred percent.
Speaker 4:  About half of which are directly related to Meta itself
Speaker 4:  and it's actions and it's advertising practices and it's content moderation
Speaker 4:  standards and it's general platforming of unsavory care, the whole thing.
Speaker 4:  So that's about half of the reasons to not trust Meta
Speaker 4:  Meta itself. The other half of the reasons are like the history of
Speaker 4:  this thing happening before Microsoft shows up to
Speaker 4:  the web with Internet Explorer and they're like, we love H T T P.
Speaker 4:  Have you heard of ActiveX? And they just foist a
Speaker 4:  version of the web on top of the web. They had a name for this. It was
Speaker 4:  embrace, extend extinguish. They would embrace the standard, they would extend
Speaker 4:  it with proprietary extensions and they would extinguish the standard and
Speaker 4:  they would be in charge of everything. Famously this got them into so much
Speaker 4:  trouble with the web that the government sued them, almost broke them up,
Speaker 4:  entered into a massive consent decree that created the
Speaker 4:  internet as we know it because Microsoft was distracted from mobile. They
Speaker 4:  had to let Google show up. This whole thing happened. I would note right
Speaker 4:  now, and we will not talk about a lot in this episode, but as we speak,
Speaker 4:  Microsoft is in trial with the F C C about buying Activision
Speaker 4:  and Addie and Tom are covering that in real time. Like while we're taping.
Speaker 4:  So we'll, we'll get to some headlines later from the trial, but we'll cover
Speaker 4:  it in depth on Wednesday. Show Anyhow, embrace
Speaker 4:  Extend Extinguish is real. Microsoft did it to the internet as a whole.
Speaker 4:  Google in many ways has done it to the web. Like big players
Speaker 4:  show up to open communities, they establish themselves as big players and
Speaker 4:  then they take over.
Speaker 6:  My favorite example of this that I think a lot of people remember is messaging
Speaker 6:  services. Remember a million years ago when all the messaging services ran
Speaker 6:  on like similar protocols and you could have an app like Jabber that pulled
Speaker 6:  your SSM Messenger and your Yahoo Messenger and your
Speaker 6:  Google messaging all into one app and everything was sort of cross compatible.
Speaker 6:  And then Google just said, nevermind, Gchat doesn't run on any of that stuff
Speaker 6:  anymore. And it all just instantly broke. That is embrace, extend, extinguish
Speaker 6:  like Yeah. Yeah. That's the job.
Speaker 4:  Very hilariously about that. Speaking of the government, my favorite topic,
Speaker 4:  government regulation of the internet. When a O l bought
Speaker 4:  Time Warner, this is a true thing that happened when, when a O L bought Time
Speaker 4:  Warner, the first time Time Warner killed its host company, which never
Speaker 4:  fails. The government demanded the Bush administration demanded that a
Speaker 4:  o l make a o l instant messenger interoperable because
Speaker 4:  they perceived it at that time, at that time, back in those days
Speaker 4:  to be a moat. So if a L owned the content and a o l owned the sticky
Speaker 4:  messaging service, no no one would switch. Yeah. The Bush
Speaker 4:  administration.
Speaker 5:  Well and it's like speaking of a o l when they first went into
Speaker 5:  Usenet too, right? Yeah. Usenet was was
Speaker 5:  this big community, a lot of nerds. It was the early internet
Speaker 5:  adopters. They were all loving it. A o l started to provide support for
Speaker 5:  Usenet. So like little 13 year old me could be like, yeah, I'm gonna go go
Speaker 5:  have fun.
Speaker 4:  Do You know about the, the story of eternal September? I
Speaker 5:  I kind of know it. I I briefly he lived it but on like I was the trash
Speaker 5:  people.
Speaker 4:  Well
Speaker 5:  I was the ones
Speaker 4:  You've you've come a long way. So it's a small way Eternal. September is
Speaker 4:  one of my favorite phrases Yeah. Of internet lingo. So in the early, early
Speaker 4:  nineties, basically how people got access to the internet would be they,
Speaker 4:  they went to college,
Speaker 5:  Right?
Speaker 4:  And like colleges would hand out like tower PCs and ethernet connections
Speaker 4:  in the dorms.
Speaker 5:  You had a fancy college.
Speaker 4:  Well they wouldn't hand they wouldi. They would tell you that you had to
Speaker 4:  buy a tower PC Yeah. And give you an internet connection in dorm. So you
Speaker 4:  people would get to college in September and they would sign onto the
Speaker 4:  internet and onto Usenet for the first time on their hardwired
Speaker 4:  internet connection in their dorm. And they would just wreak
Speaker 4:  havoc on internet forms 'cause they had no idea how to behave. Right. So
Speaker 4:  every September was chaos on the internet because
Speaker 4:  all the kids would show up to college and sign onto the internet for the
Speaker 4:  first time and just act like college students on the internet. And then
Speaker 4:  the community was big enough and they, they could see that this was happening.
Speaker 4:  It was like time boxed enough that they would wrangle the college students
Speaker 4:  back into line. Yeah. And the community would operate until they teach them.
Speaker 4:  The next September, September, 1994 would come and a
Speaker 4:  bunch of college students would show up and be idiots on Usenet and they
Speaker 4:  would wrangle them back in line. So every September is chaos. A o l shows
Speaker 4:  up says now every a o l user has access to Usenet.
Speaker 4:  And remember this is like the dominant service provider America was online,
Speaker 4:  my friends,
Speaker 5:  We were online
Speaker 4:  And they flooded Usenet with like everyone's a mom
Speaker 4:  and like all caps yelling and like crazy. And the Usenet
Speaker 4:  community started calling this the September that ever ends it Eternal September
Speaker 4:  because it just, it was just always September every day. Yeah. Was new
Speaker 4:  chaos And the community could no longer wrangle it back into line.
Speaker 4:  It was just escalating chaos.
Speaker 5:  I got kicked out of an X-Files Usenet during that time.
Speaker 5:  'cause I was like 10 or 11. I didn't know what I was doing.
Speaker 5:  I wasn't very good at it. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  You were, you were part of eternal September. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  I was part of the eternal September. It was just, what's up nerds? Let's
Speaker 4:  Talk Alex is like, I'm the face of eternal September. Yeah. It's me. So this
Speaker 4:  is, this to me is like one of those moments. So it's a great Jason Coler
Speaker 4:  advice has a great article about September forever. You should go read it.
Speaker 4:  We'll put it in the show notes. This is one of the concepts that has defined
Speaker 4:  like internet communities for generations now
Speaker 4:  since the early nineties. This concept of eternal September. You build this
Speaker 4:  tiny little community and then it hits the scale point of an influx of new
Speaker 4:  users in the existing moderators existing community.
Speaker 4:  The norms disappear because you just can't constantly enforce them the way
Speaker 4:  you could when it was You know however many college students
Speaker 4:  went to college that September. Right now it's everybody all the time.
Speaker 4:  and I think a lot of what Mastodon is responding to
Speaker 4:  is Yep. Meta for Meta. Very valid criticisms there. Yes.
Speaker 4:  Embrace, extend, extinguish, but also, oh shit, our club's
Speaker 4:  about to not be exclusive anymore.
Speaker 5:  I see. That's the part where I really think they're being overly dramatic.
Speaker 5:  And I'm so sorry to you MAs it on users. You were with me in the eternal
Speaker 5:  September. Like come on guys, you're you're being a little dramatic.
Speaker 4:  I think people on Mastodon might've been the people who experienced they
Speaker 4:  probably Yeah. The other side of eternal
Speaker 5:  September. Yeah. They were, you guys were probably on the other side of it
Speaker 5:  and you should know better at this point because one,
Speaker 5:  it's hard to find things on Mastodon currently. So how likely
Speaker 5:  is it that all of those people coming from Instagram are gonna suddenly be
Speaker 5:  descending in into all of these Mastodon communities really even
Speaker 5:  if you don't block them? 'cause a lot of them it sounds like are Blocking
Speaker 5:  them
Speaker 4:  And they're not organized the same way at all. Right?
Speaker 5:  Right. Like, so there's that part of it. And two, when things are
Speaker 5:  more accessible, it tends to make things better. Like, I don't know if I
Speaker 5:  would work at The, Verge and and b in this community if I
Speaker 5:  hadn't had that access at a young age. and I certainly hadn't had the, didn't
Speaker 5:  have the tools then to access Usenet the way the rest of you guys were
Speaker 5:  accessing it. So like I think making things more accessible is
Speaker 5:  always better. And yes, it does mean that the, that it
Speaker 5:  dilutes these communities pretty quickly and it does change
Speaker 5:  things, but it often ultimately changes things for the better.
Speaker 5:  Even though in this case Meta is the one doing the changing
Speaker 5:  and that creates a whole other set set of issues.
Speaker 6:  I really think the fact that it's Meta that the thing here, okay and
Speaker 6:  I think it's, it's the fact that it's Meta across kind of all three
Speaker 6:  of the points you just made. Neli. Like even in the case of
Speaker 6:  there are about to be a lot of people coming and sort of disrupting our club,
Speaker 6:  which I think is real, right? I think Macedon in particular has this real
Speaker 6:  like we are the, i we are the place that you go to
Speaker 6:  get away from Twitter, right? Like that's, that's its vibe. And in
Speaker 6:  the same way that Twitter is obsessed with Twitter, like Mastodon is obsessed
Speaker 6:  with Twitter. It really is. And now Meta is coming
Speaker 6:  in and a there I would say there it is overwhelmingly likely
Speaker 6:  that Instagram's product is going to be a
Speaker 6:  better product than Mastodon. Yeah. It's gonna have a better
Speaker 6:  identity system because it's gonna borrow it from Instagram, it's gonna have
Speaker 6:  better discovery because that's something that Meta is really good at. Like
Speaker 6:  it will, it will immediately be the default product for The
Speaker 6:  Fediverse. I'm not, I wouldn't guarantee that that's gonna happen, but I
Speaker 6:  would say that is overwhelmingly likely that's what's gonna happen. That
Speaker 6:  it will, it will instantly be the biggest and best thing on The Fediverse.
Speaker 6:  And so you bring in not just a flood of new people,
Speaker 6:  but a flood of new people coming from Instagram, which has its own set of
Speaker 6:  rules and norms and cultures that people hate and I think
Speaker 6:  if, if Mozilla suddenly brought in You know a hundred
Speaker 6:  million people on Mozilla social, I think there would be people with feelings.
Speaker 6:  But it would not be this aggressive and contentious and
Speaker 6:  like knee jerk. We can't allow these people here. But because it's Meta and
Speaker 6:  I think specifically because it's Instagram and because it's like you, you
Speaker 6:  can just imagine what all the like celebrities and
Speaker 6:  influencers and commenters on Instagram will do. Well
Speaker 4:  I can make that simpler for you. It's a bunch of girls, right? Like there's,
Speaker 4:  there's a part of this where because it's Instagram, a bunch of
Speaker 4:  dude nerds on Mastodon who figured out how to set up a Mastodon
Speaker 4:  account and like did it and like passed all the nerd tests
Speaker 4:  is like we no girls allowed.
Speaker 5:  There's a big strong vibe of like when I go into a comic
Speaker 5:  shop and I have to then like defend my
Speaker 5:  knowledge of comics and usually show them the Superman poster.
Speaker 5:  There's a bit like that's the feeling I'm getting here where it's just like,
Speaker 5:  oh you can't join. And it's like guys get over yourself. Yeah. Like I
Speaker 5:  don't think all these Instagram influencers are gonna be descending on your
Speaker 5:  mastodons and destroying this. Well, so this is actually world, the Tumblr
Speaker 5:  users that are eventually coming and all the other ActivityPub
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Users like get over it guys.
Speaker 4:  I think this is the big difference between what's happening now and the,
Speaker 4:  the Usenet example that we were talking about, right? Which is Usenet was
Speaker 4:  organized by topic. So I cannot believe I'm explaining Usenet on the broadcast
Speaker 4:  in 2023. It's
Speaker 5:  I'm having the best time.
Speaker 4:  The fact that we are currently embarking on completely resetting the
Speaker 4:  internet is so exciting to me. and I feel like I might be the only one who
Speaker 4:  can see it at all times. We are going back people we are in
Speaker 4:  fully, everything old is new again territory. And it is deeply
Speaker 4:  entertaining. I
Speaker 6:  Forget who it was, but I was listening to somebody a few months ago who said
Speaker 6:  that when we read about this era in the history books, the last 15 years
Speaker 6:  will be a blip on the radar. It will be like one giant false
Speaker 6:  start that we all made towards one way that the internet could work. And
Speaker 6:  Then we went right back to the way it was before and kept moving forward.
Speaker 6:  and I honestly think that's where we're headed
Speaker 4:  Until this ends 15 years from now. And we go right back to a bunch of centralized
Speaker 4:  social networking
Speaker 6:  Services. That's fair.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Use net's still out there. It's still,
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Pendulums swing back and forth unfortunately. Yeah. But use, they never
Speaker 4:  landed exactly the right spot and stay there. We haven't figured that out
Speaker 4:  yet. But anyway, so the way Usenet was organized was ba more or less Reddit.
Speaker 4:  Like Reddit is closer to how use networked. So imagine if every
Speaker 4:  September 10 million absolute newbies descended
Speaker 4:  on Reddit, found all the topics they wanted and started going insane, right?
Speaker 4:  Like that's how that worked. That's not how Twitter works. That's not how
Speaker 4:  Instagram threads is gonna work. I think there's still a follow graph there.
Speaker 4:  Like no one's going to find your like furries mastodon
Speaker 4:  and be like, I'm in it now. I will. Right? And so the question of de Federating
Speaker 4:  is really just a question of whether you want to be connected to Meta as
Speaker 4:  a version of this at all.
Speaker 6:  Well that's, that's true and it isn't. Right? Like I think one of the interesting
Speaker 6:  things about the way that The Fediverse works is you, you can have things
Speaker 6:  like tags that Yeah. Actually do work across instances. And
Speaker 6:  there are people out there who have really careful
Speaker 6:  systems for how things get tagged and how we think about topics. And you
Speaker 6:  can sort of be in your own space but also have access to, through things
Speaker 6:  like tags and topics, the other stuff that's out there. It's definitely a
Speaker 6:  smaller part of how it works. But I think because it's still such a like
Speaker 6:  power user tool, there are definitely a lot of people on Mastodon
Speaker 6:  who have like curated tag sets that they use and all of a sudden,
Speaker 6:  like, do you remember when this happened on Instagram? All of a sudden everybody
Speaker 6:  got nuts about the tags to try and game. Yeah. The explore page when people
Speaker 6:  are going around. I think that's the kind of thing that people worry about
Speaker 6:  and it's exactly what you're describing. I think it's, it's definitely less
Speaker 6:  likely than it would be if something like this were to happen to say Reddit
Speaker 6:  like you said. But I do think that risk is real here. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  That's fair. We'll see, I I think this is among the most
Speaker 4:  interesting versions of this to tap right? The,
Speaker 4:  the parallels to lots of other things are there. And what's interesting is
Speaker 4:  that many of those things have played out. Microsoft attempting to
Speaker 4:  colonize the web played itself out. Like from start to finish.
Speaker 4:  We, we see how that went. And actually a little bit of
Speaker 4:  intervention, a little bit of competition, they were unsuccessful
Speaker 4:  at doing it
Speaker 5:  And now they're a big baby
Speaker 4:  And now they just, they just want to own Call of Duty. Why won't you let
Speaker 4:  them have it? Gosh. You can see how Google's various attempts to colonize
Speaker 4:  web have been successful and unsuccessful over time. Another great
Speaker 4:  example actually is Apple and open source kind of in
Speaker 4:  a general sense. Like they showed up with an open source
Speaker 4:  kernel in OSS 10. Everyone thought they were gonna pick Linux. They picked
Speaker 4:  another project. That project does not have a life outside of Apple.
Speaker 4:  Right? Like they just like took it and they made it their thing. They did
Speaker 4:  the same thing with the rendering engine inside of Safari. They, they took
Speaker 4:  an existing one, they built upon it. Now that Apple dominates
Speaker 4:  that environment. Right? Those are all good things. I don't think
Speaker 4:  no one's looking back and saying, man, web kit really ruined our open source
Speaker 4:  project. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Apple adopting Unix really destroyed everything.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. We've just seen that these cycles come and go in various different
Speaker 4:  ways. and I think fundamentally they, they're not good
Speaker 4:  or bad, but the parallels are there and the negatives are there and people
Speaker 4:  are like extremely wide open to them. And this one is particularly
Speaker 4:  funny 'cause it is the oldest of them all right? It's the
Speaker 4:  big service provider dumping users on a pretty closed system
Speaker 4:  or a pretty small system and like they're, they're having the same reaction
Speaker 4:  as a bunch of people in the nineties had to it. Yeah. I suspect some of them
Speaker 4:  are the same people from the nineties. Yeah. Which is pretty
Speaker 4:  good. I'm
Speaker 5:  Gonna be, I'm gonna be on the other side again. Yeah. 'cause like I've got
Speaker 5:  my Mastodon account, I barely understand how it works and as soon as the
Speaker 5:  Instagram threads comes along Yeah, I'll give it a go. 'cause the user experience
Speaker 5:  will likely be a lot easier. Yes. And at this point in my life, I'm not
Speaker 5:  interested in tinkering with that. I've got a whole smart home to tinker
Speaker 5:  with. I don't need to tinker with my social media. So like, yeah,
Speaker 5:  okay I wanna go experience it this way and see what it's like when you
Speaker 5:  have all of those resources. You have like very good user
Speaker 5:  interface designers and stuff participating in this.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And we also just don't know what level of interoperability
Speaker 4:  there's going to be. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It may suck, right? Like it could just be garbage and it
Speaker 5:  doesn't even touch most of the rest of The Fediverse. And then it's like,
Speaker 5:  well boy we sure panicked.
Speaker 4:  Well so is it you can post and people can follow you.
Speaker 4:  People on a different server can follow your Instagram account. You can follow
Speaker 4:  people from different servers. That seems like the basics, right? There's
Speaker 4:  a lot of other things you can do. You can build custom moderation services.
Speaker 4:  That's what Flipboard is doing with, with Blue Sky and others. You could,
Speaker 4:  they could have it moderate, not with Mastodon, but with these Reddit
Speaker 4:  alternatives like Lemi and Kabin, there's a lot of ways. So there, from
Speaker 4:  what we understand, Instagram is like starting to have meetings. The meetings
Speaker 4:  are under N D A, which is also extremely contentious
Speaker 4:  in this community. Yep. I'll tell you, when we go have meetings at these
Speaker 4:  companies, we don, we're journalists, we don't, we don't sign the NDAs. I
Speaker 4:  always just look at the, the iPad they have and I say no and then
Speaker 4:  there's a sigh and they go and get me a different badge. And that badge
Speaker 4:  is like, don't talk to this person, don't look at this person.
Speaker 4:  So I get it, don't sign the NDAs. But I think these
Speaker 4:  conversations are basically Meta slash Instagram is trying to be a good
Speaker 4:  participant and like what they're facing is we don't want you to be here.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I I do think one, one more sort of broad point I would
Speaker 6:  make is, I think one of the things that is a real worry
Speaker 6:  is that The Fediverse is absolutely not ready for this many people. I
Speaker 6:  think you could argue that the Fediverse isn't ready to have as many people
Speaker 6:  as it currently has. It's, it's been a really interesting thing to watch
Speaker 6:  both with Twitter folks going to Mastodon and with Reddit folks going to
Speaker 6:  things like Lemi and Caban. Those products are not done. They're like beta
Speaker 6:  tech projects that everyone who works on them can make you a long list of
Speaker 6:  the things that's wrong with them. And they're now trying to figure out
Speaker 6:  and it's just complicated and slow work
Speaker 6:  to build one of these things. And then all of a sudden, like it's not an
Speaker 6:  accident that like nobody was talking about Cain and then all of a sudden
Speaker 6:  a lot of Reddit users start looking for somewhere to go. They find it. And
Speaker 6:  even on Cain's website it's like this is Alpha software
Speaker 6:  but people are showing up because they just need somewhere to go. Right.
Speaker 6:  and I think one of the things on this Fetti pact that a lot of people
Speaker 6:  are signing, which is this like incredible hot pink website, it's beautiful.
Speaker 6:  One of the very first things that they mention about why this is
Speaker 6:  a thing that you should sign and you should not let Meta on
Speaker 6:  is about content moderation. And it's partly about content moderation
Speaker 6:  based on the assumption that Meta is bad at it and won't do it for its own
Speaker 6:  stuff, which will then pollute the rest of The Fediverse. But it's also about
Speaker 6:  the fact that no one has figured this out because this got to scale so fast
Speaker 6:  that most of the content moderation is done by the people who own the specific
Speaker 6:  servers, which is just like a dude in his house for the most part. And
Speaker 6:  figuring out how to do content moderation at this scale has been tough. Like
Speaker 6:  when I wrote this story about ActivityPub, I think it was a Neil Dash that
Speaker 6:  I was talking to who was like, if Instagram shows up and just dumps
Speaker 6:  30 million people into The Fediverse, the whole thing is going to collapse.
Speaker 6:  and I think that's a real valid fear. Like Mastodon is
Speaker 6:  by no means a finished product that is ready for this many people to be interacting
Speaker 6:  with it. Right.
Speaker 5:  That's fair.
Speaker 4:  I just, the You know, You know how fuck, it's impossible. This is an
Speaker 4:  impossible task. And yes, the thing that they are saying about content
Speaker 4:  moderation is not Meta is bad at it. I think Meta is exactly
Speaker 4:  as good at it as it wants to be.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And it's actually like if you take the politics out of it,
Speaker 4:  Meta is very good at it. You get to the politics of it
Speaker 4:  specifically what speech, what kinds of speech will and won't be allowed.
Speaker 4:  Meta has made some decisions that I disagree with that other people disagree
Speaker 4:  with, that many people agree with, disagree with. On the other side of the
Speaker 4:  coin and really what people are reacting to, what almost everyone is always
Speaker 4:  reacting to is those decisions on the margin. And so You
Speaker 4:  know the position of Mastodon as a collection of people is we wish
Speaker 4:  to be so tolerant that some people are banned, which is
Speaker 4:  really where you come back around to Yeah. Like Donald Trump Jr. Is not welcome
Speaker 4:  here is like a very tolerant position in its own
Speaker 4:  weird, twisted way. Okay. Like Meta is gonna make a very
Speaker 4:  different kind of determination and that's the content moderation that they're
Speaker 4:  talking about.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Like I that, I think that's where I'm always the most interested
Speaker 4:  in The. Fediverse is lots of different servers can make lots of different
Speaker 4:  decisions and you're not tied to them forever. Right. You can go
Speaker 4:  somewhere else, you can follow people on different servers or different rules.
Speaker 4:  The market such as it may ever exist is actually making those
Speaker 4:  speech determinations and not the government or
Speaker 4:  one guy, one guy who's delegated to a bunch of lawyers that you never hear
Speaker 4:  about like that to, that's where, that's where the mistake has been. I just
Speaker 5:  Don't see that that's their real concern tho those who are,
Speaker 5:  who are fighting against Meta because like, what's it like, what's the point
Speaker 5:  of The Fediverse where every instance can determine its own content moderation
Speaker 5:  if you don't let people determine their own content moderation. Like I get
Speaker 5:  that it's a big company coming in and I think that's a certainly a thing
Speaker 5:  to be fearful of, but like it stands on content moderation isn't
Speaker 5:  because like that's the point of The Fediverse, they get to decide that.
Speaker 5:  They get to decide that for their users and all of those 30 million or whoever,
Speaker 5:  10,000,005 people that join Instagram threads or whatever
Speaker 5:  it ends up being called. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  But you don't have to, you don't have to contribute value to it. Yeah. Right.
Speaker 4:  You're like, this is my club and you can't just like take the content out
Speaker 4:  of it and put it into your app. Right. In many ways you kind of end up
Speaker 4:  right at this weird Reddit situation. Yeah. Where like my server's
Speaker 4:  content, which is really what my users have contributed to, I'll
Speaker 4:  control the boundaries of Right. I'll not let AI scrape it and I will not
Speaker 4:  let it interact with Meta's product and I, I think we're we're just in for
Speaker 4:  a few years of the internet refiguring out
Speaker 4:  that dynamic. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And I think that's gonna be fun. Yeah. I'm excited for that.
Speaker 4:  I I mean this is like, again, I think this is why The Verge exists because
Speaker 4:  covering the story is a, you have to start with Usenet, which is perfect,
Speaker 4:  and b, it's is much of a technical capability
Speaker 4:  story is it is a how do people behave on the internet
Speaker 4:  as it is a what is Mattis's product gonna be? Story and I.
Speaker 4:  I frankly challenge you to find another group of nerds that will pay attention
Speaker 4:  to it as as much as we will. Alright. We need to take a break. I
Speaker 4:  need to watch this video of Mark Zuckerberg and Jiujitsu mats one more time.
Speaker 4:  We'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  Support for this show comes from a w s We are living
Speaker 2:  in the future and artificial intelligence is completely transforming
Speaker 2:  how business is done. But without an experienced developer on your
Speaker 2:  team, how can you make the most of these emerging technologies?
Speaker 2:  Amazon Web services can help. A w s has been
Speaker 2:  democratizing access to AI and machine learning for companies and
Speaker 2:  customers. They've invested $100 million to build their
Speaker 2:  generative AI innovation center to help customers understand and
Speaker 2:  deploy generative AI to predict trends and prototype with
Speaker 2:  data-driven design. Just imagine how a W Ss can
Speaker 2:  transform your business. learn more at AWS is
Speaker 2:  how.com
Speaker 7:  Support for this show comes from Global Citizen. On
Speaker 7:  September 23rd, the Global Citizen Festival will gather thousands of people
Speaker 7:  who took action to end extreme poverty. Join the Red Hot Chili
Speaker 7:  Peppers, Ms. Lauren Hill, Jung and Anita as they take
Speaker 7:  the stage with world leaders and activists to demand action for
Speaker 7:  equity for the planet, for food and for jobs.
Speaker 7:  Download the Global Citizen app today and earn your spot at the festival.
Speaker 7:  learn more at Global Citizen dot org slash box.
Speaker 4:  All right, we're back. I'm gonna stay on the social media tip for one second
Speaker 4:  longer. Just a second. Is that okay? And
Speaker 5:  It's done. It's passed. It's done.
Speaker 4:  We, we You know there's gadgets to talk about. Yeah. Come on. There's a trial
Speaker 4:  going on. All right. We do need to talk about Reddit though. J
Speaker 4:  Peters has been just owning the Reddit story top to bottom. It's
Speaker 4:  he interviewed Steve Huffman that interview went. It went.
Speaker 4:  Sure did. Haunted car. It's fine. Reddit is,
Speaker 4:  You know they're staying the course. They're not backing down in any which
Speaker 4:  way. I would say. The protests have gotten increasingly hilarious and true
Speaker 4:  Reddit style. At one point Reddit said this needs to be more
Speaker 4:  democratic. It can't just be the moderators. I think Steve Huffin
Speaker 4:  referred to the moderators as the landed gentry of Reddit. Yeah. Which is
Speaker 4:  very funny. So the moderators started holding votes. Many
Speaker 4:  subreddits, including I think our awe others said, okay, we're only
Speaker 4:  allowing pictures of John Oliver. We're our users voted on it. There's nothing
Speaker 4:  he can do. That's what we're
Speaker 6:  Doing. I think. Not just pictures, but sexy pictures of John Oliver. Sexy.
Speaker 6:  That's a very important part
Speaker 4:  Of it. John Oliver has been like, he, we uploaded a folder of photos
Speaker 4:  for them to use, which is very good. Other subreddits allowed not
Speaker 4:  safe for work content, which is very funny. Reddit did not like this at all.
Speaker 4:  No. Just various other protests. Like
Speaker 5:  Did You know the, the female fashion advice subreddit is only
Speaker 5:  doing posts about 17 hundreds fashion now.
Speaker 5:  It's so good. That's
Speaker 4:  Very good. Some Reddits have made everybody a moderator in like
Speaker 4:  true democracy also. Very good. I don't know if this is
Speaker 4:  accomplishing anything. 'cause all these people are still using Reddit. Right?
Speaker 4:  So going dark is like a direct attack on
Speaker 4:  Reddit because new users, search users can't access the communities.
Speaker 4:  Everyone's gonna show up and post pictures of John Oliver. What's Reddit
Speaker 4:  gonna do? Like
Speaker 5:  Enjoy the engagement.
Speaker 6:  I don't know though. I think people on the internet have learned at this
Speaker 6:  point that just saying we're not gonna use this
Speaker 6:  product anymore. Doesn't work. Right? Like you can't, you can't organize
Speaker 6:  traffic killing. But what you can do, and one of the things I think has been
Speaker 6:  very clever is like all of these subreddits categorizing
Speaker 6:  themselves as not safe for work, which means they don't get monetized in
Speaker 6:  the same way. And so that's like, there's a direct hit to what
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Reddit actually cares about, which is its money. These things with
Speaker 6:  John Oliver, like it's you just at the same time Steve
Speaker 6:  Huffman is at can trying to get more advertisers to
Speaker 6:  come on. Reddit is just making a joke of itself as a platform,
Speaker 6:  which in a way I would actually argue is a much more powerful version of
Speaker 6:  protest. Which is to say like, oh, you think you actually run this platform?
Speaker 6:  Like, hell no, you don't. We run this platform and you can, you can try and
Speaker 6:  fight us all you want. We're actually in charge of what happens here.
Speaker 6:  and I think, like to me that has actually come through like loud and clear.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  But does it mean anything at the end of the day?
Speaker 6:  No. And it won't. And all these apps are gonna shut down and Reddit is going
Speaker 6:  to go about its business, but it it, at least it feels like you
Speaker 6:  can feel like you tried. Well,
Speaker 4:  So here's the thing that's really I think happening. Reddit is now
Speaker 4:  imposing its power over this community. They sent an email to
Speaker 4:  a bunch of the moderators of the subs that had gone private. The
Speaker 4:  email was a threat. Like, I don't, I'm not gonna beat around the bush. Oh
Speaker 4:  yeah. It is not in the language of a threat, but the email was, Hey,
Speaker 4:  if you want to get rid of the moderators who've chosen to go private
Speaker 4:  or you think they're not doing the job, let us know and we'll help you get
Speaker 4:  rid of them. And like that's what, how, how else should you read this?
Speaker 4:  If I'm a moderator that is choosing to stay dark, Reddit is emailing my
Speaker 4:  fellow moderators and the users of the subreddits and saying
Speaker 4:  they can get rid of me if I stay the course.
Speaker 6:  Right. And it went even further in some cases. There was a, there was a thing
Speaker 6:  they were saying to moderators that was essentially by taking
Speaker 6:  your sub Reddit dark, you're actually violating the terms of
Speaker 6:  the code of conduct on Reddit because you're not being good
Speaker 6:  to your community by not letting people use it. Which is a
Speaker 6:  leap. But then the threat there is that the consequence for not taking care
Speaker 6:  of your community is Reddit will remove you as a moderator and put somebody
Speaker 6:  else in. So they, they've been making abundantly clear that like, play by
Speaker 6:  the rules or we'll just throw you out and find somebody who will Yeah. In
Speaker 6:  every way they can.
Speaker 4:  Which is again, they, they wrote the rules. They're allowed to say you should
Speaker 4:  play by them. But the attitude and the posture here are
Speaker 4:  extremely aggressive. And You know if you are communicating,
Speaker 4:  one responsibility you have is to how people feel about how you're communicating.
Speaker 4:  And so if the moderators are telling us they feel threatened, those are,
Speaker 4:  those are threats. Like that's just how that works. If Right. That's life.
Speaker 4:  Well,
Speaker 6:  And what's so weird about this to me is like, Reddit's been around for 18
Speaker 6:  years. Like where has this been? Like, at least when Twitter went insane,
Speaker 6:  it was because somebody bought it. Right? Like at least, at least something
Speaker 6:  changed. and I think part of what has been so strange for Redditers is this
Speaker 6:  sense that like, okay, there's a guy in charge who's been on Reddit literally
Speaker 6:  since the beginning. He is a co-founder of the thing. He loves
Speaker 6:  this more than anybody. And all of a sudden just like on a dime just decides
Speaker 6:  to totally screw over the entire community all at once. and I think like
Speaker 6:  the actions have felt bad, but I think this like total surprise of it
Speaker 6:  all is the worst part of a lot of it for some folks.
Speaker 5:  Because for most people it really did come out of nowhere. It was just like
Speaker 5:  one minute,
Speaker 6:  It was that New York Times story. Like all of a sudden it's just like, oh,
Speaker 6:  Steve Huffin wants to make money and then everyone read. It's like, oh shit.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And just fury. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Well and killing the app. I mean that's the real thing. Like the rollout,
Speaker 4:  that's the precipitating factor. Right. But this we are in
Speaker 4:  control of Reddit is new. So here's the thing I wanted to bring up. We have
Speaker 4:  been reporting on this left and right. Jay Peters on our team owns the story.
Speaker 4:  He's the one who interviewed Huffman. Lots of mods are talking to him.
Speaker 4:  Lots of Reddit people are talking to him like good journalists.
Speaker 4:  We go to Reddit for comment on all these stories. Reddit is very unhappy
Speaker 4:  that people are talking to us. They have decided that their
Speaker 4:  official position is that they will wait for us to make mistakes and
Speaker 4:  then issue corrections in order to discredit our journalism. That's
Speaker 4:  straight up what they're doing. and I know this is what they're doing because
Speaker 4:  we have a statement. 'cause they
Speaker 6:  Told us, 'cause they told
Speaker 4:  Us Tim Rashme, who runs comms at Reddit says their blanket
Speaker 4:  statement is, will no longer comment on hearsay, unsubstantiated
Speaker 4:  claims or baseless accusations from The. Verge will be in touch as
Speaker 4:  corrections are needed.
Speaker 5:  Oh my guy,
Speaker 4:  I've been playing this game a long time. We'll wait for you to make a mistake.
Speaker 4:  So Then, we can correct you and say your reporting was wrong is the oldest
Speaker 4:  trick in the book and we are just not gonna fall for it. So we're just gonna
Speaker 4:  print this statement in every story from here on out. Like that's the way
Speaker 4:  it's gonna go. And if they want us to get it right, they can, they can tell
Speaker 4:  us what is actually happening. But I will come back to, we're gonna take
Speaker 4:  the people on the ground. We're gonna take the users, we're gonna take the
Speaker 4:  moderators, we're gonna take the the employees every time. And if you think
Speaker 4:  they're wrong, you can tell us and you can explain why they're wrong. But
Speaker 4:  we're not gonna stop because you've, you're running like a
Speaker 4:  1920s press playbook. Like whatever.
Speaker 4:  Like I'm, we're just gonna burn you every time. And that it's that attitude.
Speaker 4:  It's this aggressive posture where people are worried and
Speaker 4:  they're coming to reporters and saying, here are our worries. Here's the
Speaker 4:  communication we have received that makes us feel threatened. And Reddit's
Speaker 4:  response is shut up. Yeah. That's what breaks your community. And like
Speaker 4:  that story is easy to tell. We don't actually need your help to do it. and
Speaker 4:  I that, I think they're, they're misjudging all of that because
Speaker 4:  when Instagram decides to launch its lemmy clone
Speaker 4:  and start that drama, people will just go, when Google decides
Speaker 4:  crap, we need something like Reddit to exist for search to be good. Here's
Speaker 4:  a Reddit clone that will kill in five years. People will go use it. And the
Speaker 4:  danger here is this posture, I don't care. Like
Speaker 4:  we'll just print the line. We print the poop emoji from Twitter in every
Speaker 4:  single story. Like who cares, right? We are like, this is what we do.
Speaker 4:  This is what you said. We're gonna print it. Your users are gonna take a
Speaker 4:  very different message from that than we are. Like, we will just keep doing
Speaker 4:  journalism and I. I don't think that anybody quite understands that turn.
Speaker 5:  I think they understand it and they don't care.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Straight up.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I I think, I think for them they view this
Speaker 5:  as a relatively minor problem and something that they can just brute force
Speaker 5:  their way out of. And so they like, they, they don't care if, if
Speaker 5:  all of these things are are going crazy right now because they're hoping
Speaker 5:  okay, in a month or two it'll pass and we'll go back and hopefully now we'll
Speaker 5:  be able to sell ads because we'll have a much more predictable
Speaker 5:  community that we can more easily monetize. Like part of this
Speaker 5:  is taming it and getting out all of the people that would make it more
Speaker 5:  difficult to monetize. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  This is like Elon firing all of his staff. Only it's Reddit firing all of
Speaker 4:  its users. Right.
Speaker 5:  And so it's like, okay, we're just gonna get rid of all of you who makes
Speaker 5:  it more difficult for us. and I wouldn't be surprised if that's a pitch that
Speaker 5:  they're, they're doing behind closed doors because that's a pretty compelling
Speaker 5:  one. If you're an advertiser and you wanna like avoid risk at all costs,
Speaker 5:  Reddit right now is a su Reddit, even before this was super risky, right?
Speaker 5:  Because they say, no, no, not safe for work stuff here. And you would still
Speaker 5:  occasionally be like, oh, I didn't need to see that this morning. Checking
Speaker 5:  Reddit. And they can get rid of a lot of those people and have a much
Speaker 5:  calmer, easier to to sell, easier to
Speaker 5:  control community. and I think that's the point. I think that's
Speaker 5:  probably the plan is that these people will tucker themselves
Speaker 5:  out or they'll leave.
Speaker 6:  I totally agree with that. I don't think it was the plan. I agree with every
Speaker 6:  other part of that, but it, what seems clear to me now in retrospect
Speaker 6:  is that Reddit thought it could do this relatively
Speaker 6:  easily that that making these changes would cause some pain because
Speaker 6:  it always causes some pain, but that it would get through it relatively quickly.
Speaker 6:  Right. And then, and then Christian Sealey, the Apollo developer starts making
Speaker 6:  a lot of noise and a lot of people get angry and this just gets worse and
Speaker 6:  worse. And then I think at some point Steve Huffman and the executives at
Speaker 6:  Reddit decided the only thing to do is just rip the bandaid off. And then
Speaker 6:  I suspect what it seems like at any rate happened is they basically just
Speaker 6:  decided to like put on a bunch more bandaids and rip those off too.
Speaker 6:  That it was like, okay, this is a moment we we're gonna go from rage over
Speaker 6:  one thing to like just get all the rage out now. Like let's, let's have this
Speaker 6:  hard reset with the moderators that Reddit has had forever. It has had the,
Speaker 6:  the admins at Reddit and the mods at Reddit have had this contentious relationship
Speaker 6:  forever where the admins wish the mods would run it as a pla
Speaker 6:  as a platform more the way the company wants and the mods wish they got more
Speaker 6:  tools to run it the way that they want it. And this is Reddit like
Speaker 6:  Absolutely, I think you're right. Exerting its authority and saying this
Speaker 6:  is the hard reset and I think at some point you just have no choice
Speaker 6:  but to fight through it. Like I don't think Reddit wanted it to get this
Speaker 6:  bad, but I think at some point they looked at each other and said, well it's
Speaker 6:  gonna be this bad anyway. Like let's just go to war.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. You they can't back down at this point.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. This is never let a crisis go to waste. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  Absolutely. Yeah. I
Speaker 5:  Think, I think you're right though. They probably didn't intend this, but
Speaker 5:  now that they've got it, they're like, okay, let's lean in. Burn it to the
Speaker 5:  ground. The
Speaker 4:  Other way of saying that is that chaos is a ladder and you really wanna
Speaker 4:  find the line between the two. Like one
Speaker 4:  of them ends with the king being dead. Not the show being good, but the king
Speaker 4:  being dead. Yeah. Right. It's gonna win with the power of stories. You guys.
Speaker 4:  Okay. That's enough Game of Thrones on this episode of The
Speaker 4:  Vergecast. We're gonna take a break, we're gonna come back, we're gonna talk
Speaker 4:  about some gadgets. Do a little lightning round, wrap this thing up. We'll
Speaker 4:  be right back.
Speaker 8:  This is advertiser content brought to you by Zelle.
Speaker 8:  Saying no to anyone is hard. When that person's
Speaker 8:  a family member or one of your closest friends. It's woo, practically
Speaker 8:  impossible. Even when they ask things like,
Speaker 9:  Hey, it's your Uncle Walt. Listen, I'm locked out of my bank account and
Speaker 9:  I need 50 bucks stat. Can you help me out?
Speaker 10:  It can feel really overwhelming when family asks to borrow money.
Speaker 10:  I think our first instinct is always to help our family. And so we're willing
Speaker 10:  to do whatever it takes to make sure that they get what they need.
Speaker 8:  Dr. Marty Delima studies financial fraud.
Speaker 10:  When you get a call from a family member or maybe it seems out of the blue,
Speaker 10:  the first thing to do is pause. Like, how urgent is this?
Speaker 10:  And then always ask that person a question.
Speaker 10:  Only that family member would know the answer to.
Speaker 9:  Hello? Hey, don't forget about your Uncle Walt.
Speaker 8:  Oh yeah. Look, what did we have for dinner together last
Speaker 8:  week? Oh,
Speaker 9:  Gotta go. Goodbye.
Speaker 8:  Brought to you by Zelle. Who'd like to remind you to only send money to those
Speaker 8:  You know and trust Zelle is available. To United States Bank
Speaker 8:  account holders, only terms and conditions apply.
Speaker 5:  Support for
Speaker 7:  This show comes from Intel. Where do world changing ideas
Speaker 7:  get their start at Intel? It starts with real solutions.
Speaker 7:  And real solutions start with exceptional engineering.
Speaker 7:  Empowering those with disabilities starts with assistive AI
Speaker 7:  and discovering new galaxies starts with supercomputing.
Speaker 7:  The intelligent factory starts with edge analytics while the
Speaker 7:  sustainable supply chain starts with open manufacturing.
Speaker 7:  And that's just the start. The quantum computing revolution,
Speaker 7:  the next generation of AI experts, the renewable energy
Speaker 7:  grid, liquid cooling, data centers, early diagnosis for
Speaker 7:  cancer, water restoration, farmland protection.
Speaker 7:  They all start with Intel. The examples are countless,
Speaker 7:  the impacts are endless, but the foundation is always the same.
Speaker 7:  It starts with Intel. learn more at
Speaker 7:  intel.com/stories.
Speaker 4:  We're back. We're gonna clear the air from all the social networking talk
Speaker 4:  until a little bit later. Yeah, we gotta, it's like a little
Speaker 4:  between courses. Gadget palate, cleanser, little, a little grapefruit.
Speaker 4:  When I think of amused Bouch, I think of the Google Pixel Tablet, the light
Speaker 4:  refreshing. Google Pixel. Tablet. I think
Speaker 5:  Dan would probably agree with you.
Speaker 4:  I think he would agree that it is light. Yeah, I know that. Refreshing.
Speaker 4:  I don't know that we've actually refreshed the Android Tablet strategy, but
Speaker 4:  Dan reviewed the Google Pixel Tablet this week. That's the Pixel Tablet
Speaker 4:  that has the doc that makes it look like a giant Nest hub. Yeah, it's an
Speaker 4:  Android Tablet
Speaker 5:  $500 Android Tablet, which
Speaker 6:  We should say is, is not nothing like, one of my favorite things about this
Speaker 6:  was talking to Dan through this whole process. He just kept testing
Speaker 6:  the thing and being like, Google made an Android Tablet that
Speaker 6:  is actually like a kind of good Tablet for the first time in a really long
Speaker 6:  time. Is that anything? and I. And we just kinda
Speaker 6:  were like, I, we spent the whole time he, he wrote this review and I was
Speaker 6:  editing it with him, and I was like, is this anything? Because it is. It's
Speaker 6:  a good Tablet. It's a nice device. It has a nice screen, it has decent speakers.
Speaker 6:  The doc thing seems to be really clever. There's a lot of little
Speaker 6:  details missing in the way that you would expect a first generation product
Speaker 6:  to be missing. Extra docs are too expensive. It's missing some of the smart
Speaker 6:  display stuff that people might want. But it gets most of the basics, right?
Speaker 6:  It has no big ideas about what a Tablet should be, which to some extent
Speaker 6:  I love about it. It's not, there's no like heady thesis about
Speaker 6:  tablets being the future of anything. It's literally deliberately just
Speaker 6:  a screen for you to look at. And sometimes you will look at it while you're
Speaker 6:  holding it and sometimes you will look at it while you're cooking in the
Speaker 6:  kitchen and it's sitting on its stock. That's the whole story. And
Speaker 6:  the thing Dan and I spent a long time talking about was how you think about
Speaker 6:  $500 in that context, which I'm very curious what you guys
Speaker 6:  think because I've gone back and forth a million times on whether this thing
Speaker 6:  is a good deal or not.
Speaker 4:  It depends on whether you think it's a tiny portable TV
Speaker 4:  or an iPad. That'ss how I think about it. So
Speaker 4:  iPads are very cheap. They have really good software
Speaker 4:  ecosystems. Apple will update the software every year
Speaker 4:  on time without fail for like a decade.
Speaker 5:  It's 329.
Speaker 4:  There's an ecosystem of cases. If you break an iPad screen,
Speaker 4:  you can walk into any mall kiosk in the world and get
Speaker 4:  a crappy replacement for that screen for not a lot of like, right? Like the
Speaker 4:  iPad is an ecosystem and I will just come back to this.
Speaker 4:  And Apple updates the software on that iPad. Apple's gonna make iPads next
Speaker 4:  year. Yeah. Is Google gonna make Pixel tablets next year?
Speaker 5:  I hope they don't make iPads next year.
Speaker 4:  It'd be amazing if Apple is like, eh, we're doing a Google no more iPads.
Speaker 4:  I'm just like, if you think about it as a competitor to the iPad, this thing
Speaker 4:  loses left and right for $500. You can get an iPad error,
Speaker 4:  a superior product to this with a documented
Speaker 4:  history of actual support from the company that makes it. But
Speaker 5:  No Doc
Speaker 4:  Tim Cook knows they make iPads. Sundar Pcha
Speaker 4:  ever held the Pixel, Tablet You know at this point with Google Sprawl and
Speaker 4:  they are narrowing it down. But like if you think about a competitor iPad,
Speaker 4:  like just on the merits, that's tough. That's a tough comparison. And Google
Speaker 4:  has a lot of baggage. If you are like, this is a TV that sits in a dock
Speaker 4:  and shows me my Google photos and sometimes I can turn off the air conditioner
Speaker 4:  with the smart home controls 500 bucks. Actually not so bad.
Speaker 4:  Couldn't
Speaker 5:  You do that with an iPad?
Speaker 4:  There's no, there's no iPad doc for a kitchen. That's fair. Right? Like that.
Speaker 4:  That's the, if this is a slightly bigger nest hub that also happens
Speaker 4:  to run an ecosystem of video playing apps. I
Speaker 5:  Yeah. The the doc's the part you, you talked David about how there's no big
Speaker 5:  ideas here, but the doc feels not really a big idea. We've seen
Speaker 5:  Lenovo and other people experiment with it, but it seems like a well executed
Speaker 5:  version of a very old big idea. And that's kind of exciting to
Speaker 5:  me because everybody kind of sucks at these docs. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And this one seems to be good.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. One of my favorite things that Dan told me was that he has, he has
Speaker 6:  a magic keyboard for the iPad that he literally
Speaker 6:  just uses as a stand for his iPad to just dock it in and out of
Speaker 6:  which is also a thing that I've done, and it is the most ludicrously,
Speaker 6:  overpriced iPad stand you could possibly imagine. But for all the ecosystem
Speaker 6:  stuff that there is in Apple's world, there actually aren't that
Speaker 6:  many things. You can attach to an iPad. The, it has the little, the little
Speaker 6:  plugs on the bottom, the smart connector stuff. But that hasn't really turned
Speaker 6:  into anything.
Speaker 4:  So. we have a seventh gen iPad that we bought for Max. It was her first iPad.
Speaker 4:  She's on her second iPad now. Just
Speaker 5:  Flick it.
Speaker 4:  She's five.
Speaker 4:  But we still have this one line around it basically just like got too old.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Like I, I bought the cheapest one when she was born and then she got
Speaker 4:  to about three and I was like, I'm so sorry kid. Like
Speaker 4:  you, you deserve a reasonably fast computer. So. we just had this thing and
Speaker 4:  what's it there for? It's there to like show photos and I, don't know, sometimes
Speaker 4:  be a kitchen TV or whatever. and I went looking for a doc that uses the,
Speaker 4:  the smart connector on the bottom. And there are zero. Yeah, zero.
Speaker 4:  There's one. Logitech made it, it was called the Log Dock. They sold it for
Speaker 4:  like $129 and they stopped making it because it charged too slow and got
Speaker 4:  the iPad hot.
Speaker 6:  It's also like three inches thick for reasons I never understood.
Speaker 6:  But yeah, it's bad. Is
Speaker 5:  It like a technology thing? Like
Speaker 4:  No, it, I think the Smart Apple has claimed that the smart connector is open
Speaker 4:  and does not require licenses. And like that
Speaker 5:  Can't be frozen. That
Speaker 6:  Does not seem to be the case. Because otherwise
Speaker 5:  Belkin would have 12 Doss out there. Yeah. And they
Speaker 5:  have zero.
Speaker 4:  I think the reality is a smart connector might not be that great. Mm.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Right? And there's no way to test it because there's So that runs a
Speaker 5:  smart connector
Speaker 4:  Or the made for iPhone mafiaa.
Speaker 4:  Like if anybody tells us the answer, like they're dead. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  and I I would say, it's been 10 years of me asking for the story.
Speaker 4:  I've been trying to write a story about the Made for fund program, the M
Speaker 4:  F I program, and what it's like really, like for 10 years it has
Speaker 4:  destroyed reporters. The wreckage, the human wreckage of me
Speaker 4:  asking for a story about the M F I program is vast,
Speaker 4:  but if you want to tell us about it,
Speaker 6:  Several Apple employees just showed up outside the studio as you were saying
Speaker 6:  that
Speaker 4:  It is, it is the most tightly, like, we're like, we're gonna do a whole episode
Speaker 4:  at H D M I and like people are like, yeah, we'll talk about that. And it's
Speaker 4:  cutthroat politics. A whole episode at u s we're like, we wanna do a whole
Speaker 4:  episode about M f i, about the lightning connector and like
Speaker 4:  darkness falls.
Speaker 6:  Like say that again.
Speaker 4:  It's like erta. Look, it's not happening.
Speaker 4:  But I think the smart connector is wrapped up into that. Yeah. So that's
Speaker 4:  why there's no docs. There we go. Is basically the answer.
Speaker 5:  I like that plan. Yeah, that's a good idea. Yeah. But I will
Speaker 6:  Say I am very enthusiastic about the idea of a good fancy kitchen
Speaker 6:  tv. I wish this thing didn't cost $500. I think if it was like
Speaker 6:  3 49, I would've bought one already. That
Speaker 5:  That feels right.
Speaker 6:  It's just a smidge out of the range where I can just like feel like it's
Speaker 6:  an obviously good idea right now. Like I have an iPad and I can just carry
Speaker 6:  it in and outta my kitchen. And that basically works fine
Speaker 5:  Also, there's no remote for it, right?
Speaker 4:  No,
Speaker 5:  I I am firmly on.
Speaker 6:  You got 10 remotes on the end of your arms. Alex.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I, I need so many remotes. You ha like
Speaker 5:  you're in your kitchen, your hands are dirty. You don't wanna like dry. Like,
Speaker 5:  I wanna like a remote that can get all grubby in my kitchen and also then
Speaker 5:  be cleaned so I don't disease people
Speaker 4:  Like throw it in the dishwasher
Speaker 5:  Or wash it in the sink without electrocuting myself
Speaker 6:  Be, this is a point in favor of the Pixel Tablet because
Speaker 6:  Siri is garbage. And this is true. The Pixel Tablet is not, or, and Google
Speaker 6:  assistant is not garbage. It's very exciting. All
Speaker 4:  Right. I found you something called the Slim Seal five in one universal waterproof
Speaker 4:  remote control.
Speaker 5:  But does it work for the Google Pixel Tablet?
Speaker 6:  It's, it's just a stylist you use to touch the Pixel Tablet.
Speaker 4:  I don't, I don't like it. and I will say that Google's AI search results
Speaker 4:  are like, what are you doing?
Speaker 4:  This is the most useless ai.
Speaker 4:  Nevermind. I'm not every now and again, I look at what AI can actually produce.
Speaker 4:  I'm like, I'm not worried. That's how You know you're gonna be first against
Speaker 4:  the wall. Look, that's the the thing about the tv Yeah. In
Speaker 4:  the kitchen is like, it's what everybody wants. It's what everyone's trying
Speaker 4:  to build. It's been the pinnacle of technology since the fifties. It's
Speaker 4:  hard. And everyone's still kinda like looking at their phones. Yeah. Also,
Speaker 4:  the, the fact that it's like Android on the backend, I don't think that processor
Speaker 4:  is fast enough to support like fast user switching in a way that would make
Speaker 4:  having actual Android apps in your kitchen like useful to you.
Speaker 4:  Right? Like if this thing is actually signed into my Google account and it's
Speaker 4:  just like sitting on the dock in the kitchen, like Android tablets are not
Speaker 4:  swift. It's switching to my wife's account. Right. Or
Speaker 4:  whatever. Right. And that there's just like that piece of it that I'm
Speaker 5:  Worried. Why would you need that speed in the kitchen?
Speaker 4:  Oh. Because if, at least in my world, if the other people,
Speaker 4:  if it's not instant, it will just never be used. Right. If I was like,
Speaker 4:  here's what I want you to do. I want you to get into the, I walk into this
Speaker 4:  room and then to use this huge screen. I want you to push some
Speaker 4:  fiddly buttons and wait and
Speaker 5:  It takes like 30 seconds. No. Good.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. But Becky's like, I'm gonna use my phone instantly without question.
Speaker 4:  She'll use her phone's.
Speaker 6:  But Neli I would remind you again that do You know what the iPad has in terms
Speaker 6:  of multiple users? Nothing.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. True. And that's why Max has had two of them
Speaker 6:  The worst. No, I, I think like, this is one of those things that I, I sincerely
Speaker 6:  hope Google stays at this because I think there's a, there's a version of
Speaker 6:  this a couple of years from now that's maybe a little cheaper and
Speaker 6:  a little better and fixes some of the little things that
Speaker 6:  are missing, like you're talking about. And this starts to get really compelling.
Speaker 6:  I have absolutely zero faith that that is going to happen. But I sincerely
Speaker 6:  hope we like that. I live to see the Google Pixel Tablet
Speaker 6:  three.
Speaker 4:  I'm gonna like send you a sign print that says, I hope Google sticks with
Speaker 4:  this. And you can just like hang it above your desk.
Speaker 6:  Remember it'll go right next to my Rick Olow dartboard.
Speaker 5:  Remember when there was like a 27 inch Android Tablet? Yeah. That was
Speaker 5:  supposed to be a TV for your kitchen. Like in 2014.
Speaker 4:  Putting a TV in your kitchen is the only dream tech industry has ever had.
Speaker 5:  They suck so much at it. They can't fit in because they haven't figured up
Speaker 6:  The waterproof remote.
Speaker 5:  It's the remote. You figure that out, the rest of it'll
Speaker 4:  Fall into place. Yeah. It's like, can we run Windows on your TV and can that
Speaker 4:  TV live in your kitchen? And everyone's like, you've got bad ideas. No, no.
Speaker 4:  Thank you.
Speaker 4:  Other Gadget News. A bunch of Vision Pro stuff is out this week. Apple officially
Speaker 4:  released the S D K to let developers start playing with it. They're gonna
Speaker 4:  have open developer beta zones. You, you
Speaker 4:  airlift into them, you drop out and then they put a headset on your face
Speaker 4:  and you aren't allowed to test your apps.
Speaker 5:  You have to send an n d a very
Speaker 4:  Complicated
Speaker 6:  Process. I really like imagining that there are gonna be like planes and
Speaker 6:  like You know how the O Oxygen mask drops down. Yeah. You're gonna like sit
Speaker 6:  in your seat and a Vision Pro is just gonna drop down from the ceiling.
Speaker 4:  Yes. Apple has chartered a number of sevens, 40 sevens and they will circle
Speaker 4:  the globe letting people try the headset.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it's perfect. This is true. It's all right there.
Speaker 4:  The previous section was like a impassioned plea about how we make
Speaker 4:  journalism. This section, I'm lying to you, is telling you that Apple's gonna
Speaker 4:  fly developers around the world wearing headset sets to
Speaker 4:  build apps. That's just the bird test. You never know what's gonna happen.
Speaker 4:  But we've seen some apps from this S D K 'cause people have gotten it. They're
Speaker 4:  able to like start building in the simulator. The simulator's very funny
Speaker 4:  'cause all the apps are in like a fake living room. Like you just like look
Speaker 4:  at the photos and all the screenshots are like, what if you had a beautiful
Speaker 4:  living room?
Speaker 5:  Do we know whose living room it
Speaker 4:  Is? And that's some Apple living room. The number of beautiful fake living
Speaker 4:  rooms in the Apple campus is off the charts. It really is. I
Speaker 5:  Was just wondering if it's like based on anyone in particulars. Is it Tim
Speaker 5:  Cooks
Speaker 4:  You? It's Tim Cook's living room. Yeah. It's too small to be Tim Cook's living
Speaker 4:  room. Okay. You know Tim Cook. His living room is like a gigantic, he's got
Speaker 4:  a conversation of Granite.
Speaker 5:  I think he's got the pit. You,
Speaker 4:  You think he's Yeah. He's like step down with me. Yeah. All right. Maybe
Speaker 4:  who knows.
Speaker 5:  Big Fireplace.
Speaker 4:  It's like, welcome, welcome. Come down, come down into my conversation.
Speaker 6:  Step down with me is Tim Cook's memoir title. Step Down
Speaker 4:  With me is very amazing. Very good. Yeah. Anyway, so we've seen the apps.
Speaker 4:  The apps are pretty interesting, right? They, I saw a version of P Calc.
Speaker 4:  I've seen a few other apps. Some interesting things we've discovered
Speaker 4:  already is the, the concept of dark mode seems to make no sense
Speaker 4:  in like spatial computing.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And then there's two ways to get an app into the simulator. One, you can
Speaker 4:  take an iPad app and go that way. Or you can build it in the Vision
Speaker 4:  Pro S C K and the iPad apps are just floating
Speaker 4:  iPad apps. I love it. It's just here they are. And the
Speaker 4:  Vision Pro apps are like Frosted Glass. They've got depth and it's just very
Speaker 4:  clear that like, that's how you should do it.
Speaker 6:  I mean this is like back to when the iPad first came out and
Speaker 6:  there was a thing you could do where you would just hit the two x button.
Speaker 6:  Do you remember this? You could run an iPhone app and you would just hit
Speaker 6:  the two X and it would blow up to size of the iPad. You can
Speaker 5:  Still do that. That's
Speaker 4:  How, that's how the majority of the people are running Instagram on their
Speaker 4:  iPads.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, that's, yeah, exactly. I think the Vision Pro is gonna have a long
Speaker 6:  run of being just like that. Where it's just gonna be like, we took a rectangle.
Speaker 6:  Here's here it is in another place. Do you like this rectangle?
Speaker 4:  Well this is always back to Apple's initial strategy with
Speaker 4:  anything, which is you like apps, right? Here's some apps. Yep.
Speaker 4:  And they did it with the Mac. Remember they're like iPad apps now run on
Speaker 4:  your Mac. If you are the person who runs iOS and
Speaker 4:  iPad, OSS apps on your Mac natively. I would love to hear from you.
Speaker 4:  I was so excited about this concept. and I did it once
Speaker 4:  with some, like,
Speaker 5:  I do it with my air conditioning apps. That's
Speaker 4:  Good. Do
Speaker 6:  You ever like imagining how many Apple engineers are employed full-time so
Speaker 6:  that you can control your heating and cooling from your laptop?
Speaker 5:  I suspect it's one
Speaker 4:  Also. You should do that in the home app.
Speaker 5:  No, it doesn't work. It doesn't work with Home Kit, HomeKit or Home
Speaker 5:  Assistant. I'm working through it. Madea, call me.
Speaker 6:  You have to move. Oh, Alex. That's the only answer. Yeah, it's time to
Speaker 4:  Move other Vision Pro News. The information has a report that they didn't
Speaker 4:  show us everything. There are fitness features, which we haven't been talking
Speaker 4:  about since we came on. We knew it. It will guide users through yoga and
Speaker 4:  Tai Chi.
Speaker 5:  So like crummy, supernatural.
Speaker 4:  Do a kick.
Speaker 6:  That's how what Tai chi is. Neli Neli. Can you just, can you just do a, do
Speaker 6:  some Tai chi for us right now real quick, just for a couple minutes.
Speaker 4:  Do a cake.
Speaker 5:  It's also yoga.
Speaker 4:  Wave your arms around, do cakes
Speaker 4:  apparently. And that let you interact with content on a stationary bike.
Speaker 6:  Is it weird that I'm very excited about that specifically. Like for some
Speaker 6:  reason in, in this very good informational report, that was the thing that
Speaker 6:  jumped out to me is like, oh, I would use that. I
Speaker 5:  Mean, if they do it well, that would be really cool.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Like I often, the only way I will ever use a treadmill
Speaker 6:  or a stationary bike is if I can also watch a television program because
Speaker 6:  otherwise God helped me. And so I'm, I'm the guy who like brings my iPad
Speaker 6:  to the gym and just sets it up in front of me and like watches the league
Speaker 6:  for an hour while I run on the treadmill. Or stand on the treadmill and watch
Speaker 6:  the league. And, and the idea of having a headset, it's kind of like the,
Speaker 6:  the plane example, right? It's this, it's this very sort of specific
Speaker 6:  episodic thing where I would very much like to not be here. and I can totally
Speaker 6:  see why something like that would make a lot of sense on a stationary bike.
Speaker 6:  I'd be very into that. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  But you're still on the bike. The part that sucks is being on the bike.
Speaker 5:  That's the problem. I like resent it. Like I was trying to watch
Speaker 5:  Ted lasso one day on the stationary bike and I was just like, on this bike.
Speaker 5:  I could be watching this on the couch. It's just right over there.
Speaker 4:  Stupid moving, stupid moving. Well look, here's what I'm saying. Do
Speaker 4:  a kick. Have you thought about kicking more?
Speaker 5:  Do a gentle kick.
Speaker 4:  I, I think we all agree that this is one of the killer
Speaker 4:  apps for these devices. I don't know how I feel about riding a
Speaker 4:  stationary bike with a wired battery pack in my pocket.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Or mounted to the bike in some way. Getting
Speaker 5:  All hot and sweaty. Oh, gross. And then the ba ugh,
Speaker 4:  Gross. Just kick that right off your body.
Speaker 5:  You're definitely not sharing that headset with other people.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Gross. But you can see that there's an expansive vision
Speaker 4:  for this. I think the fact that they, that, I mean we know that they release
Speaker 4:  a wwc so developers could get into it. The fact that the s D K is out
Speaker 4:  so quickly afterwards and that people will beginning to use it well before
Speaker 4:  it actually launches next year. There is an amount of confidence in
Speaker 4:  this device that I think is fascinating. It's, I still, the more
Speaker 4:  I think about it, every time I think about it, I think of that picture of
Speaker 4:  the guy taking a picture of his kids wearing a headset. That's
Speaker 5:  The use case.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. There, there's a version of this where they're already
Speaker 4:  assuming people are bought into wearing the headset and they're gonna do
Speaker 4:  all the things in the headset. And it's like no. Step one
Speaker 4:  they gotta put on the headset. Like you gotta tell them something amazing
Speaker 4:  is gonna happen in that headset before they put it on.
Speaker 6:  Which is why fitness is so powerful. Like fitness is the reason wearables
Speaker 6:  worked because people will put things on their body to track their health
Speaker 6:  and fitness. I
Speaker 5:  Was gonna say it's the reason the Meta headset has done Yeah. Or one of the
Speaker 5:  reasons. Yeah. I just
Speaker 6:  Started doing Supernatural again. The boxing absolutely kicks my ass
Speaker 6:  every single time. But it's so
Speaker 5:  Fun. You're like, oh, it's only 10 minutes, whatever. And then you're like,
Speaker 5:  fuck. Just
Speaker 6:  Wrecked at the end. Yeah, it's
Speaker 5:  Great. I love it.
Speaker 4:  Speaking of do a kick. There's, there's kicks in supernatural boxing.
Speaker 4:  Literally there's like, it's like I'm gonna kick it and you kick it. It's
Speaker 4:  great. It's perfect.
Speaker 5:  Do that Vision pro. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I Well it sounds like they will only, you'll get a calming apple voice.
Speaker 4:  It's gonna be great. It's gonna be Johnny, I, I
Speaker 5:  Think Don't wanna watch you do
Speaker 4:  Tai Chi. I will buy a vision pro if you guarantee me that Johnny i's voice
Speaker 4:  will be like, do a kick.
Speaker 4:  You want me to wear the headset? I'll wear the headset. It's
Speaker 4:  ridiculous. But yeah, I think that's where fitness comes in. I think where
Speaker 4:  that's where this other stuff comes in. But the, I think Apple, like Apple's
Speaker 4:  entire approach to this is like, they've skipped the first step of like,
Speaker 4:  why you won't put this on. We'll see, we got a long way to go. More
Speaker 4:  news out of our friends in Europe. You know they're, they just keep passing
Speaker 4:  laws over there. I
Speaker 5:  Love them. I God bless 'em.
Speaker 4:  Well, so this one is tough. Barbara wrote about this. She's super into it.
Speaker 4:  A new regulation that will say phone batteries have to be easily replaceable.
Speaker 4:  Makes sense. This is like we've covered every twist and turn of the phone
Speaker 4:  battery story. Apple got into a lot of trouble for actually
Speaker 4:  throttling its phones. As the batteries got older. A to a
Speaker 4:  justified reason. Maybe you gotta tell people you're doing it a lot of trouble
Speaker 4:  for that. They've launched a battery repair program. They've launched all
Speaker 4:  these repair programs due to regulations around the country and the world.
Speaker 4:  And now we're at actually just from the beginning, you have to make the battery
Speaker 4:  replaceable. Yeah. This is pretty huge implications for iPhones were designed.
Speaker 4:  Yes.
Speaker 6:  And we should say it hasn't been passed. It seems very likely it's going
Speaker 6:  to, the initial vote was, I think, let's see, Barbara said
Speaker 6:  587 votes in favor. Nine against and 20 abstentions.
Speaker 6:  Like it's a pretty strong majority. But the thing I think is most interesting
Speaker 6:  about this is the, the phrase that it uses is that portable batteries
Speaker 6:  have to be designed quote in such a way that consumers can themselves easily
Speaker 6:  remove and replace them. And the phrase easily remove and replace
Speaker 6:  is in bold. And you can just tell this was so carefully
Speaker 6:  worded so that you can't get out of it by saying, okay, we'll make it easy
Speaker 6:  to go to the Apple store and replace it. Or a third party manufacturer.
Speaker 6:  It means no, a human being needs to be able to open up their phone,
Speaker 6:  remove their battery, and put in a new one like that couldn't, that is clearly
Speaker 6:  the outcome they're looking for here. and I think that's really fascinating.
Speaker 5:  Couldn't Apple argue that they can do that now?
Speaker 6:  No. No. You can't argue that someone could remove the battery from their
Speaker 6:  office. Oh my
Speaker 5:  God. I love when you pull the, the adhesive in there. Yeah. Very slow,
Speaker 5:  most satisfying thing in the world.
Speaker 4:  It's, it's like the way that phones are designed and structured
Speaker 5:  Right?
Speaker 4:  Are the batteries are actually in many cases now, like a component of the
Speaker 4:  structure of the phone. Yeah. Okay. Like all that's gotta change. 'cause
Speaker 4:  now you can just like take it out. I don't think we're gonna go back to plastic
Speaker 4:  tab batteries that pop out when you drop the phone. I missed this and you
Speaker 4:  might still have to be, be able to unscrew the phone. We'll see. I this is,
Speaker 4:  it
Speaker 5:  Would make the phone thicker.
Speaker 4:  It would make the phone thicker. Potentially,
Speaker 5:  Potentially affect waterproofing.
Speaker 4:  Well, it, it really just depends on like where, where the connector for
Speaker 4:  the battery is. Is it outside? Is it exposed or is it still
Speaker 4:  inside the case and you just unscrew the case? I think if it, it comes down
Speaker 4:  to you can remove two screws in the bottom of your phone, pop up in your
Speaker 4:  phone, swap out the battery with a weird little connector that's pretty delicate
Speaker 4:  and you screw your phone back together
Speaker 5:  And then they get all the money from everybody bringing it in because they
Speaker 5:  broke the delicate connector. Yeah. Boom. It's easily
Speaker 5:  replaceable. You just suck.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I think we're gonna hear Apple go to war against this. Yeah. Like
Speaker 4:  they like didn't go to war against U S P C. You know.
Speaker 4:  They're like, oh no, we have to use a connector. We designed like,
Speaker 5:  Ooh,
Speaker 4:  If you don't know Apple basically design the S P C connector. It's like a
Speaker 4:  real thing. Fine. They're like, we don't wanna do it, but we, we get it.
Speaker 4:  We're already put in iPads. This is like, they're You're gonna blow up the
Speaker 4:  phone market. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  How many, how many Apple lawyers are currently in route
Speaker 5:  to the eu?
Speaker 4:  Seven 40 sevens full of lawyers in that sense. Just going,
Speaker 4:  getting over there. All right. Let's do a little bit of lightning round.
Speaker 4:  Let's wrap this thing up. Here's my lightning round one. I wanna talk about
Speaker 4:  this Gary Vaynerchuk interview on decoder. So I interviewed Gary Vanner.
Speaker 4:  We're
Speaker 5:  Gonna allow you to talk about decoder because you're using it as your lightning.
Speaker 5:  David
Speaker 4:  Said, I'm allowed to do D V D liner notes for decoder on the Vergecast.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I just wanted, I just want you to know though, this is two weeks in
Speaker 6:  a row that you have talked about this on The Vergecast and, and I'm outraged.
Speaker 4:  Well, look, I'm the person who's always like the Phish never talk about the
Speaker 4:  water. Like this is like a phrase use all the time. and I just did it to
Speaker 4:  myself. Because if you have been in ad supported media for a decade,
Speaker 4:  you are aware that VaynerMedia is a gigantic ad
Speaker 4:  agency that basically invented the concept
Speaker 4:  of like social marketing. Like the brands are at again,
Speaker 4:  is the thing that VaynerMedia like dragged into existence.
Speaker 4:  Thank
Speaker 5:  You guys. It's not
Speaker 4:  Whatever it is, it's just true. I'm not saying
Speaker 6:  Without Gary, Uck the phrase, sir. This is a Wendy's may not exist
Speaker 4:  Any other, their clients are like real clients like Pepsi and TikTok and
Speaker 4:  what, like huge car companies or like VaynerMedia clients. So this is something
Speaker 4:  I just like know because they're, they're just, I work in ad supported
Speaker 4:  media. I'm aware of ad agencies. I, it's a thing. Our
Speaker 4:  audience does not know this. and I completely forgot that this thing that
Speaker 4:  is just like baked into my job of like knowing what ad
Speaker 4:  agencies are. It's like obviously nobody they know the N F T guy and I forgot
Speaker 4:  to like say it out loud. Like, yes, I think that, I think it
Speaker 4:  is. Anyone confused about how I feel about NFTs?
Speaker 5:  How, how do you feel about them? They're
Speaker 4:  Dumb.
Speaker 4:  Look, what do you want from me? I think they're dumb. I I, we called them
Speaker 4:  scams for the whole time of N F T summer. Great. The thing I'm
Speaker 4:  interested in is the end of the social web and the fact that being
Speaker 4:  a content creator on a social platform is a fundamentally
Speaker 4:  tenuous and hard way to earn a living. And all the big, the biggest
Speaker 4:  creators in the world, they hit a point of their fame and they pivot to
Speaker 4:  something more stable,
Speaker 5:  Like fighting other people in a cage, like
Speaker 4:  Legitimately fighting other people in a cage. Yeah. Fake
Speaker 4:  boxing is a more stable career than being a YouTuber.
Speaker 4:  That's weird. Right? Selling. Well stay with the Paul brothers. Selling
Speaker 4:  prime energy drinks is a more stable career than being a
Speaker 4:  YouTuber. We weird, just weird outcomes left and right.
Speaker 4:  You just go down the list. The Demilio sisters are selling shoes.
Speaker 4:  I think it's because their dad used to be a shoe guy, but like they've pivoted
Speaker 4:  to and they're like, we're gonna innovate in the footwear space. And you
Speaker 4:  just listen to that sentence and you're like, but why are you
Speaker 4:  doing that? And it's because it's a more stable business. And then you see
Speaker 4:  what's happening with a lot the platforms and all the change. And so my interest
Speaker 4:  is, oh, I want to go talk to the person who makes the platform's money.
Speaker 4:  So when we talk about Facebook's revenue or toss revenue, it comes
Speaker 4:  from companies advertising on those platforms and an ad
Speaker 4:  agency sit in the middle of those transactions. So Facebook makes money because
Speaker 4:  ad agencies like publicists or whatever, spend money on
Speaker 4:  Facebook on behalf of their big clients. VaynerMedia invented a bunch of
Speaker 4:  this stuff and I just forgot to say it out loud. So I, I know people are
Speaker 4:  mad at me about this interview and maybe I should have had him arrested on
Speaker 4:  site. Maybe that's how you feel like Gary Huck. But the
Speaker 4:  thing that's interesting to me is like, here's the company and here's a person
Speaker 4:  who mastered that moment and his view
Speaker 4:  on where it's going. It's super interesting. If you think the moment is ending,
Speaker 4:  which I do, he's at can this week, the big ad agency
Speaker 4:  thing in France, and he's giving speeches on stage.
Speaker 4:  They're like, ai, we're gonna ruin our creative with ai.
Speaker 4:  That's the part of him that I think you don't see where he talks to his people
Speaker 4:  on the ad agency side. Like I said, I I wish I'd reframed this interview.
Speaker 4:  David and I have been talking about it since it came out. Like, oh, I just
Speaker 4:  forgot to say the thing. I know. Yeah. Like, not everybody thinks about
Speaker 4:  a ad agencies as often as I do.
Speaker 6:  I mean the, yeah. Gary contains multitudes. He's a, he's a complicated dude.
Speaker 6:  I think n
Speaker 4:  Ft suck by the way. I I don't wanna be like,
Speaker 6:  And he, I'll say he does not make a compelling case for NFTs. He makes a
Speaker 6:  compelling case for creating cool collectibles that people want.
Speaker 6:  Why those need to be digital things on the blockchain. Dunno. But I just
Speaker 6:  wanna say
Speaker 5:  It's faster and cheaper.
Speaker 6:  I is it, I'm not even sure that's true. It's just worse
Speaker 6:  is the only thing I know for sure. But the, the one thing I wanna say, people
Speaker 6:  should listen to the episode. It's it however you feel about Gary v It's,
Speaker 6:  it's a really interesting episode, but he says this one thing to you and
Speaker 6:  Eli that has really stuck out to me. You're basically talking about kind
Speaker 6:  of where to go on platforms and he's just ruthless about it. He's basically
Speaker 6:  like, I go where the attention is. I I have no other metrics. I wanna be
Speaker 6:  where people are. And you essentially are basically asking about
Speaker 6:  how to sort of monetize as an influencer and what, whether you should worry
Speaker 6:  when one goes away or just go where the attention is. And he says
Speaker 6:  that would be like saying running commercials on Seinfeld is not sustainable.
Speaker 6:  No shit. Once it hasn't got the attention you have to move on. Like that's
Speaker 6:  just, it, like done just ruthless. It's like I will go where people are and
Speaker 6:  when people go somewhere else, I don't care where it is. I'll be there too.
Speaker 6:  That's the internet.
Speaker 4:  That's the internet. But it's also to me, that's why I keep saying like,
Speaker 4:  the influencers aren't making money. Like being the most famous TikTok is
Speaker 4:  not a great business. It's certainly not like long-term
Speaker 4:  sustainable. It'll, it'll burn you the hell out. Like all these platforms
Speaker 4:  rewards scale. I was talking to James Vincent today about just
Speaker 4:  AI and what it's gonna do to the web. And what we were talking about is,
Speaker 4:  if you are a YouTuber and you make four perfect YouTube
Speaker 4:  videos a year, you're not gonna make it.
Speaker 4:  If you make two crappy YouTube videos a day with garish YouTube
Speaker 4:  thumbnails, you're probably on your way to success. One of those things is
Speaker 4:  gonna burn you out instantly. Immediately. Like no question every YouTuber
Speaker 4:  will tell you it will. Doug Demaro, one of my favorite YouTubers, what's
Speaker 4:  he pivoting towards? Cars and bids. What's cars and bids in the big investment
Speaker 4:  in cars and bids allowing him to do right now, expand the number of hosts
Speaker 4:  on his channel. He's still gonna make as many videos. He's the first person
Speaker 4:  to tell you. But like he's, he's spreading out the workload
Speaker 4:  to make the amount of content that YouTube demands of him. That's just a
Speaker 4:  weird place to be. So you listen to Vayner Chuck's approach,
Speaker 4:  he's not trying to monetize the content. He's trying to put ads
Speaker 4:  near attention and that's the internet. Like, that's how all the platforms
Speaker 4:  are monetized. They are ruthless. And so I I just think there's a turn in
Speaker 4:  there where it's like, if you don't know where the money's going, you actually
Speaker 4:  don't, you're not gonna have an understanding of how the next
Speaker 4:  platform shift will happen. Again, I forgot to say this out
Speaker 4:  loud. Wish I had said this all out loud, but that's the
Speaker 4:  impetus of this. And You know I every day we will, we will strive
Speaker 4:  to be better. But that's, to me it's, I I really think we're at this like
Speaker 4:  crazy moment in the social web and talking to the people who built it
Speaker 4:  involves talking to the marketers who have built it because they're the money.
Speaker 4:  Like we, they have been You know that What's the saying? If the thing
Speaker 4:  is, if you're not paying for it, you're the product. Yeah. We're the, they're
Speaker 4:  the ones buying the product. and I, there's just something in there that
Speaker 4:  I think is like, are they ready for this? Is is that world ready for this
Speaker 4:  too? I'll tell you one other quick story and Then we can move on to the next
Speaker 4:  sliding round. This is the longest sliding round Entry in history. I was
Speaker 4:  the C m O of a gigantic financial services company.
Speaker 4:  And we were talking about the whole Bud Light kerfuffle. And the worry
Speaker 4:  is that the internet has pushed marketers towards ultra targeted
Speaker 4:  advertising. That's what internet platforms sell ultra targeted advertising.
Speaker 4:  You're gonna make a piece of creative to sell Bud Light. You're gonna go
Speaker 4:  find an audience for that creative that because that has been
Speaker 4:  precisely targeted to them, they're gonna be more likely to buy Bud Light
Speaker 4:  and then next to them, what is constantly happening is total context collapse
Speaker 4:  where like the precisely targeted thing becomes a cultural war issue in some
Speaker 4:  other way. And so just the way that people are thinking about even
Speaker 4:  that, like the main thing you sell targeted advertising is, oh
Speaker 4:  boy, there's danger here that we weren't aware of because of the politics
Speaker 4:  of the country. Yeah. What are you gonna do when targeted advertising is
Speaker 4:  no longer the good idea? Right? Like, is that a story? I don't know. But
Speaker 4:  it's boring. It was boring just saying it out loud just now, but like,
Speaker 4:  I'm just like that whole thing that this whole like apparatus of the
Speaker 4:  social internet is straining under the weight and like I
Speaker 4:  I, I personally think I can do a better job explaining why I'm interested
Speaker 4:  in talking to people who built it. But when they change and when that money
Speaker 4:  moves, these companies are gonna shift like that overnight to combat sports.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. The way the platforms work are is gonna change overnight. They're gonna
Speaker 4:  shift to combat sports and everything's gonna be fine. All right. Alex,
Speaker 4:  it's throw lightning round one
Speaker 5:  Microsoft who's just a whittle baby. Yeah. They just, they, they're so
Speaker 5:  ineffectual and they're so small and tiny. They are increasing
Speaker 5:  the price of Xbox Game Pass and the Xbox Series
Speaker 5:  X, not in the United States, been in a whole bunch of other places, including
Speaker 5:  the uk. So naturally our, our resident Britt
Speaker 5:  Tom Warren wrote all about it. The price is going up a little bit for the
Speaker 5:  Xbox Series X and then it's about a dollar for
Speaker 5:  Game Pass. It's kind of weird because how they're changing the prices.
Speaker 5:  So if you have never subscribed to Xbox Game Pass, you've
Speaker 5:  gotta do it before July 6th to like avoid
Speaker 5:  the, the price hike immediately. That's when the price hike goes in for new
Speaker 5:  customers. And then if you're a current customer, you don't have to deal
Speaker 5:  with the price hike until August 13th. And people are kind of upset. They're
Speaker 5:  a little bummed. But Microsoft is in telegraphing this for
Speaker 5:  a while now. Yeah. And this is all happening the exact same week that they
Speaker 5:  are going to court with the F T C over whether or not they can acquire Activision.
Speaker 5:  And part of that fight is that they have to say that they suck and that
Speaker 5:  they should totally be allowed to buy this company because they're
Speaker 5:  terrible and they suck and, and they're the worst in the world. And so they
Speaker 5:  said that they were lost the cons wars, which I think is a
Speaker 5:  massive, massive thing to drop into a legal dock. Even
Speaker 5:  if it's like just to win a fight. I feel like that's gonna
Speaker 5:  have some lasting impact for the company.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. We'll see what happens in this trial.
Speaker 5:  It's, yeah, it's ongoing. It's like five days. Yeah. Today was day one.
Speaker 5:  Tom has been covering all of it. There's a really great stream. You should
Speaker 5:  totally go watch it, read it. 'cause he's just giving minute by minute updates
Speaker 5:  and it's, it's wild. But for the most part they're, they are really aggressively
Speaker 5:  being like, we suck the most.
Speaker 4:  We're just babies. Yeah. We've lost the console battle. Yeah. I don't know
Speaker 4:  how this is gonna shake out. You know, obviously there's this trial, it'll
Speaker 4:  go one way or another. There's in the UK the
Speaker 4:  competition Markets authority there has already said no dice. Yep. It feels
Speaker 4:  like Microsoft should walk away. It
Speaker 5:  It does. It's a little perplexing that they keep going for it. 'cause
Speaker 5:  it seems like it's not gonna work in a lot of places. And how does that work?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Do you just stop operating in those countries when they say no, you
Speaker 5:  can't acquire it here? Like, do you make a ton of little splinter companies?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It's just messy. And, but I think both sides really want this
Speaker 5:  to happen. They want it to happen because they've been on a buying spree
Speaker 5:  for the last few years buying every single gaming company. So they want it
Speaker 5:  to happen. And then Activision wants it to happen because everybody hates
Speaker 5:  Activision.
Speaker 4:  They would like to stop being Activision. Yeah. Although they
Speaker 6:  Get $3 billion if the deal falls apart. So it's a That's true. It's a good
Speaker 6:  spot to be in for Activision. Either way,
Speaker 4:  I would just remind everyone, I'm not saying this is the same at all, but
Speaker 4:  remember what at t was gonna buy T-Mobile, do you remember this? And the
Speaker 4:  government stopped it. It's a real thing that happened. And T-Mobile walked
Speaker 4:  away with a breakup fee and then became T-Mobile
Speaker 5:  And then bought Sprint
Speaker 4:  Less good. Remember when our nation had four wireless carriers and now we're
Speaker 4:  down to three in Dish Network? Different times.
Speaker 4:  A little competition goes a long way. All right, David, what's your landing
Speaker 4:  round?
Speaker 6:  Mine's very quick. 'cause both the all just took forever, which is just that
Speaker 6:  the TikTok C E O of v Pappas is leaving the company, which is a big deal
Speaker 6:  because they are kind of the American figurehead
Speaker 6:  of TikTok for a minute it was Kevin Mayer who was gonna be the
Speaker 6:  American figurehead. That was a hilarious disaster. He
Speaker 6:  basically like took one look around the room and was like, nevermind. And
Speaker 6:  so v has been the COO and the, the c e o had,
Speaker 6:  shuchu has been more visible in recent months, but
Speaker 6:  v leaving is a, is a big deal. and I think continues to be
Speaker 6:  more and more evidence that TikTok is not going to get its way and
Speaker 6:  be a happy company in the United States for very long. I cannot
Speaker 6:  imagine being the like American symbol of TikTok is a
Speaker 6:  particularly fun job. And so I'm not super shocked, but it is yet another
Speaker 6:  bad sign if you're a person watching to see how TikTok fairs in the United States.
Speaker 4:  So TikTok, c e o showed Chu sent an email to the company saying V Poppas
Speaker 4:  was leaving. And then the spin is, don't worry, we've
Speaker 4:  hired 20 year Disney Zenia MUA to
Speaker 4:  join the company in the new role of TOS Chief brand and Communications officer.
Speaker 4:  Which
Speaker 6:  Is not the same thing.
Speaker 5:  Not very different.
Speaker 4:  And you can, it's like where's the challenge? The challenge is talking about
Speaker 4:  what TikTok is to a bunch of senators. Yeah. Not operating
Speaker 4:  TikTok rough. Yeah. Yeah. We're gonna try to get all these people at the
Speaker 4:  Code conference, by the way. Including our friend Steve Huffman.
Speaker 6:  There you
Speaker 4:  Go. He can correct us in person. But I, I agree with you, David. I think
Speaker 4:  the, the, the signs are ominous. I would say around TikTok right now.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Agreed. The vibes
Speaker 4:  Are bad. I don't think Project Texas is gonna go, we're
Speaker 6:  About to hit a presidential campaign and I think this is about to flare up
Speaker 6:  again in a pretty big way. and I suspect v among other people saw
Speaker 6:  the writing on the wall on that one.
Speaker 4:  One last lightning round. I wanna end on a high note. Okay. DP review.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Got purchased by Gear Patrol. Yeah, it's gonna live.
Speaker 4:  That's good. And we, we, I, we love that site. We love the work they
Speaker 4:  do. I'm very happy about that weird, weird behavior from Amazon trying to
Speaker 4:  shut it down before selling it for what I assume is just like nothing to
Speaker 4:  Gear Patrol, which is happy to take it in the right home for it. But
Speaker 4:  good, it's
Speaker 6:  Good. DP review is great. If you are a camera nerd, it's probably already
Speaker 6:  your favorite website. If you're not a camera nerd, go and you will become
Speaker 6:  a camera nerd. You will.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I'll get that Rico one day. Yeah. PR three. Ooh.
Speaker 4:  It's pretty, it's
Speaker 5:  So pretty.
Speaker 4:  Alright, we're gonna go and shop for cameras. That's it. That's The Vergecast
Speaker 4:  Wednesday. Like I said, we'll have full coverage of this Microsoft trial
Speaker 4:  that has literally been going on in the background while we're taping. There's
Speaker 4:  a live stream on the site. Tom has been covering it like as it goes.
Speaker 4:  We'll have lots of analysis that's all happening. Look at the site. The Verge
Speaker 4:  dot com. If you don't remember what it is, you are this far into the Vergecast
Speaker 4:  You know, that's The Verge sh com. It's a good one. I dunno what you're doing.
Speaker 4:  Also, we have gotten a number of submissions to our wearables equation.
Speaker 4:  We're gonna get into that next week. Right? They're very good. We're, we're
Speaker 4:  gonna lay 'em all out. We, we have to do some algebra, so we're gonna figure
Speaker 4:  out how to do algebra on this podcast.
Speaker 6:  Just imagine that scene from a Beautiful Mind. That's gonna be us next
Speaker 6:  week.
Speaker 4:  It's great. I love those submissions. If you have 'em, keep it ver Vergecast
Speaker 4:  at The Verge dot com. Email us your wearable equation submissions. It's been
Speaker 4:  fun to read them all. We'll get into it next week. Alright, that's it. That's
Speaker 4:  Vergecast. Bye.
Speaker 12:  And that's a wrap for Vergecast this week. We'd love to hear from you. Shoot
Speaker 12:  us an email at Vergecast at The Verge dot com. The Vergecast is a
Speaker 12:  production of The Verge and the Vox Media Podcast Network. The show is produced
Speaker 12:  by me, Liam James, and our senior audio director, Andrew Marino. Our
Speaker 12:  editorial director is Brooke Miners. That's it. We'll see you next week.
Speaker 2:  Support for this show came from a W SS machine learning
Speaker 2:  cloud computing generative ai. Things are changing
Speaker 2:  and they're changing fast. It can be hard to keep up with cutting edge
Speaker 2:  technologies, let alone knowing how to use them effectively.
Speaker 2:  Amazon Web Services may be able to help. They make it easy for
Speaker 2:  businesses of any size to identify opportunities that generative AI
Speaker 2:  and machine learning offer and provide a proven framework for
Speaker 2:  best practices. All with customer support. For any technical
Speaker 2:  and non-technical questions you might have. Just imagine how
Speaker 2:  A W Ss can transform your business. learn more at
Speaker 2:  AWS is how.com.