# Transcript
ID: e0586634-a8f2-4f8f-a9b9-227a41997d32
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: How Tesla became the Elon Musk Co. from Land of the Giants
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-4687440734520484658/8125631771838941398/s93290-US-2494s-1691575366.mp3
Description: Today we're sharing an episode of Land of the Giants: The Tesla Shock Wave
Not many people can name the original founders of Tesla. So how did two guys who wanted to build an electric car create a company synonymous with Elon Musk?
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (3 ads detected)
Speaker 3:  Hollywood writers and actors are still striking and one of the things
Speaker 3:  they're fighting against is AI swooping in and taking their
Speaker 3:  jobs. But truth is AI is already
Speaker 3:  all over Hollywood.
Speaker 4:  You know, Harrison Ford has come out and said that
Speaker 4:  he not only is okay with the de aging process
Speaker 4:  that was used in the most recent Indiana Jones, but he thought it was skillfully
Speaker 4:  done.
Speaker 3:  The fight over AI in TV and film. This week
Speaker 3:  on Intuit Vultures Pop culture
Speaker 3:  podcast,
Speaker 5:  Welcome to The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of corporate and fighting.
Speaker 5:  I'm your friend David Pierce and in lieu of our normal Wednesday episode
Speaker 5:  this week, I wanna play you an episode of Land of the Giants. It's
Speaker 5:  another podcast on the Vox Media podcast network. It's one of our favorite
Speaker 5:  shows and if you like The Vergecast, I'm pretty confident you
Speaker 5:  will love Land of the Giants. We've done series on Facebook, we've done
Speaker 5:  series on dating apps, we've done series on Netflix, and the current one
Speaker 5:  is all about Tesla. And this episode, the one I wanna play you is the second
Speaker 5:  episode in the new season. You can go subscribe to Land of the Giants and
Speaker 5:  listen to the first episode, but you actually don't need to have heard it
Speaker 5:  for this episode to work. This episode is really all about
Speaker 5:  Elon Musk as a leader, what he learned from being booted out of PayPal,
Speaker 5:  how he took over Tesla from its founders and how he turned
Speaker 5:  Tesla the company and Elon Musk the c e o
Speaker 5:  into very much the same thing. The big open question in this episode
Speaker 5:  is so fascinating to me, basically, is Elon Musk
Speaker 5:  a megalomaniac above all else? Who would do anything to be
Speaker 5:  more famous and more powerful? Or did he believe in the
Speaker 5:  mission of Tesla and wanna save the planet above all else and do what
Speaker 5:  was required to get there? It's hard to know for sure. I'm not sure we'll
Speaker 5:  ever know for sure, but I really think it matters given how much
Speaker 5:  this guy is at the center of business and culture right now. There's
Speaker 5:  also this underlying story here about what you might call the
Speaker 5:  Elon Musk cinematic universe and how the stories of PayPal
Speaker 5:  and SpaceX and Tesla and Twitter all actually
Speaker 5:  inform one another. You could make a really compelling case that
Speaker 5:  Tesla wouldn't have become Tesla if Twitter didn't exist, for
Speaker 5:  instance, and that if Musk had never run Tesla, he might never
Speaker 5:  have bought Twitter. It's fascinating. Anyway, this episode is great. This
Speaker 5:  series has been great. There are a bunch of Verge voices here. You're gonna
Speaker 5:  hear Liz Lipato and Andy Hawkins. Even my cohost Neli Patel has
Speaker 5:  been in the series. It's great. I can't recommend it highly enough. I really
Speaker 5:  think you'll love this episode and this whole series of land of the Giants.
Speaker 5:  You can subscribe to Land of the Giants anywhere you get podcasts. Wherever
Speaker 5:  you're listening to this, I suspect you will also be able to find Land of
Speaker 5:  the Giants. Anyway, thank you as always for listening to The Vergecast. We'll
Speaker 5:  be back on Friday with our regular news show and back next week with some
Speaker 5:  fun new stuff. In the meantime, here's Land of the Giants.
Speaker 3:  The year 2000 was a crazy good year for Elon
Speaker 3:  Musk. He was the c e o of an exciting new startup, a company
Speaker 3:  that promised to disrupt a fundamental part of daily life, how you
Speaker 3:  pay for things with
Speaker 6:  PayPal, you can pay for anything, anytime, anywhere.
Speaker 3:  A brand new company that was the result of a merger between Musk's online
Speaker 3:  bank and a payments company co-founded by a guy named Peter
Speaker 3:  Teel. Musk and Teal looked like a dream team on
Speaker 3:  paper, two Silicon Valley rising stars with one vision
Speaker 3:  blow up the banking world. Musk even felt confident enough as c e
Speaker 3:  o to take a quick break.
Speaker 7:  I've gotten married earlier that year and not had any vacation or honeymoon
Speaker 7:  or anything.
Speaker 3:  Turns out he was a little too confident 'cause Musk's honeymoon
Speaker 3:  period at PayPal was already over.
Speaker 7:  I think it's not a good idea to leave the office when
Speaker 7:  there are like a lot of major things underway, which are causing
Speaker 7:  people a great deal of stress.
Speaker 8:  Elon went on his honeymoon and they did a coup and forced him
Speaker 8:  out.
Speaker 3:  Liz Lipato has covered Musk for years at The. Verge. Musk may have
Speaker 3:  been the c e O of PayPal, but Teal had installed guys from his former
Speaker 3:  company in most of the other C-Suite slots. The moment Musk was
Speaker 3:  outta sight, they persuaded PayPal's board to oust him and
Speaker 3:  replace him with none other than Peter Thiel.
Speaker 7:  There was just a lot of worry and that caused the management
Speaker 7:  team to decide that I wasn't the right guy to run the company.
Speaker 3:  Another way to look at this coup is that Musk was never really in control
Speaker 3:  of PayPal. Even with that c e o title, teal was the
Speaker 3:  one who held all the cards. Lesson learned
Speaker 8:  Elon Musk is very much about Elon Musk and there's like a real
Speaker 8:  need for control that shows up in
Speaker 8:  his companies where he needs to be in charge all of the time. Having
Speaker 8:  learned from PayPal that if he didn't create that situation, he
Speaker 8:  could potentially be fired.
Speaker 3:  But after PayPal, Musk had no company to control licking his
Speaker 3:  wounds, he started looking around for something different.
Speaker 7:  On a personal level, At this point, I would say I'm a little tired of the
Speaker 7:  internet. The next company that I do, one of the things that I think would
Speaker 7:  be important is that it has some long-term beneficial
Speaker 7:  effect.
Speaker 3:  A few years later, a couple of guys who were also excited about changing
Speaker 3:  the world came to to him with an idea and it was just what he was looking
Speaker 3:  for. A
Speaker 3:  fast, sporty electric car, Musk went all
Speaker 3:  in.
Speaker 3:  This is Land of the Giants. I'm Patrick George, your co-host this
Speaker 3:  season. I'm an automotive journalist. I've covered the industry for about
Speaker 3:  a decade, including as the editor-in-chief of Jalopnik and editorial director
Speaker 3:  of the Drive. And the whole time I've been covering cars, I can tell you
Speaker 3:  that nothing is quite defined. The modern car industry like the rise of
Speaker 3:  Tesla, but not many people remember, it
Speaker 3:  wasn't Musk's idea to start with today, the story of how Elon Musk
Speaker 3:  made Tesla his own and the perils of shaping a company in one zone
Speaker 3:  image
Speaker 3:  before Musk even arrived, there were two guys with a dream. In
Speaker 3:  2000, Martin Eberhardt had just sold his first startup developing
Speaker 3:  an early e-reader technology. He needed a new ride and he wanted to treat
Speaker 3:  himself a bit.
Speaker 9:  I was considering getting myself a new car and something fun and sporty.
Speaker 3:  He loved to drive fast cars, but a Porsche nine 11, a Ferrari
Speaker 3:  problem was those cars were terrible on gas.
Speaker 9:  To me, by 2001, climate change looked real. I, it
Speaker 9:  looked like it was a real deal.
Speaker 3:  So he looked around for something a little less like a carbon bomb, but the
Speaker 3:  options at the time were kind of sad.
Speaker 10:  Martin called these cars punishment cars designed by people
Speaker 10:  who really didn't believe you should be driving. This
Speaker 3:  Is Mark Tarting eberhardt's friend and business partner since the eighties.
Speaker 10:  You know, you should be riding your bike or taking public transit or walking,
Speaker 10:  but if you had to drive, you needed to be put into one of these things to
Speaker 10:  be punished.
Speaker 9:  That got mark's and my heads thinking
Speaker 9:  about that this was a a real opportunity. What
Speaker 3:  If there was an electric car that was fast, sleek and sexy for
Speaker 3:  people like Everhart rich dudes who like flashy toys?
Speaker 10:  When you look at the market there, turns out there's a segment that
Speaker 10:  is super into that and that's a sports car segment and the
Speaker 10:  faster you can get to, you know, zero to 60 miles per hour, the more
Speaker 10:  people are willing to pay. And if you can really get it close, people are
Speaker 10:  willing to pay almost an insane amount of money for it.
Speaker 3:  The guys wanted that kind of car and the money didn't sound bad either,
Speaker 3:  so they decided to do something audacious, start their own car
Speaker 3:  company. The first thing they needed to do was figure out how to power the
Speaker 3:  car. At the time, lithium ion batteries were mostly used for small things
Speaker 3:  like e-readers and laptops, but the guys knew these batteries could do
Speaker 3:  a lot more like power a car for a much greater distance on a single
Speaker 3:  charge than anyone had ever seen before. But just to make sure they
Speaker 3:  mocked up a sample battery and tested it out in a car and
Speaker 3:  it worked. But these were tech guys, they didn't know where to begin
Speaker 3:  with building the rest of the car. So they partnered with a small British
Speaker 3:  automaker named Lotus, A Lotus Body would house all the
Speaker 3:  cool EV tech these guys could come up with. The last
Speaker 3:  thing they needed was a name.
Speaker 9:  I had been out on a date with a woman who became my wife,
Speaker 9:  And I had been in the back of my head thinking about this company and thinking
Speaker 9:  about names and the idea of Tesla came to me. And I proposed that to her
Speaker 9:  and she loved it.
Speaker 3:  Okay, so they actually needed one more thing money. There
Speaker 9:  Were so many reasons not to invest in Tesla that there, we didn't exactly
Speaker 9:  have investors coming outta the woodwork wanting to invest in
Speaker 9:  us
Speaker 3:  For months. The payer were in and out of dozens of venture capital firms.
Speaker 10:  It was a pretty radical idea, you know, a new car
Speaker 10:  company,
Speaker 3:  Wall Street and VCs loathed the car industry. Cars were
Speaker 3:  expensive. Capital intensive products that required complicated supply chains
Speaker 3:  and enormous amounts of manual labor. Newcomers never succeeded.
Speaker 3:  And remember nobody was taking EVs seriously back then, but there
Speaker 3:  was one person with a lot of extra cash who was not easily daunted.
Speaker 10:  We got an intro to, to Elon.
Speaker 3:  Musk was into risk. I mean his other company was trying to
Speaker 3:  colonize Mars.
Speaker 9:  My initial presser of of him was he was quite smart and and quite
Speaker 9:  enthusiastic. He
Speaker 10:  Immediately got it. He was like, oh, I see he did all the math. I love
Speaker 10:  that, you know, I'm in and
Speaker 9:  I mean you wouldn't guess it by the things he said today. But at the time
Speaker 9:  it seemed really clear that he understood that that climate change was a
Speaker 9:  real problem.
Speaker 3:  When Musk made his first investment in Everhart and Targeting's company,
Speaker 3:  he was almost four years out from the sting of being ousted from PayPal and
Speaker 3:  on his way to establishing a reputation as a kind of tech maverick.
Speaker 8:  He had a very restless mind. And I think he found he had
Speaker 8:  a very big interest with the world
Speaker 8:  dying.
Speaker 3:  This is tech journalist Kara Swisher, who's been following Elon Musk since
Speaker 3:  the nineties.
Speaker 8:  That's why he was interested in space travel to get off this planet. He always
Speaker 8:  thought there should be a multi-planetary species. He was worried about the
Speaker 8:  end times, so that's why he focused on things like Tesla, which he
Speaker 8:  thought was existential to the human race
Speaker 3:  To Swisher. Musk was nothing like his peers. Everyone around him was building
Speaker 3:  online stores or primitive social networks and Musk was trying to save
Speaker 3:  the world. He
Speaker 8:  Could have made a lot more money, a lot easier doing other things and he
Speaker 8:  didn't. I think he was always motivated by making it the
Speaker 8:  impossible happen. I think he was still motivated by his feeling that
Speaker 8:  the earth was going to be destroyed and he was critical to
Speaker 8:  stopping that in some way.
Speaker 3:  Sounds great, but maybe a bit of a red flag too.
Speaker 8:  I think he had sort of a God complex. Only I can do it sounds like
Speaker 8:  Trump, right?
Speaker 3:  But as far as Eberhart and Tarponing were concerned, they had just gotten
Speaker 3:  their first check, six and a half million dollars as the
Speaker 3:  lead investor must became the chairman of the board and appointed his brother
Speaker 3:  and an old friend as directors. The founders took on executive
Speaker 3:  positions. Eberhart is c e o and Taring is C F O and VP of
Speaker 3:  engineering. With the new money coming in, they could finally hire people
Speaker 3:  to build their very first car, the Tesla Roadster.
Speaker 3:  Dave Lyons is one of those early hires. He was an elite engineer and Tesla
Speaker 3:  wanted him to lead development.
Speaker 11:  I got brought into a back room and they said, Hey look, we're starting
Speaker 11:  this car company, it's gonna be huge. You're either with us or Guinness.
Speaker 11:  Martin Everhart is a very fast talking guy and he was pretty
Speaker 11:  charismatic, I have to say. And then there was this other quiet guy, Elon
Speaker 11:  in the corner who really didn't say anything.
Speaker 3:  Lyons didn't know if electric cars had much of a future, but the room was
Speaker 3:  full of energy and potential and he knew a little bit about that quiet guy
Speaker 3:  and his ambitions. So he was intrigued.
Speaker 11:  Well, this guy's got a rocket company and, and he's saying this was gonna
Speaker 11:  take off. So I mean that pitch sold pretty well to
Speaker 11:  me.
Speaker 3:  Lyons became employee number 12, but Tesla would need a whole lot more people
Speaker 3:  like him before he could make anything, let alone a brand new kind of electric
Speaker 3:  car. Musk had faced this challenge before at SpaceX and he
Speaker 3:  had developed a sort of recruitment philosophy that seemed to work.
Speaker 11:  I remember one day he told us about his kind of, you know, his
Speaker 11:  view of the world where like all these companies are all bound up by all
Speaker 11:  this regulatory mess and they don't get to do the good ideas and the
Speaker 11:  young engineers that are working at these aerospace companies, they're,
Speaker 11:  you know, kinda low men on the totem pole with all these
Speaker 11:  older moon launch era managers
Speaker 11:  who kind of tell 'em what they can't do all the time. And he was saying,
Speaker 11:  I like what I wanna do is I'm gonna hire all those e energetic smart guys
Speaker 11:  and give 'em freedom to soar.
Speaker 3:  There were lessons here for Tesla. SpaceX plucked young, bright engineers
Speaker 3:  out of government jobs and gave them the freedom to innovate. Tesla
Speaker 3:  could do something similar, attract the most dynamic talent from the old
Speaker 3:  rigid auto companies with promises of creative empowerment and
Speaker 3:  equity for the next few years. The whole company was
Speaker 3:  focused on one goal launching the Roadster, the car that would announce Tesla
Speaker 3:  to the world that day finally came in July,
Speaker 3:  2006.
Speaker 12:  This is one of the great cars Tesla Roadster electric car that gets
Speaker 12:  250 miles per charge.
Speaker 3:  And of course the birthday party for a flashy sports car had a celebrity
Speaker 3:  guest list, including California's governor at the time. Arnold
Speaker 3:  Schwarzenegger, a
Speaker 12:  Tester of this one. It's hot,
Speaker 3:  White, hot, the Roadster was tear your face off
Speaker 3:  Quick. Eberhart as c e o
Speaker 3:  took the lead on planning the Roadster's public debut. He hired a publicist
Speaker 3:  to help out.
Speaker 9:  She's the one who put together the basic idea of what that launch event would
Speaker 9:  look like from the idea of having it at an airport and having a track
Speaker 9:  outside where people could drive to having the event held in a giant
Speaker 9:  tent where the track actually came in and people could see these cars coming
Speaker 9:  and going and, and line up and go for a ride. All of this, this, this was
Speaker 9:  basically her idea.
Speaker 3:  This wasn't just the debut of the Roadster prototype, it was also the debut
Speaker 3:  of Tesla. I
Speaker 9:  Went to show this idea to Elon down in, in LA
Speaker 9:  and he basically had me fire her on the spot.
Speaker 3:  Eberhard was taken aback. It was the first time Musk had ever done something
Speaker 3:  like this, reach into Eberhardt's company and demands someone be
Speaker 3:  fired. But Musk was adamant. Eberhard realized if he
Speaker 3:  wanted to, Musk could take it to the board and that was a fight he would've
Speaker 3:  lost. Over the previous two years, Musk had remained the lead funder
Speaker 3:  allowing him to stack the board with guy's loyal to himself. Not everyone
Speaker 3:  was a Musk guy, but the math didn't look good. So Everhard did what he
Speaker 3:  was told,
Speaker 9:  Which was heartbreaking for me. And then he hired his
Speaker 9:  own team of people to, to produce exactly the party that
Speaker 9:  she had had laid out. Exactly. So I, I didn't understand what that was about.
Speaker 9:  It was very strange.
Speaker 3:  Now, Everhard didn't always fold on key decisions, especially when it came
Speaker 3:  to building the cars, but he could see that this moment Tesla's
Speaker 3:  debut was very important to Musk. It was Tesla's
Speaker 3:  first big splash, the reveal of its first car and Musk seemed
Speaker 3:  Like. he had to be out in front there to take credit and absorb the limelight
Speaker 3:  as the face of the company.
Speaker 7:  The opportunity is is now and and the need is now to have a Co company
Speaker 7:  of this, of this nature.
Speaker 3:  Everhart says Musk became sort of obsessed with this idea. He remembers when
Speaker 3:  the New York Times first wrote about Tesla, it left out any reference to
Speaker 3:  Musk and he was furious. By the way, we've reached out
Speaker 3:  to Elon, Musk and Tesla about this and other stuff we never heard
Speaker 3:  back. It's worth noting that Tesla doesn't even have someone who handles
Speaker 3:  media requests anymore. Anyways, Musk had inserted himself into the
Speaker 3:  process of making the car as well. Small stuff mostly.
Speaker 9:  There were a lot of little sort of random interventions that he would come
Speaker 9:  in and say, I want this change or whatever, like
Speaker 3:  Door handles. He was determined that the doors on the Roadster should not
Speaker 3:  open with a handle, but with a button.
Speaker 9:  The motorized door handles on the Roadster, you know, they're
Speaker 9:  cool, but they were also quite tricky to get right
Speaker 9:  because the door latches on a car, have to work correctly even after it's
Speaker 9:  crashed. And if the power goes out, then how does the electric thing work?
Speaker 9:  And we, we wound up spending some number of millions of dollars to
Speaker 9:  get that to work right, and to get it to to, to pass the side impact crash
Speaker 9:  test.
Speaker 3:  And it wasn't just door handles. Must decree, the seats weren't comfortable
Speaker 3:  and the doorframe needed adjustments and the headlights didn't look cool
Speaker 3:  enough. Meanwhile, the company had much bigger
Speaker 3:  problems than door handles. And it wasn't due to Musk's medley
Speaker 9:  That was over budget and and behind schedule on the
Speaker 9:  project.
Speaker 3:  Sourcing parts for a tiny car startup and an electric one no less was
Speaker 3:  extremely difficult. Suppliers were reluctant to sell just a few parts to
Speaker 3:  a small company that might not even exist within a year. But also
Speaker 3:  things like heating or air conditioning that played nice with Ev tech. There
Speaker 3:  was almost no demand for these parts. So they weren't widely available. You
Speaker 3:  couldn't just put in an order and expect a shipment.
Speaker 9:  If you could ask me what was the thing that was the most surprising to me,
Speaker 9:  the thing I was not expecting that was how hard was the supply chain problem
Speaker 9:  I had. I just, I just didn't, didn't expect it to be that difficult.
Speaker 3:  They were a whole year behind schedule and the car was shaping up to cost
Speaker 3:  way more to produce than they had ever planned to sell it for.
Speaker 9:  It was getting to be clear that I was maybe
Speaker 9:  not the right guy to be the c e o for the company for a long time to
Speaker 9:  myself.
Speaker 3:  So Eberhard began the search for his replacement, which was fine. He looked
Speaker 3:  forward to working on something else At Tesla,
Speaker 9:  I would've taken a role of, as you know, C T O or vice president
Speaker 9:  of whatever, blah. Anyways, but someplace where I'm spending most of my time
Speaker 9:  working on the technology or on evangelizing the company, that was,
Speaker 9:  that was what I imagined. That's what we, what we had discussed with the
Speaker 9:  board of directors.
Speaker 3:  But Musk had something else in mind. A few months into the search for
Speaker 3:  a new c e o, Eberhard got a call from Musk. He'd found someone who
Speaker 3:  might work as Eberhardt's replacement.
Speaker 9:  He came across as though this is a friendly suggestion. After
Speaker 3:  All, it was Eberhard who was leading his own replacement effort. This was
Speaker 3:  just a suggestion, right?
Speaker 9:  And then I learned basically the next day through email that the board had
Speaker 9:  basically voted me off the island.
Speaker 3:  Eberhard was out as c e o Musk's Pick was in
Speaker 3:  Eberhardt's own search for a new c e o looked like kind of a
Speaker 3:  sham, and the assurance that he'd always have a role at Tesla was now totally
Speaker 3:  in question.
Speaker 9:  It felt like a brick on the side of my head. I
Speaker 9:  felt it felt like I got hit on the side of my head with a brick. It was totally
Speaker 9:  unexpected
Speaker 3:  And there was nothing he could do about it. The company that had sprung from
Speaker 3:  Eberhardt's desire to drive a better sports car was now completely out of
Speaker 3:  his control.
Speaker 9:  Keep in mind, who was on the board of directors? It was Elon, right? It was
Speaker 9:  his brother. Okay. He's kind of aligned. It was Antonio Rossius, who was
Speaker 9:  an old buddy of his, who had made a lot of money off of previous investments
Speaker 9:  with Elon.
Speaker 3:  Musk controlled half the board. Eberhard says he asked for the board to vote
Speaker 3:  again this time with him, present the result, a
Speaker 3:  demotion to the made up role of president of technology. No one
Speaker 3:  reporting to him, no responsibilities. But even that wouldn't last very
Speaker 3:  long.
Speaker 9:  I was asked to resign. Well, for me it was,
Speaker 9:  it was, it was really sad. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  His co-founder, mark Tarting, left shortly after that.
Speaker 3:  If Everhart sounds a little muted, it's because he has to be. He sued
Speaker 3:  Musk and Tesla claiming liable defamation, breach of contract,
Speaker 3:  infliction of emotional distress, and failure to pay his wages. Among other
Speaker 3:  things. The lawsuit was settled out of court.
Speaker 9:  I have a mutual non-disparagement agreement signed with Musk,
Speaker 9:  and although he's been flagrantly violating that agreement
Speaker 9:  over and over and over again, he's also the richest man in the
Speaker 9:  world and if he decides to crush me with lawsuits, I can't survive it.
Speaker 3:  Tesla's founders were out. Musk had personally picked a new c e
Speaker 3:  o, but really by then he was running the show. There
Speaker 11:  Was a new sheriff in town, no doubt about that, and he
Speaker 11:  was quite drastic,
Speaker 3:  But even that wasn't quite
Speaker 3:  enough
Speaker 3:  coming up how Elon. Musk made Tesla synonymous with Elon.
Speaker 3:  Musk
Speaker 13:  Okay. Okay.
Speaker 3:  Wolves and dogs are pretty closely related. They actually
Speaker 3:  share 99.9% of their genetics
Speaker 14:  Yo sniffles,
Speaker 3:  But even when they're just a few months old, even when they're raised by
Speaker 3:  human scientists, wolves are pretty different from dogs.
Speaker 14:  They start biting you in the ears when you find down. If you don't
Speaker 14:  sit up fast enough and you hear this wonderful noise, these
Speaker 14:  little, and then they chomp you in the air and you're like,
Speaker 14:  oh.
Speaker 3:  And when they grow up, these differences get even
Speaker 3:  bigger. Dogs are our friends.
Speaker 3:  Wolves are hunters.
Speaker 14:  If I had a sore shoulder, I wouldn't go in with the
Speaker 14:  adult wolves, even if I had raised them because it could trigger their hunting
Speaker 14:  behavior.
Speaker 3:  This week on unexplainable, how did we get the nice friendly dogs
Speaker 3:  we know and love today from wolves? Follow
Speaker 3:  unexplainable wherever you listen for new episodes every
Speaker 3:  Wednesday.
Speaker 15:  A moment from American Idol recently went viral in which
Speaker 15:  one of the show's contestants got under Judge Katy Perry's
Speaker 15:  skin with the way she sang, slurring her words
Speaker 15:  together, dropping whole consonants, playing with vowels like they
Speaker 15:  were silly putty annunciate. Perry begged the
Speaker 15:  contestant. This exchange likely went viral because it
Speaker 15:  crystallized a vocal phenomenon in pop music that has as
Speaker 15:  many supporters as it does detractors. Like Perry. The style
Speaker 15:  has been dubbed cursive singing because of the way it
Speaker 15:  smoothly blurs lyrics together like the penmanship technique and it
Speaker 15:  can be heard in hits from stars like Selena Gomez and
Speaker 15:  Sean Mendes. I'm musicologist Nate Sloan, co-host of the Vulture
Speaker 15:  Music podcast Switched on pop, and on this week's episode, we are
Speaker 15:  diving deep into the techniques and the origins behind
Speaker 15:  this marble mouthed vocal fad To better understand
Speaker 15:  where cursive singing came from, why it's so
Speaker 15:  divisive, and whether this style is here to
Speaker 15:  stay.
Speaker 16:  Watch me take off.
Speaker 3:  Tesla started delivering the Roadster in 2008. Late night legend and
Speaker 3:  famous car guy Jay Leno. Got to test drive one and he was an instant fan.
Speaker 18:  You know, the thing that's fascinated me about this car is you've eliminated
Speaker 18:  all the negatives of an electric cuck. A lot of times
Speaker 3:  Tesla proved it can make an EV that didn't feel like a punishment car. The
Speaker 3:  Roadster cost as much as a Porsche nine 11, but it could keep up with one
Speaker 3:  too, and it didn't use gasoline. The founders were
Speaker 3:  gone, but their dream had become a reality and Tesla's engineering team
Speaker 3:  was primed to work on the next challenge.
Speaker 11:  And all the engineers, not just some of the engineers, all the
Speaker 11:  engineers wanted to work on the cool new high volume
Speaker 11:  project.
Speaker 3:  They knew exactly what it would be. A luxury sedan. The
Speaker 3:  model Ss. This was the plan going back to Eberhardt and Tarpon's
Speaker 3:  original business proposal. The team was ready to go, but their timing could
Speaker 3:  not have been worse.
Speaker 19:  The economy went into absolute free fall.
Speaker 3:  That's Rachel Conrad, who was the only person on Tesla's PR team. As the
Speaker 3:  company faced the Great Recession.
Speaker 19:  This was the peak. Lehman Brothers liquidity
Speaker 19:  freeze. Both General Motors and
Speaker 19:  Chrysler declared bankruptcy. This was called
Speaker 19:  Carmageddon, right? It was literally the worst
Speaker 19:  downfall in the auto industry for a couple of
Speaker 19:  generations.
Speaker 3:  This is no exaggeration. Analysts at the time fully expected at least one
Speaker 3:  of the big three American automakers to go out of business At. this
Speaker 3:  point, Musk's handpicked replacement for Everhart had already bounced, another,
Speaker 3:  followed, but didn't last long either. Ultimately, Musk looked around and
Speaker 3:  decided the crown belonged on his own head. He named
Speaker 3:  himself c e o
Speaker 19:  In December of 2008. Tesla literally had
Speaker 19:  one day of cash runway before they would have to enter the
Speaker 19:  zone of insolvency and they would just flame out.
Speaker 3:  It was a kingdom in trouble still. Tesla closed out the year with a holiday
Speaker 3:  party.
Speaker 19:  We could not rent a place. We didn't even have a caterer. We literally
Speaker 19:  set up tables in the
Speaker 19:  Tesla garage in Menlo Park.
Speaker 3:  So there they were sitting in some folding chairs in front of a hydraulic
Speaker 3:  lift, drinking cheap wine and wondering if the company would last another
Speaker 3:  day.
Speaker 19:  And Elon stands on a table
Speaker 19:  literally and says,
Speaker 19:  guys, we just shifted in
Speaker 19:  America from having a Texas oil man
Speaker 19:  who was president to an
Speaker 19:  environmentalist named Barack Obama, who has
Speaker 19:  vowed not to just help the auto industry at large, but
Speaker 19:  to specifically accelerate the shift to
Speaker 19:  electrification. If you can't
Speaker 19:  see the opportunity in that, you are not looking.
Speaker 3:  This story about Musk feels like a freeze frame in a movie. The moment
Speaker 3:  before the man is made, well, before Musk becomes the richest person on the
Speaker 3:  planet before he even becomes famous, before he gets a
Speaker 3:  Twitter account with tweets that move markets in this
Speaker 3:  moment, he's just trying to move people enough to stay in their
Speaker 3:  jobs. For Conrad, who'd been on the job just a few months, it
Speaker 3:  was a moment of clarity. Musk made it seem like anything was possible.
Speaker 3:  He seemed brilliant, he had a vision, he was in
Speaker 3:  control,
Speaker 19:  And the way he said it was so fucking
Speaker 19:  powerful that everyone in there, he had
Speaker 19:  us all like none of us were about to abandon ship.
Speaker 19:  At that moment.
Speaker 3:  Musk kept Tesla float by injecting his own money in the company.
Speaker 20:  My salary is minimum wage, you know, so I'm a
Speaker 20:  volunteer. Basically,
Speaker 3:  He was even writing personal checks to cover payroll and charging work expenses
Speaker 3:  to his credit card.
Speaker 19:  The doors of Sandhill Road, the epicenter of the global venture
Speaker 19:  capital industry were bolted shut.
Speaker 19:  Okay? Nobody would give Elon a
Speaker 19:  penny. Elon Musk, the most brilliant technologist who
Speaker 19:  ever lived, right? The one who all VCs kiss his ass.
Speaker 19:  Now, none of them would give him a penny.
Speaker 3:  Around that same time, he found another audience, one that was willing to
Speaker 3:  listen. He got a Twitter account
Speaker 19:  Almost immediately because of his
Speaker 19:  history with PayPal, et cetera. He, he
Speaker 19:  had a bit of a following.
Speaker 3:  He didn't tweet much at first. Updates about his companies recommending books.
Speaker 3:  He liked
Speaker 19:  To be able to harness very, very low cost
Speaker 19:  channels to talk directly to consumers,
Speaker 19:  policymakers, regulators, thought leaders, media, et
Speaker 19:  cetera is very high leverage.
Speaker 3:  Twitter offered Musk something that couldn't be bought.
Speaker 8:  I think Musk's insight was that he didn't just need to
Speaker 8:  speak to media. He could also speak directly to his audience
Speaker 8:  through social media.
Speaker 3:  Here's Liz Lipato from The Verge again.
Speaker 8:  And that creates the kind of direct
Speaker 8:  relationship that all of
Speaker 8:  the news interviews in the world can't
Speaker 8:  create. Because Elon Musk reads
Speaker 8:  his replies
Speaker 3:  Musk's Twitter, like no other c e o at the time. He didn't consult his publicist
Speaker 3:  to craft each tweet or hold focus groups on how to engage with his followers.
Speaker 3:  He shot from the hip and said what was on his mind.
Speaker 8:  There was a kind of un guardedness there that I think people are really related
Speaker 8:  to, and it creates a kind of closeness. Musk very much
Speaker 8:  became a star of the social media age by being
Speaker 8:  available.
Speaker 3:  So in public, Musk was cultivating a fan base for himself, lapping up all
Speaker 3:  the credit for this ambitious new car company. The
Speaker 18:  Man behind the whole project is here. Elon, Musk, Elon, come on in here.
Speaker 18:  How you doing?
Speaker 21:  So clearly you have many aspirations and an overwhelming
Speaker 21:  drive to innovate.
Speaker 22:  You are establishing a presence, certainly with Tesla
Speaker 22:  Motors, this electric car company.
Speaker 3:  He had proven to be just as persuasive in private. Musk, got some of those
Speaker 3:  reluctant investors to loosen up and he got enough cash to prevent bankruptcy.
Speaker 3:  The government also came through with a half billion dollar loan to flow
Speaker 3:  Tesla through the collapse. And then the company raised even more money by
Speaker 3:  going public. In 2010, Musk had managed to save the
Speaker 3:  company, and in 2012, Tesla released a new model.
Speaker 23:  This is a historic automobile. At a historic
Speaker 23:  time,
Speaker 3:  There was nothing else. Like the model Ss on the market. Tesla
Speaker 24:  Definitely was making waves.
Speaker 3:  Christina Raw joined Tesla's PR team to help launch the model Ss.
Speaker 24:  And so more and more coverage on Tesla, more and more
Speaker 24:  curiosity, much desire to get a peek under the hood.
Speaker 24:  And in parallel, Elon was starting to use Twitter more and
Speaker 24:  more.
Speaker 3:  Musk's tweets became the thing to watch for all things Tesla. He'd make
Speaker 3:  surprise announcements about new features or updates to the cars. Sometimes
Speaker 3:  in a reply to another user, it was chaotic, unpredictable, and
Speaker 3:  captivating.
Speaker 24:  There was definitely something that happened in those early
Speaker 24:  years that has continued, I think on to today,
Speaker 24:  where his accessibility created
Speaker 24:  more interest in the products.
Speaker 3:  Plenty of cars have avid fan bases, Ford, Mustangs, Jeep
Speaker 3:  Wranglers, even the humble Volkswagen Beetle. But the people in the C-suite
Speaker 3:  rarely get the same love their products get. Musk was different. He
Speaker 3:  made Tesla feel like a movement, and he was the leader of that
Speaker 3:  movement.
Speaker 24:  I think there was a phenomenon happening where people learned more about
Speaker 24:  Tesla and SpaceX, but really this person behind
Speaker 24:  them whom they found fascinating
Speaker 24:  and really attributed the products and the company's
Speaker 24:  successes to, and they became sort of Elon believers.
Speaker 3:  If Musk was the high priest prophesizing the future, then Twitter was where
Speaker 3:  he took people to church.
Speaker 25:  This guy's a real treat, and it took me a while to get him to come
Speaker 25:  here, but he's a really interesting entrepreneur,
Speaker 25:  very much a visionary. Many people think in space
Speaker 25:  and in cars and in all solar, solar, all kinds of things.
Speaker 25:  Elon Musk.
Speaker 3:  But everything worked towards cultivating a faith in him. Elon
Speaker 3:  Musk, that same faith we heard about from Rachel Conrad and
Speaker 3:  his believers were everywhere. They were the kids online forming
Speaker 3:  Elon, Musk fan groups. They were also deep pocketed investors.
Speaker 3:  Tesla had never made a profit as a company, but as Musk's believer,
Speaker 3:  count took off. So did Tesla's stock price.
Speaker 26:  If you look at Q one, Tesla grew about 1,700 and something
Speaker 26:  percent, and there's a lot of potential for this company
Speaker 26:  to continue to grow, and for the company itself to double and double and
Speaker 26:  double again.
Speaker 3:  Elon has been a big part in the investment in Tesla in the past, current
Speaker 3:  and future. This is Tesla investor, Ross Gerber, and what he's saying
Speaker 3:  is that his decision to invest in Tesla in 2014 was also a decision to
Speaker 3:  invest in Musk. It paid off pretty quickly for
Speaker 3:  us, and we were able to take profits off our original
Speaker 3:  investment pretty rapidly. Over the years, Musk's
Speaker 3:  followers were used to seeing a particular mix of his personality.
Speaker 8:  90% of him was really inspirational and aspirational,
Speaker 8:  and 10% was kind of a jerk.
Speaker 3:  And when he went into jerk mode, you never knew what you were gonna get.
Speaker 8:  His humor was a little juvenile for my taste, but I would say that about
Speaker 8:  three dozen people I cover and he more than others, like
Speaker 8:  memes. He thought it, things were hysterical that I didn't think were
Speaker 8:  hysterical.
Speaker 3:  One time a group of boys and their soccer coach had gotten trapped in a cave
Speaker 3:  in Thailand. A rescue diver was leading efforts to save them, and Musk
Speaker 3:  offered to build a submarine to help the diver called it a PR
Speaker 3:  stunt. He told Musk to quote, stick his submarine where it
Speaker 3:  hurts. So Musk hopped on Twitter to clap back.
Speaker 27:  You know what? Don't bother showing the video. We will make one of the mini
Speaker 27:  sub pod going all the way to K five. No promo. Sorry, pedo guy.
Speaker 27:  You really did ask for it. By the way, I'm not actually Elon Musk, I'm
Speaker 27:  an AI reading his tweets.
Speaker 3:  Did the c e o of a company just flippantly call a man a
Speaker 3:  pedophile? When another user pointed this out to him, Musk doubled
Speaker 3:  down. Bet
Speaker 27:  Your signed dollar. It's true.
Speaker 3:  The diver sued him for defamation, but Musk won the
Speaker 3:  lawsuit. Musk also got in trouble for his tweets about Tesla.
Speaker 3:  He once sent a series of coy, but confidence sounding tweets about taking
Speaker 3:  the company private. The s e c was not having it. It charged
Speaker 3:  him with securities fraud for essentially lying and misleading his shareholders.
Speaker 3:  So his Twitter feed was a mix, his special recipe of the provocative and
Speaker 3:  unfiltered.
Speaker 8:  What was problematic for me is that he started to become
Speaker 8:  sort of high on his own supply
Speaker 3:  For Swisher and many others. His tweets drifted more and more into topics
Speaker 3:  wholly unrelated to cars or space or tech. The meanness started
Speaker 3:  to take over. He started sharing conspiracy theories, promoting
Speaker 3:  anti-trans tropes and cozying up to far right-wing personalities.
Speaker 3:  If any other c e O did this stuff, they'd be strapped to a rocket and fired
Speaker 3:  into the sun. But a lot of his fans have been willing to overlook this
Speaker 3:  stuff because even if he was an asshole, he was still an aspirational
Speaker 3:  asshole. His companies were changing the world. He was literally the
Speaker 3:  richest person in the world, his brand, and by extension,
Speaker 3:  Tesla's brand was still pretty solid.
Speaker 8:  I think the Twitter acquisition was actually a really big turning point in
Speaker 8:  how people viewed Elon Musk.
Speaker 3:  Here's Liz Lipato again.
Speaker 8:  Sure, he was attention seeking and sure, he occasionally said like weird
Speaker 8:  stuff in public. But to discover his flaws as a businessman,
Speaker 8:  you actually needed to be paying pretty close attention to what was going
Speaker 8:  on at Tesla.
Speaker 3:  But buying Twitter read to just about everyone as a pretty massive
Speaker 3:  mistake. The purchase itself was a spectacular business.
Speaker 3:  Blunder. Musk offered to buy the company for way more than it was worth.
Speaker 3:  Tried to back out and then was basically forced by a court to finish the
Speaker 3:  deal
Speaker 8:  And then immediately like alienated a large percentage of the
Speaker 8:  advertisers and drove a bunch of users away and like sort of drove the
Speaker 8:  thing into the ground.
Speaker 3:  Twitter was bleeding value. This humiliation was being broadcast
Speaker 3:  everywhere, including on the platform that helped build his fandom, the one
Speaker 3:  he now owned. Those
Speaker 8:  Were not good business decisions that these things were being made
Speaker 8:  impulsively. These ideas were not
Speaker 8:  necessarily good, but there was no one around him to
Speaker 8:  say no to him.
Speaker 3:  It was complete chaos and it was Musk's fault. This
Speaker 3:  was almost a fun house mirror image of what happened after the Tesla founder
Speaker 3:  Red Wedding went down. Musk led a coup that essentially off
Speaker 3:  the founders, and then he ably steered the company through the financial
Speaker 3:  collapse. He took a tiny startup and made it into a real car
Speaker 3:  brand. He built his own brand on doing this kind of thing.
Speaker 3:  Now everyone was taking a hard look at the legend of Elon Musk. The
Speaker 8:  Rich liberals are like, what the fuck am I giving this guy money for? I have
Speaker 8:  dozens of my friends are like, I wanna get rid of my Tesla.
Speaker 3:  Ever since he bought Twitter, he's been obsessed with
Speaker 3:  it and it hasn't been good for him.
Speaker 3:  Tesla investor, Ross Gerber again. And so what's happened over
Speaker 3:  the last six months to a year, which has been really distressing to me,
Speaker 3:  is that the public opinion, at least in my area
Speaker 3:  of the world, has changed to decidedly negative about
Speaker 3:  Elon, and that hasn't been good for Tesla. There's this closely
Speaker 3:  watched poll that Axios puts out every year. It ranks the reputations of
Speaker 3:  100 different companies. Tesla fell 50 spots from last
Speaker 3:  year, an enormous drop. Why? People side
Speaker 3:  eye the company's character, culture, and ethics. Now, this poll doesn't
Speaker 3:  tell us why people are suddenly questioning Tesla, but not much has changed
Speaker 3:  with the cars. Musk had worked hard to make Tesla
Speaker 3:  nearly synonymous with himself. He created structures that helped him
Speaker 3:  seize power and keep it. He built the company's brand by harnessing
Speaker 3:  his own on social media and all that. It worked for
Speaker 3:  Tesla until it didn't. The brand has taken a
Speaker 3:  hit. Musk has become a polarizing figure in a way he never was
Speaker 3:  before. The shareholders have gotten restless. This might
Speaker 3:  have been a potential turning point, A moment where he reassessed how his
Speaker 3:  public persona played into the future of Tesla.
Speaker 28:  You know, do your tweets hurt the company?
Speaker 20:  It was a scene in the Princess Bride, great movie,
Speaker 20:  great movie where he confronts
Speaker 20:  the person who killed his father. And he says, offer me
Speaker 20:  money, offer me
Speaker 20:  power. I don't
Speaker 20:  care.
Speaker 3:  But the reality is, he might have to care at least a little
Speaker 3:  bit. Musk did hire someone else to serve as the c e O of Twitter.
Speaker 3:  Perhaps a nod to his Tesla shareholders who have begged for a little more
Speaker 3:  of his attention, but will he curb his toxic brand of tweeting?
Speaker 29:  So I've got 127 million followers. It continues
Speaker 29:  to grow very rapidly. That
Speaker 29:  suggests that I'm, you know, reasonably
Speaker 29:  popular. Now, might not be popular by
Speaker 29:  some people, but for the vast majority of
Speaker 29:  people, my follow account speaks for itself. I think Twitter is actually
Speaker 29:  an incredibly powerful tool for driving demand for
Speaker 29:  Tesla.
Speaker 3:  Maybe, maybe not, but Musk knows about control.
Speaker 3:  He's learned how to hold onto a company. So even if his personal brand is
Speaker 3:  now hurting Tesla's, it's not clear who could stop
Speaker 3:  him.
Speaker 3:  Next week we're gonna take a look at Tesla's competition. Finally,
Speaker 5:  Other automakers are starting to realize Tesla's here, we need to get
Speaker 5:  here also. And they are.
Speaker 3:  And we're gonna find out who's making the best electric vehicles right now.
Speaker 30:  You are now competing with luxury brands like Volvo.
Speaker 30:  Mercedes b m w.
Speaker 31:  Tesla's used to look cool and now they don't, and they've
Speaker 31:  become the Uber car of the
Speaker 31:  city,
Speaker 3:  Land of the Giants. The Tesla Shockwave is produced by the Vox Media Podcast
Speaker 3:  Network in partnership with our colleagues at The Verge. This episode
Speaker 3:  included clips from C N D C C N N, Jay Lenos Garage,
Speaker 3:  Vader tv, wired Science, the Wall Street Journal, and
Speaker 3:  Bloomberg. This episode was produced by Charlotte Silver.
Speaker 3:  Zach Mack is our showrunner and senior producer, Jolie Meyers is our
Speaker 3:  editor. Sarah Craig is our fact checker. Brandon McFarland, mixed
Speaker 3:  and scored. This episode. Andy Hawkins is transportation editor at The
Speaker 3:  Verge. Nisha Kua is our executive producer. Tamara
Speaker 3:  Warren is our co-host, and I'm Patrick George. If you like this episode,
Speaker 3:  give us a follow and tell a friend and follow us to hear our next episode.
Speaker 3:  When it drops.