# Transcript
ID: eb579430-b41d-11ed-9702-d5b2ebc31101
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: The Supreme Court hears Section 230 arguments, Sam Bankman-Fried's latest woes
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/7184822667862162072/1326342453828877326/s93290-US-4454s-1677227607.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, Alex Cranz, T.C. Sottek, and Adi Robertson discuss the Supreme Court cases that could reshape the future of the internet.
Later, Verge policy reporter Makena Kelly joins the show to discuss new charges against FTX founder Sam Bankman-Fried.
Speaker 2:  Hello
Speaker 4:  And welcome to first the flagship podcast of Supreme Court Argument.
Speaker 4:  Interpretation.
Speaker 1:  I
Speaker 4:  Love that. It's good. Yeah, it's, it's not what people expect of us, but
Speaker 4:  it's what we deliver week after week for some reason Here for you. I'm your
Speaker 4:  friend Eli. Alex Trans is here. I'm
Speaker 1:  Here for all of your judicial needs is, am
Speaker 1:  I allowed to say that?
Speaker 4:  That sounds like you do filing and like you're like you, you do
Speaker 4:  you like service a process like you show up, you're like you've been
Speaker 1:  So No, no. I wanna do like the law stuff, but like the law stuff, I don't,
Speaker 1:  I don't don't, don't actually ask me to do it. I don't have a bar card.
Speaker 1:  I'll
Speaker 4:  Be fine. TC Soak is here. Yes.
Speaker 5:  I'm here as the unwilling subject of human experimentation
Speaker 5:  on putting bloggers in Supreme Court for six hours for
Speaker 4:  Two days. Yeah, it's good. And Addie Robertson is here. Hey, so there's a
Speaker 4:  lot of news this week. This is be a strange episode of the ro. I'm here for
Speaker 4:  the first part.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. And then I'm kicking you
Speaker 4:  Out, Alex kicking me out and taking over. I've gotta go do our podcast
Speaker 4:  conference, hot pod summit, which we'll talk about next week. Very cool.
Speaker 4:  Very excited about that. But I wanted to make sure I was on the first segment
Speaker 4:  here and especially with TC and Addie because there were Supreme
Speaker 4:  Court arguments this week on two cases that
Speaker 4:  honestly, depending on how this goes, it could be the story of the year.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Story of the decade. This could be like the week the internet changed
Speaker 4:  forever because of how the Supreme Court might decide in these two cases.
Speaker 4:  One is Gonzalez v Google, which is Eddie, correct me if I'm wrong. That's
Speaker 4:  the one that is the boundary of two 30 where Google Correct.
Speaker 4:  Might be liable for the YouTube recommendation system in a very
Speaker 4:  narrow way. And the other one is Twitter v taney,
Speaker 4:  where Twitter allowing terrorists
Speaker 4:  to use Twitter might make it liable under the
Speaker 4:  Anti-Terrorism Act.
Speaker 6:  Right. Aiding in a vetting terrorism,
Speaker 4:  Right? Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Any terrorism act is like the nexus of both lawsuits. But
Speaker 5:  two 30 immunity is being implicated in Gonzalez v Google
Speaker 5:  and in Twitterverse Taney. It's just, they're just looking
Speaker 5:  at Yeah. Whether they aided in a better terrorist, but
Speaker 1:  It's about free speech on the internet. Basically. It's about what you are.
Speaker 1:  You can and cannot say. No, no, it's not. It's about like
Speaker 1:  the algorithms.
Speaker 4:  It's a, yeah. So I'll get, these are very strange cases I think
Speaker 4:  at a very fundamental level. And I think
Speaker 4:  Addie has written about this. Sarah Jong slacked me a couple days ago
Speaker 4:  and just asked me this out of the blue, I have found myself just like
Speaker 4:  staring into the night sky wondering this no one knows why the Supreme Court
Speaker 4:  took up these cases. They're not great examples of the problem.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. With big services and particularly the Google
Speaker 4:  case around two 30, the law is like pretty settled, right? That
Speaker 4:  this recommendation system does not make Google liable for the
Speaker 4:  contents of the, and then the facts of this case Addie are, are particularly
Speaker 4:  weird. Go through the Gonzalez case really quickly just so people understand
Speaker 4:  what, what happened here and why Google found itself in front of the Supreme
Speaker 4:  Court.
Speaker 6:  So both these cases are about, there were Islamic state attacks
Speaker 6:  and someone died in that attack and the families sued the
Speaker 6:  A full sort of host of services. There's meta, YouTube, Twitter
Speaker 6:  that saying that they aided in a vetted terrorism. And
Speaker 6:  with Gonzalez, the claim is YouTube is not necessarily
Speaker 6:  responsible for just the fact that terrorists were on the platform, but
Speaker 6:  their recommendations served up terrorist videos and ended up
Speaker 6:  then promoting the, their claim is promoting this and
Speaker 6:  actually creating content instead of just hosting third party content, which
Speaker 6:  they maybe wouldn't be liable for under section two 30.
Speaker 4:  So that two 30 is the one that says, okay, you're in the Verge comments.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And you're like, I hate Google. And Google's like, you defamed us
Speaker 4:  and they sue you. They can't sue us. Right? Right. So
Speaker 4:  we're not liable for what you publish on our internet. But
Speaker 1:  This is about like also
Speaker 5:  How Google objectively true statements are defense against Definitely
Speaker 4:  Whatever. If Google wants to sue people, Google sue people, that's not an
Speaker 4:  invitation to Google at this point in time. I'm just saying you post something
Speaker 4:  in our comments that somebody doesn't like, yeah. Two 30 is just like flat
Speaker 4:  out bars you from suing us. Right? In many cases, Addie, in this case,
Speaker 4:  what the distinction here is that YouTube's
Speaker 4:  recommendation system like took a video for
Speaker 4:  terrorist recruitment and showed it to someone else and that undid
Speaker 4:  the two 30 protection.
Speaker 6:  Right? The claim is that they are producing their own content. I
Speaker 6:  am hesitant to make any metaphors because metaphors are where everything
Speaker 6:  goes to die here. But it's more, it's sort of like if
Speaker 6:  YouTube had published a separate series of videos and was like,
Speaker 6:  Hey, these things are all really great and we endorse them is a
Speaker 6:  little bit where they're going with this.
Speaker 4:  Right? So YouTube feeds your video into the recommendation system and
Speaker 4:  merely by showing a video to someone, they've made
Speaker 4:  some sort of choice. They've created some sort of new content, right?
Speaker 5:  Because they've put content in front of you.
Speaker 4:  This is a whole argument. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  But as I think many Supreme Court justices have decided,
Speaker 6:  as far as we can tell from the questions this week, the way in which
Speaker 6:  they're making that argument is really weird.
Speaker 4:  Yes. So we'll come to that. So that's, I just wanna say that's the first
Speaker 4:  case. That's the Google case with two 30 in the middle of it.
Speaker 4:  Yes. What's going on in the Twitter case?
Speaker 6:  The Twitter case is one that was basically taken up
Speaker 6:  as a sort of, if you take up Gonzalez, please, please, please take this too.
Speaker 6:  Which is arguing that even if two 30
Speaker 6:  is falls here, even if two 30 weren't around, Twitter
Speaker 6:  is just providing a basic service. And terrorists happen to have used
Speaker 6:  that service. And you cannot say that somebody aided an embedded terrorism
Speaker 6:  if they're just, there's somebody there that is, happens to
Speaker 6:  be on your platform and you weren't trying to get them there.
Speaker 6:  You were opposed to them being there, but you failed to kick them off.
Speaker 4:  So Twitter's saying, okay, look, we know the Islamic State uses
Speaker 4:  Twitter
Speaker 5:  And, and like you said, nei, the facts of both cases are super weird because
Speaker 5:  there's no, nobody alleged that there was like
Speaker 5:  a specific video or like a specific like that one of the
Speaker 5:  attackers even used the service that's not alleged in. So is
Speaker 5:  it like super broad then? Yeah. It's basically like you contributed to
Speaker 5:  the existence of ISIS as an enterprise and therefore you're responsible for
Speaker 4:  This is what I mean when I say like many smart people are like, why did
Speaker 4:  these cases end up at the Supreme Court?
Speaker 5:  And even the Supreme Court justices seemed maybe not to fully understand
Speaker 5:  what they had done past
Speaker 4:  Years, why they accepted the
Speaker 5:  Cases, the level of confusion that they expressed, which was partly the plaintiff's
Speaker 5:  lawyers fault.
Speaker 6:  Confusion is often Supreme Court justices saying, wow, you,
Speaker 6:  you suck. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Until
Speaker 6:  Years as far.
Speaker 4:  So I, I just wanna put out the stakes here, right? So if
Speaker 4:  Google loses the Google case in the worst possible way and the
Speaker 4:  Supreme Court says, alright, your recommendation system
Speaker 4:  on a platform is a decision you have made
Speaker 4:  that creates a new content that you are responsible for, that means platforms
Speaker 4:  will become liable for what they're
Speaker 6:  Algorithms,
Speaker 4:  Algorithms do. And that is insane. Like just fully,
Speaker 4:  like there's no way to make a user maybe anything at
Speaker 4:  scale without some sort of sorting algorithm
Speaker 5:  In the mix. Google's council is actually really funny on this this cuz it
Speaker 5:  she, she said both like simultaneously in a
Speaker 5:  charitable, in a very arrogant way. Well Google may will survive,
Speaker 5:  but everyone else is, is gonna die.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Yeah. Because Google got the money, they got
Speaker 5:  The back. At least they know. At least they know. But that's
Speaker 4:  The, these are the stakes, right. Algorithms become illegal on the internet.
Speaker 4:  Right. And like at some level, everything that happens on
Speaker 4:  a computer is an exercise in sorting and prioritization.
Speaker 6:  Right. Which Atlantic Kagan said, which was a really great moment in this.
Speaker 4:  Oh right. I wanna come to the fact that the courts seemed to understand
Speaker 4:  what the stakes were, which is very, like all of us were worried.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. On both sides. They seem to understand what the stakes are.
Speaker 4:  So the Google case algorithms illegal question mark. Right. Those
Speaker 4:  are the stakes or what are the limits of an algorithm? Like any sort of
Speaker 4:  algorithmic system that makes reliable of them. Yeah. And you get the sense
Speaker 4:  that like the, these cases are outta the Supreme Court cuz there's isis
Speaker 4:  and so like everyone can agree ISIS is bad. Yeah. Right. And you
Speaker 4:  kind of like start from there and that's like maybe the only
Speaker 4:  thing in America left that we can all agree is bad. Right. Like you,
Speaker 4:  you could, if you were like, there's tweets about the Russian war in Ukraine,
Speaker 4:  like some percentage of Americans be like, I don't know. That's fine. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Right. ISIS is the one where like, yep. Bad across the board, bad
Speaker 5:  Noah liked it.
Speaker 6:  So that's a good, I mean just maybe this is clear to everyone, but on a technical
Speaker 6:  level it's also that there are basically sanctions against isis. Right? That
Speaker 6:  that is, this is the rare example where there is a group where it is literally
Speaker 6:  illegal to deal with
Speaker 4:  'em. Yeah. So, and and that brings me to the Twitter case where the stakes
Speaker 4:  are, do you have to be perfect in offering your
Speaker 4:  at scale internet service?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Well interestingly, even in Gonzalez versus Google,
Speaker 5:  the justices seemed to, I think by way of understanding what the
Speaker 5:  stakes were, maybe some of them suddenly understanding what the stakes are.
Speaker 5:  It seemed like they were trying to give themselves a little bit of an escape
Speaker 5:  hatch. And Justice Barrett at some point suggested they might not have to
Speaker 5:  decide the Google case at all. Because if the
Speaker 5:  Tamana case fails, that means there's
Speaker 5:  two 30 is moot the immunity, what would the immunity even apply to? Cause
Speaker 5:  there's no liability for the terrorism stuff. So they
Speaker 5:  could just say
Speaker 4:  We, sorry.
Speaker 5:  They could just say, we don't wanna deal with this since then, you know,
Speaker 5:  after they've discovered now that they've opened up a big world. So
Speaker 1:  They really can just be like, nevermind.
Speaker 4:  Well, so we'll see. I just wanted, I wanted to start here with these very
Speaker 4:  basic stake. Yeah. Here are the facts of the case. Here's what happened,
Speaker 4:  here's here's why we're in front of the Supreme Court. Yeah. And then what
Speaker 4:  happens if things go wrong? And what happens if things go wrong are
Speaker 4:  basically every platform has to stop operating
Speaker 4:  because there's just no way to, to open up a user account
Speaker 4:  signup form and guarantee that ISIS won't
Speaker 4:  use it. Right. Like you, you
Speaker 1:  Can't, are you in ISIS checkings
Speaker 4:  Or No? Like you have to do some work. And most
Speaker 4:  platforms it's illegal to deal with them. So they do do some work to make
Speaker 4:  sure that platforms aren't being used in this way. Yeah. But if the
Speaker 4:  Supreme Court is like anything, like they sign up for Twitter and
Speaker 4:  now Twitter is liable for an act of terrorism right down
Speaker 4:  the line. Like that just changes the entire way that
Speaker 4:  user accounts work on the
Speaker 5:  Well they can, they can choose to get really stupid with it and be like,
Speaker 5:  you cannot create thumbnails of videos anymore. Yeah. Because they may
Speaker 5:  lead to terrorist content while still like having Right. So other things
Speaker 5:  be functional.
Speaker 4:  So I just wanna Those are the stakes. Yeah. Right. One is you have to be
Speaker 4:  perfect invalidating all the users in your platform. And the other one is
Speaker 1:  Algorithms
Speaker 4:  Go by your algorithm recommendation algorithms make you liable for the
Speaker 4:  content of the video, even if there's no, and I this
Speaker 4:  is true. Right? There was no direct evidence that's showing anyone
Speaker 4:  any videos on YouTube led to terrorist sex.
Speaker 1:  So I have a question about that particular case and I would love for you
Speaker 1:  guys to help my brain understand that. So they're saying like
Speaker 1:  basically the, the, the potential stakes here are any algorithm that does
Speaker 1:  recommendations is gone, which would mean like seo,
Speaker 1:  Google searching,
Speaker 4:  Google's argument. Right? This was not Addie, this was not supposed to
Speaker 4:  be the plaintiff's argument. Right. Like the, because
Speaker 1:  Theoretically I'd be like, okay, if I'm watching YouTube and YouTube's algorithm
Speaker 1:  is like here's an ISIS video and I go join this isis,
Speaker 4:  Well now, now we're just gonna talk about how how bad these, the Casey seemed
Speaker 4:  to go and how surprisingly this is. TC mentioned this how surprisingly
Speaker 4:  intelligent the Supreme Court seemed about the stakes. Okay. What they were
Speaker 4:  early on. So what you would want, just in an abstract way, you're a lawyer
Speaker 4:  in front of the Supreme Court, you're arguing in your position, you're kind
Speaker 4:  of dancing into I want the narrowest interpretation of this thing
Speaker 4:  because that is the most likely outcome. Yeah. Right. Like every
Speaker 4:  Supreme Court opinion is like literally increasingly like this is a narrow,
Speaker 4:  like they pat themselves in the back, they're like, we threaded the needle.
Speaker 4:  We did it once again, the Supreme Court has saved the day in America right
Speaker 4:  here. It, the dude blew it. Right. Addie, they were like,
Speaker 4:  here's a narrow interpretation of this. And he is like, I don't know, maybe
Speaker 4:  Google search should be legal.
Speaker 6:  Yes. People just like justices just kept asking him things
Speaker 6:  and they were just clearly like trying to get him to draw any
Speaker 6:  level of lines that would not just blow up the internet.
Speaker 6:  Like, okay, well what if you know thumbnails? What if the, instead of
Speaker 6:  thumbnails you posted screenshot, he is like, eh. Yeah. I mean maybe
Speaker 6:  there's a Google search question that I think this was
Speaker 6:  Kagan again who was talking about, okay, well
Speaker 6:  there's search. You're clearly if you have a top result, maybe you're saying
Speaker 6:  this is really good and he just would not say, would not draw any of those
Speaker 6:  lines.
Speaker 1:  I love this. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. He was really incapable of like defining even fundamental things
Speaker 5:  about how these systems work. Which makes it hard to then figure
Speaker 5:  out how to,
Speaker 1:  Was that like that was his point though, right? Like to just
Speaker 5:  Well, no, because they'll, the whole point is trying to define
Speaker 5:  how the service works. If your goal is show that the search
Speaker 5:  provider or YouTube or something is, is creating speech, right? Like that's
Speaker 5:  the whole point is if you're, or or the attack on two 30 is if
Speaker 5:  you're recommending something to someone or you're like putting in a box
Speaker 5:  or selecting a thumbnail, you're making some kind of judgment or pushing
Speaker 5:  someone in front of people.
Speaker 6:  I should also clarify on the thumb thumbnail thing, it is so much weirder
Speaker 6:  than it sounds as anyone who has made a YouTube video knows YouTube
Speaker 6:  does not choose a thumbnail for you. I have made enough thumbnail selections
Speaker 6:  to know that's not true. And so the way that he's defining thumbnail is basically
Speaker 6:  the entire box that shows up when Google or when
Speaker 6:  YouTube recommends something, which is the actual image people
Speaker 6:  call a thumbnail. And then the url, the idea that
Speaker 6:  URLs are creating a specific new kind of content is
Speaker 6:  a thing that has been a running argument in the Gonzalez case. And
Speaker 6:  it is just hard to overstate how disruptive that would be. That if you
Speaker 6:  generated in theory, like if you generated a link shortener to something
Speaker 6:  or you just generated any kind of web address, then suddenly
Speaker 6:  you are the provider of and speaker of that content. Which is just
Speaker 6:  Yeah. A wild way to organize the web.
Speaker 4:  When I say that I stare into the night sky wondering why the Supreme Court
Speaker 4:  took this case. It's this stuff. Yeah. Right. Where it's like,
Speaker 4:  oh, maybe you've got a fact pattern. Right. Which is ISIS
Speaker 4:  exists, they used your service to recruit, some people saw
Speaker 4:  the videos and they went off and did terrorism. Right. And like
Speaker 4:  in America in 2023, that might be the only fact pattern
Speaker 4:  where everyone agrees that's bad. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And there that's, it's, it's especially tragic because there have been so
Speaker 5:  many other good cases that have, you know, well none that have reached the
Speaker 5:  Supreme Court for two 30, but like Snap got sued because Right. They did
Speaker 5:  that thing where they, they created a function that showed you how
Speaker 5:  fast you were going and some kids got killed because they were
Speaker 5:  trying to go in real fast, go as fast as they could because of the thing
Speaker 5:  that Snap created. That wasn't something that,
Speaker 4:  The one that I always think about is Herrick fee grinder. Right.
Speaker 4:  Addie is not the caption,
Speaker 6:  The harassment grinder. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Where Grinder being used to harass someone and they get Grinder got
Speaker 4:  sued not on two 30 grounds, but on product liability grounds, your product
Speaker 4:  is helping this harassment occur. Yeah. And they lost because of two 30.
Speaker 4:  But the
Speaker 6:  Google thing is,
Speaker 4:  But like, but like what we're saying is like those cases, like those things,
Speaker 4:  they're like rich fact patterns where you can say, okay,
Speaker 4:  we can dive into the difference between speech and conduct. Right. We can
Speaker 4:  say the design of this product has choices embedded in it that lead
Speaker 4:  to these outcomes. They just never made it here. Instead
Speaker 4:  this goofball set of facts made it here. Right. Where there's not
Speaker 4:  even a direct connection. Like
Speaker 6:  There's not a specific video.
Speaker 4:  It was, yeah. It wasn't this terrorist saw this video and went and did this
Speaker 4:  act of terrorism. Because
Speaker 6:  That would be
Speaker 4:  Clear. Generally people have used this platform,
Speaker 4:  some of them were terrorists and some of them maybe
Speaker 4:  are the ones who did the terrorists. There's like, like not a direct connection
Speaker 4:  there.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Cuz then like if this one goes through, then everyone
Speaker 1:  who's ever lost someone to QAN on can go ensue Google.
Speaker 5:  Oh yeah. That's another consequence. They don't have to have
Speaker 6:  They. They can't. Yeah. Oh they can't. So just to be clear, this is not any
Speaker 6:  extremist group that uses YouTube could suddenly produce this host of
Speaker 6:  lawsuits, ISIS and their sort of other specific foreign
Speaker 6:  terrorist groups. Think of it like the equivalent of sanctioning a country.
Speaker 6:  Okay. So that's what makes this illegal speech. It's, this is really sort
Speaker 6:  of, it is a narrow subset even though it does introduce all of these
Speaker 6:  big liability questions. And this is all, all this stuff we've been talking
Speaker 6:  about is what tamay hinges on a lot. Which is do you
Speaker 6:  have to have an actual connection to a specific act of terrorism or is the
Speaker 6:  enough that you are providing a megaphone that lets
Speaker 6:  ISIS recruit. Okay. So this is all at least someone unsettled.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And and
Speaker 5:  Like the speech arena, it's even weirder because with the foreign terrorist
Speaker 5:  organizations, it's not about, it's not really the speech itself that's illegal.
Speaker 5:  It's the person who's saying it. Like cuz they've banned these organizations
Speaker 4:  From Yeah, well I'm just saying in the United States there is
Speaker 4:  vanishing little speech that is illegal and ISIS is some of that
Speaker 4:  speech. Right. And that's and that. But it opens the door to, okay, we
Speaker 4:  have now said YouTube's recommendation system
Speaker 4:  gets rid of two 30 cuz it is YouTube making some sort of direct editorial
Speaker 4:  choice that exposes them to liability. And the thing they have chosen to
Speaker 4:  do is promote the illegal speech of isis. Yeah. If you can get
Speaker 4:  there, there's no reason you can't replace the illegal speech of ISIS with
Speaker 4:  this illegal defamatory speech about my
Speaker 4:  company. Yeah. Right. And then maybe you'll win and maybe you won't, but
Speaker 4:  that door right now is slam shut
Speaker 1:  And this just cracks
Speaker 4:  It open. It just cracks it open to say the recommendations are create
Speaker 4:  liability for YouTube for the content of the speech. Okay. Even though the
Speaker 4:  speech is like a bunch of thumbnails in a url. Yeah. And you just see like,
Speaker 4:  oh, this is not, I
Speaker 5:  Went for the record, like to make the shocked face thumbnails illegal speech.
Speaker 4:  So the, the again, we're we're kind of still, you can see like these cases
Speaker 4:  are just weird. Yeah. But we're still just talking about like
Speaker 6:  Justice. The spirit also raised the question of section two 30 also
Speaker 6:  protects users. So if you hit thumbs up on a YouTube video, is that
Speaker 6:  you then trying to promote and repeat the speech too?
Speaker 6:  Oh, that's great.
Speaker 4:  So this is what I wanna get to. We've now, we've mostly been talking about
Speaker 4:  how weird the cases are. Yeah. But you two actually listened to the arguments
Speaker 4:  for six hours and add this point from Justice Barrett,
Speaker 4:  surprisingly cogent. Right. Vince is an understanding about
Speaker 4:  YouTube works, which I feel like most people who
Speaker 4:  have phones have encountered YouTube, but you cannot take for
Speaker 4:  granted our court system's ability to understand internet platforms. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  But it seemed like at least in the Google case, there was an
Speaker 4:  understanding and not only the stakes, but what questions they should ask
Speaker 4:  and what the answers at least should be. Which I found surprising.
Speaker 6:  I was surprised and relieved. Okay.
Speaker 4:  What stood out to
Speaker 6:  You? I think that they just went through and asked a bunch of
Speaker 6:  the questions we have been asking at just the broadest level that
Speaker 6:  Clarence Thomas opens up with. Okay. So is there an actual
Speaker 6:  YouTube algorithm that promotes terrorism? Or is there just a single large
Speaker 6:  recommendation algorithm that happens to give you what you
Speaker 6:  want? And maybe some of that is terrorism, his example used Bryce Poff.
Speaker 6:  But I think that there are all these questions that are actually digging
Speaker 6:  into, first of all how the services work and not just taking it
Speaker 6:  for granted that there is something called the algorithm that is evil.
Speaker 6:  They recognize computers have to sort information somehow. And so
Speaker 6:  you're trying to make these very fine green distinctions. Second of all,
Speaker 6:  there's a real understanding that there are a bunch of services that
Speaker 6:  do rely on these things and these services have become enmeshed in our lives
Speaker 6:  and any decision is going to affect them greatly. But Kavanaugh
Speaker 6:  made a really big deal out of, okay, what are the economic implications of
Speaker 6:  this? Is this going to tear down a huge section of the internet while we're
Speaker 6:  trying to figure out what the law is? The third part is just that there were
Speaker 6:  these weird little moments where they actually recognized things that I think
Speaker 6:  just many average people wouldn't, which is things like ai, text generation
Speaker 6:  and images that they were talking about algorithms and can algorithms produce
Speaker 6:  content justice? Corset says, okay, yeah, well there are these
Speaker 6:  tools that can make images and texts so clearly the algorithms can
Speaker 6:  generate things and that opens up this whole other can of worms. It was just,
Speaker 6:  it was smart, but none of which means they'll rule in a way that I like.
Speaker 6:  But it was just a far cry from a bunch of the really bizarre,
Speaker 6:  sweeping, clearly politically motivated
Speaker 6:  rulings on opinions that we have gotten from a lot of courts,
Speaker 6:  including the Supreme Court sometimes,
Speaker 4:  Well in particular there has been right wing
Speaker 4:  sort of animus towards big tech and the algorithm in free speech and
Speaker 4:  censorship. We have seen Clarence Thomas, right. In dissent,
Speaker 4:  we should reevaluate two 30, we should make these platforms common
Speaker 4:  carriers. None of that appeared to come up in this argument.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. There was also surprisingly little, and I wish I, I think, I mean almost
Speaker 6:  none of the sort of, this is big tech, clearly we must stop protecting
Speaker 6:  big tech.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. But that's also coming up later this year with the net choice suits
Speaker 4:  With the moderation suits the moderations in Florida,
Speaker 6:  Which haven't been taken up yet.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. But the common carrier stuff is insanely argued
Speaker 5:  and I think at least the Texas one. And that's,
Speaker 6:  And those are both in state courts?
Speaker 5:  Those are, yeah, those are like states trying to
Speaker 4:  No, those are in federal courts. They're in federal court. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  The net choice cases went through appeals courts and then the Supreme Court
Speaker 6:  asked for the Biden administration to submit its opinion on them basically.
Speaker 6:  And so it seems very likely they're gonna get taken up, but they're not currently
Speaker 6:  in play. Okay.
Speaker 4:  But, and those are just like kind of like dead ahead First amendment cases.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Like it's, should this government make speech regulations?
Speaker 4:  No. The, the answer should be no. But like we live in a topsy-turvy time
Speaker 4:  in America, we,
Speaker 1:  You never know what what should actually be killed because somebody really
Speaker 1:  wants it to be
Speaker 4:  Killed. All right. So we talked about the argument in the Gonzalez case,
Speaker 4:  which is how does a recommendation algorithm work? Are you liable for these
Speaker 4:  thumbnails? What was the argument in the Twitter case like
Speaker 6:  Much more metaphor heavy, which is one of my
Speaker 6:  least favorite types of Supreme court hearing.
Speaker 6:  There's just a huge amount of, it turns on. Okay, so there is this
Speaker 6:  test that defines what aiding and abetting is for
Speaker 6:  specifically civil cases, like the kinds of lawsuits that are getting brought
Speaker 6:  here. And part of it hinges on, all right, well what does
Speaker 6:  it mean for Twitter to have known, does Twitter have
Speaker 6:  to have known that there was this really specific act that was being planned
Speaker 6:  and that ISIS was planning it and that there were these specific ISIS accounts
Speaker 6:  that they had the band to stop recruiting? Or did it just have to
Speaker 6:  vaguely know that there were terrorists on the platform? And then there's
Speaker 6:  also, alright, how much of a specific
Speaker 6:  relationship do they have with these terrorists? Is this like going into
Speaker 6:  a bank? Is it like selling them a gun? What other is it
Speaker 6:  like stealing sheep? They're just a million different metaphors. Stealing,
Speaker 6:  play, stealing sheep. Yes. This was one of the metaphors
Speaker 1:  Who's the farmer on, on the court on the bench.
Speaker 6:  The opening metaphor in the case was, is this more like
Speaker 6:  if you have a friend who's a murderer and a thief and you give them
Speaker 6:  a gun but you just happen to not know exactly when they'll use the gun. Or
Speaker 6:  is it you doing something like opening a gate
Speaker 6:  and then it turns out that the person you're opening the gate for is trying
Speaker 6:  to steal sheep. So that's like the level of argumentation we're talking about.
Speaker 4:  Wait, actually someone trying to steal your sheep and all you have
Speaker 4:  is a gun is fairly close to the average Twitter day,
Speaker 4:  right? It's like, I don't know, I, I've gotta protect this situation.
Speaker 4:  It's like everyone's panicking. There's a sheep thief. I'm just
Speaker 4:  firing indiscriminately. Stealing your neighbor's eggs would've been the
Speaker 4:  better manner. Tuesday on, there's 30 to 40 feral bags.
Speaker 6:  The best pick that I've heard on this from Blake Reed from
Speaker 6:  University of Colorado Boulder is that this is an example
Speaker 6:  of how hard things are gonna get if two 30 isn't around. That you have all
Speaker 6:  these really super fine lines about what counts as aiding and abetting. What
Speaker 6:  counts as something that's really valuable to Twitter, really valuable to
Speaker 6:  terrorists. What does it mean to actually know what's
Speaker 6:  happening on your platform? That right now section two 30 means you
Speaker 6:  don't really have to deal with these things if it goes away. Suddenly you're
Speaker 6:  the making these long, long lists of metaphors and long lists of
Speaker 6:  determinations about what is and is not supporting terrorism.
Speaker 4:  And to be clear, this is like one of like the classic example of
Speaker 4:  they're doing the right thing and getting no credit for it. Like Twitter
Speaker 4:  does not want ISIS on its platform. It activ
Speaker 4:  or at least until
Speaker 1:  As far as we know, Twitter does not want
Speaker 4:  Until least the recent changes. Who knows now
Speaker 6:  The tweet about 2015 and 2022, Twitter did not.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Right. Like Twitter probably had a department of ISIS prevention,
Speaker 1:  They're gone now. They
Speaker 4:  Got laid off like who knows what is happening in Twitter now but
Speaker 4:  act during the relevant time of this lawsuit, Twitter
Speaker 4:  was taking steps like active engaged
Speaker 4:  steps to remove these accounts. They just weren't perfect.
Speaker 4:  Did that come up at all?
Speaker 5:  They spent a lot of time both days talking about the
Speaker 5:  extent of, first of all, what is even knowledge, how much
Speaker 5:  knowledge did Twitter have of you know, or Twitter or Google who was
Speaker 5:  on, who's using their service? What kind of content is on the service?
Speaker 5:  And there's kind of a a weird paradox here because
Speaker 5:  the more that you know about what's on your platform, arguably the more
Speaker 5:  responsibility you have to deal with it. Whereas the less you know, the more
Speaker 5:  you can kind of plausibly say I had no relationship with these people
Speaker 5:  who use the service cuz I didn't know they were there. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  This sort of like strategic ignorance actually comes up with
Speaker 4:  platforms a lot. Like this is the argument they will all make to you. Right?
Speaker 4:  Like if you make us run a copyright enforcement system, then we will know
Speaker 4:  and we will take more stuff down and more people will be at, or it could
Speaker 4:  be a free
Speaker 5:  For all I think. I think a lot of people though do maybe assume that the
Speaker 5:  platforms know more than what they actually know about the content that's
Speaker 5:  actually on the platform. Well I think
Speaker 1:  They, they assume that because they, they do have all the data, right? Like,
Speaker 1:  like Twitter and Google have all the data theoretically system,
Speaker 1:  the computers know that ISIS is on the platform but that doesn't mean a human
Speaker 1:  knows.
Speaker 6:  Right? Now a lot of these cases hinge on the idea that there were government
Speaker 6:  officials or there was media coverage that when you say they know often what
Speaker 6:  they mean is the B D C said Hey there are all these terrorists on your platform
Speaker 6:  or that somebody in the US government pointed this out to them
Speaker 6:  and that they didn't take enough action often to
Speaker 6:  sort of play the game of whack-a-mole of keeping people off once they knew.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Okay. Well and there's also just like the inherent
Speaker 4:  nature of data and like this comes up with YouTube and
Speaker 4:  YouTubers in particular all the time where the YouTubers know what is
Speaker 4:  happening on the platform well before YouTube executives can see it.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. We've talked about it that a
Speaker 4:  Bunch on the show we were talking about in the context of, of Susan stepping
Speaker 4:  down a C of YouTube, right? Like their view of YouTube is like
Speaker 4:  echoes through data that is weeks or months behind
Speaker 4:  the frontline of actual YouTube. Yeah. So you assume they know, but
Speaker 4:  that's not, might not actually be what's happening. And in particular the
Speaker 4:  data that they need to see, if you train some automated system
Speaker 4:  against it, the system will have an error rate and you need to calibrate
Speaker 4:  what is your acceptable error rate. So if I stand up for a Twitter account
Speaker 4:  that's like, do you remember when Verizon had a payment service called
Speaker 4:  isis?
Speaker 1:  ISIS was a very popular dim for a very
Speaker 4:  Long time. For one minute it was like, we're gonna have a wallet called ISIS
Speaker 4:  and everyone's gonna use ISIS on their phones. And they're like, wait,
Speaker 4:  just ignore our whole plan. My bad we'll come back to you with a new payment
Speaker 4:  system. And then they just didn't, I think they, all the
Speaker 4:  ISIS people at Verizon were like, we don't, we don't even wanna explain what
Speaker 4:  happened here.
Speaker 1:  You're putting lipstick on that pitch.
Speaker 4:  But like if you start up a Twitter account that's like Verizon ISIS lover
Speaker 4:  and like the system just like rejects you because of straight keyword
Speaker 4:  filtering. Right. It is actually not a correct error. Or if I tweet,
Speaker 4:  remember when Verizon had a payment system called isis, didn't we all love
Speaker 4:  isis? Yeah. And it's like strict keyword filtering. Like that's an
Speaker 4:  unacceptable
Speaker 1:  Error. Yeah. Cuz it was just like there was Archer, the main like
Speaker 1:  spy organization Archer
Speaker 6:  Not bringing up Archer and you went and you wouldn't
Speaker 1:  Wow. I did it. I'm sorry but they, they called it isis. There's like a character
Speaker 1:  in DC cos like ISIS is a very common thing that people would talk about
Speaker 1:  when they're not talking about terrorism.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. There's also the speech nu the nuance that there is terrorist
Speaker 6:  speech, but there is actually a lot of speech about terrorism that
Speaker 6:  is not terrorist speech. Right. That posting a video of
Speaker 6:  someone, of a terrorist speaking can also just be a thing that
Speaker 6:  CNN does. So you also can't automatically necessarily filter
Speaker 6:  by names or by video clips even.
Speaker 4:  And the justices brought this up, right? They like struggled with this very
Speaker 4:  basic and I think the answer is, well the first amendment would cover that.
Speaker 4:  Which is, that was the part when I was reading the live blog where I was
Speaker 4:  like, oh they, they got there, they got it, they arrived the first and finally
Speaker 4:  they have arrived at the first amendment.
Speaker 1:  But they did talk about pagers first.
Speaker 5:  There is, there is a really interesting nuance also to the knowing question
Speaker 5:  that I wish they would've had 12 hours to explore. Which is like, what do
Speaker 5:  the recommendation algorithms even know? A lot of these systems don't
Speaker 5:  evaluate stuff in the same criteria. They might know what a certain type
Speaker 5:  of person wants to see and what other people that they have liked things
Speaker 5:  have seen, but they might not know the actual content that they're surfacing
Speaker 1:  At some point. Right. Because they're not, they're not humans. They're not
Speaker 1:  perceiving, they're perceiving data and that's it. And depending on what
Speaker 1:  that data is, like the worst thing we can ever do is assume the AI is
Speaker 1:  in any way things like human processes.
Speaker 4:  No, it has one, it thinks like a human in one specific way, which is if you
Speaker 4:  make it mad Yeah. It will be super mad at you in
Speaker 1:  The one way that they think like humans
Speaker 4:  It be weird and defensive if you ask it to do something it
Speaker 4:  doesn't wanna do
Speaker 1:  Doesn't think like a human except for like in the worst ways of things like
Speaker 1:  a human. Exactly.
Speaker 4:  It's like I've been a good bing, I don't know about you.
Speaker 1:  I'm
Speaker 6:  Actually honestly waiting for the moment where somebody asks an AI how it
Speaker 6:  works and tries to bring that up in court as an explanation of how the AI
Speaker 6:  works. Somebody's gonna try it.
Speaker 1:  It's gonna be weird. I'm so excited. It's
Speaker 4:  Gonna be weird. Okay. So these are the arguments. The justices seem like
Speaker 4:  they get it, they understand they're playing with fire in terms of the stakes.
Speaker 4:  What do you think happens now? Are they gonna horse trade between the two
Speaker 4:  cases? Like you were suggesting tc, I, I'm
Speaker 5:  All out. No one knows. But they did seem to be proposing
Speaker 5:  subtly that they have an escape hatch. So they might just say, forget
Speaker 5:  this, we're gonna wait for the really fun one, which is dealing
Speaker 5:  with Texas and Florida and making websites host things that we want them
Speaker 5:  to
Speaker 4:  Host. Yeah. Addie, what do you think?
Speaker 6:  I really don't wanna make predictions, but yes, it seems possible they're
Speaker 6:  just gonna rule in the narrowest least two 30 precedent
Speaker 6:  making possible way. And I don't know that they
Speaker 6:  necessarily seem that likely to say that Twitter is in the clear, but it
Speaker 6:  seems like they could pretty clearly just say this was
Speaker 6:  actually the most unsatisfying result that I have heard
Speaker 6:  described is that they just say, Hey, you changed your argument way too much.
Speaker 6:  Gonzalez lawyers we're throwing this out for now.
Speaker 4:  Well there's a, there's like a extremely funny sea plot to all
Speaker 4:  of this. Yeah. Which is that the big tech companies have hired
Speaker 4:  so many lobbyists and lawyers that the plaintiffs were
Speaker 4:  not able to hire a good lawyer. Aw. And they ended up with
Speaker 4:  this like gentleman Yeah. Who did a bad job. Aw. They've found
Speaker 5:  Plenty of good lawyers for other things like copyright
Speaker 4:  Infringement. Well, right. But it just, big tech has hired so many of the
Speaker 4:  lawyers in DC Yeah. That they were all conflicted
Speaker 4:  out of arguing this case for the, for the plaintiffs On both, in both cases.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. So both Tam Nay and Gonzalez had the same lawyer
Speaker 4:  and he'd it would not, he was what was left, I don't know how else to say
Speaker 1:  This. He's doing
Speaker 4:  His best. He was the guy, he he was there. So
Speaker 1:  It was the same guy both days. Yeah. Oh that's like, that's a
Speaker 1:  week.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. He had a,
Speaker 1:  I hope you have a drink sir.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. So we'll see. I mean I I I do think that particularly with the Gonzalez
Speaker 4:  case, I think we, the Supreme Court rule that Google is illegal does not
Speaker 4:  seem like a likely outcome. Yeah. I think
Speaker 4:  with a Twitter case the, we think you should do a better job of making
Speaker 4:  sure the terrorists don't eat. Like that's a safe ruling. Yeah. Even though
Speaker 4:  it might have some consequences about like verification or whatever. I also
Speaker 4:  think it's the guy who owns Twitter right now
Speaker 1:  Does not wanna hear that.
Speaker 4:  He doesn't wanna hear it. But he is also, I mean like the politics has come
Speaker 4:  into place somehow. Right? Like he's, he has a different ideological
Speaker 4:  reputation than the other guy who,
Speaker 1:  Which is when they took on the case. Yeah. Okay. They took it on when
Speaker 1:  it was still,
Speaker 4:  Yeah. When when they were still hanging out shirts. It said stay woke. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  I have one. It's a little tight. You gotta work on that. But
Speaker 4:  it's like, that's just a swirl around the Twitter case that I think is
Speaker 4:  different than the swirl around the Google case, which is, boy this is a
Speaker 4:  stretch and why are you here? Yeah. Which is not what I expected to hear,
Speaker 4:  so we'll see. But it's, we're expecting decisions at the end of
Speaker 4:  this term, which is like quite some time away. Right Addie?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I believe the next term starts in October. So yeah,
Speaker 6:  we probably a month.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Okay.
Speaker 4:  But I would say that the, the general valence from the
Speaker 4:  lawyers in the world as whoa, that could have got a lot worse.
Speaker 1:  Well that's good, right?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. We'll see. But
Speaker 6:  Yeah, the thing I've heard is clearly they could rule really bad ways down
Speaker 6:  the line and there are specific subtle ways that we have not talked about
Speaker 6:  here that they could do that even as part of Gonzalez.
Speaker 1:  But we came out of this much more reassured than we thought we could be.
Speaker 4:  For sure. Alright, thank you. Add and tc. We gotta take a break.
Speaker 1:  You gotta go to Hot Pod.
Speaker 4:  I gotta, yeah, I gotta go to Brooklyn. Yeah,
Speaker 1:  I gotta, you gotta get in a car. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Tutu. I haven't been in Brooklyn in years. It's gonna be great. Oh wow. Used
Speaker 4:  to live there. I go to wild, my old haunts
Speaker 1:  Gonna go just,
Speaker 4:  I'm gonna post one of those TikTok. It's like I'm back in the city. It's,
Speaker 4:  Alex is gonna talk about some stuff after this. Who knows what it'll
Speaker 1:  Be. It's gonna be super fun and stay tuned.
Speaker 4:  We'll right back.
Speaker 1:  Okay, we're back. Eli's gone. He's gonna go work on some
Speaker 1:  gross podcast. You don't need to worry about. He's overdoing hot pod. He's
Speaker 1:  having a great time. But I've got better people with me today. No, that's
Speaker 1:  mean to Addie and TC who are lovely. Eli's fine. Anyway,
Speaker 1:  Richard Lawler is here. Hey Richard. Hey. What's happening? And
Speaker 1:  our good friend McKenna Kelly is here.
Speaker 8:  Hi everyone.
Speaker 1:  And we are gonna talk about some, some kind of breaking news.
Speaker 1:  It happened today. Our good friend SPF F. How's he
Speaker 1:  doing McKenna? Well,
Speaker 8:  Four more charges against him. We had eight. Yeah. When he
Speaker 8:  was first charged. 1,
Speaker 8:  2, 3, 4, 12. Additional
Speaker 8:  bank fraud and money laundering. And then of course they modified the
Speaker 8:  campaign finance charges by adding, you know, a little bit more information
Speaker 8:  that included a lot of the signal chat that we've kind of
Speaker 8:  heard about their use of signal. But they, you know, cite some messages
Speaker 8:  in there that were, I I was very surprised.
Speaker 1:  Oh yeah, let's, let's talk about that.
Speaker 9:  There were bank fraud charges left that he hadn't already been
Speaker 9:  charged with. Like there are other kinds,
Speaker 8:  I guess there's so many. How many bank charges
Speaker 8:  can one man, he's
Speaker 1:  Just an achiever. He's just an overachiever. He wants to get it all
Speaker 1:  done.
Speaker 8:  So yeah, they had a signal group and it was called very, I mean it's very
Speaker 8:  easy for prosecutors here cause it's called donation processing.
Speaker 8:  Great. Go in there for the campaign finance stuff. Yeah. And then you go
Speaker 8:  in there and it is bankman freed, two
Speaker 8:  unnamed co-conspirators who we can basically say
Speaker 8:  were, you know, folks who have been reported before. Their names are escaping
Speaker 8:  me right now, but the guy who made the Democrat donations and the guy who
Speaker 8:  made the Republican donations. Okay. And they're in there and there's instances
Speaker 8:  of them agreeing to make donations that Ummmon Fried wanted to make.
Speaker 8:  But he had superseded right the limits of campaign finance. You can only
Speaker 8:  donate to an individual campaign or a pack so much money every year. Right.
Speaker 8:  And so he had already spent all of the money
Speaker 8:  and needed other people to spend his money for him in order.
Speaker 8:  So cuz you can look up everyone's donations on the fec fec.gov
Speaker 8:  and yeah. So they did that and they
Speaker 8:  found evidence of that being coordinated. And it's very funny. I love
Speaker 1:  You were like really excited about
Speaker 8:  No, I just love these indictments from the justice department because they're
Speaker 8:  kind of silly to read. Yeah cuz it's like encrypted messaging
Speaker 8:  app signal, right? Like it feels like so suspicious where it's like something
Speaker 8:  we all use every day. Yeah. But yeah, so they saw that, you look
Speaker 8:  at this one thing, there was one instance where bankman freed s
Speaker 8:  sp f asked who's assumingly like the Democratic
Speaker 8:  spender, you know, for his name to make at least like a $1 million
Speaker 8:  donation to a pro L G B T pack. Okay. And he was so
Speaker 8:  ridiculous cuz apparently there was like a political like, I dunno, consultant
Speaker 8:  or something in there and told that guy, like in general, you
Speaker 8:  being the center left face of our spending will mean you giving a lot of
Speaker 8:  woke s curse
Speaker 8:  word to you can say shit. Okay. I can say shit.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Oh, you can say shit on the
Speaker 8:  Vergecast. I'm quoting someone else. I'm not cursing. I would never,
Speaker 1:  Never, no, that's
Speaker 8:  Wrong. So yeah, in general, you being the center left face of our spending
Speaker 8:  will mean you giving a lot of woke shit for transactional purposes, which
Speaker 8:  is like so blatantly like, I don't know, it just, it's not
Speaker 8:  what SPF was ever painted as, you know. So he was always like, you know,
Speaker 8:  the boy wonder's going change the world.
Speaker 1:  He
Speaker 8:  Wears shorts and he is like a little weird. But you know, he has good
Speaker 8:  ideas and he wants the world to be great. Yeah. And it's like this woke shit.
Speaker 8:  Does he
Speaker 9:  Have good
Speaker 8:  Ideas? Well that's what, do you know, were you following him before all this
Speaker 8:  happened? Like everyone was like, this guy's gonna change the world. He's
Speaker 8:  so great.
Speaker 1:  Look at Richard's
Speaker 8:  Face. I know
Speaker 1:  You didn't believe it, Richard. When, when were you like, I don't know about
Speaker 1:  this SBF guy.
Speaker 9:  The very first moment I saw him, I mean like the instant I heard of him and
Speaker 9:  looked him up and saw him, I said suss that guy is not
Speaker 9:  trustworthy. I would not give him a billion dollars. I just wouldn't.
Speaker 1:  Did you, did you know that he was gonna get 12 now
Speaker 1:  indictments against him when you first saw him?
Speaker 9:  No, I was not predicting that. I didn't, I didn't know that he was that kind
Speaker 9:  of a achiever. I mean like that that, that is just going above and beyond
Speaker 9:  really. Like, like what this guy is doing and, and what he has achieved.
Speaker 9:  It's it's admirable in a way.
Speaker 8:  In a way. What is that way Richard?
Speaker 9:  I mean if you're gonna go for it, go go big. Yeah, that's true. Like, like
Speaker 9:  why? Like why stop it? Just a little bit of fraud. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  Right. Yeah. I mean when you, before you start like peeling the
Speaker 8:  layers off of this, right? When you're just like all of these major
Speaker 8:  companies and you know, whatever these people, investors putting money in,
Speaker 8:  it's like, haha, that is funny. Get screwed. And then it's like, oh
Speaker 8:  these people, these people were just, they thought it was a good spending
Speaker 8:  opportunity and then I get sad. Yeah. Which is sucks. But speaking
Speaker 8:  of the people who were affected of this, you look at this in the new indictment
Speaker 8:  that we saw today, it mentions that the money
Speaker 8:  making these political donations was coming from an Alameda bank
Speaker 8:  account. Okay. So this was, it's very much like if this is proven in court,
Speaker 8:  it's saying that customer funds were definitely used. Wow. And there was,
Speaker 8:  I I think what was the number 300 political contributions made in the last
Speaker 8:  midterms worth tens of millions of dollars.
Speaker 1:  So he like probably affected the election LA than the midterms.
Speaker 8:  That's the nuts money. That's the nuts thing about this because
Speaker 8:  you can't, you know, you do a straw donor scheme cuz you don't want, and
Speaker 8:  then of course you don't wanna mask, you wanna mask who you are, how much
Speaker 8:  money you're spending. You have all these other people that you're doing
Speaker 8:  that with. But then like the Republican donations, he called them and there
Speaker 8:  was an interview with Tiffany Fong a couple months ago who I think
Speaker 8:  she's just like a freelance journalist who reports on crypto and she had
Speaker 8:  interviewed SPF and he was like, oh, all my Republican donations were dark.
Speaker 8:  So you're giving, so dark is like a very weird word. It gets thrown around
Speaker 8:  a lot of ways, but in some instances, like you can just say dark
Speaker 8:  money goes to nonprofits, which then make that money, but then spend that
Speaker 8:  money in politics. But, you know, it's very unclear how that happened
Speaker 8:  if he's just talking about a dark money scheme of like getting his, you know,
Speaker 8:  coworkers or friends involved, or if this really was like some weird nonprofit.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. But then again, it's like really hard unless they
Speaker 8:  have some kind of, you know, evidentiary, you know, response, like some kind
Speaker 8:  of evidence produced throughout the hearing to like really figure out where
Speaker 8:  all that money went. And seeing that they have like, some of the documents
Speaker 8:  with a lot of transactions and things that have like such a large
Speaker 8:  look at all of the, you know, everything with money and stuff at
Speaker 8:  ftx, they have like a very, they have balance sheets and stuff. It would
Speaker 8:  be interesting to see where it all is going. The, and that's why I was really
Speaker 8:  interested in today's indictment because it shows us a little bit more direction
Speaker 8:  there.
Speaker 1:  Right. And so, so we saw today he donated money.
Speaker 1:  They're, they're asking all of people to return the money too, right? They're
Speaker 1:  asking all the politicians to like give it back.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. So once this SPF f guy was
Speaker 8:  indicted, I, I automatically was like, oh God, what happens to the money
Speaker 8:  that, because for the most part, when you're a political campaign, you're
Speaker 8:  spending that, yeah. You are getting that out the door. Yeah. You have a
Speaker 8:  deadline and that's election day and you wanna win. Right. So like that money
Speaker 8:  gone. Yeah. And so you look at, at, I think it was like the Democratic National
Speaker 8:  Committee, their set at arm, you know, in a congressional house arm
Speaker 8:  said that they were gonna be returning the money. The process is very, you
Speaker 8:  know, weird where they have to like wait through certain processes for clawback
Speaker 8:  or whatever, but they said, you know, together they're gonna return a million
Speaker 8:  dollars. Could
Speaker 1:  This bankrupt in Epacs who have to like return
Speaker 1:  money?
Speaker 8:  That would be nuts. Because I'm remembering, what
Speaker 8:  was it, I had just recently watched that Madoff documentary,
Speaker 8:  like going through all of that and like trying to claw back that money. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  And a lot of times like that was, it was money for, for you know, just people
Speaker 8:  who were saving for retirement or whatever. There was also like large investors
Speaker 8:  and people like that. And even then, you know, in a case, so
Speaker 8:  public facing like that, that really affected the entire, you know Right.
Speaker 8:  The entire financial system calling back money from that was
Speaker 8:  ridiculously hard. So I don't think it would bankrupt anyone.
Speaker 8:  But I do think that in many ways the new FTX management
Speaker 8:  wants to make customers whole as much as they can. But yeah, like when it
Speaker 8:  comes to political spending, it that's already gone. You know, that's already
Speaker 8:  gone through so many hands from like, right from, you know, SPF to his
Speaker 8:  co-conspirator to the pack the campaign and the campaign to
Speaker 8:  an advertising company, payroll, maybe.
Speaker 8:  All kinds of things like that. So it's very hard to figure out, you know,
Speaker 8:  what exactly have
Speaker 1:  We seen this kind of stuff happen before where there was like a big fraud
Speaker 1:  like that and then they have to like be like, Hey everybody give the money
Speaker 1:  back
Speaker 8:  In political finance. Yeah. I think there was one instance of it,
Speaker 8:  but it's always, I forget who the candidate was and for what race it
Speaker 8:  was. So this is very hard. But, but I,
Speaker 8:  what happened? It's like an organizing between people on the campaign and
Speaker 8:  campaign staffers. Okay. So like a candidate or someone on the campaign tells
Speaker 8:  a certain staffer directs that to get the money there. It's never
Speaker 8:  as, I've never seen something where it's like an outside third party.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. So this is like, this is, this is big and, and a big deal. Not just
Speaker 1:  because he went for broke, he got his 12 indictments, but also
Speaker 1:  because that's a lot of money in the, in the campaign finance
Speaker 1:  world that now is being asked for back. Yeah. And, and
Speaker 1:  probably isn't gonna come back.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. I, I mean I think, what was it, something I think the FTX
Speaker 8:  folks wanted.
Speaker 8:  What was, oh my gosh. That was the funny thing is that they were sending
Speaker 8:  confidential messages to the campaigns being like, Hey, can we have this
Speaker 8:  money back?
Speaker 1:  Like, before they got
Speaker 8:  Indicted. That was just earlier this year. So, so this was just like,
Speaker 1:  So this was like recently like the government was like, yo, can you, can
Speaker 1:  you Venmo me?
Speaker 8:  Yeah. Well, yeah.
Speaker 9:  Or was that the, the new CEO of
Speaker 8:  Ftx? It's the new ceo. It's like the new FTX Jay,
Speaker 9:  I, I can't Jay, Jonah Ray or something like
Speaker 8:  That. John Ray. Yeah, John Ray. John.
Speaker 9:  Yes. So he's like, that's Spidermans Bowl.
Speaker 1:  He's out there like on his own signal chat to, to
Speaker 1:  campaign
Speaker 8:  I guess being
Speaker 1:  Like, can I get that back?
Speaker 8:  Hey, can you get that back to me? Because what it is, it's like, it says,
Speaker 8:  I'm looking at the CNN n n article, it says, and other recipients, so the
Speaker 8:  packs and everything, the clawback assets to repay the company's
Speaker 8:  estimated 1 million creditors. So maybe that's Yeah. Just creditors. Oh
Speaker 8:  wow. And that's, this is what happens too in these big cases. Cause if you
Speaker 8:  look at the Madoff cases as well, a lot of that money ended up going to,
Speaker 8:  you know, creditors in large investors instead of like this people who
Speaker 8:  maybe just had like
Speaker 1:  The people who were just really passionate Yeah. About the FTX mission
Speaker 1:  and what everything's SPF was saying. If only they'd had Richard as their
Speaker 1:  financial advisor. Well, no, you would've put all, what crypto would you
Speaker 1:  have? Put it all into instead?
Speaker 9:  My own obviously R JCC coin is mentoring soon. And
Speaker 9:  you know, if you messaged me, I can get you in early for the premit. For
Speaker 9:  the pre pre premit and then the PostIt. That's
Speaker 8:  The only way you can win is to mi your own corn.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I love this for you Richard. You got this. Oh my
Speaker 8:  Gosh.
Speaker 9:  2023 is my big crypto year.
Speaker 1:  Who
Speaker 8:  Are you, who's gonna be like your brand ambassador?
Speaker 9:  You know, I don't, I haven't decided. All the F1 teams are out on crypto
Speaker 9:  now. All the, all the, the NBA teams are out on crypto.
Speaker 8:  You're in late.
Speaker 1:  You get Tom. Yeah. Brady. Brady needs, he needs some extra money
Speaker 1:  now.
Speaker 9:  Well, you know, he needs, he's had a
Speaker 1:  Divorce
Speaker 9:  To pay for I think. I think he, I think he's had enough. We'll, we'll we'll
Speaker 9:  find someone else. We'll find some NFL quarterback who's out of a job. What's
Speaker 9:  Johnny Menzel doing?
Speaker 1:  You
Speaker 8:  Know what I love? Did you hear about Shaquille O'Neal? Like he was not going
Speaker 8:  to, he's in all the commercials. Like he's in the general, like that man
Speaker 8:  is on everything. Yeah. And he was like, I'm not gonna do crypto. I don't
Speaker 8:  understand how that works. It sounds like a scam. I love it. I love that
Speaker 8:  for Shaq. Like the one added,
Speaker 9:  I wish more people had done that. Syd, I don't know how this works. It means
Speaker 9:  I probably shouldn't get involved. Right.
Speaker 8:  Oh my gosh.
Speaker 1:  Was onto something.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. Everyone listened to Shaq.
Speaker 1:  You should
Speaker 9:  Actually. But I think, I think one of the things in in here that kind of
Speaker 9:  jumped out to me, what exactly was he hoping to get back, get out of all
Speaker 9:  these donations and making these donations secretly? Like, was he just like,
Speaker 9:  I've, I really want these people to be elected. Did he think that he could
Speaker 9:  get favors back once they were in? Or, or is, is there any kind of
Speaker 9:  clear, clear word on that?
Speaker 8:  So I, this would've been, oh my gosh, at least
Speaker 8:  six months ago. But I think I interviewed someone at,
Speaker 8:  you know, his spending arm or something. I forget what the, I forget what
Speaker 8:  the organization was called. And because
Speaker 1:  He was pretty open about the spending this money. Oh, before
Speaker 8:  He was, yes. Well he was very open about the democratic spending. The Republican,
Speaker 8:  yeah. Not the Republican spending. And he was, I guess
Speaker 8:  we didn't really know, you know what I mean? We had like certain numbers.
Speaker 8:  I think at the time it was like, I don't know it, it wasn't an illegal amount.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. But now tens of million do tens of millions of dollars. I can't even
Speaker 8:  say it spent. That is definitely illegal. Especially. So he
Speaker 8:  did not wanna be seen on the Republican stuff. He wanted to be looking at
Speaker 8:  like this progressive cool guy
Speaker 8:  who, you know, just had the best Wait, what was it? He wanted He was
Speaker 8:  pandemic preparedness. Okay. Is what he said it was. But if you look at the
Speaker 8:  people who, the candidates who he supported, they're very like friendly to
Speaker 8:  crypto. Yeah. Representative Maxwell Frost, who is the junior
Speaker 8:  congressman from Florida now, like he's the first Gen Z congressman, he took
Speaker 8:  some money, his campaign took money. I don't wanna say he did, cuz it
Speaker 8:  wasn't dif, it wasn't like their hands exchanging it, which maybe would've
Speaker 1:  Thank you for this money. I'm gonna go use it to boost Crypto
Speaker 8:  Would've raised eyebrows probably earlier. Could you imagine
Speaker 8:  like doing a, like an unlawful campaign finance
Speaker 8:  exchange? Like on the street?
Speaker 1:  Just on the street. Just what? In May, Miami? Is that where it
Speaker 8:  Was? I know, I don't know. But I we're in Florida. I love the idea of like
Speaker 8:  a person in a trench coat, like being like, here's some money for
Speaker 8:  digital ads.
Speaker 1:  Just opening it. Right? He's got all the digital ads like right here.
Speaker 8:  No whole ad exchange in your coat.
Speaker 8:  I'm taking it to Google.
Speaker 1:  Google will buy it for $5.
Speaker 8:  That's the competition Google is talking about. Yeah. When it comes to like
Speaker 8:  the ads case that they're being sued by in the doj, it's like, it's the guy
Speaker 8:  on the, it's that the guy on the street. Like your little mom and pop ad
Speaker 8:  seller. Yeah. That definitely exists. Okay. So back to the
Speaker 8:  point. SPF F. Right? So he wanted to be seen as a democratic spender. He,
Speaker 8:  but if you look at the candidates, they're all very pro crypto. So
Speaker 8:  there are folks who at least now are voicing a little bit of skepticism,
Speaker 8:  but they're like, but crypto, we need to keep it around. It's the future.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. So those, that's where a lot of the PAC spending. Okay. He sup. So
Speaker 8:  he would send money to PACS that then supported Right. You know, certain
Speaker 8:  candidates
Speaker 1:  Because you, the, the limit to send directly to candidates is fairly small,
Speaker 8:  Right? Yeah. Right. It's like $1,700 or something. Yeah. It's like,
Speaker 8:  that's
Speaker 1:  A lot of money for a lot of people, but fairly small for someone like S B
Speaker 1:  F who is just blowing through tens of millions of dollars of other people's
Speaker 1:  money.
Speaker 8:  Right.
Speaker 1:  So,
Speaker 8:  Oh my goodness.
Speaker 1:  So he would go, he'd take this money, he'd take you to the packs, and then
Speaker 1:  he would talk with his two, his, his, his Republican guy and his his
Speaker 1:  democrat guy. And they would like, didn't see the money go from the packs
Speaker 1:  elsewhere.
Speaker 8:  Right. So it you, so it's very easy when you can like people,
Speaker 8:  it, this is like so hard for people who don't cover this or like paint
Speaker 8:  very
Speaker 1:  Explain it to me.
Speaker 8:  So there are packs political action groups. Yeah. Political action committees.
Speaker 8:  And what they do is they're very public about who they endorse. Right. And
Speaker 8:  the candidates they type like to endorse. So if you wanna get money to a
Speaker 8:  pack, which can receive much larger amount of money than a campaign, can
Speaker 8:  you find the people who have endorsed the folks that you like? So this pack,
Speaker 8:  they didn't name it in the indictment, had supported a candidate that
Speaker 8:  sbf liked. So he gives a bunch of money through this, a name
Speaker 8:  co-conspirator to the pack, which then will probably, what does APAC do?
Speaker 8:  APAC runs ads. APAC does, you know, whatever they wanna do to help support
Speaker 8:  legislative candidates that they want. So that's how that would get there.
Speaker 8:  They would also donate directly to campaigns, but of course that is always
Speaker 8:  going to be a smaller amount of money. Okay. At least when it's tied back
Speaker 8:  to an individual person. What we, I mean if we're looking at, they, they
Speaker 8:  named two co-conspirators. I don't know if there were more, it sounded like
Speaker 8:  there was the indictment said SPF F was in this group chat to
Speaker 8:  the unnamed co-conspirators. And others. And others. So I
Speaker 8:  don't know who the others are.
Speaker 1:  Are we gonna get more of the signal chat?
Speaker 8:  Could you imagine a slow leak before trial? God, that would
Speaker 1:  Be, that's what, that's what, look at Richard's face. Richard wants that
Speaker 1:  more than anything in the world.
Speaker 9:  I want to read those messages.
Speaker 8:  If I was a prosecutor prosecuting, what is this? This case is supposed to
Speaker 8:  come up later this year, right Richard?
Speaker 9:  That is the idea, I think. Yes. Yeah,
Speaker 8:  It's supposed to come up later this year. And could you imagine like the
Speaker 8:  slowly, oh my god, I'm already, I'm already thinking about it.
Speaker 8:  Richard's
Speaker 1:  Like pre-writing blogs right now. Yeah. Already in anticipation.
Speaker 1:  Some
Speaker 8:  Reporter gets like a little, like a screenshot of the signal and everyone's
Speaker 8:  like, how awful.
Speaker 1:  It's gonna
Speaker 8:  Be great. Yeah. And oh my gosh, I, that's gonna happen. Verge prediction,
Speaker 8:  verge McKenna, Kelly prediction here. I'm very excited for the slow leak
Speaker 8:  of signal messages.
Speaker 9:  And I think that's something that, you know, maybe people should be aware
Speaker 9:  of. Look, maybe you aren't running an international fraud worth
Speaker 9:  billions of dollars, but if you are sending and receiving signal messages,
Speaker 9:  especially if you're in your group chat, the messages are encrypted end to
Speaker 9:  end. So they can't be intercepted and decrypted on the way. However,
Speaker 9:  if someone like the FBI gets
Speaker 9:  ahold of your friend's phone, they can just see what's in the chat.
Speaker 1:  You set up those disappearing ones. Like even Instagram now is like, do you
Speaker 1:  wanna disappear this message? And I'm like, I do. No one needs to know how
Speaker 1:  stupid i I was at 2:00 AM. Right.
Speaker 9:  You don't need to write everything down. You can just ha you can just talk
Speaker 9:  with your voices perhaps and not into microphones
Speaker 9:  like these that we're talking
Speaker 1:  To right now. Just to avoid indictments with Richard
Speaker 9:  R jcc. Coin is satire. Just for any
Speaker 9:  agent's listening.
Speaker 8:  Oh my gosh. Don't speak into a live
Speaker 8:  microphone when committing crimes.
Speaker 1:  Don't, don't go and talk to, what was it, the New York Times?
Speaker 9:  He talked to everyone. He talked to everyone. Tim McNare was on the media
Speaker 9:  tour, the likes of which we've never seen before. I love it. Did
Speaker 1:  That, did that come up in the indictment? What, what were the other, was
Speaker 1:  there any other big news that came out of this indictment?
Speaker 8:  Let me think. I
Speaker 9:  Well, I think one of the, one of the things I was looking at that I thought
Speaker 9:  was really interesting was kind of how they broke down how the customer
Speaker 9:  deposits came in. And he was, he really, he was using like personal bank
Speaker 9:  accounts because his business couldn't get a bank account. Oh God. He's so
Speaker 9:  messy. And he
Speaker 8:  Was like getting bank accounts under different names of different
Speaker 8:  companies that he was like, making up.
Speaker 9:  Seems legit.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, that's exactly what you do. Oh my gosh, that's my favorite thing. And
Speaker 8:  it's my least favorite thing. I'd say my favorite thing, but it's actually
Speaker 8:  my least favorite thing. It's like when you make a company and then you like
Speaker 8:  get it, you start in, you register it in Wyoming and then you re-register
Speaker 8:  it in Delaware and it's like, where's, where's this company? Where's, what
Speaker 8:  does it do? What does it do?
Speaker 1:  It exi It does, it exists to launder finance money
Speaker 8:  Or just can't look at anything. Yeah. Or if you don't wanna know who is
Speaker 8:  running the company, it's just a name. This is, that's like one of the things
Speaker 8:  that I have learned to do recently is to like go through those
Speaker 8:  business registration things and it's so nuts how those work. But
Speaker 8:  yeah, there's so many ways to hide so many things, whether it's like a business
Speaker 8:  thing and money, whatever.
Speaker 1:  FDF didn't use any of them? No, none of them. All right, well we're
Speaker 1:  gonna, we're gonna take a quick break and when we get back, McKenna and Richard
Speaker 1:  are gonna stick around. We're gonna have a lightning round. It's gonna be
Speaker 1:  exciting.
Speaker 1:  Okay, we're back. It's a lightning round. There's actually a, a
Speaker 1:  fair amount of news. It was kind of a short week. President's Day was on
Speaker 1:  Monday, so it was, it was a little quiet except for Chris Welch breaking
Speaker 1:  big Sonos News. We're gonna have a really great episode of the Vercast that
Speaker 1:  goes super deep dive into that. So we're not gonna be talking about that
Speaker 1:  today in the lightning round. We are, however, gonna be talking about Spotify's
Speaker 1:  new AI powered dj. Richard, do you have thoughts?
Speaker 9:  I don't trust it. As we've said before, I'm anti
Speaker 9:  ai, I
Speaker 1:  Pro crypto anti ai. I get it.
Speaker 9:  You, you gotta, you gotta pick your battles. But so Spotify, they will create
Speaker 9:  a custom playlist and then they'll have someone talk over it because that's
Speaker 9:  what you wanted to hear was a computer generated voice talking over your
Speaker 9:  music. Like, unless it's Def punk, then no, that's not, that's not
Speaker 9:  what I wanted.
Speaker 9:  Did Was this something that people were asking for? Well,
Speaker 1:  McKenna, you were talking before the show about how like this is a thing
Speaker 1:  on TikTok already.
Speaker 8:  Well, okay, so no, now I'm actually kind of disturbed
Speaker 8:  by hearing that there was an a, because I was like, what is the difference
Speaker 8:  between an AI playlist and like an algorithm? You know, something that like
Speaker 8:  learns your interest. I was like, that sounds stupid. What are they doing?
Speaker 8:  Are they just like hopping on like the brand train? Yeah. Or like the branding
Speaker 8:  train to be like, we have ai, but no, I did not know that there was a
Speaker 8:  voice. Can you imagine if they sold voice packs or something?
Speaker 1:  A hundred percent That's coming. You're gonna get a Joe Rogan voice pack?
Speaker 1:  Well, well maybe not because I think, I think they're trying to, to
Speaker 1:  separate.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. Well I mean the thing is is the Spotify playlists are
Speaker 8:  very well beloved and well hated from musicians,
Speaker 8:  especially like smaller musicians, right? Because like if you get on a Spotify
Speaker 8:  or an Apple playlist, like that's crazy that like your song's gonna do numbers,
Speaker 8:  people just go to these things. But at the same time it's like you can't,
Speaker 8:  it's hard to find any other reach. Yeah. Besides these playlists and like
Speaker 8:  going viral online. And so something that was very interesting going on is
Speaker 8:  like on TikTok there's people who were, I, I forget her name, but there's
Speaker 8:  a person who makes curates like Spotify playlists
Speaker 8:  and went viral on like just putting all these playlists out there for different
Speaker 8:  moods for different things. And of course like it's something that people
Speaker 8:  wanted people seeking new music, new things, just somebody to
Speaker 8:  curate it for them. Yeah. And I mean it was, it's nice that you, some
Speaker 8:  they actually had a person editorializing that and then having I guess like
Speaker 8:  the off, you know, they would explain it in a TikTok video, but like the
Speaker 8:  idea of having a DJ in the middle
Speaker 1:  Of it, an AI dj.
Speaker 9:  So it's pretending to be a person that picks up music for you, but it is
Speaker 9:  not actually a person. Is
Speaker 8:  It just gonna be like Siri I, or like what is the voice doing
Speaker 9:  To sound like, it sounds like they've got like script writers. They, you
Speaker 9:  know, they're really trying to create a whole se probably more than one vibe
Speaker 9:  that it can take and then it can, the AI generated voice can say whatever
Speaker 9:  the writers decide you
Speaker 1:  Might wanna hear. Okay. So the voice will be based on Xavier X
Speaker 1:  J again, and I cannot knock the name X because that's what I was known as
Speaker 1:  in college. It was a dumb and I can't explain it. But anyway, so X
Speaker 1:  is gonna be their, their DJ voice and apparently they're
Speaker 1:  already working on ho they're hosting some podcasts and stuff already for
Speaker 1:  Spotify. So like
Speaker 8:  It's a familiar voice in a way.
Speaker 1:  Theoretically it'll be a familiar voice for Spotify listeners
Speaker 1:  who also listen to the Get Up, which is
Speaker 1:  Spotify's podcast.
Speaker 8:  In a way, this kind of reminds me there are drivers
Speaker 8:  and I think like a lot of drivers who are either Uber drivers,
Speaker 8:  Lyft drivers, every single time I'm in there. Cuz that's the only instance
Speaker 8:  that I'm really in a car. Yeah. And I don't really have friends who have
Speaker 8:  cars in New York. So when you're in there, a lot of the time they play those
Speaker 8:  radio, like those DJ stations, right. Where there's a DJ who is like blending
Speaker 8:  things in during callouts and stuff. That's the only thing I can think of
Speaker 8:  where people actually listen to music on the radio still.
Speaker 1:  Yeah.
Speaker 8:  And if that's the only, you know, if they're trying to take that on, I don't
Speaker 8:  know, that seems like a kind of silly thing,
Speaker 9:  But it it, once they have this voice they can have it, you know, obviously
Speaker 9:  they can start reading stuff off the artist Wiki page as the, as the song
Speaker 9:  starts. Or maybe where they're playing or maybe or maybe a, a new, a concert
Speaker 9:  nearby where you can buy a ticket or something or just a, that kind of basic
Speaker 9:  advertisement. But I, this is just interesting. You remember when Apple Music
Speaker 9:  launched and they suddenly paid a bunch of real DJs, a lot of
Speaker 9:  money to come on and like curate playlists and record shows and things.
Speaker 9:  Spotify decided, no, we gave Joe Rogan a trillion
Speaker 9:  dollars. So we have no money left for DJs, so we'll have a computer do
Speaker 1:  It. We're gonna give the ai the DJ's job. Aw,
Speaker 9:  Great
Speaker 8:  Job. Doesn't title do some of that too? Or am I just making that up?
Speaker 9:  No one knows. No,
Speaker 1:  No one listens to title.
Speaker 8:  My fiance uses title.
Speaker 1:  The one we found him. He's,
Speaker 9:  He's, we have a title user at, at at at the Verge. I I will
Speaker 9:  keep their identity confidential.
Speaker 1:  I think I I really respect you for that, but I wanna know who it is. It's
Speaker 1:  Neely, isn't it? Neely, just he's gotta have that, like, that flack quality
Speaker 1:  Lossless audio while he is driving up and down the, in his giant truck,
Speaker 1:  mid truck.
Speaker 1:  All right, so, so some other news that happened this week. Microsoft
Speaker 1:  went to Brussels. Tom Warren was also in Brussels. He's not on the show today
Speaker 1:  because he is recovering from going to
Speaker 8:  Brus,
Speaker 1:  Brussels. He just messaged me one day. I was like, I have to go to Brussels.
Speaker 1:  And I was like, why? And why am I learning about, why do I need to know this?
Speaker 1:  Oh, it's for work. Okay, so, so Microsoft went to
Speaker 1:  Brussels because they're trying to defend their, their right to acquire
Speaker 1:  Activision. And a lot of people are upset with that, notably Sony. Sony
Speaker 1:  does not want them to acquire it because then they'll be like, well we won't
Speaker 1:  get all the games. You're gonna, you're gonna cut us out. And so Microsoft
Speaker 1:  goes to, to brussel to defend and they brought some people with them. They
Speaker 1:  also had a bunch of big timely announcements at the same time, including
Speaker 1:  with Nvidia, where they said, okay, we signed a deal. All of our games are
Speaker 1:  gonna be coming to Nvidia, GForce Now's cloud streaming. It's gonna be really
Speaker 1:  great. It's gonna be super exciting. And also Call of Duty Day and date
Speaker 1:  on Nintendo products. So the Switch,
Speaker 9:  That sounds a little bit odd that you would be playing Call of Duty on the
Speaker 9:  Switch, but if they release a switch too, it makes a little bit more sense.
Speaker 8:  Yes. Yeah. Cuz I can't even play Scarlet Violet on my
Speaker 8:  Nintendo Switch without running into like,
Speaker 1:  It,
Speaker 8:  It frame issue,
Speaker 1:  It struggles,
Speaker 8:  It's off and it gets hot. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  I mean people play Call of Duty on their phones, right? You can play like
Speaker 8:  War Zone or whatever on
Speaker 1:  Your phone. Yeah. And, and but this is gonna be those, like the, the ones
Speaker 1:  that are meant for the pc, the one that's coming for the Xbox Series X and
Speaker 1:  stuff like that. I was really surprised that we didn't actually hear game
Speaker 1:  passes coming to the Nintendo Switch, which would've made sense, right? Like
Speaker 1:  have cloud gaming on the switch. Huge great for Microsoft, but I guess that
Speaker 1:  was probably would not have been great for Nintendo. Who wants to sell games?
Speaker 1:  Wants
Speaker 8:  To sell games, and then also and would game pass work on the
Speaker 8:  switch as it is right now. Like
Speaker 9:  If, if you stream the games, I guess. Okay. Because some games do stream
Speaker 9:  on the switch, right? Like there are some kind of like high performance games
Speaker 9:  to Stream plus like all the emulated games I think like the, the Nintendo
Speaker 9:  online stuff.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, yeah, yeah. And, and that, that all like streams
Speaker 1:  and, and you know, I use my steam deck for streaming all the time and it
Speaker 1:  works and it really helps to, to like, I get way more battery life when I
Speaker 1:  stream than when I try to actually play the game directly on the,
Speaker 1:  the steam deck. Then it just sounds like it's on fire. Just that in those
Speaker 1:  fans were very loudly. So, so yeah, this was kind of some
Speaker 1:  surprising news from Microsoft. It is unclear if,
Speaker 1:  if you know, kind of regulatory groups like UK's
Speaker 1:  competition and Markets authority are gonna allow this
Speaker 1:  to go through right now. Richard, how do you feel? Do you think it's gonna
Speaker 1:  happen?
Speaker 9:  I am a bit skeptical just because there's so many hurdles.
Speaker 9:  I think that there's an issue where the, the, the regulators who are trying
Speaker 9:  to stop this deal, maybe the case they have isn't so strong, but there's
Speaker 9:  so many of them.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. There's
Speaker 9:  A lot of so
Speaker 1:  Big and like, and all of Sony is there saying
Speaker 1:  no. And Sony's argument right now is that like, the arguments for this are
Speaker 1:  very, very funny because Sony's argument is you're gonna get all the games
Speaker 1:  and then you're not gonna give us the games or you'll give us the games for
Speaker 1:  10 years and then you're gonna charge us way more money in 10 years. Which
Speaker 1:  yes. That, that's what will happen eventually.
Speaker 1:  Meanwhile, Microsoft's explanation is, yeah, well we
Speaker 1:  suck and Sony doesn't suck, so we should be allowed to buy it
Speaker 1:  because we suck more than Sony. And that's just the wildest
Speaker 1:  like, argument on the planet for this.
Speaker 9:  Watching game companies insist that they are small and have no market share
Speaker 9:  is incredible. Yeah. These two absolutely massive giants
Speaker 9:  worldwide. And Microsoft's just like, yo, but I mean we're, we have no, we
Speaker 9:  have no share in Europe. Europe though. Yeah. And, and Sony is, well, I mean,
Speaker 9:  but we, you own so many studios. You have this, you're Microsoft, of course.
Speaker 9:  It it's just, it's like watching two people just compliment each other. Listen,
Speaker 9:  don't to to try and prove that, that the other one is actually the better
Speaker 9:  one.
Speaker 8:  Doesn't Microsoft bring up the IP stuff with Sony too? Like
Speaker 8:  Sony's just huge when it comes to, you know, just ip. They
Speaker 8:  have, I think they, they have Spider-Man, right? I'm
Speaker 1:  Like, yeah, they've got Spider-Man. They've notably have all of the
Speaker 1:  naughty dog games. So the last of us, which is, you know,
Speaker 8:  But even music like Sony music, the company there like, like Sony's
Speaker 1:  Big, but they're, but this is very narrowly focused on the gaming. And
Speaker 1:  for the gaming, it's Microsoft saying they suck even though they own
Speaker 1:  all of the game studios now. And soon, hopefully for them,
Speaker 1:  Activision and Sony saying we actually kind of suck
Speaker 1:  because yeah, we have all of the market share, but
Speaker 1:  we won't have Call of Duty and everyone plays Call of Duty and like
Speaker 1:  that's basically the argument. It's, it's a fight over Call of Duty. Hmm.
Speaker 1:  10 years ago me would be like very into this fight too. Like, call of
Speaker 1:  Duty was my life.
Speaker 9:  Well, and and I think that's one of the other things to consider is that,
Speaker 9:  especially when it comes to Call of Duty, because they've got the other aspects
Speaker 9:  of it, the mobile gaming, there are, there are all these other things that
Speaker 9:  activation owns. Activation is such a massive company. Yeah. But when you,
Speaker 9:  when you look at like Call of Duty kind of specifically, how long is that
Speaker 9:  going to be relevant in that way? Do do you expect it has been relevant for
Speaker 9:  a long time? We, we we can go back to what the mid aughts,
Speaker 1:  They're running out of like armed conflicts to base the games
Speaker 1:  on. They're
Speaker 9:  Now like, they're just repeating the ones they already did.
Speaker 1:  They're like, what if we do the cold word now? What if we do it in space?
Speaker 1:  Oh
Speaker 8:  My goodness. Well what is like Call of Duty's, like Twitch streaming numbers
Speaker 8:  now compared to maybe like even five years ago? Has it gone down?
Speaker 8:  Cuz like the only FPSs, I I don't play FPSs
Speaker 1:  Call of Duty is still massive. Like War Zone is still a really, really big
Speaker 1:  game. It's, you know, I know there's some Apex Legends fans here
Speaker 1:  right now, Richard, hello
Speaker 9:  With us.
Speaker 1:  But, but Call of Duty is still really, really, really big. And, and
Speaker 1:  it's not, I mean it isn't just Call of Duty, right? Like Activision owns
Speaker 1:  a lot of these other games and so it, it
Speaker 1:  makes sense that Sony's gonna be like, no. Right. That's like a
Speaker 1:  half of our catalog.
Speaker 8:  But you can play Call of Duty on your switch.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Well I think the idea is like go, if you go with
Speaker 1:  Sony, if, if Activision gets successfully bought by
Speaker 1:  Microsoft, Sony is then becomes the noon Nintendo
Speaker 1:  where they're like, we can only ha like we're just doing naughty dog games
Speaker 1:  and Spider-Man forever. And then one day we'll try, what was it?
Speaker 1:  1893? 1883. 1886.
Speaker 9:  1890, yes.
Speaker 1:  1886. There we go. That 1886 game, they're going to keep
Speaker 1:  trying to bring that back and
Speaker 9:  Make that happen. And Stray
Speaker 1:  And Stray. I didn't like Stray. Did you
Speaker 8:  Play Stray? I did not play it. But
Speaker 1:  People really like
Speaker 8:  It. I just got a gaming pc. I only had a switch. Yeah. I just got a gaming
Speaker 8:  PC for the, the first time like a couple weeks ago.
Speaker 1:  Do you just play more? That
Speaker 9:  Was your response to Stadia going away?
Speaker 8:  Yes. Okay. So Stadia was literally the only thing keeping me
Speaker 8:  from getting a pc. Yeah. Really?
Speaker 8:  Because I was using it for Elder Scrolls online. I really, really like
Speaker 8:  MMOs. Something about it, I, I can't Good, good. I can't play. Like I have
Speaker 8:  to play like one game. Yeah. With a lot of things in it. Yeah. You know,
Speaker 8:  that I can do. And so Stadia was allowing me to do that.
Speaker 8:  Stadia goes away. There are, there's nothing on the
Speaker 8:  switch.
Speaker 1:  So you just built a pc.
Speaker 8:  It didn't build one. You
Speaker 1:  Bought a, you bought a gaming pc.
Speaker 8:  I bought a laptop.
Speaker 1:  There we go. That's
Speaker 8:  Great. But it works really good cuz I went back on my MacBook and I was somehow
Speaker 8:  playing World of Warcraft at like, it was running at eight FPSs
Speaker 8:  or like 11 tops.
Speaker 1:  So you just died a lot.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. Yeah. And I was wondering why I was so bad cuz I was reading and I
Speaker 8:  thought I was really good and I thought I knew everything front and back.
Speaker 8:  But no, my frame rate, like I, my fiance's friend came over and he like looked
Speaker 8:  at my computer. He is like, that's making me sick. How are you doing? This
Speaker 8:  is making me Ill. And I guess like, I was never used to
Speaker 8:  what it should look like. And now I'm like doing stuff on my, I I
Speaker 8:  I have like the ACEs Zephyrus G 14. Yeah. I love
Speaker 8:  it. Monica
Speaker 1:  Loves that laptop.
Speaker 8:  That's why I got it. Shout out Monica. I read her review on the site. That's
Speaker 8:  great. And I got it. And it, it works amazing. I'm getting like 60 fps.
Speaker 8:  I I don't even know what that looks like. And now I'm, now it's just so fluid
Speaker 8:  and I, I don't know. Anyways, this is McKenna Discovers computers, a tech
Speaker 8:  reporter McKenna discovers computers.
Speaker 1:  It's
Speaker 9:  Great. McKenna's Gaming Corner. Needs to be a SEC segment. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  New, new segment. McKenna's Gaming Quarter
Speaker 8:  Where I learn about the games where
Speaker 1:  You're like 60 fps. This is cool. I love,
Speaker 1:  have
Speaker 8:  You guys ever seen anything like this
Speaker 1:  Before? They're so smooth.
Speaker 1:  So other, other big news. Do you have anything you wanna talk about, Richard?
Speaker 1:  We got some other news.
Speaker 9:  Well, there was the, Tesla announced a new engineering headquarters in California
Speaker 9:  this week, which I found really interesting because they just moved their
Speaker 9:  headquarters out of California.
Speaker 1:  Right. They went to Texas, right.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. But now they have another headquarters in California still. So,
Speaker 1:  But just engineering.
Speaker 9:  It's just engineering. It's, I find it interesting that it seems like
Speaker 9:  Elon is moving his manufacturing to hi to the, the location in Texas,
Speaker 9:  which coincidentally might be a bit closer to the plants in
Speaker 9:  Mexico that make the parts for the cars. Yeah. Just, just seems like a,
Speaker 9:  a weird coincidence. That weird, you know, he says that he's moving it because
Speaker 9:  of the taxes or this or that, but I think there's a really practical reason
Speaker 9:  for why these things are suddenly being set up that way. And why he would
Speaker 9:  keep his engineering. They're in California where, where there's plenty of
Speaker 9:  people to hire.
Speaker 1:  Had he successfully moved everybody from
Speaker 1:  California before this? Like had everybody relocated or was
Speaker 1:  people, or there's still holdouts, engineering holdouts specifically in
Speaker 1:  California.
Speaker 9:  That is, that is a good question. I, I won. I wonder, although they, they've
Speaker 9:  also had layoffs. They, they've had so many things at Tesla. It's, it's really
Speaker 9:  hard to say how, and they had the, we had his weird demand to come into the
Speaker 9:  office that everyone must be in the office all the time because he's in the
Speaker 9:  office and he sleeps in the office and he doesn't live anywhere else except
Speaker 9:  for when he's at Twitter, where he also lives in the office there.
Speaker 1:  He's a house. Someone get that man house. In fact, Elon
Speaker 1:  get
Speaker 9:  A house. I'm, I'm sure they, they built a really nice couple of bedrooms
Speaker 9:  in the new engineering hq.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Just for him. All right. McKenna, any any fun news for you you wanna
Speaker 1:  talk about
Speaker 8:  Today? Any fun news that I wanna talk about?
Speaker 8:  What's going on? There was scotus. We
Speaker 1:  Talked about scotus.
Speaker 8:  Okay, well rest in peace.
Speaker 8:  No, you
Speaker 1:  Don't wanna talk about the PCV boards?
Speaker 8:  What is that?
Speaker 8:  I'm learning, I'm learning. Dammit.
Speaker 1:  Tech corner. What is that? No. Gaming corner. Gaming corner. No,
Speaker 1:  there is one. There's one story I do wanna shout out. It's from Chris person
Speaker 1:  who is hanging out with us for a while. He just
Speaker 1:  revealed that if you wanna make your own keyboard and you want it to look
Speaker 1:  exactly how you want it to look, you can just like pay someone and they'll
Speaker 1:  print it and you can put little fun designs and stuff on it. Mm. And just
Speaker 1:  like print the board yourself. You do have to know soldering and a whole
Speaker 1:  lot of other words. And programming. I was learning a lot of this. I feel
Speaker 1:  like I could be an engineer working at Tesla, reading this curse person
Speaker 1:  story
Speaker 8:  Just in the corner building keyboards.
Speaker 1:  Like nobody, nobody asked me to do actual engineering work. My soldering
Speaker 1:  is dope. It is not dope. I do really bad soldering,
Speaker 1:  but maybe I'll do better with buying a keyboard and then putting like,
Speaker 1:  you can put anything on it. Like any image you just wanna put in, in like
Speaker 1:  black and white, you can do on a keyboards pcb, which I think is
Speaker 1:  really cool.
Speaker 8:  Hmm.
Speaker 9:  I love, I love the images here. I would never do any of this myself.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, you're like
Speaker 9:  That's, but I'm glad that someone else is doing.
Speaker 1:  There you go. There you go. Alright. Well
Speaker 1:  that is it for the show. We have had a very, very busy one. It has been
Speaker 1:  a very fun one. And we are gonna be back next
Speaker 1:  week. There's a new episode of our mini-series solo acts that's gonna be
Speaker 1:  on Monday. It is going to be absolutely delicious. Yes.
Speaker 1:  Because it's about Mick Ribs. I've never had one, but after listening to
Speaker 1:  this episode, you're gonna want one. It's really unfortunate because they,
Speaker 1:  you can't get 'em anywhere. And then on Wednesday we're gonna have another
Speaker 1:  great episode of the show and we'll be back on Friday. So stay
Speaker 1:  classy until then.
Speaker 7:  And that's a wrap for Vergecast this week. Thanks for listening. If you enjoy
Speaker 7:  the show, subscribe in the podcast app of your choice or tell a friend, you
Speaker 7:  can send us feedback at bcast@theverge.com. This show is produced by
Speaker 7:  me, Liam James, and our senior audio director, Andrew Marino. This
Speaker 7:  episode was edited and mixed by Amanda Rose Smith.
Speaker 7:  Our editorial director is Brooke Min and our executive producer is
Speaker 7:  Eleanor Donovan. The Verge is a production of the Verge and Box Media
Speaker 7:  Podcast network. And that's it. We'll see you next week.