# Transcript
ID: 1b8c7fbf-8bb8-4a44-9011-43295cd284d0
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Google Pixel Fold review, Microsoft vs FTC, and Congress’ child safety bills
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/6552972427028446772/-1201035579145281367/s93290-US-5878s-1687972535.mp3
Description: Today on the flagship podcast of the console wars:
02:42 - David Pierce chats with Verge senior editor Tom Warren about the five-day trial between Microsoft and the FTC that will determine the future of its $68.7 billion proposed acquisition of Activision Blizzard.
FTC v. Microsoft: all the news from the big Xbox courtroom battle
Has Xbox really lost the console wars?
Microsoft exec was ready to ‘go spend Sony out of business’ to strengthen Xbox
35:00 - Policy reporter Makena Kelly joins the show to explain what Congress is trying to do to address child safety online.
Texas bans kids from social media without parental consent
New bill would add mandatory age verification to social networks
1:03:07 - The Verge’s Allison Johnson and Dan Seifert discuss our Google Pixel Fold review, and how it stacks up against other foldables and flippables.
Google Pixel Fold review: closing the gap
The Pixel Fold shows how far ahead Samsung’s folding phones are
Motorola Razr Plus review: the right moves
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we love hearing from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Disabled
Speaker 2:  Welcome to The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of The Console Wars.
Speaker 2:  I'm your friend David Pierce and I am sitting here on my back patio
Speaker 2:  pulling weeds out from between all of the bricks back here.
Speaker 2:  you know, I really admire people who like gardening and I
Speaker 2:  kind of get why it could be cathartic and good and
Speaker 2:  whatever, and I guess like, yay for people who have green thumbs. But God,
Speaker 2:  I hate this. I've tried putting bleach out here. I've tried boiling
Speaker 2:  water, I've tried baking soda, I've tried all the weed be gone stuff.
Speaker 2:  I just wanna like carpet bomb this patio, so nothing can
Speaker 2:  ever live back here again. But I understand why that's a bad idea.
Speaker 2:  If you have suggestions though, or tips on how to make this a
Speaker 2:  less horrible process, I'm desperate. Please. Anyway,
Speaker 2:  in Happier News, we have a great show for you. Today we're gonna talk about
Speaker 2:  the FTC versus Microsoft trial and what it means for the future of video
Speaker 2:  games, plus what we're learning about the PlayStation versus Xbox fight.
Speaker 2:  There's been a lot of really good drama the last few days. Then we're gonna
Speaker 2:  talk about the latest attempts at passing legislation to protect kids online
Speaker 2:  and why we haven't really been able to do that in more than two decades.
Speaker 2:  And after that we'll talk about the Pixel Fold, the Razr Plus, and the folding
Speaker 2:  flipping future of smartphones. All that's coming in just a sec, but I
Speaker 2:  promised myself I would at least weed this back corner before I get
Speaker 2:  grumpy and quit. And I'm almost done. This is The Verge guest.
Speaker 2:  We'll be right back.
Speaker 3:  Hello, I'm Esther Perel. I'm a psychotherapist and host of
Speaker 3:  the podcast. Where should we begin? I invite you to enter
Speaker 3:  into my office and to listen in on the sessions that I
Speaker 3:  conduct with people from all walks of life, grappling
Speaker 3:  with the challenges and choices in their relationships.
Speaker 3:  I'll be dropping new episodes every Monday starting July
Speaker 3:  10, listen and follow. Where should we begin
Speaker 3:  on your favorite podcast app?
Speaker 4:  On criminal, we bring you true crime stories told by people
Speaker 4:  who know them best.
Speaker 5:  We didn't believe in setting fires cause that was too dangerous. We were,
Speaker 5:  you know, a kind, a gentler kind of crooks so to speak.
Speaker 4:  So the best plan you had was that you'd LaSow it?
Speaker 6:  Yes. Never imagined I'd use it for a camel.
Speaker 4:  I'm Phoebe Judge and this is criminal. Did you have to say what
Speaker 4:  was in the box
Speaker 7:  Phoebe? We told lies,
Speaker 4:  Listen to criminal every week, wherever you get your podcasts.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. I did it back corner's done. Only most
Speaker 2:  of the patio to go. But let's get to it. As of right now, as you're
Speaker 2:  hearing this, we're on day four of a supposedly five day trial between
Speaker 2:  Microsoft and the FTC, which will determine the future of Microsoft's
Speaker 2:  68.7 billion acquisition of Activision
Speaker 2:  Blizzard. Microsoft only has a few weeks left to get this deal done
Speaker 2:  or renegotiated entirely. The UK has already decided to block the deal
Speaker 2:  and the last few days at this trial has basically been a
Speaker 2:  parade of gaming executives dishing about the state of the industry.
Speaker 2:  We've learned a ton from this trial. So we grabbed the verges, Tom Warren
Speaker 2:  to walk us through it and tell us what's coming next. Hi Tom.
Speaker 8:  Hello.
Speaker 2:  Thank you for taking a break from like the deep, deep chaos of the last several
Speaker 2:  days to do this with us. I know,
Speaker 8:  I, I need a break. I need a beer, an holiday and yeah, just
Speaker 8:  everything.
Speaker 2:  Okay, so this trial is not over, like we said at the top. There's more to
Speaker 2:  come, but let's rewind a little bit because obviously this
Speaker 2:  Microsoft Activision Blizzard thing has been going on for a while. Coming
Speaker 2:  into the trial though I don't wanna start it all the way at the beginning,
Speaker 2:  but I do wanna go back six days ago,
Speaker 8:  Right,
Speaker 2:  Coming into the trial. What was your sense of sort of the leading theory
Speaker 2:  about what might happen? Obviously this, this deal has been litigated
Speaker 2:  elsewhere, which we should get into. There have been lots of questions. There
Speaker 2:  have been sort of pieces of evidence coming out for a long time. Was there
Speaker 2:  kind of a running theory as to who was more likely to win this
Speaker 2:  case coming in?
Speaker 8:  Yeah, I think, I think most people probably assume that the FTC will lose,
Speaker 8:  but then most people assumed that the cma, the Competition Markets
Speaker 8:  authority in the UK would approve the deal and they didn't. so like interesting
Speaker 8:  and I think in this case from following it from January, 2022 when
Speaker 8:  they first announced it to, to now is like anything can happen. It's is the,
Speaker 8:  it is the main thing I've learned anything and everything cause it's such
Speaker 8:  a big acquisition, it's like Michael's biggest acquisition
Speaker 8:  and there's obviously regulators in the US wanna crack down on big
Speaker 8:  tech. So this is like a test case almost for it. And yeah, I,
Speaker 8:  I think the feeling is still that the FTC could potentially lose the
Speaker 8:  case just because it's, it's quite hard to win a preliminary injunction
Speaker 8:  cuz you, you have to prove that there's gonna be immediate harm or
Speaker 8:  you know that this is gonna cause anti-competitive effects if, if Microsoft
Speaker 8:  goes and closes the deal. The reason it's all kind of come about right now
Speaker 8:  is because Microsoft has a cutoff date of July 18th the, the terms of the
Speaker 8:  deal of Activision. So there's a sense of a bit of rush there
Speaker 8:  and a sense of some behind the scenes sort of Microsoft perhaps
Speaker 8:  saying to the cma, we're gonna close overview and maybe
Speaker 8:  potentially separate the exports business in the UK and the FTC hearing
Speaker 8:  about that in press reports panicking and finding the pre preliminary
Speaker 8:  junction. But I still feel like it's gonna be difficult for them to win it
Speaker 8:  and on on on their sort of merits of what they're trying to argue. And I
Speaker 8:  don't think they're, I think from what we've heard as well, they're not necessarily
Speaker 8:  making a good case. I think they're, some of their arguments are really sound
Speaker 8:  but some of them just aren't. And it's like those ones that aren't are the
Speaker 8:  ones that the judges kind of feels like she's most interested in like Call
Speaker 8:  of Duty and stuff because obviously that's been a a running thing over the
Speaker 8:  past sort of year or so as well.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, so it seems to me, and I want to get into some of the specific things
Speaker 2:  we found, cuz I think this case more than most has been full of like really
Speaker 2:  fascinating sort of small details. But it seems to me that the big
Speaker 2:  story that this trial has turned into, and I guess it's kind of
Speaker 2:  two stories, but it's also sort of one story is basically
Speaker 2:  PlayStation versus Xbox and yeah, on on one level it's about
Speaker 2:  the competition between those two things and their respective consoles. And
Speaker 2:  then on the other level it's about whether Nintendo is a real
Speaker 2:  competitor to those two as well. So it's kind of w who is
Speaker 2:  winning this fight and then who is winning that larger fight and
Speaker 2:  is that larger fight the same as this fight and this is where it gets messy,
Speaker 2:  but like why did this become PlayStation versus
Speaker 2:  Xbox so quickly and so aggressively.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, I mean that's obviously emerged sort of with regulatory filings in
Speaker 8:  the UK and some of the EU stuff that we've seen
Speaker 8:  back and forth over the sort of past year as well that Sony's obviously opposed
Speaker 8:  the deal and has been very vocal about that in their filings, which
Speaker 2:  It would Right. Just people keep seeming surprised that Sony would be mad
Speaker 2:  about Microsoft buying Activision, but like of course it is, right? Yeah,
Speaker 8:  You'd assume so, right, but I think so that the day one sort of
Speaker 8:  how it all went down on day one was there was this bond show email from
Speaker 8:  Sony PlayStation chief Jim Ryan who apparently said a few days
Speaker 8:  after the deal was announced by Microsoft that you know, it's not an
Speaker 8:  Xbox exclusivity play and that he doesn't have to worry about Call
Speaker 8:  of Duty being exclusive and that Microsoft's thinking bigger than that. And
Speaker 8:  he basically said that in an email to a former c Sony CEO who he's obviously
Speaker 8:  friends with and has known for years, who's, I think he was his previous
Speaker 8:  boss in, you know, decades ago. But yeah, so he had that sort of
Speaker 8:  impression that Jim Ryan knew all along that it wasn't about Xbox
Speaker 8:  exclusivity and that Sony was never really worried about that all along.
Speaker 8:  So that's kind of where Mikes was coming at it from, Sony's been moaning
Speaker 8:  to regulators, all this sort of stuff. And then on day two actually we'll
Speaker 8:  get back to the rest of day one, but on day two we actually had an exchange,
Speaker 8:  another exchange around that email where it was brought up again and then
Speaker 8:  there was like dates where there was some email back and forth and then
Speaker 8:  basically Microsoft insinuating that Jim Ryan and Sony
Speaker 8:  hadn't complained to regulators until after a specific
Speaker 8:  email in on the August 26th, 2022. Now that date is kind of
Speaker 8:  important because before then we hadn't heard about Sony being
Speaker 8:  against the deal. There's obviously talk and and press and all that sort
Speaker 8:  of stuff, but apparently Phil Spencer, so the export chief sent a list
Speaker 8:  of games that would be available in PlayStation to to Jim Ryan
Speaker 2:  And it was not an impressive list of games.
Speaker 8:  No, yeah, he wasn't, he wasn't impressed with the games cuz one of them was
Speaker 8:  Overwatch, but Overwatch two wasn't on there even though Overwatch two
Speaker 8:  hadn't totally come out at that time, but whatever. But the point was that
Speaker 8:  they didn't include all the games that they would expect to be on there.
Speaker 8:  So that's, that triggered the alarm bells. Just days after that
Speaker 8:  email was sent, Phil Spencer said to The Verge that called G was
Speaker 8:  gonna remain on PlayStation for a few more years. That kicked off another
Speaker 8:  sort of public thing with between them. So obviously the communication had
Speaker 8:  broken down over that 26th of August email and it all went, started
Speaker 8:  going public. And what Mike's are saying is, well, Sony didn't have a problem
Speaker 8:  with this deal. We, we were, we were sort of working out a deal between us
Speaker 8:  for the six months or or more. And then they just went rogue and went to
Speaker 8:  regulators and started complaining and saying, yeah, cool. Review's gonna
Speaker 8:  be exclusive even though they knew all along it wouldn't be and all this.
Speaker 8:  So that's Microsoft's argument. So it has descended into this whole Sony
Speaker 8:  versus Microsoft thing pretty much every day. And then the Nintendo Switch
Speaker 8:  part is kind of interesting also really annoying to hear every day.
Speaker 2:  It just comes like every 10 minutes, somebody keeps bringing up the switch
Speaker 2:  it seems
Speaker 8:  Like. Yeah, swear someone's gonna like just butt in and be like Switch, just
Speaker 8:  shout it from the audience or something one day. But the, the core argument
Speaker 8:  of that is that basically the FTC is defined the console market as a high
Speaker 8:  performance one between Sony and Microsoft, say Xbox and PlayStation. It
Speaker 8:  excludes the switch in that argument saying that it's a mobile sort of device,
Speaker 8:  you know, a portable game console, which it is. And that it doesn't compete
Speaker 8:  with Xbox and PlayStation, which it does, let's be honest. They, they all
Speaker 8:  compete with each other, it's just a little bit different.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I feel like that's one of those where they, they've spent all this
Speaker 2:  time sort of very carefully litigating whether it does or doesn't,
Speaker 2:  but I feel like yeah, the much more useful thing would just be like ask a
Speaker 2:  hundred people if they're competitive and I suspect 99 of them at least would
Speaker 2:  say, yeah, of course they're competitive,
Speaker 8:  But all those 99 people also agree they're very different. Sure. Those those
Speaker 8:  consoles. Right. So, and I think that's what they're kind of trying to lean
Speaker 8:  on to say that they don't compete. Sure. And then, then there's some Microsoft
Speaker 8:  internal analysis which where they just compete against PlayStation and it's
Speaker 8:  clear that Microsoft and Sony are sort of goes head to head cuz the switch,
Speaker 8:  the power of the switch is slightly behind anyway for, for the sort of game.
Speaker 8:  So, so that has been a running theme cause you f TOC has been adamant
Speaker 8:  about proving that because it is very key because it, it it, it defines the
Speaker 8:  market and it means whether Microsoft has nearly 50% of the market in the
Speaker 8:  US so they're not talking globally or whether it has, you know, it's in a
Speaker 8:  distant third according to Phil Spencer globally. So it does,
Speaker 8:  it does matter like that, that is a key point and it's why they keep hammering
Speaker 8:  it every single time you, you'll get through an hour of testimonial and then
Speaker 8:  it'll come up, you get through an hour round, then it'll come up like it,
Speaker 8:  there's this constant back and forth throughout this case. I'm sure it'll
Speaker 8:  come up again today cuz Nvidia are there talking about cloud gaming. You
Speaker 8:  got Satya Nadella and Bobby Kotick, so there's definitely gonna
Speaker 8:  be some more stuff about the switch in there. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  But it seems like Microsoft's the, the switch is so useful to Microsoft
Speaker 2:  because it seems like the biggest thing Microsoft is trying to do here is
Speaker 2:  play this like, woe is us, we're so tiny,
Speaker 2:  the Xbox is a miserable failure, everybody hates it. And we're,
Speaker 2:  we're buying this company in order to give ourselves
Speaker 2:  just like a tiny little fighting chance in the gaming
Speaker 2:  wars. And on the one hand there are like numbers that
Speaker 2:  support some of that narrative, but on the other hand, like
Speaker 2:  this is Microsoft, it is one of the largest, most successful companies on
Speaker 2:  earth. Xbox has been around for a long time, they're spending 70 billion,
Speaker 2:  which is not what you do with your like failing tiny little business. Is
Speaker 2:  that argument working at all? Like, do you get any sense that Microsoft is
Speaker 2:  successfully painting itself as like the hapless loser in the gaming industry?
Speaker 8:  Yeah, I I don't think that argument really washes. Does it like it it it
Speaker 8:  does in certain circumstances like sure they are probably third in the console
Speaker 8:  market. Like I think that's, that's clear. They're, they're behind the switch,
Speaker 8:  behind the PlayStation, but they also, like the Xbox business isn't terrible,
Speaker 8:  right? Like, he had Phil Spencer saying, you know, we're distant third,
Speaker 8:  we haven't able to compete with PlayStation. But then a week before that,
Speaker 8:  you know, behind closed door meeting, he's saying the exports
Speaker 8:  revenues now are, are more than they were in the 360 era. And they have all
Speaker 8:  these crazy targets that they're hitting, they're doing going for PC game
Speaker 8:  pass growth. And it's like all the positives that investors want hear.
Speaker 8:  So where is the middle line essentially? Like what, what's the reality
Speaker 8:  of the situation? I I think it's like the exports business is, is healthy,
Speaker 8:  but Microsoft has way bigger targets for it internally. And in
Speaker 8:  that respect it's not competing with, with PlayStation. So what
Speaker 8:  they've been trying to say, like Phil Spencer's obviously tried to target
Speaker 8:  buying zinger. They had some talks with, with them for mobile.
Speaker 8:  They've also looked at Sega as well potentially for mobile and
Speaker 8:  and console. But ultimately they're, they're saying that their strategy came
Speaker 8:  around Activision Blizzard for mobile for like Call of Duty mobile
Speaker 8:  and the sort of Candy Crush games that King makes. So they're, they're trying
Speaker 8:  to center it around that, that's our opportunity going forward. So
Speaker 8:  they're trying to say that it's not really gonna make a big difference in
Speaker 8:  consoles, although it probably will because they're gonna have control of
Speaker 8:  Call of Duty and the FTC argues if they have control of Call
Speaker 8:  of Duty and Sony argues as well that will they, you know,
Speaker 8:  essentially make it worse on the PlayStation or, or make it less, you know,
Speaker 8:  even putting it on Game Pass is gonna make it more appealing for
Speaker 8:  you to switch to exports. Right. I think we can all agree that that's probably
Speaker 8:  a thing that you might think, do I wanna pay 70 bucks or should I get a,
Speaker 8:  like should I get an export? So you have to, as someone who likes Call Duty
Speaker 8:  might start thinking that way and then, and then they've had some economic
Speaker 8:  analysis around that. But nothing, nothing that I would say is you could
Speaker 8:  prove it your way. You, you can use analysis models, financial models,
Speaker 8:  all sorts of stuff to sort of guess stuff, but who knows really what's gonna
Speaker 8:  happen. Right.
Speaker 2:  But the College of Duty piece of this does seem important because I think
Speaker 2:  one of my questions coming into this was why is this
Speaker 2:  specific acquisition the one that's being litigated? And I think this question
Speaker 2:  has come up over and over, right? Because there is this question of we're
Speaker 2:  arguing about game exclusives and, and like everyone on all sides keeps
Speaker 2:  reminding the judge in this case that every company has exclusives, gaming
Speaker 2:  exclusives are like foundational to how the gaming industry works. Sony
Speaker 2:  has them, Nintendo has them, Microsoft has them. Like this is just, this
Speaker 2:  is just how business is done in the gaming industry. So it's like, okay,
Speaker 2:  why are we mad at Microsoft for trying to get itself some
Speaker 2:  exclusives? And it's, that's complicated. And I think it's mostly just because
Speaker 2:  the FTCs only move to be mad about it is when acquisitions like this happen.
Speaker 2:  So it's just sort of picked its moment to have this bigger fight. Yeah. But
Speaker 2:  then it does seem like there is something potentially unique
Speaker 2:  about Call of Duty, both as like an economic engine and also just like
Speaker 2:  the place it holds in the gaming industry. Yeah. It's just
Speaker 2:  so specifically important to this industry that it, it can
Speaker 2:  actually make those changes in a way that other exclusives can't.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, I think, I think there's a couple of things. So Call of Duty is obviously
Speaker 8:  massive and it is, it's, it's also the fact that they deliver a, a version
Speaker 8:  of Call of Duty pretty much every year. Mm. As a AA game that's kind of
Speaker 8:  unheard of in the industry. I mean you have like FIFA and Madden and stuff
Speaker 8:  like that. It to fair
Speaker 2:  To fair it's basically the same game every year most of the time. Exactly.
Speaker 2:  But it is
Speaker 8:  Still a game. They changed the crowd, you know? Right. Yeah. It's very iterative
Speaker 8:  isn't it? But the but, but Call of Duty has a narrative driven story
Speaker 8:  content every year without fail pretty much. And that, that is very different
Speaker 8:  of a game to, to sort of other games really in such, in such
Speaker 8:  a way that they do it as where it's so popular as well. So it is different.
Speaker 8:  I would totally agree there. But it's also the other aspect to all of this
Speaker 8:  is Microsoft only Call of Duty is they're only Activision, they're only a
Speaker 8:  big publisher, right? Like that's, Microsoft is obviously a publisher but
Speaker 8:  they are a platform holder as well. They own exports. So if they own
Speaker 8:  a lot of the content as well and that's obviously what they're trying to
Speaker 8:  build for Game Pass and cloud streaming eventually is that the, the power
Speaker 8:  shifts sort switch it switches and network where, where Sony's been buying
Speaker 8:  up individual studios, not necessarily big publishers. Microsoft's obviously
Speaker 8:  going after the publishers like Division Blizzard is, is is a giant one for
Speaker 8:  them. Like if they, if they have that they own such a wider range of
Speaker 8:  content that they can, they can license that they can do it, do what they
Speaker 8:  want with it really. And it really enforces their content library.
Speaker 8:  So Jim Ryan testified yesterday that he doesn't think cloud gaming will be
Speaker 8:  a thing until like 2025 between 2025 and 2035. So
Speaker 8:  he's not thinking it's, it's gonna be a thing for a while. But obviously
Speaker 8:  Microsoft's thinking, well they were and now they claim they're not. But
Speaker 8:  they that that Microsoft is thinking ahead to this cloud era
Speaker 8:  and obviously in that cloud cloud era you need this content and content is
Speaker 8:  key. Call of Duty is obviously key there. If they can deliver that every
Speaker 8:  year from, from now on and ca carry on that cadence and, and get people
Speaker 8:  into Game Pass and and paying for that subscription, then the fear from the
Speaker 8:  FTC side is well what happens when they raise prices down the line? What
Speaker 8:  happens when it's monopolist behavior when they've got all this content?
Speaker 8:  That's the fear. It's not necessarily about impacting consoles cause it's
Speaker 8:  such a small market, but it's how does it affect cloud and in into the mobile
Speaker 8:  gaming market If, if Microsoft's ever able to sort of stream these games
Speaker 8:  reliably to mobile phones, if Apple lets them in the app store or is forced
Speaker 8:  to, eventually that opens up a bigger market. Microsofts looking
Speaker 8:  at by the building and exports game store as well for mobile. So they
Speaker 8:  obviously have big broad ambitions for, for mobile and how that plays into
Speaker 8:  the cloud and stuff. But
Speaker 2:  They've spent a bunch of time during this trial playing those down,
Speaker 2:  right? Like Phil, Phil Spencer and others have kind of come out and said,
Speaker 2:  well we had these big cloud plans, now we're walking them back.
Speaker 2:  Apple won't let us. Like I Is that more of the sort of apples
Speaker 2:  loser strategy or is there actually something there?
Speaker 8:  Yeah, I I mean. So, so there was some testimony from Sarah Bond on the first
Speaker 8:  day where the FTC brought up that last year they were looking at a separate
Speaker 8:  skew, a dedicated version of X cloud exports, cloud gaming, which I think
Speaker 8:  we all kind of assumed would happen. It's been interesting over the past
Speaker 8:  year of X Cloud, Microsoft kind of went, they, they announced a bunch of
Speaker 8:  stuff they were gonna do this streaming device, Xbox cloud gaming on the
Speaker 8:  tv, all of you have content library in X Cloud. And then
Speaker 8:  since the regulators have kind of been involved with this deal, it's all
Speaker 8:  gone quite like that, that that whole library that was supposed to come,
Speaker 8:  supposed to be here by the end of the next year at end of last year, we haven't
Speaker 8:  heard anything about it. That, that that streaming console was
Speaker 8:  mysteriously canceled even though Microsoft was about to announce it.
Speaker 8:  Like they were definitely ready to announce it.
Speaker 2:  We saw it like sitting above behind Phil Spencer in a video, right? Like
Speaker 2:  it was real, it was there.
Speaker 8:  You could argue they've had the strategy shift cuz that that's what Sarah
Speaker 8:  Bon argues, that they looked at the pricing for it and the usage and they
Speaker 8:  thought, okay, we can't introduce this now. Which is probably fair. They,
Speaker 8:  the I mean, let's be honest, no one really uses cloud. Microsoft says
Speaker 8:  they think most people just use it to try games before they download them,
Speaker 8:  which is probably true. That's it's likely true. But at the same time
Speaker 8:  it's are they just pausing work on this stuff until regulators are outta
Speaker 8:  the question and then, and then they can spin it all up again. And at the
Speaker 8:  same time, you've obviously got Sony who hasn't really built a cloud network
Speaker 8:  for PS five, but now they're saying, oh we've, we were building it and testing
Speaker 8:  it now and we're gonna bring it to our subscriptions first. Our subscribers
Speaker 8:  at some point and they're also creating a, a handheld that only plays PS
Speaker 8:  five games that streamed over wifi and presumably over this, this cloud service
Speaker 8:  that they're building now. so like there's, there's obviously they're both
Speaker 8:  putting in sort of a lot of work leading to this
Speaker 8:  cloud sort of war even though everyone's play clouds and they think it sucks
Speaker 8:  now, but it's not gonna forever be like that. Right? So streaming
Speaker 8:  videos on the internet in the early days was terrible until YouTube came
Speaker 8:  along pretty upended everything.
Speaker 2:  So even as Microsoft is saying cloud is the future, we think the
Speaker 2:  console market is small and the cloud market is huge and this is the thing,
Speaker 2:  this is how we get to mobile, all this stuff. They're also saying outside
Speaker 2:  out the other side of their mouth, the console market is small and we're
Speaker 2:  not doing anything else. Why are you so worried about it? Right? Like that's
Speaker 2:  the regulatory story. While they're saying to investors, there's this bigger
Speaker 2:  thing on the horizon.
Speaker 8:  Yeah they, they're saying like the console market is is stagnant essentially
Speaker 8:  and they can't compete in it because obviously Sony's got a bunch of exclusives
Speaker 8:  and they don't, so they need to buy out that content for that. But that the
Speaker 8:  bigger argument is that they're doing it for mobile and then if, if you,
Speaker 8:  if you believe that argument then they're a really small player in mobile
Speaker 8:  right now, so, so who cares. But if you think they're just saying that, that
Speaker 8:  they're going into mobile I mean obviously they are because that's a big
Speaker 8:  revenue opportunity. But also you could still pull back some of that console
Speaker 8:  revenue at the same time as well. Right. They're not surely they don't think
Speaker 8:  that they're not gonna sell more exports consoles if they have a bunch of
Speaker 8:  Activision exclusives, you know, and if they don't have to compete with Sony
Speaker 8:  having a marketing agreement for Call of Duty like, like they do
Speaker 8:  until 2025. So it is always, it's always in the middle, right? These arguments.
Speaker 8:  So, but I, I feel like they're definitely still gearing up for that
Speaker 8:  cloud gaming thing that's not something that they've just suddenly given
Speaker 8:  up on. They've probably slowed it down a bit. The reasons behind that you
Speaker 8:  can take it of one of two ways. Was it regulator pressure
Speaker 8:  or was it you know, strategy and or was it a mix of both? Probably a mix
Speaker 8:  of both arguably. But yeah like they're not
Speaker 8:  gonna take the, the pedal off of that cloud work that's for sure.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, no that makes a lot of sense. I wanna talk about Pete Heinz who I think
Speaker 2:  was one of the most interesting piece of
Speaker 2:  testimony from this whole week. He is like a publishing executive
Speaker 2:  at Bethesda, is that right?
Speaker 8:  Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 2:  Which is a big Microsoft publisher. Like this is, this is the last one that
Speaker 2:  they could have done this for before this one. He said a few things that
Speaker 2:  I thought were really interesting. One was he just, he I mean he just shredded
Speaker 2:  the red fall game to bits like over and over and over again.
Speaker 8:  He's like some people might call it a triple A but I don't know.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And then he was like, oh yeah basically this game sucked so don't hold
Speaker 2:  it against us. Sorry everybody. Yeah but the other thing he said that I thought
Speaker 2:  was really interesting was talking about, well A then he also said that the
Speaker 2:  Indiana Jones game is gonna be an Xbox and PC exclusive, which seems
Speaker 2:  like a bad look for Microsoft trying to
Speaker 2:  prove its point because that's presumably gonna be a big game that a lot
Speaker 2:  of people care about, right? Definitely. But then he also just talked about
Speaker 2:  kind of how Bethesda came to be a Microsoft company, which I thought was
Speaker 2:  really interesting and that was when a lot of this kind of debate about how
Speaker 2:  Sony handles third parties and what Sony is doing with its
Speaker 2:  exclusive stuff came up. Like what did we learn from his testimony on that
Speaker 2:  front?
Speaker 8:  Yeah, I think we learned that Pete Hees was a bit
Speaker 8:  uncomfortable having to do Xbox exclusives initially,
Speaker 8:  although on the stand he wasn't in in the emails and stuff, it paints a
Speaker 8:  picture of him being like, I think, I think a lot of it is when you get acquired
Speaker 8:  by a big company and you go, you know, they try to integrate you in Microsoft
Speaker 8:  hasn't really necessarily integrated Bethesda in fully yet. So there's that
Speaker 8:  like us and them mentality still cuz it's still very
Speaker 8:  run separately and stuff. So I think some of it was like well hang on,
Speaker 8:  Microsoft's promised Sony that they're gonna keep Call of Duty on
Speaker 8:  PlayStation. This was like an email. And he's like, but that's
Speaker 8:  one's you know, opposite to what they said to us, we we were gonna you know,
Speaker 8:  make Redford and Starfield exclusive cause they obviously came in, we know
Speaker 8:  cuz one of the Redford developers said that they yanked the PS five version
Speaker 8:  of the game and obviously we know from this testimony that it was also
Speaker 8:  possibly gonna be a timed or some sort of exclusivity for PS five
Speaker 8:  for for Starfield. So obviously Moses has come in and said no
Speaker 8:  you ain't doing PlayStation, it's Xbox now. So I
Speaker 8:  think we learned that he was not necessarily comfortable with that and he
Speaker 8:  FTC brought up some, some YouTube interview, I think it was with
Speaker 8:  GameSpot when they said that they, you know, was gonna, Starfield was gonna
Speaker 8:  be Xbox exclusive and how he was apologizing to PS five players
Speaker 8:  about it. Right. Which is like ooh, you know at the time it was
Speaker 8:  ooh but when you read all the emails it kind of like makes sense. It's that
Speaker 8:  uneasiness of doing exclusives. But then at the same time when he was on
Speaker 8:  the stand he then defended exclusives which was yeah, what Microsoft
Speaker 8:  would expect him to do, right for Indiana Jones for example. That was obviously
Speaker 8:  that had a, a contract with Disney for it to be on multiple consoles
Speaker 8:  and then obviously Microsoft acquired Bethesda then that changed
Speaker 8:  and it became Xbox and PC and he defended it saying you know,
Speaker 8:  like essentially it makes it more streamlined for us to dev
Speaker 8:  develop this game for which is true, you know, sure you didn't have to worry
Speaker 8:  about multiple consoles, all that sort of stuff. That is, that is true and
Speaker 8:  he defended it in that sort of way and he, he said
Speaker 8:  something to the effect of like, we wouldn't be shipping Starfield, you know,
Speaker 8:  however many weeks it is, eight weeks or whatever it is. If we were
Speaker 8:  also on PlayStation insinuating and the, you know, having those mob platforms
Speaker 8:  slows down the game development which obviously is is true as well.
Speaker 8:  So yeah, so it's obviously he's slightly changed his mind
Speaker 8:  from from the emails but I think some of these emails were just frustration
Speaker 8:  right at at having to explain this stuff to play to to players and gamers
Speaker 8:  for sure.
Speaker 2:  But I do think if I'm the FTC lawyers, that's one piece of it where
Speaker 2:  you're like, yes we got one because yeah, the, the case they're trying to
Speaker 2:  make here essentially is that Microsoft can say all the right things for
Speaker 2:  as long as it wants until the acquisition closes and then it can just change
Speaker 2:  its mind about how all of this works and there's really nothing to
Speaker 2:  prevent it from making all of those changes. Like Phil Spencer,
Speaker 2:  what like literally raised his hand and was like we will keep Call of Duty
Speaker 2:  on the PlayStation five and it's like the number five is doing a lot of work
Speaker 2:  in that sentence but also like they can say this stuff all they want but
Speaker 2:  there's very little to prevent them from making this change other than if
Speaker 2:  there is sort of an economic benefit to it. And what the Bethesda example
Speaker 2:  seems to prove is that maybe even if there is, there are things that outweigh
Speaker 2:  that economic benefit. So if I'm the FTC it's like look, they've done this
Speaker 2:  before, this is the worst case scenario. The thing we're trying to avoid
Speaker 8:  And I think that's like Microsoft is happy for the conversation to be all
Speaker 8:  about Call of Duty cuz they can have Phil Spencer stand there on oath and
Speaker 8:  say you know, I swear I'll put my hand up, this is gonna be on PlayStation,
Speaker 8:  you don't have to worry about it. But as soon as it veers into like all of
Speaker 8:  Activision games then it starts to get murky, right? Cuz they obviously wanna
Speaker 8:  pick and choose which ones like they did with Bethesda, which ones to make
Speaker 8:  exclusive and then which ones to say okay yeah we have to have that on the
Speaker 8:  PlayStation because in their best interests for revenue, right? Like they're
Speaker 8:  not gonna pull a game. Like they're not gonna pull call a G from PlayStation
Speaker 8:  are they, when there's tons of revenue opportunity there,
Speaker 2:  It's like capitalist suicide to not sell to Call of Duty to most
Speaker 2:  people. Yeah that's, it would be a terrible idea
Speaker 8:  But, but over the years when they try and sort of sway pull people towards
Speaker 8:  Game Pass with those incentives and they have all the market, they, they're
Speaker 8:  not gonna give Sony a marketing deal for court of duty are they, you know,
Speaker 8:  in in those commercials you see at the end of like football games and stuff
Speaker 8:  like that. You're not, this is going be all experts now. So that will
Speaker 8:  eventually push people over I think is the FTCs argument as well.
Speaker 2:  Let's come back to the cloud and mobile thing really fast because that seems
Speaker 2:  to be as we kind of look out to the next few years of where
Speaker 2:  this would go, that seems to be kind of the big open question, right? It's
Speaker 2:  like the, is Nintendo a real competitor is the sort of right now question
Speaker 2:  but like how big is cloud and how much is Xbox gonna matter
Speaker 2:  on mobile in the next like 10 years is kind of the the unknown thing everybody's
Speaker 2:  trying to figure out. And Nvidia ended up playing a surprisingly big
Speaker 2:  role in this in a way that I really didn't know any of the history of
Speaker 2:  how did it come to be that Nvidia ended up on the stand here at all?
Speaker 8:  Yeah, so Nvidia was on the stand briefly yesterday but they've been referenced
Speaker 8:  a bunch throughout the day. So essentially when they first did
Speaker 8:  G-Force, now they, their cloud gaming streaming service and they had
Speaker 8:  a beta of it and it had a bunch of television games on it including Call
Speaker 8:  of Duty and they had some sort of weird agreement with Blizzard
Speaker 8:  around those games apparently and that they were there on beta
Speaker 8:  and then Activision were like now we're gonna pull it. So they pulled those
Speaker 8:  games off of off of there and that was their stance cause they obviously
Speaker 8:  were happy to play around with it and be part of this new thing
Speaker 8:  cuz it was emerging there. I mean obviously cloud is still very nascent but,
Speaker 8:  but they were obviously happy to be there early on but then they were like,
Speaker 8:  hang on a minute, we can make some money here, we should lock this up. Like
Speaker 2:  It reminds me of like the early days of Netflix when everybody, Netflix is
Speaker 2:  like, we wanna stream stuff on the internet and all the studios were like
Speaker 2:  whatever, okay here you go, give us $10, we'll call it a day. And then everybody's
Speaker 2:  like, oh this is actually successful and might be a thing like hold on, yeah
Speaker 2:  let's let's have a new conversation. Yeah, it feels like that's what happened
Speaker 2:  here too. Exactly.
Speaker 8:  Yeah so, so they were involved obviously there and then you had Matt
Speaker 8:  Buty the experts, game studios chief who had recommended
Speaker 8:  once they acquired Bethesda to pull their games off of GForce now
Speaker 8:  and that they'd already pulled their own ones. The Microsoft first party
Speaker 8:  one Xbox ones not as, not to compete with X Cloud
Speaker 8:  but it was the quote so it's obviously they don't, they don't want those
Speaker 8:  games on there cause they compete with their own streaming service and that
Speaker 8:  was the strategy back in, I think that was 2021, that email and then obviously
Speaker 8:  you come to this year when regulatory pressure,
Speaker 8:  particularly the CMA of obviously blocked over cloud concerns this deal
Speaker 8:  and the EU was sort of hinting at cloud concerns as well. Microsoft went
Speaker 8:  out and done a bunch of deals with cloud gaming companies like Boost Steroid
Speaker 8:  and Nvidia. So basically offer them their own export PC games
Speaker 8:  on the service and you know, if the deal closes Call of Duty and other ads
Speaker 8:  provision titles. So they've obviously played a key role because they were
Speaker 8:  opposed to the deal initially when the FTC and the CMA and all
Speaker 8:  that were doing, you know, talking to Nvidia, they were like, yeah we
Speaker 8:  don't want this deal because obviously they've had their games pulled off
Speaker 8:  the service but in Microsoft swooped in, I was like here's a deal. And then
Speaker 8:  they were like, we love you Microsoft, please whatever
Speaker 8:  we said before to the FTC, it is irrelevant, right? So obviously the
Speaker 8:  FTC is trying to say that, you know, like Microsoft has got this deal but
Speaker 8:  interestingly the FTC kind of causes deals like irrelevant and the terms
Speaker 8:  of them aren't very good. We don't really know the terms obviously we haven't,
Speaker 8:  you know, we haven't got the, the deal sort of documented in front of us.
Speaker 8:  So it is interesting to see that. But they have argued in a roundabout way
Speaker 8:  that the deals obviously mean people still have to have a Windows license
Speaker 8:  like the the, the actual companies have to a Windows server license to serve
Speaker 8:  these games and they brought sort of stadia on the stand to say that as well.
Speaker 8:  And obviously Chief Horse now we've seen a little bit of testimony
Speaker 8:  around that, not too much, it was like a nine minute video but it kind of
Speaker 8:  like half backed the FTC a little bit and then it was like Microsoft
Speaker 8:  came in and just said well you know, we signed these deals and they're like
Speaker 8:  yeah it is great, it solves our problems literally. So it's like
Speaker 8:  they've had an interesting role to play for sure but, but based on the fact
Speaker 8:  that their games were blocked initially by big publishers.
Speaker 2:  Okay, so we have one more day of real testimony including like you said Satya
Speaker 2:  Nadella and Bobby Kodak and then we have closing arguments on Thursday. A
Speaker 2:  any, any sort of big things you're expecting big like unknown
Speaker 2:  open questions left for the next day or so of this.
Speaker 8:  Well I guess we had Jim Ryan yesterday who basically testified
Speaker 8:  that he spoke to Bobby Kotick at some European Commission
Speaker 8:  meetings earlier this year and he said he just wanted to block the deal and
Speaker 8:  that Bobby was trying to negotiate some sort of Call of Duty deal
Speaker 8:  if their transaction failed. So obviously Bobby's paying to both sides, right?
Speaker 8:  Yeah because sure business, which was interesting. So I dunno whether Bobby
Speaker 8:  Kotick will be questioned about that potentially I, I'd assume and some of
Speaker 8:  the, some of the deals but also Sarah Bond mentioned in her
Speaker 8:  testimony that Activision almost forced Microsoft into
Speaker 8:  renegotiating the rate that they give publishers. So
Speaker 8:  it's usually a 70 30 split, right? That's pretty typical. Apple does it Google
Speaker 8:  every, everyone does that split right to a certain degree and they've actually
Speaker 8:  been negotiating 80 twenties with some publishers and
Speaker 8:  apparently Activision to force them to negotiate that split to get Call of
Speaker 8:  Duty optimized for export series X at launch when they'd already
Speaker 8:  negotiated with Sony. So they were kind of using it as a beating stick saying,
Speaker 8:  you know, PS five's gonna have an optimized version of Call of Duty but you
Speaker 8:  won't unless you give us more revenue from every game sale. So that'll be
Speaker 8:  interesting to hear whether that comes up. So I think that the Bobby code
Speaker 8:  te testimony could be interesting. Satya Nadella, as much as I love him,
Speaker 8:  is not the most interesting to hear from
Speaker 2:  Not a gamer that man I don't
Speaker 8:  Think. Not a gamer, no. So I, I'm not sure, I'm not entirely sure how his
Speaker 8:  testimony is gonna go, but I mean he's, he's obviously, he's a very intelligent
Speaker 8:  and he speaks very well and he, he's very aware of
Speaker 8:  the I mean he might not be a gamer but he's very aware of the gaming market.
Speaker 8:  So I think we're gonna get some interesting insights into exactly why
Speaker 8:  he is willing to give the company or the, the exports division
Speaker 8:  his biggest ever acquisition when apparently they're third place in consoles
Speaker 8:  and struggling and all that sort of stuff. So I think we, we, we get some
Speaker 8:  sort of color around that. But yeah, today's obviously the big day with the
Speaker 8:  big CEOs but I think we have had the other big days with the fact
Speaker 8:  the Phil Spencer testimony and the Jim Ryan testimony that those, Jim Ryans
Speaker 8:  was quite kind of small but Phil's was quite large and quite a lot of stuff
Speaker 8:  covered in that. So it's particularly his feelings about Sony's, you know,
Speaker 8:  evil competition, all this sort of stuff. So I feel like we're recap on some
Speaker 8:  of that sort of stuff and yeah, it could be an interesting day, but I think
Speaker 8:  the biggest testimony we've already had, I think personally
Speaker 2:  Makes sense. All right, well you gotta go get ready for that and we need
Speaker 2:  to take a break, but thank you Tom as always, good luck. I hope this doesn't
Speaker 2:  end at midnight for you. We're all
Speaker 8:  Root for, you know, I'm gonna be like crying if it does. All right
Speaker 1:  Soon.
Speaker 9:  I'm Nam Aza and I produce and I'm on the podcast on with Kara
Speaker 9:  Swisher. Last week Kara and I went out to Martha Stewart's house
Speaker 9:  and it was, well just have a listen. It's great. Let's
Speaker 9:  set the scene a little bit.
Speaker 10:  Okay. The scene is we come in, we get taken in another vehicle throughout
Speaker 10:  the estate. There's chickens, there's peacocks,
Speaker 9:  There's horses, there's horses,
Speaker 10:  There's
Speaker 9:  Stables, and there's a giant copper pot, which is the size of you actually
Speaker 9:  get in the copper pot. It's ly size of you.
Speaker 10:  I'm not leaving here.
Speaker 9:  She could cook us into chili and that thing she might, if the interview gets
Speaker 9:  too tough, she
Speaker 10:  Would and it would be delicious.
Speaker 9:  Don't worry, we didn't get cooked in the cold cauldron. But thanks to Martha Stewart,
Speaker 9:  the interview did get spicy.
Speaker 11:  I was hired by Mark Burnett to fire Donald.
Speaker 11:  Oh okay. To say you fired just Like. he had said to hundreds of
Speaker 11:  people right during his apprentice I was to fire him and take
Speaker 11:  over,
Speaker 9:  Oh Martha, to hear why she says she didn't get to fire Trump. Listen to
Speaker 9:  On with Kara Swisher, wherever you get your podcasts,
Speaker 12:  We have clients that are Titanic enthusiasts, which we refer
Speaker 12:  to as Titanics. We've had people who have mortgaged their home
Speaker 12:  to come and do the trip and we have people who don't think twice about
Speaker 12:  a trip of this, this cost.
Speaker 13:  For the record, the trip cost $250,000.
Speaker 13:  That was Stockton Rush, the founder of Ocean Gate Expeditions and one of
Speaker 13:  five men who died when a submersible bound for the wreckage of the
Speaker 13:  Titanic imploded on today explained a deep sea explorer and a friend
Speaker 13:  of one of the passengers tells us that he saw this coming
Speaker 14:  The old line that says, A man needs to know his limitations
Speaker 14:  and you just can't fix stupid and stupid games will win you
Speaker 14:  stupid prizes. It was unnecessary. Everyone in the industry
Speaker 14:  knew that this vessel had no business being out there,
Speaker 14:  had no business being on the Titanic,
Speaker 14:  none
Speaker 13:  Today explained in your feeds every weekday at 2:00 PM
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. Congress is back in session in the US and one of the
Speaker 2:  issues being most hotly debated right now is child safety
Speaker 2:  Online. We have a bunch of new bills in play. There are some big
Speaker 2:  ideas about technically speaking how kids can be protected online.
Speaker 2:  And, as always, there's some fiery talk about who's to blame and
Speaker 2:  what has gone wrong online. The verges, Makena Kelly has been following all
Speaker 2:  of these efforts and talking to the folks trying to get these new bills passed
Speaker 2:  and she's here to tell us what's going on and whether any of it might
Speaker 2:  amount to anything. Makena, hello, Welcome back. It's
Speaker 15:  Great to be here.
Speaker 2:  We have a bunch to talk about, but I realized in prepping for this, that
Speaker 2:  coppa, which is this big bill about this big law,
Speaker 2:  about child protection online is way older than I realized. So
Speaker 2:  I wanted to start with not quite a history lesson, but like
Speaker 2:  let's look back at coppa, right? So this thing was passed in 1999, went into
Speaker 2:  effect in 2000 and has basically governed the way we think
Speaker 2:  about child protection online for 23 years
Speaker 2:  now. It's still everywhere. We still talk about it all the time. Is this
Speaker 2:  a good law? Like what, what is the sort of vibe around what
Speaker 2:  Kapa is doing to the internet 23 years later?
Speaker 15:  So yeah, the wild thing that you bring up about coppa, which stands for
Speaker 15:  the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act is, yeah, it's been around
Speaker 15:  forever and most importantly it's like the only real
Speaker 15:  privacy law on the books. Like we talk about, you know, having some
Speaker 15:  kind of nationwide privacy framework, all of that COPPA is pretty much what
Speaker 15:  we got other than, you know, some minor things here and there and then maybe
Speaker 15:  some stronger things at the state level. I don't know if you remember, this
Speaker 15:  is what I say when I try and explain it, but when I signed up for a
Speaker 15:  Neopets account in like 2009 Yep. I
Speaker 15:  had to click some box that said I
Speaker 15:  am over 13 years old. Yep. I think people have had
Speaker 15:  that kind of relationship with the internet that, or even there was, there
Speaker 15:  was some websites where I had to put in my parents' email
Speaker 15:  before I could have access to it and they had to like say, okay, yeah, they're
Speaker 15:  whatever and they can use this. So that was essentially put in place by
Speaker 15:  COPPA and that's how online platforms were using it at the time.
Speaker 15:  It's still kind of that way now, but essentially like Facebook does
Speaker 15:  the same thing. Like you're not supposed to have a Facebook page unless
Speaker 15:  you're like over 13. So it's stayed pretty much the same for like you said,
Speaker 15:  23 years. And the important thing about COPPA is
Speaker 15:  that when we talk about the companies that we talk about on the site
Speaker 15:  constantly meta, Facebook, Instagram, TikTok,
Speaker 15:  Amazon, so many of them when it comes to being
Speaker 15:  sued or having settlements with the government, it comes from Kapa
Speaker 15:  multimillion dollar settlements for breaching certain parts of
Speaker 15:  Kapa and doing things that the government deems harmful to
Speaker 15:  children. So COPPA is basically the biggest weapon that the federal
Speaker 15:  government has on data privacy and it's only, you know, protecting kids
Speaker 15:  under 13.
Speaker 2:  By the way, I love the idea of thinking about laws as what
Speaker 2:  check boxes do they introduce to the internet? Like that's, that's just a
Speaker 2:  very good way of thinking about privacy laws, like what check boxes do they
Speaker 2:  add and what pop-ups are required As a result, you can kind of sort 25
Speaker 2:  years of tech legal fighting by check boxes and pop-ups,
Speaker 2:  but there's been fights and debates over changing
Speaker 2:  Kapa and updating it and having new things over the years. But
Speaker 2:  what I can't tell I guess is whether this is like a very sort of prescient
Speaker 2:  and durable law in a way that I think Section two 30 has been
Speaker 2:  over time, like Section two 30 has grown to do a lot more work than anyone
Speaker 2:  expected it to, but still kind of does its work, right? Or if Kapa is like
Speaker 2:  hopelessly outdated and we should have changed it a long time ago. It's just
Speaker 2:  that this is the kind of law that takes forever to change. Do you have a
Speaker 2:  sense of which one it is?
Speaker 15:  I think most Democrats, if they don't support
Speaker 15:  stronger child protections that come in a different law,
Speaker 15:  they want COPPA to be updated. COPPA is strong,
Speaker 15:  it's proven. This is the thing that's really important is that it's already
Speaker 15:  proven to be constitutional. It's held up in the courts, you know, it's
Speaker 15:  already been litigated. So COPPA is something that they don't really have
Speaker 15:  to worry about updating it. Whereas when you think about new laws
Speaker 15:  like the Kids Online Safety Act, things that we'll talk about later, these
Speaker 15:  could be put up to legal challenges for being unconstitutional.
Speaker 15:  I think when you talk to lawmakers, COPPA is just extremely durable. It
Speaker 15:  is a law that's withstood litigation, it's proved to be constitutional,
Speaker 15:  there's bills out there to update it. I think it's the easiest path forward,
Speaker 15:  but if it's the right move that's currently what's being debated in Congress
Speaker 15:  right now.
Speaker 2:  Got it. Okay. So yeah, let's talk about what's happening in Congress right
Speaker 2:  now. You wrote a story I think in May, basically saying there's
Speaker 2:  a lot of energy around child privacy online again, and this seems to
Speaker 2:  happen in waves kind of based on what's coming in the news and usually
Speaker 2:  like a Facebook scandal of some kind. A lot of people get excited and then
Speaker 2:  it fades as we talk about other things and then it comes back and right now
Speaker 2:  it is back in like a very big way. What is kind of leading the debate
Speaker 2:  at this particular moment as we talk about child safety again?
Speaker 15:  Right? So when we talk about regulating tech, there
Speaker 15:  is a series of things that normally happens, something bad happens, a tech
Speaker 15:  company does something, Congress freaks out, they talk about it
Speaker 15:  for a little bit until they forget and another really big bad thing happens
Speaker 15:  and draws them away.
Speaker 2:  Well you're forgetting the part where Josh Hawley introduces legislation.
Speaker 2:  That's one very important necessary step that
Speaker 15:  Josh Hawley introduces a bill to allow you to sue for things. Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 15:  That man loves to sue. He loves to sue.
Speaker 15:  So while that new big bad thing is happening, like I said, the states
Speaker 15:  are still a little bit behind and they're still working on what that big
Speaker 15:  tech company did that was bad. And right now we're in this part
Speaker 15:  where the states have already put out so
Speaker 15:  much legislation that has become law, basically childproofing the
Speaker 15:  internet in many, many ways. and Congress is looking at that
Speaker 15:  and being like, oh crap, we need to do something now. And so there's
Speaker 15:  a handful of bills that have been put out and the wild thing is,
Speaker 15:  yeah, I, I, when I look at this, it's like this is the one thing tech-wise
Speaker 15:  that I can imagine Congress doing this year. It sounds like a very admirable
Speaker 15:  thing to protect children online, but when you do these things and
Speaker 15:  like we've seen with the state laws, they have a real impact
Speaker 15:  and could I should say, could have a real impact on civil rights
Speaker 15:  for not just children, right, but for everyone on the internet.
Speaker 2:  Got it. Okay. So big picture, like you said, there are a bunch of bills and
Speaker 2:  I want to get into some of the specific ones, but do we
Speaker 2:  agree on kind of big picture what the
Speaker 2:  solutions are to this problem? Like you say, childproofing the internet,
Speaker 2:  right? That's sort of a big vague term that I think most people kind of agree
Speaker 2:  on. Do we have a sense of what everybody actually wants
Speaker 2:  to do, even sort of in broad strokes here?
Speaker 15:  I think the best answer to that is just protect kids. What protect
Speaker 15:  kids means is very different. So there are some
Speaker 15:  laws like the ones that have gone into effect in Texas and Louisiana
Speaker 15:  that is just strictly restricting a minor's access to the internet. You
Speaker 15:  cannot create certain accounts with social media platforms without
Speaker 15:  explicit permission from your parents. In some instances that sounds great
Speaker 15:  for lawmakers, but then you kind of peel back the layers of this and
Speaker 15:  you look at, oh my gosh, well what if a child is in an abusive
Speaker 15:  situation with their parents? What if a queer kid is looking for
Speaker 15:  resources online? They, they can't sign up for these
Speaker 15:  websites, they can't go into these forums, they can't receive these resources
Speaker 15:  without basically outing themselves to their parents, which is so
Speaker 15:  oftentimes the last thing they want to do. And so that gets
Speaker 15:  at the heart of the problem of these bills and what they end up doing. When
Speaker 15:  we talk about what is the solution, it's a, it's a handful of different
Speaker 15:  things that people have proposed and there's a handful of issues. So
Speaker 15:  the one thing is just like making sure kids aren't accessing really bad
Speaker 15:  content and they can't see it. We've heard a lot about disordered eating
Speaker 15:  content, basically, you know, pro ana stuff. Anyone who's on
Speaker 15:  Tumblr in the 2010s has seen this like prota content and
Speaker 15:  having social media platforms over moderate that and
Speaker 15:  that, yeah, that might sound great at face. Like I don't wanna see prota
Speaker 15:  content that can be triggering to a lot of people, but then it's like, oh,
Speaker 15:  how does a tech platform actually moderate that?
Speaker 15:  They might just be going ahead and removing all content
Speaker 15:  related to eating disorders. Stuff that is actually like resources like
Speaker 15:  we said, or people posting TikTok being like, this is how I
Speaker 15:  overcame this eating disorder. And it could encourage platforms to
Speaker 15:  over moderate in a way that could be challenged as being
Speaker 15:  unconstitutional and violating the first amendment.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And then it, it does seem like we've been in this place for a long
Speaker 2:  time where those are the trade-offs and that seems to be, at least from my
Speaker 2:  perspective, what has held this up over and over and over again is it's like,
Speaker 2:  okay, this stuff is like you said, sort of admirable and in the
Speaker 2:  positive case everybody kind of agrees this is what we should do, right?
Speaker 2:  Like we, we should have better controls for what kids see. Parents
Speaker 2:  should have more, but then it's like there's just edge case after edge case
Speaker 2:  after edge case after edge case. And it seems like that has bogged all of
Speaker 2:  this down, but you've been talking to people about this new run of bills.
Speaker 2:  You talked to Ed Markey, I know, and a couple of other folks I think, and
Speaker 2:  I'm guessing after, or at least I'm hoping after all of
Speaker 2:  these other tries to do this and we've been back and forth through all of
Speaker 2:  this that maybe we have found some new
Speaker 2:  strategies and nuances that we can figure out here. Like walk
Speaker 2:  me through kind of what you've heard from these folks this time around.
Speaker 15:  So Senator Ed Markey is the senator from Massachusetts and he was the
Speaker 15:  original author of coppa, the bill that we've been talking about that has
Speaker 15:  been used, you know, hundreds of times. He, for the last couple years
Speaker 15:  has been putting out something called COPPA 2.0. I spoke to him a couple
Speaker 15:  weeks ago about that and what that bill exactly does.
Speaker 16:  COPPA 2.0, it says very
Speaker 16:  specifically that companies must get consent before
Speaker 16:  collecting data about users age 13 to 16
Speaker 16:  bans targeted ads to children and teens, which are
Speaker 16:  inherently manipulative and it actually creates an online
Speaker 16:  eraser button so kids and parents can tell companies to delete
Speaker 16:  the data they've collected about child users. It
Speaker 16:  ultimately then creates a digital privacy bill of rights for children
Speaker 16:  and teens in our country.
Speaker 15:  Sounds great.
Speaker 2:  It
Speaker 15:  Does compared to a lot of what's being proposed in Congress. And I
Speaker 15:  think when you look at Markey's bill, it is one of the bills that makes
Speaker 15:  fewer changes that would do fewer things. When we look at
Speaker 15:  other bills with the potential to be passed, there's the Kids Online Safety
Speaker 15:  Act that was introduced, that's a bipartisan bill introduced by Senator
Speaker 15:  Marsha Blackburn and Senator Richard Blumenthal that does a wide variety
Speaker 15:  of things. It touches on the moderation stuff that we talked about before,
Speaker 15:  which the bill could encourage platforms to over moderate
Speaker 15:  content that the bill decides could be harmful for kids.
Speaker 15:  Then there's another bill that Senator Brian Schatz put out called the Protecting
Speaker 15:  Kids Online Act. And that starts
Speaker 15:  something that has spooked a lot of people, which is like a nationwide pilot
Speaker 15:  program on age verification. Ah, yes. So making
Speaker 15:  counts online, you would have to basically
Speaker 15:  show your ID to show that you are above the above a certain age
Speaker 15:  and that has spooked a lot of people
Speaker 2:  What could go wrong,
Speaker 15:  Right? Basically just uploading your ID to platforms
Speaker 15:  that who knows where that data could go. So that would be a
Speaker 15:  pilot program. The marque build does not do age verification. It
Speaker 15:  basically follows through on like a lot of what the initial COPPA does,
Speaker 15:  which is if a content is, looks like it should
Speaker 15:  be for a kid, you just, you know, abide by COPPA from that. It's more of
Speaker 15:  like an assumption rather than a confirmation. And
Speaker 15:  yeah, that spooked folks pretty bad because when
Speaker 15:  we talk about protecting privacy, you don't want to make
Speaker 15:  people offer up even more data to protect kids. You're
Speaker 15:  then requiring even more data from people
Speaker 15:  25, 35 45, you know, anybody on the internet.
Speaker 2:  One thing Marky said in that clip you played is the age
Speaker 2:  16, which feels like I, I think I've seen this come up in
Speaker 2:  a bunch of these discussions that 13, and I actually, I don't know if Kapa
Speaker 2:  did this or not, but there was at some point where 13 was sort of established
Speaker 2:  as like the the age at which you were allowed to use the internet. And I
Speaker 2:  think we can have lots of interesting arguments over whether that is too
Speaker 2:  young or too old or whatever. But it seems like more recently, and you've
Speaker 2:  covered this a bunch, there's been a push to make that age 16 and instead
Speaker 2:  of 13 is that marquee is that somebody else? Like what's going on here?
Speaker 15:  So the Markey bill moves it up to 16 I think with the Francis Hogan
Speaker 15:  revelations about how Instagram and Facebook
Speaker 15:  has inflicted, you know, actual real harm on kids that's
Speaker 15:  kind of had senators and lawmakers thinking about, oh my gosh, well
Speaker 15:  you have a ton of kids online with unfettered access to the
Speaker 15:  internet, seeing things that they necessar that could be really
Speaker 15:  damaging. And what's changed since CAPA
Speaker 15:  and what's been really pressing for lawmakers is that we're actually undergoing
Speaker 15:  a nationwide mental health crisis for youth.
Speaker 15:  We can debate like what is actually causing this, but the surgeon General,
Speaker 15:  for example, has put out social media as one of these reasons.
Speaker 15:  And so that, you know, when we talk about a youth mental health health crisis,
Speaker 15:  that is everyone under the age of 18 and those kids lawmakers
Speaker 15:  seeing need the same protections.
Speaker 2:  Got it. Okay. Folks on the other side of this who have been, you know, the
Speaker 2:  civil liberties groups and the internet freedom groups and the sort of free
Speaker 2:  speech maximalist, what do they make of this
Speaker 2:  new round of bills? I mean? It seems like Ed Markey in particular with COPPA
Speaker 2:  2.0 is trying to do kind of as little as possible in order to
Speaker 2:  make some changes without sort of blowing up the whole thing. Which I guess
Speaker 2:  probably goes back to what you're talking about, about Kapa being kind of
Speaker 2:  tested and proven and constitutional and it's like, okay, how much
Speaker 2:  can we change that without having to sort of reinvent the wheel and do this
Speaker 2:  all over again? Is it possible to do that stuff without making this other
Speaker 2:  side angry? Like are are, what do they make of this new round
Speaker 2:  of things?
Speaker 15:  Experts are really freaked out by this. Okay. For a
Speaker 15:  wide variety of reasons. I spoke to India
Speaker 15:  McKinney from the Electronic Frontier Foundation about these bills
Speaker 15:  and I got the answer that I think everyone has been thinking about
Speaker 15:  this is we need a strong comprehensive
Speaker 15:  data privacy framework for everyone.
Speaker 17:  A strong, comprehensive, federal consumer data privacy
Speaker 17:  bill that is consumer driven, consumer focused that gives power to
Speaker 17:  consumers that will actually help everybody including children.
Speaker 17:  And it may sound like it's harder, like children's privacy
Speaker 17:  sounds easier because who was gonna argue with children's privacy?
Speaker 17:  But as soon as you introduce this new additional component of determining
Speaker 17:  who is a child that ups the difficulty level, you don't have
Speaker 17:  to do that. You could just go back to doing privacy for everyone and
Speaker 17:  a rising tide lifts all boats.
Speaker 2:  Okay, I have two thoughts on this and I'm curious what you think. One, this
Speaker 2:  makes me think we're still in this phase of, it's just
Speaker 2:  impossible to suit everybody that if you say the sort of buzzwords like
Speaker 2:  comprehensive privacy framework, everyone's like, oh cool, good idea. And
Speaker 2:  then as soon as you drill one level further down, it all falls apart because
Speaker 2:  everything is tradeoffs and nobody agrees. It also makes me think that the
Speaker 2:  one thing India gets wrong there in that the
Speaker 2:  only bipartisan thing in Congress in tech for years, and I
Speaker 2:  don't know if this is still true, I'm curious what you think, but you could
Speaker 2:  say children need to be protected online and everyone in Congress would agree
Speaker 2:  with you. There's like no other sentence in America that you can say that
Speaker 2:  everyone in Congress agrees with. But on that one, everybody agreed, and
Speaker 2:  it seems to me that's why there's been energy to do this because it
Speaker 2:  is an actually functional bipartisan thing and
Speaker 2:  it's small enough and narrow enough that you can maybe possibly do something
Speaker 2:  about it. Whereas if you say privacy online for everybody,
Speaker 2:  like that becomes the size of the universe and everything explodes. What
Speaker 2:  do you think? Like, am I, am I thinking about this the wrong way or is she
Speaker 2:  kind of maybe not giving it as much credit as it needs?
Speaker 15:  Yeah, I, when you talk to people you know who are digital rights advocates,
Speaker 15:  they are, they wanna shoot for the moon. you know, they want
Speaker 15:  what they see as the best solution. Now that solution is
Speaker 15:  actually viable. That's, you know, that's the real question actually. When
Speaker 15:  I was talking to Markie, I asked him specifically, I said, well why
Speaker 15:  COPPA 2.0? why not a, you know, a comprehensive data privacy framework?
Speaker 15:  And he basically said that it's so much more difficult and he doesn't imagine
Speaker 15:  it happening anytime soon.
Speaker 16:  The better target for now is to yes, worry about people
Speaker 16:  who are 25, 35, 45, 55, et cetera, but know that the
Speaker 16:  politics of getting that done are much more difficult in my opinion, in
Speaker 16:  this environment than protecting kids 16 and under
Speaker 16:  because that's always been a special category that
Speaker 16:  has been singled out in the courts
Speaker 16:  in political life for special protections while young
Speaker 16:  people's brains develop. So we want a comprehensive bill,
Speaker 16:  but my position is the least we can do this year is to
Speaker 16:  protect teenagers and children from the pernicious
Speaker 16:  strategies of the big tech companies.
Speaker 15:  I think that's the same sentiment from a lot of Democrats as well, especially
Speaker 15:  because President Biden, the White House has made it a priority
Speaker 15:  to do something on this front. In the past two state of the Union
Speaker 15:  addresses, Biden has explicitly called for child
Speaker 15:  protections.
Speaker 18:  We must finally hold social media companies accountable for
Speaker 18:  experimenting or doing running children for profit. There's
Speaker 18:  time to pass bipartisan legislation.
Speaker 15:  They see this as like you were saying something that Republicans and
Speaker 15:  Democrats can get behind and as something they can maybe do
Speaker 15:  before Biden's term is over.
Speaker 2:  So given all that, what do you think is the most likely outcome
Speaker 2:  this year we're about to head into a campaign season. So I think like prognosticating
Speaker 2:  basically anything after like six months from now I think is, is sort of
Speaker 2:  crazy. But like you said, there is real energy to do this right now and there
Speaker 2:  is a possibility of doing something this year. Do you think we're likely
Speaker 2:  to see one of these bills pass? Are we likely to see sort of an amalgam of
Speaker 2:  them come together? What's your sense,
Speaker 15:  Right. When we see lawmakers introduce these bills, they are
Speaker 15:  not going to be the same as they were introduced if they were to be
Speaker 15:  voted on on the floor at any, you know, that's just what happens. A lot
Speaker 15:  of bills being introduced is a senator putting out their
Speaker 15:  position publicly in language that they can then edit and work with
Speaker 15:  other people to get it done. When we see bills with a lot of energy behind
Speaker 15:  them, Marques is not being
Speaker 15:  talked about as much, which is why I wanted to talk to him specifically,
Speaker 15:  it's the Kids Online Safety Act, the one that has all these moderation
Speaker 15:  requirements that has a lot of people supporting it, it's
Speaker 15:  bipartisan in nature, it looks PR fairly viable. But the
Speaker 15:  funny thing about this is that Blackburn and Blumenthal have been having
Speaker 15:  all of these press conferences with parents and kids who support this bill
Speaker 15:  and support something being done. But at the same time you have all of
Speaker 15:  these civil liberties groups being like, this is too far. This could have
Speaker 15:  drastic consequences for everyone on the internet. And
Speaker 15:  over the last couple months, CSA has been edited
Speaker 15:  a bit to dampen down these concerns to make certain
Speaker 15:  language changes that would better protect everyone and the kids.
Speaker 15:  I imagine that is still ongoing. So when I look at
Speaker 15:  the timeline for this year, we are currently in June. I don't know
Speaker 15:  if listeners no, but Congress doesn't really follow
Speaker 15:  the Schoolhouse rock framework where things go through committee,
Speaker 15:  they go to the floor and everyone's so happy and they vote on it. That doesn't
Speaker 15:  want, that doesn't really happen anymore. Bills get attached to certain
Speaker 15:  must pass vehicles. So there's like a defense authorization
Speaker 15:  that basically authorizes all the money that we give to the defense department
Speaker 15:  and the military every year people love to stick things on that because
Speaker 15:  they have to pass that otherwise the military doesn't get funded. And then
Speaker 15:  there's also another option when it comes to appropriating money to make
Speaker 15:  sure all federal employees get paid, that all the federal
Speaker 15:  agencies get paid. And that's normally done in the fall. So I imagine
Speaker 15:  that if they want to get this done and they wanna get it done before the
Speaker 15:  end of the year, the best solution would be to spend
Speaker 15:  the next couple working periods editing down csa, maybe
Speaker 15:  implementing some COPPA 2.0 language, whatever that happens to
Speaker 15:  be, and then attaching it to some kind of
Speaker 15:  appropriation spill in the fall that gets included in, you know, all that
Speaker 15:  stuff. And that's how it gets passed. The final language just won't be clear
Speaker 15:  until it gets dropped in the fall. But I do imagine if they
Speaker 15:  want to get this done and if, if this is a priority for Biden, if this is
Speaker 15:  something he wants to run on, it's a kitchen table issue. We have seen Biden
Speaker 15:  focus on kitchen table issues. I'm sure listeners know the
Speaker 15:  Ticketmaster stuff that happened about junk fees recently. Biden
Speaker 15:  is looking at these issues that people see every day and they get
Speaker 15:  pissed about every day and they want that to be front of
Speaker 15:  mind to democratic voters and all voters technically. So
Speaker 15:  I see if this is a priority, it'll get done around that timeframe. So
Speaker 2:  The real question here is how do we get Taylor Swift really riled up about
Speaker 2:  children's privacy online? Cuz that's how we get this done.
Speaker 15:  Organize the swifties. Yeah. Oh my goodness. They
Speaker 2:  Can do anything they want,
Speaker 15:  You know, and that's, that's kind of the funny thing too because Taylor
Speaker 15:  Swift actually got Congress upset enough to do something about Ticketmaster,
Speaker 15:  like talked about a bunch of legislation and basically asked
Speaker 15:  the FTC or in the DOJ to investigate Ticketmaster for an
Speaker 15:  antitrust case to break it up. There's a lot of action there after Taylor
Speaker 15:  Swift said some stuff, I don't know who would
Speaker 15:  be the major figure here. The only person coming to mind is
Speaker 15:  I'm imagining like Blippy getting really upset about this. Sure. Perhaps
Speaker 15:  or Bluey, maybe there's a bluey episode where Bluey is like, kids
Speaker 15:  need to be protected. I don't know, I haven't seen Bluey, I just know kids
Speaker 15:  love it. That
Speaker 2:  Was a perfect bluey impression. That's all. That's all I'll tell you. So,
Speaker 2:  okay, so the last thing and then I'll let you go here is I wonder how
Speaker 2:  we're coming to think about this even like structurally. Cuz I think part
Speaker 2:  of the question is, is there a middle ground between these questions about
Speaker 2:  you know, encryption and free speech and privacy and protection,
Speaker 2:  which feels like it's this, that's also the debate about privacy
Speaker 2:  frameworks for everybody. It's a question of like does one side or the other
Speaker 2:  win or is there a middle ground? And then there's the question of like who
Speaker 2:  is responsible for this? And I think one of the things that's been interesting
Speaker 2:  to me about this round of bills is that some are still out there saying
Speaker 2:  the companies that run these platforms ought to be responsible and the way
Speaker 2:  that we held them responsible is by punishing them. And then there are other
Speaker 2:  people out there saying, you know, we need age verification system that works
Speaker 2:  across the whole internet and that's its own thing. But that's different
Speaker 2:  from saying like, YouTube's job is to fix this, right? Or the
Speaker 2:  questions about the online eraser button that's different from saying each
Speaker 2:  individual platform has to just do it themselves, but that also introduces
Speaker 2:  all other kinds of complexity. so like are we still in this kind of
Speaker 2:  spaghetti throwing phase of trying to figure out how all this works or are
Speaker 2:  we gonna land on sort of broader ideas about how
Speaker 2:  to even go about making some of this legislation? Does that make sense?
Speaker 15:  Yeah. I wanna point out the Ticketmaster thing again because
Speaker 15:  how did Biden move something and have like this meeting at the White House
Speaker 15:  with Ticketmaster Live Nation Airbnb and everyone celebrating this?
Speaker 15:  Well it wasn't actually a lot that they agreed to. They
Speaker 15:  basically agreed they don't get rid of junk fees, but they agreed
Speaker 15:  to show them upfront nothing gets less expensive, you just aren't
Speaker 15:  surprised by it later. So when we think about this, maybe the
Speaker 15:  most practical and real scenario is that there's some kind of
Speaker 15:  little change that happens. Maybe something updating Kapa a little bit,
Speaker 15:  maybe just moving the age, I don't know what it could be. That could
Speaker 15:  be the end game here. And I love that you brought up enforcement of this.
Speaker 15:  How do you enforce something like this? Because that gets at another really
Speaker 15:  consequential issue to all of this legislation frankly,
Speaker 15:  because you look at a lot of these bills and the language of these bills,
Speaker 15:  there's a Texas one for example that does some
Speaker 15:  similar stuff like COSA where there is additional moderation requirements
Speaker 15:  and kids can't see certain content. Everyone agrees that, you know,
Speaker 15:  CS Sam gone should be eradicated from the internet. But
Speaker 15:  in the law there is language explicitly calling
Speaker 15:  grooming bad content that needs to not be
Speaker 15:  online. And we've seen with the culture wars
Speaker 15:  over the last however long grooming being
Speaker 15:  used as an excuse to
Speaker 15:  discriminate against queer people essentially. And
Speaker 15:  I could see in interpretations of that, and the interpretation is really
Speaker 15:  important here because the people who are enforcing this, it could be the
Speaker 15:  FTC, it could be the D O J, but most of these bills
Speaker 15:  allow state attorney generals to enforce this. So imagine
Speaker 15:  a red state like Texas getting a law that has something about
Speaker 15:  grooming and going after Facebook, Instagram,
Speaker 15:  whoever for just having queer people on their
Speaker 15:  platforms or maybe saying that kids cannot see this content.
Speaker 15:  It just gets into all of these conversations when we look at like drag queen
Speaker 15:  story hours, all of this stuff, those culture war elements that we see
Speaker 15:  played out, book banning all of this, this is a
Speaker 15:  way to bring all of that to the internet and for it to be enforced
Speaker 15:  by red states. And that's what spooked people a lot.
Speaker 2:  All right, well Congress is back in session. This is all moving really fast.
Speaker 2:  I suspect we're gonna have more to talk about on this front very soon. But
Speaker 2:  for now we need to take a break and then we are going to get into the Google
Speaker 2:  Pixel Fold review and finally decide once and for all,
Speaker 2:  whether flippable or foldable phones or neither or both
Speaker 2:  or whatever are the future. We'll be right back
Speaker 19:  This September. The code conference enters the new era. Join
Speaker 19:  me Nili Patel, editor-in-chief of The Verge and my two
Speaker 19:  co-hosts, platformers Casey Newton and CNBC's Julia Bors.
Speaker 19:  As we talk to the leaders making headlines in tech, business,
Speaker 19:  politics, and the messy collision between them all, we'll dig
Speaker 19:  deep into the topics that are shaping our world like AI streaming
Speaker 19:  and the future of social media. And as always, with code no one will
Speaker 19:  be saved from the hot seat. You can apply to attend the code
Speaker 19:  conference@vvoxmedia.com slash code. That's
Speaker 19:  vox media.com/code
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. We've had two reviews on The Verge dot com the last couple
Speaker 2:  of weeks that I think are a really big deal. The Motorola Razr Plus and
Speaker 2:  the Google Pixel Fold. The Razr Plus is a flip phone and the Pixel Fold is
Speaker 2:  a foldable phone and both have a chance to give us a
Speaker 2:  new glimpse into the future of phones. Plus we're likely to see
Speaker 2:  new flippables and foldables from Samsung this summer. So we've gotta figure
Speaker 2:  out what's really the future here. What do we want from these devices? What
Speaker 2:  are they supposed to be? How do they change the way that we think about our
Speaker 2:  phones? The Verges, Allison Johnson and Dan Seifert have been using these
Speaker 2:  phones for a while now, so I brought them both in and we're gonna get into
Speaker 2:  all of it. Allison Hello.
Speaker 20:  Hello
Speaker 2:  Dan. Hello, hello. So we have a lot of things to talk about. I wanna talk
Speaker 2:  about the Pixel Fold first and then I want to have a very long drawn out
Speaker 2:  fight about flippable phones and foldable phones and which one is
Speaker 2:  the future?
Speaker 20:  So ready
Speaker 2:  Because I have feelings that I, I feel more deeply every day
Speaker 2:  and we're gonna talk about them.
Speaker 21:  This is when hot foldable summer gets real sweaty. Oh yeah,
Speaker 2:  It's exactly right. It's, it's about, it's about to get real fiery up in
Speaker 2:  here. Let's start with the Pixel Fold because you both wrote stories about
Speaker 2:  the Pixel Fold, you've been testing it for a while. This phone is a big deal,
Speaker 2:  a lot of people have been talking about it and I think I wanna start with
Speaker 2:  just like what it is like to figure out how to live life with a
Speaker 2:  foldable phone. Because one of the things I got from both of the stories
Speaker 2:  you guys have written and the stuff you've written about foldable phones
Speaker 2:  over the last couple of years is that these are fundamentally sort of different
Speaker 2:  kinds of devices. It's not like you like bought a phone with a bigger screen
Speaker 2:  like you, you bought a different thing when you get a foldable device.
Speaker 2:  So Allison, you go first. Dan is the, the foldable phone sicko here.
Speaker 2:  So, we'll, we'll leave him alone for a second, but tell me about like what
Speaker 2:  it's like to live with and review a foldable phone as opposed to some of
Speaker 2:  the other sort of more standard devices you spend most of your time with.
Speaker 20:  Yeah, the way I keep thinking of like, and this is sort of falling apart
Speaker 20:  with the thing Motorola just announced, but like a flip style phone,
Speaker 20:  it feels like a foldable plus. It's like a regular phone plus a smartwatch.
Speaker 20:  The Galaxy Fold, the Pixel Fold, those are like
Speaker 20:  a phone plus tablet. So that kind of dictates like
Speaker 20:  what is enjoyable to do with it, what you get out of it. So really
Speaker 20:  the Pixel Fold, it is a normal phone when you have it closed and it
Speaker 20:  has that like lovely kind of normal phone
Speaker 20:  shape as opposed to the the remote control that is the
Speaker 20:  Galaxy Fold. So that's where you do your like quick
Speaker 20:  texting notification stuff and then you
Speaker 20:  open it up and in the case of the Pixel Fold you have kind of like a
Speaker 20:  landscape oriented tablet out of the gate as opposed to the
Speaker 20:  Galaxy folder, which is more portrait oriented. Okay. So,
Speaker 20:  and that's where you, you multitask, you play a game, you watch your
Speaker 20:  video, you set it up in the little laptop position and
Speaker 20:  play Elmo so your kid will brush their teeth. All kinds of
Speaker 20:  fun to be had.
Speaker 2:  And thi this kind of gets at like the big sort of philosophical question.
Speaker 2:  I feel like you're both reckoning within these stories, which is like, what
Speaker 2:  are, what are these things for? And I feel like Dan, you kind of commit this
Speaker 2:  from the point of view of like, I want do as much stuff on this as
Speaker 2:  I can. I have more screen. Yeah, more stuff to do. Give me like a
Speaker 2:  computer. I feel like you're, you're the person who is like, I use the iPad
Speaker 2:  as my primary computing device. Right? And then Allison, I feel like you
Speaker 2:  come at this as like the iPad is like a thing for my kid to hold and
Speaker 2:  a thing for watching movies, right? Like it's, it's a bigger screen and that's
Speaker 2:  like, it is sort of the tablet debate in a nutshell, right? And I feel like
Speaker 2:  what a foldable phone should be is just like fundamentally the tablet debate
Speaker 2:  again, right? And it feels like as we look at the Pixel Fold, which I think
Speaker 2:  the, the sort of tldr of your review Allison was basically like good first
Speaker 2:  generation device missing some stuff. And I want to get into all the stuff
Speaker 2:  that's missing, but it does still feel like it has a very different idea
Speaker 2:  about what a foldable phone like is supposed to do than something like
Speaker 2:  the Samsung devices.
Speaker 20:  Yeah, I Dan, I'm, I'm gonna steal your line, but you
Speaker 20:  mentioned that like the Samsung phone just feels like a little computer
Speaker 20:  that you have in your pocket. You can do like an incredible number of things
Speaker 20:  on it. And what I ended up doing with it was
Speaker 20:  sitting on the couch and when you're having that moment of like, oh I
Speaker 20:  need to put this expense report together, I need to get up and get my
Speaker 20:  computer. You're like ha, no I don't have to.
Speaker 20:  I can run four apps on this thing and keep
Speaker 20:  sitting here and and do that. And the kind of person who wants to do that
Speaker 20:  is a Samsung foldable person. The Pixel Fold is more
Speaker 20:  like, I just found it more approachable and
Speaker 20:  it's, it's sort of like a friendlier, more like guardrail device
Speaker 20:  where you can only run two apps side by side and split screen. So that
Speaker 20:  just kind of like cuts down what you're gonna do with it,
Speaker 20:  like productivity wise. But then there's, there's really useful stuff. Like
Speaker 20:  I'm looking at Google Maps and I'm opening up a restaurant website
Speaker 20:  in Chrome is right next to it. I don't have to like tab around
Speaker 20:  it. It's good for stuff like that, but the gist of it that I kind of got
Speaker 20:  is like this is nice. I enjoy being able to do these things.
Speaker 20:  I do not care to spend $1,800 on it and
Speaker 20:  carry around like a very heavy phone for these moments.
Speaker 20:  Whereas with the Galaxy Fold it sort of felt like,
Speaker 20:  wow, this is, this is a lot like I am getting a lot of
Speaker 20:  value for $1,800.
Speaker 2:  Right. Yeah. Dan, I feel like the guardrails Allison is talking about sort
Speaker 2:  of drove you slowly nuts over the course of testing this phone.
Speaker 21:  Yeah, and I, I think Allison really hit it on the head with the price of
Speaker 21:  the thing. Like the reason that I wanna do so much or try to get so much
Speaker 21:  out of a device like this is one because it's always gonna be on my person,
Speaker 21:  but the other is because I'm paying $1,800 or if I'm getting more storage
Speaker 21:  like almost $2,000 for this phone, which is like a lot of money. So
Speaker 21:  I wanna be able to use it as much as possible. And for me at
Speaker 21:  least, if you're buying a folding phone like this that turns into a small
Speaker 21:  tablet, the whole appeal is the big screen that fits in your
Speaker 21:  pocket and all the things that you can do on that big screen. And I think
Speaker 21:  it's like a lot of people are looking at the Pixel Fold and they say, oh
Speaker 21:  that outside screen is more usable because it's more normal
Speaker 21:  looking. It looks right because it's like normal proportions and things
Speaker 21:  like that. And yes, I agree to all of those things, it's easier to use the
Speaker 21:  outside screen and it's like more normal looking. But then
Speaker 21:  when you open the phone and Allison kind of gets into this in her piece,
Speaker 21:  the landscape orientation of the inside screen and the limitation
Speaker 21:  with the software means that you could just do a whole lot less with the
Speaker 21:  inside screen than you can on the Samsung. I think
Speaker 21:  maybe an analogy that might make sense is the Pixel Fold feels like
Speaker 21:  an iPad in terms of like the guardrails that are sent around you and like
Speaker 21:  obviously Apple is like kind of changing this on its high end iPads but
Speaker 21:  if you buy a base model iPad you're pretty limited with your multitasking
Speaker 21:  abilities. You're limited with what you can do and things like that. It's
Speaker 21:  a
Speaker 2:  Big screen for watching things like that's what the base iPad is. Yeah,
Speaker 21:  It's a big screen for watching things and the Pixel Fold is really great,
Speaker 21:  a big screen for watching things. If you wanna watch video on it, you want
Speaker 21:  to play games on it. I think Allison pointed out both of those things as
Speaker 21:  really excellent use cases. The Z Fold is like a PC
Speaker 21:  in like every single way. Sure that can be, it means it's
Speaker 21:  like super powerful. You can run four apps at the same time. You can
Speaker 21:  be in your banking app and pop open a calculator on top of it and run calculations
Speaker 21:  without ever reliving your banking app. And you can do all these things
Speaker 21:  and you can split the screen multiple ways and then you can save that setup.
Speaker 21:  So you can always jump back to that setup quickly. And then you take out
Speaker 21:  the yes pen and you can doodle things and you like the list goes on and
Speaker 21:  on and on. You can literally plug it into an external screen and run a whole
Speaker 21:  desktop environment off of it, turn it into a pc. And I think Allison is
Speaker 21:  like very correct in saying that like the approachability of that
Speaker 21:  is way lower than sure the
Speaker 2:  Approachability
Speaker 21:  Of the Pixel phone where it's like, oh I've got a thing that's twice the
Speaker 21:  size of the screen that's on the outside and now I can run two apps side
Speaker 21:  by side and I can watch a, a video on this bigger screen. And so
Speaker 21:  like introducing people to this concept, I think the Pixel Fold to
Speaker 21:  Alison's point does a really good job of that. But it just like, once you
Speaker 21:  get there and once you figure it out, it doesn't take long to be like, oh
Speaker 21:  I wanted to do something else or oh, I could like make more use of this
Speaker 21:  than it's letting me do. And that's the same problem that like everyone's
Speaker 21:  had with the iPad for forever is like, I wanna do more with this and the
Speaker 21:  software's not letting me well and
Speaker 2:  It's $1,800 not to keep putting a fine point on
Speaker 2:  this, but like I would be very into the idea of like, let's have sort of
Speaker 2:  a sliding scale of power of these devices and like
Speaker 2:  the, the iPad is actually a good example, right? You can get the souped up
Speaker 2:  ultra bonkers 12.9 inch iPad Pro and it will cost you
Speaker 2:  $1 million and you, you essentially know what you're getting, right? Like
Speaker 2:  you, you get the iPad Pro, you get the magic keyboard, you get the Apple
Speaker 2:  pencil and it costs as much as a car and that, but like you
Speaker 2:  know what you're getting. And then on the flip side you can spend $329 and
Speaker 2:  get an iPad and I feel like Samsung is doing the iPad Pro thing and Google
Speaker 2:  is doing the iPad base model thing, but Google
Speaker 2:  forgot to make it cheaper. Yeah. And I just feel like that to me is where
Speaker 2:  the kind of value prop here falls apart is Google is like here's less phone
Speaker 2:  for the same money and I have a hard time with that.
Speaker 20:  Right? Yeah. And something else that just kind of bothers me is the
Speaker 20:  durability is just a question mark. It's I p x
Speaker 20:  eight rated, so it's like waterproof to like full
Speaker 20:  water immersion, which is really good, but it is a first
Speaker 20:  gen product, you know repairs, you can't just waltz it into any
Speaker 20:  repair shop on the street. Not that that's a great idea anyway,
Speaker 20:  but yeah, there's more of a process, there's more cost involved. I got,
Speaker 20:  I have a little tiny scratch on the screen protector
Speaker 20:  inside my review unit and I was, I didn't baby it but I didn't like
Speaker 20:  put it, you know, next to my car keys. Right. With
Speaker 20:  this screen unfolded, what does that look like after a year of using it?
Speaker 20:  It's when you come back to like keep coming back to $1,800,
Speaker 20:  you're like well that that doesn't seem great.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, so the Pixel Fold I would say on the, so like Samsung has had four
Speaker 2:  tries at this, right? We think the the next one is coming in August or in
Speaker 2:  July or August sometime this summer. Where on that history
Speaker 2:  would you put the Pixel Fold because it seems to be clearly better than the
Speaker 2:  first Galaxy Fold, which was a mess. Yeah. Hardware wise.
Speaker 2:  Oh
Speaker 21:  Totally.
Speaker 2:  Is it like the Z Fold, the Fold two, the Fold three, the Fold four? Like
Speaker 2:  where would we put the Pixel Fold?
Speaker 21:  I would put it at 2.5 or three. Okay. Like
Speaker 21:  there's like it's, it's, it's a much better first generation start
Speaker 21:  than Samsung had for very obvious reasons.
Speaker 2:  It doesn't instantly break as soon as you start using it,
Speaker 21:  It doesn't instantly break. You don't, it doesn't look, you don't look at
Speaker 21:  it wrong in it like you know, the screen explodes but Samsung fixed that
Speaker 21:  pretty quickly. But the Z Fold two, which was the next generation, the
Speaker 21:  the screen hinge was made much better. They started introducing some things
Speaker 21:  to mitigate dust and water resistance and things like that. Google's already
Speaker 21:  starting at that point so they have the same as Allison mentioned the I
Speaker 21:  P X eight rating as Samsung, which means you can get it wet, you can even
Speaker 21:  submerge it, which is kind of fascinating for a phone that folds with moving
Speaker 21:  parts and everything and and it has that level of water resistance and the,
Speaker 21:  the hinge is very smooth, it's strong enough to hold the phone open like
Speaker 21:  Allison mentioned in like a laptop mode if you wanna prop it up to to watch
Speaker 21:  a video or something like that. Which Samsung didn't have on its first generation
Speaker 21:  things. So it's clear that Google has been paying attention to what
Speaker 21:  Samsung was doing and learning from it and, and that's great love to see
Speaker 21:  it. There are areas though, even in the hardware I mean we talked a lot
Speaker 21:  about the software experience but even in the hardware experience where
Speaker 21:  Samsung is just kind of ahead just because it's had so many
Speaker 21:  years to iterate on this idea, one of them is the screens. Samsung's screens
Speaker 21:  are brighter. Like they're just brighter. Like there's, I don't know what
Speaker 21:  else to put it and it feels like the Google screens are generation or two
Speaker 21:  behind because if you look at Samsung's history, the Z Fold three to the
Speaker 21:  Z Fold four, the big change was they made the screens brighter. So it's
Speaker 21:  like oh this feels like the Z Fold three screens.
Speaker 2:  Is Google just buying parts from Samsung from a year ago? Is that basically
Speaker 2:  what's happening here?
Speaker 21:  I mean it could be The Pixel folds been in development for a long time,
Speaker 21:  they've been reporting rumors on this for like two years. Yeah. I mean these
Speaker 21:  things take forever. And so it could be that like the panels that they secured
Speaker 21:  were at the Z Fold three generation level or whatever. Or maybe Samsung
Speaker 21:  is just kind of like hoarding the good stuff for itself, which would not
Speaker 21:  be surprise anybody. Right. The other thing and and Allison made quite a
Speaker 21:  few points about this in her review, the Pixel Fold is heavier than the
Speaker 21:  Z Fold and on paper it doesn't sound like a lot, it's 20 grams
Speaker 21:  but in use you notice it and you notice it every time you pick up the phone
Speaker 21:  or put it in your pocket or put it in your bag or whatever. Older Z Fold
Speaker 21:  phones were heavier, Samsung made them lighter over time. I believe the
Speaker 21:  Z Fold five specks have now leaked and it looks like it's gonna be 10 grams
Speaker 21:  lighter than the Z Fold four. so like Samsung's been doing these like very
Speaker 21:  small iterative chipping away at these problems and making
Speaker 21:  it a better overall experience that Google just hasn't been able to catch
Speaker 21:  up with because it is it's first generation and I think Google will get
Speaker 21:  there and if they start off this far ahead like at two and a half
Speaker 21:  generations or three generations in and in a year or two if they stick at
Speaker 21:  it they can very well keep up or surpass Samsung because
Speaker 21:  Samsung's been moving very slow with the iteration on the, the Fold devices.
Speaker 21:  So that's kind of where I'm, I'm placing it, it's a couple generations behind
Speaker 21:  where it is. It's still a very strong start.
Speaker 2:  Okay. Allison, let's talk about the weight thing cuz that was the thing in
Speaker 2:  your review I think of, of all of the imperfections of the
Speaker 2:  Pixel Fold, that was the thing that bummed me out the most because what you
Speaker 2:  said was, it was so heavy that you found yourself not
Speaker 2:  wanting to use it in one hand and so you end up sort of sitting down and
Speaker 2:  opening the screen. And to me the thing that has been compelling all along
Speaker 2:  about the Pixel Fold is it has a usable outside screen,
Speaker 2:  not like the TV remote like the Fold is like we were talking about. But it
Speaker 2:  almost sounds like you found yourself not wanting to use that much better
Speaker 2:  outside screen just because of the actual physical size of the thing,
Speaker 2:  which to me sort of kills the whole appeal. Was it as bad as it sounds?
Speaker 20:  Yeah, I, I don't wanna make too much of it. It's like it'll,
Speaker 20:  it'll bother people on different levels. I think maybe I'm more
Speaker 20:  sensitive to a heavy phone but you know, I just found myself
Speaker 20:  again and again, like you have it in one hand sitting on the couch
Speaker 20:  and the way it just kind of weighs down on your pinky finger. I was like,
Speaker 20:  I, I don't like this, I have to keep moving my hand.
Speaker 2:  There's definitely that thing where you find yourself sort of stretching
Speaker 2:  your hand every couple of minutes. Yeah you
Speaker 21:  Get the divot in between your knuckles. Yeah.
Speaker 20:  You're like ugh is that little divot there from using this bone
Speaker 20:  too much it and it feels more balanced like you're
Speaker 20:  distributing the weight more when you open it up. So I ended up doing that
Speaker 20:  more in instances where I didn't really need the big screen.
Speaker 20:  Yeah, I, I think I would like a phone I could use more
Speaker 20:  comfortably, you know, with this screen folded and I feel like I'm asking
Speaker 20:  for a lot. Like I don't wanna, you know, be like oh a phone
Speaker 20:  that folds in half, it's too heavy and like this is an
Speaker 20:  accomplishment and it's right. It's a wonderful device to use
Speaker 20:  in a lot of ways. For me personally for $1,800 I
Speaker 20:  don't wanna feel like my phone is too heavy when I'm using it for
Speaker 20:  five or 10 minutes at a time.
Speaker 2:  Well and I think this comes back to like Dan what you're talking about with
Speaker 2:  this sort of philosophy of it all right? Because I think the way you think
Speaker 2:  about it would be that the goal is to kind of get to the inside
Speaker 2:  screen as much as possible because that's why you bought this thing, that's
Speaker 2:  what it's for. Did the size of kind of holding the thing
Speaker 2:  bother you in the same way or are you just like yeah whatever, just let me
Speaker 2:  open up the thing, who cares?
Speaker 21:  It absolutely did. I think there's like a couple of factors with it. One
Speaker 21:  the weight, which I noticed right away. Two just kind of like if you look
Speaker 21:  at the really nitty gritty design differences, the Pixel Fold
Speaker 21:  folds flat closed which is really awesome. There's no gap between the halves,
Speaker 21:  which Samsung hasn't done yet. We expect the Z Fold five will based on the
Speaker 21:  leak so far. But for now the Z Fold four has a little gap. It's
Speaker 21:  also thicker when it's closed. The z the Pixel Fold is nice and thin when
Speaker 21:  it's closed, but like the bottom bevel or edge of the Pixel Fold is
Speaker 21:  not smooth and flat and that kinda like hurts the comfort when you're
Speaker 21:  holding it on your pinky and things like that. The weight is noticeably
Speaker 21:  different. The other difference is the Pixel Fold has this like kind of
Speaker 21:  noticeable bezel around the screen. So it's footprint is larger,
Speaker 21:  which means that it's more that you have to like deal with and wrangle in
Speaker 21:  your hands, especially when it's open. That's, that's mostly noticeable
Speaker 21:  when it's open. And like we talked about landscape versus portrait
Speaker 21:  orientation, you end up turning the Pixel Fold into portrait
Speaker 21:  orientation a lot in order to get the best experience because
Speaker 21:  Android apps don't expect you to be using a landscape screen. So when they
Speaker 21:  open on the Pixel Fold, a lot of them will open with black bars on the side
Speaker 21:  or they will stretch weirdly across the screen because it's like a landscape
Speaker 21:  screen that it's trying to switch to. But if you rotate at 90 degrees, the
Speaker 21:  app kind of knows what to do. It fills the screen vast majority of the time
Speaker 21:  and it just looks more normal. The, the layout makes more sense. It's a
Speaker 21:  vertically scrolling app which is like the vast majority of the of apps
Speaker 21:  that we use today have that kind of vertical scrolling interaction. So portrait
Speaker 21:  kind of makes sense for a lot of things and when you turn the Pixel Fold
Speaker 21:  to portrait, not only is that like annoying to do all day long, it's like
Speaker 21:  a big platter that you're holding, whereas the Z Fold is much more comfortable
Speaker 21:  to hold in that orientation and much easier to hold in that orientation
Speaker 21:  just because it's a little bit more compact even though they both have the
Speaker 21:  exact same size screen on the inside.
Speaker 2:  So did you get to the point where you're using it where you kind of, you
Speaker 2:  hold the phone in one hand normally and it's like holding a phone and then
Speaker 2:  as you're opening it you're like also kind of turning it 90 degrees in your
Speaker 2:  hand? I do that all the time. It's just like the natural way of Yeah. Interacting
Speaker 2:  with it now. Yeah
Speaker 21:  Like I I mean I would like basically I would open it, I would unlock it
Speaker 21:  with the fingerprint scanner or whatever. I would open the app I want to
Speaker 21:  use and then I would rotate the phone and hold it and then try and like
Speaker 21:  prop it up on my finger and like that's how I used it the vast majority
Speaker 21:  of the time. And then occasionally I'd wanna split screen like Alison mentioned,
Speaker 21:  put maps next to a browser, whatever. Or I'd, if I was watching a video
Speaker 21:  I'd rotate it back to landscape. But the majority of my use case is in portrait
Speaker 21:  orientation because that's what most apps are.
Speaker 2:  Allison. Does that match your use? Like as you find yourself just sort of
Speaker 2:  using it day to day? Is that, is that what you're doing too?
Speaker 20:  Well I wasn't as smart, I didn't like rotate it as much but
Speaker 20:  yeah when I would open it up I would find myself, you get the like black
Speaker 20:  bars on either side of Instagram or whatever, it just made me
Speaker 20:  wanna open more apps just to put something there. Oh
Speaker 20:  interesting. Which I was
Speaker 2:  Like, so you end up just like side by sighting apps just because it yeah
Speaker 2:  like that's what looks better.
Speaker 20:  Yeah I'm like well I might, as I've got this space I might as well open
Speaker 20:  something else and then I'm sort of like scrolling two things at once and
Speaker 20:  I don't know, I think my mindset is just sort of, I wanna be like
Speaker 20:  a little less engaged with my phone overall or like feel like I'm
Speaker 20:  just more in control and
Speaker 20:  yeah, just in that kind of scenario with a Pixel Fold I was like this is,
Speaker 20:  I do not need more phone here.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, that's very fair. The last thing we should talk about before we get
Speaker 2:  to Flip versus Fold and all of my strong feelings, y'all can leave for that
Speaker 2:  part. I'm just gonna yell into the microphone for about 45 minutes but we
Speaker 2:  should talk a little bit about Android cuz I think my general stance on
Speaker 2:  phones has always been that Samsung goes about 250%
Speaker 2:  too far with its stuff. It just adds a lot of things you don't need and one
Speaker 2:  of the reasons I have always defaulted to telling people to buy pixels is
Speaker 2:  that Google's version of Android is just still the best one out there.
Speaker 2:  That seems less true here. It seems like the Pixel Fold
Speaker 2:  has some good ideas about larger screens and foldable devices. Android seems
Speaker 2:  to have gotten a lot better, Google's own apps work better, but it seems
Speaker 2:  like both of you are kind of, of the opinion that all the crap Samsung
Speaker 2:  has added is actually mostly a good thing in the actual Android
Speaker 2:  has some catching up to do on how foldables work. Is
Speaker 2:  that Allison, is that that your take?
Speaker 20:  Yeah, it's, there's kind of a maximal list like ethos
Speaker 20:  to the, to the folding phone and that vibes really well
Speaker 20:  with Samsung I think. And that's where it makes sense is
Speaker 2:  Samsung never met a feature it doesn't want to shift. Yeah, right.
Speaker 21:  The full Samsung experience can only be had on a folding phone and
Speaker 21:  and they're gonna give you everything.
Speaker 20:  It's the ultimate Samsung experience.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, but is Google catching up there do you think? Because again, like we
Speaker 2:  were talking about with the sort of slightly more guardrail, less chaotic
Speaker 2:  way, it does seem like there's a middle ground there that I believe in Google
Speaker 2:  for and it seems like at least with like the maps and some of the other Google
Speaker 2:  apps, it's pushing in a good direction. It just kind of needs, I guess the
Speaker 2:  rest of I Android to catch up, which is the same story of a decade of larger
Speaker 2:  screen devices. But is there, does it feel like progress now? At least
Speaker 20:  It does. Yeah. And there's there's a lot. Yeah the work they put
Speaker 20:  into optimizing a lot of the Google apps for
Speaker 20:  the folding phone is really good. I mean, I, you know, I opened up Google
Speaker 20:  Meet, which we all love and you, you Fold the phone and
Speaker 20:  the content just kind of flows into the right place in your, in
Speaker 20:  your meeting. Like that is great. I think what they're approaching is,
Speaker 20:  is a folding device that a lot of people can come to and pick up
Speaker 20:  and just and feel like welcome and I think
Speaker 20:  I'm gonna really like that in a few generations when maybe
Speaker 20:  it's less expensive and doesn't weigh as much as a
Speaker 20:  break.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, that is very fair. Dan, you even more than Allison
Speaker 2:  seem to appreciate the full Samsung
Speaker 21:  In this context. Yes. And like I don't appreciate experiencing the full
Speaker 21:  Samsung all the time and when I say the full Samsung I mean like you are
Speaker 21:  running the three apps and then you put the popup app up and then you pull
Speaker 21:  out your si like I don't recommend people do
Speaker 2:  That and then Bixby shows up and is like, do you want help with your phone?
Speaker 2:  It's good times. Yeah.
Speaker 21:  What I, what I appreciate is the ability to do that if I so want it. If
Speaker 21:  I don't want go the full Samsung, maybe I want the half Samsung or like
Speaker 21:  the three quarter Samsung for whatever job I need to do and like the Pixel
Speaker 21:  just doesn't let you get there because they, they put those guardrails in
Speaker 21:  place that means that you can only do certain things. Like one thing that
Speaker 21:  kind of blew my mind was like no Pixel phone allows you to plug into an
Speaker 21:  external display. You can't mirror the screen, you can't put your video
Speaker 21:  on a bigger screen or whatever over A U S B C cable rumors are saying that
Speaker 21:  like the Pixel eight line will change that, but we're not there yet. So
Speaker 21:  those are like kind of like small productivity things, but they all add
Speaker 21:  up and like they, they make a difference when you're thinking of like I
Speaker 21:  could live with a Z Fold four is my only computer, I couldn't
Speaker 21:  really get there with a Pixel Fold at least for my needs and my desires.
Speaker 21:  And again, $1,800, that is like a big ask
Speaker 21:  for something that like only does certain things and doesn't do everything
Speaker 21:  I wanna do with it. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  I, I just, I really am so I'm so much more hung up on the price with this
Speaker 2:  device than most because just at this price it is such a
Speaker 2:  self-selecting thing for people who are
Speaker 2:  going to want to do a lot more stuff with this device. Like no one
Speaker 2:  is buying it to just like put it in a case and look
Speaker 2:  at TikTok like if that's what you're buying this for, you're, you're insane.
Speaker 2:  Like don't buy that in this phone. These people are going to want to do more
Speaker 2:  stuff and I think Google is trying to build a phone that seems like it's
Speaker 2:  gonna be way more compelling. Like you were saying Allison like in three
Speaker 2:  years at half the price. Whereas Samsung I feel like might
Speaker 2:  continue to be able to make an interesting case for a device that costs this
Speaker 2:  much just because of all the stuff that it can do for you. And I like, I
Speaker 2:  kind of hope they both stay on that path because they'll end up in really
Speaker 2:  different really interesting places in Foldables.
Speaker 20:  Yeah, I think like software wise the Pixel Fold is the kind of phone I would
Speaker 20:  recommend to a lot of people. Like if my dad, you know, I think he would
Speaker 20:  get a lot out of using all those apps on the big screen but there's, there's
Speaker 20:  just no way in hell I'm gonna town to buy an $1,800 phone. Right.
Speaker 20:  So someday.
Speaker 2:  All right, let's switch gears just for a minute and talk flip phones because
Speaker 2:  the other phone you just reviewed Allison is the Motorola Razr Plus, which
Speaker 2:  is a phone. I have been eagerly looking forward to your review for a very
Speaker 2:  long time and it seems like it's great. It's like the perfect flip phone
Speaker 2:  does not exist yet, but we're getting much closer
Speaker 2:  very quickly. The price is good, the phone is good. It seems like the, the
Speaker 2:  Razr Plus is like, it's a, it's a good thing, right?
Speaker 20:  Yeah, yeah. And I was kind of waiting for it to betray me a
Speaker 20:  little bit cuz everything did seem so promising.
Speaker 20:  But yeah, it, it pretty much delivers, the really notable
Speaker 20:  thing of course is the outer screen is that big
Speaker 20:  3.6 inch, like big, relatively speaking right?
Speaker 20:  Small but big. It's just a full kind of phone on its own.
Speaker 20:  You can run any app you want, like speaking of
Speaker 20:  guardrails, Motorola is like go for it. You have
Speaker 20:  to tap on a little tiny text box that says like, this
Speaker 20:  app might not look great on this little tiny screen but you can do it.
Speaker 20:  It's just like you gotta live with your choices there.
Speaker 2:  I always like to think that if I call that the the hey idiot popup
Speaker 20:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Where they can't say like, you're stupid and this is a bad idea, but they're
Speaker 2:  just like, this is stupid, don't do this. Yeah,
Speaker 20:  Please don't, but
Speaker 2:  Okay. And and Allison's just here being like whatever.
Speaker 20:  Yeah, I'm like, you don't tell me how to live my life Motorola.
Speaker 2:  But I think, and you said this with the foldable phone too, that one of the
Speaker 2:  things that you like about this new kind of device is like control over
Speaker 2:  your experience with devices and to me that's the whole appeal of flip phones,
Speaker 2:  right? Is there is there's something real about this idea that
Speaker 2:  like I can close my phone and even on the smaller screen you can sort of
Speaker 2:  tap at a text message. I loved the screenshot that you had that it was the
Speaker 2:  keyboard takes up the whole screen on the ERs display really the whole screen,
Speaker 2:  which is like a little bit ridiculous but also kind of
Speaker 2:  works and it works just well enough that I'm gonna like respond to my text
Speaker 2:  message and then put my phone down and move on as opposed to just like swiping
Speaker 2:  back to the home screen. Yeah. And then getting lost in Instagram for three
Speaker 2:  and a half hours. But it, it does feel like, I think running full apps
Speaker 2:  on your outer screen is insane and we, no one should be allowed to do that
Speaker 2:  and you should be thrown in prison for doing that. But the idea of having
Speaker 2:  this sort of not quite phone, like you said, it's a smartwatch on the outside
Speaker 2:  and a and a smartphone on the inside that really works for me. Dan,
Speaker 2:  I feel like you and I are probably very different on this, given that you
Speaker 2:  just spent the whole weekend with your phone plugged into an external monitor.
Speaker 2:  What, what's your, how do you feel about flip phones as a, as a
Speaker 2:  concern?
Speaker 21:  I, I think they're really cool. I don't know if they're the right device
Speaker 21:  for me, if we're talking just like flip phones versus foldables or whatever,
Speaker 21:  I kind of will lean towards the one that gives me the, the biggest screen
Speaker 21:  possible in my pocket. But I think to Allison's point, the
Speaker 21:  Razr is the first flip phone that's actually intrigued me. I
Speaker 21:  think I reviewed one of the Z flip models one of the earlier generations
Speaker 21:  and that one really annoyed me because the outside screen was so useless
Speaker 21:  and then in order to do anything with the phone you had to open it up and
Speaker 21:  it requires two hands to open it and like then it's just a, you
Speaker 21:  know, S 20 or S 21 at the time once you open it and then there was not,
Speaker 21:  there's no novel novelty about that. Whereas the Razr to Allison's point,
Speaker 21:  you can do things on that outside screen and you can be more intentional
Speaker 21:  with your actions on the phone and actually respond to the message or check
Speaker 21:  you know, the upcoming directions or skip a track on your music or whatever
Speaker 21:  it is that you're doing really quickly without getting like sucked into
Speaker 21:  whatever distraction might be there. If you're using the full-size screen
Speaker 21:  all the time, I end up picking my phone with a specific reason,
Speaker 21:  like I need to like add something to our shopping list or look up the price
Speaker 21:  of something or whatever and I pick it up and I get distracted by notification
Speaker 21:  and then like five minutes later I'm like standing there like not remembering
Speaker 21:  what I wanted to do on my phone. I feel like that's less likely to happen
Speaker 21:  if you have to be so intentional to open up the phone but you
Speaker 21:  can still, you know, have a useful device that's like the level of a smartwatch
Speaker 21:  in capability on the outside. And I think that the Razr is really
Speaker 21:  interesting on that front. It's also like it's about a thousand dollars,
Speaker 21:  which is premium and expensive but not $2,000. So it's much
Speaker 21:  more approachable. I think it makes a lot of sense for a lot of people at
Speaker 21:  that level, you know, to be, people already spend that much on most phones
Speaker 21:  now, so it's not like a reach to to get this like more
Speaker 21:  intentional compact experience and actually still be useful
Speaker 21:  and still be usable.
Speaker 2:  Totally. Yeah. And I also Allison, I appreciate that you keep banging the
Speaker 2:  drum in all of these reviews that the fact that you can put it down
Speaker 2:  on a table, flip the screen up and either like look at something or
Speaker 2:  use it as a camera. And this is true of foldables and flippables, but the
Speaker 2:  thing where it's like halfway its own kickstand is awesome and it sounds
Speaker 2:  so stupid and so small, especially for a device that expensive. But it's
Speaker 2:  great and I love it and I appreciate that you do too.
Speaker 20:  I mean I, I take a lot of pictures of my child, like all of us do.
Speaker 2:  I also take a lot of pictures of your child. Yeah.
Speaker 20:  I mean he's pretty cute so no, you can prop it up like
Speaker 20:  that and like w and you can stay engaged in what's going on.
Speaker 20:  Like it's not, it's not gonna work in every situation, but it's just
Speaker 20:  nice to have the option. You're like, oh I can, I don't have to be
Speaker 20:  like glued to having my phone in front of me. I can set it here,
Speaker 20:  play with stickers, whatever we're doing and yeah, it's just nice.
Speaker 2:  It does seem like the big holdup for both the flip phones and the
Speaker 2:  foldable phones is durability both in terms of like real
Speaker 2:  sort of measurable things like the IP ratings and the scratchiness
Speaker 2:  of the internal screens, but also just the, the the sort of
Speaker 2:  feeling that you get using them and the like we're all used to
Speaker 2:  carrying slabs of glass in our pocket but there is something about these
Speaker 2:  devices, they have the crease, they, you feel something using the hinges
Speaker 2:  like Allison, you talked about that last little push to kind of go from like
Speaker 2:  160 degrees to 180 degrees open and it feels bad. It's like I
Speaker 2:  wonder if it's just gonna take a while both for us and for the technology
Speaker 2:  to get to the point where like I don't have to treat this thing like it is
Speaker 2:  a very fragile object.
Speaker 20:  Yeah. Something that people are always asking me about when they see a Fold
Speaker 20:  foldable for the first time. Like, oh, so you can open it with one hand.
Speaker 20:  I'm like, no, no, no, that actually feels
Speaker 20:  terrible. Like it, it, I think it will take some adjustment like just even
Speaker 20:  in our mindset of like what we expect to be able to do with them and what
Speaker 20:  they're actually capable like up for right now.
Speaker 21:  I, I think as a price comes down that becomes easier to manage as well.
Speaker 21:  I mean again, $1,800 phone in six months, you don't want
Speaker 21:  to have the hinge breaking or the screen breaking or whatever. I think that
Speaker 21:  all of the companies can do a lot better with support not only just like
Speaker 21:  giving you places to go and options if your folding device breaks,
Speaker 21:  but making them in a way that it is easier to repair them
Speaker 21:  when you know, the inevitable happens. Because we've had
Speaker 21:  Samsung's foldables for about four years now, but there
Speaker 21:  were lots of reports in the early generations of like the screens just randomly
Speaker 21:  cracking or you know, failing and things like that. You can look back to
Speaker 21:  lots of user reports about those things and I think Samsung has slowly been
Speaker 21:  addressing those as the generation's moved on, but that requires buying
Speaker 21:  a new $1,800 phone every time. So it's like, it is how iteration works and
Speaker 21:  improvement works, but we're not there where it's just like you can just
Speaker 21:  carelessly or not carelessly but like not worry about it
Speaker 21:  as much. It is something that you think about like when I go to the beach
Speaker 21:  this summer, probably won't be bringing my foldable phone to read something
Speaker 21:  on the beach, right? Because I'm terrified of getting a grain of sand in
Speaker 21:  there still after four years. so like there, there's definitely lots of
Speaker 21:  progress that needs to to happen on that front, both in the how
Speaker 21:  durable the things are, how easy it is to get them fixed and how we're parable
Speaker 21:  the devices are in the long run.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, and the thing that gives me hope on all of those fronts is that both
Speaker 2:  the Pixel Fold and the Razr Plus represent like real competition in those
Speaker 2:  spaces kind of for the first time it's just been sort of Samsung off on its
Speaker 2:  own island. There are a bunch of Chinese manufacturers doing really interesting
Speaker 2:  work, but especially in the US it's just basically been Samsung and nobody.
Speaker 2:  And now it feels like there is at least a good alternative
Speaker 2:  in both Foldables and flippables and I'm very excited about that fact.
Speaker 2:  I'm also just glad the Razr is back. Like I'm realizing as I talk about this,
Speaker 2:  just saying the Razr like brings me joy as a person who grew up
Speaker 2:  in the time the razors were the coolest. Like this just makes me happy. The
Speaker 21:  Best part about the new Razors, David, is that you can launch the old Razr
Speaker 21:  experience complete with the key tag. Wait, can you really? And the apps
Speaker 21:  and everything, you can make it what? Oh yes, on the inside look like a
Speaker 21:  2003 Razr. Yes.
Speaker 2:  Oh, okay. Well done. I have to buy one now that I didn't know this. This
Speaker 2:  changes everything. All right, well we need to wrap this up, but before we
Speaker 2:  do, there are three of us, so we get to decide right now, majority rules
Speaker 2:  once and for all flippable phones, foldable phones, both will exist
Speaker 2:  forever, but only one gets to be the like default phone choice
Speaker 2:  for everyone forever. Which one is it? Allison, you go first.
Speaker 2:  Flip Dan.
Speaker 22:  I gotta go with foldable
Speaker 2:  Two to one. Flip phones win. I love it. Yeah,
Speaker 1:  I knew I was losing this one.
Speaker 2:  All right, before we go, let's get to The Vergecast hotline. And a reminder,
Speaker 2:  the hotline number is 8 66 Verge 11. Or you can always email
Speaker 2:  Vergecast at The Verge dot com. Ask us all of your deepest, darkest,
Speaker 2:  weirdest, best tech questions. We love them. Here's one from Rob.
Speaker 23:  Hi, my name is Rob, calling to see if you guys have some suggestions
Speaker 23:  as to how to best play my PC games
Speaker 23:  on my tv. I built a really great
Speaker 23:  computer, but I find that sometimes I just want to sit back on the couch,
Speaker 23:  relax and play some video games on my tv
Speaker 23:  I'm hoping you guys have some suggestions on how to do that. Thanks.
Speaker 2:  All right. True story, as soon as this one came in, Liam James, our producer
Speaker 2:  was like, oh me, pick me. Pick me. I have to do this one. So here we go,
Speaker 2:  Liam. Take it away, my friend.
Speaker 22:  Hey Rob. Thanks so much for this question and for calling in. Okay, so I
Speaker 22:  just built a gaming pc so you have perfect timing. I had to answer this
Speaker 22:  very same question, and it turns out that the answer is
Speaker 22:  the same. No matter what your situation, let's say your gaming PC is in
Speaker 22:  your living room or across the room or in another room, a
Speaker 22:  long H D M I cable is still gonna be the best way to go. It is the most
Speaker 22:  reliable, the lowest latency, and obviously those things are really important
Speaker 22:  for gaming. It's the only thing that's going to not
Speaker 22:  give you headaches. There are some wireless solutions out there. They're
Speaker 22:  expensive, they're flaky, they're unreliable. I can't recommend them.
Speaker 22:  As far as controlling your gaming pc though, from the couch,
Speaker 22:  you may have heard of Steam's big picture mode, but if you haven't, it's
Speaker 22:  a great solution. If you're, especially if you're buying games in Steam,
Speaker 22:  it just lets you navigate your library and pull up games and start them
Speaker 22:  and, and move around without needing a mouse on a keyboard. Okay, hope that
Speaker 22:  helps.
Speaker 2:  Good stuff. All right. That is it for The Vergecast today. Thanks to everyone
Speaker 2:  who came on the show, and thank you as always for listening. There's lots
Speaker 2:  more from everything we talked about, especially the Microsoft and FTC trial.
Speaker 2:  There's a ton going on. Keep up with our stories dream at The Verge dot com.
Speaker 2:  We'll put links to everything in the show notes. But you know, go to the
Speaker 2:  website. It's a good website. I'm a fan. If you have thoughts, questions,
Speaker 2:  feelings, or really just please dear God away to fix
Speaker 2:  my patio. You can always email us at Vergecast The Verge dot com or call
Speaker 2:  the hotline eight six six Verge 11. we love hearing from you. We want all
Speaker 2:  your questions. It's so fun. This show is produced by Andrew Marino and Liam
Speaker 2:  James. Brooke Minters is our editorial director of Audio The. Vergecast is
Speaker 2:  a Verge production and part of the Vox Media podcast network. Neli, Alex,
Speaker 2:  and I will be back on Friday to talk more about Microsoft versus FTC.
Speaker 2:  We're gonna talk about what's going on at Reddit. We're gonna talk about
Speaker 2:  the Mac Pro. We're gonna talk about all kinds of stuff. We'll see you then.
Speaker 2:  Rock and roll.