# Transcript
ID: 543d3160-a67e-11ed-84a4-8706d87c2046
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: HomePod (2023) review, the Steam Deck one year later, and faking your death online
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-1707298632881035329/8814778927218122834/s93290-US-5335s-1675729698.mp3
Description: Today on the flagship podcast of removable power cords:
02:14 - The Verge’s Alex Cranz, Jennifer Pattison Tuohy, Chris Welch, and Nilay Patel discuss the updated version of the Apple HomePod.
Apple’s new HomePod plays it safe
How to use the Apple HomePod’s temperature and humidity sensors
43:23 - Katharine Trendacosta joins the show to discuss why and how faking your death has been a common practice in online communities.
A Fake Death in Romancelandia
She created a fake Twitter persona — then she killed it with COVID-19
1:05:19 - Verge senior editor Sean Hollister gives an updated review of Valve’s Steam Deck, which had a buggy start in 2022.
The Steam Deck wasn’t born ready, but it’s ready now
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Disabled
Speaker 2:  Hello, you're listening to The Verge has the flagship podcast of Removable
Speaker 2:  Power Cords. I'm your friend Alex Kranz. And you know,
Speaker 2:  it's, it's kind of nice here in New York City today cuz it's snowing
Speaker 2:  technically big fat flakes but it's super warm so they're not actually
Speaker 2:  sticking. But it's a nice change of pace because if you didn't know
Speaker 2:  until yesterday, north Texas had actually gotten more
Speaker 2:  snow than New York City this year. Absolutely Wild stuff.
Speaker 2:  More wild is the show we've got coming up today. It's gonna be a lot of
Speaker 2:  fun. I'm talking with Chris Welch and Jen Tuy and also Eli.
Speaker 2:  And we're gonna be talking all about the home pods place in like the
Speaker 2:  smart home ecosystem. What it means for matter, what it means for
Speaker 2:  home theaters. It's a lot of fun. I'm also gonna be talking to Katherine
Speaker 2:  Trin Acosta from the EF F, all about faking your death online.
Speaker 2:  And finally hanging out with my good friend Sean Hollister. We're gonna be
Speaker 2:  talking about your favorite gadget. My favorite gadget, everybody's favorite
Speaker 2:  gadget, the steam deck. It's going to be a super fun, super
Speaker 2:  nerdy time. All of that's happening right after this.
Speaker 2:  I wonder if I could do a snow angel in this. I
Speaker 2:  probably should not.
Speaker 2:  This episode is sponsored by TurboTax. TurboTax has
Speaker 2:  experts who can help relieve you from the stress of taxes and follow for
Speaker 2:  you so you can do not taxes With TurboTax, an
Speaker 2:  expert will do your taxes from start to finish, ensuring your taxes are done
Speaker 2:  right so you can relax. Feels good to be done with your taxes,
Speaker 2:  right? Come to TurboTax and don't do your taxes. You can visit
Speaker 2:  turbotax.com to learn more. Intuit TurboTax, full service products
Speaker 2:  only video meeting while expert does your taxes required. See guaranteed
Speaker 2:  details at turbotax.com/guarantees.
Speaker 3:  When you arrive in the all new Toyota Crown, every entrance
Speaker 3:  becomes a grand one with an available hybrid max
Speaker 3:  powertrain that says you always arrive fashionably on time
Speaker 3:  style that says emphasis on the fashionably
Speaker 3:  and presence that says you speak softly and
Speaker 3:  everyone listens. Introducing the Toyota Crown, the car that says so
Speaker 3:  much
Speaker 3:  Toyota. Let's go places.
Speaker 2:  Okay, welcome back. Apple's Big HomePod has
Speaker 2:  returned.
Speaker 2:  The second gin HomePod is not that much different from the original, but
Speaker 2:  it has added a couple of updates including for like audio for the
Speaker 2:  smart home, even some of the home theater stuff. So I had to get together
Speaker 2:  with Jennifer Patterson Tui, who has been reviewing it from
Speaker 2:  like the smart home perspective and Chris Welch who's been reviewing it from
Speaker 2:  like that audio nerd perspective. And then Eli Patel who
Speaker 2:  reviewed the original one way back in 2018. Let's get to the convo.
Speaker 2:  I've got three incredible people with, with me, well two incredible people
Speaker 2:  in NEI with me to talk about. Wow. To talk
Speaker 2:  about the new home pod. Nei Tellis here.
Speaker 2:  Hi Nei.
Speaker 4:  I'm gonna just interpret this the other way, which is that y'all are incredible
Speaker 4:  but I'm fabulous. I
Speaker 2:  Love that. That is exactly what I meant. You
Speaker 4:  Gotta look inward to your own heart and find your own validation in life.
Speaker 4:  That's a real lesson when you hit 40.
Speaker 2:  Jen Tuey is here.
Speaker 5:  Hello. I'm very pleased to be here also. Feeling fabulous. There
Speaker 4:  You go. See, welcome to my team Jen. We're the fun ones.
Speaker 2:  And Chris Walters here.
Speaker 6:  Hello. I'm surrounded by three home pods right now, so Wow. A party
Speaker 6:  over
Speaker 5:  Here. They're taking over. Okay,
Speaker 2:  Well this will surprise no one. We're talking about the home pod today. Jen
Speaker 2:  and Chris have a review. They're up on the site right now. You can go read
Speaker 2:  it and see their, their feelings or you can listen to this
Speaker 4:  Or both. This is like a, like a spatial audio DVD commentary. What you need
Speaker 4:  to do as you're reading review, play this podcast
Speaker 4:  from three or four home pods. Play strategically throughout your
Speaker 4:  home
Speaker 2:  And we're slowly all creeping up on you. It's gonna be great. All right,
Speaker 2:  so, so this is kind of a big deal for them because we thought the HomePod
Speaker 2:  was dead or at least pretty done and now there's a whole new one.
Speaker 2:  How different is it Jen, from like a smart home perspective?
Speaker 5:  Well, from the smart home side, it's actually very different from the
Speaker 5:  original home pod. Okay. It's identical to the HomePod Mini.
Speaker 5:  There's like no difference other than
Speaker 5:  $200. Well the, the one thing that's different, I'll take
Speaker 5:  that back one, one small but large difference is speed. So the
Speaker 5:  new HomePod has the fastest, has a fastest processor, it has
Speaker 5:  the S seven, whereas the HomePod mini has the S
Speaker 5:  five. And that is the one thing I definitely noticed
Speaker 5:  that the new HomePod, the HomePod two responded
Speaker 5:  very snappily to my Siri requests very few
Speaker 5:  on it or
Speaker 5:  compared to the mini, which you know has is getting a little long in the
Speaker 5:  tooth. You know it's turning three this year. So there's, you know what you
Speaker 5:  would expect to see a bit more speed but feature parody is identical
Speaker 5:  between the two. There are a lot of new features though. There's a lot of
Speaker 5:  sound focus outside of audio sound which Chris I'm sure is gonna
Speaker 5:  regal us with. But there's a new feature coming in the spring
Speaker 5:  as actually not here yet, which is gonna turn the, the mini and the HomePod
Speaker 5:  two into a smoke alarm and co monoxide
Speaker 5:  alarm detector. Not the sound detector. So it's not
Speaker 5:  actually turning into a smoke alarm, but it will listen for your smoke alarms
Speaker 5:  and your carbon monoxide alarms because they have unique signatures and that
Speaker 5:  will come in the spring and mean you'll get sent an alert to your
Speaker 5:  phone if one of your home pods in your home, here's an alarm going off.
Speaker 5:  Which is a very useful feature that all the other smart home speakers
Speaker 5:  already do. Which is kind of a theme in my review is
Speaker 5:  that this is really Siri and the the HomePod kind of playing catch up
Speaker 5:  in the smart home space and adding a lot of features that are
Speaker 5:  great and super handy and that everyone else already did
Speaker 5:  so. But that's good for Apple Home users who are, you know, a dedicated bunch
Speaker 5:  and who don't necessarily want to switch ecosystems to get some of these
Speaker 5:  features. You know, we finally have multiple timers which has, those have
Speaker 5:  been around for a little while now and
Speaker 5:  those have been actually around for a year or so. But they, they work great
Speaker 5:  and you can name your timers now. Oh wow. Which is yeah very
Speaker 5:  handy. You can even dismiss a timer from one room if
Speaker 5:  the home pod is in the another room, which is nice. You don't have to yell.
Speaker 5:  There's a lot of little things like that that just kind of little quality
Speaker 5:  of life features, smart home features that have come to the new HomePod
Speaker 5:  and to the HomePod Mini and you know, you can, one thing I really like,
Speaker 5:  which is unique to the HomePod is the fine
Speaker 5:  my capability. So you can now track your family
Speaker 5:  just with your voice. You know, where's my child,
Speaker 5:  where's my husband? You know, don't have to get your phone out and like put
Speaker 5:  effort
Speaker 4:  In you. That's the next great Apple commercial is just someone screaming,
Speaker 4:  where's my husband and a speaker lighting up
Speaker 2:  And saying the answer. He's outside.
Speaker 4:  Do you ever think about the people who spend their lives like laying
Speaker 4:  underground under ocean fiber optic cables on
Speaker 4:  ships or the engineers who spend their entire lives
Speaker 4:  developing the next process technology for like a microchip
Speaker 4:  like the S seven? Yeah. And like one day they wake up and they're like, it's
Speaker 4:  all in service of people being able to set two timers at once and that's
Speaker 4:  what we're gonna be excited about tomorrow.
Speaker 5:  It's exciting.
Speaker 4:  Siri in particular, every time it comes up I'm like this is all we get, like
Speaker 4:  all
Speaker 5:  This work. Two
Speaker 4:  Timers and it's like you can name one timer and you can scream where's my
Speaker 4:  husband? And that is the pinnacle of of assistant technology.
Speaker 4:  You
Speaker 5:  Can do lots of timers. Actually I did up to five at once, which is quite
Speaker 5:  exciting. Oh my
Speaker 4:  God. See take that cruise ship people so much
Speaker 4:  re nihilism.
Speaker 5:  Well and we do also have the temperature and
Speaker 5:  humidity sensing, which we've actually written about quite a lot on the site
Speaker 5:  this week. But that's, that's gonna be in the, the home pod too and
Speaker 5:  I've been finding that really kind of fun cuz it's cold right now in
Speaker 5:  South Carolina, which is very unusual. So I've been using it
Speaker 5:  to keep my rooms temperate and it's worked really well. Although I
Speaker 5:  was talking with deputy editor Dan who is also a big HomePod
Speaker 5:  Apple home user and he's been trying to set up the humidity
Speaker 5:  sensor to do things which I don't really need to do in South Carolina cuz
Speaker 5:  South Carolina is humidity personified
Speaker 5:  and he's not been having any luck with that. So there's still a bit of testing
Speaker 5:  we need to do to sort of, you know, put that through its paces. We've only
Speaker 5:  only had these Diddy little devices for a few days now I'm
Speaker 5:  holding mine up. It's actually quite hefty. You could do good arm workouts.
Speaker 2:  Is that what you've been doing Chris? You've got two of 'em so you can do
Speaker 2:  both arms at the same time.
Speaker 4:  Yes. Just mention those every night. It's like the, you know the rock curls
Speaker 4:  as children. I have ever seen that. It's very funny. HomePod curls. Jen,
Speaker 4:  can I ask you this question? It seems like there's the updates to Apple
Speaker 4:  Home and sort of matter coming along for the ride. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  so the Apple home and home kit ecosystem is getting a big upgrade
Speaker 4:  and there was a software update to existing home pods and
Speaker 4:  HomePod. Many that sort of exposed these sensors added more
Speaker 4:  capabilities what is required in that
Speaker 4:  suite of new features to get a new HomePod for cause I think the
Speaker 4:  line for me is really blurry. It doesn't seem like the hardware of the new
Speaker 4:  HomePod is required for a lot of the new features of
Speaker 4:  Apple Home that are coming out now.
Speaker 5:  So you in terms of matter, you don't need a new HomePod
Speaker 5:  for matter. In fact the original HomePod will be a matter controller.
Speaker 5:  It will not be a thread border router though it doesn't have a thread radio
Speaker 5:  in. And that is something you might want with matter
Speaker 5:  because a lot of, or some new devices are coming out that use
Speaker 5:  thread and Apple Home is kind of leaning more on thread as
Speaker 5:  opposed to Bluetooth. Yeah for a lot of its connectivity, which is a good
Speaker 5:  move cuz Bluetooth in the smart home has never been a, a great experience.
Speaker 5:  We
Speaker 4:  Know Bluetooth is just a hot mess next year. All right,
Speaker 4:  next year.
Speaker 5:  So I, you know, I definitely see Apple Home moving away from reliance
Speaker 5:  on Bluetooth and Thread is really where they're putting their, the eggs in
Speaker 5:  the basket and thread is still kind of a nascent technology. It's,
Speaker 5:  it's been around for almost a decade but this, the infrastructure is still
Speaker 5:  not quite there to support a strong thread network.
Speaker 5:  I've been talking to a different number of different companies who are all
Speaker 5:  producing thread border routers, which is part of matter. They're two
Speaker 5:  distinct technologies that work hand in hand matter and thread. And the problem
Speaker 5:  is right now if you have like a Google Home Thread border router, which
Speaker 5:  it's the Nest hub, max is one and you also have say an Echo
Speaker 5:  fourth gen which is gonna be a border router in the next few months,
Speaker 5:  they'll all create their own separate oh no thread networks which kind of
Speaker 5:  defeats the purpose of thread. So we are waiting, everyone
Speaker 5:  promises me that this is all gonna be fixed soon and eventually all
Speaker 5:  of these devices will work together in sort of harmony in your home, which
Speaker 5:  is, you know, the promise of matter. So I would recommend if
Speaker 5:  you are on fence and you don't have a home pod or an Apple TV that supports
Speaker 5:  thread and you're looking at buying one, it's worth having a device with
Speaker 5:  a thread boarder outer if you want to work in the smart home because it,
Speaker 5:  it will it's future proof in your smart home but you don't need
Speaker 5:  one necessarily today. So it's interesting cuz Apple came out with two new
Speaker 5:  Apple TVs and didn't put thread in one of them but did in the other.
Speaker 5:  So I mean maybe, I don't know they're hedging their bets there a little too
Speaker 5:  but it does, it is an important step for matter
Speaker 5:  which Apple has been fully kind of on board with
Speaker 5:  since the beginning cuz it actually sort of started matter one of the, it
Speaker 5:  was one of the founding companies and it has you know, contributed
Speaker 5:  home kit to the infrastructure of matter. There's a lot of
Speaker 5:  similarities between Apple home using Apple Home and using matter
Speaker 5:  devices. The problem right now is there are just not very many matter devices
Speaker 5:  to use and they sent us, apple sent us a matter, an
Speaker 5:  eve matter device to use with the HomePod which is great.
Speaker 4:  This had a light switch? A plug?
Speaker 5:  The plug, yes. Okay. The Eve energy plug and I'd already used,
Speaker 5:  I'd already been using a matter Eve energy plug that I'd upgraded myself
Speaker 5:  but there's just not enough devices out there yet to really get a feel of
Speaker 5:  how this is all gonna work. The momentum is there though and I would, you
Speaker 5:  know, I'm definitely gonna sort of check in in a a few months time and see
Speaker 5:  if the thread solution, the thread situation has
Speaker 5:  resolved itself and you know whether these devices are actually
Speaker 5:  creating a stronger, more robust network in your home or
Speaker 5:  if they're all still competing with each other and and causing issues, which
Speaker 5:  unfortunately is one of the problems at the moment. So
Speaker 4:  The, the dumb question here is if you have an existing home pod and you're
Speaker 4:  happy with it, your reasons to upgrade from a smart home perspective are
Speaker 4:  kind of zero, right? It's like you want thread but there's not enough reason
Speaker 4:  to have thread yet and if you have a new Apple TV or you have a home pod
Speaker 4:  mini or they actually get together and work together, you have hero routers
Speaker 4:  or an echo like that stuff will serve the purpose.
Speaker 5:  Correct. There's no major benefit to having multiple fed border
Speaker 5:  routers. You can do it and it will help extend your network, your mesh
Speaker 5:  network, but only if you live in a reasonable sized home you're not gonna
Speaker 5:  need multiple border routers. Yeah. So yes, if you have an original home
Speaker 5:  pot and you're happy with it, it's fast enough for you and it responds well
Speaker 5:  enough for you then you know you can get thread for less than
Speaker 5:  $300 quite easily by adding HomePod mini or an Apple TV
Speaker 5:  or as you said a border router from a, from a different company. Cuz
Speaker 2:  The new one's faster,
Speaker 5:  The new one is faster. Yes, that's been my experience from the smart home
Speaker 5:  side. Like I put a HomePod two and a mini together and asked
Speaker 5:  my questions and the HomePod two always got, got there first,
Speaker 5:  grab the glory and ran with it and responded quickly that like I said,
Speaker 5:  much less sort of, I mean an RN and kind of waiting, spinning its
Speaker 5:  wheels. There was a much fast response. I am actually on the new
Speaker 5:  Apple Home architecture, which I think is not actually to do with
Speaker 5:  matter but it's sort of like in preparation for matter and that is
Speaker 5:  something that they pulled, apple had a lot of issues
Speaker 5:  when it first rolled out but if you did get it when it first rolled out and
Speaker 5:  it worked for you, it's still working And I found
Speaker 5:  that it has been a lot more stable and a lot more reliable. So
Speaker 5:  the improvement in the HomePod two could also be down to
Speaker 5:  the improvement in the home architecture. I don't have an original HomePod
Speaker 5:  here to kind of compare but, but my mini is
Speaker 5:  not as fast so
Speaker 2:  It's probably probably gonna generally be faster. Chris, does it
Speaker 2:  sound better?
Speaker 6:  It sounds very similar to the first HomePod. Very similar and not the same.
Speaker 6:  Like if you, you put them side by side you can tell some differences. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  But sometimes the new one sounds clearer and better and sometimes the old
Speaker 6:  one sounds a bit more detailed, like all comes down to what song you're playing.
Speaker 6:  But on the whole it's very, very similar.
Speaker 4:  They cut down the number of tweeters right?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. There are five now as opposed to seven last time and there are four
Speaker 6:  mics instead of six. There's also a new system sensor is
Speaker 6:  what it's called, which is the most vague thing I've ever heard in my life
Speaker 6:  that's supposed to like help with all like the computational tuning even
Speaker 6:  better than it was last time. So on the whole those things should hopefully
Speaker 6:  balance out for like a very similar overall sound, which it is. So if you
Speaker 6:  like the first one you like this one, if you didn't like the first one, you're
Speaker 6:  probably not gonna love this one either. So
Speaker 2:  You're not gonna sit there, you never like we're listening to stuff on the
Speaker 2:  new one and being like man I just missed those seven tweeters.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Not myself but I'm sure there will be like a small group of people
Speaker 6:  who swear that they ruined it and that the first HomePod was like a really
Speaker 6:  special product.
Speaker 4:  Oh yeah, the stereo form people are about to, I mean this is, this
Speaker 4:  is the greatest gift they've ever been given is arguing with the number of
Speaker 4:  tweeters in the HomePod. So the, the first one when I reviewed it a
Speaker 4:  long time ago, there was a lot of apple like made a lot of noise
Speaker 4:  about computational audio using the
Speaker 4:  tweeters. They, you know, they have a sensor in the body
Speaker 4:  of the HomePod to measure the distance the woofer is going right.
Speaker 4:  They were bouncing some sound off the walls and measuring that in real time.
Speaker 4:  If you moved it they would remeasure it. Oh very cool. I was never like,
Speaker 4:  oh this is the greatest sounding speaker in history. Which is kind of where
Speaker 4:  Apple like led people to believe like their version
Speaker 4:  of computational audio would dramatically blow away speakers
Speaker 4:  costing tens of thousands of dollars and at the end of the day it's like
Speaker 4:  it's limited by its size, right? It's like it's this big and it can
Speaker 4:  do this much and like it sounds very good and the
Speaker 4:  Sonos one sounds pretty good too. And the Sonos five sounds
Speaker 4:  a little bit better and it has bigger low end drivers so
Speaker 4:  it can make more base, right? Like it's just very much they overhyped it
Speaker 4:  because I think Siri was bad so their solution to marketing it was like
Speaker 4:  it's the best sounding speaker in the world. Are they doing that again this
Speaker 4:  time or are they just kind of like here's you love the HomePod mini
Speaker 4:  now it's bigger,
Speaker 6:  There was less talk of all that stuff but it is still the same as far as
Speaker 6:  like the room Yeah stuff goes and all that background process goes.
Speaker 6:  But yeah, I mean the review that like the sound is very clear,
Speaker 6:  super detailed, rich, whatever, but there's no warmth to the HomePod sound
Speaker 6:  or as like Sonos does have some of that and some other speakers do. This
Speaker 6:  is very like this is what the lab told us a speaker should sound like.
Speaker 2:  Oh that's interesting though cuz I remember the one
Speaker 2:  HomePod having a much warmer sound than the Sonos one
Speaker 6:  Sometimes I guess certain tracks again it comes down to again but on the
Speaker 6:  whole it's just very clear to me like that's the one thing that I always
Speaker 6:  like vocals are right there in the center. It sounds good. I think two is
Speaker 6:  where it really starts to like sound really, really good but that's
Speaker 6:  $600 so at that point you are looking at a Sonos five
Speaker 6:  or whatever else too.
Speaker 4:  You will get more serious separation from two obviously.
Speaker 6:  Yeah so two together and that's where the spatial audio thing a case can
Speaker 6:  be be made that when you have two very nice speakers
Speaker 6:  beaming sound all over the room, that spatial audio does start to make a
Speaker 6:  bit more sense and sounds pretty good for like the very good master tracks.
Speaker 2:  Okay. It started to make sense. Did it actually like were you like okay I
Speaker 2:  get spatial audio now
Speaker 6:  For a few songs. Yeah but there are still so many that are bad that still
Speaker 6:  don't sound, don't sound as good as their stereo versions. But yeah there
Speaker 6:  are certainly some tracks where there's just like a more atmosphere and you
Speaker 6:  can hear instruments throughout the room and it's a bit more than stereo
Speaker 6:  itself. So it's there certainly more than headphones and earbuds where it's
Speaker 6:  still just very
Speaker 4:  Silly. My new go-to rules, it only sounds good if the music
Speaker 4:  was meant to be listened to on drugs. And so like music for being
Speaker 4:  on drugs that's like great and then everything else and we've got notes
Speaker 4:  about this PE people like it but everything else just kinda like loses impact.
Speaker 4:  And I think where Apple could succeed here is by getting away from
Speaker 4:  spatial audio for music which they are just relentlessly
Speaker 4:  promoting to to no discernible effect and focusing on the
Speaker 4:  TV features they've added to the HomePod, right? And saying okay you can
Speaker 4:  get two home pods together. They've added this new feature where you can
Speaker 4:  do er off of TV so you can send all the audio from your TV to your home pods.
Speaker 2:  Can we talk about that?
Speaker 4:  Well Chris explained that but then you get, you, do you get Atmos when you
Speaker 4:  do that? Like proper movie atmos?
Speaker 6:  I think it mixes down Atmos. Like there are no like up firing speakers obviously
Speaker 6:  in the HomePod. Yeah but it sounds pretty good. Yeah, so that feature's been
Speaker 6:  around, I guess they've called it beta to like last week when they actually
Speaker 6:  put out TV OS 16.3 or whatever it was. And so now it's like a full on
Speaker 6:  feature and so you can plug the Apple TV 4k, you need the new one that goes
Speaker 6:  into your TV's ER port and then the home pods will play all of your TV's
Speaker 6:  audio. So like I was playing a PS five game and there was like no latency,
Speaker 6:  no audio sync issues. I was like this is not supposed to work this well.
Speaker 6:  This is er, it's supposed to be a Hellscape,
Speaker 4:  It's htm I, yeah like none of this is supposed to work right, this public
Speaker 4:  service. What TV do you have that you are using this with?
Speaker 6:  I've got the hiene E eight H myself and I have very good wifi so I'm sure
Speaker 6:  that that plays into it too. There, there are many factors that could make
Speaker 6:  this worse for you but it does work. And so that by itself has me convinced
Speaker 6:  that Apple has more home theater stuff coming down the pipeline cuz like
Speaker 6:  why would you go through all that work just for the HomePod,
Speaker 4:  You know? Well I remember the number one thing when I did the review of the
Speaker 4:  first one, the number one question people asked was can I use it with my
Speaker 4:  Apple TV all the time? And so I think just from a, you know, not Apple doesn't
Speaker 4:  do like proper focus groups so just from like a market research perspective
Speaker 4:  they're like what would make the HomePod better? And they're like, I wanna
Speaker 4:  use it for my tv. It's like you would build it, they built it, you know,
Speaker 4:  I think I would put this in the same category of like, it doesn't detect
Speaker 4:  a fire but it can listen for a smoke alarm. It's like a Rube
Speaker 4:  Goldberg machine to get what you want out of the HomePod, right? It's like
Speaker 4:  you need an Apple TV and you er into the Apple TV and that wireless is sends
Speaker 4:  to the HomePod and we don't actually detect a fire but we'll listen for a
Speaker 4:  a smoke like it gets to the right outcome, which is your phone
Speaker 4:  beeps if there's a fire and the TV audio is coming outta the speaker. It's
Speaker 4:  just a winding path to get there that is kind of like distinctly on Apple.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it seems strange to leave your Apple TV on at all times for, for that
Speaker 6:  feature too. But it sounds better than like a Sonos Ray soundbar, like the
Speaker 6:  two of them together really The base those woofer are Yeah those are legit
Speaker 6:  wolfers. So like if you don't have like a subwoofer for your Sonos or any
Speaker 6:  kind of like budget level soundbar, this is gonna sound much better than
Speaker 6:  that. But again, you've gotta leave your Apple T on all the time, which I'm
Speaker 6:  sure some people do like that's their mainstreaming device and that's fine.
Speaker 2:  It's kind of in a weird place financially though because a beam is like
Speaker 2:  $300 and this is
Speaker 6:  $600.
Speaker 2:  Yes $600 and then an arc is what, $200 more
Speaker 2:  than that? Yeah. And that'll give you true atmos and
Speaker 2:  and everything. So it's like I don't really know if the people who are buying
Speaker 2:  a Sonos are like, do I wanna go into this weird middle ground
Speaker 2:  necessarily with two home pods?
Speaker 6:  Right? Yeah. That's for people who just like live like all in Apples world,
Speaker 6:  thoroughly in the ecosystem, don't want to go anywhere else and they're happy
Speaker 6:  there. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  If you're like an exceedingly well groomed person
Speaker 4:  who wears all black Yeah and you live alone and you
Speaker 4:  don't allow strangers into your house and all the magazines are perfectly
Speaker 4:  arranged, this is gonna be great for you. Yeah. And all of your
Speaker 4:  furniture's made out concrete, you know, like I'm describing like my idealized
Speaker 4:  lifestyle, like let's be, I'm not trying to talk down to be like if I was
Speaker 4:  very single, like I'd be like yes, all my furniture's made out of concrete
Speaker 4:  and you're not allow my home and all I have is home pods The wire
Speaker 4:  perfectly routed so you don't see it. But like in reality
Speaker 4:  that's like not how it works for most people.
Speaker 5:  Well you can remove the wire now. Yeah, exactly. Now that you can remove
Speaker 5:  the wire. I know we're gonna see third party battery mounts for this thing.
Speaker 4:  Oh my god.
Speaker 5:  There's, there's still a lot of question like why bring it back? Okay.
Speaker 5:  And I'm biased because I'm coming from the smart home side, but I think honestly
Speaker 5:  it all ties in with matter and thread because the
Speaker 5:  original home pod was discontinued just after they started Matter
Speaker 5:  and I think Apple realized that this was not gonna be capable
Speaker 5:  of supporting this new smart home platform. And the biggest
Speaker 5:  change really in, in this device I from the
Speaker 5:  original is the support for Thread and it has
Speaker 5:  matter which you can have in both, but this is now their flagship
Speaker 5:  smart home controller for matter. And the people
Speaker 5:  were sad it was gone, they wanted it back, it wasn't as successful as perhaps
Speaker 5:  people expected, but there's a passionate user base behind this,
Speaker 5:  this device, the original version and I'm sure there will be with the new
Speaker 5:  version and it it, it fits perfectly into the lineup
Speaker 5:  but it's not what they really needed to do. What they really need to do
Speaker 5:  is bring us a smart home controller that we can actually use to control our
Speaker 5:  smart home that has a touch interface and that works
Speaker 5:  with multiple people because right now Apple just
Speaker 5:  sucks at that. Yeah. I really struggled. I could
Speaker 5:  not get personal requests to work for all of my family with the
Speaker 5:  new home pod or the old home pod.
Speaker 2:  Just your your husband and you were the only ones that worked
Speaker 5:  For only my husband. I would work soon as I had my kids. It just went crazy.
Speaker 5:  Did
Speaker 2:  It? Was it just like they do not like pay the
Speaker 2:  mortgage so they do not get a say,
Speaker 5:  I dunno what it was. I've been talking to Apple, they've been troubleshooting
Speaker 5:  but we haven't found a solution. But every time I added either of my children,
Speaker 5:  one of whom is over 14 and one of whom is under, cuz that's a, a cutoff point
Speaker 5:  with family sharing, it would just stop recognizing anyone's
Speaker 5:  voice. And the personal request side is a real challenge
Speaker 5:  in the smart home. None of the other platforms have actually nailed it very
Speaker 5:  well either. I I struggle with both Google Home and
Speaker 5:  Amazon's Alexis ecosystem for them to recognize personal
Speaker 5:  requests. It's, it's a hard, it's a hard problem but it's one that really
Speaker 5:  needs to be solved because the smart home is not about the single guy in
Speaker 5:  the concrete house. It's about multi-user
Speaker 5:  homes and, and places where, you know, you've got roommates, there's
Speaker 5:  very few people that live alone and that are gonna have a, a vast or
Speaker 5:  a comprehensive smart home ecosystem because, and that's something that all
Speaker 5:  these solutions need to work on and hopefully,
Speaker 5:  I mean Apples has been the most useful to date because of the
Speaker 5:  tight integration with the phone. But obviously if not everyone in your home
Speaker 5:  uses iPhones or iOS devices, then it's, it's just not
Speaker 5:  useful. And as much as matter is helping bring down those ward
Speaker 5:  gardens for the smart home, apple is still
Speaker 5:  very much a curated garden party.
Speaker 4:  Well so, so the the the matter piece for Apple is really interesting. They're,
Speaker 4:  they're very much behind it. They did give up a bunch of home kit or share
Speaker 4:  it with the, the Matter consortium to build off of it and that's because
Speaker 4:  the other smart home ecosystems were ahead, right? Alexa
Speaker 4:  notably is, is much more ahead, many more devices work
Speaker 4:  with Alexa, you get everybody to support Matter. All those devices work with
Speaker 4:  Home Kit as well. You can control them from your phone. That's great for
Speaker 4:  Apple but isn't the flip side of it that the Alexa, you know,
Speaker 4:  in Echo show can also control your, your smart plugs just
Speaker 4:  as well as home kit on your phone?
Speaker 5:  Well that's the, that's the key phrase just as well
Speaker 5:  will it, I mean because Matter is giving that
Speaker 5:  common infrastructure so that everyone can control the same devices
Speaker 5:  but you still have to have the, the good user experience on top.
Speaker 5:  And as I've talked about before in articles, it, the Home
Speaker 5:  pod and the Apple Home ecosystem is one of the better user
Speaker 5:  experiences. The Alexa experience, the Amazon experience is
Speaker 5:  still, it's, it's so big and it does, it can do so many things
Speaker 5:  that it's also really hard to kind of keep track of
Speaker 5:  and remember exactly what what you want it to do. And you might ask it to
Speaker 5:  turn on a light and it will go and buy you some toilet paper. You know, there,
Speaker 5:  there is too much going on. Whereas the Siri ecosystem and
Speaker 5:  Apple Home is a lot more tightly controlled. So if you're using matter
Speaker 5:  devices in either platform, you're gonna have different experiences
Speaker 5:  because of the experience that each platform adds. And that's
Speaker 5:  where the, they're gonna differentiate is by, you know, with Apple Home
Speaker 5:  you can use adaptive lighting and that's not part of a matter yet, but
Speaker 5:  hopefully it will come so that, you know, you don't just have to buy the
Speaker 5:  expensive light bulbs to get that expensive feeling feature where the
Speaker 5:  lights change naturally during the day with sunlight you'll
Speaker 5:  be able to use any matter enabled light bulb and you know, have that
Speaker 5:  feature that you can use through Apple Home. Amazon Alexa
Speaker 5:  doesn't offer that feature yet. So you know, there's gonna be things like
Speaker 5:  that that make the difference that that make you choose one platform over
Speaker 5:  the other.
Speaker 6:  I think this product was just, just like so easy for them. It's like such
Speaker 6:  an easy lift like so they call this the all new HomePod and that's just the
Speaker 6:  funniest thing I've ever heard in my life. Cause it's like the same design
Speaker 6:  and it's like here's your new speaker. It's very similar and so they just
Speaker 6:  like bought themselves probably two years to build something new that's actually
Speaker 6:  gonna like be that new thing for the home.
Speaker 4:  Well so you were talking about what they should build, right? Which is like
Speaker 4:  a tablet with a touch screen that you can actually click the buttons on,
Speaker 4:  like put put an iPad on a stand. That's what Google is doing with the
Speaker 4:  next version of the Nest. We don't know when it's gonna come but they showed
Speaker 4:  one. I'm wondering on a more conceptual level
Speaker 4:  home kit in particular doesn't live anywhere that a
Speaker 4:  user understands, right? You buy an Echo and
Speaker 4:  it's like now I'm in control of your smart home and you're like, okay this
Speaker 4:  computer is the one that's in charge of my smart home and that's not
Speaker 4:  exactly right. There's a lot of cloud services and all this other stuff going
Speaker 4:  on, but like you're like this is the thing that controls my House Home Kit
Speaker 4:  lives on an Apple tv, it lives on an
Speaker 4:  iPad until recently it could live on this thing. Like a lot you can solve
Speaker 4:  a lot of home kit problems by just like rebooting your Apple tv which
Speaker 5:  Or your iPhone. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Or your iPhone and it's like the lights aren't working. I needed to turn
Speaker 4:  off my phone. Like I say this stuff out loud to people and I I know I just
Speaker 4:  sound like a maniac.
Speaker 5:  That's so true.
Speaker 4:  Does this solve that problem? It's like all right, I'm just gonna reboot
Speaker 4:  the HomePod and that'll fix it.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So it, that has been the go-to solution for any
Speaker 5:  issue with home kit, your phone and your whichever
Speaker 5:  home hub you have and with Alexa in particular and a lot of Google
Speaker 5:  Home there's much more reliance on the cloud but the
Speaker 5:  intricacies of how the Apple TV and the HomePod and the
Speaker 5:  phone and all work together have very much been kind of a black box.
Speaker 5:  We just know that rebooting the phone works, who
Speaker 5:  knows why Apple has said, I think that the new home architecture is gonna
Speaker 5:  kind of make some of that a little clearer but that hasn't
Speaker 5:  officially arrived yet. So we, we still don't really understand the difference.
Speaker 5:  I did notice in my testing since I've been on the new home architecture
Speaker 5:  that it does stick with one home hub rather than bouncing
Speaker 5:  around like it used to love going to my HomePod minis, which I would
Speaker 5:  constantly unplug for various reasons and would mess everything up. Now it
Speaker 5:  just sticks with my Apple TV that's hardwired and it's like hallelujah, this
Speaker 5:  makes sense, this is what we should have done since the beginning. Do you
Speaker 5:  get to choose that? No. No you still can't choose it
Speaker 5:  but it just seems to be more rational than it used to be before.
Speaker 5:  And it did try and use the HomePod, the new HomePod a couple times but then
Speaker 5:  it was like eh went back to the Apple tv. So and that's something
Speaker 5:  about the smart home in general that I think confuses people and what is
Speaker 5:  gonna help with matter because we're gonna bring almost
Speaker 5:  most devices and most interactions that you need to be
Speaker 5:  quick and happen on a regular basis into your home and local
Speaker 5:  without having to use the cloud because that's where, you know, when people
Speaker 5:  get frustrated with Siri, I think we talked about this on our last episode
Speaker 5:  together Alex, you know, because she's, it is waiting or it's, it
Speaker 5:  can't connect to the internet or it can't get some device to work. Yeah it's
Speaker 5:  normally something is broken in a cloud connection or some kind of wifi
Speaker 5:  connection. Whereas once we have this more robust
Speaker 5:  infrastructure for the smart home, those kind of issues won't, won't happen
Speaker 5:  so much hopefully and it'll be a much smoother experience, you know,
Speaker 5:  just as easy as actually turning the light switch on
Speaker 4:  The ever elusive goal. It's so funny because I still have my little
Speaker 4:  HomeBridge tamagotchi in the garage that I have to go and like reboot and
Speaker 4:  open up to take the SD card out and like reformat it every few
Speaker 4:  months and I'm like, this is better. Like this is like
Speaker 4:  concentrated effort into chaos like every three months I started all over
Speaker 4:  and then it's fine for three months as opposed to you know like
Speaker 4:  matter which is one day I'm sure just like Bluetooth it'll be better.
Speaker 4:  But right now it's like a lot of like diffuse effort to even
Speaker 4:  know what the hell is going on.
Speaker 5:  I think the good thing though, the thing that I'm most excited about with
Speaker 5:  Matter and Thread is that you won't need a tamagotchi, you won't
Speaker 5:  need a single device that runs everything because when you have a single
Speaker 5:  device that runs everything, you have a single point of failure and that's
Speaker 5:  when things go belly up. And you know, with thread in particular
Speaker 5:  and with Apple and most of the ecosystems putting matter and
Speaker 5:  thread into every device, most people these days with smart
Speaker 5:  homes have more than one smart speaker. So you're gonna have these multiple
Speaker 5:  points that can keep your smart home running if you know,
Speaker 5:  because someone unplugged your Echo speaker to use their hair
Speaker 5:  dryer and you didn't realize and now nothing's working in your home anymore,
Speaker 5:  you know that that won't happen anymore. And that's one of the reasons I
Speaker 5:  think that thread B got chosen over ZigBee because in
Speaker 5:  previously and when you use ZigBee, if you're familiar with, you know like
Speaker 5:  Phillips Hugh runs on a ZigBee bridge and you know, one morning I might wake
Speaker 5:  up and I'm like why are none of my lights turning on? And I realize it's
Speaker 5:  because someone unplugged my hub bridge for some reason. But nothing, you
Speaker 5:  know, it's, you're gonna lose that single point of failure and
Speaker 5:  the smart home is gonna become much more kind of diffuse
Speaker 5:  and more integrated into your home rather than just relying on little white
Speaker 5:  boxes or or Tamagotchis in the garage.
Speaker 4:  No, but Jen, here's my solution though. Everything is routed through my HomeBridge
Speaker 4:  Tamagotchi but then independently of that, that is plugged into a
Speaker 4:  smart plug that is on home kit natively. Oh my gosh. So when the home bridge
Speaker 4:  crashes I can just reboot people living. No that's my smart
Speaker 4:  plug. It's sounds like a genius
Speaker 5:  That works unless your WiFi's gone down.
Speaker 4:  That's true.
Speaker 5:  And then you're just outta luck.
Speaker 4:  This is also a great solution for troubleshooting anything at your parents'
Speaker 4:  house remotely is you get a smart plug on their network and then you just
Speaker 4:  turn Yes. Not from your
Speaker 5:  As I, I spent like three hours on the phone with my dad the
Speaker 5:  other night because he couldn't figure out why when he reconnected his router
Speaker 5:  it wasn't working and he just put two cables the wrong way round and it's
Speaker 5:  like ugh. Yep this the smart home is doomed.
Speaker 2:  Well it we, we are gonna face like a challenge for the next couple of years
Speaker 2:  though, right? As everybody has cuz people still have to upgrade
Speaker 2:  everything that's never gonna support matter and they're still gonna have
Speaker 2:  to like wait for some companies Dyson's like yeah we're doing matter and
Speaker 2:  then crickets.
Speaker 5:  There's a lot of crickets. Yeah. Sonos crickets. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah though the good thing is that matter works with your existing
Speaker 5:  ecosystems, right? So if you are all in on Apple Home or all in on
Speaker 5:  Amazon or Google or smart things, you can start adding matter
Speaker 5:  devices now and they will work just like they do.
Speaker 5:  Like your system works today. So it's not like we are asking, you know, it's
Speaker 5:  not matter's not going to make everything have to start from scratch. It
Speaker 5:  is gonna be a slow process. It's, you know, like when they try and redo roads
Speaker 5:  or redo the plumbing, they're not gonna do it all at once because everything
Speaker 5:  would explode. You need, it's a slow process. So yes, I
Speaker 5:  think ultimately I'm gonna be doing this for a long time. It's gonna keep
Speaker 5:  me in a job.
Speaker 6:  Speaking of Sonos, I do kind of wonder, we did mention Sonos and I do
Speaker 6:  kind of wonder if like six months down the line we're gonna wonder like did
Speaker 6:  Apple play it too safe with the home pot too? Cause like Sonos is gonna come
Speaker 6:  out with a brand new like holy designed speaker, like spatial audio. You
Speaker 6:  say, okay, here's like a 10 driver like speaker that's gonna have u
Speaker 6:  s BBC in and all sorts of crazy stuff. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  It, I'm just really hesitant to think of how many people who
Speaker 2:  can afford a home pod are also thinking like it's either that
Speaker 2:  or the Sonos. I would assume most of those people are usually like, it's
Speaker 2:  that and the Sonos.
Speaker 4:  I make this mistake too, I think, I always think the home pod is like, you
Speaker 4:  should get two of them. And so like I think it costs $600 but it costs
Speaker 4:  $300.
Speaker 2:  Cost 300.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It's, it's in a, a pretty reasonable range for a lot of
Speaker 4:  of people who are willing to spend money on smart light, light switches and
Speaker 4:  whatever. Like I think what Chris is getting at is Sonos is gonna offer you
Speaker 4:  more advanced technology than what Apple has. It might have even more
Speaker 4:  unnecessary audio processing and it will work with more things. For
Speaker 4:  example, a thing that the Sonos speaker will do is work with
Speaker 4:  Spotify,
Speaker 6:  Which is still not there as a default service, but I guess that's
Speaker 6:  Spotify's fault at this, at this point. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  But I I think like they're different products, right? Like one is
Speaker 2:  probably more intended for the home pod I see is more like,
Speaker 2:  oh I've got Sonos in my, my living room, that's my home theater.
Speaker 2:  I'm not gonna necessarily want to use Home Pods for that. The Home pod is
Speaker 2:  more like, I need to have music while I'm cooking dinner and I need to
Speaker 2:  be able to talk to it because one is talking and like Sonos is bad
Speaker 2:  at the assistant. Sonos is real, real bad. Oh yeah. Assistance. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  So I just don't like if you're getting it for the assistant, you don't need,
Speaker 2:  like, those are two different things.
Speaker 5:  It falls in a slightly odd spot because if you just need the, the
Speaker 5:  music while you're cooking dinner, then you've got the mini Yeah. If you
Speaker 5:  want more interaction, you want to follow a recipe in the kitchen, then
Speaker 5:  you're gonna go with like a show, an echo show or a a Nest hub, you know,
Speaker 5:  an iPad sitting next to a mini is just, just feels kind of wrong.
Speaker 5:  I just feel like it's, it is, as Chris said, it was an easy upgrade now,
Speaker 5:  but I don't think it's the grand plan for Apple Home going forward, right?
Speaker 5:  Yeah,
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I might, but I think I'm in a very small minority because we use
Speaker 4:  Google Assistant on our Sonos one and we use Google
Speaker 4:  Homes and their default audio devices
Speaker 4:  set to Sonos speakers and the various streams they're in
Speaker 4:  and these companies are suing each other and they hate each other and everyone
Speaker 4:  says it's not supposed to work.
Speaker 5:  I was gonna say, how did you get that to work?
Speaker 4:  I think it's because I cover the lawsuit that they're both like, we can't
Speaker 4:  screw this up in this one house whitelists like one engineer from
Speaker 4:  each company on call to be like, all right, they asked to play classic rock
Speaker 4:  at 7:00 PM like make it happen. And like someone pushes the play on
Speaker 4:  Spotify on the Sonos side. Like, I don't know, I
Speaker 4:  I'm assuming there's some sort of complicated legal PR rub
Speaker 4:  Goldberg machine to make sure it works in my house, but I like
Speaker 4:  that's the dream, right? Is that you assemble all these components from all
Speaker 4:  these different vendors and you kind of get the, the best of everything
Speaker 4:  or at least as solution is more tailored to you. Yeah, right,
Speaker 4:  because what I want is the, the only reason we have Google
Speaker 4:  Homes is cuz of the photo feature on the, the on the Nest hubs. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  It's really good. And like, I don't know why Amazon hasn't built a good photo
Speaker 4:  system for the, I dunno why Apple they've tried,
Speaker 2:  Hasn't built one at all
Speaker 4:  And yeah, apple does the default, like just make the thing with the
Speaker 4:  screen, like people will buy it without a second hesitation. But like that's
Speaker 4:  what we want. So that's what we have. And then we want Sono speakers cuz
Speaker 4:  that works with all the other stuff we have and it's like I would get a home
Speaker 4:  pod, but again it's like the concrete table problem where it's like, it's
Speaker 4:  designed for this one, it's designed for Tim Cook. Yeah, Tim Cook's house
Speaker 4:  a lot of concrete furniture in it, you know, and like, it's just like you
Speaker 4:  don't make enough products here. I like, it's not versatile
Speaker 4:  enough where there's not, the product line is not versatile enough to,
Speaker 4:  to fit into all these spots in your house. So I I guess I'm coming out
Speaker 4:  from kind of the same place as you Alex, which is like, there's maybe one
Speaker 4:  room in my house where this would be great. Yeah, but there's like, I
Speaker 4:  want a smart home is like the home.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. This home pod is like slightly better, slightly cheaper, but
Speaker 6:  it's not gonna change the calculus on like who's buying it in the first place.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And so I think like the first one wasn't a hit, I can't see this one
Speaker 6:  being like a smash hit either at 2 99, maybe once it goes down like
Speaker 6:  2, 2 49 at some stores that'll pick up some. But I think like on the whole
Speaker 6:  it's, it's the same HomePod, bit smarter.
Speaker 2:  What is the price you would like instant buy it
Speaker 6:  At? I think 1 99 for sure.
Speaker 4:  I'd be like sure buy it.
Speaker 5:  And that's the studio. The Echo Studio is 1 99.
Speaker 5:  Sonos one is 1 99 2. Right. Thereabouts.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I'm just gonna say this out loud. A really good pair of regular
Speaker 4:  old stereo speakers sounds better than any of this stuff.
Speaker 4:  Blasphemy. Yes. It's it's just true. It's true.
Speaker 2:  It's true. Do you ever go into the, the home theater Reddit and it's like
Speaker 2:  half the people are there like I've just replaced my, my Sonos or my
Speaker 2:  vio soundbar or whatever and I just got two speakers and got
Speaker 2:  rid of my sub and it's like I'm hearing everything for the first time.
Speaker 4:  It's like way better. It's just way better. Yeah. There's there's an entire
Speaker 4:  other episode of the show on the specs that get marketed and in
Speaker 4:  whatever. I'm just saying like all these speakers are like inherently noisy
Speaker 4:  and they try to cover it up with extra processing because they're full of
Speaker 4:  radios and like if you just like make speakers that are not full of
Speaker 4:  radios and are connected with wires to clean sources, you're like in
Speaker 4:  a much better spot.
Speaker 2:  Whoa. But
Speaker 5:  That's the problem everyone, you know, we, we want these multi-use devices
Speaker 5:  now in our home. We expect more out of our speakers than to just play music
Speaker 5:  or just to play the audio from our tv. And it's, it's a problem
Speaker 5:  and it's actually a another problem. I mean Chris and I have talked about
Speaker 5:  this in the past, like Matter actually has a casting spec built in.
Speaker 5:  So in theory, if all these players keep playing nice
Speaker 5:  together, you know, we could be playing all our music on all of our
Speaker 5:  smart speakers and our airplay speakers. Everything could all work
Speaker 5:  harmoniously. But that doesn't seem like it's going to
Speaker 5:  happen.
Speaker 5:  Mainly because Sonos and, and Bos and, and a couple of
Speaker 5:  the other big speaker companies who are part of the csa,
Speaker 5:  which is behind Matter, don't seem to be actually making any movement
Speaker 5:  or any headway on doing this multi-room audio
Speaker 5:  between companies and the individual companies that have
Speaker 5:  multi-room audio like Amazon and Google and Apple, you know,
Speaker 5:  they wanna keep their, that the, these are little fons that look like they're
Speaker 5:  gonna stay. We're not, the whole kumbaya part of Matter
Speaker 5:  doesn't necessarily look like it's going to go through the entire
Speaker 5:  smart home space unfortunately. And audio is such a big ticket item for most
Speaker 5:  of these companies, right? Cuz they want you to stick with their streaming
Speaker 5:  service, their subscription service.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I think at the end of the day, like Amazon and Apple and Google, like
Speaker 4:  have no interest in making smart plugs or window shade
Speaker 4:  controllers cuz there's no recurring revenue against them. Like exactly.
Speaker 4:  And Apple's like it's our new smart plug. It, it's part of iCloud, it'll
Speaker 4:  cost $10 a month, people go away. And so like you see
Speaker 4:  where they're like willing to commodify the ecosystem, but streaming
Speaker 4:  services are recurring revenue. They are locked to a certain
Speaker 4:  extent. They are excellent places to upsell you to other parts of their
Speaker 4:  services bundle. There's no way to wanna go that
Speaker 5:  Stuff. No. So yeah, it's always going. The fragmentation is going to remain
Speaker 5:  on those levels for sure. We're not gonna get the simple Smart home for
Speaker 5:  many years.
Speaker 4:  Just make me in charge of everything. Who's the president of the CSA and
Speaker 4:  how do I take him out?
Speaker 2:  They gotta get you your Apple tv, your TV made by Apple.
Speaker 4:  I'm gonna go to that guy's house, reboot his Apple TV and he'll be having
Speaker 4:  shot.
Speaker 4:  I Sorry.
Speaker 2:  All right guys, so the, the reviews up now, Jenna and Chris worked on it
Speaker 2:  together. Thank you guys. We're gonna take a break and then when we get back
Speaker 2:  I'm gonna be talking with Catherine Tri DeCosta about faking your death online.
Speaker 2:  It makes sense in context. I swear
Speaker 4:  It's a hard segue. Can we fake the CSA guy's death
Speaker 4:  online?
Speaker 1:  Okay.
Speaker 7:  Support for this episode comes from Brex, the corporate card and
Speaker 7:  spend management software teams actually love. If you're a CFO
Speaker 7:  or finance leader today, you know we are operating in
Speaker 7:  transformational times. It can be hard getting people all in the same
Speaker 7:  place and not over another Zoom call Now more
Speaker 7:  than ever before, you need to help build a connection with not only your
Speaker 7:  team, but with your clientele in real life. Thankfully
Speaker 7:  Bra can help. Brax is an integrated solution of corporate
Speaker 7:  cards and span management software that drives 100%
Speaker 7:  compliance and zero receipt chasing in over 100 countries.
Speaker 7:  Brex is easy to set up and easy to use with dedicated
Speaker 7:  implementation software and intuitive consumer grade design
Speaker 7:  and the Brex mobile app. And if you ever need support, you can always
Speaker 7:  reach out by phone app or chat twenty four seven. It's that simple.
Speaker 7:  Brex makes it easy to manage every aspect of spending from the
Speaker 7:  smallest purchases to the biggest procurements. No matter where your team
Speaker 7:  works, they help empower employees to do the right thing and spend
Speaker 7:  responsibly and compliance is built in. So with everything from
Speaker 7:  restaurants to retail stores to your work platform, all going
Speaker 7:  cloud-based, isn't it time for your company to use a spend management
Speaker 7:  solution for modern times? Learn more at
Speaker 7:  brex.com/podcast.
Speaker 8:  Running a business is stressful, but worrying about how to grow
Speaker 8:  your company in the digital space can make any ambitious person wanna give
Speaker 8:  up. Wouldn't it be nice to have a set of expertly designed tools to help
Speaker 8:  you create your own growth tailored exactly to your company's needs?
Speaker 8:  That's where uny comes in. Unisys is a global technology
Speaker 8:  solutions company dedicated to helping people and organizations reach
Speaker 8:  their next breakthrough. They offer tools to help you run your business more
Speaker 8:  efficiently, like systems integration, consulting services,
Speaker 8:  application management and device management software plus
Speaker 8:  Unisys applies specialized expertise to strengthen and transform
Speaker 8:  teams and processes by helping organizations act on new opportunities
Speaker 8:  through digital workplace cloud applications, enterprise
Speaker 8:  computing and business process solutions. To learn more, visit
Speaker 8:  uny.com. That's U N I S ys.com.
Speaker 8:  Unisys, keep breaking through.
Speaker 2:  All right, welcome back. I'm very excited because I'm talking with my friend
Speaker 2:  Catherine Tri DeCosta. We've worked together, we've been colleagues for many,
Speaker 2:  many years and one of our favorite things to talk about is
Speaker 2:  faking your death online.
Speaker 2:  I know that's like a weird thing to have a favorite to talk about, but Catherine
Speaker 2:  and I love to talk about it. And there was a super weird one that actually
Speaker 2:  appeared in the New York Times last month called a Fake Death in Romance
Speaker 2:  Landia. And it's all about this romance novelist who, you know,
Speaker 2:  faked her death. So like naturally I had to get together with Katherine,
Speaker 2:  we had to talk about it. She's like categorized fake deaths
Speaker 2:  into different buckets for reasons. It's, it's a whole thing. We're just
Speaker 2:  gonna go ahead and get to that chat right now with Katherine Trin DeCosta.
Speaker 2:  Hello Catherine. Thank you for joining me today. Thank
Speaker 2:  you for having me to talk about one of my favorite
Speaker 2:  topics of the world. Yeah, you, you and I have talked many times
Speaker 2:  about fandom and online communities in the absolutely
Speaker 2:  wild things that come out of it. And what we're talking about today
Speaker 2:  is this woman was a member of the romance novelist
Speaker 2:  community, specifically self-published romance novels. She was a
Speaker 2:  member of this community. She was super, super active. She was so active
Speaker 2:  that she was getting a lot of hate. And then one day someone appeared
Speaker 2:  on her her account and said she had this, was that it was her daughter and
Speaker 2:  she had passed away. Everybody mourned two years
Speaker 2:  passed. She reappeared on January 2nd of this year
Speaker 2:  to say, surprise, I am alive. I'm excited to get back into the
Speaker 2:  community. Let's have some fun. And the community
Speaker 2:  did not react with the same enthusiasm that this
Speaker 2:  author had. It's weird, it's almost as if if
Speaker 2:  you fake your own death and people mourn you, if you show
Speaker 2:  back up, people are not happy to see you. They are in
Speaker 2:  fact very upset by the emotional manipulation. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  and it was very interesting. The New York Times did a piece on
Speaker 2:  this and it was very focused on the mental health element. This woman had
Speaker 2:  been battling depression, she'd been battling other mental health issues
Speaker 2:  and she really laid a lot of it of the situation at the feet of, of, of
Speaker 2:  that. And we've just seen this
Speaker 2:  particular circumstance appear over and over and over again. Well, here's
Speaker 2:  the thing, if you are burnt out or if you are being attacked, it is
Speaker 2:  perfectly valid to want to take a break,
Speaker 2:  to want to leave that community, to want to not interact
Speaker 2:  with the people who are causing you harm. You see that actually a fair bit
Speaker 2:  when people are like, I'm just leaving social media, it's bad for me. People
Speaker 2:  are yelling and I I can't handle it. That is all perfectly valid.
Speaker 2:  Right. What you can't do is affect
Speaker 2:  other people's health by putting them through the trauma of
Speaker 2:  thinking someone they know has died. Right. And that's,
Speaker 2:  that's what happened here. Yes. If it's just about you, if it's just about
Speaker 2:  your health and this is a thing you actually see on the internet all the
Speaker 2:  time, you can just disappear. You don't have to make an announcement
Speaker 2:  even. Right. If you're not using your real name and they don't know who you
Speaker 2:  are, you can just leave. Yeah. You can always just leave.
Speaker 2:  So when you do something like this, it
Speaker 2:  becomes pretty clear that it's not just about
Speaker 2:  your own health, it's about something
Speaker 2:  else. It's either about like, you want to
Speaker 2:  bury this and never come back, which is why this person coming back was
Speaker 2:  unusual. Usually it's about trying to escape because yes,
Speaker 2:  something's about to catch up to you and you wanna cause trauma so that people
Speaker 2:  don't poke into it harder or it's just about attention on
Speaker 2:  its own. Right. So faking a death is like a
Speaker 2:  very extreme thing to do because it's not about you, it's about
Speaker 2:  the effect that fake death has on many other people. And I talked
Speaker 2:  to you about this like, it's like a spectrum. Yeah. When you fake your own
Speaker 2:  death, there's like a, an x-axis at Y axis and on the
Speaker 2:  xaxis is like, you should be a chart. You made a whole chart. Yes.
Speaker 2:  I drew a chart. So on the X axis there's like, are you killing
Speaker 2:  your fake killing yourself or are you fake killing like
Speaker 2:  members of your fake family or other things to like
Speaker 2:  get attention or to just like give an excuse as to
Speaker 2:  why something. And then the Y axis is like,
Speaker 2:  you are doing this because people are catching up to your con
Speaker 2:  and you need to go or you're doing it for attention
Speaker 2:  just purely for attention. And like these things
Speaker 2:  is all a spectrum and you can be, because it's the internet, it can both
Speaker 2:  be yourself and someone else at the same time.
Speaker 2:  And it can be a little bit of like, yeah, I wanna
Speaker 2:  leave this situation before my lies catch up to me, but I also want
Speaker 2:  attention. Yeah. And I think it's interesting that it, it really happens
Speaker 2:  in these fandom communities, right? Like you and
Speaker 2:  I are both members of fandom communities. We've both been, we've seen this
Speaker 2:  happen a lot in, in in the last 20 years.
Speaker 2:  What are some examples of this happening before? Because this wasn't the
Speaker 2:  first time we've seen somebody in a very small, very active
Speaker 2:  community suddenly, nope. Out of that community by
Speaker 2:  faking a death. So my little chart that I
Speaker 2:  made for myself actually doesn't have a ton of fandom examples because I
Speaker 2:  wanted to be more accessible to normal people. Ah-huh. So like
Speaker 2:  on one hand you have the Ban Tao thing, which has a documentary
Speaker 2:  came out recently about it and that was very
Speaker 2:  clearly a getting away fake
Speaker 2:  death, right? So the Man Tao story
Speaker 2:  was this football player on this Notre
Speaker 2:  Dame team that was doing really well. The major news cycle of that story
Speaker 2:  was that man Tao's grandmother and girlfriend
Speaker 2:  both died, that he continued to during that year
Speaker 2:  that he was playing for them, all of those things. And it turned out that
Speaker 2:  the girlfriend did not exist and that Tao
Speaker 2:  had been catfished, which is, you know, the term for someone pretending
Speaker 2:  to be someone else online to lure people into
Speaker 2:  various kinds of relationships. And in that case, the,
Speaker 2:  the person pretending to to be the girlfriend
Speaker 2:  was very clearly had killed this person off in an
Speaker 2:  attempt to end the lies, to sort of
Speaker 2:  get away from this sort of fake thing that the catfishing kill the
Speaker 2:  catfish. Right. So that's sort of in the self getaway
Speaker 2:  category in the dead center, this was a big story like I think a couple
Speaker 2:  years ago, like at zero zero on the graph is
Speaker 2:  Beth Ann McLaughlin. Now Beth Ann McLaughlin
Speaker 2:  was a professor at a university who
Speaker 2:  announced the death of another academic from C
Speaker 2:  O V I D, this academic having been a person
Speaker 2:  who had been very vocal and active in the
Speaker 2:  move for greater equality within the
Speaker 2:  sciences. So this person had been Native American
Speaker 2:  and disabled and queer I believe as well. And
Speaker 2:  then in a truly horrifying manipulation,
Speaker 2:  this other academic came up and said, oh she's,
Speaker 2:  she's died of Covid. And that turned out that she had less
Speaker 2:  died of Covid and more never existed and had in fact
Speaker 2:  been Beth and McLaughlin the whole time. So she had to get
Speaker 2:  rid of her because she couldn't have anybody. Yes. So this was both killing
Speaker 2:  somewhat a fake someone else and your fake self and it was to get
Speaker 2:  rid of both the con and clearly for attention, otherwise you wouldn't announce
Speaker 2:  it using your own real name. Like there's a lot going on
Speaker 2:  in that one. It's one of my favorites because it's, if this person
Speaker 2:  had paid attention to online fandoms, she would've known like
Speaker 2:  anytime you make an announcement
Speaker 2:  about someone else's death, they're gonna look at
Speaker 2:  you. So don't attach your real name to it. Like it was wild.
Speaker 2:  And then in the form of like clearly just doing it for
Speaker 2:  attention and like killing random family members
Speaker 2:  or like other people and then giving themselves cancer
Speaker 2:  is the infamous Miss Scribe, the fandom
Speaker 2:  person who had so many
Speaker 2:  massive moments of fandom, drama that it
Speaker 2:  involved a giant like eight part series
Speaker 2:  of posts where this person did more work than journalists
Speaker 2:  do in dissecting what had gone on. There's like a term
Speaker 2:  for when you're killing other people where it's, it's called munchhausen
Speaker 2:  by internet. Right. Because the, the famous thing is munchhausen by proxy.
Speaker 2:  That's when usually parents pretend or make
Speaker 2:  their child sick so that they can get attention as the
Speaker 2:  caregiver of a sick child, at least in munch housing by internet there
Speaker 2:  usually isn't a real child, but people will
Speaker 2:  for attention or sympathy beef up their trauma.
Speaker 2:  And I think the reason we're sort of seeing this acceleration of it
Speaker 2:  is that it's come with the acceleration of like
Speaker 2:  attention as a commodity online. Yes.
Speaker 2:  And so you can't just step away. You have to get attention
Speaker 2:  when you step away too. What's bigger attention getting
Speaker 2:  than dying? There's also like a
Speaker 2:  vindictiveness about it that is very internety that's very like,
Speaker 2:  you people did not appreciate me enough and
Speaker 2:  you did not like me enough or you did not pay me enough
Speaker 2:  attention. So in addition to doing this thing that'll get attention,
Speaker 2:  I'm gonna make it painful for you. I'm gonna make you feel bad
Speaker 2:  about it. Right. So I both get attention and I've gotten
Speaker 2:  back at you. Yeah. And going back to the, the Miss
Speaker 2:  Scribe example because that's I think one of the most interesting ones.
Speaker 2:  It was one of the earliest ones. This was like what early two thousands.
Speaker 2:  It was in the Harry Potter fandom community, which at the time was
Speaker 2:  one of the biggest online communities out there.
Speaker 2:  There was a lot of people involved and this whole
Speaker 2:  saga like took down fan websites. Like it it did
Speaker 2:  a lot. Yeah. It was, it created this, this huge
Speaker 2:  kind of catastrophe through the entire fandom community.
Speaker 2:  And a lot of people were involved, I believe Cassandra Claire, the
Speaker 2:  now very famous New York Times author was a part of that
Speaker 2:  community and, and was having to deal with the the, with it's having to
Speaker 2:  deal with it while also being accused of I think plagiarism within the community.
Speaker 2:  There was just a whole whole lot of mess. And
Speaker 2:  at the center of it was Miss Scribe who had had gotten involved with a
Speaker 2:  whole lot of people and then when things started to get really intense,
Speaker 2:  started killing off family members that we assumed did
Speaker 2:  not really exist. And a lot of the reporting done since then
Speaker 2:  bears out that, and I think it's really interesting because we really only
Speaker 2:  see this when the internet came around, this wasn't a
Speaker 2:  phenomenon as common pre-internet. And it was like, okay, we
Speaker 2:  can all communicate, we can all gather in these smaller groups now
Speaker 2:  and we can also get so intense that we don't necessarily
Speaker 2:  know how to regulate ourselves and escape these.
Speaker 2:  And I think like we've all had those moments where you're like, oh, I'm really
Speaker 2:  into this community and you need to figure out a way out. And these people
Speaker 2:  are like, okay, my great-grandmother's gonna die for a third time today.
Speaker 2:  Well I I didn't think of it actually as like going full circle before like
Speaker 2:  pictures and documents. You could fake your own death by
Speaker 2:  just walking to another town and claiming to be someone else, right? Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Like this used, this used to be an easier thing, but it didn't used to be
Speaker 2:  for attention. It was escape. It was always an escape thing.
Speaker 2:  It was a conmen trying to escape or
Speaker 2:  you know, various other things. People just trying to leave scandal behind.
Speaker 2:  There is sort of the infamous like theories about, about various
Speaker 2:  lords who fake their own deaths to just sort of get away.
Speaker 2:  So it used to be very easy to fake your own death, but that was killing your
Speaker 2:  real, the identity you were born in. Right. It wasn't
Speaker 2:  constructing and then killing off a fake identity quite as much. I mean for
Speaker 2:  conmen. Yeah. But like again, it was sort of, it was solely to get
Speaker 2:  away. The attention was not really part of it because you didn't actually
Speaker 2:  want that much attention. You wanted to be able to to get away. And
Speaker 2:  so now we've reached this this era where you can create
Speaker 2:  and kill non-real people sort of easily,
Speaker 2:  but you aren't doing it to get away from your real life
Speaker 2:  obligations or from the police. Cuz that's not gonna happen. You're
Speaker 2:  really doing it just to see how people react to get attention.
Speaker 2:  It's like the, it's like a TV trope, right? Where people like
Speaker 2:  attend their own funerals to see how people feel and, and all of those things.
Speaker 2:  And like yeah, in television that's not real.
Speaker 2:  It's a, it's a rhetorical device to, to allow you to
Speaker 2:  find out how people feel about characters.
Speaker 2:  And then people are now just like, I would like to know what people would
Speaker 2:  say about me if I died so I shall
Speaker 2:  die. I'll, I'll do a quick announcement, I'll post it
Speaker 2:  on Facebook or Tumblr or Twitter or wherever and then
Speaker 2:  I'm just gonna sit back and rake in the, the true feelings
Speaker 2:  that that everybody has about me. Some personal news I
Speaker 2:  died. Right. Yeah. That's basically what it's, they're just
Speaker 2:  say okay, you know what, I'm just, I'm just looking for it. We don't know
Speaker 2:  if that was necessarily the case in this instance. We don't
Speaker 2:  know if this is the case with MEChA but revealing
Speaker 2:  it and coming back to me very much screams I would like
Speaker 2:  attention. Yeah. And very much screams too of that like of that
Speaker 2:  internet vindictiveness of like, you all drove me to this and so I'm
Speaker 2:  revealing it to you now so you'll feel extra bad. I believe her husband
Speaker 2:  is now taking the blame as being the one who told her to do it. Yeah. And
Speaker 2:  when she spoke with the New York Times, she said that things just got out
Speaker 2:  of control. Her husband insisted on faking her death on the internet
Speaker 2:  and when she started to feel better and feel like she wanted
Speaker 2:  to return to the community, she did, the community has naturally
Speaker 2:  not been really enthusiastic about her return.
Speaker 2:  They are are not excited to see her. And
Speaker 2:  it's unfortunate, it's unfortunate that she, she felt this was
Speaker 2:  her best avenue forward. It's unfortunate that
Speaker 2:  this community had to deal with a lot of trauma and grief over the last two
Speaker 2:  years and a lot of people probably felt really bad. Good
Speaker 2:  reminder, always be kind on the internet. You never know what's going on
Speaker 2:  with someone else. Just be kind. But
Speaker 2:  this one was, I just thought it was so interesting because reading it,
Speaker 2:  every single part of it I heard, I was like Oh this sounds like Miss Scribe,
Speaker 2:  this sounds like half a dozen other situations I've seen
Speaker 2:  over the years in these smaller insular communities where someone
Speaker 2:  just says F it, I wanna see what happens. And
Speaker 2:  it was just truly kinda wild to me. This person seemed a lot less
Speaker 2:  destructive about it in a, in a way because you can tell because
Speaker 2:  she underestimated the negative response to coming back. Because
Speaker 2:  in the sort of fandom examples it's either like desperation like
Speaker 2:  oh no, people are real mad about real things that I have done
Speaker 2:  to them because there are also many instances of like
Speaker 2:  fake outs to get money for, for the fake conventions and
Speaker 2:  things like I need to get away in a way that they won't, they
Speaker 2:  will feel bad asking questions about Right. Or it's f all
Speaker 2:  y'all like you are the worst people. Like you've
Speaker 2:  ruined me and I wanna make you feel as bad as I did. So
Speaker 2:  time to fake a death. And sometimes too like time to
Speaker 2:  fake a death in the like most attention
Speaker 2:  zeitgeisty way like the Beth Ann McLaughlin one to kill a
Speaker 2:  fake native person with Covid. There's just like
Speaker 2:  a lot of appropriation packed into like that
Speaker 2:  one sentence as far as we know, she's, she's white, she's not
Speaker 2:  part of the disabled community. She is not queer. Like
Speaker 2:  she was just doing a lot of appropriation and then killing that
Speaker 2:  person off just to feel happy. Yeah. Just to feel good about
Speaker 2:  herself to like hurt other people. I think the thing that
Speaker 2:  too about that one is like to look at Covid
Speaker 2:  early on too. Like early on in the pandemic when it was
Speaker 2:  so horrifying. I mean it's still b horrifying but when, when it was
Speaker 2:  both horrifying and really uncertain what was going on, to
Speaker 2:  see that as an opportunity to get rid of this thing you
Speaker 2:  built is callous in a real specific way. Super, super
Speaker 2:  callous. I think too, it speaks to like a very sort of immature
Speaker 2:  internet sense. Like people being sort of, because they
Speaker 2:  don't have to to act like an adult in a room with other adults, they sort
Speaker 2:  of regress because it is the like childish like,
Speaker 2:  oh I need to get out of a test. Grandma's been dead for
Speaker 2:  five years, she won't mind if I kill her again. Like
Speaker 2:  it, it has sort of that kind of logic to it. Yeah. The kind of
Speaker 2:  logic a child has who does not really understand the real
Speaker 2:  effects. Like you want attention but the, the difference between like I want
Speaker 2:  attention and like this causes other people real pain to
Speaker 2:  feel my pain is like a very sort of
Speaker 2:  immature child conception of how like people process
Speaker 2:  those kinds of announcements about peop about people because
Speaker 2:  like to them it's gonna make them feel bad but it's not traumatic
Speaker 2:  cuz it's not a real person that they know. Yeah. Except to those
Speaker 2:  people who have empathy and are real humans. It does.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I think it's, it's this common thing we see in communities.
Speaker 2:  It's often people who are kind of new to these communities, they, they
Speaker 2:  forget that you can forge real relationships online without seeing
Speaker 2:  people all the time. Catherine, you and I live on other sides of the country
Speaker 2:  and we talk constantly. We talk
Speaker 2:  all the time and we have a real relationship. We're friends. Yes we're gonna
Speaker 2:  go to Disney World together. And I think people forget that. Yeah you can
Speaker 2:  forge those relationships online. You can forge really impactful relationships
Speaker 2:  online. And so when they, when they kill someone off, when they
Speaker 2:  start to disrupt those for their own personal gain, there's
Speaker 2:  something really kind of egregious about it. It feels just a little feels
Speaker 2:  wild and you kind of laugh because we've seen enough of these at this point
Speaker 2:  that I almost always laugh but it still feels kind of like you've taken
Speaker 2:  advantage of people, other people's kindness and
Speaker 2:  forgotten kind of the social codes that we are all usually very cognizant
Speaker 2:  of in real life. And we oftentimes forget in a virtual
Speaker 2:  space. I think one of the reasons that you and I are so fascinated by
Speaker 2:  the fandom stuff is, this is gonna sound weird, it's
Speaker 2:  like porn. Whatever technology porn goes to
Speaker 2:  first is going to be the big technology. Similarly,
Speaker 2:  fandom finds the drama center points
Speaker 2:  years before the main street. So like when the internet
Speaker 2:  first sort of started, everyone did this drama and now
Speaker 2:  we're seeing it leak more into like other places,
Speaker 2:  right? Like the Man Tayo thing was like a major college
Speaker 2:  sports scandal, right? Which is far away from like
Speaker 2:  two Harry Potter fanfic archives having a fight. Right?
Speaker 2:  So you can, you can do that archiving like every time one of these things
Speaker 2:  happen I text like various people who are
Speaker 2:  journalists, friends of ours and I'm like, you're writing about this story.
Speaker 2:  I need you to understand how many times this has happened and how
Speaker 2:  easy it is to investigate and check and how it happens. And I think
Speaker 2:  too for the fandoms where it still happens, they tend to be young
Speaker 2:  fandoms because they tend to be younger people because they tend to have
Speaker 2:  not lived through it already. Or in the case of of this fandom, this was
Speaker 2:  a fandom where you had a lot of people who weren't
Speaker 2:  maybe as online as someone like you or I or are people generally involved
Speaker 2:  in fandom. It was right. These are people who were kind of new to using the
Speaker 2:  internet to connect this way or were because they were
Speaker 2:  self-publishing as authors were using real names or
Speaker 2:  names that had associations to them that gives them a
Speaker 2:  sense of security because it's like no one's going to do anything weird with
Speaker 2:  their own name or the name. That is what they publish under
Speaker 2:  not really realizing that that's what happens in Fanfic all the time.
Speaker 2:  I think you're right. I think this is something that we see again and again
Speaker 2:  in fandom. This is why you and I immediately both went, oh yeah, that woman
Speaker 2:  faked her own death and then came back in the romance community. That's normal.
Speaker 2:  And like we didn't even blink as other people were going, oh my god, you
Speaker 2:  and I are like seen it. She didn't start a cult so she's like, yeah
Speaker 2:  there's no snake wives, there's no cult going on. This is still
Speaker 2:  beginner fuckery and fandom. Right. But, but thank you
Speaker 2:  Katherine so much. I'm sure I'll probably, we'll probably have to bring you
Speaker 2:  back the next time somebody does something truly wild that you and I have
Speaker 2:  seen a billion times before in fandom to talk about it. It's gonna be a lot
Speaker 2:  of fun. Thanks Katherine.
Speaker 2:  We're gonna take a real quick break and when we are back we're gonna talk
Speaker 2:  about the valve steam deck and what's actually changed in the last year since
Speaker 2:  it came out.
Speaker 7:  Men's Mobile offers premium wireless for just 15 bucks a month.
Speaker 7:  That means spending a little less money on your phone bill and a little more
Speaker 7:  for online shopping probably on your phone. All plans come with
Speaker 7:  unlimited talk and text plus high-speed data. You can use your own phone
Speaker 7:  with any Mint mobile plan and switch easily in minutes with eim
Speaker 7:  To get your new wireless plan for just 15 bucks a month and get the
Speaker 7:  plan shipped to your door for free, go to mint
Speaker 7:  mobile.com/v. That's mint
Speaker 7:  mobile.com/vox.
Speaker 7:  Support for this episode comes from Brex the corporate card and
Speaker 7:  spend management software teams actually love. If you're a CFO
Speaker 7:  or finance leader today, you know we are operating in
Speaker 7:  transformational times. It can be hard getting people all in the same
Speaker 7:  place and not over another Zoom call Now more
Speaker 7:  than ever before, you need to help build a connection with not only your
Speaker 7:  team but with your clientele in real life. Thankfully
Speaker 7:  BRA can help. Brax is an integrated solution of corporate
Speaker 7:  cards and span management software that drives 100%
Speaker 7:  compliance in zero receipt chasing in over 100 countries.
Speaker 7:  Brex is easy to set up and easy to use with dedicated
Speaker 7:  implementation software, an intuitive consumer grade design
Speaker 7:  and the BR mobile app. And if you ever need support you can always
Speaker 7:  reach out by phone app or chat twenty four seven. It's that
Speaker 7:  simple. Brex makes it easy to manage every aspect of spending
Speaker 7:  from the smallest purchases to the biggest procurements. No matter
Speaker 7:  where your team works, they help empower employees to do the right thing
Speaker 7:  and spend responsibly and compliance is built in. So
Speaker 7:  with everything from restaurants to retail stores to your work platform,
Speaker 7:  all going cloud-based, isn't it time for your company to use a spend
Speaker 7:  management solution for modern times? Learn more at
Speaker 7:  brex.com/podcast.
Speaker 2:  Okay, we're back. And you know what else is back The steam deck.
Speaker 2:  You know, it honestly didn't leave, it's been over a year since the steam
Speaker 2:  deck came out and it's still going strong and there's been
Speaker 2:  over like a hundred updates on it. There's been a ton of weird
Speaker 2:  little software quirks and changes over the last year. It really, it feels
Speaker 2:  like a different device from the thing that shipped back in
Speaker 2:  February, 2022. And so that also means I gotta bring back Sean Hollister
Speaker 2:  because he has spent over 435 hours
Speaker 2:  with the steam deck. He and I are gonna talk about what's changed, what
Speaker 2:  the drawbacks are that still exist and what Sean would probably score the
Speaker 2:  thing if he had to score it right now. Hey Sean, thank you for joining me
Speaker 2:  talking about the steam deck.
Speaker 10:  Hey, it's great to be back. I love this thing.
Speaker 2:  I really, really like my steam deck and I think you were one of the few people
Speaker 2:  that likes their steam deck more than me. You loved it when it first came
Speaker 2:  out, but you also were very clear-eyed about its mini mini flaws
Speaker 2:  when it first came out. Yeah. And you've changed since then. But
Speaker 2:  kind of walk me through when it first came out, how much you were disappointed.
Speaker 10:  Yeah, let me, let me go back even a little bit further. I got to go to Val's
Speaker 10:  headquarters before the Steam deck came out months
Speaker 10:  before I got to try it. And I, I had this vision in my head
Speaker 10:  of like, this is going to be where I buy my games
Speaker 10:  now because I, I changed where I buy my PC games. I used to, I used
Speaker 10:  to buy 'em of course on a PC and then I was like, well now all these great
Speaker 10:  indie games and small games are coming out and I'm gonna play them on the
Speaker 10:  Nintendo Switch instead. This is where I'm going to buy them because this
Speaker 10:  is where I could actually play them. I can take them with me, I can play
Speaker 10:  them in the bedroom, you know, and my, when my kids are trying to sleep
Speaker 10:  and things like that, I can, I can take them on the go. I just wasn't getting
Speaker 10:  enough time with kids to play my games on my actual pc. So
Speaker 10:  I was giving Nintendo my money and I tried this steam deck. I'm like, oh
Speaker 10:  my gosh, this is going to be the Nintendo switch of
Speaker 10:  PCs not in that. It's gonna be like this thing I buy at retail that just
Speaker 10:  plays my games well, but it's going to be where I buy my games cuz
Speaker 10:  I can, I can just have the time to play them finally. And I was like, this
Speaker 10:  could be great. And then the steam deck arrived on my doorstep
Speaker 10:  in February, 2022 and the thing was
Speaker 10:  just felt so messy and broken
Speaker 10:  and buggy up, like, how the heck could you put this thing God's sail valve?
Speaker 10:  And it wasn't just that it was, it was broken. Cause I, I've, I've used
Speaker 10:  a lot of broken gadgets before. It was that valve was pulling the
Speaker 10:  rug out from under me every single day with new updates. And
Speaker 10:  some of these updates made things better and some of these updates made
Speaker 10:  things worse during the period that I was supposed to review this and
Speaker 10:  let the entire world know whether this device is any good or not.
Speaker 10:  And so I wrote this thing was a mess. I said if
Speaker 10:  Valve sold the console have been playing it best by our GameStop, people
Speaker 10:  would return it in droves. The UI was
Speaker 10:  sluggish and, and and crappy. The games, you'd launch a lot of
Speaker 10:  games and they would just not launch, they would just go to a black screen.
Speaker 10:  Some would crash in the middle, my wifi connection would
Speaker 10:  disappear. My Bluetooth headset would pair and un pair so
Speaker 10:  many issues with this thing at launch.
Speaker 2:  There was other like big stuff like wasn't there an
Speaker 2:  SD card issue where it would like just delete your games? Oh
Speaker 10:  My gosh. Okay. So SD cards are this thing I I bricked,
Speaker 10:  I i I could, you know, I bricked three SD cards,
Speaker 2:  Like just had to throw 'em
Speaker 10:  Out. Yes. Like I have one right here. I have a 256 gigabyte, very nice
Speaker 10:  sand desk, extreme 256 gigabyte card here that I
Speaker 10:  used to help review the Skydio two drone cuz you know, you need a very
Speaker 10:  fast SD card for drone footage. You're getting a hundred megabits per second
Speaker 10:  down from that, that camera. I stuck that thing in there. It it, it's a
Speaker 10:  brick now because it didn't format the card properly.
Speaker 10:  Valve had this issue where it was, it was trying to do like a
Speaker 10:  full and complete format, like overwriting
Speaker 10:  every bit on an SD card when you're doing it. And they switched to a quick
Speaker 10:  format that's better. Doesn't break SD cards as far as I'm aware. But this
Speaker 10:  thing where I, I lost three cards because of this. I plugged a,
Speaker 10:  a solid state drive into the deck's USB port and
Speaker 10:  the deck didn't know, I guess not to run
Speaker 10:  devices too fast when it doesn't prive enough power cuz you know, it's,
Speaker 10:  it's a small device with like a 48 wat hour battery. This steam deck. It
Speaker 10:  doesn't have a lot of power for its SB port. Well my s sd in my
Speaker 10:  enclosure a nice SSD I've been using for a while to transfer things between
Speaker 10:  computers. The deck decided that it was going to just blow through
Speaker 10:  that thing, download Giant game to it very quickly
Speaker 10:  without providing it enough power. And so that got brick too.
Speaker 10:  And so like this thing was a shit show at launch
Speaker 10:  and yet you could already see the potential. There was so much
Speaker 10:  potential there. They were fixing things very quickly. And so by
Speaker 10:  the end of the review period, I was like, you probably should buy this
Speaker 10:  thing today. It's not ready. But wow,
Speaker 10:  you can play all of these old PC games and all these new PC
Speaker 10:  games with all these horsepower, these amazing controls you can customize
Speaker 10:  to do any kind of game. Phenomenal. And so I was like, okay,
Speaker 10:  maybe this thing will be great.
Speaker 2:  So was it like the flexibility of the
Speaker 2:  device was so good that you could overlook the fact
Speaker 2:  that you had now spent hundreds of dollars of your own
Speaker 2:  money in the process of reviewing it just washed that money down
Speaker 2:  the drain?
Speaker 10:  There were, yes. Yes. I I I
Speaker 10:  wanna throw some caveats in there. First off, we gave this thing a score
Speaker 10:  that today would've probably fleshed would probably be at like a
Speaker 10:  4.5 at the time we give it a 6.5. But like if you read
Speaker 10:  our descriptions of how we review devices today, we
Speaker 10:  would've have, we would have to give it like less than a 5.0 back then because
Speaker 10:  Right. We do not like telling people to bike gadgets
Speaker 10:  that are not ready, that have a lot of issues with them that may not pan
Speaker 10:  out. Yeah. At the time though, yes, I, I could see that
Speaker 10:  this thing was already fun to use
Speaker 10:  and that's super important. Like, people wanna buy things that are fun.
Speaker 10:  Right. Even if, yeah, even if part of the fun is like figuring out how to
Speaker 10:  make games run on a console. I I I've read so many, I don't, I
Speaker 10:  I think you're also in the steam deck subreddit. Yes. And there are so many
Speaker 10:  people in there who post how much fun they're having, just figuring out
Speaker 10:  how to make various games work, figuring out all kinds of
Speaker 10:  cool things to do with it as a full Linux pc. A lot of people say
Speaker 10:  they're doing more of that than they are actually playing games, which is,
Speaker 10:  yeah.
Speaker 2:  Funny to me there's guys who are saying, oh, I, I plug it
Speaker 2:  into my TV and I use like a PS4 controller and I
Speaker 2:  just use it as like a console, like a traditional console now. And, and there's
Speaker 2:  people who are like, oh yeah, I use it as my primary computer.
Speaker 2:  It just seems like this great, it's, it's for the tinkerers, it's for all
Speaker 2:  the people who just like to, to mess with
Speaker 10:  Stuff. I've seen people do video editing on this,
Speaker 10:  on this computer. Oh, I, I've seen people like piece together, you know,
Speaker 10:  stuff for their work. I saw there's a, one of the developers of
Speaker 10:  vlc, the amazing open source video player
Speaker 10:  that, you know, just, you can play it plays anything you throw at it is
Speaker 10:  working on a way to turn the deck into like a miniature tv, internet
Speaker 10:  streaming tv. So it'll, it'll just stream down like channels over the web
Speaker 10:  or something. I don't know. Yeah. I want a portable tv, I want a
Speaker 10:  handheld device that can double as my work PC and a pinch. I
Speaker 10:  want a, a game system that flawlessly runs all my
Speaker 10:  Game Cube and we games because there's an emulator that somebody put
Speaker 10:  on Linux like
Speaker 2:  Just flawlessly.
Speaker 10:  Yes. It does all these things and the controls,
Speaker 10:  which are many of them carryovers from the, the, the cult classic steam
Speaker 10:  controller that valve released a number of years ago and then had to put
Speaker 10:  on a $5 fire sale. Anyhow, if you missed out on the steam controller,
Speaker 10:  the controls in here just let you do
Speaker 10:  so much. I have, I'm, I'm playing through trails in the sky
Speaker 10:  now. It's a, it's an RPG game with a lot of dialogue. I have
Speaker 10:  three of the buttons on my steam deck set to be turbo buttons
Speaker 10:  so that I can speed through the dialogue and you know, the sword swinging
Speaker 10:  when, when I'm, you know, trying to build up my CP to do the big flashy
Speaker 10:  magic and special attacks. Yeah. When I am playing
Speaker 10:  Genson impact, which you're not really supposed to be able to play on the
Speaker 10:  steam deck but you can because somebody built a client
Speaker 10:  for it in Lennox and also because I can stream
Speaker 10:  Genson impact for my PlayStation five cuz there's a PlayStation five streaming
Speaker 10:  client on the deck, which is amazing and
Speaker 2:  It works really well.
Speaker 10:  It works really well when I'm playing that game on a PS five by itself or,
Speaker 10:  or or you know, any of the other consoles. It's really difficult to aim
Speaker 10:  a bow with like some of the bow characters in that game. Which is
Speaker 10:  annoying because the game roars you for you know, pitting enemy creatures
Speaker 10:  in the head with a bow for some reason. I don't know why. Anyhow, the deck
Speaker 10:  has gyroscopic aiming that you can add to
Speaker 10:  literally anything you play on it. Including
Speaker 10:  streaming a game from my PlayStation five to the
Speaker 10:  handheld. So my deck is transmitting its
Speaker 10:  gyroscopic motions over my home wifi to my PlayStation
Speaker 10:  five to tell my PlayStation five how far to move virtual analog
Speaker 10:  stick so that the bow of my anime character can line up with
Speaker 10:  the head of some legendary monster in this game. And
Speaker 10:  it feels like it's running locally because,
Speaker 2:  And that's just
Speaker 10:  Cool. There's just so much cool shit you can do with the deck. But that's
Speaker 10:  not what the focus of my recent piece was.
Speaker 10:  Like. The main thing I want to tell you today, the main thing I wrote in
Speaker 10:  my like long-term review is that yes there's, there's
Speaker 10:  this whole ecosystem of cool things but also you can
Speaker 10:  just use the steam deck now as a game system and it works
Speaker 10:  and it did not at launch. That was not the case. Yeah. Nearly a year ago
Speaker 10:  when it launched.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And it works with like a wide variety of
Speaker 2:  games. I know we've seen some complaints on the, the the
Speaker 2:  subreddits cuz somebody goes and they played like this really
Speaker 2:  nobody's ever heard of it game from 20 years ago and they're like, oh the
Speaker 2:  steam deck doesn't work out of the box with it. But most modern games, most
Speaker 2:  new games, it works pretty, pretty well out of the box. I played
Speaker 2:  like just three days of vampire survivors. My sister was like, don't you
Speaker 2:  wanna say hi to me? I haven't seen you in a year. I'm here for Christmas.
Speaker 2:  And I was like, I I sure. But after I get through this
Speaker 2:  level Yeah like just totally glued to it cuz it
Speaker 2:  played so, so well. It works so well. And also I could like
Speaker 2:  huff the, the fumes off of the fan on the steam deck.
Speaker 10:  This is, this is a beautiful in joke also from the steam deck subreddit
Speaker 10:  and discords everybody, ed sa how, how good it
Speaker 10:  smells the the chipped fumes that are coming out through the fan. I don't
Speaker 10:  know what that is. I'm guessing it's just warm air.
Speaker 2:  Probably the should not be huffing it probably, this is a
Speaker 2:  disclaimer. Do not huff those smells. We
Speaker 2:  cannot be held liable for it. Please don't do it. We don't know what's
Speaker 2:  in it but man it smells great.
Speaker 10:  It does, it does. At the risk of reduction, there are three
Speaker 10:  reasons why games might not work on the steam deck.
Speaker 10:  Okay. One is they are big modern games
Speaker 10:  but they use anti cheat software. That's the biggest one. Some of the
Speaker 10:  biggest games in the world will not work on the steam
Speaker 10:  deck. Like PUBG Lost Ark, college Duty,
Speaker 10:  war Zone, rust, destiny two, a lot of of
Speaker 10:  these games don't work Bec not because the Steam deck doesn't support anti
Speaker 10:  Sheet. In fact, valve went out of their way to go ahead and say
Speaker 10:  Hey big providers of anti sheet, easy anti sheet and
Speaker 10:  battle I we're gonna make you work. Hey developers, all you have to do is
Speaker 10:  enable them. That's not the reason they don't work. They don't work because
Speaker 10:  the developers, the publishers decided they weren't willing to take
Speaker 10:  the risk of enabling these. And then maybe
Speaker 10:  somebody on Linux figures out some kind of cool hack
Speaker 10:  because these anti cheat software can't necessarily run
Speaker 10:  as effectively in the kernel level manner that it wants to
Speaker 10:  because there is no way for them to control what happens on
Speaker 10:  Lennox the way they can on Windows. Now somebody's gonna listen to
Speaker 10:  the podcast, they're gonna be like, oh it's totally possible. You could
Speaker 10:  totally build a system where this works. What Tim Sweeney
Speaker 10:  at Epic Games who says Fortnite will not come to this.
Speaker 10:  What, what Tim Sweeney will tell you is that they don't
Speaker 10:  want to spend the money to build such a system. They don't think it's worthwhile
Speaker 10:  for the amount of players they'll get in return. Right. So I I mean he didn't
Speaker 10:  say that explicitly but reading between the lines of what he told us, that's,
Speaker 10:  that's what he's saying.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. It it's an investment to to build support for
Speaker 2:  the Steam deck. And one of the reasons I think it's so popular thus far is
Speaker 2:  that the investment for most game developers is fairly
Speaker 2:  minimal. Right. When they don't have the anti cheat
Speaker 10:  Software. Yeah I would say even if they do have the anti cheat software,
Speaker 10:  it's minimal to enable it to work but
Speaker 10:  it's not necessarily minimal to satisfy your
Speaker 10:  company and your shareholders that you will have not
Speaker 10:  inadvertently created some kind of loophole that will come to bite you in
Speaker 10:  the ass down the road. Yeah. That might be the expensive part. Yeah. Most
Speaker 10:  games just work Anti cheat is one reason they don't work.
Speaker 10:  Another reason why they don't work is because they are old
Speaker 10:  enough that whatever game company built it
Speaker 10:  had to do something very customer proprietary with
Speaker 10:  the software that they used to run, say the video cut scenes at
Speaker 10:  the beginning of the game, some games will not launch
Speaker 10:  simply because they cannot launch the video that plays
Speaker 10:  at the very beginning of the game and the rest of the game would run.
Speaker 10:  And the reason we know this is because most of the games on the steam deck
Speaker 10:  that are designed for Windows run on a compatibility layer called Proton
Speaker 10:  that is developed primarily by valve open source developers that
Speaker 10:  Valve is paying to improve proton's compatibility but there is
Speaker 10:  also a fork of proton called Proton ge which stands for
Speaker 10:  glorious egg roll.
Speaker 2:  Oh
Speaker 10:  Wow. Which I love. Which is maintained by people who do not care so much
Speaker 10:  about proprietary things that they may not have the legal rights to use
Speaker 10:  and they're some games that will just run because they said they built in
Speaker 10:  whatever the proprietary video Kodak was and so you can see a game that
Speaker 10:  wouldn't work on the main fork of Proton just does on the
Speaker 10:  glorious egg roll version.
Speaker 2:  Are there examples of games off the top of your head that that don't work?
Speaker 2:  Because I definitely have, I think I've run into this situation and I'm just
Speaker 2:  completely blanking on any games
Speaker 10:  A persona for Golden was not working on the steam deck
Speaker 10:  at launch. It had issues with I think with cut scenes and also with audio
Speaker 10:  there was some kind of audio glitch as well in glorious egg roll. It worked
Speaker 10:  perfectly and then Valve went back and worked with
Speaker 10:  Proton two I think get around some of those issues. I don't know if it uses
Speaker 10:  some kind of compatibility layer for the for the Codex now or what, but
Speaker 10:  they did make it work and they made it a full deck verified game.
Speaker 10:  I know that currently the longest journey the last time I tried to play
Speaker 10:  the Longest Journey, which is a, a famous point and click adventure
Speaker 10:  that does not run on Steam deck. I can't remember if it works in glorious
Speaker 10:  egg roll or not but I would, I would bet you 10 bucks that is one of those
Speaker 10:  issues where it's just some Kodak or some thing
Speaker 10:  that they try to launch at the beginning of the game doesn't work properly
Speaker 10:  and that's the reason it doesn't play cuz there's no reason why the deck
Speaker 10:  shouldn't be able to play that
Speaker 2:  Game. Yeah, I think one of the ones I run into is Crusader King's three.
Speaker 2:  Ah, it's got some like weird popups at the beginning of the game and sometimes
Speaker 2:  I can get right through 'em and get to play and sometimes
Speaker 2:  I wanna fling my beloved steep deck across the room.
Speaker 10:  Yeah. So it's so it's anti cheat. One reason video codex or
Speaker 10:  or other proprietary techniques that they use that you
Speaker 10:  know, the Steam deck doesn't know how to interpret yet or and this is also
Speaker 10:  a a relatively large category at this point. It actually does work
Speaker 10:  and and Valve just is marking it as unsupported because they haven't
Speaker 10:  fully tested it yet. Which is wild. It is wild to me. Not that they haven't
Speaker 10:  tested the whole library, but it's wild to me how many games valves says
Speaker 10:  hey this doesn't work. But they haven't gone back to
Speaker 10:  retest and it actually does.
Speaker 2:  Mass Effect is a good example of that. The the legendary edition, the majority
Speaker 2:  of people who play it have no issues with it but it continues to say
Speaker 2:  does not work, don't try it.
Speaker 10:  Mass effect is the one where there was a period of time where it wouldn't
Speaker 10:  launch unless you like jumped through some hoops because
Speaker 10:  EA broke that and it broke a lot of other EA games
Speaker 10:  by introducing a new version of their EA launcher, which used to be called
Speaker 10:  Origin. That's a whole long story. They introduced a new version of the
Speaker 10:  EA app and it just, they never tested it on the deck and it didn't work
Speaker 10:  and it broke everything and you couldn't see the prompts that you
Speaker 10:  needed to click through in order to get into your game. It would ask you
Speaker 10:  like several things and those things wouldn't graphically show up on the
Speaker 10:  deck they do now, particularly if you enable proton experimental.
Speaker 10:  But those are still all marked unsupported because EA hasn't quite
Speaker 10:  finished it yet. So they run properly like EA keeps breaking
Speaker 10:  it with new versions and so Valve, I think Valve is waiting until that all
Speaker 10:  settles down. But like the Witcher two stalker
Speaker 10:  shadow of Chernobyl excom enemy within the original
Speaker 10:  Halflife, those games are all marked as unsupported and they all just
Speaker 10:  run
Speaker 2:  And now everything seems to be ready. Well not everything but
Speaker 2:  a lot of it like it seems like something where I could
Speaker 2:  recommend it to a family member and not have to worry about
Speaker 2:  doing tech support all the time.
Speaker 10:  Yeah, I largely agree with you. Like I recommend this now to people
Speaker 10:  who want a PC gaming system that they
Speaker 10:  could take with you. I wouldn't necessarily recommend it to people who do
Speaker 10:  not like the PC of experience of like tweaking
Speaker 10:  settings because you can still absolutely play a game on Steam Deck and
Speaker 10:  be like, this runs, but it doesn't run very well. And
Speaker 10:  if you come from the PC background where you're like, okay, I will turn
Speaker 10:  down the shadows and you know, and set the game spec to low,
Speaker 10:  but then I will increase the anti aliasing because this is a
Speaker 10:  seven 20 p, you know, 800 piece screen where you really need anti
Speaker 10:  aliasing or else games look Pixely if I'm coming from that background or
Speaker 10:  if I know the person I'm recommending it comes from that background. Absolutely
Speaker 10:  no question. If you have $400 to spend, you want this portable gaming pc
Speaker 10:  do it. If you're the kind of person who, like you want everything to
Speaker 10:  just work like sticking a cartridge into a Nintendo Switch
Speaker 10:  works and you don't want to think about settings ever,
Speaker 10:  it's not there yet. It could be there someday,
Speaker 10:  but if you're that kind of person, I would wait until Future
Speaker 10:  handhelds.
Speaker 2:  That's fair. I think that's, well they can go just get a switch and tell
Speaker 2:  then it plays a lot of these games.
Speaker 10:  But you probably shouldn't because there'd probably be a Switch Pro next
Speaker 10:  year. But anyhow, moving on. Or this year it's 2023. I expect
Speaker 10:  this holiday. Well may maybe we'll have something. I don't know.
Speaker 2:  Well thank you Sean for coming on and, and talking about the seam deck.
Speaker 2:  We're, we're gonna let you go cuz we'll have to bring you back again to talk
Speaker 2:  about the seam deck and we wanna do it over lots of different episodes. Appreciate
Speaker 2:  you taking the time.
Speaker 10:  I'm so happy. I will come back to tell you about the latest hack later
Speaker 2:  On. Awesome. Okay, that's it for the Vergecast today. Thank you
Speaker 2:  for listening as always. There's a ton more coverage on the site and
Speaker 2:  you can see all the stories that we've talked about this week on the
Speaker 2:  verge.com. If you have thoughts, feedbacks
Speaker 2:  feelings, steam deck game recommendations, you can always
Speaker 2:  email the vergecast vergecast the verge.com
Speaker 2:  and if you have questions, call the hotline. It's eight six six
Speaker 2:  Verge 11, that's 8 66 Verge 11. This show
Speaker 2:  is produced by Andrew Marino and Liam James Nori Donovan is our executive
Speaker 2:  producer and Brook Mentors is our editorial director of audio. The
Speaker 2:  Vergecast is a Verge production and part of the Vox Media podcast network.
Speaker 2:  I will not be here on Friday, I'm gonna be in Disney World, but NEI will
Speaker 2:  be back this Friday with a whole bunch of the Verge crew and they're gonna
Speaker 2:  be talking about the Samsung Galaxy Unpacked event and all the other news
Speaker 2:  that popped up this week. So stay tuned till then. Rock on.