# Transcript
ID: 0318b3c4-54dd-4a14-b90b-3169100539d4
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: The TV of the future costs zero dollars
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-8247414665043084774/3902556736958776219/s93290-US-3682s-1696843252.mp3
Description: In episode one of our miniseries all about connectivity, The Verge’s David Pierce talks with Ilya Pozin, founder and CEO of Telly, a new startup promising to give you a free 55-inch TV with an additional second screen for ads and apps.
Before founding Telly, Ilya Pozin also founded PlutoTV, one of the first and most successful ad-based streaming services. There are many similarities between these two companies, and Ilya has a grander vision for how he sees the world and how he thinks he can revolutionize the TV hardware and TV show business.
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we love hearing from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (4 ads detected)
Speaker 3:  Welcome. To. The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of the second screen
Speaker 3:  experience. I'm your friend David Pierce, and this is the first episode
Speaker 3:  in a new miniseries we're doing about connectivity. But I don't mean
Speaker 3:  connectivity in the like five g change everything
Speaker 3:  sense or the let's test some wifi speeds sense,
Speaker 3:  either. Those are fine, but that's not what we're talking about. For the
Speaker 3:  next four Mondays, we're gonna talk about how we connect online,
Speaker 3:  how we connect to each other, how we connect to the stuff that we care about,
Speaker 3:  how we make connections that are private and personal and safe
Speaker 3:  and make sense. It's a big digital universe out there
Speaker 3:  and connecting all of it and us is hard, but important
Speaker 3:  work. For our first episode, we're gonna talk about content. Obviously the
Speaker 3:  internet completely changed the way that we watch, listen, read
Speaker 3:  and everything else. I mean, really, it wasn't that long ago
Speaker 3:  that the only way to access something was to get in your car and go to a
Speaker 3:  store and buy it. Now the whole universe of content is available, like
Speaker 3:  from your phone. You don't even have to get up off the couch. But that has
Speaker 3:  its own set of challenges. We're all signed up for a million increasingly
Speaker 3:  expensive subscriptions. We spend way too much time scrolling
Speaker 3:  through streaming services instead of actually watching the content on them.
Speaker 3:  You're stuck upgrading your tv, your phone, your everything, every couple
Speaker 3:  of years just to keep up with it all. I'm pretty sure making you go to Blockbuster
Speaker 3:  and Sam Goody back in the day was not the perfect solution, but I'm not sure
Speaker 3:  this is either. Over the last few years I've
Speaker 3:  talked to a lot of people with ideas about how the content ecosystem
Speaker 3:  might change, but I don't think I've met anyone with ideas quite
Speaker 3:  as big and quite as wacky as this guy.
Speaker 4:  Hey, I'm Billy Pose and I'm the founder and c e o of Telly.
Speaker 3:  Telly is a new startup, like it hasn't officially launched any of its
Speaker 3:  products yet, but I think you might have heard of it. It's the one promising
Speaker 3:  to give you a free 55 inch four K TV with a
Speaker 3:  second screen below it that Telly thinks it can sell ads and apps on to
Speaker 3:  make up for the money it loses by giving you a tv. Telly is either
Speaker 3:  the best or the worst idea I've heard in a really long time,
Speaker 3:  and I sincerely don't know which one, it's before he founded
Speaker 3:  Telly. Ilya also founded PlutoTV, which was one of the first and is still
Speaker 3:  one of the most successful ad based streaming services. His big
Speaker 3:  idea was people don't have infinite money to pay for streaming,
Speaker 3:  let's make one for free. And it worked. There's a lot of similarities
Speaker 3:  between those two companies and those two ideas. And there's a bigger vision
Speaker 3:  in there for how Ilya sees the world and how he thinks he can
Speaker 3:  change both the TV hardware and the TV show business.
Speaker 3:  That is what we're gonna talk about today, the future of the biggest screen
Speaker 3:  in your house and the way that we find and connect with the content we care
Speaker 3:  about.
Speaker 3:  But before we got into that, I wanted to start the conversation with Ilya
Speaker 3:  by going all the way back to the PlutoTV days.
Speaker 4:  So back in 2013 when we saw the entire
Speaker 4:  kind of streaming ecosystem change, right? Everyone started going on
Speaker 4:  televisions to open up their apps, right? You had publishers like Netflix
Speaker 4:  that went from mobile and desktop environments to the,
Speaker 4:  to the tv, right? And yeah, the idea that everyone was launching subscription
Speaker 4:  services was great, but there was an opportunity, I believe, to,
Speaker 4:  to have a free television experience. Like when you went on YouTube,
Speaker 4:  that was free, right? You're, you're able to browse You know various videos,
Speaker 4:  but there was nothing, no curated experience, nothing that felt
Speaker 4:  like tv, nothing that served you up content when you didn't actually want
Speaker 4:  to think, right? And, and we always had this theory at PlutoTV where from
Speaker 4:  an on-demand perspective, on demand is really, really good if You know what
Speaker 4:  you're looking for. But if you don't know what you're looking for, it's a
Speaker 4:  horrible experience, right? Because how, how do you search for something
Speaker 4:  where you don't know what to search for? So that was the theory behind PlutoTV,
Speaker 4:  is can we create a linear television experience and deliver it
Speaker 4:  completely free, right? Can we go out there and find content that
Speaker 4:  maybe isn't on, maybe it's third window, fourth window, right? Isn't on television
Speaker 4:  anymore and isn't being monetized anymore, but it's still valuable and people
Speaker 4:  still wanna see it. And, and can we, can we create a revenue model where
Speaker 4:  maybe it's a rev share type deal, similar to a YouTube play with short form
Speaker 4:  videos, but we did that with a long form content and, and, and recreate this
Speaker 4:  kind of TV experience. And we did just that, right? Initially we launched
Speaker 4:  on web mobile, but very quickly we built an experience that
Speaker 4:  You know on television, we, we quickly became the number one free app on
Speaker 4:  platforms like Roku and Amazon Fire TV and so forth.
Speaker 3:  So is that two separate insights, the idea that there is a
Speaker 3:  way to do this without charging a subscription fee and
Speaker 3:  people need something that isn't quite linear tv, but also isn't quite
Speaker 3:  on demand? Like is that two separate things that you built the company on,
Speaker 3:  or is there an overlap of that Venn diagram?
Speaker 4:  It was two separate things, but they kind of converged, right? So the idea
Speaker 4:  that cable companies were double dipping where you were paying for a cable
Speaker 4:  subscription fee and then you were watching content with advertising. I mean,
Speaker 4:  that to me was, was always one of those kind of mind boggling instances that
Speaker 4:  that was right for disruption. We proved that at PlutoTV, right? Where
Speaker 4:  we said, you can run a very sustainable business on just one one of
Speaker 4:  those monetization streams alone, right on just advertising. And if you look
Speaker 4:  at PlutoTV today, You know, fast forward You know 10 years, it's done over
Speaker 4:  a billion dollars in ad revenue alone with You know 80 million plus consumers,
Speaker 4:  right? Yeah. So, and then the other was the curated
Speaker 4:  linear TV experience where You know my original idea with
Speaker 4:  PlutoTV was actually with my daughter sitting on my lap, and I was working
Speaker 4:  on one monitor and I was on YouTube picking out You know kids' videos on
Speaker 4:  the other monitor. She was two years old at that time, and I just learned
Speaker 4:  how to change diapers and I didn't know anything about kids' content. I didn't
Speaker 4:  know what to search for. So I was like, All, right? Let me, let me try to
Speaker 4:  find this kind of linear TV experience with internet content and it didn't
Speaker 4:  exist, right? That was the original hypothesis. So I, so I built a prototype,
Speaker 4:  I put it out there, and we then drove some users to it, and right away
Speaker 4:  we saw like 36 or 40 minute session durations. And at that
Speaker 4:  point, YouTube was getting three and a half minute sessions, right? So we
Speaker 4:  knew that this curated experience worked. And I said, okay, well we were
Speaker 4:  living in this era of cord cutting. Everyone's cutting the cord, the writings
Speaker 4:  on the wall, right? Because consumers didn't want to pay twice,
Speaker 4:  right? So can we create an experience where it's actually monetized on a
Speaker 4:  single revenue stream, right?
Speaker 3:  Yeah. And I think one of the things that's been very funny since then is
Speaker 3:  the world has kind of come around to that way of thinking, right? Everybody
Speaker 3:  now has an ad supported thing, as is an ad supported tier of
Speaker 3:  their subscription. They still wanna also charge you money for it and also
Speaker 3:  show you ads, which is very funny. Like we're still in the old cable world,
Speaker 3:  but also now we're in this place where this idea that it's hard to find
Speaker 3:  stuff to watch. And actually maybe we should just curate it for you so that
Speaker 3:  you can turn it on. And like, one of the good things about cable was channel
Speaker 3:  surfing. Like we got away from channel surfing for a long time and everybody's
Speaker 3:  kind of coming back to it. But 10 years ago, I kind of feel
Speaker 3:  like the industry thought you were just wrong. That like, this was not the
Speaker 3:  future. You can't make money in avod, you can't make money from curation
Speaker 3:  on demand. Is the future like not a chance? Am I overstating
Speaker 3:  kind of the forces against you?
Speaker 4:  No, it was, it was spot on. I I, I've, for a long time I didn't think PlutoTV
Speaker 4:  was gonna happen. Yeah. I've never felt so rejected in my life on all
Speaker 4:  sides, right? From we, we went out to capital to get capital from investors.
Speaker 4:  I think we had 93 noss before we had a yes. Wow. Right? We,
Speaker 4:  'cause look, we're we're entering the market that seemed like it was going
Speaker 4:  subscription on demand. And we said, no, we're going linear and ad
Speaker 4:  supported, and everyone thought we're completely crazy. And also a lot of
Speaker 4:  the, a lot of the people that are writing checks from an investment perspective,
Speaker 4:  You know they have the means of the capital to go out there and pay for service
Speaker 4:  and re remove ads, and they're like, ads are bad, right? So, so naturally
Speaker 4:  we just didn't, didn't fit within that mold. And then on the other end, from,
Speaker 4:  from the content perspective, right? As you mentioned, all the content owners,
Speaker 4:  now, all the media companies have ad supported tiers, but back
Speaker 4:  then we went to, we went to them to get content and they also laughed us
Speaker 4:  out of the room like, no, we're going, we're licensing our content. There's
Speaker 4:  no way we're giving to you on a rev share basis and ad support and forget
Speaker 4:  it. We're we're going subscription. So they thought we were crazy too.
Speaker 3:  What was the point it started to turn? Like do you remember like a thing
Speaker 3:  happening where you were like, okay, we were not wrong about this?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I, I mean, so the data was there from the, from the get go, right?
Speaker 4:  Where consumers showed us that they actually love this
Speaker 4:  curated linear experience. And we were doing this with like two, three minute
Speaker 4:  videos from YouTube at that point, right? Sure. We're just short form content,
Speaker 4:  but when we stitched it together until long form experience, it worked.
Speaker 4:  And people loved the whole channel surfing idea. They loved the curation,
Speaker 4:  they loved not thinking, and we even went like out of our way to
Speaker 4:  remove the ability to like restart a show. If you, if you came in at
Speaker 4:  8:08 PM to PlutoTV, you watched the same thing at the same time as everyone
Speaker 4:  else, even if it was like four minutes into an existing clip, right? And,
Speaker 4:  and we brought that kind of nostalgic thing back and it worked from a consumer
Speaker 4:  side, but then I remember, I think it was Lionsgate that gave us
Speaker 4:  a chance, right? And said, All, right? Look, let's give you some older content.
Speaker 4:  We're not monetizing it currently. Let's put it up there. We will do a rev
Speaker 4:  shared deal and, and let's see what happens, right? And we started
Speaker 4:  writing a bigger check, and then the, the bigger check we wrote, right?
Speaker 4:  The better the content they gave us, the better the content they gave us,
Speaker 4:  the more people watched. And we started getting into this, into this flywheel,
Speaker 4:  right? Right. And then You know th and then the industry kind of started
Speaker 4:  to, to hear that, hey, like this is actually happening. Consumers are growing,
Speaker 4:  revenues growing, this is becoming a sizable opportunity. And
Speaker 4:  others started giving us a chance, right? And once again, it started with
Speaker 4:  older, older content. And then as the content got better and newer,
Speaker 4:  everything kind of started going up and the flywheel started turning in a
Speaker 4:  faster way.
Speaker 3:  Got it. Okay. So draw the line from that to
Speaker 3:  tele for me, because I feel like there's a bunch of, like the market condition
Speaker 3:  stuff you described in the like TV content industry
Speaker 3:  that is also true of the TV set industry. You're also making a
Speaker 3:  similar bet on ads versus You know money. But like how
Speaker 3:  do you get from from PlutoTV to Telly?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, yeah. No, great question. So at PlutoTV, we partnered with
Speaker 4:  every TV manufacturer out there, right? Because, and, and then we saw the
Speaker 4:  writing on the wall. They, they came to us and, and we quickly realized
Speaker 4:  they don't make any money selling TVs, right? Right. There's like TVs have
Speaker 4:  hit this commodity state where there's no margin to hardware,
Speaker 4:  it's a race to the bottom on price. And when you don't have any margin in
Speaker 4:  the hardware, you also have no innovation, right? So right now, when you're
Speaker 4:  looking at a TV in your home, I'm sure you have one on your wall and everyone
Speaker 4:  else does, but you don't really know, is it three months old? Is it three
Speaker 4:  years old? Has it been there for 10 years? It looks exactly the same, right?
Speaker 4:  And that's when, when kind of the light bulb hit, if you will, right? Where
Speaker 4:  if, if everyone's coming to us to get a piece of our ad revenue because
Speaker 4:  they don't make any money selling hardware, right? And you can't, if you
Speaker 4:  can't make any hard money selling hardware, why fight for that tiny margin
Speaker 4:  anyway? Right? Why not build a product in a way that you can give away and
Speaker 4:  quickly take the market like we did with PlutoTV?
Speaker 3:  So wait, so just hang on, explain that part out really fast, because if,
Speaker 3:  if I'm understanding you correctly, basically, when you're at PlutoTV, you're
Speaker 3:  You know building an app for all these TV operating systems and such,
Speaker 3:  but part of the appeal of working with PlutoTV is that the TV
Speaker 3:  manufacturers can figure out how to get a cut of your rev
Speaker 3:  share. And that's the only way they're making any money. And I actually feel
Speaker 3:  like, like I pause on this because I think this is a part of the TV business,
Speaker 3:  people don't understand that. Like, there's money in outrageously
Speaker 3:  expensive, like a hundred inch Samsung televisions a little,
Speaker 3:  but this like T C L behind me, like TCL l's not making any money that's
Speaker 3:  interesting to anybody on here. They're all making money on like the
Speaker 3:  weird spyware stuff that they put on, and they're all making money on
Speaker 3:  the ads that they show you, right? Like, that is what the business has become,
Speaker 3:  even for the people who make the hardware
Speaker 4:  Completely. And it's no different than the double dipping I mentioned on
Speaker 4:  the cable side, right? Where they're right now, TV makers are selling you
Speaker 4:  a tv, they're monetizing your data, they're selling advertising, they're
Speaker 4:  getting a cut of advertising from streaming services like PlutoTV, and, and
Speaker 4:  they're selling, they have their own programming now they're selling their
Speaker 4:  own ads, so they're double dipping, right? So, so once again, if you're in
Speaker 4:  a business where you're not making money on the hardware, similar to PlutoTV,
Speaker 4:  we felt like if you could take away one of the revenue streams, you can quickly
Speaker 4:  take that market. But you're, you're absolutely right. As part of the deals
Speaker 4:  with PlutoTV, every TV maker, You know, got a cut of of that revenue.
Speaker 3:  Okay? So then I can imagine the leap from there to, well,
Speaker 3:  if this is the business already, why don't we just make this the
Speaker 3:  business? That's
Speaker 4:  Right. That's right. Okay. And You know, the way to the way we also looked
Speaker 4:  at it is it was very difficult to build PlutoTV for every TV
Speaker 4:  manufacturer. And and that's because they're all trying to optimize the tiny
Speaker 4:  amount of margin they had. So the, the processors, the memory,
Speaker 4:  the stuff that goes inside the TV that's on your wall now is very
Speaker 4:  weak. Yeah. And, and You know the way we looked at, it's, it's 2023
Speaker 4:  TVs are the biggest screen in your home, but they're the dumbest, right?
Speaker 4:  They're, they're drastically underpowered, right? There's very little that
Speaker 4:  they can do to go beyond streaming, right? Like you've, you even saw like
Speaker 4:  Netflix and others try to get into, into gaming, and it's so hard to do
Speaker 4:  gaming when, when your processor is like as weak as an a t m machine, right?
Speaker 4:  Right. So, so when, when we looked at, at building tele, like,
Speaker 4:  don't let the price point fool you of free, right? This is not a
Speaker 4:  budget tv. We said, let's build actually the smartest
Speaker 4:  TV on the market, right? So let's disrupt it from a TV perspective. What
Speaker 4:  would, if we were to build a TV right now in 2023, what would it do?
Speaker 4:  And if you look at the market, look, look what happened, because TVs haven't
Speaker 4:  innovated, right? There's no margin to innovate. So there's been no innovation
Speaker 4:  whatsoever. So what happened, we had speakers pop out, we had
Speaker 4:  assistance, we had You know mirror come out with a fitness
Speaker 4:  device for $800, which is literally a screen and a camera. All of these
Speaker 4:  different devices popped out into the market. And frankly,
Speaker 4:  I, we believe that a TV should have been doing that all along, right? And
Speaker 4:  if there was any room for innovation, and if TV companies were actually figuring
Speaker 4:  out how to drive an actual improvement of their product, rather than just
Speaker 4:  making the screen thinner or making it four K to eight k, I think they just
Speaker 4:  missed a mark of what consumers actually want, right? Yeah. And if you
Speaker 4:  recall, when the iPhone came out, it killed a bunch of other devices very
Speaker 4:  quickly. There used to be cameras at Best Buy, those went away,
Speaker 4:  used to buy like a Tom Tom or a Garmin g p s that went away, right?
Speaker 4:  So like music players portal music. So the iPhone killed a bunch of devices.
Speaker 4:  We expect the same thing to happen here, right? So Telly is the
Speaker 4:  smartest TV on the market, right? It's got great speakers, right? You've
Speaker 4:  got a, a camera that lets you do Zoom, calling fitness mo, You know
Speaker 4:  gaming, motion tracking gaming. It's got a full assistant built
Speaker 4:  in. So you can say, Hey, Telly, put on Spotify or whatever you want. You're
Speaker 4:  playing music through it. It's got all your extra widgets from
Speaker 4:  like sports scores and news and whatever. And, and it's, it's so much more
Speaker 4:  than a tv, right? Imagine like somebody rings your Ring doorbell and their
Speaker 4:  video appears in the bottom, or you do a Zoom call with your friends or family
Speaker 4:  across town, then their videos are on that bottom screen and you're watching
Speaker 4:  the same, let's say, football game on the top screen, and now you're watching
Speaker 4:  together, right? And there's some really other interesting things that like
Speaker 4:  we're building and innovating that goes well, well beyond, beyond tv,
Speaker 3:  Right? Yeah. And I, I, I wanna get to that in just a second, but I think
Speaker 3:  the, the last version of the, like, why on earth are you building a TV
Speaker 3:  question I have is basically like the iPhone example is really interesting,
Speaker 3:  right? And I think where we are in the TV market is essentially
Speaker 3:  like deciding to build a camcorder 20 years
Speaker 3:  after the iPhone comes out. Like, this market is dead. Everybody agrees there's
Speaker 3:  no money in it. Everybody is like desperately trying to find something else
Speaker 3:  to do. Like I've been a proponent the last several years of like, bring back
Speaker 3:  dumb TVs, right? Like, I think there is a, a compelling case to make that
Speaker 3:  all of the interesting stuff should happen in set top boxes. It should happen
Speaker 3:  in Soundbars whatever, because you can buy a big display that is
Speaker 3:  gonna keep being good for a very long time, put all the smart stuff somewhere
Speaker 3:  else, and then upgrade the parts that you need while this still
Speaker 3:  very good four K display gets to sit on my wall for a decade, even though
Speaker 3:  all of the parts inside it are gonna become outdated. So for you,
Speaker 3:  even as you come into this saying, You know, we wanna figure out how to disrupt
Speaker 3:  the space. You look around, why build the set
Speaker 3:  itself? There's so many other ways you could have attacked the TV market
Speaker 3:  rather than building big screens. Why decide to build big screens?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I mean, I, I think when you, when you look, when you look at the market,
Speaker 4:  it's even from a streaming perspective, it's so fragmented, right?
Speaker 4:  And people are using different apps and different services and, and
Speaker 4:  cables kind of taking a nose dive, right? There's, there's, people are switching
Speaker 4:  apps and htm I ports and from gaming to everything else, I think the, the,
Speaker 4:  the TV is really the, the glue of the entire home, right? It's
Speaker 4:  the, it's the way you really connect, not only all the smart
Speaker 4:  devices that are external, but also the family. And, and it's, it's where
Speaker 4:  people stay together, right? People come home with their families, they sit
Speaker 4:  in front of the tv and it's kind of like the last part that keeps everyone
Speaker 4:  together. And when you live in this kind of fragmented environment with content
Speaker 4:  living in different places, there's a conflict of interest between the
Speaker 4:  consumer and those content owners. Because everyone wants you to be within
Speaker 4:  their app, app. They don't wanna promote other apps. But the one You know,
Speaker 4:  kind of Switzerland, if you will, neutral place that, that can keep all those
Speaker 4:  things together is the actual hardware and the television, right? So I think
Speaker 4:  that that's where we see the opportunity is we can build a content
Speaker 4:  recommendation engine that is agnostic of, of what services you're
Speaker 4:  subscribed to, right? We can help you find content or, or
Speaker 4:  services that are like for you that based on your profile that are
Speaker 4:  different than, than someone else's. So I think that's really the, the opportunity
Speaker 4:  and with, with so many different options for hardware and
Speaker 4:  different devices and smart home and IOT kind of growing, and once again,
Speaker 4:  these different services, you need something that glues together and, and
Speaker 4:  the hardware and the kind of TV becomes that central point
Speaker 3:  That makes total sense to me. And I think is kind of the central question
Speaker 3:  of tele for me, which I think is part of why this company is so fun, because
Speaker 3:  you're either dead, right? That this idea that the TV should be
Speaker 3:  much more than it is has only not happened because of essentially
Speaker 3:  like lack of incentive and innovation, or it hasn't happened yet
Speaker 3:  because you're wrong and smartphones are gonna be that thing, or glasses
Speaker 3:  are gonna be that thing. Or like Alexa everywhere is gonna be that thing.
Speaker 3:  And essentially the TV's job is only going to become less and less over time
Speaker 3:  and only time will tell. But I think like for people who live in the
Speaker 3:  world, it's actually one of the most interesting technology questions at
Speaker 3:  the moment is like, what is the job of a television in the next decade?
Speaker 3:  I think it's such a fascinating question in a way that we've never really
Speaker 3:  asked before because the job of a television has been to watch things, right?
Speaker 3:  Like it was, it was a furniture piece that you watch stuff on, and then it
Speaker 3:  became smaller, and then it got flat screen and then it got higher res. But
Speaker 3:  it's fundamentally like we watch shows and movies, And, what you're talking
Speaker 3:  about is like a fundamentally much bigger, broader, wider
Speaker 3:  cooler vision for what a TV could be that no one has ever really
Speaker 3:  all the way tried to execute before. Yeah. Why don't you think anyone
Speaker 3:  has tried that? Like, to the full extent of what you're talking about?
Speaker 4:  I think it's timing, it's product market fit. You can have the greatest idea,
Speaker 4:  but release it at the wrong time and it won't work, right? Sure. And I'm
Speaker 4:  sure there's been plenty of attempts at PlutoTV before Pluto's time, but
Speaker 4:  it's, it's all about coming in at the right time when, when different parts
Speaker 4:  of the market are, are kind of right for disruption. And, and in my view,
Speaker 4:  the there's no better time to disrupt a category when it hits that commodity
Speaker 4:  state when there's very little brand loyalty. You know
Speaker 4:  to You know to purchasing a TV when a consumer walks into Costco and
Speaker 4:  there's 8 55 inch TVs in front of them and just, they just, they're all good.
Speaker 4:  They're all the same specs and they look at what's in sale and that's what
Speaker 4:  they buy. And, and that's when something really has an opportunity to be
Speaker 4:  disrupted, right? And I, I I think that timing is there. I think broadband
Speaker 4:  connections are, are now obviously a, a normal state. Yeah. I think it
Speaker 4:  took time for that to happen. I, and I think because we live in this kind
Speaker 4:  of court cutting, You know a different app ecosystem,
Speaker 4:  fragmented world with a bunch of different devices popping up, it's becoming
Speaker 4:  very difficult from a consumer perspective to know what to get to know
Speaker 4:  what to You know, to what to subscribe to. Where's my favorite show here?
Speaker 4:  You know, should I get this assistant or that assistant? I need a speaker,
Speaker 4:  I need this, I need that. It needs something to glue it all together. At
Speaker 4:  the end of the day, as I said earlier, the TV is, has the perfect opportunity
Speaker 4:  to do it because it is the biggest screen in the home. It's what keeps the
Speaker 4:  family together. Of course, we've got our iPhones and they're more than capable
Speaker 4:  of, of doing what our TVs do, but it's, it's a single use, e
Speaker 4:  experience with one consumer, no one's gathering around around their iPhones,
Speaker 4:  right? So I think that TV is, is more than capable of doing that. And if
Speaker 4:  you look at, at Telly, it's, I I always kind of make this analogy to a car
Speaker 4:  in a, in a weird way because the top screen is kind of like your
Speaker 4:  windshield, right? Okay. That'ss your main focus. That's what your You know.
Speaker 4:  That's where your content plays, that's your driving. But imagine a car
Speaker 4:  without a dashboard. Imagine you didn't have a speedometer, a radio,
Speaker 4:  a nav, like all the other things to kind of enhance your, your viewing experience.
Speaker 4:  We have to accept that right now we live in a multi-screen world,
Speaker 4:  right? And if we're watching a football game or a movie, everyone
Speaker 4:  around us is on their phones, right? That's a huge distraction. They're taking
Speaker 4:  their phones out, they're looking at You know scores. Maybe they're betting
Speaker 4:  on a game or whatever it is, right? Like, oh, lemme see what actors in that
Speaker 4:  movie. Lemme let's check out your Rotten Tomatoes reviews before you pick
Speaker 4:  something. But imagine doing that right there on that single screen right
Speaker 4:  in front of you, right? You're, you're browsing Netflix titles and the Rotten
Speaker 4:  Tomatoes reviews just show up right there below you. That's, that's what
Speaker 4:  a car's dash does, right? As as you're driving. And, and, and that's
Speaker 4:  why we believe this kind of dual screen approach solves so many
Speaker 4:  problems, right? Because if you're a TV maker, you can't
Speaker 4:  overlay someone else's content, right? Sure. Unless you're, maybe you're
Speaker 4:  Amazon, you've got the device and you've got the content, you have some opportunities
Speaker 4:  to enhance it, and you could see a lot of what they're doing. And I think
Speaker 4:  that's fantastic, right? But if, if you want to stay neutral,
Speaker 4:  right? And you wanna be able to do it across the board, you've gotta do it
Speaker 4:  on a device and you've gotta do it on a device that lets you do that agnostic
Speaker 4:  of whether you have You know that opportunity with the media companies
Speaker 3:  You just named a lot of things that are very hard to execute. Which I think
Speaker 3:  is, again, part of why this is gonna be really interesting, like, just to,
Speaker 3:  just to pull it one, right? This question of there's a lot of stuff on a
Speaker 3:  lot of different services. How do you find this stuff to watch? Like, everyone
Speaker 3:  has tried that, that's not like, it's not like an unknown problem, right?
Speaker 3:  And then Netflix just has no interest in playing
Speaker 3:  nicely and the metadata of all of it is a mess. And so
Speaker 3:  like that alone, you could have built a big company trying to solve
Speaker 3:  and that's, you're just, that's just like one small feature of this thing.
Speaker 3:  I guess part of what I'm trying to figure out is like, especially as you
Speaker 3:  start thinking about building Telly, you're like, okay, we're gonna be a
Speaker 3:  hardware company. We wanna do a lot of stuff, A lot of it's software, a lot
Speaker 3:  of it's hardware. We wanna do a lot of things. Like how, how do you figure
Speaker 3:  out sort of where to start? Like what's the, you you need a way in that is
Speaker 3:  compelling, that is new and different and going to like, get people
Speaker 3:  interested in a TV that isn't just like, whatever cheap one I can find best,
Speaker 3:  find it best Buy. How do you sort of pick those first couple of spots
Speaker 3:  to try and press at?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, no, that's a great question. And, and look, and you said we're a hardware
Speaker 4:  company. We're, we don't operate like a hardware company, okay? We're, we're
Speaker 4:  very much running this like a software company, right? And, and a
Speaker 4:  media company where hardware is just, is is a box. Obviously you
Speaker 4:  have to check 'cause we You know that's the product we're building. Sure.
Speaker 4:  But we're very much treating it almost like a Tesla where You know,
Speaker 4:  let's overload it with extra hardware and sensors and computing power. And
Speaker 4:  every two to four weeks let's push updates to make this thing better and
Speaker 4:  better and start unlocking capabilities that go beyond beyond
Speaker 4:  television, right? At a core, when we're building this, I mean, first and
Speaker 4:  foremost, you have to build a good product. You know, luckily in the TV world,
Speaker 4:  there are a a, there's like four ODMs that make the majority of
Speaker 4:  televisions. Like, so our screen is made by the second largest TV panel manufacturer
Speaker 4:  in the world. They make 20% of all the TVs, right? For all the major brands.
Speaker 4:  So you don't have to kind of reinvent the wheel, right? Right. Like that's,
Speaker 4:  that's kind of the position you're in when you're in a commodity business,
Speaker 4:  right? Is there are a lot of support layers to help you
Speaker 4:  build a product that's very comparable in the market. And that's why you
Speaker 4:  see a lot of newcomers, like, like the Rokus of the world, for example, going
Speaker 4:  into the TV space, right? I mean obviously there's challenges, but there
Speaker 4:  are also a lot of ways, a lot of things that have already been done where
Speaker 4:  you don't have to reinvent the wheel. Yeah. If
Speaker 3:  Your job is just like make a television that will display things that look
Speaker 3:  pretty good. Yeah. That's not that hard anymore.
Speaker 4:  It's not. And, but that was our, like from a product perspective, TV
Speaker 4:  1 0 1 is what we called it internally. Sure. That was first and foremost
Speaker 4:  our goal. Let's, this thing has gotta work like any other TV period, right?
Speaker 4:  But then we started looking at what are the big problems that exist right
Speaker 4:  now? Okay, well first of all, TVs are so thin now and they're, because there's
Speaker 4:  no margin and people wanna make money from something else. So they're, they're
Speaker 4:  selling you a soundbar. Well that's kind of like a shitty experience. Like
Speaker 4:  what I just bought a tv, now you're forcing me to buy a speaker. Like, let's
Speaker 4:  include that, right? Like let's make that part of it. Right. And the same
Speaker 4:  thing with a camera. Like once again, like once you try Telly and you do
Speaker 4:  a Zoom call on a big screen where, where people look life
Speaker 4:  size, you don't want to, you don't want to do a video call on any other platform.
Speaker 4:  It's, it's just, it's, it's completely game changing. So that's kind of the
Speaker 4:  way we look at, it's let's look at things that are people are doing on other
Speaker 4:  devices that we can bring to this device from a central perspective,
Speaker 4:  right? Like, like video calling and gaming and, and having great
Speaker 4:  speakers and having an assistant like there's no need for another device
Speaker 4:  that plays your music or has an assistant where your TV literally should
Speaker 4:  be doing this in 2023. Right? So that's kind of the way we approach it. What
Speaker 4:  are some kind of proven low hanging fruit that have been already
Speaker 4:  validated from, from other devices that people are spending money on that
Speaker 4:  we can just package it all in into this one device.
Speaker 3:  Alright, we gotta take a quick break and then we will be back with more from
Speaker 3:  Ilio Pozin on the future of tv.
Speaker 3:  Let's pick up where we left off talking about the job of the tv.
Speaker 3:  I have to admit, I'm sort of taken by Ilya's vision for what a TV
Speaker 3:  could be. It's the biggest screen in your house. It lives front and center
Speaker 3:  in your home. It feels like it ought to be much more than a big blank
Speaker 3:  black screen most of the time. Right. But nobody's ever
Speaker 3:  really tried to do it the way he's describing. And I don't think it's because
Speaker 3:  nobody ever thought to try. Which is why I think the way Telly is
Speaker 3:  planning to sell the TV is one of the most important things about it.
Speaker 3:  So I asked Ilya how early in the process did he decide that the TV
Speaker 3:  was going to be free for customers?
Speaker 4:  Oh, that from the get go. Yeah. Our intention was never to go out there
Speaker 4:  and become yet another hardware company and sell a TV right away.
Speaker 4:  It was the idea is, okay, can we do the same thing that we did at PlutoTV
Speaker 4:  Free, free is by far the best way to market any kind of product, right?
Speaker 4:  Sure. And this was proven even here, like we've, in our first week of launching
Speaker 4:  in May, we had hundreds of thousands of people sign up, right? We had
Speaker 4:  to sign up every second. We, they shared their data. They, they understood
Speaker 4:  that their data is already being monetized by their TV makers. But here,
Speaker 4:  there's a real value exchange and they're sitting on our wait list, waiting,
Speaker 4:  waiting for, for us to deliver a tv. And, and if you look at the kind
Speaker 4:  of people that signed up and the kind of people that are signing up every
Speaker 4:  single day, they're, they're actually over index on income. They over index
Speaker 4:  on education. They're savvy. They understand that this is a better smarter
Speaker 4:  You know TV of the future. And the fact that it's free is not because
Speaker 4:  it's a low income, low budget TV whatsoever.
Speaker 3:  Do you think you could have made the opposite case? Like if you had come
Speaker 3:  out and said, we made this tv, it's better in every way. It's more powerful.
Speaker 3:  It, it fulfills this vision of what we think a TV can be. And also
Speaker 3:  it's a thousand dollars. It's it's twice the price of your like piece of
Speaker 3:  crap Roku tv, but trust that it's worth it. You don't think so?
Speaker 4:  They would fall on our, on our nose. It would fail because once again,
Speaker 4:  consumers are like, they're, you walk into a store, you see what's on sale
Speaker 4:  and that's what you buy. It's the, the, the driver's price, right? There's
Speaker 4:  a baseline of quality that you're looking for, and then the next factor of
Speaker 4:  how you make a decision of what, of, of purchasing a TV s price. So even
Speaker 4:  the idea of making the TV $50 more by adding a camera
Speaker 4:  to it, I don't think it would work. Okay. Right. I just, I I I think the
Speaker 4:  majority of consumers are, are kind of driven by what the norm is And
Speaker 4:  what the standard is. And I think the only way to introduce a
Speaker 4:  disruptive product into the market in a category where it's commoditized
Speaker 4:  and there's so many other players is to also disrupt a price point.
Speaker 3:  Okay. Yeah. So this really is the same as PlutoTV in that way, right? It's
Speaker 3:  two separate insights. This should be free and this
Speaker 3:  should be better that just kind of crash into each other
Speaker 4:  Completely. Right?
Speaker 3:  So what do you make of the reaction? I, I like when Telly first came out,
Speaker 3:  my reaction, and I think a lot of people's was
Speaker 3:  basically this is one of three things. This is either like a scam, this is
Speaker 3:  either a horrifying, dystopian, You know
Speaker 3:  surveillance nightmare that is just going to show me ads 24 hours a day,
Speaker 3:  or this is the future of television because this is essentially the present
Speaker 3:  of television and I'm just now getting it for free. Am I missing any, did
Speaker 3:  I, did I go through the full range of emotions? What, what other ones were
Speaker 3:  there? No,
Speaker 4:  That I think, I think obviously when you're coming out with a free product
Speaker 4:  that it's, people automatically think this is too good to be true. Right?
Speaker 4:  Like, what's the catch? What, what's out there? And I think they quickly
Speaker 4:  realize that it's actually on the flip side, that, that when you look at
Speaker 4:  other TV makers, they're double dipping on, on the revenue stream. They're
Speaker 4:  selling you a piece of hardware, they're monetizing with ads, they're selling
Speaker 4:  your data, right? And that's the reaction we got from
Speaker 4:  consumers. Like we, we've had little to no hesitation of people signing up,
Speaker 4:  right? People understood that, that there's that value exchange that, that
Speaker 4:  they're willing to share their data and because they're getting a thousand
Speaker 4:  dollars TV completely free, right? And they understood that this is a product
Speaker 4:  that is far superior than anything else in the market. So, and,
Speaker 4:  and that it's proven not only in our signup rate
Speaker 4:  and our wait list, but it's also proven in all the usage, right? Like we're,
Speaker 4:  we're in public beta right now. We're, we're in thousands and thousands of
Speaker 4:  homes and, and this thing is working and people are using it every single
Speaker 4:  day, right? TVs are owned for six to seven years and they're used for
Speaker 4:  their primary TV in a home is used for many hours per day. And when you're
Speaker 4:  a device in the biggest screen in your home, in the, in the, and the most
Speaker 4:  important device essentially in a home that's used for six, seven years,
Speaker 4:  it's not just a tv, it's a platform. Right? And that's the way we're looking
Speaker 4:  at it and we're building it, is let's check the box on tv. Yes, it
Speaker 4:  could do everything else here, TV can, but then let's start innovating
Speaker 4:  and pushing updates. And there's so much more we could have built from the
Speaker 4:  get go, but we don't wanna overwhelm the consumer like, oh, this thing could
Speaker 4:  do this and this and this and this. Like, it's coming, right? Like there's
Speaker 4:  like, you might come home one day and and you might see that,
Speaker 4:  hey, like you see a list of your, of your friends that have tellies online,
Speaker 4:  you might be able to like You know, Hey, David's online, let's let's watch
Speaker 4:  TV together. There's a game on, right? Or let's, let's say, Hey, hey Telly,
Speaker 4:  take a photo of me and send it to mom. Mom comes home, sees a photo
Speaker 4:  of her son, right? And pins it to the bottom screen in a, in a cute little
Speaker 4:  photo frame. And that lives there, right? There's so many things that, that
Speaker 4:  we can do with this device, but because it's free, there's no barrier entry,
Speaker 4:  right? The idea of another TV maker coming out with,
Speaker 4:  with a TV and try to do something social, it's, it's, is gonna fail because
Speaker 4:  You know if let's say you're vio you wanna build a social experience, you
Speaker 4:  have to make sure everyone else has a VIO tv. But then that's You know that's
Speaker 4:  not gonna happen. But if Telly is completely free, the idea that everyone
Speaker 4:  now starts having a tele and you can actually connect them and create this
Speaker 4:  network effect is absolutely feasible. And you'll bet that that's something
Speaker 4:  that we're gonna start rolling out more and more of in, in the coming months.
Speaker 3:  Okay. What do you say to the people who look at what you're offering
Speaker 3:  both in terms of like the ad supported stuff and the,
Speaker 3:  the camera and the data collection and see a total
Speaker 3:  nightmare surveillance hellscape? Are you interested in winning
Speaker 3:  those people over? Like what do you, how do you make that case?
Speaker 4:  I I look, we're, we're a privacy first company. We're a product first company,
Speaker 4:  right? So even from our ad experience, it's non-intrusive, non
Speaker 4:  interrupting. You're not gonna see a video ad with sound on while you're
Speaker 4:  watching tv.
Speaker 3:  To be fair, that's what everybody says about ads. And most people are lying
Speaker 3:  when they say that about ads.
Speaker 4:  That's right. And the camera is closed by default, right? Sure. When you
Speaker 4:  open up Zoom, we literally pop put up a message on the screen saying, would
Speaker 4:  you like to open up the camera to do a zoom call? The second you close the
Speaker 4:  zoom call, the camera closes, right? This is not the business we're in, right?
Speaker 4:  When you're looking at once again, other TV makers, they're monetizing your
Speaker 4:  data with very little to no permission, right? They're monetizing in many
Speaker 4:  different streams. We're just very upfront and transparent about it. We let
Speaker 4:  consumers know everything is fully opt in. Nothing is hidden in long terms
Speaker 4:  of service, right? You're, you're, you're there. We tell you that you're
Speaker 4:  opting into this, you're opting into that this is how we use your data, this
Speaker 4:  is how we advertise, and in exchange we're giving you a free TV and all these
Speaker 4:  other guys aren't, right? So I think it's a, it's a conscious decision and
Speaker 4:  we're seeing very little to no pushback from the consumer side of things,
Speaker 4:  right? And if you, even if you look at some of like, like the interview we
Speaker 4:  had in like Wall Street Journal for example, right? They did a,
Speaker 4:  I think the reporting was fantastic. They obviously interviewed some privacy
Speaker 4:  experts and they said, yeah, they could be a concern about this. But then
Speaker 4:  they interviewed consumers and said, yeah, You know what I signed up because
Speaker 4:  I know all these other guys that I'm paying it to for already do this and
Speaker 4:  they do it with my, without my permission and this case I'm getting a very
Speaker 4:  clear value exchange, so why not? Right? Yeah.
Speaker 3:  I think that is a slightly nihilist way of looking at the world. And
Speaker 3:  also I think absolutely true, right? And I think this is a thing we struggle
Speaker 3:  with a lot is like, to some extent, it's really important
Speaker 3:  to talk about privacy and how your data moves around the internet, And
Speaker 3:  what companies and platforms know about you And, what they can do with that
Speaker 3:  information, how it matters. And on the other hand, I think most people either
Speaker 3:  don't care or think it's so far gone that it's not useful to
Speaker 3:  think about. Like personally, I just, I struggle with that all the time.
Speaker 3:  It's like, how much does being a privacy zealot
Speaker 3:  mean anything to anyone anymore? I genuinely don't know the answer. And I
Speaker 3:  think part of what you just said that I think is so interesting is like,
Speaker 3:  you, you're basically just saying the quiet part loud, right? Like, you're
Speaker 3:  like, you're like, yes, we are going to make money off of the data that
Speaker 3:  you give us when you use our product. So is everybody else. We're just going
Speaker 3:  to be much louder about it. And that's right. Yeah. That's kind of, it's
Speaker 3:  kind of a wild approach, but I, I like, I kind of respect it, I have to say,
Speaker 4:  Well, I think transparency is key. I think when consumers get upset is
Speaker 4:  when something happens that was obfuscated, right? And that's when you see
Speaker 4:  a lot of trouble in, in any kind of iot companies is when,
Speaker 4:  when people thought one thing and another thing happens, right? And, and
Speaker 4:  for us once again, we You know we, we led this from a privacy first perspective,
Speaker 4:  right? If you go do focus groups, you'll, and, and if you're like a Samsung
Speaker 4:  and you run a focus group, should we put a camera in our tv? Right? There's
Speaker 4:  already such a bad reputation and there's like some negative connotation
Speaker 4:  about the product that most people will say no. Right? And that's what a
Speaker 4:  lot of focus groups are wrong from that perspective, right? Because they
Speaker 4:  don't actually position it the right way. But if you understood
Speaker 4:  the value ads that it gives you that you could do the video calls and fitness
Speaker 4:  and gaming and all these other things that a camera unlocks, but you make
Speaker 4:  people feel comfortable, right? Because the shutter's closed and because
Speaker 4:  you're very upfront about how you use the data and how you monetize. I think
Speaker 4:  it's a very different kind of experience and relationship that a company
Speaker 4:  can have with that consumer. And that's, that's how we're positioning. It's,
Speaker 4:  it's when it's the other way that it becomes a challenge.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. No, I think that's totally fair. And I think there is in there
Speaker 3:  somewhere though still a a bar you have to
Speaker 3:  hold on your own, right? Like, I think the, the idea that everybody's
Speaker 3:  gonna like read the terms of service carefully and, and fully understand
Speaker 3:  it and think about it and agree to it is it's just not true. Like nobody
Speaker 3:  does that. So you can come in and say like, we are much clearer about it
Speaker 3:  the way that this works. And I think realistically, you're, you're right
Speaker 3:  that just by virtue of the fact that the TV is free, people are going to
Speaker 3:  like inherently understand what the trade off is like that makes total sense
Speaker 3:  to me. I am curious what you think sort of your own
Speaker 3:  internal bar for, like you say you're, you come from a privacy first
Speaker 3:  perspective. Like what does that look like practically like on
Speaker 3:  behalf of the users who still aren't paying enough attention to really know
Speaker 3:  what's going on?
Speaker 4:  I mean, once again, I think transparency is key. I I do think there are a
Speaker 4:  lot of people that overlook privacy, right? And as you said, they kind of
Speaker 4:  just click, I agree on every terms of service and, and move forward. And
Speaker 4:  that whether, and, and maybe that's because they don't care maybe, or maybe
Speaker 4:  it's because they already realize that it's gone too far and everyone,
Speaker 4:  it's, it's one of those things everyone already does and they're selling
Speaker 4:  the data. So might as well get a You know some value exchange for it. I don't
Speaker 4:  really know You know, like from my perspective, I, I know that
Speaker 4:  there, that are a lot of software that I use and a lot of hardware that I
Speaker 4:  use kind of obfuscates the, the transparency around privacy. Sure.
Speaker 4:  They're absolutely out there selling my data, right? But I also think
Speaker 4:  there are a lot of laws and regulations in place,
Speaker 4:  truthfully, that make sure that if your data is sold,
Speaker 4:  it's anonymized and those things are absolutely real. Like, and anyone who
Speaker 4:  violates those laws should not exist, right? So first and foremost, you gotta
Speaker 4:  stay above every state and federal law. Like that bar is already there. So
Speaker 4:  even anytime we have any kind of data, it's, it's anonymous, right? We're,
Speaker 4:  we're not attaching any personal level level data to any ad targeting data.
Speaker 4:  And that's how you have to operate a business. Like I've been in the ad world
Speaker 4:  on both the buy side when I had an agency to, to the sell side when I had
Speaker 4:  PlutoTV, right? To now with Telly, that is extremely important. You,
Speaker 4:  you have to protect people's data and you have to build
Speaker 4:  environments that enable those levels of protection. Those actually already
Speaker 4:  exist, right? Even if you're working with servers and services like Amazon,
Speaker 4:  they're built in to be able to You know, have that level of data protection.
Speaker 4:  So that's kinda my view. I think there's, there's a few people that are really
Speaker 4:  vocal, if you will, on privacy and data, but what
Speaker 4:  are they gonna do? Like, like is there a TV that you can go out there and
Speaker 4:  purchase that doesn't sell your data, that doesn't deliver advertising? Like
Speaker 4:  what are your options? Or do you just get You know no TV at all and
Speaker 4:  You know run everything behind A V P N or I, I You know, I
Speaker 4:  I think you can complain all day or you can realize that people need to run
Speaker 4:  their businesses so they need access to, to data. And at the end of the day,
Speaker 4:  advertisers want to target homes effectively. Like so, right? So for,
Speaker 4:  for us, for example, we ask you at signup, what car do you own You
Speaker 4:  know? Are you in the market for a new car in the next six months? If you
Speaker 4:  are an advertiser wants to know that, but frankly you want to know that as
Speaker 4:  a consumer too, right? Because you wanna start seeing relevant
Speaker 4:  advertising for things that you have intent to buy, right? But if you
Speaker 4:  block all your data, cover your data, now you're seeing ads for You know
Speaker 4:  stuff that doesn't even important. And that's where I think that's where
Speaker 4:  people start having a negative association Advertising is when ads aren't
Speaker 4:  relevant, right? And it feels like it's benefiting, benefiting one side and
Speaker 4:  not the other side. We've built our whole business to make sure that
Speaker 4:  that benefit. It goes two ways, right? That, that you, you're getting ads
Speaker 4:  that are relevant and advertisers are, are, are advertising to you because
Speaker 4:  they know that you need this product.
Speaker 3:  Okay, we gotta take one more break and then we will be back with more from
Speaker 3:  Ilya Pozin on Telly, PlutoTV TVs and
Speaker 3:  lots more
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Right? And it's like, I think we have hit that threshold in a really
Speaker 3:  real way. And I think your timing is super interesting as a result because
Speaker 3:  what you're doing is you're not just saying, we're gonna make one part of
Speaker 3:  this cheaper for you. You're like, let's just blow the whole thing up, top
Speaker 3:  down and start over. Like, yeah, it's gonna be super
Speaker 3:  interesting to see kind of how far that goes because I think like Avo is
Speaker 3:  having a moment right now, right? Like PlutoTV is growing really fast, Tubi
Speaker 3:  is growing really fast. We're in this place where people are looking for
Speaker 3:  a way to make things less expensive and they will happily watch some ads
Speaker 3:  in order to do so. I absolutely think you're right about that. How far that
Speaker 3:  goes I think is really interesting. And I think that goes back to the question
Speaker 3:  of the reaction to Telly and like how you think about the product itself.
Speaker 3:  Because I think what a lot of people are reacting to is the idea that the
Speaker 3:  second screen is basically going to be an always on billboard showing
Speaker 3:  me ads. And from the way you're describing the product, it doesn't sound
Speaker 3:  like that's the case. My initial impression is certainly like, it's just
Speaker 3:  gonna be a a, a scrolling ticker of ads as long as my TV
Speaker 3:  is on. And that just sounds like a crummy user experience in a lot of
Speaker 3:  ways. Is it not that, like how do you, how do you avoid it's not being
Speaker 3:  so bad at ads that people hate it even though they like the trade? Yeah,
Speaker 4:  That's a great question. It's not that whatsoever, right? The majority of
Speaker 4:  the screen is dedicated to widgets and content that
Speaker 4:  actually is standalone amazing and then enhances what you're viewing, right?
Speaker 4:  So we've got like things like, like time and weather and
Speaker 4:  a news sticker and sports scores, right? Stocks, right? Things that are
Speaker 4:  very relevant and people are buying. You know they have assistance now from
Speaker 4:  Google and Amazon that have a lot of visual additives, not just You
Speaker 4:  know, not just your voice assistant with a speaker, but they're actually
Speaker 4:  showing you a lot of useful information. So that's built in and th and
Speaker 4:  that's like 75, 80% of the screen is dedicated to that,
Speaker 4:  right? And then because we understand what you're watching on the main
Speaker 4:  screen, we're able to automatically adjust those widgets based on what you're
Speaker 4:  watching. So if you turn on a movie, we show you accurate information, right?
Speaker 4:  We show you You know description of the movie, maybe some trivia, some fun
Speaker 4:  things to enhance that movie. You're gonna look at your phone anyway Sure
Speaker 4:  for that, right? And we're we're saying let's put that front and center.
Speaker 4:  The best way to look at it's, it's the bottom screen is almost like an iPad
Speaker 4:  attached to the tv. Once again, you're, you're, you've got your family in
Speaker 4:  front of this big device. Everyone's looking at their phones for different
Speaker 4:  reasons. You're watching a sports game, you wanna know how the other teams
Speaker 4:  are doing. Maybe maybe your fantasy, maybe your fantasy team. You wanna
Speaker 4:  look at the stats, why not put that front and center right? And maybe sports
Speaker 4:  betting, right? Why not have Fando or DraftKings integration right there
Speaker 4:  natively. The ad is a small part of, of that, of
Speaker 4:  that screen, right? It's, it's not there to distract you. It's
Speaker 4:  there to obviously You know support this value exchange of being free and
Speaker 4:  to connect with a consumer in a very transparent way. But it's not the majority
Speaker 4:  of the screen whatsoever. In fact, once you use You know tele, this is,
Speaker 4:  this is across the board and you can look at our data and look at any customer
Speaker 4:  feedback is, is people love it and it's very hard for them to go back to
Speaker 4:  a single stream screen and they'll, they'll, they'll tell you that it's not
Speaker 4:  a distraction. We haven't had a single consumer switch out of a
Speaker 4:  tele and go back to a device that doesn't have that bottom screen. 'cause
Speaker 4:  they're not looking at it in a negative way.
Speaker 3:  Interesting. Okay. Have you tested to see like, how many ads is too
Speaker 3:  many ads? I would, I would think that would be a really interesting experiment
Speaker 3:  to run. Have you done that?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. There's, that's still data we're, we're looking at every single day,
Speaker 4:  right? Like our, and we've built a You know a rockstar team like our head
Speaker 4:  of product. Sasha was the head of product that Android TV for You know
Speaker 4:  for Google. He's running our product here and, and You know the same thing
Speaker 4:  across the board and the ads and everything else. We've got just the right
Speaker 4:  team that has industry experience and startup chops to make this work. And
Speaker 4:  we're You know if you notice You know we're in a beta program. What TV
Speaker 4:  company goes into a beta program, right? Sure. Like Google launches, Gmail
Speaker 4:  and beta or whatever new product. That's the way, that's the way software
Speaker 4:  is done even by bigger companies. That's unheard of From a hardware perspective,
Speaker 4:  and this is kind of going back to like my, my Roots. I'm a, I'm, I've been
Speaker 4:  a software guy my, my entire life. We're very much running this
Speaker 4:  like a software company and we're very transparent. We, we've been in private
Speaker 4:  beta where we tested this with You know CLO close family and friends just
Speaker 4:  to You know, make sure we've got like TV 1 0 1 and the core product done
Speaker 4:  and stable. And then we opened up to public beta for people that we don't
Speaker 4:  have a relationship with, but that agreed to kind of go on this journey with
Speaker 4:  us and to kind of shape the future of TV and make this product better. And
Speaker 4:  they're giving us feedback and they're sharing their data and they're telling
Speaker 4:  us how to make this better and improve it. And it's working like the data
Speaker 4:  is there. People are using this every single day. In fact,
Speaker 4:  even our original business model of how many hours per day people will use
Speaker 4:  this, we, we were wrong by almost half. Wow. You
Speaker 4:  know. So, so it's, it's working right? And people have multiple TVs in their
Speaker 4:  house. We wanna make sure that this is their primary TV and not get stuck
Speaker 4:  in a, a basement somewhere. One way to solve that is to make it the right
Speaker 4:  size. Right. The average American family has a 49 inch tv, so we made a
Speaker 4:  55. Right? So naturally it's gonna go in a, in a main room, but
Speaker 4:  also people could just shove it in a, in a guest room or somewhere else,
Speaker 4:  but they're not Right. And the data shows based on, based on how often they're
Speaker 4:  watching it.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. What happens if they do. I mean, I think part of what's been interesting
Speaker 3:  about tele is trying to figure out how to make sure people
Speaker 3:  use the product in a way that works without being scary. And you have
Speaker 3:  some scary sounding rules about like You know what you can and can't do to
Speaker 3:  the TV without violating the terms of service. Like what balance
Speaker 3:  have you found there where you're like, we, we need you to use your TV in
Speaker 3:  a certain way for this business to make sense for us, but we also want it
Speaker 3:  to feel like a thing that you own that isn't just like a box that
Speaker 3:  we've put into your house that we can take back at any time. Do You know
Speaker 3:  what I mean?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, yeah. No, I think that's a great question too. I look, we, we want
Speaker 4:  to have a positive, transparent relationship with our consumers and we don't
Speaker 4:  want consumers that fraud us. Right? We don't want consumers that You know
Speaker 4:  tell us they're gonna do one thing and then do another thing. Because that's,
Speaker 4:  we're we're trying to be successful as a company and, and if you have a bunch
Speaker 4:  of fraudulent consumers that take advantage of you, we're it, it's not gonna
Speaker 4:  be good for business. Right? So, so for us, we put policies in
Speaker 4:  place, You know to be able to have that opportunity to,
Speaker 4:  in, in case someone is frauding us to be able to take the device back and
Speaker 4:  saying like, look, you're covering up the bottom screen or you're not using
Speaker 4:  this in the main room. Right? But first and foremost, we want to build the
Speaker 4:  right experience. You can't even cover up the bottom screen. Right? All of
Speaker 4:  your settings, your volume controls, your H D M I switching, everything
Speaker 4:  happens on the bottom. Sure. Right? So we actually cleaned up the top to
Speaker 4:  make it to easier to watch in the bottom. Actually, that's where your control
Speaker 4:  center is for your whole device. And frankly, you don't want to cover it
Speaker 4:  up 'cause that's where you're playing your music, that's where you're doing
Speaker 4:  your Zoom calls, right? That's where your ring doorbell appears. That's where
Speaker 4:  you're getting like news and weather. It's work. So first and foremost, you
Speaker 4:  build a good product that people don't want to fraud, right? Sure. I think
Speaker 4:  that's a prerequisite. If we built a product that is
Speaker 4:  there just for our sake from a business perspective that's there to monetize
Speaker 4:  and make ads and we don't, and that bottom screen doesn't actually provide
Speaker 4:  any actually valuable in inventory, then of course people are naturally gonna
Speaker 4:  say, okay, I'm just gonna get this. I'm gonna tell 'em I'm gonna do that.
Speaker 4:  I'm gonna do something else 'cause I just want a free 55 inch tv. But then
Speaker 4:  we failed from a product perspective. Right? Right. And, and that's first
Speaker 4:  and foremost what, what our approach is, is let's build a killer product
Speaker 4:  that people don't actually wanna keep as their main tv. 'cause it's better.
Speaker 4:  Right. And if that's where you're playing your music and that's where you're
Speaker 4:  doing your Zoom calls and everything else, why would you put that in a guest
Speaker 4:  bedroom? Then your primary TV in your living room is now not as
Speaker 4:  powerful. Right? Sure. And I think that's the way we do it. And of course
Speaker 4:  we put things in place to give us the ability to
Speaker 4:  You know, take the TV back and things like that for people that fought it.
Speaker 4:  But we're not seeing that, like we're seeing everyone use it in the right
Speaker 4:  way, at least so far.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I mean it's, I I'm not surprised they had a beta test, right? Like
Speaker 3:  you have a self-selecting group group of people who are likely to use it.
Speaker 3:  But I guess the, the sort of extreme example would be like the idea that
Speaker 3:  I could go on vacation for two months and come home and my TV has been
Speaker 3:  repoed,
Speaker 4:  That wouldn't happen. We would never do that. We would never do that. And
Speaker 4:  we don't have policies in place to do that. We, that's, that's just not realistic
Speaker 4:  whatsoever.
Speaker 3:  Okay, fair enough. Yeah. So the, all the software you've mentioned, all the
Speaker 3:  stuff you're thinking about building, you mentioned You know, doing integrations
Speaker 3:  and all that stuff. What's your sense over time of how much of this you are
Speaker 3:  gonna try and build versus like opening a
Speaker 3:  platform? Like is is the tele app store gonna be a thing? Like you wanna
Speaker 3:  build this giant corpus of stuff onto a big screen, right? Yeah. What's
Speaker 3:  your sense of how much of that you need to do yourself?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, no, that's a great question. So initially we're doing it ourselves.
Speaker 4:  We we are built on, on Android, right? Sure. Which, which gives us a
Speaker 4:  huge advantage and a big existing ecosystem, right? And similar to Amazon
Speaker 4:  Fire tv, which is built on, on Android as well, right? It gives you an advantage
Speaker 4:  because you can, you can use existing apps. Like when we, when we put
Speaker 4:  Spotify into the, into Telly, there was pretty much no work, right?
Speaker 4:  'cause Spotify already had an Android TV app, so we just poured it over,
Speaker 4:  right? And those things give you an advantage as a startup, but also, and
Speaker 4:  potentially in the future, allow us to open up the app store and create
Speaker 4:  experiences that go beyond streaming. And, and that, I think that's the key
Speaker 4:  phrase here is beyond streaming, right? And if we
Speaker 4:  do open up an app store, it'll still be on an approval basis of course, that
Speaker 4:  we bring anything in is we don't want yet again, another kind of
Speaker 4:  congested environment where there's like hundreds of apps and only five of
Speaker 4:  them are good. But more importantly, we want people to build for tele
Speaker 4:  things that they wouldn't normally build for another TV maker, because it's
Speaker 4:  impossible to get that from another TV maker because maybe they don't have
Speaker 4:  a microphone, they don't have a camera, they don't have a second screen,
Speaker 4:  they don't have great speakers, they don't have this computing power, right?
Speaker 4:  Our remote You know it's got a, it's got a microphone's, got some sensors
Speaker 4:  in it that'll also enable things in the future. Imagine this thing becoming
Speaker 4:  a karaoke machine in a couple months where You know words appear on the top
Speaker 4:  songs in the bottom, you pick up your remote, this has a mic, right? Or a
Speaker 4:  gaming pad or whatever it is, right? So, so initially we're gonna kind
Speaker 4:  of create these examples of different use cases that show how we can
Speaker 4:  go beyond a normal television of what you're used to for the last 20, 30
Speaker 4:  years. And then eventually we'd love to open it up to those
Speaker 4:  that want to build for it. But once again, to go, we don't want just another
Speaker 4:  fast service to appear on this thing, right? Like there's, there's plenty
Speaker 4:  of those. We, we really want to take this thing and to become the main
Speaker 4:  device in a home, just like your, your iPhone or your your Android
Speaker 4:  phone is, is the, is the main device outta your home.
Speaker 3:  What kind of appetite do you think there is in, in the world for folks who
Speaker 3:  wanna build that kind of stuff? I just think about like, it, it feels like
Speaker 3:  every three years Apple tells a story about the Apple TV being like an amazing
Speaker 3:  game console and it, it just isn't true. Like people don't
Speaker 3:  play games on their Apple tv. That's just like not a thing. But Apple
Speaker 3:  desperately wants people to, and there's also, I I think like you talk about
Speaker 3:  with the smart TV platforms, we've gone on this race to the bottom where
Speaker 3:  all the apps are bad. Everybody has just given up on doing interesting stuff
Speaker 3:  because it's pure commodity and it sucks and nobody caress anymore.
Speaker 3:  Can you get to the point where you're big enough and cool enough and exciting
Speaker 3:  enough that you think you can like win back some of these people who have
Speaker 3:  been burned by building TV stuff before?
Speaker 4:  I think you'll be surprised we're already seeing it, right? Not just from
Speaker 4:  individual like kind of developers, but major, major
Speaker 4:  companies who have already built platforms for tv, right?
Speaker 4:  Or second screen experiences for TV that are
Speaker 4:  so behind what we're doing and and blown away by our You know two screen
Speaker 4:  form factor that even though we're not yet at millions
Speaker 4:  of homes wanna build for us right now, right? Whether that's
Speaker 4:  You know sports betting, which has a natural environment or You know
Speaker 4:  there, there are a number of startups that you may have seen that are trying
Speaker 4:  to enable You know shopping on, like you're watching your favorite
Speaker 4:  show and you want to buy that, that sweatshirt, right? Like the famous You
Speaker 4:  know friend sweatshirt episode. But You know they've built second
Speaker 4:  screen experiences, but they're struggling because getting a consumer to
Speaker 4:  take out their phone or their tablet while you're watching TV is a huge hurdle,
Speaker 4:  right? But they wanna build for our, our bottom screen experience because
Speaker 4:  it's right there front and center, right? It's almost like a dual second
Speaker 4:  screen experie put on the main screen. And even knowing kind of our
Speaker 4:  stage and where we are, they're very interested and a lot of 'em are already
Speaker 4:  building for us. So you'll start seeing a lot of these partnerships that
Speaker 4:  I can't yet speak to will will be front and center and the
Speaker 4:  developer feedback is there without us even soliciting it.
Speaker 3:  I would think that building a future-proof TV is really important
Speaker 3:  and also really challenging. Like I, I have this Roku TV behind me that I
Speaker 3:  swear to God gets slower every day because the apps update and new things
Speaker 3:  come in and the processor just can't hang, like you were saying, six or
Speaker 3:  seven years, people are gonna keep these, these are not devices you upgrade
Speaker 3:  frequently. People I think would like to keep most of 'em even longer. Is
Speaker 3:  it, as hard as I would think to build something like what
Speaker 3:  Telly wants to be six or seven years from now is so ambitious and so big
Speaker 3:  that like you kind of have to build a TV that works now and can get all the
Speaker 3:  way there. I just think from a hardware perspective, that seems like it would
Speaker 3:  be hard to do.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I mean, I think that's a great question. When, when, if you're a TV
Speaker 4:  maker and you're optimizing for the tiny margin that you make on hardware,
Speaker 4:  you're not buying the best and fastest processor. Sure.
Speaker 4:  But we are,
Speaker 3:  You're buying the worst one you can find,
Speaker 4:  Right? So, so because of that, you kind of have this natural obsolete, if
Speaker 4:  you will, where like, like I mentioned earlier, even building PlutoTV for
Speaker 4:  the most modern TV now is not, it's a PlutoTV is a very heavy app. It's not,
Speaker 4:  it's not easy. And You know if you're building an app for Roku, they're running
Speaker 4:  like almost like a, like a digital billboard script to, to be able to develop
Speaker 4:  for, it's very challenging for us. We're treating this like a computer, the
Speaker 4:  power inside of the device and the sensors that we've put in, some of them
Speaker 4:  aren't utilized right to its full effect now because we want
Speaker 4:  to enable that, that future utilization in the future. And we even added
Speaker 4:  a bunch of expansion ports on the device. So let's say say
Speaker 4:  later we want to add like a temperature sensor. So for whatever reason, like
Speaker 4:  let's say you want this thing to know what temperature's in your home and,
Speaker 4:  and be a thermostat. I'm, I'm making completely making it up. We've put
Speaker 4:  expansion ports on there so that you can expand the TV in other means, but
Speaker 4:  we're very much treating it like a Tesla, right? Where I'm on my third Tesla,
Speaker 4:  even in the beginning, a lot of the autopilot hardware wasn't really enabled.
Speaker 4:  And, and, and then how like delighted are we s Tesla customers where we get
Speaker 4:  in the car, we turn it on and we, and we see like, hey, we updated your car
Speaker 4:  and here's all the new stuff it can do. Like, that's awesome, right? And,
Speaker 4:  and that's the way we're treating our software updates is it's not about
Speaker 4:  fixing bugs and issues, it's about making this thing better
Speaker 4:  and better and better. And the only way to do that is if you overload your,
Speaker 4:  your device with extra computing power processors, memory
Speaker 4:  storage, connectivity, and then you allow it to expand into
Speaker 4:  additional sensors beyond potentially what you loaded in. Because You know
Speaker 4:  you can't get everything right out the get go. So we're, we believe we built
Speaker 4:  a very much a future-proof device. We don't want to get get you
Speaker 4:  into a new TV in two, three years like the other makers do. And I think that's
Speaker 4:  the other big difference is if you look at a, the makeup of like the engineering
Speaker 4:  team at any other TV company, the majority of them are
Speaker 4:  supporting old models of TVs and building new models of TVs,
Speaker 4:  right? Because TVs like, there's so many models of every other TV maker,
Speaker 4:  we've got one, right? So we, we put this out and the whole team
Speaker 4:  is focused on making this one better. And I think when you have that and
Speaker 4:  when you're concentrating your team on improving the product rather than
Speaker 4:  supporting legacy or building the next, you come out with a product at the
Speaker 4:  end of the day that's far superior and continues to grow as, as people
Speaker 4:  and and consumers evolve.
Speaker 3:  It would also be terrible business for you. Right? If you had to ship me
Speaker 3:  a new free TV every two years just to keep using tele. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Horrible. Yeah. It's not the way to do it If
Speaker 3:  This works, like if this hits, this really takes off, this becomes you, you
Speaker 3:  become like a real huge player in the TV business. Do you think others
Speaker 3:  will start to follow, like play this sort of same game, start giving people
Speaker 3:  substantially cheaper or even free TVs in exchange for some of this other
Speaker 3:  stuff? Like do you think others can come after you that way? Potentially,
Speaker 4:  Potentially. You know, you never know how the market's gonna change. We've
Speaker 4:  got a lot of You know patents that we filed on, on, on what we've done and,
Speaker 4:  and we're also set up in a way where we can enable these partners with
Speaker 4:  us to be You know successful. So You know we're happy to work with others
Speaker 4:  and we've actually been in communication with some as well on, on these kind
Speaker 4:  of things. So I think it's quite possible. I think for a, a
Speaker 4:  very well-known TV maker to go out there and all of a sudden cut their
Speaker 4:  prices to zero and cannibalize their core business would be
Speaker 4:  probably detrimental to their stocks and probably, yeah. And You know not
Speaker 4:  good for their business, but it You know you. Who knows? I think a lot of
Speaker 4:  people are waiting and seeing what, what happens to us, which obviously
Speaker 4:  also gives us a big advantage, right? Startups move quickly. That's the one
Speaker 4:  advantage that, that we have over every big company. We don't deal
Speaker 4:  with the bureaucracy and the politics. We're, we're a small, nimble team
Speaker 4:  and speed is our only advantage. It's not, it's not our pocketbooks, right?
Speaker 4:  We're not gonna outspend a big company, but we're gonna outs speed 'em,
Speaker 4:  we're gonna outperform 'em and that's exactly what we're doing. And by the
Speaker 4:  time they're You know the others realize that hey, this is working and this
Speaker 4:  is something we need to do. We'll be years ahead like PlutoTV, right? Where
Speaker 4:  we're still by Pluto's by far in the leading company in the space.
Speaker 4:  We had a head start. We maintained that head start through just great execution.
Speaker 3:  Fair enough. All, right? I could talk to you about this forever. I find this
Speaker 3:  totally fascinating, but I should let you go. I know I've kept you a long
Speaker 3:  time. Thank you for doing this. This was incredibly fun. Appreciate
Speaker 4:  It. Thanks Eric.
Speaker 3:  Alright, that's it for The Vergecast today. Thank you so much to Ilya for
Speaker 3:  being on the show, and thank you as always for listening. Like I said, we
Speaker 3:  have three more episodes to come in this series. We're gonna be looking at
Speaker 3:  connectivity from all different angles. It's gonna be really fun. This show
Speaker 3:  is produced by Andrew Moreno and Liam James The. Vergecast is a Verge production
Speaker 3:  and part of the Vox Media podcast network. We'll be back with episodes on
Speaker 3:  Wednesday and Friday. There's still tons of news to cover this week and
Speaker 3:  a bunch of gadgets we haven't gotten to talk about yet. We'll be back next
Speaker 3:  Monday with the next episode in our connectivity series. We'll see you then.
Speaker 3:  Rock and roll.