# Transcript
ID: 10c8f666-9ed0-426b-9471-4258bc958080
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Apple OS betas, how to talk about AI, and our video game picks
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/4734174120816489870/6040172684135670124/s93290-US-5582s-1689149695.mp3
Description: Today on the flagship podcast of transformers (both the movie and the AI thing):
03:46 - The Verge’s Victoria Song, Chris Welch, Allison Johnson, and David Pierce discuss using the new features and tools in beta versions of Apple’s watchOS 10, tvOS 17, iOS 17, and iPadOS 17.
28:36 - The Verge’s James Vincent joins the show to discuss how we should think about using the popular vocabulary terms in AI like GPT, LLM, transformers, hallucinations, etc. Are we using them the right way? Does it matter how we use them?
54:20 - David is joined by The Verge’s Ash Parrish and Polygon’s Chris Plante to share the video games they are most excited about after a string of announcements from Nintendo, Sony, Microsoft, Ubisoft, Summer Game Fest, and others.
1:25:46 - We answer a question from the Vergecast Hotline
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com, or call us at 866-VERGE11, we love hearing from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Disabled
Speaker 2:  Welcome to The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of Transformers,
Speaker 2:  both the movie and the AI thing. I'm your friend, David Pierce. And
Speaker 2:  I am sitting here catching up on Wimbledon, the best tennis tournament of
Speaker 2:  the year. Whoa,
Speaker 3:  Surely pointed the tournament so far. That one,
Speaker 4:  You have got to be kidding me.
Speaker 2:  Wow. It's been a busy few days for me so I'm a bit behind. But luckily
Speaker 2:  wimbledon.com has a pretty good set of highlights so I can catch up
Speaker 2:  on all the matches I missed in just a few minutes at a time. And I, don't
Speaker 2:  know if you know this, but Wimbledon is doing a thing with AI commentary
Speaker 2:  in these highlights. It's part of some collaboration with IBM's Watson.
Speaker 2:  And. I can See how it's an interesting and cool idea, but oh boy,
Speaker 2:  it's so, so, so bad. Like, okay, listen
Speaker 2:  to this one. A recap of Monday's match between Christopher Eubanks and
Speaker 2:  Stefanos Cepa.
Speaker 5:  Eubanks plays Tootsie Pass for the first time in the car.
Speaker 2:  First of all it gets one of the two names just
Speaker 2:  wrong. And then that's all it says for like 30 seconds.
Speaker 2:  This is not commentary. Actually wait, this will be fun. Here
Speaker 2:  is every single thing the AI says throughout the rest of this.
Speaker 2:  Three and a half minute highlight clip.
Speaker 5:  Tootsie Pass wins the first set after Eubanks unforced backhand error
Speaker 5:  set. Number two, Tootsie Pass is forced into a backhand era, loses the second
Speaker 5:  set. Set number three, unable to return the forehand from Tittie Pass.
Speaker 5:  Eubanks loses the set break point opportunity for Eubanks. Eubanks
Speaker 5:  wins the set after Tootsie Pass. Cannot deal with his serve. Tittie pass
Speaker 5:  facing Breakpoint wins the Matchpoint defeating
Speaker 5:  Tootsie passed six games to four in the last set.
Speaker 2:  Did you get anything from that I mean? What is the point of this? It's not
Speaker 2:  commentary. I'm not really sure what it is. I am
Speaker 2:  very intrigued in general by the idea of AI commentary, which could have
Speaker 2:  access to data and insights and real time knowledge
Speaker 2:  that even the best humans can't see. But this ain't it
Speaker 2:  folks. Oh wait, one more thing on this and then we will actually get to the
Speaker 2:  show. Today's Vergecast is not about Wimbledon I promise, but the
Speaker 2:  most actually commentary ish thing the AI has done
Speaker 2:  for me, at least in the highlights I've seen so far was in a match with Andy
Speaker 2:  Murray from a few days ago where it completely spoiled the play that was
Speaker 2:  coming like three shots before it happened.
Speaker 5:  Penton hits a backhand winner on Game point.
Speaker 2:  It's really ridiculous, right? AI has lots of potential in
Speaker 2:  lots of areas. We're gonna talk about some of it today, but it is definitely
Speaker 2:  not stealing any commentary jobs just yet. Anyway, let's get to
Speaker 2:  the show because it's a good one. We're gonna talk about all the new stuff
Speaker 2:  in Apple's new betas because we're probably getting public betas soon, which
Speaker 2:  means you'll be able to download the new software if you want to and there's
Speaker 2:  lots of interesting stuff coming to phones and tablets and watchOS and TVs
Speaker 2:  and all of Apple's devices. We're also gonna talk about how we talk about
Speaker 2:  ai, LLMs chatbots and all this other
Speaker 2:  vocabulary we've had to learn these last few months. And we're gonna talk
Speaker 2:  about the video games we're most excited about this summer because there
Speaker 2:  are a lot of them. All that is coming in just a sec. But first I
Speaker 2:  just heard that a tennis player named Andre Rublev did like the coolest shot
Speaker 2:  anyone has ever seen. Let me watch this real fast.
Speaker 1:  He can't believe it and we can't either. The crowd up.
Speaker 2:  See now that is commentary. Oh, and in case you were wondering, I
Speaker 2:  went back and just watched the AI highlight and it had literally nothing
Speaker 2:  to say about that point. Great job Watson. Cool future we're living in.
Speaker 2:  This is The Vergecast. We'll be right back.
Speaker 7:  That is one of the great shots we've seen here in years to get
Speaker 7:  him to match point.
Speaker 8:  I'm Lisa Ling, a journalist and host and
Speaker 9:  I'm Ho Lee But. you may know me as chow on the Max original series Warrior
Speaker 9:  based on the writings of Bruce Lee
Speaker 8:  After. every new episode, join us here. Ho and I and a
Speaker 8:  series of special guests are going to discuss how the show is made.
Speaker 9:  So, Stream, Warrior, season three starting June 29th only on Max
Speaker 9:  And. join us here or wherever you listen to podcasts
Speaker 10:  On criminal, we bring you true crime stories told by
Speaker 10:  people who know them best.
Speaker 11:  We didn't believe in setting fires cause that was too dangerous. We were,
Speaker 11:  you know, a kind, a gentler kind of crooks so to speak.
Speaker 10:  So the best plan you had was that you'd LaSow it?
Speaker 12:  Yes. Never imagined I'd use it for a camel.
Speaker 10:  I'm Phoebe Judge and this is criminal. Did you have to say what
Speaker 10:  was in the box
Speaker 1:  Phoebe? We told lies.
Speaker 10:  Listen to criminal every week, wherever you get your podcasts.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back First up. Today we're gonna dive into all of the new
Speaker 2:  Apple software coming to your devices this fall. The developer betas have
Speaker 2:  been out for a while, so people who make apps can learn how to use the new
Speaker 2:  features and tools and we're pretty sure the public beta is coming soon as
Speaker 2:  well. So we figured we'd go through the stuff that matters, the stuff that's
Speaker 2:  unexpectedly good and bad and somewhere in between and what you can
Speaker 2:  expect either on the beta or this fall when you get the updates.
Speaker 2:  We got a bunch to do. So let's get to it.
Speaker 2:  First up, let's do watch OS with V Song. Hi V.
Speaker 13:  Hi.
Speaker 2:  We're gonna talk about watch OS 10.
Speaker 13:  Yes, the the great old watch OS 10.
Speaker 2:  Which Apple build as, what was it the biggest change to watch OS
Speaker 2:  since watch OS?
Speaker 13:  It was billed as a milestone and having used it for
Speaker 13:  a couple weeks, I get why, but just on the surface it kind
Speaker 13:  of feels like a mm, I think we should redefine what
Speaker 13:  milestone is like at ww d c I was like, what
Speaker 13:  milestone? It's just widgets. But having used it, it's, oh,
Speaker 13:  it's widgets. It's widgets all the way down.
Speaker 2:  Oh, interesting. Tell me more. What like what does it actually change about
Speaker 2:  how you use the thing? A little
Speaker 13:  Bit of everything. It's one of those significant but subtle
Speaker 13:  changes like I can now use watch faces that don't have
Speaker 13:  complications on it and not feel like I'm missing out, which for me is
Speaker 13:  huge because I aesthetically don't love the look of
Speaker 13:  modular duo or like modular, which is my go-to watch face.
Speaker 13:  Yep. But you know, I have them because I'm a data
Speaker 13:  girly, I need to see everything. I need to access my complications, I need
Speaker 13:  things now, I need it yesterday and widgets allows me to use something
Speaker 13:  like this little Snoopy guy, which by the way, Snoopy watch face,
Speaker 13:  they undersold that. But basically the widgets allow
Speaker 13:  me to use all these watch faces that I felt were not
Speaker 13:  available to someone like me before. So you basically get a lot
Speaker 13:  more personalization because of the widgets. And I actually liken it
Speaker 13:  to kind of reading Chinese and Japanese versus English because you can
Speaker 13:  absorb so much more, more quickly with a
Speaker 13:  widget than you can with a tiny little complication or even just a little
Speaker 13:  thing on your watch face. You can see it and go like, oh I now know the
Speaker 13:  weather conditions for the next six hours in an instant. Which you
Speaker 13:  know, it's wild. you know, widgets are not a revolutionary concept on
Speaker 13:  smart watchOS where OS has them, their tiles, whatever they wanna call
Speaker 13:  their particular brand of widgets. It makes a lot of sense
Speaker 13:  to have. But watch OS has kind of been fumbling
Speaker 13:  along without it since watch OS three I believe. So it's, it's kind of
Speaker 13:  odd to see it come back and it's like dominoes because you've added
Speaker 13:  widgets. Everything else needs to change in small subtle ways. So it's,
Speaker 13:  it's really kind of been blowing my mind at how natural yet
Speaker 13:  different everything feels compared to watch at West Nine. So
Speaker 2:  The idea of the watch now, right, is that you have your watch face and then
Speaker 2:  the stack of widgets kind of lives underneath it in sort of the the like
Speaker 2:  mental model of the software, right? And so you do, you swipe up, do you
Speaker 2:  scroll the, like how do you get to the widgets?
Speaker 13:  You can either swipe or scroll up. So what you would use to do to get to
Speaker 13:  control center now will bring you the smart stack of widgets
Speaker 2:  Much better use of the space underneath than control center.
Speaker 13:  Yeah, well control center you still have it. You just basically have to
Speaker 13:  hit the slide button, which makes more sense when you think about it.
Speaker 13:  But my muscle memory is completely effed up because
Speaker 13:  I'm so used to doing things a certain way that now I'm always like, oh no
Speaker 13:  wait, if I wanna find my phone because I used the find iPhone button like
Speaker 13:  20 times in a day, I never know where my iPhone is. Like if I wanna
Speaker 13:  use that I have to hit the side button. But now I'm bringing up widgets
Speaker 13:  and just, oh like oh I appreciate the widgets but that's not what I wanted.
Speaker 13:  So it's that type of small change that is
Speaker 13:  really big when you think about it. But like that's just cuz I've been
Speaker 13:  using Apple watchOS for forever. If you're new to it, you'll get used to
Speaker 13:  it a lot faster than I am.
Speaker 2:  That's fair. So the big thing I've been wondering about watch OS 10 is
Speaker 2:  the thing I do probably more than any other activity on my watch
Speaker 2:  is just like play and pause stuff that's like the
Speaker 2:  most I touch my watchOS is if I'm like walking And I want to like change
Speaker 2:  the song or go back in a podcast, part of the reason I like the watch is
Speaker 2:  I don't have to dig into my pocket. I can just, you know, hit the thing.
Speaker 2:  Are the widgets interactive? Do they work that way in that you
Speaker 2:  can like I can just scroll up and hit pause in the pocket cast widget and
Speaker 2:  this'll solve all my problems.
Speaker 13:  Well right now I can't answer that fully because all the widgets are
Speaker 13:  apple widgets. Yeah, it's all for the Apple native apps.
Speaker 13:  We'll have to see what third parties do with it. But there is one
Speaker 13:  widget that's basically three complications in one little widget
Speaker 13:  stack. So Oh that's neat. you know that's, that one's kind of neat. It took
Speaker 13:  me a while to figure out how I wanted to use it but I actually think that's
Speaker 13:  pretty cool. But widgets are both like instantaneous
Speaker 13:  information and an Appalachia in one. Okay. Which is interesting.
Speaker 13:  So it's like complications magnified and then at the same
Speaker 13:  time all the apps have been redesigned so the way you use apps
Speaker 13:  on the watch is going to change. So you can still do all of that pretty
Speaker 13:  quickly. It's just, I think the way you perceive and process information
Speaker 13:  in watch OS 10 is much different. It feels like an actual
Speaker 13:  mini phone app as opposed to like, let's just draw this phone
Speaker 13:  app from memory and make it small. It's a very, it's a
Speaker 13:  very subtle but significant change. Yeah. And I think that's kind of the
Speaker 13:  theme with watch OS 10 where you're really not going to notice
Speaker 13:  how different it is until you sit and think about it. Which is what
Speaker 13:  I've been doing while writing my preview.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, as as one does. Yeah
Speaker 13:  It was like, oh there's not much different. Actually wait this app is completely
Speaker 13:  changed. Like the weather app completely different. I love it. It's so,
Speaker 13:  it's so much better than it. It was because you know the weather app used
Speaker 13:  to just be like this giant screen that you scroll down and you're just like
Speaker 13:  endlessly scrolling cuz you wanna know the chance of precipitation now you
Speaker 13:  just like tap a thing and you switch to like, I guess I would
Speaker 13:  call it the precipitation tab and there it is and you can see for the next
Speaker 13:  12 hours like what your chance of rain is. It's, it very much feels like
Speaker 13:  a better adaptation of a phone app than it's ever felt like before.
Speaker 13:  Yeah,
Speaker 2:  Thank God we're getting rid of the everything you need. Just scroll forever
Speaker 2:  and ever on your wrist. That was not good App design, this is better.
Speaker 13:  There's so much less scrolling and yet I use the Digital Crown a lot
Speaker 13:  more. It's very weird. I don't understand why
Speaker 2:  This is how they get you v it's a revolutionary input device. It's,
Speaker 13:  It's the mouse of the Apple watch. I'm still
Speaker 13:  scarred by that from the Apple Ultra podcaster did. But it's,
Speaker 13:  it actually is more useful and more intuitive to use than it
Speaker 13:  has been because then previously I would just be like scrolling
Speaker 13:  and now it's just, it makes more sense to use it as I scroll between
Speaker 13:  the different screens of, of the different watch OS apps.
Speaker 13:  It's, I just can't wait to see what third party developers are gonna do
Speaker 13:  with it because whether or not watch OS 10 does well
Speaker 13:  overall I think it'll depend a lot on that because the app will
Speaker 13:  watch apps are fine. Like the workout app is basically
Speaker 13:  the same thing. It's just slightly easier to read but you know
Speaker 13:  it, you can just be a lot more creative with how you design the watch. Like
Speaker 13:  the activity app is completely different. The weather app is completely
Speaker 13:  different and the way I interact with those apps is much more
Speaker 13:  creative and free flowing than it would have been in the past.
Speaker 13:  So you know, you know me, I love my focus modes. I'm gonna go ham, I'm gonna
Speaker 13:  go ham on them. Love it. So that's, yeah but
Speaker 13:  Snoopy watch face totally underrated. Okay,
Speaker 2:  Well hard disagree but we'll, we'll save that for another time. This mostly
Speaker 2:  seems like good news. Is there anything that sucks about watchOS 10? Anything
Speaker 2:  you hate so far?
Speaker 13:  Nothing I hate so far. Just like I haven't
Speaker 13:  had as much time as I would like to get into the
Speaker 13:  fitness stuff just because it's mostly cycling. I am a public hazard on
Speaker 13:  a bike. I should not ride a bike so I'm gonna rope somebody in to give a
Speaker 13:  more informed opinion on that And. I haven't had a chance to go hiking with
Speaker 13:  it yet, so I can't tell you how good the maps are just yet. But
Speaker 13:  I guess if I were to hate something, I actually don't love
Speaker 13:  the way that they've changed your activity app in the sense
Speaker 13:  that they've grouped your trophies and badges in a slightly different
Speaker 13:  way. And it's kind of obnoxious to me. I don't, I don't love it.
Speaker 13:  It's weird.
Speaker 2:  That's one place where I like all the scrolling. I'm like, look at all this
Speaker 2:  cool stuff I did.
Speaker 13:  Oh it's, it's not like it's gone. It's just, you just, it's like switching
Speaker 13:  between tabs and a mobile app. You just hit something and there it is and
Speaker 13:  you can scroll a little bit to get more, more data. But it's just everything
Speaker 13:  is much faster with less scrolling. Like it just makes
Speaker 13:  sense when you use it. You just have to use it and you'll get what I mean.
Speaker 13:  But it's, it's very hard to describe is what I'm learning right now.
Speaker 2:  Fair enough. All right, well this is good news. This is better than I was
Speaker 2:  hoping for. I was kind of expecting when we came out of WWDC being like,
Speaker 2:  this doesn't seem like all that much but it sounds like it's, it all adds
Speaker 2:  up to something that's exciting.
Speaker 13:  Yeah and I'm telling you, you're wrong about the Snoopy one. It adjusts
Speaker 13:  to your day. It's very cool in ways that I did not expect. I
Speaker 13:  don't even like peanuts. I'm not a peanut head. I don't like Snoopy but
Speaker 13:  I like the, the watch face. It's very strange.
Speaker 2:  You're, you're a data girly but not a peanut head. This is what we're learning.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 13:  Data girly not a peanut head. That's me. I like it.
Speaker 2:  All right v thank you.
Speaker 13:  All right,
Speaker 2:  Next up. TV v OS, the Apple tv. Chris watchOS is here. Hi Chris.
Speaker 2:  Hello. Good to be back. I feel like TV v OS is
Speaker 2:  more exciting than it was advertised at wwdc. It turns out there's actually
Speaker 2:  like some stuff going on, right? What have you found so far? Yeah,
Speaker 14:  I agree. This seems to be one of the bigger years for T V O S in quite a
Speaker 14:  while. There's FaceTime obviously, which is one of those things that I kind
Speaker 14:  of feel like would've been nice during the pandemic but I guess better late
Speaker 14:  than never. Fair. So that's gonna be on there. And, I, guess Zoom and also
Speaker 14:  WebEx are gonna have their apps on Apple TV as well. So that's one of the
Speaker 14:  big ones. They redid the control center so it's a lot more dense with
Speaker 14:  information now and shows the stuff you actually want there. There's like
Speaker 14:  a sleep timer for your tv. If you're one of those people just, you know,
Speaker 14:  nods off during Netflix There you go, you can have six icons per row now
Speaker 14:  instead of five. And of course the most important thing is they have a lot
Speaker 14:  more screen savers. Those dazzling four K screen savers. How
Speaker 2:  Are the screen savers? Like you, I, I don't know if you're joking or not
Speaker 2:  when you say that's the most important thing but I genuinely believe that
Speaker 2:  is like the most important I, I don't know what it is about those screensavers
Speaker 2:  but there's something, it's those screensavers and it's Roku City on the
Speaker 2:  Roku. Yeah. That have like really solved the thing where I will just sit
Speaker 2:  and look at my TV and not watch it for long periods of time as a result.
Speaker 2:  Same are the new ones up to par with the old ones on, on Apple
Speaker 2:  tv.
Speaker 14:  So the new ones weren't in the first couple betas so I think there's gonna
Speaker 14:  be like a later edition. I see. But I can't wait and I'm very excited like
Speaker 14:  you, I don't know who does those, who's responsible for them but that should
Speaker 14:  be a story.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, whoever you are, you are please come on The Vergecast and tell us everything.
Speaker 2:  What have you been using that surprised you either in good and bad ways so
Speaker 2:  far?
Speaker 14:  I mean the control center is nice. It feels more like the iPhones now that's
Speaker 14:  easier to get around or get to your, your home scenes and your cameras and
Speaker 14:  whatnot or change profiles. So just a lot of like just very small quality
Speaker 14:  of life stuff. I mean Apple tv, just like the overall UX and like interface.
Speaker 14:  I'm still a guy who like likes the home screen of apps cause I know where
Speaker 14:  my shows are. Usually And, I can search if not or go to the TV app and up
Speaker 14:  next and all those things. But yeah, they didn't have to add a lot I feel
Speaker 14:  like. But they kind of did FaceTime. You can do like karaoke and see yourself
Speaker 14:  on the screen now with Apple Sing and all. Oh wow kinda stuff and even add
Speaker 14:  effects to it. How
Speaker 2:  Does the continuity camera stuff work? Have you been able to test it?
Speaker 14:  Yeah so you just start a FaceTime session on the TV and then you get like
Speaker 14:  a prompt on your phone right away that asks like can I use this phone for
Speaker 14:  continuity camera? Just like your Mac basically. And you say yes and
Speaker 14:  away you go.
Speaker 2:  What's the go-to strategy there? Do you sit on the couch and kind of hold
Speaker 2:  your camera, like hold your phone up to be the camera? Do you prop it up
Speaker 2:  somewhere? Like what's, what's the move here? Yeah I
Speaker 14:  Think you had to prop it on a table maybe. Okay. I mean maybe they'll sell
Speaker 14:  mounts cause they have like all the same stuff, you know like center stage
Speaker 14:  on those like auto zoom and pan things right. That kind of just focus on
Speaker 14:  you. You can put it pretty much wherever it should be able to do a decent
Speaker 14:  job just finding you and putting your people on the big screen, which is
Speaker 14:  pretty cool. And I must say.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, one of my theories this year is that the iPad
Speaker 2:  is turning into a sneaky great video conferencing
Speaker 2:  device in part because like you're talking about, you can use it
Speaker 2:  as a continuity camera thing for your tv. You can just set
Speaker 2:  it down in landscape mode on your coffee table
Speaker 2:  and it'll use center stage to follow you around And. I generally think center
Speaker 2:  stage is ridiculous and stupid and bad because no one wants their
Speaker 2:  webcam moving around as they talk on a video call. It's just distracting
Speaker 2:  and awful. But in a case like this it actually makes sense why it would exist
Speaker 2:  because it can kind of solve for some problems that exist. Yeah, for sure.
Speaker 2:  I'm very happy about that. Any new apps? You mentioned the Zoom and stuff
Speaker 2:  like are there, have you, have we heard anything from developers doing stuff
Speaker 2:  for TV OS yet? Any ideas?
Speaker 14:  Not a ton yet. There's more small stuff like there's VPN support now you
Speaker 14:  can use those right on the Apple tv. So if you care about security and privacy
Speaker 14:  like a lot of folks do, that's nice to have and a lot of small things. You
Speaker 14:  can actually find your remote now. Oh yeah. With your iPhone, which is another
Speaker 14:  blessing. There's no U one chip so it's not quite as precise as like a air
Speaker 14:  tag or whatever, but you can you know, find it easily enough, which is better
Speaker 14:  than before where you just had to say your prayers and go hunt for it.
Speaker 14:  But yeah, so far so good.
Speaker 2:  Yeah I'll take it. Is there anything, anything you don't like so far, anything
Speaker 2:  still missing or not working properly that it, the beta, at least from what
Speaker 2:  I've heard seems to be pretty solid for folks so far. Yeah, it's
Speaker 14:  Pretty good. It's a low stakes. Beta I mean it's not the same thing as like
Speaker 14:  putting like iOS 17 on your phone on your main iPhone or whatever. So if
Speaker 14:  you're gonna play around the tv it's a pretty safe environment to do it.
Speaker 14:  But yeah, so far so good. I'm looking forward to those screen savers and
Speaker 14:  seeing what else comes up over the beta cycle.
Speaker 2:  I like it. Yeah, the control center to me is like a sneaky big deal. I'm
Speaker 2:  excited that that one has turned out because Apple is desperate to figure
Speaker 2:  out how to make it like the hub of your home in all these interesting
Speaker 2:  ways and this is a good way to do it that isn't just put more
Speaker 2:  app icons onto your TV screen. Right. And, I think that that seems to
Speaker 2:  be they get getting that right. Right.
Speaker 14:  Yeah it's there if you want it. If you're a power user it's right there
Speaker 14:  and easy to get to If you just wanna ignore it, you can do that too and
Speaker 14:  just do whatever. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  I used an Apple TV for the longest time without realizing control center
Speaker 2:  was there at all. And. I actually have come around to thinking that's a big
Speaker 2:  win. Like that's actually how that should work.
Speaker 14:  Exactly. Yeah, same.
Speaker 2:  I like it. All right Chris, thank you as always. We'll talk to you again
Speaker 2:  soon.
Speaker 14:  Yes sir. Cheers.
Speaker 2:  Now let's do iOS 17 Allison Johnson's here. Hi
Speaker 2:  Allison. Hello. You have the hardest job in this particular segment,
Speaker 2:  which is just that you have by far the most to talk about because
Speaker 2:  iOS 17, I was just going through the list. There's actually a lot of new
Speaker 2:  stuff. Let's not get into everything. We have lots of time to
Speaker 2:  get into everything, but you've been using it so far and the question I'm
Speaker 2:  most curious about is in using the betas, what
Speaker 2:  have you found yourself using that's new most often? Like what has
Speaker 2:  actually sort of crept into your daily life of the new stuff?
Speaker 16:  It's a lot of little things. And, I. Think that's, yeah there's just a
Speaker 16:  huge laundry list of stuff that's updated like across
Speaker 16:  everything you can imagine. But some things that stick out to me
Speaker 16:  and they're not like glamorous or exciting but like the updates
Speaker 16:  to the keyboard, you can write a swear word now and
Speaker 16:  it doesn't just swoop in there and correct it for you.
Speaker 2:  I have found auto autocorrect is wrong much less often. Yeah. Than it
Speaker 2:  used to be. Yeah. And it might just be anecdotal, I might be paying more
Speaker 2:  attention than normal but the number of texts that I have sent with
Speaker 2:  autocorrect mistakes has gone way down.
Speaker 16:  Right. I feel like I'm fighting it less. Yeah. Where you're constantly having
Speaker 16:  to go back and be like, ah no that's not what I wanted to write. There's
Speaker 16:  like extra little tools in there where it underlines something that it changed
Speaker 16:  so you're less likely to like send the text and be like, oh my god I that's
Speaker 16:  not what I meant to say. Just like little, little pleasant things
Speaker 16:  throughout the keyboard that will be hard for anybody to really
Speaker 16:  like identify even or be like wow this is a
Speaker 16:  great new experience but it's just nicer. One that I know
Speaker 16:  we're both fans of is standby. Yes. Which is a
Speaker 16:  delightful little feature where you start charging your
Speaker 16:  phone, turn it sideways and it turns
Speaker 16:  the display into like a little clock or there's a couple options
Speaker 16:  like a calendar with some widgets and the idea is you
Speaker 16:  put it on kind of your nightstand and it's there for you when you
Speaker 16:  wanna check the time in the middle of the night. It's so
Speaker 2:  Nice. I really like it. There's a version of standby that you can basically
Speaker 2:  just use as a photo viewer and the aspect ratio is not amazing.
Speaker 2:  Right. Cuz you're basically on a like long short screen. But
Speaker 2:  it's great. I just set it up to show my photos, And I, just have a photo
Speaker 2:  viewer that sits there while my phone charges. Yeah, it's awesome. It's
Speaker 16:  So nice. I love that. Works with any charger, you can use wired charging,
Speaker 16:  you can use MagSafe, you can use whatever wireless charger you have lying
Speaker 16:  around that's just like kind of un apple and lovely.
Speaker 16:  I know, right? Yeah. So thanks guys. One that surprised me I was not
Speaker 16:  expecting the like as much as I do is the new kind of
Speaker 16:  interface for stickers. Okay. Gotta admit I don't use
Speaker 16:  stickers a lot, but in IO 17 you can,
Speaker 16:  you know how in IO 16 you could do those like image cutouts of someone
Speaker 16:  from a photo or
Speaker 2:  Yeah. You just long press and it like pulls out. Yeah, whatever the thing
Speaker 2:  you're talking about is. Yeah,
Speaker 16:  Yeah. Takes it outta the background. Everyone was like, this is cool, what
Speaker 16:  do I do with this now you go, there's just an option right there
Speaker 16:  to turn it into a sticker and you can go into your iMessage chat and
Speaker 16:  you can put that sticker all over the chat like just on
Speaker 16:  any message and it'll show up for everybody where you put it
Speaker 16:  and you can turn a live photo into a sticker now too.
Speaker 2:  That's awesome. I didn't know that actually is genuinely useful.
Speaker 16:  It's fun. It's like a great new way to annoy your
Speaker 16:  partner, which is I'm using it, I'm
Speaker 2:  A big believer in anything that makes it so I can respond to a
Speaker 2:  text message in like two taps. Yeah. Like the tap back
Speaker 2:  stuff is so good for that reason and having a bunch of stickers where I can
Speaker 2:  just like anytime we're talking about the dog, I can just like press the
Speaker 2:  dog sticker and just boom, there it goes. Love that. Yep. Into that. What
Speaker 2:  have you seen with the phone call stuff so far? Obviously this'll be easier
Speaker 2:  to see once more people have iOS 17, but there's the contact
Speaker 2:  posters, there's the live voicemail stuff. Any, anything jump out to
Speaker 2:  you in that space so far?
Speaker 16:  Yeah, I played with contact posters a little bit. It's very much like the
Speaker 16:  lock screen on Iowa 16. Same kind of deal.
Speaker 2:  Did you pick a photo or AMO for your contact poster?
Speaker 16:  Oh I did a photo. I can't do an emoji. I don't know, I think I'm too old
Speaker 16:  or not old enough or like I'm in a middle ground where like I
Speaker 16:  missed emojis. But yeah, it's a lot of pressure. It
Speaker 2:  Really is a lot of pressure. I spent a long time setting mine up.
Speaker 16:  Yeah. I have like three different ones that I'm like, maybe I'll be on a
Speaker 16:  different mood and I'll pick a different one. So those will be fun. It'll
Speaker 16:  be really interesting to see like who adopts it and what the uptake rate
Speaker 16:  is is like everyone gonna have a contact poster all at once so that that
Speaker 16:  one will get, I think more interesting as the beta rolls out and the full
Speaker 16:  release comes. But the live transcription on
Speaker 16:  voicemail a hundred percent love it. I'm never picking it by phone
Speaker 16:  again. Like this is, this is what I need and it, it's
Speaker 16:  should mention that Google Pixel phones do a similar thing where the
Speaker 16:  assistant will kind of be like, this person is using a screening
Speaker 16:  service, what are you calling about? But I kind of love the Apple. It's
Speaker 16:  just like you're just leaving a voicemail and then you can just
Speaker 16:  like spy on what they're saying as they say it.
Speaker 2:  It is really good. It works surprisingly seamlessly too. I've had a couple
Speaker 2:  where I'm just straight up screening calls. It's like being in the nineties
Speaker 2:  again. It's the best. Yeah.
Speaker 16:  Oh it's so good. I had some robot call me about
Speaker 16:  Comcast offers And I was like, see ya. Nope.
Speaker 2:  Love that. Anything you haven't liked so far in, in the beta, I've had some
Speaker 2:  pretty real performance and battery issues, which is like
Speaker 2:  normal for a beta and so I'm not super worried about it. But have you had
Speaker 2:  any, anything that's jumped out to you in IO 17 You Don't like so far
Speaker 16:  Not terrible. I am running it, I've used it a little bit on a 14 pro,
Speaker 16:  but I have it on my own 13 mini. So when the battery life
Speaker 16:  is kind of crummy, I'm like, this could be because the battery life is
Speaker 16:  sort of crummy on my phone. But yeah. Yeah, just a couple of like
Speaker 16:  bugs and things, you know as we've observed getting onto
Speaker 16:  threads, like there's some weird bug where you couldn't post a photo but
Speaker 2:  The app would instantly crash every time you tried to post a photo on threads.
Speaker 2:  It's great.
Speaker 16:  Yeah, it was, it was fun. This is the first thing you do is get in there
Speaker 16:  like, I'm gonna post a photo. Nope. Yep. Try it again.
Speaker 16:  Yeah, no, overall it's been a really positive experience and
Speaker 16:  I'm, I'm excited. Like I'm excited for people to download it
Speaker 16:  and then they can see what I'm talking about. Cuz right now I'm just telling
Speaker 16:  my friends like stickers and they're like, what?
Speaker 2:  Yeah, this is that awkward time of year where you're sending people like
Speaker 2:  broken things that they can barely see. You're like, look at this sticker.
Speaker 2:  And they're like, what is this tiny image that you just sent me?
Speaker 16:  I kept trying to put them in Slack and they just look like the grossest
Speaker 16:  little PNGs where I was like, you guys have to trust me.
Speaker 16:  It looks cool.
Speaker 2:  All right, awesome. Well yeah, there's, there's lots more to talk about in
Speaker 2:  iOS 17, so we'll we'll have to come back to lots of this, but good luck with
Speaker 2:  betas and Godspeed as always.
Speaker 16:  Thank you.
Speaker 17:  The iPad,
Speaker 2:  The last one we should talk about quickly is iPadOS 17, which is the one
Speaker 2:  I've been goofing around with. I have it installed on an iPad Mini and an
Speaker 2:  iPad Pro. There are lots of little new things here. Most of them borrowed
Speaker 2:  from iOS 16 and 17. So if you use an iPhone, most of the stuff on the
Speaker 2:  iPad will not be surprising. But there are two things on the iPad that I
Speaker 2:  wanna mention. The first is the lock screen. iPadOS 17
Speaker 2:  lets you customize your lock screen mostly like you can on the iPhone with
Speaker 2:  different fonts and colors and stuff. But you also get a rail of lock screen
Speaker 2:  widgets on the left side, which is super useful and you can actually fit
Speaker 2:  a lot of widgets there because you just have more screen space. I would much
Speaker 2:  rather have more of them though since there's so much screen space here.
Speaker 2:  It's just kind of being unused, putting just the tiny widgets on the left.
Speaker 2:  Give me full sized widgets, give me the new interactive widgets on iOS
Speaker 2:  and iPadOS. Let me like really do stuff from my lock screen.
Speaker 2:  But hey, some widgets is better than no widgets, so I'll take it. The
Speaker 2:  other thing is stage manager. If you're a longtime Vergecast listener, you
Speaker 2:  know that last year when Stage Manager came out, I hated it. Like
Speaker 2:  hated it. Stage Manager is the multitasking feature that lets you switch
Speaker 2:  between collections of apps. So you can have a few things on the screen at
Speaker 2:  a time, but mostly it's buggy and bad and pointless. I don't know, I
Speaker 2:  don't get it. But this year Apple did make some big improvements. And I
Speaker 2:  still don't think it's great, but I at least see the potential. The big
Speaker 2:  change is that you can now move apps more or less freely around the screen.
Speaker 2:  They can be almost any size and go almost anywhere on your iPad instead of
Speaker 2:  just having to fit into these predetermined slots like before.
Speaker 2:  That alone makes it feel much more like actual multitasking and makes
Speaker 2:  Sage Manager way more useful. If you're the kind of person who uses their
Speaker 2:  iPad with a mouse and keyboard and external monitor, Sage Manager really
Speaker 2:  is for you. It's a decent system for managing multiple apps on multi multiple
Speaker 2:  screens and it's a lot better now than it was, but it's still
Speaker 2:  just awkwardly implemented on the iPad. You can't command tab
Speaker 2:  between stages, you can only have four apps in a stage. You can only have
Speaker 2:  one app in a single stage and you can't save stages as
Speaker 2:  they are. So everything just kind of ends up awkward and strewn about unless
Speaker 2:  you set up your stages and then never ever change them or download new apps
Speaker 2:  or anything. It's just still too much work for not that much gain. I
Speaker 2:  think I still don't plan to keep using Stage Manager, but I do at
Speaker 2:  least think there's maybe a future in the idea as Apple figures out ways
Speaker 2:  to integrate it more and more with the rest of the iPad. I still don't plan
Speaker 2:  to keep using Stage Manager, but I at least think there's maybe a
Speaker 2:  future in the concept as Apple keeps working to integrate it better and better
Speaker 2:  with the rest of the iPad. Otherwise, on the iPad there's a health app now,
Speaker 2:  which is nice. and iPadOS 17 actually does make the iPad maybe
Speaker 2:  the best PDF editing device I've ever used. It actually automatically
Speaker 2:  detects all the fields you can fill in and you can either just type or scribble
Speaker 2:  to fill it out. It's awesome. But mostly, you know, the iPad is
Speaker 2:  the iPad is the iPad. Alright, we gotta take a break and then
Speaker 2:  we're gonna come back and talk about how we talk about ai. We'll be right
Speaker 2:  back.
Speaker 18:  Hello, I'm Esther Perel. I'm a psychotherapist and host of the
Speaker 18:  podcast. Where should we begin? Relationships, expectations
Speaker 18:  are at an all time high and yet the norms
Speaker 18:  are less and less clear and we are literally making up the new
Speaker 18:  norms as we go. Whether it's your work relationships,
Speaker 18:  friendships or romantic relationships. I invite you
Speaker 18:  to enter into my office and listen in on my
Speaker 18:  sessions where I help people explore the challenges
Speaker 18:  and choices in their relationships. You will listen
Speaker 18:  intensely to them, but you will actually see
Speaker 18:  yourselves and in the process you become unstuck
Speaker 18:  and empowered in your own relationships.
Speaker 18:  Join me in my office every Monday morning for a new
Speaker 18:  episode. Listen and follow. Where should we begin
Speaker 18:  on your favorite podcast app?
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. One of the weird things that has happened over the last,
Speaker 2:  let's say nine months, is that all kinds of AI terms have
Speaker 2:  found their way into our vocabulary. GPT, LLM,
Speaker 2:  transformers, hallucinations, all these things that no reasonable
Speaker 2:  human knew about before are just words we use now, but Are,
Speaker 2:  we using them the right way and Does it matter how we use them.
Speaker 2:  As we talk about AI and as AI changes so fast, I
Speaker 2:  can't stop thinking about this. So I called up the verges James Vincent to
Speaker 2:  help me sort it out. Hi James.
Speaker 19:  Hi David. How are you doing?
Speaker 2:  I'm good. You're now three days into book leave on a very mysterious book
Speaker 2:  that you're not willing to tell anyone about. How's it going to you? Miss
Speaker 2:  is terribly already.
Speaker 19:  I miss you terribly. I wake up every day. I see things in
Speaker 19:  my feeds in my Twitter follows. I genuinely have been lurking on
Speaker 19:  Slack. I've had, this is so terrible. I've had Slack open. I'm already regretting
Speaker 19:  somewhat my decision to take leave, but I'm, I'm trying to make predictions,
Speaker 19:  write some stuff down now what I think is gonna happen the rest of the year
Speaker 19:  and then six months time I'll check in and be like, oh, did was
Speaker 19:  that right? Was that wrong?
Speaker 2:  Once you finished that list, come back on the show. I, we, we should do that
Speaker 2:  in public so we can shame you for this. But the reason I've dragged you here
Speaker 2:  today is because I want to talk about how we
Speaker 2:  talk about AI And, I've been thinking about this for a while, but this has
Speaker 2:  really sparked for me listening to a podcast a couple of weeks ago where
Speaker 2:  they had this otherwise very interesting conversation about ai, but
Speaker 2:  kept talking about it in just the worst ways. And it was talking about like
Speaker 2:  when you do something with the ai and it just, it makes me cringe every time
Speaker 2:  that happens. And then I've been reading all this stuff and we're using all
Speaker 2:  these terms like AI and machine learning and LLMs
Speaker 2:  and chat GPT and chat bots and all this stuff just becomes
Speaker 2:  so sort of interchanged to the point of being meaningless.
Speaker 2:  So what I wanna do here with you, my, my British pedantic
Speaker 2:  friend is try and sort this out a little bit because I actually think it's
Speaker 2:  really important we're in this moment where this stuff is moving really fast
Speaker 2:  and it's so transformative that I actually think the way we talk about it
Speaker 2:  matters. And so I want to just not exactly like
Speaker 2:  define terms, but I want to just sort of think through how we talk about
Speaker 2:  this stuff. Does that sound good? Is that a good plan?
Speaker 19:  Yeah, perfect. Loved it. Love to be
Speaker 2:  Pedantic. I love it. So let's just literally start with the term ai, which
Speaker 2:  is a thing we force ourselves to use and have to use all the
Speaker 2:  time. It gets used for everything. It is, it is like so
Speaker 2:  broadly defined as to be almost sort of meaningless now. Mm.
Speaker 2:  I it's not quite a technical term because it's like
Speaker 2:  just to call something the AI is to refer to like the code, which is just
Speaker 2:  not how we talk about things. But I am curious, like as you think about
Speaker 2:  what you mean when you say AI at this point, both for you as a reporter
Speaker 2:  reporting on this stuff, and for you as just a person in the world living
Speaker 2:  with this stuff, where does it fit into kind of your vocabulary
Speaker 2:  correctly?
Speaker 19:  You are completely right in that the definition of AI is so diffuse as to
Speaker 19:  be sort of useless. It is such a broad term. It applies to so many
Speaker 19:  different specific applications, technological methods,
Speaker 19:  ideas, concepts, that it's very difficult to say
Speaker 19:  what it is. What I like to do is not think about necessarily
Speaker 19:  what the strict definition is, but think about how
Speaker 19:  we use it in terms of how it fits into other frameworks
Speaker 19:  and how we think about it conceptually. So you mentioned just now one of
Speaker 19:  the things you dislike is talking about the ai, like the AI did this, the
Speaker 19:  AI did that. I hate that too. you know, I, I've spoken to Verge staff
Speaker 19:  people about this And I. I, I try to sort of give a Verge
Speaker 19:  framework on it and there's no Official policy, but one of my
Speaker 19:  big no-nos for covering AI is anthropomorphizing the ai. And
Speaker 19:  that involves turning it into this discreet entity that happens when you
Speaker 19:  use the grammatical form. The AI and ai, AI did this.
Speaker 19:  So I, I don't really mind the term. I know some people,
Speaker 19:  some researchers are really critical of it and they're like,
Speaker 19:  you know, they put artificial in and intelligence in, in inverted commerce
Speaker 19:  and they, you know, they really hate seeing it used And I. I respect that
Speaker 19:  as a viewpoint, but it is not the one I think is the right approach
Speaker 19:  because I think that has to be a language for people who are
Speaker 19:  non-experts to talk about this stuff. And AI has become the phrase we use.
Speaker 19:  Fine, let's just go with it. If we've accepted it is the phrase we use,
Speaker 19:  then what becomes important is yes, as I say, how we conceptualize it. So
Speaker 19:  we don't want to anthropomorphize it, we don't want to give it agency
Speaker 19:  when it has none. So we can, I think we can talk about AI as much as we
Speaker 19:  like and we can talk about what people are doing with it. But that is the
Speaker 19:  thing. Yeah, we need to remember how it is being used and who is ultimately
Speaker 19:  responsible for it. you know, there's that great, been a bit of a
Speaker 19:  meme on Twitter for a while, a presentation card from an IBM
Speaker 19:  sort of slideshow given to management in the 1970s. This is a great old
Speaker 19:  looking presentation card, old sort of courier type font being used. And
Speaker 19:  it says, machines must never make a management decision because
Speaker 19:  machines can't be held responsible for management decisions. Something like
Speaker 19:  that. Mm. I think something similar applies to AI
Speaker 19:  in that we may say casually AI is doing that or AI is
Speaker 19:  doing this, but we need to remember who put those systems in place, who
Speaker 19:  bears responsibility. you know, we live in a society where
Speaker 19:  machines cannot be responsible, humans can be responsible. And
Speaker 19:  if there is to be justice, if there is to be, you know, a, a sort of
Speaker 19:  fair, a fair society to live in, then we need to remember the humans at
Speaker 19:  the heart of it, not ai. So that's, that's a terribly
Speaker 19:  conceptual over the top approach to that question. But in short, I don't
Speaker 19:  think definitions matter so much as the context sheet that you put those
Speaker 19:  terms in. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  No, I think, I think that makes a lot of sense. And, I think as we talk about
Speaker 2:  the ai, I've come to think of it as sort of synonymous with like the technology
Speaker 2:  that it's, it's a thing that you use if you don't sort of immediately further
Speaker 2:  define it, you're just telling on yourself as somebody who doesn't understand
Speaker 2:  what the hell you're talking about. Because what it is is like technology
Speaker 2:  is not a thing, it's an umbrella term for lots of things, right? And, I think
Speaker 2:  AI is the same way. Like AI is not a thing, but it is, it is
Speaker 2:  a category of things. But if you're gonna talk about it, you have to then
Speaker 2:  talk about the more specific things right away or else I'm just gonna
Speaker 2:  assume you have no idea what you're talking about.
Speaker 19:  Yeah, I agree with you. You, you, you, it's fine. You can use the term and
Speaker 19:  maybe you're against using the term.
Speaker 2:  No, I, I'm actually with you in the sense that I think there are lots of
Speaker 2:  interesting arguments to have been made a very long time ago about whether
Speaker 2:  artificial and intelligence are the right words at this point. I think it's
Speaker 2:  like the, the toothpaste is outta the tube. It almost doesn't matter. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  That just is the term And I think. My hope would be that we kind of get to
Speaker 2:  the point where AI is like, it's like s a t or MTV
Speaker 2:  in that kind of the original definition gets lost and then AI just means
Speaker 2:  AI and we all kind of know what it means. But artificial and intelligence
Speaker 2:  doesn't really matter anymore. But again, I think I'm with you in the sense
Speaker 2:  that like the time to have had that debate was a long time ago and it's over
Speaker 2:  and it really doesn't matter anymore.
Speaker 19:  Yeah. And, I I mean that I think there is one argument to make perhaps that
Speaker 19:  AI is in many ways a fitting term in that it is as diffuse
Speaker 19:  as the entity it describes in the world. And it also
Speaker 19:  reflects and embodies grammatically the problems we have
Speaker 19:  talking about ai. you know, AI is a difficult thing to describe
Speaker 19:  cause it is so multi formed. It has so many different variations
Speaker 19:  and in a way just doing what we're doing now, I'm gonna give both of us
Speaker 19:  a big pat on the back right now. There we go. you know, talking about this
Speaker 19:  stuff is useful. It puts it in context. People think about it in you, obviously
Speaker 19:  the, you know, the, the worst, not the worst sin, but the sin with using
Speaker 19:  words every time you use them, no matter what you're talking about them,
Speaker 19:  is using them thoughtlessly and not thinking about the words you're using.
Speaker 19:  And I think if we think about them, we're okay. AI can be okay.
Speaker 2:  I like it On the AI front. The, the other one that I have come across a bunch
Speaker 2:  in trying to report about this is AI versus machine learning. And, I think,
Speaker 2:  yeah, they get used interchangeably in part because I think machine learning
Speaker 2:  is perceived to be the less kind of magical sounding version of it.
Speaker 2:  It's like, if you wanna make AI seem real, you just call it machine learning.
Speaker 2:  But that's not quite the right distinction, I don't think. Where
Speaker 2:  do you draw the line between those things? Are they synonymous with one another?
Speaker 2:  Yeah,
Speaker 19:  I mean, the thing is that like there are distinctions to be made. So you
Speaker 19:  could distinguish between machine learning methods and stuff like
Speaker 19:  expert systems methods, which, you know, were based
Speaker 19:  on creating ai, both of them fall under the AI category, but were more
Speaker 19:  about structuring and sort of hard coding. The rules that were being used
Speaker 19:  in these systems and expert systems had a vogue decades ago. And you know
Speaker 19:  what, they're still, they're still used now in many places. It's not, it's
Speaker 19:  not fair to say they've gone out of use, but it's been
Speaker 19:  overtaken by the learning quote unquote learning methods, the deep learning
Speaker 19:  methods, the machine learning methods which are more reliant on letting,
Speaker 19:  letting systems, you know, learn on their own, not on their own, but you
Speaker 19:  know, look at data and find rules in there under the guidance of humans.
Speaker 19:  I think machine learning is, it's used generally now, it's just like being
Speaker 19:  a little bit more fussy, a little bit more, as you say, a little no and
Speaker 19:  a little bit more correct as well to be like, well let's just take some
Speaker 19:  of the, let's just take some of the energy out the room. Let's take some
Speaker 19:  of the hype out of the room and call it machine learning instead.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. It's funny, you wanna remind people that this isn't some fake thing
Speaker 2:  that's happening. Yeah. It's just, it's just you're, you're just letting
Speaker 2:  machines do things for you. It's a reminder that like, this is just a thing
Speaker 2:  that happens on a computer, it's fine.
Speaker 19:  Yeah, a bit arguably it's also sort of inflationary in terms of what
Speaker 19:  it, what it draws our expectations from. you know, you talk about machines,
Speaker 19:  you think about physical machines, You don't often think about software.
Speaker 19:  That's one mistake and that plays into AI myths. You talk about learning
Speaker 19:  and then you imagine an autonomous system that is able to read
Speaker 19:  and engage with and analyze information in the same way as a human does.
Speaker 19:  But that's a poor illusion of terms as well because conceptually these things
Speaker 19:  work very, very differently. you know, and then you have the
Speaker 19:  sort of self-directed aspect of learning. And then we've had this
Speaker 19:  wonderful piece up on the site last week, Josh jeer this
Speaker 19:  fantastic piece looking at the huge amount of human labor that goes
Speaker 19:  into it. Yep. Is that machine learning, if you need to employ thousands,
Speaker 19:  tens of thousands of people around the world to click on pictures of fire
Speaker 19:  hydrants in captures day after day, you know, is that machine learning was
Speaker 19:  that human rule making turned into machine decision
Speaker 19:  making? So yeah, machine learning is to all intents and
Speaker 19:  purposes the less hyped way of saying ai.
Speaker 19:  But again, I think defining the term is perhaps less important than
Speaker 19:  the context within which you use them and talking about these other parts
Speaker 19:  of, of the systems.
Speaker 2:  Right? Yeah. I found myself trying to use machine learning less
Speaker 2:  unless I am specifically referring to a type of system
Speaker 2:  that is machine learning. Yeah. Because it is a thing that has a sort of
Speaker 2:  strict simple definition in how it is used in some of these systems.
Speaker 2:  And, I think I've definitely fallen under the trap of using machine
Speaker 2:  learning as, as the less sexy term for AI And. I'm trying not to do that
Speaker 2:  because I think it's unhelpful sometimes. What
Speaker 19:  Would you give as the definition for machine learning?
Speaker 2:  I, I think it's, it's what you said at the beginning, right? It is, it is
Speaker 2:  the, these automated systems by which a huge amount of training data is fed
Speaker 2:  in and algorithms run and they learn what fire hydrants look like. Right.
Speaker 2:  And, I think in frankly in my world, mostly covering products, I
Speaker 2:  have very little actual reason to use machine learning as a term. So
Speaker 2:  I'm just trying to use it less and less. Right. It's, it's, I think you're
Speaker 2:  right to say it is more useful as a way of talking about how these
Speaker 2:  systems are built than the actual output of these systems. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Which brings me to my next question, and this is the one that I have struggled
Speaker 2:  with the most as a reporter, which is terms
Speaker 2:  like LLM, large language model and GPT, which is generative
Speaker 2:  pre-trained transformers. These are things that if you had asked me a year
Speaker 2:  ago, would I ever use these terms in a story, I would've said, no, you're,
Speaker 2:  you're insane. Absolutely not, never and all at once. These feel like they
Speaker 2:  have become like mainstream terms. I don't think anybody knows what
Speaker 2:  GPT stands for, but I think everyone has heard the phrase chat GPT
Speaker 2:  now and it's just kind of in the lexicon now And I find myself wondering
Speaker 2:  like, are we good with this? Like, like are we just going to, are we gonna
Speaker 2:  get to a point where I can just say LLM and assume most of our
Speaker 2:  audience and most of the people in the world know what I'm talking about
Speaker 19:  I mean?
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 19:  The these, you know, oh God, this is a lovely conversation about language.
Speaker 19:  I love the, I love these sort of discussions. I'm sorry to be heard discursive
Speaker 19:  at them, but you know, I am very much a descriptiveness when it comes to
Speaker 19:  language word I, words are what we say they are and they are the context
Speaker 19:  they're used within GPT you are right. Has become this completely
Speaker 19:  denatured term. you know, I I made a joke when I had
Speaker 19:  my last day that you were guys were gonna train a language on model on all
Speaker 19:  my articles and you'd obviously replace me in my absence. And I. Oh yeah.
Speaker 19:  It'll be called James GPT. And GPT is a sort of suffix
Speaker 19:  now just means a program you talk to. Totally. It just means like a, a a
Speaker 19:  chatty program, which is very unusual and LLM is another one
Speaker 19:  in that, you know, the large in it is completely subjective as a value
Speaker 19:  in that the importance of having a large language model as opposed to
Speaker 19:  a small one. No, you know, no one you can speak to in AI will give you a
Speaker 19:  clear cutoff about what makes the difference between a large and a small
Speaker 19:  one. Especially as, you know, scales go up and down
Speaker 19:  and size itself, which is, you know, we measure a number of parameters.
Speaker 19:  The connections within the model has sort of become more and less
Speaker 19:  important. you know, there was this, obviously there was this push where
Speaker 19:  you would scale it up and we just got larger and larger models and now it's
Speaker 19:  sort of going the other way. And there are different methods of training
Speaker 19:  them using fewer parameters. So maybe the large isn't important at all.
Speaker 19:  And actually I think there's probably a good argument there to get rid of
Speaker 19:  large and just call them language models. And that is, to me,
Speaker 19:  usefully generalized as an approach. The underlying methodologies
Speaker 19:  advancing and mutating so rapidly
Speaker 19:  that any turn, any descriptive term, GPT or otherwise
Speaker 19:  is bound to become obsolete in a matter of months. But I
Speaker 19:  think GPT will hang on cause it's become a marketing term
Speaker 19:  and like ai, the point at which something becomes a marketing term, you
Speaker 19:  know, you may as well give up on a technical definition and then it just
Speaker 19:  becomes about, well, what type of story are you trying to tell? What information
Speaker 19:  do you need to give to your reader, whoever they may be. Yeah. you know,
Speaker 19:  I, I feel like chat GPT Neli has said this in the past. He just thinks it's
Speaker 19:  a awful name. Oh, it's
Speaker 2:  Objectively a horrendous product name. One of the things you're
Speaker 2:  making me realize with all of this is that we kind of don't have
Speaker 2:  middle-sized terms in AI right now. We either have these like
Speaker 2:  incredibly small descriptive things like large language model and machine
Speaker 2:  learning or GPT or we just call it ai. Mm Right. And there's like nothing
Speaker 2:  in between. And, I wonder if the thing in between is like, we'll end up just
Speaker 2:  calling it software because fundamentally it's just software created in a
Speaker 2:  different way. And like, we're pretty comfortable just calling things software
Speaker 2:  at this point. But it does occur to me that even as I'm describing this stuff,
Speaker 2:  like I don't have an answer to, if I'm not just going to refer
Speaker 2:  to it as a large language model powered chatbot, which is
Speaker 2:  messy, And I, think not how we should talk about this stuff forever. All
Speaker 2:  I call it is AI and that's too much And I. So I wonder like we're, we're
Speaker 2:  sort of stuck between these two polls for now, and And I wonder if our our
Speaker 2:  vocabulary needs some stuff in the middle. I think
Speaker 19:  That's a really good point. I I, I think something about the dilemma you
Speaker 19:  are describing is due to where we are in the product cycle. you know, I've,
Speaker 19:  I've been covering AI for not too long,
Speaker 19:  five, six years or something like that now. And before this last
Speaker 19:  year, the amount of products I talked about was fairly small. And I, you
Speaker 19:  know, I, it used to be a thing where I would, some archive paper
Speaker 19:  would be going around with some new sort of GaN technique involved with
Speaker 19:  image synthesis generation, whatever it was. And we'd write, we'd write
Speaker 19:  that up and we'd talk about whatever the specific name for that neural
Speaker 19:  network architecture was. But we would never really be important again.
Speaker 19:  And the realize was, was there was no continuity to those stories that term,
Speaker 19:  you know, unless it became a very successful model or approach like GaN
Speaker 19:  itself, which started off as this, you know, obscure,
Speaker 19:  well not obscure, you know, it became very popular very quickly. But
Speaker 19:  in terms of public knowledge, obscure term. And then, you know, I think
Speaker 19:  a few, many of our listeners would recognize the term GaN and know it has
Speaker 19:  something to do with image generation. But my story, my point is that when
Speaker 19:  we cross over from the research stage to the product stage
Speaker 19:  A, the idea of marketing gets involved and how you sell it. But B, you have
Speaker 19:  these known narratives about these technologies and that takes on a life
Speaker 19:  far apart from the research itself. And some
Speaker 19:  terminology sticks around. I think a really interesting example is
Speaker 19:  hallucinations. Yeah. So hallucinations for listen, listeners who are not
Speaker 19:  aware is a sort of name given to essentially the mistakes made by
Speaker 19:  language models. you know, you give them a question and they come up with
Speaker 19:  an answer that is, you know, not derived from anything directly in their
Speaker 19:  training data derived from the patterns within it. But it's wrong in some
Speaker 19:  way factually incorrect. And a lot of scientists, a lot of researchers
Speaker 19:  dislike the term hallucination because they think it
Speaker 19:  implies a mental model that is akin to a human mind.
Speaker 19:  Humans hallucinate, conscious beings, hallucinate machines do
Speaker 19:  not hallucinate, they just make mistakes. But I think that's a really interesting
Speaker 19:  example of how a term that starts off as something within the research world
Speaker 19:  then takes on this greater meaning. Cause it happens to
Speaker 19:  describe something that is very common to people using these products.
Speaker 19:  I love your suggestion that we need more middle terms, but I think,
Speaker 19:  again, another reason for this, apart from the fact that we're in the sort
Speaker 19:  of productization stage of this development cycle is
Speaker 19:  that actually a lot of attention is being focused on a relatively small
Speaker 19:  zoo of different technical animals as it were. you know, a lot of it comes
Speaker 19:  down to language models, the differences between them. If we wanna talk
Speaker 19:  about, you know, specific structures with how they're trained, it's really
Speaker 19:  just not relevant to the general population. you know, if we're talking
Speaker 19:  about the difference between how GPT three, 3.5, and four were trained,
Speaker 19:  we're talking about transformer heads and all this sort of stuff, tension
Speaker 19:  heads. I've definitely got one of those terminologies wrong. I apologize,
Speaker 19:  you know, this is what I mean. Like, but a lot of that stuff is really not
Speaker 19:  relevant unless you are, you know, you're sitting in a data center somewhere
Speaker 19:  or not sitting in a data center. You're just trying to train this stuff
Speaker 19:  yourself.
Speaker 2:  Right.
Speaker 19:  Are there particular areas of AI that you think we are deficient
Speaker 19:  in language to describe that we're missing terminology?
Speaker 2:  I think you're right that right now we're doing an okay job just because
Speaker 2:  there aren't that many things to do. But the thing that catches me the most,
Speaker 2:  the two things everybody thinks about with AI are sort of generative image
Speaker 2:  platforms. Yeah. And, I think that's a slightly messy term, but is at least
Speaker 2:  kind of understandable, right? It's like, use AI to make new art out of nothing.
Speaker 2:  I can sort of understand what that is. I suspect we'll have pretty good vocabulary
Speaker 2:  for that pretty fast. And then the other one is the chatbots. And I. Actually
Speaker 2:  think chatbots is like a fine term for that. It's, it, it may not be perfect,
Speaker 2:  but it works and everybody kind of understands what it is. And that's the
Speaker 2:  other side of things. The one where I get tripped up is like, I feel like
Speaker 2:  I read a hundred press releases every day that a company is like, we put
Speaker 2:  AI into our product. And I'm just like, what does that mean? Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And and to me it's like, I just read that now. It's like we put technology
Speaker 2:  into our products.
Speaker 19:  It's
Speaker 2:  Like, well congratulations. Like, I don't know, did we, is that anything?
Speaker 2:  And so I think, and that's where I get to the point where it's like, okay,
Speaker 2:  I think we, we might just need more words for this. Mm. And maybe
Speaker 2:  what'll happen is we'll get to the point where this stuff is just sort of
Speaker 2:  unsexy enough that we don't talk about it. It's like, it's like talking about
Speaker 2:  like you added a new file to your code base. Like it's, that's nothing
Speaker 2:  true. Right? And this was back when everybody was saying like, we're all
Speaker 2:  in on web three. And I was like, well what does that mean? Yeah. And they're
Speaker 2:  like, we don't know either. And so maybe this is just kind of how the hype
Speaker 2:  cycle works, but it does feel to me like we just need a
Speaker 2:  larger set of ways to talk about what it means to put
Speaker 2:  some of these tools into your product. Yeah. Because what you're not doing
Speaker 2:  is putting chat GPT or an image generator into your product. And if you're
Speaker 2:  not doing either of those things, we need a third thing to call it
Speaker 2:  And I. Just don't know what that is yet. But, okay. I have, I have two more
Speaker 2:  things. I have two more terms I'm gonna throw at you and then I'm gonna let
Speaker 2:  you go here. Sure. One is, where are we on Spicy Auto Complete
Speaker 2:  as a descriptor for some of this AI stuff? Oh, I've been seeing this for
Speaker 2:  months. I loved it at first. I like it less and less over time, but I wanna
Speaker 2:  know what you think.
Speaker 19:  Okay. So I mean, I think this is a, a, again, a fascinating example
Speaker 19:  of the limits, the benefits, the drawbacks of certain terms.
Speaker 19:  So auto complete as a way of
Speaker 19:  describing language models and their abilities. I actually, I
Speaker 19:  tweeted about this a few, a few months ago. Cause I was trying to, I was
Speaker 19:  trying to work out where the term Fast first started getting
Speaker 19:  applied to these And I, actually I think it was Robin Sloan, I don't know
Speaker 19:  if you know him at all. He is an author. He wrote Sourdough
Speaker 19:  Mr. Penumbra's 24 hour bookstore, but he also has a fantastic
Speaker 19:  newsletter. He does. And he's very like involved in technology. He's done
Speaker 19:  like a, he's got a side music project that uses ai, you know, he's been
Speaker 19:  experimenting with these tools for ages. His was the first instant I could
Speaker 19:  find of it being applied to language models, And I, think it was like 20 16, 20 17,
Speaker 19:  something like that a while ago. Then of course it became
Speaker 19:  attached to essentially criticisms of these models. I mean, and particularly
Speaker 19:  the, the, the, the Stochastic Parrots paper I think did a lot about
Speaker 19:  connecting these things. And because it got attached to
Speaker 19:  criticisms of these models, it's then become somewhat politicized term
Speaker 19:  within AI communities. And if you use
Speaker 19:  it, it can put you in camps, in people's mind, camps of
Speaker 19:  political or ideological belief or thought. So it's a very, it's a very
Speaker 19:  interesting term. And you know, if you, if you someone who derives language
Speaker 19:  models as just fancy auto complete or whatever it is, some people
Speaker 19:  in the AI community who let's just say, you know, are, are more likely
Speaker 19:  to believe in existential risk problems, for example, will be quite dismissive.
Speaker 19:  Or they can be quite dismissive cuz they'll think You don't fully understand
Speaker 19:  the qualities that these systems have. And the thing is, I think it
Speaker 19:  was a really useful term for a long time, it was a really useful way
Speaker 19:  of quickly explaining, I'm communicating, sorry, the
Speaker 19:  abilities of these systems and also something about the way they're trained.
Speaker 19:  you know, it, it is a statistical predictor that is definitely true. That
Speaker 19:  the problem with the term, and I'm still, I don't have a decision, I haven't,
Speaker 19:  you know, made a decision in my head about this, is that it doesn't quite
Speaker 19:  convey to people now the full capabilities of these
Speaker 19:  systems. Which, you know, you get something like the
Speaker 19:  famous Sparks of AGI paper, the one that came out from the Microsoft research,
Speaker 19:  And I say famous, also very controversial. A lot of people
Speaker 19:  disagree with the contents, the conclusions of that paper, which was basically
Speaker 19:  saying that GPT four had abilities in it, which were not
Speaker 19:  adequately described by our current mental models of language models. And
Speaker 19:  it was something perhaps closer to, as the title suggests, sparks of
Speaker 19:  artificial general intelligence. And I haven't come down at a sign on that.
Speaker 19:  I still think auto complete is a useful term in many contexts when talking
Speaker 19:  about language models. But it's also sort of lacking now because it does
Speaker 19:  underplay the fantastic breadth of
Speaker 19:  capabilities that these systems have and the fact that there may be,
Speaker 19:  you know, aptitudes within them that just don't
Speaker 19:  apply to our model of what auto complete software does. So I think it's
Speaker 19:  a term that we're gonna see phased out in the years to come because it's
Speaker 19:  been slightly lacking or perhaps it's a term that's gonna become increasingly
Speaker 19:  politicized and that using it will align you with one
Speaker 19:  or other political camp of beliefs or research camps and belief. But a really
Speaker 19:  fascinating term. Do you, do you like it still spicy auto to complete?
Speaker 2:  I liked it at first because I think it's a really helpful
Speaker 2:  kind of kindergarten level understanding of what's actually going on, right?
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Like, it's because everyone, everyone has had that experience and you
Speaker 2:  type something and it throws up the three options and sometimes they're insane
Speaker 2:  and sometimes they're great. And it's like, that is not a terrible metaphor
Speaker 2:  for what's happening in a lot of these systems. I think it's becoming an
Speaker 2:  incomplete enough metaphor is to not be useful very, very, very quickly.
Speaker 2:  So I I kind of like it less over time. And I agree. I think the way
Speaker 2:  that people use it has gotten, people are either very dismissive
Speaker 2:  when they use it, or very dismissive of people who use it. And I. Think both
Speaker 2:  of those are kind of annoying. And for that reason alone, I'm, I'm
Speaker 2:  ready to move on to something else. But as a, as a first run at making
Speaker 2:  this stuff really understandable to people, I think it kind of worked. It,
Speaker 2:  it, it got us, yeah, it got us six months of decent metaphors. So I I'm not
Speaker 2:  mad at it.
Speaker 19:  No, absolutely. I'm, I'm glad to hear we're staking out the radical centrist
Speaker 19:  ground here, David. Absolutely. We are annoyed by both people on both sides
Speaker 19:  of this argument.
Speaker 2:  I'm really the The Verge cast's Official position is, everybody should just
Speaker 2:  calm down for five minutes, I think.
Speaker 2:  But here's, here's one I suspect you And I will aggressively agree, agree
Speaker 2:  on, and then we can go, okay, which is the, the term magic to describe AI
Speaker 2:  like in magic eraser and magic editor and magic, whatever,
Speaker 2:  that needs to die in a fire as quickly as possible, right? Like,
Speaker 2:  yeah, we gotta stop with the magic. There's no magic here. I'm done with
Speaker 19:  This. There's no magic. We're good on
Speaker 2:  This. Right?
Speaker 19:  Well, but you know, when you deliver a product, David, David, listen to
Speaker 19:  me, listen to me for a second, Dave. When you deliver a product that uplifts
Speaker 19:  your customer's heart, that brings light to them, when they get rid of
Speaker 19:  that obnoxious pug dog that was learing at them in that family photo in
Speaker 19:  the background, is that not magic? Is that not a type of wizardry of
Speaker 19:  sorcery? No, you, sorry,
Speaker 2:  Did Johnny, I've just come into your room weird. How did that that was amazing.
Speaker 19:  Terrible. Yeah, but but the context, you've just described it within a purely
Speaker 19:  marketing context. So I think people already know that magic is
Speaker 19:  bullshit for want of a more polite term.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Yeah, that's fair. Hopefully it stays that way. All right, James, you
Speaker 2:  got a book to write? We need to take a break, but thank you as always. Thanks
Speaker 19:  Guys. Bye.
Speaker 2:  All right, we gotta take one more break and then we're gonna come back and
Speaker 2:  talk about all the video games. We cannot wait to play. We'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  We're back. So usually the gaming world has a couple of
Speaker 2:  big moments a year with the E three conference usually in June
Speaker 2:  being the biggest by far. But E three is no longer. So
Speaker 2:  instead we've had a string of announcements from Nintendo Sony,
Speaker 2:  Microsoft Ubisoft, there was the Summer, Game Fest and a bunch of others.
Speaker 2:  All detailing what's coming to a console and computer near you. This year
Speaker 2:  is actually a big year for games, it turns out. And it's a lot to keep up
Speaker 2:  with. So I asked the verges, Ash, Parrish and Polygons Chris Plant
Speaker 2:  to come on the show and tell me all the new stuff that they're most excited
Speaker 2:  about. Ash. Hi.
Speaker 20:  Hi. Great to be back.
Speaker 2:  It's good to have you back. And speaking of coming back, Chris Plant, welcome
Speaker 2:  back to The Vergecast. It's been a while. Hi.
Speaker 21:  Thank you. It's been six years, seven years. Obviously you missed me
Speaker 21:  and you're just so happy to have
Speaker 2:  Me listen, you were just here. I don't know, I, I opened up the link and
Speaker 2:  you were just here and, and we're scrolling with it. It's fine.
Speaker 2:  Okay. So the way we wanted to do this is basically there's been a lot of
Speaker 2:  video game announcements. There was no E three, so there was no one like
Speaker 2:  moment for video games and said, it's been the summer of video games, And
Speaker 2:  I. Just want to like rattle through some of the coolest stuff that people
Speaker 2:  have been talking about. So the way we set this up is the, the
Speaker 2:  homework we each had is we each had to come with two games that we
Speaker 2:  are excited to play this summer. Ideally brand new games. But if you wanna
Speaker 2:  cheat on that one, I'll allow it. And then two games you're excited
Speaker 2:  about coming this fall. So games you can't play yet, but will
Speaker 2:  before the end of the year. Are you guys prepared? Are you ready? Does this
Speaker 2:  sound like a plan?
Speaker 20:  This sounds like a tentative plan. I
Speaker 21:  Think we're gonna maybe be okay,
Speaker 2:  This is The Vergecast, maybe be Okay. Is the best we're ever gonna do. Great.
Speaker 2:  Let's start with this summer and we'll just, we'll just go around in circles
Speaker 2:  here. So Ash, you go first. What's the first game you're excited about this
Speaker 2:  summer?
Speaker 20:  So my first pick is Boulder's Gate three.
Speaker 20:  I am really excited about this game. It has been an early access for about
Speaker 20:  forever. I remember the first time it went to like early access, And
Speaker 20:  I got to play like an early build of it. And I've never played the Boulders
Speaker 20:  Gate games before. I kind of really haven't dabbled with like the, the
Speaker 20:  Dungeons and Dragons games that have been, you know, made into video games.
Speaker 20:  But Boulders Gate was like the first time I had a, an experience with a
Speaker 20:  game like that. And I loved it. It was really fun. I got
Speaker 20:  such a kick out of not like doing anything for like my class. I think
Speaker 20:  I played like a Paladin or something like that. I don't remember if that's
Speaker 20:  not one of the classes. Don't, don't at me on that. But I got more
Speaker 20:  fun out of like pushing people off of things and lighting
Speaker 20:  them on fire than I did doing anything else that was like
Speaker 20:  class-based because they just do so much damage and it's so much fun being
Speaker 20:  a little chaos gremlin that like pushes people off buildings and stuff like
Speaker 20:  that. So I'm really excited to see what a full version of that game looks
Speaker 20:  like, especially because there's romances, And, I haven't had a good game
Speaker 20:  with romance in it since Mass effect three. So I'm really
Speaker 20:  excited to get back into that like real crunchy
Speaker 20:  C R P G type experience that has like
Speaker 20:  50 million lines of voice dialogue and 20 million different things that
Speaker 20:  you can do. I am jazzed about that.
Speaker 2:  I love that. Chris, any feelings about boulders? Skate?
Speaker 21:  I mean, I'm just intimidated, you know, intimidated by what it could do
Speaker 21:  to me if I allow myself to enjoy a game like that. Because it's definitely
Speaker 21:  one of those games that you start playing I mean like, you know, I'll put
Speaker 21:  20 hours into it, that's a reasonable amount of time to play a video game
Speaker 21:  and then 300 hours later you're like, what did I do? Yeah,
Speaker 21:  yeah. you know, and, and that's not to say that's a bad use of time.
Speaker 21:  It just, it slips away. I, I, I played a little bit of
Speaker 21:  divinity, original sin too, same kind of game. And
Speaker 21:  yeah, it was definitely that thing where I
Speaker 21:  thought I had only played for 10 hours and it had been about 40 or 50.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. That feeling of, oh God, I cannot afford to lose my life
Speaker 2:  to this game is a running theme through all of my picks, which you will see.
Speaker 2:  Yes. Very shortly. But Chris, what's your first one? What are you excited
Speaker 2:  about this summer?
Speaker 21:  So I'm, I'm cheating and I'm using California summertime, which means
Speaker 21:  it goes to the end of October
Speaker 2:  And hasn't started yet.
Speaker 21:  Exactly. I mean definitely correct. So there is a
Speaker 21:  week in October that has like three huge releases. And I'll be picking two
Speaker 21:  from them. One of them is just a very old video game, which
Speaker 21:  is the metal gear solid master collection. Yes. Coming out on
Speaker 21:  October 24th.
Speaker 2:  Okay. Are we giving you that first? That feels like a October 24th is a
Speaker 2:  stretch.
Speaker 21:  I said the end of October. I, I created the rules and then I used the rules.
Speaker 21:  That's how this game works.
Speaker 2:  You were just here when I clicked the link, man. That's all, that's all I
Speaker 2:  know.
Speaker 21:  Here's why it matters. There are a bunch of like flashier games coming out.
Speaker 21:  Middle gear solid is one of the most important video game franchises in
Speaker 21:  the history of the medium. And you effectively cannot play it right now
Speaker 21:  legally. Hmm. And that is absolutely absurd. There
Speaker 21:  was a documentary at Tribeca Film Festival about he
Speaker 21:  kajima, he has new games coming up with death stranding too. And yet if
Speaker 21:  you wanted to go play Metal gear solid or metal gear solid two or
Speaker 21:  three or any of the original games, good luck. You will need to go get
Speaker 21:  an original system because they're no longer available on Windows
Speaker 21:  pc. They used to be on good old games and they're not on modern
Speaker 21:  consoles. It doesn't make sense how hard it is to
Speaker 21:  play these games. And this, this isn't exclusive to metal gear,
Speaker 21:  but I think it is kind of the shining example of video games.
Speaker 21:  Terrible habits of erasing or legally blocking out its
Speaker 21:  past And I am very glad that this is going to become available and then
Speaker 21:  everybody can play it and realize, you know what, dust ending's actually
Speaker 21:  a better game than all of them. So.
Speaker 20:  Oh, that's, that's big.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And this is, is it the whole collection coming to basically all
Speaker 2:  of the major platforms?
Speaker 21:  So this is Metal gear solids one, two, and three. Okay. And
Speaker 21:  some I believe like the Ns or
Speaker 20:  Metal gear, not the solid just metal gear.
Speaker 21:  Yes. Thank you. Thank you. But sadly, I do not think metal gear solid for
Speaker 21:  the Game. Boy color is part of this, despite being a delightful game
Speaker 21:  and metal gear solid four and five are not on this though. I think it's
Speaker 21:  pretty safe to assume that there will be a sequel collection in the next
Speaker 21:  year or two to make sure that people can buy those too.
Speaker 2:  And then he's and, and Kojima's very busy getting all his stuff to work on
Speaker 2:  a Mac. So it's gonna, it's it's all gonna be very exciting. It's all coming
Speaker 2:  up Metal gear. All right. My first pick is comparatively very small.
Speaker 2:  It's the new Mario Kart d l c for the Nintendo Switch Wave
Speaker 2:  five.
Speaker 2:  Mario Kart is the only game I can play for any amount
Speaker 2:  of time, whenever, for any reason and be very happy about it.
Speaker 20:  It's a very good appointment game.
Speaker 2:  Yes, that's exactly right. Yeah,
Speaker 20:  You can just sit down, pop in, have like a bespoke 20 minute experience,
Speaker 20:  get everything, like experience an entire gameplay loop and stop and
Speaker 20:  You don't have to worry about falling behind or anything like that. Mario
Speaker 20:  Kart is a perfect game for that.
Speaker 2:  And the thing that they've done really well is I feel like every Mario Kart
Speaker 2:  game before I've, I feel like I've sort of played through and then
Speaker 2:  it gets a little bit repetitive. And, I have to kind of take a break and
Speaker 2:  go, but they're, they're doing these waves at just the right cadence where
Speaker 2:  it's like, oh, I have a new character that kind of makes everything feel
Speaker 2:  new. And then, oh, there's a new course that makes everything feel kind of
Speaker 2:  new. And this one, there's a a handful of new characters and it's
Speaker 2:  going to give me endless reasons to play this game a lot
Speaker 21:  More. You buried the lead comic Yes. Is one of the new Cam
Speaker 21:  characters. And this is huge in the plant house because my five year old
Speaker 21:  thinks comic is the star of Mario. He's very misguided.
Speaker 20:  You know what? I would believe that, yeah, if I had not ever played
Speaker 20:  Mario, if I didn't know what Mario was, I would 100% believe that
Speaker 20:  because this is the guy that comes in on like the cloud, right? He's Bower's
Speaker 20:  Herald. Right. This is the first person who shows up and is like given
Speaker 20:  this like outsized importance. He he is, he's talking to you. I would 100%
Speaker 20:  believe that your, your kid is 100% right and you can tell him I said that.
Speaker 20:  Wow.
Speaker 2:  That's kind of deep, honestly. Like I was about to come out firing about
Speaker 2:  how wrong that opinion is, but I think you might be right. I take it back.
Speaker 2:  All right. Ash, what's your next one for the summer
Speaker 20:  Ghost Trick? Oh,
Speaker 20:  ghost Trick is a switch game. It's kind of like, like a, like a
Speaker 20:  phoenix right kind of game where you go through and you have to like solve
Speaker 20:  mysteries and things like that. And this has this weird mechanic where like
Speaker 20:  you're a ghost and you have to stop people's untimely deaths and you have
Speaker 20:  like these weird Rube Goldberg like device way of going about
Speaker 20:  that. And I'm looking forward to getting into that cause that looks like
Speaker 20:  a fun, nifty little game that'll scratch that Ace Attorney itch.
Speaker 2:  I had not seen this before. And, I'm looking at it now and also has this
Speaker 2:  amazing kind of retro animation style that I'm very into.
Speaker 21:  Yeah, yeah. For people who wanna try it right now it's on iOS
Speaker 21:  and yeah, it is a delight. All
Speaker 2:  Right, well I'm gonna have there, there goes my summer. Chris, what's your
Speaker 2:  second one?
Speaker 21:  I'm gonna follow the rules this time. My pick is my house
Speaker 21:  dot wa or my house dot wad
Speaker 21:  and it is a mod for Doom. Oh, And I am just targeting The
Speaker 21:  Verge audience.
Speaker 2:  Wait, tell me everything about this. I don't know about this.
Speaker 21:  It is an absolutely bonkers mod that in the
Speaker 21:  cannon of the Forum post where it was published, two friends
Speaker 21:  were making it in 1999 and then they grew
Speaker 21:  apart. And more recently one of those friends passed away.
Speaker 21:  So the friend who is still alive found this mod that they were working on
Speaker 21:  and decided to like touched up and just released it out onto the world.
Speaker 21:  And it is just their house. It is, it is the,
Speaker 21:  the pass away friend's home that is not the mod at all. And
Speaker 21:  you should keep playing it. It is a very different
Speaker 21:  thing and it is, it is the kind of like prize,
Speaker 21:  you know, nesting doll toy. Is it Inscription?
Speaker 20:  Is it like inscription?
Speaker 21:  I mean as somebody who like inscription after the first act, I would say
Speaker 21:  it's better than Inscription. Oh you know what, that's okay. I admire Inscription
Speaker 21:  a lot. I think the, the first third of that game is, is fantastic. But I
Speaker 21:  think what this is doing is I hate doing
Speaker 21:  a Lynchian thing because that is such a meaningless comparison, but
Speaker 21:  it is not trying to ascribe a meaning to every
Speaker 21:  decision that it makes. It is I think a lot looser and more playful
Speaker 21:  than that, which is why it's a mod not a retail game because it probably
Speaker 21:  would make a total of $5,
Speaker 2:  But instead just show up for random insanity and see what happens. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  I love that. I do really appreciate it. I'm just reading about this now and
Speaker 2:  one of the things that says is are you expecting to battle demons? Yes, this
Speaker 2:  will happen, but first you must uncover the secrets of what seems to just
Speaker 2:  be a suburban house.
Speaker 21:  Yes.
Speaker 2:  Sounds amazing.
Speaker 21:  That does sound
Speaker 20:  Amazing, especially because this is in Doom
Speaker 2:  Sold. I'm in, I will play this.
Speaker 21:  Can I give you like one little spoilery thing? Sure. This is like no story
Speaker 21:  or anything. There is a point in the game where you come across two dogs
Speaker 21:  and one of the dogs is like a three-headed hell beast with
Speaker 21:  like borderline infinite health and the other dog is like
Speaker 21:  a cute puppy with like two health and whichever one
Speaker 21:  you kill, it kills the other and that's the only way to move on.
Speaker 21:  Oh no. Which really puts a like choice on your
Speaker 21:  platter. Wow. Yeah, it's like I, it's not even a Charlie problem, it's just
Speaker 21:  an awful problem. I swear the game is not that dark
Speaker 21:  in general, but that that certainly Yeah.
Speaker 21:  It leaves a, a funky taste in the in the palette.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Real, real summer vibes coming outta that one my pick
Speaker 2:  because unlike the two of you I followed the rules is out now and it
Speaker 2:  is F 1 23 the racing game.
Speaker 21:  Oh wow.
Speaker 2:  Specifically because, well a, I love racing games, as you can tell
Speaker 2:  from my two picks so far, And I like them because I can just like
Speaker 2:  sit down for 10 minutes and do it like in between things or go somewhere
Speaker 2:  else. Like the main thrust of my life right now is I have a six month old
Speaker 2:  kid, so I get like 15 free minutes at various times. And, I'm like, I'm gonna
Speaker 2:  sit. I had a friend who bought me a steering wheel for these games. And I
Speaker 2:  love them. But F1 23 has this new mode called F1 World,
Speaker 2:  which is basically for anyone who's ever played like two K or
Speaker 2:  like FIFA ultimate team, it's one of those where you get to just like build
Speaker 2:  up your team and you play over time and instead of just like beating the
Speaker 2:  game over and over and over again, which most of these games just make you
Speaker 2:  do in career mode, this one you can just like hang out in the world and keep
Speaker 2:  racing and getting better and doing new things. Which again for me will keep
Speaker 2:  me interested much longer than just like trying to kind of
Speaker 2:  achieve the same goals over and over again. And people seem to really like
Speaker 2:  F1 world so I'm very excited about it.
Speaker 21:  Have you, you gotten into many of these th this always just seems so
Speaker 21:  intimidating. Intimidating not in the, I'll get sucked in forever. It
Speaker 21:  more intimidating in the like where do I even start? Yeah.
Speaker 2:  The challenge I have with these games is that if I don't get in
Speaker 2:  early, I'm so far behind everybody else. Like I've been playing
Speaker 2:  sports video games for a very long time. I'm like pretty good at most sports
Speaker 2:  video games, but I just don't grind. Like the people who
Speaker 2:  grind And I think this is true of sort of any competitive like Playto Pay
Speaker 2:  to win games to some extent. There's just like people with credit cards who
Speaker 2:  are just like buying their way to the top of all of these things. So I've
Speaker 2:  had to learn to just have a very zen approach. And I lose most of the time
Speaker 2:  and it's basically fine. Yeah. And I just like tell myself stories about
Speaker 2:  these all being teenagers with their parents' credit cards who are beating
Speaker 2:  me and I'm morally superior to them.
Speaker 21:  I had lunch at a friend's house last night and he is the person who is always
Speaker 21:  beating you in this game. Yeah. And I had no idea. These friends, they build
Speaker 21:  decks, And I didn't even know that they liked video games cuz they never
Speaker 21:  have talked about video games. And then he showed me his garage and he is
Speaker 21:  like, oh by the way, I do play one video game. I play
Speaker 21:  F1 and here's like a steel rig I built. Oh boy.
Speaker 21:  Like a like full, like it's like half their garage
Speaker 21:  and it's like, oh this is who this is. Who plays these games? Yeah.
Speaker 21:  It's like fighting game fans. They're like that hardcore.
Speaker 2:  I bought a steering wheel and like anchored it to my desk. And I thought
Speaker 2:  that was like very impressive. And then, and then I had the same experience.
Speaker 2:  People are like, here's the $10,000 rig with three giant
Speaker 2:  wraparound screens that I got. And I was like, oh you're gonna, you're gonna
Speaker 2:  beat me in all of our races, aren't
Speaker 20:  You? One of the things that I remember most about attending summer games
Speaker 20:  Fest last year was they had this like rig set up, I don't even remember
Speaker 20:  what game it is now. And I feel bad where you kind of like, it mimics sitting
Speaker 20:  in an F1 car so it's really low to the ground on the floor. Like
Speaker 20:  you're fully like recumbent and you use like your feet to press the pedals
Speaker 20:  and everything. And it like the, it had a line like really long for people
Speaker 20:  to try it out. And I just was so intimidated for trying it out because
Speaker 20:  Summer Games Fest, or at least what it was last year was like, it's this
Speaker 20:  open space where all these game demos are so people are like walking around
Speaker 20:  and you've got like Twitch influencers on those like little standing
Speaker 20:  like oh yeah Roomba things where they have like a Roomba attached to like
Speaker 20:  a screen. so like influencers who are not there can walk around the
Speaker 20:  floor and like look and like, oh this is cool. you know, that kind of stuff.
Speaker 20:  And there were so many people there with like cameras and stuff. And I was
Speaker 20:  just so super intimidated of getting in that thing and looking like an idiot.
Speaker 20:  That's so I never tried it even though I was deathly curious about it. And
Speaker 20:  that's one of my bigger regrets.
Speaker 2:  Those games are tough. They do a better job now of making
Speaker 2:  the racing simulators a little more sort of approachable to get into. But
Speaker 2:  like they're so accurate at this point that every time I
Speaker 2:  play one of these games I sit down and the very first thing I do is crash
Speaker 2:  my cart like 30 to 60 times.
Speaker 21:  So you're saying they don't send 30 streamers to your house with
Speaker 21:  video cameras to Shane, that's no. Great, great,
Speaker 21:  great thing. I'm on board now.
Speaker 2:  All right, let's shift and go to this fall, which I guess for
Speaker 2:  Chris Plant means the months of November and December. Yeah. But any, any
Speaker 2:  game that's not out yet or won't be out until the end of the summer, we'll
Speaker 2:  we'll say is fair game here Ash, what's your first one?
Speaker 20:  So this is what I was holding onto from the previous segment thing
Speaker 20:  that I'm looking forward to the most that is supposed to come out by
Speaker 20:  the end of 2023 is Sonic Superstars.
Speaker 20:  Big huge Sonic fan. I was jazzed as hell to see
Speaker 20:  that they're making another 2D Sonic
Speaker 20:  Platformer. I'm not really a big fan of the 3D Sonic platforms.
Speaker 20:  Sonic Frontiers broke my heart famously because it was like, I was so
Speaker 20:  excited for this game and then I played it and it was just like such a mess
Speaker 20:  in terms of how they implemented systems that it, it literally broke my
Speaker 20:  heart. Like, cause I wanted to like this game so bad. So I'm really excited
Speaker 20:  to see that, you know, even though Sega won't give me Sonic Mania two,
Speaker 20:  they'll give me Sonic Superstars, which you know, I consider that a fair
Speaker 20:  trade. So I'm really excited to get back into like these
Speaker 20:  2.5 2D side scrolling Sonic Platformers
Speaker 20:  because those are just fantastic perfect games in every way. And I
Speaker 20:  can't get enough of them.
Speaker 2:  I almost picked this one too. I'm very excited about this. And I was trying
Speaker 2:  to think when was the last really great sonic
Speaker 2:  game? I feel like it's been a really long time since True Sonic fans have
Speaker 2:  had a real winner.
Speaker 20:  Sonic Mania was 2017. Okay,
Speaker 21:  Yeah. Okay. This is, this is the controversial thing amongst like Sonic
Speaker 21:  fans. We're a, we're a sonic house out here. And the
Speaker 21:  truth is, you could both say that there have never been good ones because
Speaker 21:  going back and playing Sonic One and Sonic Two and Sonic Three, they're
Speaker 21:  designed to be headaches. The pleasure of the game is to like get
Speaker 21:  a your speed going right and getting a flow and the game does everything
Speaker 21:  it can to prevent that And I feel like my, I was a diehard sonic
Speaker 21:  kid as a kid then literally fell off it. And now like with my kid
Speaker 21:  now I'm like really falling in love with it, kind of meeting it on its own
Speaker 21:  terms. I'm like, oh it's actually just a traditional platformer
Speaker 21:  And I. Think once you start thinking about it like that, a lot of these
Speaker 21:  recent Sonic games have been pretty okay. Sonic Colors.
Speaker 21:  It happens. I think that there's kind of like weird, some weird
Speaker 21:  rose colored glasses for what people think Sonic was in the past for us,
Speaker 21:  what it actually was. But also the short answer like actually that is just
Speaker 21:  Sonic Mania. Yeah
Speaker 2:  I guess that's true. I was thinking mania was longer ago than it actually
Speaker 2:  was. And I Guess Mania did what I hope Superstars does, which is just be
Speaker 2:  a sonic game. Yes. Like, like you're saying, Ashley don't, don't try to do
Speaker 2:  other things. Just could be more Sonic. Yeah.
Speaker 20:  Give me more Sonic and Knuckles three and we're good. Yeah, you can keep
Speaker 20:  making that game forever and ever with new stuff. And I will always buy
Speaker 20:  it. And I will always be happy.
Speaker 2:  And you barely even have to update the graphics. No. Like it's fine.
Speaker 20:  Not at all. Exactly. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  All right Chris, what's your first one?
Speaker 21:  Super Mario Brothers Wonder Nice
Speaker 2:  Ice,
Speaker 21:  Which actually comes out before Metal Gear. So I am seeing the flaw in
Speaker 21:  my plan.
Speaker 21:  It comes out on October 20th. And I. Just love that this is the most
Speaker 21:  Nintendo thing to do on the planet that Nintendo spins
Speaker 21:  decades making a, and like refining an image of Super Mario
Speaker 21:  to the point where they finally make a movie and they're like, cool, great,
Speaker 21:  we nailed it. Now we're gonna change the entire aesthetic. And they're like,
Speaker 21:  no, are you sure You don't wanna make a game that looks like, you know Mario?
Speaker 21:  Like that movie that just made a gajillion dollars And. I'm like, no, no,
Speaker 21:  no. We're gonna make it look like a Dreamworks movie now instead. And they're
Speaker 21:  like, God dammit, I am so excited. I am so glad that
Speaker 21:  Mari was going to turn into an elephant. It's gonna be a delight.
Speaker 21:  And I kind of don't wanna see another image or trailer or anything
Speaker 21:  from this game. Because as the wonder in this subtitle suggests like
Speaker 21:  I think the surprise of it all and the hint that it could be a little bit
Speaker 21:  like Super Mario Brothers two in the us, that's enough to get me to play
Speaker 21:  it.
Speaker 20:  I wanted to ask like, how do you feel about people saying like, this just
Speaker 20:  looks like a updated version of New Super Mario Brothers. Which, you
Speaker 20:  know, as I was a sonic household, I was not a Mario household. So looking
Speaker 20:  at this from the outside, like this just looks like a new version of
Speaker 20:  New Super Mario Brothers. But instead of, I don't know, being
Speaker 20:  a cat, I know that's not new Super Mario's brothers don't like don't at
Speaker 20:  me. I know that's not it. Instead of being a cat, Mario just gets high,
Speaker 20:  right? Like it just seems like, okay, Mario drops acid. That's what
Speaker 20:  the thesis of this game is. Versus something like Super Mario Galaxy
Speaker 20:  or Super Mario Odyssey or you know, where they definitely
Speaker 20:  innovated on that formula. This just looks like, you know, a newer game
Speaker 20:  was not that new of a game, rather with like slightly updated graphics and
Speaker 20:  maybe one twist that doesn't really feel as
Speaker 20:  different as it should, which though sounds
Speaker 20:  exactly what tears of the Kingdom was. And then you played it.
Speaker 20:  Yeah. And it was a completely different experience on the level that
Speaker 20:  is like media shifting, like earth shattering. So I hope
Speaker 20:  you're right in that we don't get to see anything else about it and they
Speaker 20:  just release it, which is kind of what Nintendo kind of does is like, okay,
Speaker 20:  yeah, wait till they see this shit. I'm gonna knock the fucking socks off
Speaker 20:  of them. So yeah,
Speaker 21:  I think also to your point that like loving video games is a lot
Speaker 21:  like being a wine connoisseur no matter like what your franchise is.
Speaker 21:  So if you're inside of it, you're like, oh, I love Sora, I love Mario.
Speaker 21:  And you'd taste the the difference. And it feels more
Speaker 21:  substantial than it probably is. Like if every Mario game is
Speaker 21:  red wine, this is like Lambrusco or like something sugary and like
Speaker 21:  bubbly and it's like, oh, I didn't know that a wine should do that. I don't
Speaker 21:  know that much about wine so I'm kind of flying by the scene of my pants
Speaker 21:  here. But I, yeah, I think, I think we searched for those, those
Speaker 21:  like slight variations because we both want the thing that we're familiar
Speaker 21:  with but also want just a little hint of something new.
Speaker 2:  I mean. It also feels like we're, I don't know if this is a bigger trend
Speaker 2:  or not, but there is definitely in a lot of these franchises a sort of
Speaker 2:  pullback to like, let's do the thing that works. I think everybody,
Speaker 2:  everybody has been brought in by the, the lure of the battle
Speaker 2:  royale and the open world everything. And now everybody's just like, what
Speaker 2:  if we just like made a cool game that's fun to play? Hmm.
Speaker 21:  Which is why you're gonna tell us about Mortal Kom one. Is that a AlleyOOP?
Speaker 2:  No, it's why I'm gonna tell you about Assassin's Creed Mirage.
Speaker 21:  You're right. The other one doing it.
Speaker 2:  The two series I have played most completely in the course of my life are
Speaker 2:  the the AUM games of Batman, which I absolutely love to pieces
Speaker 2:  and I'm very excited that they're coming to Switch and the Assassins Creed
Speaker 2:  games. And the thing that happened with the last two, with the last few really
Speaker 2:  Assassins Creed games was they just got too big. Everything got too open
Speaker 2:  world. And it was just like, do you just wanna be on a ship for the next
Speaker 2:  five days? And I was like, no, I don't like, give me something to do. Give
Speaker 2:  me a task. Let me go and actually play this game.
Speaker 2:  Instead of just sort of aimlessly wandering yet another ancient town
Speaker 2:  like, I don't know, I that got old for me. And the story about Mirage so
Speaker 2:  far is that it is a return to form in the sense that it is
Speaker 2:  still big and interesting, but more sort of straightforward. And it's like
Speaker 2:  a game you play rather than a world you explore. And I've just
Speaker 2:  never been the like wander the world video gamer. I like
Speaker 2:  appreciate those games, And I understand why people like them. It's just
Speaker 2:  never been for me. And Assassin's Creed is, is like a puzzle solving game
Speaker 2:  at its best and I'm very excited for that to happen again. I'm very hopeful
Speaker 2:  for Mirage. The last two have been very disappointing, but I have high hopes
Speaker 2:  for Mirage.
Speaker 21:  Eh,
Speaker 2:  No you're out on Mirage.
Speaker 21:  I mean it's a UB soft game in the year of far, Lord
Speaker 21:  2023. I, I hate to do that because a lot of talented people work at this
Speaker 21:  publisher and everybody's trying their absolute best, but
Speaker 21:  everything coming outta Yousoft right now just feels so completely
Speaker 21:  mismanaged. I would love for it to work. I really, really would. And
Speaker 21:  it might be like my surprise there because everything you're saying is like
Speaker 21:  spot on. That is what I want. I just, I just feel like
Speaker 21:  I keep getting burned every time I let
Speaker 20:  Myself get excited for one
Speaker 2:  Of their games. It's fair. And the worry would be that this is basically
Speaker 2:  just, they just release, you know, a a 10 year old game
Speaker 2:  with slightly better graphics because they're like, well we couldn't forget
Speaker 2:  a news story. People like the old one, we'll just do that again and you're
Speaker 2:  not wrong that that would be potentially the most obvious thing for Ubisoft
Speaker 2:  to do here. So we'll see. All right, let's keep going through last round
Speaker 2:  here. Ash, what do you got?
Speaker 20:  So I have a couple things that I, I want to mention. So the one thing was
Speaker 20:  the Prince of Persia got side scroller that was announced at the Ubisoft
Speaker 20:  Direct. That looks really, really cool.
Speaker 25:  The
Speaker 26:  Prince has been kidnapped and taken to a forbidden land.
Speaker 20:  I don't really jive with the Prince of Persia games like the newer ones.
Speaker 20:  I kind of really like the Xbox One where the girl like shoots flowers out
Speaker 20:  of her butt when you know you unlock a thing. That was fun. That was a fun
Speaker 20:  game. But beyond that, like the Prince of Persia, like that original trilogy
Speaker 20:  and all that, that really didn't jive with me. But seeing like the side
Speaker 20:  scroller, I guess there's something about like side scroller platform puzzle
Speaker 20:  solving action that just really gets me and seeing that game
Speaker 20:  was like, oh okay, yeah I, I think I would like that a lot. So I'm really
Speaker 20:  excited about that. There was another game that was kind of like that but
Speaker 20:  gives me more Hades vibes. It was shown during summer
Speaker 20:  games, Fest, it's from this, I don't know actually where it's from.
Speaker 20:  It's just like this, it had this like one-off thing, it's called lga,
Speaker 20:  the Time shift. Warrior
Speaker 25:  Have another me I look good.
Speaker 20:  It has this like Prince of Persia like aesthetic. But this woman can like
Speaker 20:  split herself into different copies of herself to like solve puzzles and
Speaker 20:  stuff like that and fight enemies. It looked really cool. It was one of
Speaker 20:  the coolest things that were shown off during summer games. Fest and like
Speaker 20:  one of the only games I like featured a woman, sorry, I had to get that
Speaker 20:  in there. And then finally this, this one really does not fit within
Speaker 20:  the purview that you set out for us, but it is a thick game that is always
Speaker 20:  on my, I cannot wait for this list. And that is Dragon Age
Speaker 20:  Dread Wolf.
Speaker 25:  But now he wanted to tear down that veil
Speaker 25:  and destroy the world and we're the only
Speaker 25:  ones who can stop him.
Speaker 20:  We have been waiting for this game forever. Every so often
Speaker 20:  BioWare will pop up and be like, Hey, we're still working on this game.
Speaker 20:  It's still coming. Development is fine, we promise,
Speaker 20:  here's a little tidbit. And then they go back into their hole for like another
Speaker 20:  three years and we're about that time where it's time to pop out of
Speaker 20:  their hole and say, Hey, this game is still in development and it's still
Speaker 20:  coming. Here's, I don't know, here's crumbs for you, dragon age freaks and
Speaker 20:  then go back into their hole. So I'm really excited to see what that next
Speaker 20:  little tidbit is, but I, I'm excited. Dragon Age is a series
Speaker 20:  that saved my life in so many ways, so I'm really excited to
Speaker 20:  get a chance to play another one. All
Speaker 2:  Right, I like that that one isn't like a game you're excited about so much
Speaker 2:  as it is like a YouTube video that will happen at some point that you're
Speaker 20:  Excited about eventually.
Speaker 2:  Okay. All right. Well yeah, none of those, those count technically under
Speaker 2:  the rules. Sorry but I'll allow it. It's okay. Chris Plant last one. What
Speaker 2:  do you got?
Speaker 21:  I have one that's in the rules and one that transcends the rules. It
Speaker 2:  Transcends, it doesn't break the rules. It transcends the rules. Yeah.
Speaker 21:  Okay. The, the one that follows the rules is Alan Wake two. Yep.
Speaker 27:  I'm trapped here
Speaker 27:  in this nightmare.
Speaker 27:  I write to escape
Speaker 21:  Because Remedy makes interesting games. They made
Speaker 21:  control a couple years ago, which I think was one of the top five games
Speaker 21:  for polygons into the year list. And Allen Wake continues
Speaker 21:  creator of the Allen Wake games. Sam Lakes fascination with
Speaker 21:  Stephen King and by fascination I mean borderline
Speaker 21:  stalking obsession. I just think the games are a delight. And I think
Speaker 21:  that they understand the limitations of video games storytelling
Speaker 21:  while actively wanting to push them. I think video games stories
Speaker 21:  tend to have a bad reputation pretty understandably. And that's because
Speaker 21:  they have a really tough task of both giving the player some sense of
Speaker 21:  freedom and choice while then also having authorial
Speaker 21:  intent, which those things seem to conflict. And I think that
Speaker 21:  they enjoy toying with that, knowing
Speaker 21:  that like almost thinking of story as an experiment. Unless it's like,
Speaker 21:  oh I need to make the greatest thing ever because they kind of know from
Speaker 21:  the beginning that that's not entirely possible within the strictures of
Speaker 21:  a video game.
Speaker 2:  Wait, just real quick, how do you feel about the fact that Alan Wake looks
Speaker 2:  absolutely exactly like Bradley Cooper? What are your thoughts?
Speaker 21:  I like that, but I like Max Payne better because Max Payne
Speaker 21:  actually has the face of the creator of Alan Wake Has
Speaker 21:  his face and he looks Like. he is p like the world's biggest dump.
Speaker 21:  Oh my God. Oh that's it is such a good, good thing.
Speaker 21:  And then my, my like transcending the rules is I am ready for the game of
Speaker 21:  capitalism to come to an end and for this Microsoft Ft.
Speaker 21:  Cade Oh good glory, yes. To just be absolutely over with cuz I'm just
Speaker 21:  so done with it. Do you care at all? I care because living
Speaker 21:  in Irvine there are so many Blizzard and
Speaker 21:  Activision people in this area and my personal
Speaker 21:  stance on this is I, I think it's like a parody
Speaker 21:  of government action where things were not done when they
Speaker 21:  mattered. So now it's going to be done over the people who make Call of
Speaker 21:  Duty and Diablo And I think it's gonna blow up in the FTCs face,
Speaker 21:  which is bad and embarrassing for them. The good
Speaker 21:  news is I think a lot of people who already work at a place that is
Speaker 21:  notorious for being a difficult place to work can like get
Speaker 21:  out of this like purgatory period and start moving on with their lives,
Speaker 21:  which I think is like a better thing than whatever the past six
Speaker 21:  months has been for all these people.
Speaker 2:  Fair enough. That does in fact transcend the rules. I will g I will grant
Speaker 2:  that one. My last one is Spider-Man two because
Speaker 2:  I loved Spider-Man. One
Speaker 2:  Venom is the villain you can play as multiple characters. It's just one of
Speaker 2:  those things where they're like, we took a game that you love and we made
Speaker 2:  it slightly better. Would you like to play it again? And my answer to that
Speaker 2:  is yes. Always. Every single time.
Speaker 20:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  And they're gonna be like, we made swinging through buildings 6% more
Speaker 2:  fun. And I'm like, yes, I will play it 500% more often now
Speaker 21:  He just flies. Right? Like I, I feel like on that trailer of this like,
Speaker 21:  but what if he just flies? Yeah. And I was Like.
Speaker 2:  He has like flying squirrel wings now. It's like, I don't think that's
Speaker 2:  Canon, but I'm cool with it
Speaker 20:  As a, across the Spider verse per Enjoyer person I who
Speaker 20:  did not play Spider-Man one or the Miles Morales dlc. I,
Speaker 20:  well I can't say I'm excited for Spider-Man two, I'm excited to, I
Speaker 20:  guess try it to see if it can sell me on what it is because it seems
Speaker 20:  like a good experience. But beyond that, like, I don't
Speaker 20:  know man those I get it but I just don't get it.
Speaker 21:  It's a certain type of, of game, right? Like I mean we were talking about
Speaker 21:  the Ubisoft thing earlier, but I feel like it, it demands a certain
Speaker 21:  thing of the player both in terms of like, well the politics
Speaker 21:  yeah, but also the like the open world of the game and the, and the kind
Speaker 21:  of to-do list. But that said, I get it is somebody
Speaker 21:  who I feel like I could really use a good to-do list game. I cannot, I should
Speaker 21:  have said this earlier, I'm so excited to get deeper into Final Fantasy
Speaker 21:  16 because after Zelda I am so happy to have a game that's
Speaker 21:  like you
Speaker 20:  Are on rails. You cannot go anywhere except
Speaker 2:  Where we tell you to
Speaker 21:  Go. You'll do this and it will be pretty and You don like it and it will
Speaker 21:  confuse you
Speaker 20:  And Yeah,
Speaker 20:  exactly. Totally
Speaker 2:  Get it. Yeah. I'm, I'm glad to have a game that doesn't feel like a
Speaker 2:  creative exercise all the time. Sometimes yes. All right, well
Speaker 2:  we need to take a break, but thank you both for doing this. This was, this
Speaker 2:  was really fun and we're, we're gonna have to do this periodically cuz God
Speaker 2:  knows the games don't keep coming. But thank you both.
Speaker 21:  Thank you.
Speaker 20:  Thank you for having us.
Speaker 2:  All right, before we go, let's get to The Vergecast hotline. As a reminder,
Speaker 2:  the hotline number is eight six six Verge 11. Call and ask us
Speaker 2:  all of your deepest, most personal, most chaotic
Speaker 2:  tech questions. We love it. Here's one that seemed fitting for today's episode
Speaker 2:  from aj.
Speaker 28:  Hi Vergecast, this is AJ from Minneapolis. I'm curious to know, what
Speaker 28:  advice do you have to keep an iPhone feeling fresh and performing well
Speaker 28:  as it gets closer to its third year and beyond? A little background, I've
Speaker 28:  been a mostly happy owner of an iPhone 13 pro since that device
Speaker 28:  launched about a year and a half ago, but the battery quality has gotten
Speaker 28:  significantly worse recently. Some days I'm charging it twice
Speaker 28:  fully just to make it through one day. I've made all my past smartphones
Speaker 28:  last at least three years, but I am not looking forward to another year
Speaker 28:  and a half of this phone. I'll probably be tempted to buy their latest device
Speaker 28:  in the fall. Any advice to keep my battery in tip top shape and
Speaker 28:  keep this iPhone 13 pro going strong. Thanks
Speaker 2:  Aj. I asked around did some research, And I have goodish news? I
Speaker 2:  would say the first thing that I tell everyone to do and is just generally
Speaker 2:  good advice is reboot your phone more often than you think every few
Speaker 2:  days. Just turn it off and turn it back on again. It's good advice frankly
Speaker 2:  for any gadget that you own, but you'll be amazed at the number of things
Speaker 2:  that stop running in the background, that stop trying to access your location
Speaker 2:  that stopped trying to access your microphone. These things just drain battery
Speaker 2:  and they really add up. So reboot your phone every once in a while. A clean
Speaker 2:  start always helps also to the same end. Delete some apps, apps you don't
Speaker 2:  use might be running in the background. Might be refreshing every now and
Speaker 2:  then. Apps that you genuinely don't use or care about, just get rid of
Speaker 2:  them. The Ticketmaster app on your phone that you use two times, you're better
Speaker 2:  off just downloading that and relogging in every once in a while than letting
Speaker 2:  it linger on your phone. If you ask Apple how to help your battery, the first
Speaker 2:  two things it will tell you are use wifi whenever possible and turn down
Speaker 2:  the brightness on your screen. Those are only really doable
Speaker 2:  things in certain situations, but take that for what it's worth. As little
Speaker 2:  brightness as you can wifi whenever possible. The thing I do to save battery
Speaker 2:  life that I've had really good luck with is turning on low power mode on
Speaker 2:  the iPhone. In theory it turns some stuff off. Mostly background refreshing
Speaker 2:  and push email and that kind of thing. The place I notice it is, it turns
Speaker 2:  off background iCloud syncing. So if you use apps that sync
Speaker 2:  through iCloud to other devices, you might notice it not syncing quite as
Speaker 2:  often or successfully, but otherwise I can have low power mode on all day
Speaker 2:  and frankly barely notice the difference but actually get significantly better
Speaker 2:  battery life. One thing you should do for sure is make sure that on your
Speaker 2:  iPhone you have optimized battery charging on, it's a setting I think under
Speaker 2:  battery health, in the battery settings, in the settings app. And basically
Speaker 2:  what that does is not fully charge your iPhone until you're gonna need it.
Speaker 2:  And there are a lot of people who will tell you that leaving your phone at
Speaker 2:  a hundred percent for a long time, especially plugged in, can be bad for
Speaker 2:  your battery health. So turn that on. I'm generally not of the mind that
Speaker 2:  you need to like really babysit the way that you charge your
Speaker 2:  phone. I just think that's too much work. But you can at least turn that
Speaker 2:  setting on and have the device do it for you at some point. But ultimately
Speaker 2:  the honest truth is you're just gonna have to get a new battery at some point.
Speaker 2:  I think we keep our phones longer and longer and the idea that you
Speaker 2:  can keep your phone for several years but replace the battery somewhere in
Speaker 2:  the middle of that range is not a terrible trade off. I checked Apple's thing
Speaker 2:  and it said that it'll be about $89 to put a new battery in the
Speaker 2:  13 pro, which to me is totally worth it and certainly a lot cheaper than
Speaker 2:  buying a new phone. If you're otherwise happy with your phone, I think it's
Speaker 2:  a bummer that you're already experiencing battery troubles with a 13 pro,
Speaker 2:  which is not an old phone. But if that is the case, you can check the battery
Speaker 2:  health also in the battery settings, in the settings app. And if it's below
Speaker 2:  80% of its original capacity, that's when Apple recommends
Speaker 2:  and will actually work with you to replace it. So get a new
Speaker 2:  battery, low power mode, reboot your phone every once in a while and
Speaker 2:  otherwise good luck. You can be one of those people who obsessively charges
Speaker 2:  your phone between 40 and 80%, which is is what a lot of people will tell
Speaker 2:  you to do. I think that's too much work do without you will.
Speaker 2:  All right, that is it for The Vergecast today. Thanks to everyone who is
Speaker 2:  on the show, and thank you as always so much for listening. There's lots
Speaker 2:  more from everything we talked about ai, apple stuff on The Verge
Speaker 2:  dot com, lots of Apple things coming in the next few days. I think we'll
Speaker 2:  put some links in the show notes, but also, you know, read The Verge dot
Speaker 2:  com. It's a website. We like it. If you have thoughts, questions, feelings,
Speaker 2:  or other tips on how to make your battery work better, you can always email
Speaker 2:  us at Vergecast The Verge dot com or keep calling the hotline. Its six six
Speaker 2:  Verge one 11. We are already building a bunch of episodes based on your hotline
Speaker 2:  questions, so thank you so much for that. This show is produced by Andrew
Speaker 2:  Marino and Liam James. Brooke Minters is our editorial director of Audio
Speaker 2:  The. Vergecast is Verge production and part of the Vox Media podcast network.
Speaker 2:  Nili Alex now will be back on Friday to talk about threads, Reddit, apple,
Speaker 2:  and lots more. We'll see you then. Rock and roll.