# Transcript
ID: 7744a3bb-f960-475d-838b-c887115e83da
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Macs and M3s, shot on iPhones
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/2545754577394053364/-7908192560817399514/s93290-US-3758s-1698833289.mp3
Description: Today on the flagship podcast of spec bumps:
02:21 - The Verge’s David Pierce, Alex Cranz, and Dan Seifert discuss the announcements from Apple’s “Scary Fast” Mac event.
Apple’s ‘Scary Fast’ Mac event: all the news from Apple’s online keynote
27:56 - Becca Farsace joins the show to share her thoughts on smartphone photography in 2023, and if the “Pro” branding can live up to its name.
iPhone 15 Pro Max camera: 1000 photos later, it’s still missing something
1,000 photos with the Pixel 8 Pro: AI, UI, and Pro stuff
52:06 - Adi Robertson answers a question from the Vergecast Hotline.
Xreal’s Air 2 AR glasses ship in November in the US
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we love hearing from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Disabled
Speaker 2:  Welcome To The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of Spec Bumps. I'm your friend
Speaker 2:  David Pierce and I am once again in the e Barrett
Speaker 2:  Prettyman Courthouse in Washington DC. That's right folks. I am back
Speaker 2:  at USV Google this time. I'm here for Sundar Phai, the CEO of Google.
Speaker 2:  His testimony was on Monday and we learned some fascinating
Speaker 2:  stuff about the Apple deal, about the things that Google wanted to preload
Speaker 2:  onto iOS devices. There's this fascinating alternate universe that Apple
Speaker 2:  and Google could have gone down. We're gonna get into all of that I think
Speaker 2:  next week we have a lot of catching up to do on some of the trials with SBF
Speaker 2:  and antitrust and some new antitrust stuff happening, lots to get to. But
Speaker 2:  for today we're gonna talk about two things. First, we're gonna talk about
Speaker 2:  the Apple event from Monday night, the big Scary Fast event with all of
Speaker 2:  its new devices and unlabeled y axes. We're gonna get into the
Speaker 2:  new devices, whether they're interesting, why Apple chose to do this at 8:00 PM
Speaker 2:  Eastern on a Monday night and a bunch more. Then I'm gonna talk to
Speaker 2:  Becca Farsace from our video team, all about phone cameras. We've spent
Speaker 2:  a lot of time this year talking about and shooting with these new phone cameras
Speaker 2:  and increasingly on things like the Pixel and the Galaxy Line and the iPhone.
Speaker 2:  The phones are the thing like that is the reason you buy a new phone
Speaker 2:  herein and year out. It's either that or like your battery dies. So we're
Speaker 2:  gonna get into are phones getting better? Are they getting more different,
Speaker 2:  developing their own taste or are we getting kind of to a platonic ideal
Speaker 2:  of smartphone photos? It's a super fun conversation. It goes like all over
Speaker 2:  the place, but it's a good time. All that is coming up in just a minute,
Speaker 2:  but I just found the cafeteria in this courthouse after like a
Speaker 2:  lot of days of being here and that means I actually get to have lunch
Speaker 2:  during the trial. This is very exciting for me. I'm gonna go make that happen.
Speaker 2:  This is The Vergecast. We'll see you in a sec.
Speaker 3:  Support for this episode comes from Sonos experience fully immersive sound
Speaker 3:  with the new era 300 smart speaker from Sonos. It's a spatial audio
Speaker 3:  speaker that doesn't just surround you with sound. It puts you inside your
Speaker 3:  music. Plus you can pair two era three hundreds with a Sonos arc or beam
Speaker 3:  soundbar for the ultimate in home theater experience. The ERA 300 is easy
Speaker 3:  to set up and even easier to use with the Sonos app, your voice and Apple
Speaker 3:  Airplay two, unlock the most innovative spatial listening experience with
Speaker 3:  the ERA 300. Visit sonos.com to learn more and find thoughtful gifts
Speaker 3:  for everyone on your list.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back All, right? They let me outta the courtroom. It was very exciting.
Speaker 2:  I don't have a cold anymore, let's get to it.
Speaker 4:  Good evening. And Welcome To Apple Park.
Speaker 2:  On Monday night, apple held an event that it called Scary Fast. For some
Speaker 2:  reason in my head, this event is called Spooky Scary, but it's not. It was
Speaker 2:  called Scary Fast and there were signs from the beginning that this event
Speaker 2:  was always gonna be a bit unusual. First of all, it was
Speaker 2:  on a Monday at 8:00 PM Eastern, 5:00 PM Pacific, which is up
Speaker 2:  against like Monday night football. Nobody was invited, it was all virtual.
Speaker 2:  And like we talked about last week on the show, this sort of seemed like
Speaker 2:  Apple trying to flex its muscles in prime time. My theory going
Speaker 2:  in was that either this was gonna be one of Apple's sneaky big
Speaker 2:  announcements ever. It was gonna like announce it bought Disney or something
Speaker 2:  or that it was essentially trying to bury an event, which seemed weird because
Speaker 2:  normally when Apple thinks it had S news that isn't all that interesting.
Speaker 2:  It just puts out a press release. So I was very confused about what this
Speaker 2:  was gonna be and as you can see, I also had a million theories about how
Speaker 2:  this event was gonna work, whether there would be costumes, And, what we
Speaker 2:  would see announced and I was wrong about, I think just about every single
Speaker 2:  one of them. But we'll get to that to talk about what did happen. Alex Cranz
Speaker 2:  and Dan Seaford are here. Alex Cranz. Hello. Hello. Dan Seaford.
Speaker 2:  Hello. Hello. I have no idea where to start. I con, I confess I'm
Speaker 2:  so confused now. Many hours after this Apple event that
Speaker 2:  I'm not sure what to do. But let's, let's just start with the vibe of the
Speaker 2:  thing itself. So Dan, we got this invite and it was
Speaker 2:  for 8:00 PM Eastern on a Monday night and we immediately started
Speaker 2:  trying to decide what is Apple doing here? We had
Speaker 2:  a lot of theories now that we've seen the thing. Why did Apple do this at
Speaker 2:  8:00 PM on a Monday night?
Speaker 6:  I think the strongest theory, which we still really don't know the answer
Speaker 6:  to why they did it on Monday night, but the strongest going theory is it's
Speaker 6:  a testing of the waters to see if they can get the audience and the
Speaker 6:  interest in the primetime time slot for when they do a bigger
Speaker 6:  event that's either the next iPhone or the next iPad event or their
Speaker 6:  spring event, whatever it might be. That's my guess. And I think that
Speaker 6:  in Apple's eyes, at least based on what I've seen, based on the interest
Speaker 6:  on our own site, they probably have the interest to do it.
Speaker 6:  And so going forward,
Speaker 5:  No Dan, they're
Speaker 6:  Probably gonna be at 8:00 PM on Monday nights.
Speaker 5:  Dan, this is incorrect because we all watched this one
Speaker 5:  because we were hoping it was gonna be something interesting and something
Speaker 5:  a little more because it was, it was at 8:00 PM or 5:00 PM if you're on the
Speaker 5:  Pacific time, there was that little bit of like desire and then instead it
Speaker 5:  was not just a a very traditional Apple event. It was like the
Speaker 5:  most traditional Yeah. And it just, I
Speaker 5:  do not think it was successful at what they wanted to do. Yeah, people
Speaker 5:  watched it. But are people gonna tune in every time or did they
Speaker 5:  just like waste it?
Speaker 6:  I honestly, I think that for an iPhone event, they could have it at three
Speaker 6:  in the morning and people will tune in.
Speaker 2:  I think that's right. I agree with that.
Speaker 6:  The audience probably has heard to say this, but the amount of
Speaker 6:  attention that Apple can pull is so much more than
Speaker 6:  basically any other company. And so Apple can do
Speaker 6:  basically what it wants. I will say that they did lean into the fact that
Speaker 6:  it was at night, like their prerecorded infomercial was shot at night
Speaker 6:  and they were all wearing dark clothes because it was spooky and
Speaker 5:  It's the dynamic range on the iPhone that shot it all was incredible.
Speaker 2:  We're gonna talk about that in the next segment. I don't, that's just, that's
Speaker 2:  for Becca to talk about later. Don't even worry about it.
Speaker 6:  There was lots of like cloud or smoke effects and You know
Speaker 6:  nobody wore a costume. I was hoping that they would be a little bit more
Speaker 6:  fun and wear a costume. I
Speaker 2:  Was a little disappointed that no one even, there weren't even like little
Speaker 2:  jokey costumes that appeared for a second and then dis like I was, I was
Speaker 2:  hoping for something.
Speaker 6:  Nobody even had like a jack of lantern pin or anything.
Speaker 5:  Right. I have an additional theory for why they did it at this time. Okay.
Speaker 5:  Because I was sitting there last night after the event. It was about
Speaker 5:  8 31 because the event ended exactly at eight 30. It was a 30
Speaker 5:  minute event. And I was like, why was it at this time of day? Because
Speaker 5:  generally speaking, you wanna get as maximum, you wanna get as many people
Speaker 5:  watching as possible, right? So everybody on the Pacific Coast is watching
Speaker 5:  as they watch right before they leave to work. Right? Everybody on the East
Speaker 5:  Coast and everybody in central time is watching over like dinner because
Speaker 5:  I guess that's what we all did. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  We had people on our staff who were like, I just put my kids to bed in the
Speaker 2:  middle of an Apple event. What is happening here? I
Speaker 6:  Speed ran bedtime last night. I was like, you guys are all getting to bed.
Speaker 6:  Brush your teeth as fast as possible. Gotta go. I
Speaker 5:  Would, I would argue that it wasn't the best time to maximize
Speaker 5:  American views. And so then I was like, I was thinking about it and I was
Speaker 5:  like, okay, well maybe Europe. And I was like, no, Europe, it's even later.
Speaker 5:  So this is actually a much worse time for Europe because they're all in bed
Speaker 5:  to sleep. 'cause it's sleeping time for them. So you're cutting out that
Speaker 5:  whole market. So the best I could think was, maybe this was
Speaker 5:  for China where it would've been first thing in the morning would've been
Speaker 5:  seven, eight o'clock. Where we're currently having a massive
Speaker 5:  debate with the country about processors and who builds those
Speaker 5:  processors. And this entire event was about processors. So
Speaker 5:  there's, I was like, is there something there or was it really just, we wanna
Speaker 5:  see if Americans will tune in as they're putting their kids to
Speaker 5:  bed the day before Halloween. In which case
Speaker 5:  I feel like that was a weird, weird bet to me.
Speaker 6:  I could see the China argument more for an iPhone event. A Mac event.
Speaker 6:  But this,
Speaker 5:  It wasn't a Mac event as much as it was a processor event that had Macs
Speaker 5:  in it. Right? Sure.
Speaker 6:  But it was the processors that go into Macs. It's not the processors
Speaker 6:  that go into iPhones and most of the iPads, it is like their
Speaker 6:  desktop computing processors.
Speaker 5:  But those processors are just as important just as like the iPhone is
Speaker 5:  obviously more important than the Mac, but those processors as it compares
Speaker 5:  to, to the other big folks making processors that go in
Speaker 5:  computers and servers and stuff just as important.
Speaker 2:  It's a good theory. Yeah. I think and and Apple is definitely going out of
Speaker 2:  its way to flex itself as a chip manufacturer in all ways. But
Speaker 6:  The only difference is they don't sell the chips.
Speaker 2:  That's what I was just about to say.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. They sell computers that have the chips. Right? You cannot
Speaker 6:  go to Apple and be like, I wanna run a server farm. Right? Gimme your chips
Speaker 6:  so that I can put 'em in there. Like they're not competing with Intel and
Speaker 6:  TSMC and and the others that are fabricators and also You know
Speaker 6:  building server chips and all this stuff. They are building their products
Speaker 6:  chips for their products that they sell either directly to businesses or
Speaker 6:  to consumers as a fully fledged product. So like that's how it
Speaker 6:  is a Mac event. Like yes, they were flexing about their chips, but the only
Speaker 6:  way to get these chips is in a Mac and there's no other way to get it
Speaker 5:  Dan. I need it to be the chips scenario. 'cause otherwise we're gonna
Speaker 5:  be like doing 8:00 PM Mac events for the rest of our lives.
Speaker 2:  I'm with Dan. I I think if you made me bet $50 right
Speaker 2:  now on what time will the iPhone event be next year? I'm gonna say it's,
Speaker 2:  it's e evening East coast time.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. 'cause You know what evening east coast time is. It's not the middle
Speaker 6:  of the workday. Yeah, like, like for us it's our job to watch it. We
Speaker 6:  stopped our whole workday many workdays to focus on it and to to
Speaker 6:  plan for it and stuff like that. But for most people it's like you were
Speaker 6:  sneaking it in the middle of your workday.
Speaker 5:  Before I was a journalist, that was one of my favorite things was like middle
Speaker 5:  of the workday I'd be like, oh I'm gonna take my lunch and watch an Apple
Speaker 5:  event.
Speaker 2:  It's so that Apple can make sure its employees work the whole day and then
Speaker 2:  watch the Apple event. It's really, this is about Apple Park getting its
Speaker 2:  full productive use All. right. Let's move on. So I. Think I agree. It was
Speaker 2:  odd but I also suspect this will not be the last time Apple does this. But
Speaker 2:  let's, let's talk about the chips. So we got the the M three, the M three
Speaker 2:  PRO and the M three Max. This is the first time Apple has launched the whole
Speaker 2:  family of chips all at once, which I thought was very interesting. Dan, we
Speaker 2:  were talking just before we started recording and you were saying basically
Speaker 2:  that the story of these chips is slightly
Speaker 2:  more complicated than usual. It's not just kind of the good,
Speaker 2:  better, best it has been in the past.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, so the typical rollout for M Chipps, at least for the M one and the
Speaker 6:  M two generations was Apple would come out with the M base model and then
Speaker 6:  six months, 12 months later that you'd have the M three pro, the M three
Speaker 6:  Max and then eventually the M three Ultra and each one would build upon it.
Speaker 6:  So the unique thing here is that the M three, like you said,
Speaker 6:  David is all rolling out at the same time. But there is some like
Speaker 6:  real weirdness once you get into the pro and the Max because
Speaker 6:  not only are there M three PRO and M three Max, but there's also like M three
Speaker 6:  PRO with a certain number of cores on it and then M three Pro with more cores
Speaker 6:  on it and then M three Max with a certain number of cores and M three Max
Speaker 6:  with more cores on it. And that will determine how many
Speaker 6:  features each one of them has And what capabilities it has. So if you want
Speaker 6:  the absolute best CPU, you have to get the M three Max with the
Speaker 6:  best GPU, which wasn't always the case in the past. Okay. The way
Speaker 6:  that Apple split the power cores and the efficiency cores
Speaker 6:  is not linear anymore. The M three PRO has a 12
Speaker 6:  core CPU on it and six of those are efficiency cores and six are
Speaker 6:  performance cores. And then the M three Max does like 12
Speaker 6:  performance cores and then four efficiencies cores. So in
Speaker 6:  prior models it was like a linear thing and you had the same
Speaker 6:  ratio of performance and efficiency cores in the pro and the Max chips. But
Speaker 6:  that's upended now. We'll have to see how that shakes out in the real world
Speaker 6:  And, what that performance means. But it is just more
Speaker 6:  stuff you have to think about and consider when you're, when you're buying
Speaker 6:  these,
Speaker 5:  I like this 'cause ultimately it's not gonna be more stuff for most people
Speaker 5:  listening to this. 'cause ideally a bunch of people are gonna get ahold of
Speaker 5:  these things and benchmark them and you're gonna get a better sense of which
Speaker 5:  is the right one for you. But I like, it feels like the company is
Speaker 5:  thinking more as being more thoughtful about their processor design by
Speaker 5:  by adjusting the amount of efficiency of cores. 'cause if you've got the
Speaker 5:  Max, that's like the biggest one, right? It's equivalent of the AMD thread
Speaker 5:  ripper or something like that. Yeah. You don't necessarily want energy
Speaker 5:  efficiency there, right?
Speaker 2:  You're buying that for like raw power.
Speaker 6:  You're buying it for raw power. Sure. But if you're buying a pro
Speaker 6:  as opposed to the standard M three because that's the other thing is now
Speaker 6:  the standard M three is part of the MacBook Pro line. So if you're stepping
Speaker 6:  up to the M three Pro for reasons, one of those reasons
Speaker 6:  is probably power. And I will tell you from personal experience with
Speaker 6:  a standard M Chipp versus an M Pro chip, I can Max out
Speaker 6:  those performance scores on a standard M chipp pretty easily with simple
Speaker 6:  workloads in Lightroom and stuff like that. And the extra performance scores
Speaker 6:  in the M Pro chip allows me to have the headroom where I do not maximum out
Speaker 6:  or if I do Max amount that's for a shorter amount of time and stuff like
Speaker 6:  that. If I run a Lightroom export on an M series, MacBook
Speaker 6:  Air, that computer is, I can't do anything with it until that export is done.
Speaker 6:  Whereas my M one Pro, even a two year old M one Pro allows me to run
Speaker 6:  an export and do other things. It allows me to do more quote professional
Speaker 6:  tasks. But if the new chips don't have as many
Speaker 6:  performance scores, then that might change that equation. But it's hard
Speaker 6:  to say without actually testing all of them.
Speaker 5:  I mean it's still fairly linear from the regular to the pro.
Speaker 2:  You're right Alex that there is still some measure of like good,
Speaker 2:  better, best going on. It's just that the kind of leap from one to
Speaker 2:  the next is maybe less clear to me than before. What I have a hard time with
Speaker 2:  is seeing where I would want the base chip. Like why would I buy
Speaker 2:  the entry level 14 inch MacBook Pro? Yeah. I guess is a question we've been
Speaker 2:  asking for a while because the MacBook Air has gotten so good, but for me
Speaker 2:  it's like I see why the top end
Speaker 2:  computer here, the 16 inch MacBook Pro, you've got 128 gigs of unified memory
Speaker 2:  like the 40 core GP, this thing costs, what is it? Like $7,200? Like?
Speaker 2:  Like hell yeah. Fully loaded. Yeah. I see why that computer kicks ass.
Speaker 2:  What I don't understand is this sort of middle ground of
Speaker 2:  everything is more powerful but not
Speaker 2:  necessarily sort of dramatically. So in some ways here,
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I think we should talk about this base model. 'cause this base model
Speaker 6:  is really the the new thing in the lineup. The others, the M three PRO and
Speaker 6:  the M three Max are upgrades of the M two pro. But now we have this base
Speaker 6:  model 14 inch MacBook Pro with the M three standard ship
Speaker 2:  And the 13 inch is dead. Dead now, right? 13
Speaker 6:  Inch is dead and gone. Okay, goodbye touch bar. Cranz loves the touch bar.
Speaker 6:  Sorry Cranz.
Speaker 5:  I love the idea of the touch bar. Let's be clear.
Speaker 6:  The idea, great execution, not so much now it's gone. So now the pro
Speaker 6:  line starts at $1,600, which is a $400 price drop from
Speaker 6:  where it started with the M two generation. But that
Speaker 6:  $1,600 computer comes with a base M three chip, not a pro or a Max chip.
Speaker 6:  And it's got other compromise in it. It has eight gigs of RAM for
Speaker 6:  $1,600, it has fewer ports on it. They took
Speaker 6:  away A-U-S-B-C port so there's none on the right hand side. So it's
Speaker 6:  really basically set up like a MacBook Air except with an HDMI port
Speaker 6:  and an SD card slot.
Speaker 2:  I mean there's all kinds of little things like that. It doesn't, yeah, it's
Speaker 2:  not fully like Thunderbolt four certified right in its
Speaker 2:  like, and again, I just, I just wanna say this again one more time for emphasis
Speaker 2:  it's $1,600 and it has eight gigs of ram. Yeah that is
Speaker 2:  ludicrous. Like that should not be allowed. Apple should be ashamed of itself
Speaker 2:  for trying to sell that to people
Speaker 6:  And like Apple's line is that unified memory is more efficient and you don't
Speaker 6:  need as much. But my retort to that is you can hit
Speaker 6:  swap very easily on an eight gigabyte. Oh yeah. Mac, I've done it. We've
Speaker 6:  done it in testing. I hit swap on my 16 gig Mac all the time. And you do
Speaker 6:  notice when that happens. And then if eight gig was all anyone needed, why
Speaker 6:  are you selling 16 gig and 24 gig upgrades for 200 and $400
Speaker 6:  anyways? So now you have this computer at $1,600
Speaker 6:  that is right next to the price of the 15 inch MacBook Air that
Speaker 6:  has a larger screen, a lighter chassis, thinner design, all that
Speaker 6:  stuff. It's a little bit cheaper. But the question is like now you have even
Speaker 6:  more of a confusion of like what do you go for? Like if you wanted, prior
Speaker 6:  to this, if you wanted the Good Pro computers, you started at $2,000, you
Speaker 6:  got a faster processor, more capable, more ports, all the whole nine yards
Speaker 6:  and you got the great display and all that kind of stuff. Now the main difference
Speaker 6:  is the screen and an HDMI port.
Speaker 5:  I mean that's often been the big difference between the MacBook Air and the
Speaker 5:  MacBook Pro. Like historically that was the primary difference was
Speaker 5:  not the processors but the display and, and people were like, yeah, I wanna
Speaker 5:  play more for prettier display because So I like I think that makes
Speaker 5:  a lot of sense. I honestly, I think this positioning makes sense because
Speaker 5:  it's saying look, if you, if you care just about lightness and good
Speaker 5:  battery life, go get one of the two heirs or maybe wait until
Speaker 5:  they release the M three version of those errors. But go get those errors
Speaker 5:  and then if you actually want like a better display, if you want the good
Speaker 5:  display, then you can get better battery life in similar
Speaker 5:  speeds for similar price and get the the MacBook
Speaker 5:  Pro the base model. I
Speaker 2:  Think that theory made a lot more sense to me like six
Speaker 2:  years ago when the AIRS screen was pretty crappy.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, it's now you're going from like very good screen to even better screen,
Speaker 2:  which is again like I think Apple would be happy with the outcome of this
Speaker 2:  conversation being most people should still buy MacBook Airs. Like I think
Speaker 2:  most people still do buy MacBook Airs and that's all fine and good to me
Speaker 2:  it's just like the MacBook Pro is sort of inexorably moving
Speaker 2:  towards being the Mac Pro. I think that it's just gonna get higher and higher
Speaker 2:  and higher end. But Apple cannot let go of this idea that they're like, we
Speaker 2:  have to have one that is under $2,000. Yeah. And it's like just don't just
Speaker 2:  get rid of it. It's the air. It's fine. The
Speaker 6:  Theory for the longest time was that they kept around that stupid 13 inch
Speaker 6:  MacBook Pro because this is quote a theory that businesses will
Speaker 6:  only buy a computer if it has pro in its name and they don't actually care
Speaker 6:  about the specs or whatever. And so they want the cheapest one that has pro
Speaker 6:  in the name. And so now the cheapest one with pro in the name is $1,600.
Speaker 6:  It's up from $1,300 on the 13 inch model. I would argue that
Speaker 6:  like that makes sense. It's a much better computer and that is who's buying
Speaker 6:  this? So it's like almost not even a consumer pitch. And you
Speaker 6:  can see that in ways where like you don't get the new color option,
Speaker 6:  which is not really a color, but you don't get that option on the base model.
Speaker 6:  And you like if you buy the 16 inch model and then
Speaker 6:  you do upgrade the ram, you're at 1800 or $2,000 at that point you
Speaker 6:  might as well just buy the better processor and all that stuff. Ooh,
Speaker 5:  We're ignoring one thing. The airs all come base
Speaker 5:  2 56 gigabytes of storage. The pro comes base five
Speaker 5:  12. That's a
Speaker 6:  Fair point. Sure. But the airs start at $1,100.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, but so to get, they basically spend the same amount to boost the
Speaker 5:  storage.
Speaker 6:  Not quite, you don't get there. You, you get close to it, but it's still
Speaker 6:  cheaper. You get
Speaker 5:  Close enough that you're like, oh, if I spend a hundred dollars more, I get
Speaker 5:  a prettier display too kind of deal.
Speaker 6:  You get a smaller display and I would argue that that customer that really
Speaker 6:  cares that much or is looking at a 15 inch MacBook error is looking
Speaker 6:  at that because it has the bigger display and that actually matters more
Speaker 6:  to them
Speaker 5:  Then why would we compare it to the 14 inch at all? Because
Speaker 6:  They're in the lineup there. This is modern apple where
Speaker 6:  it'll always be where at you're at one point and you're like, well if I just
Speaker 6:  spend a little bit more, yeah, I get more, oh now that I'm here,
Speaker 6:  I'm, I'm at 1600. Well shoot, I really should get that 16 gigs of ram
Speaker 6:  because I'm spending almost $2,000 for this computer already. I want to last
Speaker 6:  a few years and stuff like that. Oh, now I'm at $1,800. This is how you step
Speaker 6:  your, you rationalize every single step and every single step.
Speaker 6:  The profit margins are bigger. And so like this is modern apple and this
Speaker 6:  is, this is how it goes with everything.
Speaker 5:  Okay. We talked about the eight gigabytes of ram and that's very offensive.
Speaker 5:  I do wanna talk like I'm, I'm still just thinking about that 256
Speaker 5:  gigabytes of storage minimum on the air. That's just,
Speaker 5:  that feels as bad as eight gigabytes.
Speaker 6:  I don't think that's as big of as a problem as some of these other constraints
Speaker 6:  on the pros for one, the air, if you think about how people use
Speaker 6:  computers these days, they're living in a browser. Most of their life lives
Speaker 6:  in the clouds. This is
Speaker 5:  Spoken like a man who doesn't hoard his data.
Speaker 6:  I I I hoard data. My computer is a terabyte drive. I've got seven terabytes
Speaker 6:  of drive plugged into it. Do not talk to me about hoarding data. I pay, I
Speaker 6:  pay a, a inordinate amount of fees for cloud storage in the terabytes of
Speaker 6:  range. But if I think about like a typical consumer buying the MacBook Air,
Speaker 6:  a student or someone who's just looking for a home computer or whatever,
Speaker 6:  most of their life is living in the cloud. They are living in a browser and
Speaker 6:  things like that. There aren't, they aren't storing a lot of stuff directly
Speaker 6:  on their driving. They don't even know
Speaker 5:  What files
Speaker 6:  Are. Exactly. So I, I I don't think that's a problem on the airs. When the
Speaker 6:  airs first launched, there was a lot of controversy about the speed of that
Speaker 6:  storage. I don't think that's a problem at that level either. But once you
Speaker 6:  add a pro to the name and once you step up to these price brackets, that
Speaker 6:  is where all of these considerations do matter and, and make differences
Speaker 6:  depending on the workload. If you're buying the pro computer and you're saying,
Speaker 6:  I'm gonna be editing images and video, I wanna be a creator, I wanna
Speaker 6:  pursue this and stuff like that, you will quickly run into these walls if
Speaker 6:  you stay with the base model. And that's just the reality of it.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. My guess would be that the, the kind of
Speaker 2:  consistent choice for a lot of people here is gonna be the 14 inch
Speaker 2:  either pro or Max depending on the person. But like the 16
Speaker 2:  just feels like it's so much bigger and more expensive that you're gonna
Speaker 2:  lose some people. It's also just a Yeah, big machine. Like it's a it's heavy
Speaker 6:  Big computer. Yeah, you're pushing almost five pounds of that.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. But I think as the, as the like You know c creator tool for
Speaker 2:  people with expendable income, the 14 inch with the pro and the Max,
Speaker 2:  if, if it benchmarks the way we probably expect it to based on all
Speaker 2:  of Apple's unlabeled graphs that say it's faster. Do you see the one where
Speaker 2:  it was just like image processing two x and you're just like, what is that
Speaker 2:  app? That's nothing. You just said image processing two x, like that's,
Speaker 2:  and with a, with a swoopy line, they
Speaker 5:  Did have labels for the graphs, but it's very, very small
Speaker 5:  and like just a shade lighter than the background.
Speaker 6:  The y axis is those is relative performance. It
Speaker 2:  Said relative performance. That's nothing. Just don't even put words
Speaker 2:  there. Just
Speaker 6:  Draw lines floating out in space.
Speaker 5:  Look, I, I used to do this too. I would make charts and it would just be,
Speaker 5:  I'd just be like, people don't care about the actual speed. They just wanna
Speaker 5:  see a big number. And I got yelled at a lot for it.
Speaker 2:  But I just think the M three Pro, I'm just, I just specked this out while
Speaker 2:  we were talking here and you can get the 14 inch MacBook Pro with an M
Speaker 2:  three PRO 18 gigs of unified memory, five 12 gigs of storage,
Speaker 2:  blah blah blah. $2,000 on the dot. Yeah, it's, it's 1999.
Speaker 2:  I suspect that one is going to be the one that most people do. 'cause you're
Speaker 2:  gonna start with the base one and like you're talking about Dan just slowly
Speaker 2:  step your way up to that. Anyway, that's the one I think Apple wants to sell
Speaker 2:  you.
Speaker 6:  If history follows what happened with the M one PRO and the M two Pro, that's
Speaker 6:  the one that's like gonna be in stores at Best Buy and B and H and all this
Speaker 6:  stuff. And they are gonna discount it by $200 when they put it on sale. And
Speaker 6:  then at $1,800 you have a hell of computer for $1,800. And I think a lot
Speaker 6:  of people can be really happy with it and they should not get the $1,600
Speaker 6:  base model.
Speaker 2:  Have you seen the Space Black one? Alex and I we're both very excited about
Speaker 2:  this place. Black one. It's so pretty.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it's space dark gray.
Speaker 6:  I, I'm not gonna quote him exactly, but Jason Snell over at Six Colors had
Speaker 6:  a really great line about it in his piece. You should go check it out. But
Speaker 6:  him and I were kind of talking about it yesterday. It is just a darker version
Speaker 6:  of Space Gray. It is not really black. So if you have in your mind
Speaker 6:  that this is the return of the black book, which was that black plastic
Speaker 6:  MacBook from the mid two thousands, this is not it, it's,
Speaker 6:  it's still gray. It's
Speaker 2:  A
Speaker 5:  Shame. Nevermind
Speaker 6:  I, I know what to say. It's, it's another shade of gray. They are claiming
Speaker 6:  that this anodization is like supposed to be more
Speaker 6:  resistant to fingerprints and I did slap my palm on it and smear my fingers
Speaker 6:  around on it to try and see, but it was hard to tell if they actually remained
Speaker 6:  or not. I think once we have it in use and see if it's any better
Speaker 6:  than the midnight, 'cause the midnight grossed up almost immediately. This
Speaker 6:  might be slightly better.
Speaker 2:  Let's talk about the iMac for two minutes, which I think is as long as the
Speaker 2:  iMac deserves. I started out when Apple announced the iMac, which is
Speaker 2:  literally just the same damn computer, but they took out the old chip and
Speaker 2:  they put in the new chip, the end, no new accessories, no nothing, nothing.
Speaker 2:  Still Lightning keyboard. I was outraged by this. I'm still kind of
Speaker 2:  outraged by this, but I also now understand this And. what I think it is
Speaker 2:  is Apple believes that there are people who buy imax and that's a very specific
Speaker 2:  set of person And. what they are going to do is they're going to take their
Speaker 2:  11 year old iMac that they bought that runs an
Speaker 2:  Intel thing and no longer gets software updates and is basically falling
Speaker 2:  apart. They're gonna replace it with this one and they're gonna be very happy.
Speaker 2:  And I think they're right and I think that is like a sad way to think about
Speaker 2:  the iMac line at this point in time. But I think that's where we are.
Speaker 5:  The iMac was always there though. There was like the, the, the bit of time
Speaker 5:  where the iMac was used by kids and teens, but
Speaker 5:  for the most part it's always been like your parents' computer that they
Speaker 5:  keep in their computer room because they're the ones that still have computer
Speaker 5:  rooms.
Speaker 6:  Yes, it served the role as the shared family computer or the home computer.
Speaker 6:  And I would argue that at this point that is an increasingly shrinking
Speaker 6:  audience and does not exist for the reality of most modern families
Speaker 6:  or modern homes. People have moved on to personal devices whether they're
Speaker 6:  Chromebooks or laptops or iPhones or tablets or whatever. So
Speaker 6:  it makes sense to me that they are not throwing lots of investment at the
Speaker 6:  iMac like David said. I agree. Like we don't have an iMac Pro because the
Speaker 6:  Mac studio exists and the Mac Pro exists and that serves those customers
Speaker 6:  better because they can swap out that computer without having to like deal
Speaker 6:  with the whole thing. And the audience for
Speaker 6:  imax, which we all know, is you go into a spa or a fancy
Speaker 6:  doctor's office or whatever and they are sitting there on the desk as they're
Speaker 6:  checking computers. Yes. At the reception
Speaker 2:  Or your kitchen according to Apple, while you cook, you just like hang out
Speaker 2:  on your iMac like a super cool guy.
Speaker 6:  Same. Yeah, I, I can't wait to read divorce notes of like the husband insisted
Speaker 6:  on putting the iMac in the kitchen so they got to, the wife was like, this
Speaker 6:  is invading my space. But yeah, that's the reality of it. So what we got
Speaker 6:  is You know, I'm glad that they didn't completely ignore the iMac like they
Speaker 6:  have for two and a half years that they did put a faster chip in it. But
Speaker 6:  everything else is exactly the same. It would've been great to have USBC
Speaker 6:  accessories 'cause I would've heavily replaced some of my older accessories.
Speaker 6:  These
Speaker 5:  Prices are goofy if I'm reading this correctly. The base
Speaker 5:  model iMac doesn't have USB ports.
Speaker 6:  It has two instead of four. So the base model,
Speaker 6:  this is the same as the M one generation. It has two US BBC ports on the
Speaker 6:  back. If you upgrade the processor to the higher bin version or whatever
Speaker 6:  it jumps up to four.
Speaker 5:  That's goofy.
Speaker 2:  Goofy All, right? We have spent now exactly as long talking about the event
Speaker 2:  as the event was itself. So we're, we're done here. This, this event deserves.
Speaker 2:  So more thank you guys. Dan, I'm assuming we will have reviews
Speaker 2:  of these at some point in the hopefully not to distant in future. So stay
Speaker 2:  tuned for that. Stay tuned.
Speaker 6:  Yep.
Speaker 2:  Thank you both. We gotta take a break and then we're gonna come back and
Speaker 2:  we're gonna talk about cameras like iPhones, which shoot events sometimes
Speaker 2:  at night. We'll be back
Speaker 3:  Support for this episode comes from Sonos. Me and the rest of The Vergecast
Speaker 3:  team are all audio professionals. And at The Verge we have an office full
Speaker 3:  of Sonos products. Personally I use the Sonos era 300 in
Speaker 3:  particular a lot. It's an all-in-one plugin smart speaker designed for immersive
Speaker 3:  sound and spatial audio listening out loud. Its breakthrough acoustic design
Speaker 3:  projects sound from wall to wall and floor to ceiling, allowing listeners
Speaker 3:  to feel like the music and sound is all around them no matter where you are
Speaker 3:  in the room or what you play. The listening experiences. Nothing short of
Speaker 3:  extraordinary. For a full immersive home theater experience, you could take
Speaker 3:  two era three hundreds and use them as your Dolby Atmos surround speakers
Speaker 3:  when paired with an arc or beam and my favorite feature, it actually has
Speaker 3:  a three and a half millimeter Jack So I can plug in literally anything to
Speaker 3:  this device. You can also connect the ERA 300 to a turntable CD
Speaker 3:  player or other audio device using the USBC port. Also know speakers
Speaker 3:  connect wirelessly over wifi so you can group speakers in different rooms
Speaker 3:  and experience the joy of multi-room listening. Visit sonos.com to learn
Speaker 3:  more about ERA 300 and find thoughtful gifts for every listener on your list.
Speaker 2:  We're back right at the end of the Apple thing. The other night there was
Speaker 2:  this little notice on the stream that said the event had been shot on an
Speaker 2:  iPhone, an iPhone 15 pro Max I think and
Speaker 2:  edited on a Mac, which is impressive given all the dark shots and
Speaker 2:  swoopy drone stuff and the huge empty rooms and the tricky camera moves.
Speaker 2:  It was a pretty good flex from Apple. But how big a flex
Speaker 2:  really? That's the question for me. The event was shot on an iPhone, but
Speaker 2:  as we saw in some of the behind the scenes footage, it was an iPhone plus
Speaker 2:  like a room full of giant lights and a bunch of drones and gimbals
Speaker 2:  and much more. They didn't just like put the phone in video mode and pointed
Speaker 2:  at Tim Cook You. know what I mean? And I don't mean that as a dig. That's
Speaker 2:  not how anyone ever shoots anything professional. And this is still really
Speaker 2:  cool. And actually one of the things I thought was interesting was one of
Speaker 2:  the folks who produced the event said that it was remarkable how not different
Speaker 2:  it was to use the iPhone. Here's a clip from the behind the scenes shot.
Speaker 7:  We're able to get the same complex shots on such a small device similar
Speaker 7:  to how we would do any traditional camera. We're on cranes,
Speaker 7:  dollies, drone shots,
Speaker 3:  Drones going up.
Speaker 2:  This all raises a question we've been kind of asking all year, how
Speaker 2:  good are smartphone cameras really? Have they gotten so
Speaker 2:  good over the last 15 years that we've stopped noticing the ways they keep
Speaker 2:  getting better but they continue to be mind blowing. Are they going
Speaker 2:  to be as good as or better than big pro level cameras anytime
Speaker 2:  soon? We've been made these grand promises about the evolution of smartphone
Speaker 2:  cameras. Where are we on that road to figure that out? I grabbed Becca
Speaker 2:  Farsace who has been running around all summer and fall taking photos and
Speaker 2:  video with all of these new high-end smartphones. And we're gonna get to
Speaker 2:  the bottom of this Becca Welcome back to The Vergecast. Thanks
Speaker 8:  For having me.
Speaker 2:  Let's talk cameras. 'cause you've been doing tests of really the
Speaker 2:  iPhone and the Pixel are the two I'm I'm most curious about. And I think
Speaker 2:  the biggest question that I've had over the course of this year is
Speaker 2:  where are we in smartphone cameras? I feel like we've, we've been on this
Speaker 2:  trend of like smartphone cameras are getting really good, really fast, better
Speaker 2:  every year. They're eventually going to be as good as pro cameras. Just you
Speaker 2:  wait, it's, and I feel like that idea has really aggressively plateaued for
Speaker 2:  me the last couple of years. But then Apple comes out and they're like, it's
Speaker 2:  the most pro whenever you can You know, use video out through USBC. This
Speaker 2:  is a pro camera. Where are we in smartphone cameras.
Speaker 8:  Okay, question for you. When was the last time you were impressed with the
Speaker 8:  smartphone camera?
Speaker 2:  Like truly like blown away, impressed. I think the,
Speaker 2:  the cinematic mode on the iPhone was the first one in a long
Speaker 2:  time. It had been a while before that, but the cinematic mode on the iPhone
Speaker 2:  was a moment that I was like, holy crap, this takes a thing I couldn't do
Speaker 2:  before and works. I can now. All of my like
Speaker 2:  awful video walking down the street now looks passable.
Speaker 2:  But just in terms of like the photos I get out of a phone, it's been years.
Speaker 8:  Okay. Talk to me about cinematic mode. Do you still use it
Speaker 2:  Occasionally? It's one of those things that I use when I remember to turn
Speaker 2:  it on. Okay. Which I think is the problem with a lot of phone cameras is
Speaker 2:  they have a lot of cool features that are six swipes away and thus I
Speaker 2:  don't use them.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. And that's something about the Pixel eight pro and the Pixel
Speaker 8:  eights camera system that I will we'll talk about in a bit. Okay. Interesting.
Speaker 8:  Cinematic mode. Okay. And And that basically cinematic mode applies a blur
Speaker 8:  effect to the background of your videos. It makes them look a bit more what
Speaker 8:  some would call professional. It came in the iPhone 13 I believe.
Speaker 8:  Maybe just the pro,
Speaker 2:  I think it started in the pro and has since worked its way down. Yeah. And
Speaker 2:  it like stabilizes things as you're walking. It just, it just feels,
Speaker 8:  Adds a little bit of a color look better.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Yeah. And so all the things where you're like, I want, I wanna walk
Speaker 2:  through something as I'm taking video and it used to just feel jumpy and
Speaker 2:  bad. It smooths it out in a way that like I will actually watch those videos
Speaker 2:  later.
Speaker 8:  Cool. And that's a software? Yeah that That's software. Yeah. Okay. So really
Speaker 8:  you weren't impressed with the camera, you were just impressed with software.
Speaker 8:  That's fair. That this company added. That's fair. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Okay.
Speaker 8:  That's fair. Hardware side of things. It is very slow. But the way I look
Speaker 8:  at it, like I think You know you entered this question kind of comparing
Speaker 8:  them to You know standalone cameras, cameras that have interchangeable lenses
Speaker 8:  or that we only use to take photos and there's just really no comparison
Speaker 8:  to me because the experience is so different. Okay. Like when I pick
Speaker 8:  up a smartphone to take a photo, like it feels like I'm picking up a brick
Speaker 8:  and I'm pointing it at someone and they know the etiquette, they know what
Speaker 8:  to do. But when I pick up like a camera that's made to take photos, it
Speaker 8:  feels different. I feel like my purpose is to only take photos and the person
Speaker 8:  who's standing in front of me all of a sudden is a lot more nervous. And
Speaker 8:  so they're two like very different things. So now if we talk about
Speaker 8:  just phones and their cameras, do we think that they are
Speaker 8:  progressing me meaningfully? Maybe like every three years. Okay.
Speaker 8:  Every three years. I feel like if you look at like the iPhone 12
Speaker 8:  and you compare it to the 15, there is a big difference in quality.
Speaker 8:  That's fair. And I, I would know because I use an iPhone 12. Nice.
Speaker 8:  But if I look at the 14 to the 15, yeah, no, you're not gonna notice a
Speaker 8:  difference.
Speaker 2:  Right. And I guess that's fair. I mean that's like the upgrade cycle of a
Speaker 2:  phone now, right? Yes. People are keeping them for three, four, or five years.
Speaker 2:  So if, if you're feeling that upgrade every time you actually upgrade your
Speaker 2:  phone, maybe that still counts. But I just can't let go of this idea that
Speaker 2:  for, I don't know, the last say eight years, we have been told it's sort
Speaker 2:  of right around the corner where your phone's photos are going to
Speaker 2:  be possibly the same as what you'd get from A-D-S-L-R or
Speaker 2:  a Fuji Street camera that people run around with for thousands of dollars
Speaker 2:  or whatever. I
Speaker 8:  Love the Fuji Street camera. I love that one. This is what I
Speaker 2:  Call that, that I don't like. There's a million of them and they're, they're
Speaker 2:  all X one whatever. They're just the Fuji Street camera. But I just don't
Speaker 2:  feel like we're getting closer to that at this point. I feel like we're teaching
Speaker 2:  these cameras to do new things on smartphone, which are cool. But just in
Speaker 2:  terms of like how my photos and videos look, I don't
Speaker 2:  necessarily feel like I've gotten much closer to,
Speaker 2:  I truly won't miss my camera in a while.
Speaker 8:  Okay. Back to your point about like forgetting to turn on cinematic mode.
Speaker 8:  There are settings if, let's talk about the iPhone for a moment. Sure. 'cause
Speaker 8:  I think it actually, I do think the iPhone 15 pros camera comes close
Speaker 8:  in some ways Okay. To some standalone cameras, but you have to be
Speaker 8:  willing to click some buttons. Okay. And I don't think you're gonna
Speaker 8:  be that person. And I don't think phones are like, I don't think they're
Speaker 8:  trying to have you pick it up and like take the photo that maybe
Speaker 8:  you imagine that a standalone camera takes, right? That's right. You have
Speaker 8:  to like go in and and tune some things. Right. Which
Speaker 2:  Again goes back to your point about like the object itself. Like you just
Speaker 2:  have all that stuff one thumb movement away when you pick up
Speaker 2:  a big camera in a way that on your phone it's actually like buried in settings,
Speaker 2:  venues. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  Buried in settings. And also not one thumb. Yeah. My God. I mean these
Speaker 8:  things are huge. Like I had tiny hands and reaching across the screen sucks
Speaker 8:  and, and I'm less likely to push buttons that are across the screen. So let's
Speaker 8:  make them small.
Speaker 2:  Okay. So like what would, what do you do on the 15 pro to get
Speaker 2:  there?
Speaker 8:  Oh, I'm so excited. Let me tell you about it. Please. So there is like a
Speaker 8:  48 megapixel mode, right. And you can turn that on and you can take a photo
Speaker 8:  like I find faces. It's gonna find faces. It's like it loves faces. Yep.
Speaker 8:  And if you are say like five feet away from somebody and then
Speaker 8:  the, the background is like far beyond them, you'll actually start to get
Speaker 8:  some depth. Like some, some like natural depth because the sensors are
Speaker 8:  actually getting bigger and the lenses are bigger and You know, like
Speaker 8:  real camera things are starting to happen. And
Speaker 2:  So much of that is physics. Like you need space for those things.
Speaker 8:  Real physics. Yeah. Yeah. Can I explain it? Well, some days
Speaker 2:  I know big sensors good
Speaker 8:  Big sensor good. Bigger lenses. Good. Got that. Sometimes more
Speaker 8:  megapixels fine. Yeah. But yeah, you're starting to get like some
Speaker 8:  real depth. I especially notice it if I, if I turn on like You
Speaker 8:  know raw photos, 48 megapixels, blah blah blah. And I flip the
Speaker 8:  camera around and I take a photo of myself with the main camera, like
Speaker 8:  that distance from like, I don't know, maybe that's two feet on me that
Speaker 8:  like I'm gonna actually see depth and you can compare that to like You know
Speaker 8:  some of the, the lower end Sony cameras. Okay. And it's like
Speaker 8:  not terribly far off. You know something that has like a smaller sensor
Speaker 8:  like an AP PSC sensor. Like it's looking pretty good and the colors
Speaker 8:  are really nice. I mean Apple has always kind of had really
Speaker 8:  great color science. Yeah. And, and so it's just like for me I love like
Speaker 8:  a little bit more blue and so like denim, oh my God. The way it reproduces
Speaker 8:  denim. I'm just like, wow, I'm gonna wear this denim jacket every day.
Speaker 2:  So All. right. Well what else? I feel like to me the thing on the 15 that
Speaker 2:  has actually been the biggest improvement is the fact that you can now do
Speaker 2:  portrait after. Which goes back to your point of like, I don't have to remember
Speaker 2:  the thing anymore. I can just take the picture and figure out what
Speaker 2:  to do with it later. Yeah. Which is a weird, like, we like to talk about
Speaker 2:  what is a photo? There's like a weird philosophical question behind all that.
Speaker 2:  But just like leaving that aside, it's nice that I don't have to sit there
Speaker 2:  and go, oh I have two seconds to get this like cute photo of my dog doing
Speaker 2:  a funny thing. I don't have to swipe it to portrait and then try to, it says
Speaker 2:  like back up. You're too close. And then I have to and I've just missed it.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Now you just take the picture and it does the thing sometimes,
Speaker 8:  But Yeah. Most
Speaker 2:  The time. Yeah. But I wonder how much we can put that in
Speaker 2:  software because like you Yeah. You spend a lot of time, one of my favorite
Speaker 2:  things is to be in The Verge office and just watch you or
Speaker 2:  someone else on the video team set up a camera because it's such a good reminder
Speaker 2:  of like, you like that there's so much time of just you, you hit a button
Speaker 2:  and then you look at the screen and you look at the histogram, you're like,
Speaker 2:  Hmm, that's not it. And then you hit more buttons and it's just like there's
Speaker 2:  work that goes into doing this stuff that all these companies are trying
Speaker 2:  to abstract out. Yeah. On your phone. I wonder how possible that is
Speaker 2:  ever going to be and if the, if the answer is just give people more knobs,
Speaker 2:  now we're back to like the user interface for that on a phone is just never
Speaker 2:  quite gonna work.
Speaker 8:  I think it can get really good. It can get really good and I, I see a world
Speaker 8:  where You know the iPhone starts suggesting more like try
Speaker 8:  portrait mode on this. So it's like even more like you're not thinking about
Speaker 8:  it. I mean Google has proven time and time again with their camera systems
Speaker 8:  that like software can do a lot. True.
Speaker 2:  And there is an amazing amount you can do in post,
Speaker 8:  Oh my god. An amazing amount if you feel like digging and then also manipulating
Speaker 8:  images. But I do wanna, I mean, flat out software can do a lot. I
Speaker 8:  don't know where we're headed. I don't have an answer for like, oh yeah.
Speaker 8:  In 10 years, like all of our photos are gonna have this great blur and it's
Speaker 8:  gonna look more natural and the cutout's gonna be better. I don't know. That's
Speaker 8:  what I love about my job is that like I get a new product and I get to be
Speaker 8:  like, oh, did this happen this year? But back to like the, what is a photo?
Speaker 8:  Like I love this question. I love thinking about it. I think about it a lot.
Speaker 8:  I don't think phones like really take photos anymore. I mean they take photos,
Speaker 8:  but like they're manipulating so much of the color. They're like, I mean,
Speaker 8:  and then now you can like change anything you want. Like you can take a photo
Speaker 8:  on iPhone and put it in Google photos and change everything. So like
Speaker 8:  these to me aren't like, let's stop like asking yourself like what is a photo?
Speaker 8:  Like, I mean like,
Speaker 2:  First of all, I will never stop asking that question.
Speaker 8:  Go ahead. Keep asking and I'll, I'll,
Speaker 2:  I'll fire me if I stop asking that question. No, somebody described it to
Speaker 2:  me relatively recently, which I thought was really interesting. Ooh, let
Speaker 2:  me hear. What we're doing with our phone cameras now is to
Speaker 2:  photography. What, like the cameras spinning around on
Speaker 2:  top of the Google maps mapping things are Hmm. Where they are like
Speaker 2:  they are fundamentally data collection devices. Yeah. And then you can
Speaker 2:  do all kinds of interesting things with the data. Google uses it to map roads,
Speaker 2:  it uses it to get street view. It uses it to find places, it uses it for
Speaker 2:  AR and Google Maps. Like all this stuff. Technically what it is capturing
Speaker 2:  is video. Yes. But the point of it is not the video, the point of it is the
Speaker 2:  data inside of the video. And they were like, that's just what our phones
Speaker 2:  are now. They're Yeah. Collecting a bunch of data about their surroundings
Speaker 2:  that you then manipulate to be whatever you want. Yeah. And I was like, that's
Speaker 2:  a cool way of thinking about it that is fundamentally not photography. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  But it is a really interesting way of thinking about like what happens when
Speaker 2:  I hit the button on my camera. Well
Speaker 8:  Let's also think about like what you're taking photos of. I, I mean, I'll
Speaker 8:  tell you what, I take photos of like receipts
Speaker 2:  You and denim jackets
Speaker 8:  Me and denim. Yeah. The top number one is me and denim
Speaker 8:  number two is receipts. Yep. Number three is like I, I'll just like,
Speaker 8:  oh, I wanna remember this restaurant. Let me just take a photo of it 'cause
Speaker 8:  that's quicker. Totally. Like I'm not really taking like photos.
Speaker 8:  I mean I like, I'm collecting data as you're saying. And so like I don't
Speaker 8:  have this big problem around like, oh, our phones don't take photos. It's
Speaker 8:  like, I just need it to like collect information. You know and like, and
Speaker 8:  then I'm gonna send that information to my friends and they can see that
Speaker 8:  I, I don't know, went swimming and it was really fun. And that's
Speaker 8:  just data to them too on me. Right?
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Andrew, our producer was saying to me before we started that we're
Speaker 2:  still in this phase where if you shoot something on a smartphone, you always
Speaker 2:  say you shot it on a smartphone that like every magazine cover, nobody talks
Speaker 2:  about the camera that they use, but they'll always tell you that they shot
Speaker 2:  it on an iPhone. I love this. I do too. And, and it's, and it's so true.
Speaker 2:  And it's like I, I could name you the movies that Steven Soderberg shot with
Speaker 2:  an iPhone. I could not for one second tell you what camera he uses when it's
Speaker 2:  not an iPhone. Right. Okay. And that to me goes to either we're just doing
Speaker 2:  different things with different goals or phones are not getting
Speaker 2:  anywhere near the realm of the other stuff because the camera shouldn't matter.
Speaker 8:  Disagree. I think if everyone actually knew cameras, like I would love to
Speaker 8:  know what every magazine cover is shot on because I know cameras, right.
Speaker 8:  Everyone knows phones. So of course if you tell 'em, oh it was shot on an
Speaker 8:  iPhone, it's like they know what that is. If you show told 'em it was shot
Speaker 8:  on like a Nikon Z nine. That's
Speaker 2:  True. But I also think part of it is like proving it's still such a novelty
Speaker 2:  that you can take a cool photo on a phone. Yeah. And, what they don't show
Speaker 2:  you is that you have to do twice as much lighting. Yeah. And work way harder
Speaker 2:  to get that photo to look good on a phone. Yes. Such that it will exist on
Speaker 2:  a magazine cover. Yeah. But I just think it's still like, oh my God, you
Speaker 2:  can take a good photo with a phone. And to me it's like until we're way past
Speaker 2:  that where it's
Speaker 8:  Like, it's like, wait, you don't believe that? Are you still at that point
Speaker 8:  where you're shocked that you can take a good photo on a phone? No,
Speaker 2:  But everybody is,
Speaker 8:  You think they are?
Speaker 2:  It's still such a novelty that you can do something cool on a phone. Like
Speaker 2:  can we
Speaker 8:  Pull the audience?
Speaker 2:  Marquez Brownley started a whole new YouTube channel where he shoots stuff
Speaker 2:  on his phone and part of the shtick is I'm shooting it on my phone to prove
Speaker 2:  that you can,
Speaker 8:  And it's genius because then he is also just like testing the phone at the
Speaker 8:  same time. Oh it's
Speaker 2:  Great. Smart. And the channel's great's so smart. The kids he played, he
Speaker 2:  did it all extremely well and very smart. And he just like sits next to cars
Speaker 2:  and films himself doing selfie videos. Yeah. Great job. But it is, we're
Speaker 2:  still at the point where like I can do this on my phone is like mind blowing
Speaker 2:  to lots of people.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. Interesting. I would love to hear from folks if you agree or disagree
Speaker 8:  with that because I don't know, like I remember Casey Nys stat was shooting
Speaker 8:  videos and like, I don't know, on his like Samsung Galaxy S seven
Speaker 8:  or something. Yeah. And like that I was like, whoa, that's crazy.
Speaker 8:  But that was like six years. No, that had to be more than six years ago.
Speaker 8:  That had to be like eight years ago now. Yeah. So. I. Guess that Novelty's
Speaker 8:  like gone to me. Like it's, there's no doubt you can take a good photo on
Speaker 8:  a phone. That's fair. And so then your point of like, are we gonna get any
Speaker 8:  better? It's like, yeah, marginally, but
Speaker 8:  like we can already do all the things that we wanna do on them. Yeah. So
Speaker 8:  then the bigger question for me that I get a lot is like, why would I buy
Speaker 8:  a standalone camera? Like I really believe that people think that their phone
Speaker 8:  cameras are good enough. And so then I ask them like, well what do you wanna
Speaker 8:  do? Like what do you think a camera can give you that your phone isn't right?
Speaker 8:  And it's always experience. And that's like where I base all of my like
Speaker 8:  reviews around is like, what is the experience of holding this thing? What
Speaker 8:  is the experience of using this thing? Like that's what it is for me because
Speaker 8:  we can all take a good photo. I even have, oh, I should have brought that.
Speaker 8:  I have the first iPhone. Right. Nice. And like the camera on it. I
Speaker 8:  love it takes good photos. Like And, what does good mean? Okay.
Speaker 8:  They're exposed well enough. Sure. You can see things
Speaker 8:  well enough. Like the color's fine, it's kind of in focus,
Speaker 8:  but the experience is so fun and like I, there's just, yeah.
Speaker 8:  So like, yeah, phones will get better, but like, I think everyone believes
Speaker 8:  that what they have in their pocket is actually pretty good. Good.
Speaker 2:  This is my point. You're grading on a curve. We're still grading phones on
Speaker 2:  a curve. Like it's because they're phones. Like you're, you're not replacing
Speaker 2:  your professional gear. You still carry 11 Pelican pieces every time
Speaker 2:  you wanna shoot something.
Speaker 8:  No, I carry one Pelican case and it's got a lot of stickers and it's very
Speaker 8:  cute and we love her. What are you talking about? 11? I don't even, I don't
Speaker 8:  have, I don't have enough hands for that.
Speaker 2:  There's like a van that follows Becca around every time you go to shoot something.
Speaker 2:  That's all.
Speaker 8:  Boy, I wish, if anyone wants to drive that van, it has
Speaker 8:  that van hit me up.
Speaker 2:  Okay, let's switch gears a little bit. Just before we have to go, I'm curious
Speaker 2:  about the differences between the iPhone 15 and I guess
Speaker 2:  specifically the iPhone 15 Pro, which is like Yeah, the camera, east camera.
Speaker 2:  Oh yes. And the Pixel eight Pro. And we were talking about this on the show
Speaker 2:  a couple weeks ago that like we've sort of settled into a place where those
Speaker 2:  two companies and Samsung to some extent too, have different ideas
Speaker 2:  about photos. Yeah. But everybody had kind of settled into their lane and
Speaker 2:  it's like we'd gotten to a point where I think you could fairly reliably
Speaker 2:  look at a photo and guess which company Yeah. Made the phone that
Speaker 2:  it captured. You've spent a bunch of time with the Pixel and the iPhone.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Over the last couple of months. Is that still the case? Are they kind
Speaker 2:  of in their own lane about what their photos should look like?
Speaker 8:  I think we are all coming together to the
Speaker 8:  most collective. We think this photo looks good.
Speaker 2:  Interesting. Okay. I
Speaker 8:  Really do. We do this fun thing. I do this fun thing and then I see who will
Speaker 8:  take the bait. When I'm doing these photo comparisons, I basically start
Speaker 8:  the edit. Here's some like video jargon for you or some background on my
Speaker 8:  process. I start the edit before I even start the script because like I just
Speaker 8:  take so many photos, like I really take over a thousand photos
Speaker 8:  and then I put them all next to each other in the timeline. And I sit there
Speaker 8:  and I watch a blank timeline. Sometimes I put music in just for fun and I
Speaker 8:  just like watch the slideshow happen. Mm. And then I screenshot it
Speaker 8:  and I send it to people and I'm like, okay, these are three different phones.
Speaker 8:  Tell me which one's which. And like I would say one person always takes the
Speaker 8:  bait and that's Verin. My boss and coworker, he's like a photo
Speaker 8:  person. He can't even, he can't even tell anymore. Sometimes I can't even
Speaker 8:  tell. Sometimes they're like, oh wait, I forgot. Let me go look at the file
Speaker 8:  names. Interesting.
Speaker 2:  Like
Speaker 8:  We are really coming to like the point of like, this is what the most people
Speaker 8:  think is a good photo. And that's what all of the, the, the North
Speaker 8:  star for all of these companies is.
Speaker 2:  So what, what are the characteristics of that? I'm assuming it's a little
Speaker 2:  extra saturation everywhere. We love dynamic range. Oh my god. My God. We
Speaker 2:  love dynamic range. Doesn't,
Speaker 8:  Can't get enough.
Speaker 2:  The number one most we love dynamic range. Yes. Let me see the sky and
Speaker 2:  and the ground. Let's do this. Yes. Ugh. Yes.
Speaker 8:  Ugh. And the shadows like the man lurking in the back. Exactly. Want him
Speaker 8:  too.
Speaker 2:  And I would think that everything, you wouldn't want it to be too colorful,
Speaker 2:  but you'd want it to be like 3% extra colorful.
Speaker 2:  I don't know. You tell me. What are you seeing
Speaker 8:  You know? I think the, the dynamic range is actually interesting 'cause I
Speaker 8:  think there's like a pendulum, right. And I think companies really swung
Speaker 8:  out on the dynamic range. Yeah. And it was like all of a sudden everything
Speaker 8:  was not believable. Which is funny that like Yeah
Speaker 2:  Like sometimes things are dark. Yeah. Which phones forgot for a while.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. Like I, I see shadows and that's okay. And So I think we we're now
Speaker 8:  we're like coming back to like more of a middle ground there. I think You
Speaker 8:  know white balance is really important. You know more. So there's
Speaker 8:  some like focus things happening. Like people do like a little depth of field
Speaker 8:  You know people do want things to be a little out of focus properly exposed.
Speaker 8:  But that's been good for a long time. But the big thing is the white balance
Speaker 8:  that used to be the differentiator between like Google and Apple
Speaker 8:  You know it was like the iPhone was always warmer and the Pixel
Speaker 8:  was always cooler. And now we're seeing the Pixel kind of like realize that
Speaker 8:  it was a little too cool Okay. And come towards Apple in that way.
Speaker 8:  But it does feel like the competition has always kind of been chasing Apple
Speaker 8:  and continues to. And I find that where their photos have been
Speaker 8:  consistent throughout cameras, the You know Pixel has changed
Speaker 8:  more and has adapted more to that style.
Speaker 2:  Okay. So you think we're we're headed towards a much more like coherent
Speaker 2:  version of what a smartphone photo looks like?
Speaker 8:  Yes. Because You know much like we don't label magazines with like what camera
Speaker 8:  took them like on Instagram. Like you don't know what everyone's phone,
Speaker 8:  who's everyone. True You know what what phone they have. And I think people
Speaker 8:  wanna like fit in on Instagram, right? So you want the photo that looks good
Speaker 8:  but also doesn't look too different from everyone else's. And You know
Speaker 8:  maybe if you're an iPhone user you wanna like call out your Android friends
Speaker 8:  and your Android friends just wanna live in peace All. right. It's
Speaker 2:  Just they're doing fine. Yeah. Just leave them alone. Fine.
Speaker 8:  All shut up. We don't care that we're green. That only affects you.
Speaker 2:  Wow. That's kind of deep. Actually we're gonna come back to that another
Speaker 2:  time. It's fine. So what about the like pro experience
Speaker 2:  of doing this? Obviously Apple made a bunch of noise about this is a pro
Speaker 2:  camera. Yeah. Having used these things kind of within an inch of their life.
Speaker 2:  Like is it, does it feel more pro? There's more stuff to do but I would not
Speaker 2:  say that's the same thing as being a pro camera.
Speaker 8:  No I, I think You know, obviously Pro is like marketing. It's like a way
Speaker 8:  to say this is the best phone but they can't call it like the iPhone
Speaker 8:  15 best
Speaker 2:  Max parentheses the the good one. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  I wish they would The better iPhone 15 pro,
Speaker 8:  the bigger better. Yeah that would be incredible. The smaller not so good.
Speaker 8:  I mean it's good. Nevermind So I mean all of that's marketing. Right. And
Speaker 8:  I was talking to some folks at Google at the event and I was kind
Speaker 8:  of picking their brain on like pro tools and pro this and pro that and You
Speaker 8:  know Google at the Pixel eight Pro didn't say this is for pros. Whereas
Speaker 8:  in the iPhone 15 pro Max they were like, this is for
Speaker 8:  pros. And Google's kind of stance on it was like You know if
Speaker 8:  folks who are professional photographers come to the system, they will have
Speaker 8:  tools that they recognize in their professional workflow and that's cool
Speaker 8:  and that's great. And they're like, and they honestly said to me, but we
Speaker 8:  find that most pros don't like You know they they pick up a
Speaker 8:  phone because they know that it's like the easy thing and they're not trying
Speaker 8:  to work with it. And, and I haven't spoken to Apple about this So I don't
Speaker 8:  know where they stand on it. The thing is they label everything pro but then
Speaker 8:  they don't give the pro tools, which it's like okay.
Speaker 8:  Like that's fine 'cause we've established that like pros aren't maybe using
Speaker 8:  this system for their professional work. Sure. But it does just kind of like
Speaker 8:  baffle me and I think it's just 'cause they want people to buy apps and pay
Speaker 8:  for things You
Speaker 2:  Know. I think that's right. And I do think there, there's potentially more
Speaker 2:  interesting stuff to come on the third party side. Like what we've seen from
Speaker 2:  the third party camera apps in the last few months has been really interesting.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And there's potentially a lot more to do there. And I, and
Speaker 8:  I wanna shout out all the developers there. Like I did feel bad when I You
Speaker 8:  know I made this whole like a thousand photos with the iPhone 15 pro and
Speaker 8:  I went to the desert and it was sick and I drove in sand for the first time
Speaker 8:  and I'm nice addicted. I just wanna like, ooh, whip through the sand
Speaker 8:  anyway. And in that I was like, You know Apple, if you wanna be a programmer
Speaker 8:  you have to have like pro controls. And I, and I didn't really mention and
Speaker 8:  shout out all the folks who like have built pro controls for
Speaker 8:  the iPhone and there's many good ones that I wish
Speaker 8:  I could list off for you right now. And I, and I can't just pull them outta
Speaker 8:  my brain like that. But there's lots of folks that are building really good
Speaker 8:  tools if you're interested in that. And I think it is cool that there is
Speaker 8:  like a marketplace for those people to make what they love and do what they
Speaker 8:  love. So
Speaker 2:  Yeah, totally All, right? We have to go but before we do, okay. You have
Speaker 2:  to tell me. Yeah. Only one answer. Okay. What is the best smartphone for
Speaker 2:  taking pictures and video right now?
Speaker 8:  Oh my god. Okay. Can I tell you what it's not? No.
Speaker 8:  Aw. Okay. Well it's the first gen iPhone. It's gorgeous.
Speaker 8:  It, it has like a filmic quality. It makes the cutest noise.
Speaker 8:  It's really slow and she's just so cute to hold in your hands and
Speaker 8:  everybody's like, oh my God, what is that? And then you get to open the camera
Speaker 8:  and take a photo and everyone is just like amazed and it
Speaker 8:  warms my whole heart. I, it's a great bar trick. I've been doing it a lot.
Speaker 2:  It's actually a really good answer. I'll allow that. I was not gonna allow
Speaker 2:  that when you started talking and now I will allow that. I
Speaker 8:  Get it outta my desk.
Speaker 2:  What is the future of Polaroids is just like first gen iPhones that they
Speaker 2:  just like make a comeback as the new retro camera that everybody's obsessed
Speaker 8:  With and they're gonna sell 'em on Urban Outfitters where they're selling
Speaker 8:  the iPod. God and Urban Outfitters is gonna make a killing.
Speaker 8:  Becca,
Speaker 2:  This is gonna happen now you just did this and I'm gonna be so upset with
Speaker 2:  you when this happens.
Speaker 8:  No, you're gonna love it. But also I
Speaker 2:  Will buy one.
Speaker 8:  It's the greatest experience. Get 'em on eBay while you can. Everybody
Speaker 2:  All right? We gotta take a break. Becca, thank you so much. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Support for this episode comes from Sonos experience fully immersive
Speaker 3:  sound with the new era 300 smart speaker from Sonos. It's a spatial audio
Speaker 3:  speaker that doesn't just surround you with sound, it puts you inside your
Speaker 3:  music. Plus you can pair two era three hundreds with a Sonos arc or beam
Speaker 3:  soundbar for the ultimate in home theater experience. The ERA 300 is easy
Speaker 3:  to set up and even easier to use with the Sonos app, your voice and apple
Speaker 3:  airplay too. Unlock the most innovative spatial listening experience with
Speaker 3:  the era 300. Visit sonos.com to learn more and find thoughtful
Speaker 3:  gifts for everyone on your list.
Speaker 2:  All right, we're back. Let's get to the Hotline as always. The number is
Speaker 2:  8 6 6 Verge one one and the email is Vergecast at The Verge dot com.
Speaker 2:  We love all your questions, call us, email us, bring us the weirdest thing
Speaker 2:  you can think of and we always try to answer at least one on the show every
Speaker 2:  week. This week we have a question about VR and AR and XR and
Speaker 2:  mixed reality and all these new things about glasses on your face.
Speaker 2:  So, I, grab Daddy Robertson, who knows this space better than anybody. Addie,
Speaker 2:  thanks for being here. Hi, this is about a product that of the people at
Speaker 2:  The Verge only you and I have used so far, So, I'm just gonna play you the
Speaker 2:  question and we're gonna go from there. Sound good? Sounds good. All right,
Speaker 2:  let's do it. It's from Peter.
Speaker 9:  Hi guys, this is Peter. Long time listener, first time caller. I love what
Speaker 9:  you do but I am at a little bit of an impasse. I'm a big
Speaker 9:  proponent of the future and of potential for spatial
Speaker 9:  computing. I love this idea of the Apple Vision Pro headset and I'm excited
Speaker 9:  to try it out. But I recently saw a really good
Speaker 9:  review of the Xreal glasses formerly called N
Speaker 9:  Reel Glasses and I think you guys were talking about them recently too. And
Speaker 9:  I can't help but wonder if this really is something that
Speaker 9:  captures 90% of the use cases
Speaker 9:  that I'm particularly, that I'm going to use the Apple Vision Pro for at
Speaker 9:  one 10th of the price and much more convenient form factor, no battery,
Speaker 9:  much lighter. You can pop it in your pocket. I really feel like we need to
Speaker 9:  think about this and this might be closer to where we're heading
Speaker 9:  than the big heavy Apple Vision Pro thoughts. Thank you.
Speaker 2:  I love this question but I wanna know like right off the top what you think.
Speaker 10:  Okay, So I just have to caveat a, I'm assuming we're talking
Speaker 10:  about the NRE or sorry, the Xreal errors,
Speaker 10:  not the Xreal lights. That's correct. The Xreal airs are the new headset
Speaker 10:  and I am also going to only be able to talk about this from really a theoretical
Speaker 10:  perspective perspective. Haven't used the Vision Pro have just played a
Speaker 10:  bit with the new Xreal glasses. I think it depends on what
Speaker 10:  you see 90% of the use cases as being that Apple has
Speaker 10:  all of this sort of, you'll be able to do situational things kind
Speaker 10:  of promise going on that the idea is that it can sense your surroundings
Speaker 10:  to some extent that it can pin things to your desk or your wall or
Speaker 10:  it can give the illusion that it has actual
Speaker 10:  virtual objects in your real space. And that is a thing you will not get
Speaker 10:  at all with the new Xreal headset that that is
Speaker 10:  purely, it's like imagine you stuck a tablet up in front of your face and
Speaker 10:  the tablet was always there and the tablet was also like slightly
Speaker 10:  transparent, especially in light. Those are the downsides of Xreal. The
Speaker 10:  upsides is that in a lot of ways I agree with you A, you have a
Speaker 10:  thing that is not tied to Apple's ecosystem
Speaker 10:  or to a bunch of XR developers making things that it's really just you
Speaker 10:  plug it in, you see a screen in front of your face, it's incredibly convenient
Speaker 10:  B, that you can see everything else. Actually you're not
Speaker 10:  passing through a video feed, which is just kind of almost inherently
Speaker 10:  going to be lower resolution and an inferior experience to the real world.
Speaker 10:  And C yeah, they're kind of surprisingly comfortable even compared
Speaker 10:  to the older Xreal glasses. And I haven't tried the Vision Pro, but
Speaker 10:  it's, it's a big thing.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, it's, it's less comfortable I can say with great confidence. Okay.
Speaker 2:  Yeah,
Speaker 10:  So yeah, I really think people should be giving this a look. I'm not necessarily
Speaker 10:  clear that it's a super viable product yet and I haven't had a chance to
Speaker 10:  seriously review it, but I am similarly optimistic about it. I think Xreal
Speaker 10:  iss a really interesting company.
Speaker 2:  I agree. And I, I think your your point about it depends on what 90% of your
Speaker 2:  use cases are is really right. 'cause it, the thing that Xreal has done for
Speaker 2:  me is make it very clear that the Vision Pros idea of
Speaker 2:  a $3,500 device that essentially puts a bunch of virtual computer
Speaker 2:  monitors in the air and you'll sit there with your mouse and keyboard
Speaker 2:  and use a headset to be a bunch of monitors that is gonna be,
Speaker 2:  if not like, totally commoditized very soon then like not worth
Speaker 2:  $3,500 because that's fundamentally what the extra glasses are. Right? Like,
Speaker 2:  like you said, they are, they are just computer monitors I imagine plugging
Speaker 2:  any device you have into a monitor that just floats in front of your face.
Speaker 2:  So if that's your use case, Xreal is pretty good. I don't
Speaker 2:  think it'll be as good as a lot of the Subdivision Pro is doing, but it does
Speaker 2:  the job fairly well. To me, the biggest downside of these glasses so far
Speaker 2:  and really a lot of these sort of plug and play products is just the
Speaker 2:  interface. Like holding up my phone while
Speaker 2:  watching something through the Xreal glasses is cool 'cause I can just like
Speaker 2:  lean back and watch on a big screen, but I'm still navigating on my phone,
Speaker 2:  which means I'm constantly looking down at my phone and kind of
Speaker 2:  losing the thing. Whereas You know the Vision Pro and the meta stuff has
Speaker 2:  native interactions and it feels like you're in a space as opposed to this
Speaker 2:  much hacker feeling thing that is the glasses. So again, it's, it's a much
Speaker 2:  less elegant system but if the goal is like I need more screens in front
Speaker 2:  of my face while I sit at my computer, like Excel's pretty close,
Speaker 10:  I think it also, a phone is kind of the worst way to interact with it. That's
Speaker 2:  True.
Speaker 10:  I was using it with a steam deck and the steam deck is basically just, I'm
Speaker 10:  holding a controller and I can see the screen in front of my face now and
Speaker 10:  so it's just, I
Speaker 2:  Did it with the Switch for a while for the same reason. Yeah. Pretty much
Speaker 10:  Just like using a console.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And in that case it's very good. So I, think in general, like
Speaker 2:  we're, we're both pretty bullish on this kind of glasses,
Speaker 2:  right? I think is, is Xreal even like doing anything sort of
Speaker 2:  unusual or are they just sort of first in this space you've been paying attention
Speaker 2:  to these like wacky manufacturers of AR glasses longer than I have. Like
Speaker 2:  is is doing something special.
Speaker 10:  My sense is that they are just ruthlessly conceptually efficient.
Speaker 10:  Okay. That their first glasses were a bit more in
Speaker 10:  the, they have cameras and you can play sort of AR games and
Speaker 10:  you can pin things sort of to the floor and they
Speaker 10:  completely cut that. There's no cameras in the new glasses. It's just a
Speaker 10:  thing that sits there. It doesn't give any illusion of interacting with
Speaker 10:  space, but that also means that they can be really light. They can be, I'm
Speaker 10:  not gonna say normal looking, but more normal looking and they can be
Speaker 10:  comparatively really cheap. Yeah. And I think that they really have actually
Speaker 10:  just figured out there's a thing maybe we can make people want to do with
Speaker 10:  this and we're gonna deliver the best experience of that we can.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I said, I said on the show last week that I'm, I'm super intrigued
Speaker 2:  by this race between companies like Meta, which are basically saying we're
Speaker 2:  gonna take various stylish classes, start with essentially audio and then
Speaker 2:  try to figure out how to add more screen stuff to it. And companies like
Speaker 2:  Xra who are like, we have a screen, it looks kind of silly in in
Speaker 2:  comparison to like the RayBan's meta selling, but it has a screen
Speaker 2:  and we'll figure out how to do the rest of it later. And those two companies
Speaker 2:  are sort of running at each other from opposite directions and it's gonna
Speaker 2:  be interesting to see what happens. And then I think like the Quest and Vision
Speaker 2:  Pro stuff are just like all the way off in a different dimension and I think
Speaker 2:  it's not impossible that the simpler stuff is gonna end up being
Speaker 2:  way more appealing to way more people. I would not bet on that yet, but I
Speaker 2:  don't think that's outta the question.
Speaker 10:  Yeah, I think pass through has just really inherent limitations. I know
Speaker 10:  that there are cases that it's very good for, there are specific things
Speaker 10:  it's very good for, but as a really casual consumer device, it is not the
Speaker 10:  thing I'm most bullish on. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  That's fair. So $400 for, for Xra Glasses. Glasses, again we've,
Speaker 2:  we've only used them a very little bit like strikes me as a lot to spend,
Speaker 2:  they're, they're a little bit of a, a novelty but compared to You know whatever,
Speaker 2:  $3,500 for the Vision Pro next year, which isn't even shipping yet.
Speaker 2:  I guess it's a good deal. It's more than 10% is fun for 10%
Speaker 2:  of the price I guess. I don't know. Yeah,
Speaker 10:  I think that if you think what you need is a really versatile,
Speaker 10:  albeit imperfect screen that goes pretty much anywhere with
Speaker 10:  you and that has a level of privacy. If you're, I, I don't know,
Speaker 10:  somewhere you don't want people to see what you're doing and that you can
Speaker 10:  just really, as far as I can tell, plug into most things you own pretty
Speaker 10:  easily. It seems like a good early adopter thing.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, my main use case so far has been sitting here in this chair at
Speaker 2:  my desk like with feet up on my desk leaning back head sort of slightly
Speaker 2:  upwards with the glasses on playing video games with the controller in my
Speaker 2:  hand. And like you said, it's an excellent setup. The screen's not amazing,
Speaker 2:  neither is the switches, it does the job.
Speaker 10:  Yeah. My biggest problem so far is really just that you have to angle them
Speaker 10:  precisely to not get some really heavy blur at the bottom of the
Speaker 10:  screen. Yes.
Speaker 2:  I've spent a lot of time moving the nose pads around to get them
Speaker 2:  just so, and I eventually can get them there, but it is, it is a fair amount
Speaker 2:  of work. You're right. Yeah,
Speaker 10:  It, it's way better than the original, like the lights, but it's still
Speaker 10:  I think the biggest drawback to them. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  That's fair. All, right Addie, thank you as always. Appreciate it.
Speaker 1:  Yeah,
Speaker 2:  All right. That's it for The Vergecast today. Thanks to everybody who's on
Speaker 2:  the show and thank you as always for listening. There's lots more on everything
Speaker 2:  we talked about from becca's thousand photos series to all of the Apple coverage
Speaker 2:  on The Verge dot com. We'll put some links in the show notes, but read The
Speaker 2:  Verge dot com. It's a good website. As always, if you have thoughts, questions,
Speaker 2:  feelings, or other costumes you wish Tim Cook had worn, you can always email
Speaker 2:  us at Vergecast at The Verge dot com or keep calling the Hotline 8 6 6 VERGE
Speaker 2:  one, one. All your thoughts, questions, ideas, everything. We love it all
Speaker 2:  and we do, like I said, one Hotline question every week, so keep 'em coming.
Speaker 2:  This show is produced by Andrew Marino and Liam James Vergecast is VERGE
Speaker 2:  production and part of the Vox Media podcast network. Neli Alex now will
Speaker 2:  be back on Friday to talk inevitably more about Apple plus Sam bankman
Speaker 2:  free Google and all the other stuff happening in in tech. We'll see you then.
Speaker 2:  Rock and roll
Speaker 3:  Support for this episode comes from Sonos. Me and the rest of The Vergecast
Speaker 3:  team are all audio professionals. And at The Verge we have an office full
Speaker 3:  of Sonos products. Personally, I use the Sonos era 300 in particular
Speaker 3:  a lot. It's an all-in-one plugin smart speaker designed for immersive sound
Speaker 3:  and spatial audio listening out loud. Its breakthrough Acoustic design projects
Speaker 3:  sound from wall to wall and floor to ceiling, allowing listeners to feel
Speaker 3:  like the music and sound is all around them. No matter where you are in the
Speaker 3:  room or what you play, the listening experience is nothing short of extraordinary.
Speaker 3:  For a full immersive home theater experience, you could take two air three
Speaker 3:  hundreds and use them as your Dolby Atmos surround speakers When paired with
Speaker 3:  an arc or beam and my favorite feature, it actually has a three and a half
Speaker 3:  millimeter Jack So I can plug in literally anything to this device.
Speaker 3:  You can also connect the ERA 300 to a turntable CD player or other audio
Speaker 3:  device using the USBC port. Also know speakers connect wirelessly over
Speaker 3:  wifi so you can group speakers in different rooms and experience the joy
Speaker 3:  of multi-room listening. Visit sonos.com to learn more about ERA 300
Speaker 3:  and find thoughtful gifts for every listener on your list.