# Transcript
ID: 0b1a2dc7-26c9-4f73-a7e2-04cf6469791a
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Handheld gaming is the future — again
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/7991694728144790774/-597249312334330185/s93290-US-3281s-1699268144.mp3
Description: In the first episode of our series about the future of gaming, The Verge's David Pierce chats with Polygon's Chris Plante and Russ Frushtick about handheld game consoles. Is this portable, all-in-one form factor where all of gaming is headed?
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we love hearing from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (4 ads detected)
Speaker 4:  Welcome To. The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of Thumbs Sticks. I'm your
Speaker 4:  friend, David Pierce, and this is the first in a new mini series of
Speaker 4:  episodes that we've made all about the future of gaming. We're doing this
Speaker 4:  series, as you might expect with some of our friends from Polygon, Chris
Speaker 4:  Plant and Russ Frushtick. And we're gonna talk about some of the
Speaker 4:  biggest open questions and big ideas that we're thinking about
Speaker 4:  in the gaming world in general. It's gonna be very fun this week. For instance,
Speaker 4:  we're talking about handheld gaming. You know the, the switches and the steam
Speaker 4:  decks and the Rock allies and the analog pockets and
Speaker 4:  the Neo and all the things on Amazon whose names I
Speaker 4:  can't pronounce, but seem to be selling very well. Basically the question
Speaker 4:  is Is this portable all in one form factor.
Speaker 4:  The future of gaming like is the Game Boy Back. That's really all I want
Speaker 4:  to know. I'm gonna consult with Chris and Russ and then I'm gonna go out
Speaker 4:  and see if I can find some answers. I'm gonna talk to people, I'm gonna do
Speaker 4:  some research, and then I'm gonna bring back what I found out and see if
Speaker 4:  they agree about the future of gaming. Let's get into it.
Speaker 4:  Chris Plant. Hello.
Speaker 5:  Hey, how you doing?
Speaker 4:  Russ Frushtick. Hello. Hello. Welcome. To. The Vergecast. It's been a million
Speaker 4:  years since we've had Polygon people in The Vergecast, and it's because we
Speaker 4:  hate your guts. But I'm very excited to have both of you here. This is very
Speaker 4:  exciting.
Speaker 5:  I respect that sometimes you do need interesting things to talk about and
Speaker 5:  that's when we show up.
Speaker 4:  That sounds about right. And speaking up. So the way that we've set this
Speaker 4:  series up is basically for the next three episodes we're gonna take on sort
Speaker 4:  of three big things happening in gaming. And
Speaker 4:  the way it's gonna work is that I'm an idiot. That's not like a shtick. That's
Speaker 4:  just largely true, especially when it comes to video games and you guys are
Speaker 4:  not, so what what we're all gonna do is try and sort of answer questions
Speaker 4:  together and you're essentially going to send me on some adventure
Speaker 4:  and I'm gonna have to go figure out what is going on and come back and see
Speaker 4:  if I've learned anything real and true. That feels right. Does that make
Speaker 4:  sense to you guys? This work? Hell yeah.
Speaker 5:  Okay. That makes a lot of sense. I will also rebut, you're not an idiot.
Speaker 5:  I I wouldn't say that. I would say we know a lot about like the, the
Speaker 5:  beeps and the boops, right? We can talk about the Pac Mans and the Assassins
Speaker 5:  Creed. You have the brain that tells me how do these things work,
Speaker 5:  right? I, I feel like if I look at a sheet of code, I say throw it over
Speaker 5:  to The Verge, they'll figure it out. Also,
Speaker 6:  If I need a printer, I know the guy who's gonna get it for me.
Speaker 4:  Listen, if you need printers, we've got you. Yeah. So the first thing we've
Speaker 4:  decided to talk about, which I think is actually like a perfect crossover
Speaker 4:  of all of our interests, is handheld gaming. This is a thing that
Speaker 4:  I have been sort of rooting for for many years. Like
Speaker 4:  going back to a bunch of years ago there was this company called Shadow that
Speaker 4:  was like, we're just gonna stream a Windows PC so that you can play all of
Speaker 4:  your games on a Windows pc, but it's in the cloud so you can do it anywhere
Speaker 4:  you want. And I was like, that's the best idea ever. And it failed for a
Speaker 4:  bunch of what turned out to be extremely predictable reasons. Really quick,
Speaker 4:  let's just sort of set the scene on where we are right now. I feel like we
Speaker 4:  talk a lot about the Nintendo Switch. We talk a lot about the Steam deck,
Speaker 4:  but in this like reboot phase of
Speaker 4:  handheld gaming, how big is this market? Like how much do people actually
Speaker 4:  care about what's happening with handhelds?
Speaker 6:  Well, you mentioned the Switch. I mean that really, I think rebooted the
Speaker 6:  whole concept of, hey, there's money to be made here. There's been a number
Speaker 6:  of handheld over the years, the Sony PSP, the Sony Vita, which were
Speaker 6:  like, beloved, sure, but realistically not very successful. So the Switch
Speaker 6:  proved them, oh, there's actually money here. And Val
Speaker 6:  followed suit and made their own with the steam deck as you mentioned. And
Speaker 6:  since then we've seen a number of other companies jump into this space and
Speaker 6:  there is so much demand for it that I, I mean it's great 'cause honestly
Speaker 6:  it just allows for way more flexibility in terms of gaming.
Speaker 5:  And then I, I would say the market is even bigger with all of your
Speaker 5:  mobile games, your, your smartphones, your iOS devices and Android
Speaker 5:  and tablets. I really sound like a real Verge person right now.
Speaker 5:  I I can't wait to be shredded for saying your iOS
Speaker 5:  devices, but no, I, I think there are kind of three phases
Speaker 5:  to what got us here. One is the iPhone launching
Speaker 5:  and the app store with it, and then I, that sort of phase of
Speaker 5:  social gaming. There is the end of the
Speaker 5:  Nintendo formula, which was yeah, the DSS and the three dss, which is where
Speaker 5:  you had to kind of design games for that system. Right? And then the switch
Speaker 5:  in Steam deck, what they really changed, I think, and why I think it's it's
Speaker 5:  really blown up is a lot of what is being designed for PC
Speaker 5:  or Xbox or PlayStation can now also be
Speaker 5:  handheld. So it, it's not just that like, oh,
Speaker 5:  Handheld is blowing up. It's that the line between traditional gaming
Speaker 5:  and handheld is, is blurrier than ever before.
Speaker 4:  Right. And it seems like if we're also headed into this phase of cloud gaming
Speaker 4:  being the thing, and it's like most of the work of
Speaker 4:  really powerful gaming hardware can happen somewhere else. The
Speaker 4:  recipe should be right. Pure.
Speaker 5:  We'll see, we'll see. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  Maybe that's something you're gonna look into, but I think we're not quite
Speaker 6:  there yet.
Speaker 5:  Intense skepticism. But I, I would say devices are more
Speaker 5:  powerful than ever that your new iPhone can play the brand new resident evil.
Speaker 5:  Maybe you don't even need the cloud gaming part of it. That doesn't work,
Speaker 5:  but we'll, we'll get to that.
Speaker 4:  Okay. I think that's right. So, okay. I'm still trying to figure out what
Speaker 4:  sort of the big overarching question is here, right? Because on the one hand
Speaker 4:  you have, how big is this gonna be? 'cause like you guys said, we've been
Speaker 4:  at this for a while and I think, I think we have to throw the iPhone out.
Speaker 4:  This is gonna be my, my hottest take so far is that I think if we talk about
Speaker 4:  mobile phone gaming, you end up just down a completely different road. And
Speaker 4:  it's like, yes, everybody has a mobile phone, everybody plays games on it.
Speaker 4:  I think we can just like mark that as like done checked on the checkbox.
Speaker 4:  I wanna talk about like gaming specific devices and that
Speaker 4:  goes all the way down from like the, the things you have to like emulate
Speaker 4:  old Game boy games, like the analog pocket, which everyone's obsessed with.
Speaker 4:  And then from there all the way up to like the steam deck, which is essentially
Speaker 4:  just trying to be like a gaming PC in your, in your hands. Is that a fair
Speaker 4:  way to define this?
Speaker 6:  I think So I think the larger question that you're trying to answer is, is
Speaker 6:  this the norm? So when Sony or Microsoft creates
Speaker 6:  their next console, are they making it with handheld gaming in mind?
Speaker 6:  Whereas right now they are not. And is this just the future we're gonna
Speaker 6:  live in from now on?
Speaker 5:  And that's why I wouldn't rush to throw out your iPhone on this
Speaker 5:  case because I think that Apple is trying to start
Speaker 5:  to pull these like AAA games the same year that they come out onto the
Speaker 5:  iPhone. That raises the question of are they even trying to finally, I mean,
Speaker 5:  it's a forever question You know, I don't wanna be Charlie Brown missing
Speaker 5:  the football here, but like, are they also trying
Speaker 5:  to get into this? If, if handheld is the future of gaming, they're the best
Speaker 5:  positioned to take advantage of that.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Resident Evil four is not a Handheld game that is like a
Speaker 6:  game that you would play on a plays Station five or an Xbox or a gaming pc.
Speaker 6:  The fact that it's running on an iPhone is crazy. So it is
Speaker 6:  genuinely kind of a new era for mobile games in ways that it was
Speaker 6:  not previously, but you're right. It's, it has been a struggle to get people
Speaker 6:  to do that.
Speaker 4:  Okay. All, right. So maybe the question I need to go figure out is basically
Speaker 4:  the people who make games and make the hardware to run them, are
Speaker 4:  they thinking about you holding a device in your hands
Speaker 4:  or is it just another screen on which you can play games, right? Like is
Speaker 4:  handheld gonna change the way that we play games or is it just gonna be another
Speaker 4:  way to play Resident Evil feels like kind of the big open question here.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, and I, and I think there are comparisons in other pop culture. You
Speaker 5:  know the shift to people watching movies on their iPhones and
Speaker 5:  Christopher Nolan Getting Furious or the car test when
Speaker 5:  you are mixing pop music and making sure that It works as well
Speaker 5:  on a car radio or like cheap headphones as it would anywhere else. I'm curious
Speaker 5:  is, is that something people are thinking about when they design games
Speaker 5:  now? Because especially everything from like the text on the screen
Speaker 5:  to having control options there, there's a lot that goes into how
Speaker 5:  you designed for it and yeah, I'm, I'm curious what you'll find out.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, you're just trying to get me to really piss off all the purists. That's
Speaker 4:  what I'm hearing here. Everyone who believes in like the fidelity of the
Speaker 4:  sound and the frame rates is gonna hate me at the end of this episode. And
Speaker 4:  it's gonna be your fault, Chris.
Speaker 6:  Well it's funny 'cause the purists are playing old game boy color games
Speaker 6:  on their like, ancient game boy hardware. So like they'll be on board.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And, and like video game purists are like notoriously calm and
Speaker 5:  chill, so like that is true. Yeah, it
Speaker 4:  Should be fine. Yeah. Ev everything will go fine. Are you guys handheld gamers?
Speaker 6:  Almost exclusively.
Speaker 5:  We're parents, of course.
Speaker 4:  What do you guys play? It's
Speaker 6:  Usually a steam deck since it launched. I know a plant uses the
Speaker 6:  ACEs Rock ally quite a bit, but yeah, I'm, I'm a Steam Deck
Speaker 6:  person through and through. Love
Speaker 5:  It. Yeah. And they're interchangeable in my opinion. I, I use the ROG
Speaker 5:  because I'm playing it on a couch and I can have it plugged in and the
Speaker 5:  resolution is slightly better and the frame rate is slightly better. But
Speaker 5:  the steam deck may be my favorite console of all time.
Speaker 6:  But I also use a MIU Mini, which is like a tiny little retro Handheld
Speaker 6:  gaming device. So like, it kind of depends on the situation and I think you're
Speaker 6:  gonna find that a lot of people are looking for a lot of different things
Speaker 6:  from Handheld gaming these days.
Speaker 4:  I like it. Alright, we are gonna take a break and then through the magic
Speaker 4:  of time and editing, I'm gonna go talk to some people. I'm gonna come back
Speaker 4:  with some answers. We're gonna see what we can figure out. Thank you both.
Speaker 4:  We'll be right back.
Speaker 4:  All, right? Welcome back. It's been a few weeks. We're back in the studio.
Speaker 4:  Chris Russ still here. How are your lives? How are things? I,
Speaker 6:  My son is sick so he is stuck at home and I'm just surviving,
Speaker 6:  so things have been great.
Speaker 5:  I'm doing great. I've never felt more alive.
Speaker 4:  All, right. So you, you sent me off to find out what is the deal with Handheld
Speaker 4:  Gaming. I have figured out the deal with handheld gaming. Yeah. This went
Speaker 4:  totally differently than I expected. I have come back absolutely
Speaker 4:  a hundred percent convinced that handheld is the future of gaming in
Speaker 4:  every meaningful mainstream way. I think this, this is
Speaker 4:  the answer, I don't know if it's the 25 year answer, but I think the next
Speaker 4:  10 years of gaming looks like handhelds. Like I really, truly earnestly believe
Speaker 4:  that in a way that I did not when I started this process. I
Speaker 5:  Already have so many questions. I'm excited
Speaker 4:  I have what I have developed into David's five grand theories of handheld
Speaker 4:  gaming's, supremacy and victory. That's the, that's the official technical
Speaker 4:  term. Sure,
Speaker 5:  Sure,
Speaker 4:  Sure. The first thing I realized in talking to folks about this and going
Speaker 4:  back and doing a bunch of research, I spent a lot of time watching like 20
Speaker 4:  year old game console introductions like
Speaker 4:  E three, 2004, all kinds of good stuff going on at E three
Speaker 4:  2004. And I think, I think I didn't realize is that this
Speaker 4:  is kind of what the gaming industry has always wanted.
Speaker 4:  Like there was stuff from the PSP and the early days
Speaker 4:  of the DSS that it's like Nintendo and Sony and a lot of these gaming
Speaker 4:  companies have been talking about this idea that you should have something
Speaker 4:  that is powerful and feels like a console but is not tied to
Speaker 4:  your television in your couch. Like they've been talking about this forever
Speaker 4:  in a way that I really did not realize.
Speaker 5:  You know what's funny about that, I swear that when I
Speaker 5:  went to the very first PlayStation Vita Press event, they
Speaker 5:  showed us a build of the PlayStation Vita with an
Speaker 5:  HDMI out on it. The original premise was like you would be
Speaker 5:  able to actually plug it into your tv and that just got erased from
Speaker 5:  time. I don't even know if I can find this anymore, but I am positive
Speaker 5:  that I remember this and now that you say this that like, yes, this
Speaker 5:  has been a dream for a long time, this kind of blurring in the lines makes
Speaker 5:  a lot of sense.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. This stuff is so much less new than I expected. And I will say
Speaker 4:  to some extent it kind of gives me pause because like if you rewind
Speaker 4:  back to 2004, all these people were launching these devices saying
Speaker 4:  this is the moment for handheld gaming and that, nope, it
Speaker 4:  wasn't. But it,
Speaker 6:  It was in the sense that like the DSS sold like gobs and gobs of units.
Speaker 6:  Right? But totally like not on the console side.
Speaker 4:  So this is actually what I was gonna ask you guys is there was this moment,
Speaker 4:  right? We had the dss, the PSP, there was this real
Speaker 4:  energy around consoles you could hold in your hand and then they
Speaker 4:  just died. And you guys have been paying attention to this a lot longer than
Speaker 4:  I have. Like what happened to that generation of handheld gaming?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I think it ran through the three dss. You, you had the
Speaker 6:  DSS and the three dss which were, which both did quite well. Incredibly well.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. But on the like high-end handheld gaming side, the both the
Speaker 6:  Vida and the PSPI think just struggled to like reach
Speaker 6:  a wider audience for whatever reason. Maybe it was 'cause they were going
Speaker 6:  for like more mature games or something like that. There just
Speaker 6:  wasn't, I, I don't know the, maybe the hardware wasn't ready to the point
Speaker 6:  where people w wanted to make discreet software for those
Speaker 6:  platforms. Whereas Nintendo was like, whatever our games will run on anything,
Speaker 6:  we can make it happen. I
Speaker 5:  Agree with fresh. I think it definitely is partly that Nintendo is always
Speaker 5:  fine selling effectively like graphing calculators and making
Speaker 5:  cash off of it, right? That was the original model of the game. Boy You know
Speaker 5:  what you're saying of this has been a long time coming that maybe
Speaker 5:  smartphones threw a wrench in it temporarily. I think
Speaker 4:  That's right.
Speaker 5:  And that we did have this period of, well maybe mobile
Speaker 5:  gaming is just Farmville, right? Maybe it's, it's
Speaker 5:  these idle games. I mean I remember Fresh,
Speaker 5:  I think we were at this together at a game developers' conference where
Speaker 5:  I think it was RO from Nintendo went on stage and
Speaker 5:  was like, can people please stop making 99 cent games?
Speaker 5:  Like this actually is not good for the industry. And at the time
Speaker 5:  everybody was like, ugh, You know. Like here's Nintendo, the old
Speaker 5:  industry coming into the room telling us not to do this anymore. But in hindsight
Speaker 5:  that kind of proved right in some ways.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I think free to play ended up taking over that model. But yeah,
Speaker 6:  100% it does diminish I think the higher end products and
Speaker 6:  results in games that are designed for that cheap price point to get even
Speaker 6:  more money out of people.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I think that's right. I think there, there's a really interesting version
Speaker 4:  of this story where you could argue that mobile was kind of the great
Speaker 4:  diversion for the gaming industry for a really long time and it led a lot
Speaker 4:  of people down really profitable, really unpleasant roads that ultimately
Speaker 4:  led to nothing. And like we got to Farmville and whatever that was. And
Speaker 4:  I mean even the Sony story, right? They got obsessed with the Xperia phones
Speaker 4:  and trying to build gaming phones and then just trying to build regular phones
Speaker 4:  and kind of got away from what it was doing really well before that.
Speaker 4:  So I. Yeah, I, I think you guys are right that some combination of the hardware
Speaker 4:  wasn't quite ready and mobile was just sort of ate
Speaker 4:  that thing. Which brings me to theory number one, which is that the hardware
Speaker 4:  is ready now. Oh yeah. Which is a huge, huge change. Like I
Speaker 4:  went back and looked at the, the specs for like the PSS four when it came
Speaker 4:  out. Do you guys remember everybody was talking about it as if it was like
Speaker 4:  a supercomputer. It was like this is the most powerful, that thing is basically
Speaker 4:  specs like a like mid-level laptop. Like yeah, that's, we can do
Speaker 4:  powerful gaming systems now without trying all that hard. The chips are super
Speaker 4:  accessible. You have more and more of these really powerful chips that are
Speaker 4:  being built with mobile in mind. They care more about battery life. They're
Speaker 4:  much more efficient, they're much cheaper to get, like it's there now in
Speaker 4:  a way that it wasn't. And you can build really good games for these platforms
Speaker 4:  in a way that you couldn't before, which I think is a huge, huge change.
Speaker 4:  And it's just like, it, it's just sitting there now like you can now make
Speaker 4:  these if you want to.
Speaker 6:  And I think the, the fact that people are making games that run on
Speaker 6:  not only the handheld system but also the console system and it's the same
Speaker 6:  game. They haven't changed one iota. The fact that I can play Elden ring
Speaker 6:  on the steam deck and also on my PS four Yeah. And also on my PS
Speaker 6:  five makes a huge, huge difference from just like a bandwidth
Speaker 6:  standpoint. There's only so many games that everyone can produce, let alone
Speaker 6:  games. They're discreetly made for each individual platform.
Speaker 6:  So yeah, it, it's a big change.
Speaker 4:  I think that's actually exactly right. And that's one of the things I only
Speaker 4:  realized in talking to folks about this that I had never really realized
Speaker 4:  before is there was this obsession for so long with like there were console
Speaker 4:  games and then there were Handheld games and they were different. And that
Speaker 4:  the way to make these systems work was to build like specific games
Speaker 4:  for these devices and they had to be their own genre. So when
Speaker 4:  anybody stopped doing it because they didn't sell really fast immediately
Speaker 4:  or whatever, they just died. Right? It's this like death spiral of nobody
Speaker 4:  caress that leads to these platforms dying now it's not the case. And this
Speaker 4:  is actually you, you stole David Grand theory number four from me.
Speaker 6:  Oh man. Sorry.
Speaker 4:  It's fine. We're just, we're jumping around here. Theory number four is parody.
Speaker 4:  It's that you can just build a game now and It works everywhere. I found
Speaker 4:  myself talking to a bunch of people who have been building games like this
Speaker 4:  for a long time. You like, you look at a company like ea, right? EA makes
Speaker 4:  console games and it makes mobile games with the same names but
Speaker 4:  that are fundamentally totally different games. And that barrier
Speaker 4:  is sort of collapsing, right? Where like Fortnite and Roblox
Speaker 4:  are functionally the same thing no matter what screen you play on. And it
Speaker 4:  seems to me that that is much more the future than
Speaker 4:  tailoring everything to this specific device and controls and console that
Speaker 4:  you're on. Do you guys think that's right?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Not only is that better for the players, that's also from a
Speaker 6:  business standpoint way more cost productive. So there's really no reason
Speaker 6:  that you would ever need if you needed to. I just think people
Speaker 6:  are gonna gravitate towards just making a A game that'll work on just about
Speaker 6:  everything.
Speaker 4:  Chris, you made a face like you might hate this idea.
Speaker 5:  No, I like this a lot. I think there's like one other piece to all of this
Speaker 5:  in this separation between mobile and console, which
Speaker 5:  is gender misconceptions in the history of video games. Hmm.
Speaker 5:  I think that not only were there these two different types of games, I
Speaker 5:  think people saw people who play mobile games as women
Speaker 5:  or people who are on Facebook as quote You know mom gamers
Speaker 5:  and that hardcore counsel gamers were men And. what I
Speaker 5:  think marketers are realizing slowly and hopefully
Speaker 5:  exponentially is that not only is that not true, it it's never
Speaker 5:  been true. And once you blow that thought up, then that is
Speaker 5:  when the games that were on mobile, the like kind of like casual games
Speaker 5:  actually just show up on Xbox You know because why not? Why shouldn't they
Speaker 5:  be there? There's an audience for them there And that's when Call of Duty
Speaker 5:  shows up on your iPhone that these are not discrete places. I I,
Speaker 5:  I remember an event back in the DS days where Nintendo
Speaker 5:  had brain age or something and they threw like high tea for it.
Speaker 4:  Nice,
Speaker 5:  Nice. But like they were, they were very transparent. Like who they thought
Speaker 5:  was Yeah. The audience for this game and who they thought wasn't and
Speaker 5:  when in reality everybody liked Brain age.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Do that for Call of Duty next time. That's the hell yeah. Give me high
Speaker 4:  tea for Call of Duty and we'll we'll be somewhere. No, I think that's right
Speaker 4:  And I think the overall collapse of gaming
Speaker 4:  into just being across everything is kind of the
Speaker 4:  thing that underscores all of this for me, right? Is that we're now to a
Speaker 4:  place where gaming was once a specific thing you did on a
Speaker 4:  specific device in a specific place. Mm. And it has just ballooned out to
Speaker 4:  being worlds that you dip in and out of no matter where you are. And it feels
Speaker 4:  like with that comes working on lots of different platforms, lots of different
Speaker 4:  kinds of hardware. Like it's the same thing that's happening with computers,
Speaker 4:  right? It's that instead of being a thing in a room that you sit down at
Speaker 4:  to do a thing, it's just like woven into your life in these new
Speaker 4:  ways. And that's what the, the game developers want. Increasingly it seems
Speaker 4:  that's where the money is. That's how you get people to be involved. That's
Speaker 4:  where like the online communities are moving. So it makes sense to me that
Speaker 4:  all of this stuff is just sort of 10 tickling out into everything with a
Speaker 4:  screen and a chip in it.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I don't think this is, it's solely just a realization that
Speaker 6:  yeah the mar the audiences are more or less the same across everywhere.
Speaker 6:  It's also just a hardware consideration that like you could not
Speaker 6:  have a handheld that could run a console game 10, 15 years ago. We just Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Like physically, right? The hardware was not gonna handle it. So the fact
Speaker 6:  that we've caught up and also the fact that we've diminished the importance
Speaker 6:  of console generations is a huge impact on this as well. The fact that
Speaker 6:  there are so few PS five exclusive games or
Speaker 6:  Xbox Series X exclusive games means that you're making
Speaker 6:  games that run on all these different generations, which include
Speaker 6:  handheld games at this point. So e, everything is sort of working together
Speaker 6:  to kind of get us there.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I was listening back to old interviews with Reggie Fme
Speaker 4:  from Nintendo and he was talking about one of the
Speaker 4:  challenges for the gaming industry is thinking about like the 10 year horizon
Speaker 4:  of every console generation that it's like anything we do we have to be able
Speaker 4:  to live with for a decade because that's how this works and we
Speaker 4:  are just not in that world anymore. Everything overlaps, things are
Speaker 4:  moving, especially with You know cloud and sort of this move to digital.
Speaker 4:  It just feels like all of the ideas about what you can run and where
Speaker 4:  and how long you have to support things, that's all just rapidly going out
Speaker 4:  the window. It seems like
Speaker 6:  What's really exciting is your library stays with you. Like Steam obviously
Speaker 6:  has had a consistent library. God willing, Nintendo is finally gonna
Speaker 6:  like You know they've promised that they're gonna continue the library
Speaker 6:  for the first time ever on whatever the switch followup is. So I think
Speaker 6:  that is a big pusher as well.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I think that's the funny part that you mentioned Reggie, because we
Speaker 5:  still don't know if Nintendo is on board with this. We've
Speaker 5:  heard a lot of promises but until the switch to is out,
Speaker 5:  I would never bet against Nintendo doing something deeply strange
Speaker 4:  If they call it the switch to and don't let you keep your library that is
Speaker 4:  the most like outrageous user hostile thing imaginable.
Speaker 5:  Also they need to call it the Super Switch. Oh that's good. In the same way
Speaker 5:  that they should have called the we the super we instead of the we you just
Speaker 5:  like go back to that classic Nintendo convention.
Speaker 4:  I was so with you until you said super we
Speaker 5:  Super we.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, no I I think you guys are right And I think that idea is part of what
Speaker 4:  makes me think that handheld is the thing. Because I think if you were to
Speaker 4:  boil it all the way down to something and it's like what is the single most
Speaker 4:  versatile version of the hardware here? It's a handheld object
Speaker 4:  which I think is like why we start from there going forward. Which brings
Speaker 4:  me to thing number, I don't know two, I've lost track. We're just,
Speaker 4:  there's some theories it doesn't matter which is just, it's somewhere between
Speaker 4:  like manufacturing and momentum. I couldn't decide which MI wanted to
Speaker 4:  do but there has been like an explosion of this hardware over the last
Speaker 4:  couple of years in a way that I didn't even realize. Like I'm, I own a switch,
Speaker 4:  I have played some steam deck and I was kind of like there's those two and
Speaker 4:  then nothing else of real great consequence and like good lord was I
Speaker 4:  wrong? There's so much stuff out there and you have like the
Speaker 4:  PC manufacturers are getting super into this because you can, it's essentially
Speaker 4:  just a like relatively high powered PC in a slightly different case.
Speaker 4:  You have all of these new companies like Analog coming outta the woodwork
Speaker 4:  to do some of this stuff. You have gaming companies like Razor and Logitech
Speaker 4:  doing all this stuff. It's like this feels like a hardware category
Speaker 4:  that a lot of folks can get into in really interesting ways, which makes
Speaker 4:  me think it's gonna get much bigger than just the like game
Speaker 4:  maker companies really, really fast. And it feels like that momentum is already
Speaker 4:  happening. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  I completely agree. I mean we You know, we haven't even dove into the like
Speaker 6:  random flyby night handheld developers companies that
Speaker 6:  you might see on like Amazon or whatever. But yeah, the fact that as and
Speaker 6:  Lenovo and as you mentioned Razor and Logitech,
Speaker 6:  the fact that they are going hard on this and so quickly after seeing
Speaker 6:  the success of the Steam deck is really just I think a huge
Speaker 6:  indicator of where things are going. I also think it's, they have the luxury
Speaker 6:  of being able to sell older chips in these devices that aren't like
Speaker 6:  cutting bleeding edge chips because they need to keep the power usage
Speaker 6:  down so they can use stuff that's like maybe one or two years
Speaker 6:  old, which is really the the model that the switch set out, right? Like the
Speaker 6:  Switch was not a blazingly powerful system when it launched and it
Speaker 6:  allowed Nintendo to sell it at a profit. And I think you're gonna see a lot
Speaker 6:  of companies these days sell these things at a good profit,
Speaker 6:  not steam deck. I, my understanding is they lose some money there but they
Speaker 6:  also own the library. So it comes back around
Speaker 4:  Actually tell me about all of the ones that you find on Amazon. 'cause I
Speaker 4:  have been looking into all of these and it, it kind of reminds me of like
Speaker 4:  the smartphone market of say seven or eight years ago. Yeah. When
Speaker 4:  it was, it was very clear that now there's like the parts for this exist
Speaker 4:  in factories in China, right? And if you want to go buy some of those parts
Speaker 4:  you can make a phone without trying super hard. And so there was just this
Speaker 4:  rush of companies you've never heard of making phones that all had the exact
Speaker 4:  same specs because those are the ones you can buy from the factory in China.
Speaker 4:  It feels like that's the phase of handheld gaming we're in right now where
Speaker 4:  like there are 600 slightly hard to pronounce
Speaker 4:  versions of what look like about the exact same thing all over Amazon. Are
Speaker 4:  they any good?
Speaker 5:  Are you a pow kitty man or a a Brunick boy
Speaker 5:  You know,
Speaker 4:  I feel like I can't legally answer that question.
Speaker 6:  Those are a few of the bigger ones if you can believe it. Yeah, Anick is
Speaker 6:  one of the biggest of these companies that is making these devices
Speaker 6:  and I think what's so interesting about these is unlike I
Speaker 6:  think a lot of those phones that you're talking about, these are mostly
Speaker 6:  supported by software that the community is developing and
Speaker 6:  working on. A lot of them are Linux based or Android based, but in terms
Speaker 6:  of the actual interfaces and the firmware, a lot of
Speaker 6:  communities are kind of rallying around specific devices. I know the MIU
Speaker 6:  Mini in particular is a very popular iteration and folks
Speaker 6:  just sort of make open source software to run on these devices. So it
Speaker 6:  is this like really exciting community event that's happening.
Speaker 5:  It's also created a cottage industry around it because
Speaker 5:  not everybody likes setting up devices and installing custom
Speaker 5:  firmware. So I'm sure if you happen to look on Etsy
Speaker 5:  you might find versions of these exact same things that have been just
Speaker 5:  slightly tinkered with and maybe they include all of the
Speaker 5:  emulators or all of the software that Brush is talking about
Speaker 5:  along with maybe some other stuff that's not so legal or
Speaker 6:  Perhaps a more legit approach. 'cause we do legal things on this podcast.
Speaker 6:  Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Speaker 6:  I would recommend there's some great YouTube channels that like specifically
Speaker 6:  dedicate themselves to this group of handhelds. Retro game core
Speaker 6:  is an excellent one that I'd highly recommend, but there are a number
Speaker 6:  that do a really good job of covering this space and giving people instructions
Speaker 6:  on how to like do some of this heavy lifting in the firmware.
Speaker 4:  Chris, did you say Etsy by the way? This is an Etsy phenomenon. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  They're not sending you like knitted covers for them. They're actually like
Speaker 4:  they're, that's you. But you get Linux, Etsy
Speaker 5:  Is so much bigger and weirder than anybody
Speaker 5:  imagines it it, it reminds me of Pinterest too where people are
Speaker 5:  like, I think I know what that is and then you like realize half of Pinterest
Speaker 5:  is people with guns and you're like wait, what?
Speaker 6:  I will say I looked at list things on Etsy for replacement
Speaker 6:  triggers for the Miu Min handheld that I use and someone
Speaker 6:  had three D printed a new design for the triggers.
Speaker 6:  That's how esoteric it gets on there. It's pretty amazing.
Speaker 4:  That's awesome. Okay. Yeah. Who knew Etsy not just
Speaker 4:  for buying coffee tables that barely work in my house. Okay, my
Speaker 4:  next theory, and this is one I am torn about
Speaker 4:  more than any of the others, which is that the handheld gaming revolution
Speaker 4:  is also the cloud gaming revolution and
Speaker 4:  I remain torn on whether I believe cloud gaming is like
Speaker 4:  the future or not and I'm very curious to know what you guys
Speaker 4:  think about this.
Speaker 5:  I think you could be right if handheld gaming
Speaker 5:  continues to look how it does right now, which is to say you get a
Speaker 5:  steam deck and you can play 90,
Speaker 5:  95% of what you want on that device.
Speaker 5:  But the brand new stuff, the real cutting edge heavy
Speaker 5:  ray tracing stuff like Allen Wake two, that's
Speaker 5:  not gonna work on it. That you're still gonna need a really nice PC or a
Speaker 5:  PSS five to make that work in those games if you must play them
Speaker 5:  now and you don't wanna buy that if you can play that on cloud.
Speaker 5:  I think that's it. But I think cloud for the foreseeable
Speaker 5:  future and I'm curious what Fresh thinks here, but I think cloud is a
Speaker 5:  nice to have. It is a supplement to most of
Speaker 5:  your stuff being powered by the actual hardware itself.
Speaker 4:  Wait, that's really interesting. So fresh. I am curious what you think too
Speaker 4:  but Chris you just said the opposite of the argument that I hear from most
Speaker 4:  people, which is that like most people when I talk to them about cloud gaming,
Speaker 4:  they're like well the, the people who play the most intense games and
Speaker 4:  worry the most about things like controller lag, like
Speaker 4:  the people who go on our battle stations for fun, like those people, those
Speaker 4:  people are never gonna want cloud gaming because they want something that
Speaker 4:  is local, that is theirs, that is offline like that with the minimal lag
Speaker 4:  and their wired mouse and all that stuff. But for the more like casual
Speaker 4:  user cloud gaming is the answer. But you just kind of said the opposite.
Speaker 6:  No I think plant agrees with you because I think the more casual user isn't
Speaker 6:  gonna have the hardware that can run Allen Wake two with Ray tracing and
Speaker 6:  everything but they wanna play the game 'cause it's a great narrative experience,
Speaker 6:  whatever. So this is the solution. The hardcore, they have
Speaker 6:  the 40 90 card, they have the hardware to run those games so they
Speaker 6:  don't need to worry about it. It is the people that like don't wanna bother
Speaker 6:  getting that system together.
Speaker 5:  David, I think what is changing is what the idea of the casual user
Speaker 5:  is. Hmm. Somebody who plays PC games just in general
Speaker 5:  that can be the casual user now, right? Yeah. So like I think
Speaker 5:  somebody having this steam deck who's like yeah playing some pretty hardcore
Speaker 5:  stuff. What would be hardcore in our childhood now is just
Speaker 5:  somebody who's used to watching these people stream since the day they were
Speaker 5:  five. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  To go back to like whether I think it's there yet, I think it's actually
Speaker 6:  surprisingly close, but there is an element of like the closer you get, the
Speaker 6:  further it feels away. Yeah. Because there is still lag, there are still
Speaker 6:  dropouts and if anyone like cares about playing a platforming game or a
Speaker 6:  shooter or anything that revolves around timing, it just doesn't
Speaker 6:  feel as good as playing a locally installed game.
Speaker 6:  All these Nintendo games that are made within an inch of their lives to feel
Speaker 6:  awesome every second of the way can never
Speaker 6:  necessarily get there. At least with the where, where the systems are at
Speaker 6:  right now with cloud. 'cause there will always be a slightly tactile
Speaker 6:  delay there that will make it feel a little worse. But I
Speaker 6:  do think knowing technology that it can get there
Speaker 6:  to the point where the delay will be so small as to be
Speaker 6:  indistinguishable from playing a game locally in the same way that like I
Speaker 6:  play with wireless controllers all the time. An eSports person
Speaker 6:  can't stand playing with wireless controllers 'cause they feel that 10 millisecond
Speaker 6:  delay. But like I think for most people it's totally fine. I think we will
Speaker 6:  get to that point with cloud gaming.
Speaker 5:  I agree and I agree that it feels like we're very close but it might still
Speaker 5:  be a long time until we get there in the same way that it felt like we would
Speaker 5:  never cross the uncanny valley in video games. Hmm. Until we just
Speaker 5:  did one day and there was a good decade. We're like
Speaker 5:  we're never gonna get this right. Like human eyes are just gonna look awful.
Speaker 5:  Faces are always gonna look weird. It's going to be uncomfortable
Speaker 5:  looking at characters and video games and then suddenly the
Speaker 5:  US weren't talking about that anymore. You know, I mean unless it was a Bethesda
Speaker 5:  game but otherwise you you were like yeah it just looks
Speaker 5:  nice and good. I sure why not. I think that'll happen with cloud gaming and
Speaker 5:  that's again why I say it'll start out supplemental and then at some
Speaker 5:  point it'll just be second nature.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I mean right now it is supplemental. You can play whatever Catan
Speaker 6:  or any turn based strategy game and it's perfectly fine. Like I've
Speaker 6:  played games like that, it's great. But yeah, anything with timing is
Speaker 6:  kind of miserable.
Speaker 4:  Do you think that's tied to handhelds as a thing? 'cause I think that the
Speaker 4:  case for those two things growing together is essentially that
Speaker 4:  over time you wouldn't need something that looks and feels like
Speaker 4:  the steam deck, which is, I mean it's, it is a big thing. You could
Speaker 4:  essentially just have anything with a screen and two controllers becomes
Speaker 4:  this like ultra powerful gaming machine. I mean
Speaker 6:  Logitech made a dedicated cloud handheld, right? That is their
Speaker 6:  entire focus with that device, right? That is cloud gaming.
Speaker 4:  I have to say I don't see a ton of those things in the wild
Speaker 6:  Well, right, and the problem is again, the cloud gaming our infrastructure
Speaker 6:  is not there yet. Right. So people don't necessarily want that yet. I do
Speaker 6:  think you're right. In a few years when the lag becomes minimal
Speaker 6:  you can run it on a $50 hand. Like the fact that you could run two
Speaker 6:  on a $50 Handheld gaming system is possible
Speaker 6:  thanks to cloud gaming. We're just not there yet.
Speaker 5:  I do wonder if ironically power is getting so cheap,
Speaker 5:  a lot of the games that people play don't even use that much power that
Speaker 5:  we are getting to a point where maybe You know
Speaker 5:  a few years from now Steam or valve releases a
Speaker 5:  $150 steam deck that has
Speaker 5:  internal power and can still play the vast majority of what you want.
Speaker 5:  And like by the time we actually get to You know cloud gaming
Speaker 5:  working, we actually won't need cloud gaming.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I mean like our phones do ray tracing now. Like it's we're we're getting
Speaker 4:  there really fast. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I'd much rather play Resin Evil four remake just directly on
Speaker 5:  my phone than I've tried playing Resin Evil four. Oh my gosh. I played
Speaker 5:  all of Resin Evil Village on Stadia. I was the person
Speaker 5:  AMA and let me tell you it was,
Speaker 5:  it was a journey. I'm very happy to never do that again.
Speaker 5:  They
Speaker 4:  Were like, why is anyone still using our services and it's just Chris Plant
Speaker 4:  throwing his controller at the screen.
Speaker 5:  They saw that final achievement on lock and they, they're like, wait, what?
Speaker 5:  Somebody on the IP must be doing it.
Speaker 4:  No. Okay. I think you're right and I think that also dovetails into
Speaker 4:  my next theory, which is about app stores. One person I talked to
Speaker 4:  made the case to me that Apple and Google could have
Speaker 4:  essentially won the next generation of gaming in a, they,
Speaker 4:  they won like part of that generation of gaming but because of the way that
Speaker 4:  they governed their app stores making companies
Speaker 4:  that wanted to have game libraries like You know allow list each game and
Speaker 4:  list each game separately and pay this huge tax on a difficult margin business
Speaker 4:  to be in with that, not only did those companies prevent themselves from
Speaker 4:  being hugely powerful players in the gaming industry, they
Speaker 4:  actually inspired this whole new run of hardware because
Speaker 4:  instead of set, instead of saying we're gonna build great games for
Speaker 4:  the very powerful mobile device you already have, they're saying we have
Speaker 4:  to build a new kind of device to play this kind of game because
Speaker 4:  we can't literally afford to play by the app store rules.
Speaker 4:  And I find that fascinating and I kind of think it's true that I think
Speaker 4:  a lot of these companies are showing up saying rather than
Speaker 4:  just try to compete with all of the amazing games that are already
Speaker 4:  on your phone, we're out here saying we, we can give you games that you can't
Speaker 4:  otherwise get. And that becomes very compelling in a way that it
Speaker 4:  wouldn't have been if all that stuff was just in the play store or the app
Speaker 4:  store. Yeah, it's
Speaker 6:  Tricky because there are a lot of the reason why a lot of those games
Speaker 6:  didn't show up on those platforms. You're right, there's like a huge cut
Speaker 6:  that they're taking. But I also think there were hardware limitations. You
Speaker 6:  couldn't run Resident Evil two remake on a phone when that
Speaker 6:  game came out three or four years ago. Yeah, that's fair. So I think that
Speaker 6:  that is part of it. But you're right, I think there's also an element of
Speaker 6:  like it being a pretty big lift, whether it's a rev share
Speaker 6:  or just a development lift to get devices to get software onto
Speaker 6:  those devices that is diminishing over time.
Speaker 6:  I know Apple I think is course correcting in a lot of ways by making it
Speaker 6:  much easier to port games both to iPhone
Speaker 6:  and Max using their backend software in a
Speaker 6:  very similar way to the way Steam allowed Proton
Speaker 6:  to run all of these PC games on Linux. I think they
Speaker 6:  realized that people aren't gonna take the time to make the platform specific
Speaker 6:  pieces of software. Apple was not quite there yet. They're still kind of
Speaker 6:  one foot in, one foot out, but I think that is the future.
Speaker 5:  I hear your theory and I think parts of it are right. I
Speaker 5:  wouldn't say that any of Apple's moves inspired
Speaker 5:  anything though because that would require believing that
Speaker 5:  Apple at any point would even make a mild
Speaker 5:  competent effort to get into this space. I don't think Nintendo
Speaker 5:  was like shaking in its boots that Apple was going to
Speaker 5:  get into You know the Making Good Games business. Right. I think that they
Speaker 5:  were very concerned about the like free games
Speaker 5:  shovel wear. I, I think that was a a legitimate concern
Speaker 5:  but I mean it really is astonishing how, how they have refused
Speaker 5:  to just put a controller wrapper around a iPhone. Yeah. That
Speaker 5:  you have to use a third party to do that and that that has been for a decade.
Speaker 5:  The problem, while they say that You know we care about video games.
Speaker 5:  I I agree with fresh in that yeah, resident Evil four wouldn't have run but
Speaker 5:  like most indie games would have, there is a way to solve
Speaker 5:  this problem. I I have to believe it's that they were making so much
Speaker 5:  money, so much money off of the type of mobile game apps they
Speaker 5:  had. They just felt like, hey we don't even need to think about that. Like
Speaker 5:  that's not our problem. And then eventually You know life comes at you fast.
Speaker 6:  I think it's also that Indies, you're right, like a lot of indie games would've
Speaker 6:  run on iPhone. I think those indies did not want to
Speaker 6:  be in the same storefront as games that were being sold for a dollar
Speaker 6:  and or or free that like that's a really tough thing to fight
Speaker 6:  against Now Apple Solve has been Apple Arcade which allows you
Speaker 6:  to subscribe and obviously you could bundle that all together with a cloud
Speaker 6:  subscription et cetera. And their services revenue has really increased
Speaker 6:  dramatically. Yeah. Over the last few years. That seems like more of a play
Speaker 6:  but that's a business play that's not like a game development play. And I
Speaker 6:  know even though there have been real highlights on the Apple arcade list,
Speaker 6:  they've also been like very fallow times. So it's, it kind of is an up and
Speaker 6:  down in terms of games you wanna play on there.
Speaker 4:  Okay, we're gonna take one more break and then I will get into my last
Speaker 4:  Big Grand Unified theory about the future of handheld gaming and why it's
Speaker 4:  totally gonna win Tmm. We'll be right back.
Speaker 4:  All. right, we're back. My last theory, all I wrote down for this one is
Speaker 4:  just Nintendo because a thing that I have learned as
Speaker 4:  the longer I cover the gaming world and talk to people about it is that everybody
Speaker 4:  kind of wants to be Nintendo all the time and Nintendo
Speaker 4:  proved this thing can work. Like the Switch is very good and I think in
Speaker 4:  a lot of ways accomplished a thing that
Speaker 4:  no one else has accomplished before where it made a thing that is
Speaker 4:  genuinely excellent as both a TV console and a
Speaker 4:  portable console. And I think it has been theoretically possible to
Speaker 4:  do some of that in some ways in the past. But the Switch just like did it
Speaker 4:  and I kind of think because Nintendo did it and did
Speaker 4:  it well that's just out of the bag now, right?
Speaker 4:  Like I think that is now the bar that everybody is going to have to figure
Speaker 4:  out some way to clear If you wanna make a mainstream console,
Speaker 5:  I will. I will go a step further. Okay. I'll go many steps further.
Speaker 5:  I think there are four futures for
Speaker 5:  handheld. Okay, ready? Nintendo is a video game console
Speaker 5:  that is also portable valve and now its
Speaker 5:  competitors are PCs that are portable. Then there's
Speaker 5:  the emulator machines which are like novelty toys and then
Speaker 5:  there's the last one which I think Xbox is trying to corner
Speaker 5:  this market. I think people see Game Pass as its main influence. I don't
Speaker 5:  think that's true Xbox. What it really wants to be is Kindle.
Speaker 5:  It wants to be the, we're not going to win any of
Speaker 5:  these. We've we, we don't see ourselves as the winner. We see us as the thing
Speaker 5:  that's everywhere you go, we wanna be on every screen that you have.
Speaker 5:  I think all of those are like valuable and interesting
Speaker 5:  approaches to it. I think the mistake that people will make, what you said
Speaker 5:  is like, yeah, everybody sees Nintendo and says I wanna do Nintendo
Speaker 5:  is that you don't realize no I need to do something different. Nintendo nailed
Speaker 5:  that and they're owning that right now. Valve so far seems to
Speaker 5:  have like really nailed the PC gaming. I think Xbox is making a pretty
Speaker 5:  competent play at whatever its thing is. I think that's honestly what a lot
Speaker 5:  of the whole Sony versus Xbox versus world
Speaker 5:  governments was actually about is is the fear of
Speaker 5:  that So I agree but I think Nintendo is just one
Speaker 5:  pillar of this handheld first future that you
Speaker 5:  described.
Speaker 4:  So I, I think I agree except I think the gaming PC
Speaker 4:  that's also portable and video game console that's also portable are
Speaker 4:  more closely going to resemble one another over time. I
Speaker 6:  Think they already do really the biggest difference between a steam deck
Speaker 6:  and a switch is just power. Yeah. There are so many games that run
Speaker 6:  on both Steam Deck and Switch. Now obviously I know what
Speaker 6:  plant's gonna say. Chris
Speaker 4:  Just stopped mid drink of water to disagree
Speaker 6:  With me. Yeah, it was almost a spit take. It was almost great. You can fully
Speaker 6:  mod the games on a steam deck. You can add
Speaker 6:  whatever your own software you can add, you can change the whole experience
Speaker 6:  if you want. Plant says, I'm totally off base with these guesses on what
Speaker 6:  he was gonna say.
Speaker 5:  Here's a better way of putting it. You're right. I made a mistake. If Steam
Speaker 5:  Deck is the PC console, Nintendo is, is
Speaker 5:  Nintendo the reason you buy the Switch, the reason Nintendo will
Speaker 5:  always be dominant is because Mario met
Speaker 5:  Zelda, Pickman, smash Brothers, Mario Kart, all of those games.
Speaker 5:  Nintendo has throughout, its the vast majority of its history, long
Speaker 5:  before it was making video games saw itself as a toy company and I
Speaker 5:  believe it still does. And I think that is secret power
Speaker 5:  is that it makes interesting fun things. It
Speaker 5:  doesn't get too bogged down by the rest of it.
Speaker 6:  And I would, I would add to that Nintendo interestingly enough is losing
Speaker 6:  the one differentiator their head outside of their exclusive software.
Speaker 6:  Because when the Nintendo Switch launched, it was the only game in town
Speaker 6:  from a handheld high-end gaming perspective. And that is no longer
Speaker 6:  the case. So when we go to the Switch to, they kind of have to
Speaker 6:  rely on, we have these exclusive titles once again, which was
Speaker 6:  really their strategy for like the Game Cube which kind of struggled the
Speaker 6:  weu, which kind of struggled. So it is not like smooth
Speaker 6:  sailing necessarily, although they do have this huge install base and now
Speaker 6:  a huge library. So like they're in much better position. But it is a much
Speaker 6:  more interesting competitive generation that we're stepping into.
Speaker 4:  I totally agree with that, except it's called the Super Switch. That part's
Speaker 4:  very important.
Speaker 5:  What if they call it the super we? Oh
Speaker 6:  God,
Speaker 5:  Wait, super. Super. We go because
Speaker 5:  like we go outside to play the, Ooh,
Speaker 4:  There we go. Okay, we're almost done here. We're almost, we should be long
Speaker 4:  done. Yeah, but we're almost done. I have two more questions for you and
Speaker 4:  then then we're gonna get outta here. Two more things I've been thinking
Speaker 4:  about. Okay. One is, if handhelds are
Speaker 4:  the thing, if the next version of the like mainstream console that most people
Speaker 4:  buy for Christmas every year is a handheld thing. And I increasingly believe
Speaker 4:  it's going to be where are Sony and Xbox
Speaker 4:  in this, why do you have, do we have any sense of what the hell these two
Speaker 4:  companies are doing?
Speaker 5:  David? Do You know that Sony has a new handheld?
Speaker 4:  I do. It's called the Portal.
Speaker 5:  Okay. Okay. Okay. That's good. Knows I I, I wasn't like testing your research,
Speaker 5:  I was actually more testing. Is Sony this bad at
Speaker 5:  getting it promoted?
Speaker 4:  I literally, I don't count the portal because it is an accessory to the PSS
Speaker 4:  five. Correct. It doesn't count. It's a, it's a fancy controller to the PSS
Speaker 4:  five. And I actually think there's a really interesting world down the road
Speaker 4:  in like a cloud gaming world where the controller becomes the console in
Speaker 4:  a way that I think is very exciting and possibly very cool. That's not happening
Speaker 4:  anytime soon. What I don't understand sincerely at this point is
Speaker 4:  why neither Sony nor the Xbox team at Microsoft seems
Speaker 4:  more invested in this space.
Speaker 5:  I think I have an answer. Okay. And it's different for both. I think for
Speaker 5:  Microsoft it's because historically they have seen themselves as a software
Speaker 5:  company,
Speaker 4:  A surface team. I don't buy that argument at all. No,
Speaker 5:  I I'm saying, I'm saying historically. Okay,
Speaker 4:  Sure. Historically fine.
Speaker 5:  But sure. I think that comes with like a lot of baggage. And I would say
Speaker 5:  for Sony, the irony is they make so much hardware
Speaker 5:  of like every, like right, you're gonna get your headphones and your hair
Speaker 5:  dryer. I remember there was Sony released
Speaker 5:  a three D TV that you could play video games
Speaker 5:  on and it was like a Sony PlayStation three D tv and if you
Speaker 5:  put on your three D glasses, you could actually have two people use full
Speaker 5:  screen at the same time. Because three D was projecting the dual image.
Speaker 5:  Right. Very neat. I had that meeting the next day. I went to another
Speaker 5:  meeting with Sony and saw a three D tv, four video
Speaker 5:  games that you could place games on with two glasses.
Speaker 5:  It was two separate teams making the same
Speaker 5:  product. And I think that is a real challenge
Speaker 5:  for Sony when they think about going out and making this is they have
Speaker 5:  so many teams with different goals that I imagine it could
Speaker 5:  be quite difficult to get the Vita two through,
Speaker 5:  which is a shame because they came so close. The vita is
Speaker 5:  I think fresh and I both like, it was maybe our favorite video
Speaker 5:  game console until the steam deck.
Speaker 6:  Until the switch. The switch I think
Speaker 5:  Until Switch, yeah.
Speaker 6:  Took it over. But yeah, and then the steam deck took it, took that over.
Speaker 6:  Here's my prediction, and this is not based on anything I, but I think it
Speaker 6:  would be cool. PlayStation has a tendency, actually all consoles have a tendency
Speaker 6:  to, when the generation, the console generation comes to an end, they release
Speaker 6:  like a little mini version of that console. 'cause the hardware is super,
Speaker 6:  super cheap by then. And they put that out there and that becomes like You
Speaker 6:  know, oh, you buy that as a gift on Christmas for 150 bucks, whatever. At
Speaker 6:  the end of the, let's say PlayStation five generation, when
Speaker 6:  that hardware is super cheap, throw that hardware into a little handheld
Speaker 6:  promise that every PS five game and everything before it will run on this
Speaker 6:  handheld. That seems like a strategy that I would totally get behind.
Speaker 5:  Give me Xbox series S mobile right now
Speaker 6:  It's not that far off in terms of its size, like it's 50% smaller
Speaker 6:  and you're kind of there.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And, and, and again, that runs into exactly what we were talking about
Speaker 5:  with like there will still be some games that won't run, which is true for
Speaker 5:  S versus series X, which is still just the worst naming convention.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, it's awful.
Speaker 4:  I have really come to a point where like the more I've gotten into this,
Speaker 4:  the more I've come to see it is basically like, there's like four
Speaker 4:  versions of how to play games now, right? There's like the
Speaker 4:  mega intense custom PC build. Like gaming
Speaker 4:  PCs is one area. There's like the Xbox, PlayStation
Speaker 4:  consoles, there's the people who play games on their
Speaker 4:  smartphones and then there's gaming handhelds. And if those are like,
Speaker 4:  it's sort of crude, but that is like the four categories I've come to think
Speaker 4:  of. Am I, does that make sense? Am I missing any in the, in the landscape
Speaker 4:  there?
Speaker 6:  Sounds pretty comprehensive.
Speaker 4:  Nice. Okay. My theory is what happens in the next 10 years
Speaker 4:  is that those four things basically coalesce into two. I think the, like
Speaker 4:  the consoles go up towards the PCs where it's like we're gonna have, there's
Speaker 4:  always going to be a market for people who want these super, super high
Speaker 4:  settings on Allen Wake two stuff. Those people are going to be increasingly
Speaker 4:  well-served by increasingly amazing hardware. And then I think the sort of
Speaker 4:  casual user of consoles, the handheld consoles and
Speaker 4:  the mobile games all get sort of smooshed together
Speaker 4:  in this thing you can hold in your hand or doc to your television world.
Speaker 4:  And I think that's where most people are gonna live in the next 10 years.
Speaker 4:  That's my big theory. That's where I've landed at the end of all of this.
Speaker 6:  I totally agree with that. I think you're 100% accurate. I don't think there's
Speaker 6:  gonna be a ton of games that will be made exclusively for
Speaker 6:  the high end market that you were just telling. I think we will continue
Speaker 6:  to see all these games eventually, whether it's at launch or six months
Speaker 6:  after or a year after trickle down to that more casual group.
Speaker 6:  But I totally see that becoming the majority.
Speaker 5:  Only one trick to it that I, I, I don't know how this plays out.
Speaker 5:  I think the laptop is the destroyer of the, of worlds,
Speaker 5:  of like mediums. I think the laptop is like, what got
Speaker 5:  music piracy, like really going teenagers having a laptop in their room and
Speaker 5:  they could like dig into it without being on the family computer, right?
Speaker 5:  I think the laptop used to have ADVD player and got people
Speaker 5:  really accustomed to watching movies on their
Speaker 5:  laptop and then that made a natural transition into streaming, which has
Speaker 5:  led to all of these issues, right? And I think the kind of like
Speaker 5:  weirdly end game, it feels like these always play out in a similar way, is
Speaker 5:  the laptop, is the, is truly the one device that that does it all, even more
Speaker 5:  so than your phone. And I just wonder what that is
Speaker 5:  for games, like will games follow that trend? Is that going to be cloud
Speaker 5:  gaming? Right? It is always like a little weird that you can play
Speaker 5:  games better on your phone than on your MacBook
Speaker 5:  Air or MacBook Pro. But I I, I'm just curious. I I, I truly don't have
Speaker 5:  an answer, but I do think it's valuable to look at like historical precedent
Speaker 5:  and wonder what is the thing I'm missing? It feels like
Speaker 5:  there's something there that I, we've yet to see yet. And I think that's
Speaker 5:  what Google Stadia was trying to get at. They really liked the idea that
Speaker 5:  you would be watching a streamer and then you would just open a browser tab
Speaker 5:  and and start playing with them. But You know so much for that.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Well, and, and if, again, if the world we're headed to, like Fresh
Speaker 4:  was saying earlier, is this one where you have a screen and a control mechanism
Speaker 4:  and games are games and you can, you can kind of get at them with any screen
Speaker 4:  and any control mechanism you have in front of you. The experience might
Speaker 4:  change slightly. The settings might change slightly, but like the game is
Speaker 4:  the game then ultimately it doesn't, it doesn't even necessarily have to
Speaker 4:  break down once you sit down at your laptop. That is not the world we live
Speaker 4:  in now. My like hottest take ever is, I think Stadia was like right about
Speaker 4:  the way the world should be and wrong about the way the world is. And I like
Speaker 4:  wish Stadia had worked with every fiber of my being, but it was also never
Speaker 4:  going to. But that's neither nor there. We'll cover that some other day.
Speaker 5:  Turns out there's a difference between a philosophy and belief system and
Speaker 5:  an actual business. But yeah, You know small
Speaker 4:  Things. This is why they don't let me run Google. Chris,
Speaker 5:  No comment.
Speaker 4:  All, right? We need to get outta here. Thank you both for doing this. This
Speaker 4:  was very fun. We have two more of these episodes to do it. We're gonna come
Speaker 4:  back next week and we're gonna talk about emulating and preserving gaming,
Speaker 4:  which has sent me down rabbit holes I still don't understand. So
Speaker 4:  we're gonna sort through all of that together. But for now, thank you both.
Speaker 4:  This was super fun.
Speaker 4:  All, right? That's it for The Vergecast today. Thanks again to Chris and
Speaker 4:  Russ and thank you as always for listening. As always, if you have thoughts,
Speaker 4:  questions, feelings, favorite mobile games, old consoles you wanna
Speaker 4:  sell me or anything else, you can always email us at Vergecast at The Verge
Speaker 4:  dot com or call the hotline. Eight six six Verge one one. I wanna know what
Speaker 4:  you think about handheld gaming and the future of everything. And as
Speaker 4:  always, we're gonna try to answer at least one hotline question on the show
Speaker 4:  every week. So keep 'em coming. This show is produced by Andrew Marino and
Speaker 4:  Liam James The. Vergecast is The Verge production and part of the Vox Media
Speaker 4:  Podcast network. We'll be back on Wednesday to do a big courtroom catch
Speaker 4:  up. We're gonna talk about the SPF trial. We're gonna talk about Epic versus
Speaker 4:  Google. We might even talk about us versus Google because boy, there's a
Speaker 4:  lot of Google stuff going on. We'll see you then. Rock and roll.