# Transcript
ID: a4eb649d-736e-42b0-be79-20fecac64246
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: RIP DVDs
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/1312765618522673868/-5832235384534559216/s93290-US-3559s-1696207808.mp3
Description: Today on the flagship podcast of the laserdisc resurgence:
While Netflix’s DVD.com service shuts down later this week, The Verge's David Pierce chats with Bill Rouhana, the CEO of Chicken Soup for The Soul Entertainment, about the potential of Redbox and physical media in 2023.
Netflix’s DVD service shuts down: here’s the complex tech behind it
Later, David and Alex Cranz talk with New York Magazine’s John Herrman about his recent story on social media metrics and what they actually mean.
Lies, Damned Lies, and Social-Media Metrics
Keep listening for this week’s Vergecast hotline question.
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we love hearing from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (4 ads detected)
Speaker 2:  Welcome to The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of the LaserDisc
Speaker 2:  Resurgence. I'm your friend David Pierce and I am at a Redbox
Speaker 2:  kiosk near my house outside of A C V ss. I confess, I have never
Speaker 2:  done this before. I've been watching DVDs since, like I
Speaker 2:  had one of those DVD V C R combo things and
Speaker 2:  back then the only DVD we had was clueless. So I watched it like
Speaker 2:  65,000 times. Then my family was a pretty early Netflix
Speaker 2:  house So. we had those red envelopes coming and going all the time. And then
Speaker 2:  somewhere along the way I gave away my DVD collection and just went all in
Speaker 2:  on streaming. There was a piracy phase in there too, but we don't
Speaker 2:  have to talk about that. But now here I am at the Redbox because this kind
Speaker 2:  of feels like the last bastion of the old DVD era.
Speaker 2:  Like I'm looking at this and I can get DVDs of Asteroid City and the Super
Speaker 2:  Mario Brothers movie and Shazam, which I definitely won't do,
Speaker 2:  and Cocaine Bear, which I might do. And this just feels
Speaker 2:  like an era. That's ending DVD dot com, which is the name of
Speaker 2:  Netflix's old DVD delivery service, is shutting down for good this week.
Speaker 2:  Oh, and quick p s A on that front, actually, if you're still a DVD subscriber,
Speaker 2:  put all your favorite movies at the top of the queue right now because you
Speaker 2:  get to keep everything you have when the service goes down. So do that as
Speaker 2:  fast as you can. But with that gone and streaming still really ascendant
Speaker 2:  even though it's kind of a mess right now. I just wonder what's gonna happen.
Speaker 2:  Is physical media just dead? Is it gonna have a huge comeback like vinyl
Speaker 2:  did where everybody's suddenly buying albums Again, I really don't know,
Speaker 2:  but I'm very curious about it. So in the first part of the show today, I
Speaker 2:  am actually going to talk to the person responsible for this kiosk I'm standing
Speaker 2:  in front of. That's Bill Rouhana, the C e O of Chicken Soup for the Soul
Speaker 2:  Entertainment, which now owns Redbox as of a year ago. He has, it turns
Speaker 2:  out some surprisingly strong thoughts on the subject. After that, we're gonna
Speaker 2:  switch gears a bit and talk about metrics. The numbers we see everywhere
Speaker 2:  online, especially around video views and what it means that
Speaker 2:  everyone reports those numbers and none of it really seems to have anything
Speaker 2:  to do with anything. All that is coming in just a sec. But first I gotta
Speaker 2:  pick a movie here, right? We've got a bunch of Spidermans,
Speaker 2:  John Wick three plane, which I don't think I
Speaker 2:  knew was a movie until right this second. Oh, they have Dungeons and Dragons.
Speaker 2:  Okay, Dungeons and Dragons Honor Among Thieves. Rent DVD $2
Speaker 2:  and 25 cents. Or I can buy it for 3 99. I'm buying a DVD. Let's do
Speaker 2:  this. Alright, taking this home. Here we go. This is The Vergecast.
Speaker 2:  See you in a sec.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. Alright, I got a movie, I made it home and then
Speaker 2:  I realized I don't own a DVD player anymore, which was problem for a second.
Speaker 2:  But then I realized that's why game consoles exist. Someday I
Speaker 2:  will own one of those little small disc list ones, but for now I have
Speaker 2:  an old Xbox One and a PS four, both of which have disc drives. So
Speaker 2:  I am wired up and ready for movie time. But for now, let's talk about
Speaker 2:  the future of those discs. Redbox is probably the biggest
Speaker 2:  brand left in physical movies. DVD dot com obviously
Speaker 2:  dying this week. Blockbuster is long gone. I don't think anybody goes to
Speaker 2:  Best Buy or Walmart to buy movies anymore, right? And
Speaker 2:  Redbox just kind of seems like the last game in town. And Redbox
Speaker 2:  actually got a new owner last year. It's called Chicken Soup for the Soul
Speaker 2:  Entertainment, which also owns the streaming service, crackle and
Speaker 2:  popcorn flicks. Plus it has film production and distribution companies.
Speaker 2:  The company paid $375 million for Redbox last
Speaker 2:  year, which a lot of people thought was totally bonkers at
Speaker 2:  the time and still do, frankly. But Bill Rouhana, the c e o of chicken
Speaker 2:  Soup for the Soul Entertainment is convinced that physical media is
Speaker 2:  not dead, or at least is not dead yet and won't be dead anytime
Speaker 2:  soon. So I called him up to talk about why he thinks this is a good
Speaker 2:  business and why he's betting on discs, even when his own company is in the
Speaker 2:  streaming business. And maybe most of all why he tried to buy
Speaker 2:  DVD dot com from Netflix before it shut down. One thing you should know before
Speaker 2:  we get into the interview, bill uses the terms a v O D and s o d a
Speaker 2:  bunch, and a o d means ad supported video on demand. And ss
Speaker 2:  o d means subscription video on demand, avod you pay with ads, SS o d you
Speaker 2:  pay with money. Fairly simple. Just wanted to clear that up in case you hadn't
Speaker 2:  heard it before. Anyway, let's get into it.
Speaker 2:  What was interesting to you about Redbox in the first place?
Speaker 4:  Oh, really many things. Let's start with the brand and
Speaker 4:  the, the very loyal customer base spread out across the country
Speaker 4:  that hadn't, probably hasn't fully migrated to the digital world
Speaker 4:  for a variety of reasons. Not the least of which is some places they
Speaker 4:  don't have bandwidth. That's enough to be able to download movies and watch
Speaker 4:  them without a circle of death, you know, to make, to make the experience
Speaker 4:  miserable. In some cases, they're just late adopters and other cases
Speaker 4:  they can't afford the internet or they can't afford the kind of internet
Speaker 4:  that's required to be able to do digital downloads. They're
Speaker 4:  movie lovers. They're, they're entertainment lovers. So they, they're highly
Speaker 4:  motivated to, to consume the stuff that we have. I mean, I can go
Speaker 4:  on and on and on about this. There were many things, yeah, but the starting
Speaker 4:  point was the brand, the 42 million people in the customer loyalty
Speaker 4:  program, the beginning of the foray into the digital world,
Speaker 4:  the ownership of a very large transactional video business,
Speaker 4:  which is very hard to start. And then the kiosks, which in
Speaker 4:  my mind someday I hope to prove this would be generators
Speaker 4:  of significant cashflow if handled correctly. That could be
Speaker 4:  the cashflow machine that allowed us to build our digital business out over
Speaker 4:  the next decade.
Speaker 2:  The audience is one that I'm particularly interested in.
Speaker 2:  'cause we, we've been talking a lot about who physical media is for in
Speaker 2:  2023, right? And I think a lot of people look at that audience and say
Speaker 2:  that audience is dwindling really fast. It's much smaller than it used to
Speaker 2:  be. Most of those people are going to one way or another find a way to get
Speaker 2:  into this streaming era So. We're just gonna kind of leave that
Speaker 2:  audience behind and trust that they'll eventually catch up. You win a
Speaker 2:  different way. Or maybe you think that's true, but there's money to be made
Speaker 2:  along the way. Like how do you think about sort of who that audience is right
Speaker 2:  now?
Speaker 4:  Well, I, I think it's the people I just described, people who are not
Speaker 4:  sure able to have access to bandwidth, who can't afford it is another
Speaker 4:  category. It's smaller, but it's likely to grow of people who
Speaker 4:  say, wait a minute, I'm not getting the same quality out of
Speaker 4:  a digital download that I would've if I had the physical disc and I had all
Speaker 4:  that additional capability to see things more crisply. I know
Speaker 4:  some people who won't watch a Bond movie unless it's on a DVD. It
Speaker 4:  has to be blue, right? It has to be the topnotch 'cause they wanna feel every
Speaker 4:  bit of it. This is early for this, this conversation, but at some
Speaker 4:  point this probably takes the turn that eBooks took
Speaker 4:  back to physical books that downloads and music took
Speaker 4:  back to actual albums where people
Speaker 4:  started to differentiate a little bit. And you had this growing cohort
Speaker 4:  of people who thought, you know, quality is important too. And I get
Speaker 4:  a much higher quality picture, a much higher quality experience if
Speaker 4:  I actually have the physical media, which is so much more richly packed with
Speaker 4:  information. Oh, and then there's all this other stuff that comes
Speaker 4:  with these DVDs that, you know, you might wanna have actually have seen.
Speaker 4:  You know, so it's, you know, all the extras that that you get, that you don't
Speaker 4:  get in a digital download very often. For us, it's really about giving you
Speaker 4:  access to first class, top-notch
Speaker 4:  current content from any studio at the lowest
Speaker 4:  possible price, the earliest in the ecosystem after a
Speaker 4:  theatrical that you can do it. And so there's something that we're,
Speaker 4:  we're meeting a need that's a little different than that collectible need,
Speaker 4:  that's for sure.
Speaker 2:  Right. Yeah. And I think that piece of the kind of windowing
Speaker 2:  that you've, you're into is part of the thing about your strategy that I
Speaker 2:  think is so interesting. 'cause it seems to me that, you know, you have crackle,
Speaker 2:  you have chicken Soup for the Soul, you have Redbox, everyone else is kind
Speaker 2:  of out in the streaming industry fighting about content. Everybody's making
Speaker 2:  shows and spending more and more money throwing it into their own platforms.
Speaker 2:  It seems to me that what you're building is this sort of every step
Speaker 2:  of the way distribution pipeline.
Speaker 4:  That's correct.
Speaker 2:  Rather than saying, we're gonna throw a bunch of money at David Fincher,
Speaker 2:  you're trying to get in sort of every step of where content is.
Speaker 2:  Is that a fair description of, of how you think about this?
Speaker 4:  It is. And I mean, look, we thought and have always thought that
Speaker 4:  understanding what consumers want is most easily achieved
Speaker 4:  by watching what they do. And if you want
Speaker 4:  to watch what they do, you have to be in that first line of
Speaker 4:  consumption so that you see what they do. And one of the things I loved
Speaker 4:  about, and still love about Redbox, those 42 million people in the customer
Speaker 4:  loyalty program give us a group of people who we know, we
Speaker 4:  know who they are and we know when, when their places and we can learn what
Speaker 4:  they like. And eventually, artificial intelligence can help
Speaker 4:  us, I think, figure out how to serve them stuff on the home
Speaker 4:  screens of our, of our networks that are tailored to them. By the
Speaker 4:  word. I will repeat the word eventually because we cannot do
Speaker 4:  that today, nor can anyone else, no matter what they call you.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, yeah. Everybody's, everybody's doing a lot of voodoo that I think doesn't
Speaker 2:  add up to much in a lot of cases.
Speaker 4:  No, not yet.
Speaker 2:  So w was that part of the thinking with Redbox that you can get
Speaker 2:  this very early sense of what people like and what's successful and, and
Speaker 2:  that informs like what ends up on, you know, crackle months or years later?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, so from one perspective, that's what it was about. And
Speaker 4:  you know, if you think about it, the kiosks transactional
Speaker 4:  video, the fast business, the A V O D business, we
Speaker 4:  have some subscription stuff, but it's not really our focus. I don't think
Speaker 4:  that's a particularly good business right now. But having so many different
Speaker 4:  places that people interact with us as they consume it
Speaker 4:  is very valuable. It is a, a great bit of information that other people
Speaker 4:  don't have. And, and actually other than Amazon, there really isn't
Speaker 4:  another company with as many connecting points with consumers in the media
Speaker 4:  space as us. We are a very unique beast. And
Speaker 4:  that's all intentional. That was really what I was looking for when I was,
Speaker 4:  as I was putting these pieces together. We haven't taken advantage of that
Speaker 4:  yet, David. We haven't yet integrated all this stuff in a way that we know
Speaker 4:  how to smartly take advantage of what we can do. But we've certainly set
Speaker 4:  the stage for that to happen so that, because we have the
Speaker 4:  early access all the way across a, a wide number of things.
Speaker 4:  So that was the plan. There's a flip side to this too, by the way. If
Speaker 4:  you're thinking about creating content and you wanna make sure
Speaker 4:  that as you create it, you're doing it in the le the least risky
Speaker 4:  way, having all this information about what is consumed in these
Speaker 4:  various ways, like what works at the kiosks, what works in t o d,
Speaker 4:  what works in A V O D, what works on fast, that informs your
Speaker 4:  thinking about how you will commit to content creation. And
Speaker 4:  a lot of times, because you're the first dollar in a lot of these places,
Speaker 4:  you have superior economics to people who otherwise were creating
Speaker 4:  content and would've to go through your system and you get a piece of their
Speaker 4:  revenue. So if you believe, as I do that ultimately content
Speaker 4:  and distribution are irrevocably and completely tied to each
Speaker 4:  other, it is the kind of ecosystem that allows you to actually
Speaker 4:  lower your risk and create content over time and get the most money
Speaker 4:  back from it. And it completely blows
Speaker 4:  away the theory that an s o standing by itself is a good idea. 'cause it
Speaker 4:  isn't. And everybody's now figured that out. We've, we've done this,
Speaker 4:  I I've been talking about this for since 2017 that the
Speaker 4:  S five business was a disaster waiting to happen.
Speaker 2:  Do you think physical media keeps being part of that equation over
Speaker 2:  time? I mean, if you, if you play it out a ways more people have broadband,
Speaker 2:  the windowing system maybe changes so that there are fewer
Speaker 2:  ways to get stuff, but it's still kind of, you, you get the $20 downloads
Speaker 2:  instead of the DVD rentals and stuff like that. Do you think there's a place
Speaker 2:  for physical media in this long term?
Speaker 4:  I do. If only because experience tells us that
Speaker 4:  inertia is a, is the most powerful force of all,
Speaker 4:  and changing people's habits is really hard to do. Now,
Speaker 4:  COVID broke a lot of things, right? It, it forced people to
Speaker 4:  change their habits. One thing it did is it accelerated the digital
Speaker 4:  transformation dramatically. But if you looked at our, at our business
Speaker 4:  and understood the assumption we made about what would be
Speaker 4:  successful in the physical space, we said
Speaker 4:  we expected the Redbox kiosks with a full,
Speaker 4:  full of the content that it used to have prior to Covid would do
Speaker 4:  30% of the business that it did in 2019 before covid.
Speaker 4:  With that very low expectation, we were highly profitable.
Speaker 2:  Okay,
Speaker 4:  Wow. Which was why I thought this was a good idea
Speaker 4:  that even if two thirds or more of the people had changed their mind about
Speaker 4:  consumption, and that's a pretty aggressive assumption that two thirds of
Speaker 4:  the people have changed their habits, that that would be amazing. Then, we
Speaker 4:  would still be profitable at 30%. And, and that is further
Speaker 4:  enhanced, I'll say for lack of a better word, by the fact that we have a
Speaker 4:  couple of other businesses that make the kiosks profitable
Speaker 4:  at a lower level than that from things other than just rentals. We
Speaker 4:  are putting screens on top of them and selling digital out of home advertising.
Speaker 4:  We have a business that's built around the service
Speaker 4:  company that services our Redbox kiosks, does
Speaker 4:  the break fix of them and does the merchandising of them.
Speaker 4:  We now do that service for other big kiosk owners and every
Speaker 4:  time we add one of those customers, we bring our costs
Speaker 4:  down to service our own kiosks. To the point that I think
Speaker 4:  by the end of next year we'll be close to zero net cost to
Speaker 4:  actually run our own kiosks from a servicing point of view. And that changes
Speaker 4:  the business entirely. So if you took a one dimensional
Speaker 4:  view of this question and said, Hey, DVDs are gonna go away over the next
Speaker 4:  10 years, how are you gonna handle this? I would say, okay, great, let's
Speaker 4:  start with the fact that I believe it's at least 10 years because of the
Speaker 4:  way people's habits are, but let's also be smart and think about the ways
Speaker 4:  we could make that less relevant to our success. Let's use these
Speaker 4:  kiosks in more diversified ways. Let's bring down the cost through the service
Speaker 4:  business. Let's figure out what the right price increases
Speaker 4:  might be over the course of a decade to help make up for some of the lost,
Speaker 4:  you know, customers. And when you look at it on an, on that kind of amalgamated
Speaker 4:  basis, you start to realize, hey, it's relevant that
Speaker 4:  physical media is going away, but perhaps less relevant than people thought
Speaker 4:  when we bought the company. Which is why we are crazy, but
Speaker 4:  not for the reasons people thought.
Speaker 2:  That's fair. So if that's the timeline you're thinking about, do you think
Speaker 2:  Netflix is nuts to shut down its DVD program now? I mean,
Speaker 2:  if if we're in a 10 year time horizon, they're really jumping the gun here.
Speaker 4:  I think if you're them is a wholly different analysis. This is such
Speaker 4:  a tiny little thing in a gargantuan business.
Speaker 4:  That's fair. It's not strategic, it's, it's more like a
Speaker 4:  pain, you know, it's, it's not like it has any in any way
Speaker 4:  affects your core business. Not at all. So the kind
Speaker 4:  of, I mean, the better question is why keep it, you know, the bigger question
Speaker 4:  is why didn't you just sell it to me when I tried to buy it? Because I could
Speaker 4:  have created a whole bunch of synergies out of that business. You know?
Speaker 2:  So why, why didn't they sell it to you?
Speaker 4:  I don't know. They just didn't even return our phone calls asking about it
Speaker 4:  really. We told them, we told 'em we wanted it, but they just, I think they
Speaker 4:  just want it gone. You know, it's a distraction for them. Sure.
Speaker 2:  What would you have done with it?
Speaker 4:  Well, I don't know that I would've bought it, but you know, if they, if they
Speaker 4:  returned my calls, what I would've looked at was, can I create
Speaker 4:  operational synergies and keep the cost lower and drive additional
Speaker 4:  revenue into this portion of our business? There's a whole other question
Speaker 4:  lurking here, which is, who else is in the retail and media business?
Speaker 4:  Can you think of any companies like Amazon for example, that might be
Speaker 4:  in the retail and media business and have found ways to make those two businesses
Speaker 4:  work incredibly well together? People tend to have sort of a very
Speaker 4:  single-minded view of almost everything. Yeah. And if you, if you kind
Speaker 4:  of challenge that single-minded view, you know, they go off the
Speaker 4:  rails so they kind lose it. But you know, there are examples of the
Speaker 4:  retail business and the media businesses working very well together. There
Speaker 4:  are examples of them not working at all. Walmart and Voodoo was not
Speaker 4:  a good example of it. No, no insult to Walmart. They just are, they're
Speaker 4:  not a media company, they're a retailer. That's what they are. Amazon
Speaker 4:  god knows what they are. They're, they're just awesome at everything they
Speaker 4:  do, which scares everybody to death. But you know, they're really good at
Speaker 4:  what they do. So look, I don't think there's any anything inherently
Speaker 4:  contradictory about being in the two businesses if you know, if you know
Speaker 4:  how to be in them. There are a couple of other companies I've learned of
Speaker 4:  that are similar. There's a company called Go Digital, I, which a company
Speaker 4:  I like very much is in both sides of the, both in retail
Speaker 4:  and media. They make it work. So I think it can work, that's all.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I think part of the reason I'm, I'm curious about kind of the, the
Speaker 2:  hypothetical of what you would've done is, it seems like, you know, it goes
Speaker 2:  back to what you said about Redbox at the very beginning, right? It's, it's
Speaker 2:  a really good brand. People know it. Yeah. There are a lot of people in the
Speaker 2:  program and it seems to me that if you take the idea of
Speaker 2:  this is a very accessible brand that gets new stuff, there are a lot of
Speaker 2:  ways you can go with that. You could just do Redbox by mail
Speaker 2:  and I don't know if the economics work for a lot of the reasons you're describing,
Speaker 2:  but that's a thing you could do. Or there are, you know, you could start
Speaker 2:  selling movies to people through Redbox. It just, there are so many
Speaker 2:  sort of splinters off of this thing that is Redbox
Speaker 2:  this good brand that people know and are used to interacting with.
Speaker 2:  Especially if you're betting that physical media as a thing is gonna be around
Speaker 2:  for a long time, that's an increasingly not competitive space. And
Speaker 2:  it feels like if you wanted to sort of branch out from Redbox into,
Speaker 2:  we just want to own all of the ways that you get acquire
Speaker 2:  and watch physical media, you could have pretty big
Speaker 2:  ambitions there without a lot in your way. Right?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I agree. Well that was part of the reason to look at the, at the
Speaker 4:  Netflix DVD business too. I mean, you know, there were, if we had gotten
Speaker 4:  the opportunity, if we'd gotten the opportunity to have a conversation about
Speaker 4:  it, we would've then analyzed whether it made sense. We never got
Speaker 4:  to that point. I I just thought there were a lot of inherent possibilities
Speaker 4:  in that, you know?
Speaker 2:  Yeah. What do you think about DVDs and Blu-rays in particular? Like I, I
Speaker 2:  I I grant you, this is getting pretty far in the weeds of physical media
Speaker 2:  here, but I think I, I was thinking a lot about the vinyl thing Yeah. Today
Speaker 2:  and in prepping for this, because it's telling to me that we didn't go back
Speaker 2:  to CDs and we didn't go back to cassettes, we went to vinyl. Because
Speaker 2:  that is the object. It feels better. Like if
Speaker 2:  you're gonna buy the physical thing, that is the best version of it. It sounds
Speaker 2:  the best, it looks the coolest, it has the most kind of cultural history.
Speaker 2:  Like that's the one. And I wonder if we're, if we're gonna get some of that
Speaker 2:  same stuff for movies and TV shows, are we, are
Speaker 2:  we gonna get a new format? Are we gonna go back to like, like is v h s gonna
Speaker 2:  come back? What's your sense of Blu-ray and DVDs kind of staying power
Speaker 2:  over this next decade?
Speaker 4:  I think it's Blu-ray DVD that that gives you the, what you need. You know,
Speaker 4:  we're
Speaker 2:  Not getting laser discs back. This is all a way of winding up to say, can
Speaker 2:  you please bring laser discs back? That's what I thought.
Speaker 4:  We don't think so. But partly it's because, you know, you've got
Speaker 4:  an embedded base of equipment that's quite extensive where the
Speaker 4:  DVD can be used and the Blu-ray can be used. And of course there were a lot
Speaker 4:  of turntables even though they weren't really running that much. People had
Speaker 4:  'em and they were dying to turn 'em back on, you know, to get 'em back and
Speaker 4:  get the, you know, the quality of, and I guess the feeling you know of,
Speaker 4:  of that. So yeah.
Speaker 2:  Do you think there are ways we can make physical and
Speaker 2:  digital stuff interact better over time? Like I, I
Speaker 2:  remember years ago talking to people who said, you know, if you buy a DVD,
Speaker 2:  you should also get the digital downloads so that you can watch it on the
Speaker 2:  devices that don't have DVD players. Yes. And especially now, I mean, people
Speaker 2:  watch a lot of stuff on devices that don't or can't connect
Speaker 2:  to DVD players. It's true. Are there ways to kind of put those pieces
Speaker 2:  together?
Speaker 4:  Yes, there are, but I don't know if, if that's a game
Speaker 4:  changer, but I think it's, you know, an incrementally
Speaker 4:  better world. If you can use, if you can put those two things together, I
Speaker 4:  think it's good. But I I the things that drive the, that drive our
Speaker 4:  business and now look, that's, you're asking me a generic question. So, you
Speaker 4:  know, what do you think about this as a general principle? I always think
Speaker 4:  about it. What does it mean to my business? I can't help that. That's what
Speaker 4:  I do. And you know, so when I think about it from our, our businesses
Speaker 4:  point of view, what drives our business is the fact that we're the, the least
Speaker 4:  expensive way to get first run movies. That's what drives our business.
Speaker 4:  And get 'em right very early and get 'em from every studio. If you look
Speaker 4:  at only any of the streamers, not a single one
Speaker 4:  of them can deliver. You first run movies early
Speaker 4:  from every studio. They can deliver theirs. Sometimes they can deliver
Speaker 4:  one other guy's, but nobody can deliver everybody's, except
Speaker 4:  we can. Or you can get it through transactional video, but that is so much
Speaker 4:  more expensive that for a large chunk of people it's
Speaker 4:  prohibitively expensive. So
Speaker 2:  I guess the question then would be, if that's the thing, right? If you boil
Speaker 2:  it all the way down and say that the thing that we have is cheap ways to
Speaker 2:  watch first run movies, what do you press on customer
Speaker 2:  experience wise to make that better? Is the answer more kiosks so
Speaker 2:  that it's quicker to get to? Is the answer find ways to make it even cheaper?
Speaker 2:  Is it find ways to convince Netflix to put its stuff on DVDs so people can
Speaker 2:  get it? Like what's, what's the next turn if there is one
Speaker 2:  in, in how to do that even better?
Speaker 4:  I think that the thing that drives the business is always content. Sure.
Speaker 4:  And making and getting the most content as quickly as possible is the key.
Speaker 4:  And here's where the window word, which you've used a few times already and
Speaker 4:  I've ignored,
Speaker 4:  becomes an important word. Sure. You know, because
Speaker 4:  getting an organized window strategy from the
Speaker 4:  studios so that consumers know what to expect
Speaker 4:  would be a very good thing for everybody. You wanna make this experience
Speaker 4:  better, make it clear to people when they could expect to see these
Speaker 4:  things. I mean, right now the media business has destroyed
Speaker 4:  itself between taking television and breaking it into
Speaker 4:  5,000 pieces and making it impossible for people to figure out where
Speaker 4:  to watch things. And, and going through layer after layer of search to try
Speaker 4:  and find stuff between that. And the fact that the
Speaker 4:  windowing strategy of the various studios are completely,
Speaker 4:  they look ad hoc to me. They don't look like strategies. They look like,
Speaker 4:  you know, just, Hey, let's see what happens. You know, that is not good
Speaker 4:  for the consumer. We have not made life better for consumers in either
Speaker 4:  of those ways. And good, solid, understandable windows,
Speaker 4:  which are, you know, you don't have to be slavishly adherent to them, but
Speaker 4:  which generally are followed is a huge service to the consumer
Speaker 4:  in terms of understanding when to expect to see something. It's mind
Speaker 4:  boggling to me that this is not returned faster. So the best thing I think
Speaker 4:  we could do for consumers is come up with a windowing strategy that actually
Speaker 4:  everybody abides by so that they know when to look for things. Otherwise
Speaker 4:  they're just kinda like wandering around going, I don't know, when does this
Speaker 4:  come out? Why is Barbie out this week and Oppenheimer out this week? Weren't
Speaker 4:  they in the theaters at the same time? Why are they six weeks apart? I don't
Speaker 4:  know. Universal and Wi and Warners. Okay, great. Do, do you as a
Speaker 4:  consumer care, which studio made the movie you wanna see? I don't think
Speaker 4:  so. They, what you care about is what is it available and do you know how
Speaker 4:  to find it?
Speaker 2:  I, no, I agree and I actually love that example because I think the Barb
Speaker 2:  Inheimer thing was such a phenomenon that there are going to be a lot of
Speaker 2:  people who want to get both of those movies and watch them in the same day.
Speaker 2:  Nice. And that is going to be so stupidly difficult for so long.
Speaker 4:  It is. It's really ridiculous. So silly. We've
Speaker 4:  got Barbie coming to the kiosk within the next few weeks, which we're excited
Speaker 4:  about. There you go. But Oppenheimer's not coming to the kiosk until November
Speaker 4:  or maybe even later. I don't even know at this point. You know, it doesn't
Speaker 4:  make a ton of sense. It's, it's not smart. But this is
Speaker 4:  part of the covid recovery of the media business, trying
Speaker 4:  to come back to a new, a new approach with c o d having
Speaker 4:  driven so much digital, you know, take up, it changed
Speaker 4:  everybody's, you know, kind of focus in the media business to
Speaker 4:  digital, digital, digital. And now as we start to realize, well
Speaker 4:  wait a minute, it's really not that smart to only have one way to monetize
Speaker 4:  your movie when you should. You could have seven, you know, or six or whatever
Speaker 4:  it is. And you one doesn't cannibalize the other. In fact, a lot
Speaker 4:  of people like to watch it in all those different forms. It's adjusting to
Speaker 4:  that and changing who's in charge in these studios
Speaker 4:  is really, really taking the time. Because when you really get right down
Speaker 4:  to it, this is just a fight between different parts of the same company
Speaker 4:  as to when they're gonna do things. How long we gonna put it in the theaters?
Speaker 4:  Where's it gonna go next? Is it tva? Is it, you know, you got a different
Speaker 4:  guy who runs TVA than a guy who runs the DVD business, right.
Speaker 2:  And they hate each other. Yeah. Right.
Speaker 4:  And then there's another guy who's licensing this stuff. You know, this is
Speaker 4:  like a free for all trying to figure out who's turn, is it, you know, every
Speaker 4:  studio's gonna go through this in their own way.
Speaker 2:  And then there's just Redbox kind of kicking it increasingly on its own.
Speaker 2:  I mean, does it, does it feel like this is a competitive space at
Speaker 2:  the moment? Like what, what are you looking for?
Speaker 4:  No, no. We're we're at, we're all, let's laugh.
Speaker 2:  Do you think that's gonna change anytime soon? If are, if we get kind of
Speaker 2:  a, a pushback towards some of the stuff you're talking about, are you gonna
Speaker 2:  get new competition?
Speaker 4:  No, I don't think so. Because the physical presence that you have to create
Speaker 4:  to be in our business is so vast and we have 30,000 kiosks
Speaker 4:  spread out across the entire United States. You've got leases with
Speaker 4:  people, you've gotta be able to service these things. We're not gonna have
Speaker 4:  any real competition. What is interesting is the growth of kiosks in general
Speaker 4:  in the country is, is amazing to me. I mean, there's kiosks popping up
Speaker 4:  all over the place that's good for our service business. 'cause that's lots
Speaker 4:  of customers for us there. And I think that's going to be one of our great
Speaker 4:  businesses.
Speaker 2:  All right. Thank you. This was, this was really great and really fun. I really
Speaker 2:  appreciate you taking the time.
Speaker 4:  It is my pleasure. Nice talking to you.
Speaker 2:  We gotta take a break and then we're gonna talk about numbers. Big,
Speaker 2:  ubiquitous, meaningless numbers. We'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. We talk a lot on this show about numbers,
Speaker 2:  what it means to go viral and how creators use numbers
Speaker 2:  and metrics to understand their business and just what it means
Speaker 2:  to be a person when everything you do and post and see
Speaker 2:  has a million numbers attached to it. And all of these numbers seem
Speaker 2:  so, if not meaningless then at least really hard to make sense of,
Speaker 2:  like, can you compare a YouTube view to a TikTok view, to an
Speaker 2:  Instagram view? Is doing that even useful? And
Speaker 2:  how do you make sense of any of it when everyone knows at this point that
Speaker 2:  so much of it can just be gamed in one way or another? Well,
Speaker 2:  our friend John Herrman over at New York Magazine recently wrote a column
Speaker 2:  that basically made the case that all of these numbers are nonsense. It
Speaker 2:  really resonated with me and it kind of made me wonder what we do now.
Speaker 2:  So I asked him to come on the show and talk about what it means that the
Speaker 2:  internet is just swimming with numbers, most of which have nothing to do
Speaker 2:  with anything. I also grabbed Alex Cranz because we can't talk streaming
Speaker 2:  numbers without Alex Cranz. Let's get into it. John Herrman Welcome to The
Speaker 2:  Vergecast, thanks
Speaker 5:  For having me.
Speaker 2:  Alex is here too. Hi Alex. What's up David? John, can you just like sort
Speaker 2:  of run down the thesis of your piece for somebody who hasn't read it? Like
Speaker 2:  why did you write about why Twitter views don't make any sense?
Speaker 5:  I mean, I'll take any chance to write about weird metrics. I feel like this
Speaker 5:  is, this is like a trick that I use at like a few times
Speaker 5:  a year for a decade now, where it's like, hey, there's a number out there
Speaker 5:  that doesn't really make any sense. If you explain that number to people,
Speaker 5:  everyone else will be like, oh wait, that's what that means. Nothing. The
Speaker 5:  thing is that way of like measuring
Speaker 5:  everything in ways that are kind of off and manipulative
Speaker 5:  and misleading and, and serve all these different purposes
Speaker 5:  is becoming more and more a part of just like the fabric of daily life
Speaker 5:  online. Like everything that people use in
Speaker 5:  any social network, in a lot of non-social context, just in their software
Speaker 5:  is sort of counting what they're doing and returning it to them with higher
Speaker 5:  and higher numbers that are meant to sort of suggest that you, or they're
Speaker 5:  sort of meant to inform your behavior or make you feel good or make you feel
Speaker 5:  bad. Like you need to do something else. You're just surrounded by these
Speaker 5:  numbers all the time and it's just this background part of your online life.
Speaker 5:  But as a lot of stories start these days, there was a ridiculous tweet
Speaker 5:  and was it the Tucker Carlson thing? Yeah. Yeah. So, okay.
Speaker 5:  Donald Trump and Tucker Carlson kind of counter programmed the Republican
Speaker 5:  primary debate with an interview on Tucker
Speaker 5:  Carlson's show, which if pe if you haven't been following this is now,
Speaker 5:  I guess you would say hosted on X, like exclusively. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  He is just blogging and posting it straight to
Speaker 5:  straight to X and the interview happens, the debate happens,
Speaker 5:  the debate gets like 12, 13, 14 million views
Speaker 5:  according to Nielsen, which is its own can of worms. Fox comes out and says
Speaker 5:  like, yeah, I don't know, 15 million people watch this. If you count the
Speaker 5:  streaming and stuff like that, no one really cares. Donald Trump comes out
Speaker 5:  and says, Hey actually we got like
Speaker 5:  230 million views on my interview,
Speaker 5:  which is nearly as many people as living the entire, the entire United States.
Speaker 5:  That number kept going up and up and up eventually it's like 300 million
Speaker 5:  people. And you know, he play, he's pretty loose
Speaker 5:  with numbers. You sort of, you wanna revise down a lot of Trump numbers.
Speaker 5:  That's we're, we're kind of used to that. But in this case, he was just actually
Speaker 5:  citing a metric attached to the tweet
Speaker 5:  under Tucker Carlson's video. And it really did say,
Speaker 5:  at the time I wrote the article, it was like 265 million views
Speaker 5:  for what was like, you know, Donald Trump has given a lot of interviews and
Speaker 5:  he's given interviews to Tucker Carlson. This was like, I'm sure very
Speaker 5:  interesting to quite a few people in a variety of different ways. It is
Speaker 5:  not something that everyone in the world or everyone, more than every
Speaker 5:  voter in the United States would watch. It's just like completely implausible.
Speaker 5:  Everyone knows that's ridiculous, but it's not just, you know, kind of like
Speaker 5:  a notoriously misleading public figure doing this.
Speaker 5:  It is the platform saying that's what happened. Views a word that
Speaker 5:  we're supposed to interpret like in some sort of way, 265 million,
Speaker 5:  a big number that you know exists, exists in the world.
Speaker 5:  So I dunno you that doesn't make any sense. That's the kind of thing that
Speaker 5:  you would expect to hear from like Tabula or Outbrain talking about how their
Speaker 5:  chum box videos are performing, right? And instead it is
Speaker 5:  like being cited by the former president directly on, still very
Speaker 5:  influential social media platform, right? So just kind of walk, wanna walk
Speaker 5:  back from there. Like that can't be real. Of course it's not Twitter
Speaker 5:  internally tracks video views and if you use the
Speaker 5:  Twitter for Mac client, you can still see those views, which Elon Musk
Speaker 5:  had removed. The real number of views on that was like 12 million
Speaker 5:  or 15 million about the same as the Republican debate. Nielsen
Speaker 5:  ratings, which again, a big number. However, that number is
Speaker 5:  tracked after I believe two seconds of video playtime
Speaker 5:  anywhere on the screen, which if you ask someone what it means to watch something,
Speaker 5:  no one's gonna on their, unless they work in advertising or something,
Speaker 5:  no one's gonna be like, oh yeah, well if you look at it for two seconds and
Speaker 5:  then scroll past it, you watched it. Like that's the opposite of watching
Speaker 5:  it. However, that is the Twitter video metric. Somehow
Speaker 5:  Twitter is now measuring something that is like
Speaker 5:  that, that is like 50 times less rigorous than that and
Speaker 5:  telling everybody that that's how many people are seeing something. And you
Speaker 5:  know, it's funny, it's silly, it's a specific example. It is also how the
Speaker 5:  entire internet works right now. There are just these
Speaker 5:  bullshit numbers absolutely everywhere. They're all bullshit in slightly
Speaker 5:  different ways. They're all kind of like, you know, fundamentally
Speaker 5:  bullshit in the same way. But they're all these like different stacks of
Speaker 5:  invented measurements. They're frequently compared to each other. They're
Speaker 5:  frequently touted for marketing. They're used to just sort of like contextualize
Speaker 5:  conversations about something.
Speaker 6:  I mean, is that true or are they mainly used to sell ads or like
Speaker 6:  convince people to buy ads, right? Like, like saying, oh yeah, we got 300 million
Speaker 6:  views. Don't, don't look into the numbers, but we got 300 million, you're
Speaker 6:  gonna get 300 million impressions if you advertise on this
Speaker 6:  Tucker Carlson show.
Speaker 5:  That's absolutely the logic of the like gradual number inflation.
Speaker 5:  But I think what's weird about it now is that that sort of on
Speaker 5:  its face absurd, but everyone just goes along with it.
Speaker 5:  Number inflation is bleeding out of just, you know, the
Speaker 5:  sales teams at websites and Social platforms. It's now's just like something
Speaker 5:  that everyone talks about and fandoms talk about metrics all the time.
Speaker 5:  They try to manipulate metrics even if the metrics are sort of fake to like
Speaker 5:  get their people, you know, seen or in some cases paid more.
Speaker 5:  You've got Elon Musk kind of making the case for his entire, the existence
Speaker 5:  of his entire platform and the relevance of his entire platform going on
Speaker 5:  to like double down on this after a bunch of people pointed out that yeah,
Speaker 5:  this, for example Trump tweet is kind of ridiculous. The
Speaker 5:  other day he was suggesting that 3 billion people
Speaker 5:  a month see long tweets Like
Speaker 5:  okay, just the Twitter blue long form content is,
Speaker 5:  is viewed by 3 billion people. Which I'm sure in some
Speaker 5:  extremely narrow way is true. Like that content somehow
Speaker 5:  produced in a combination of people scrolling, kind of
Speaker 5:  like loading or you know, internal a p I calls
Speaker 5:  calling upon these posts. I'm sure, I'm sure that number of
Speaker 5:  impressions to borrow the ad world term here was somehow
Speaker 5:  kind of generated and logged, but that just has no relationship to
Speaker 5:  the reality of how many people are engaging with something or seeing something
Speaker 5:  or, or like taking something in. Well, and I think
Speaker 2:  There, there are like two sides of this to me. One is this sort of nonsense
Speaker 2:  advertiser metrics we've always had, right? And every company has their own
Speaker 2:  special metrics that don't make any sense to anyone and essentially
Speaker 2:  mean nothing. You know, Elon Musk has been doing this loudly with Twitter,
Speaker 2:  like he talks a lot about like regretted user minutes. Yeah. Which like what
Speaker 2:  on earth does that mean? But that has nothing to do with sort of my life.
Speaker 2:  It's just like a thing they say to seem big and everybody has numbers that
Speaker 2:  they wanna make big or small when it's useful doing small and that's all
Speaker 2:  fine and good. But I think your point about the word views to me is,
Speaker 2:  is like what makes this specific thing so interesting? Because one of the
Speaker 2:  very few comparable things across all of these platforms that
Speaker 2:  we have all the way down to like linear television on your
Speaker 2:  TV in your living room is we call them all views and
Speaker 2:  the content is different. The way that they're delivered is different. The
Speaker 2:  way that they're measured is different. But we call them all views and So,
Speaker 2:  we compare this like it's this apples to apples thing and
Speaker 2:  they just honestly have nothing to do with each other. Like what Netflix
Speaker 2:  thinks is a view is so diametrically
Speaker 2:  different than what YouTube thinks is a view and what TikTok thinks is a
Speaker 2:  view and what Twitter thinks is of you that we're not talking about remotely
Speaker 2:  the same thing, but because we use the same word, we like obsessively
Speaker 2:  pit these things against each other all the time. And
Speaker 6:  It's kind of weird because nowadays, you know, 30 years ago
Speaker 6:  these metrics were actually difficult to measure, right? Like you had to
Speaker 6:  sit, you had to have a little box on your TV in your house, that was it.
Speaker 6:  And maybe the cookies could sometimes get it, but nowadays everybody's logging
Speaker 6:  into these services, they're logging into YouTube, they're logging into Twitter,
Speaker 6:  they're logging into Netflix. It is very, very easy to get actual
Speaker 6:  super valuable, super like Nitty get into the nitty gritty
Speaker 6:  on these metrics and they're still going for the broadest, most
Speaker 6:  useless metrics they can announce.
Speaker 5:  That's sort of like the central funny thing about this to me,
Speaker 5:  which is that, yeah, I guess we're talking on a 30 year time scale now,
Speaker 5:  but if you think about, you know, linear TV or print publications,
Speaker 5:  you had some data about how many people were
Speaker 5:  seeing your things. You had like, you know, your circulation number or your
Speaker 5:  subscription numbers, then you estimate your circulation numbers. You have
Speaker 5:  the number of people in a certain market, you have all this, but you don't
Speaker 5:  have this direct access to like how people are interacting with your stuff.
Speaker 5:  So the people making media had this need
Speaker 5:  to like figure out what was going on. And so you end up with things like
Speaker 5:  Nielsen where people sit in their houses and log what they're doing and then
Speaker 5:  you do some statistical work on that and come up with an estimate for how
Speaker 5:  many people are watching things and then advertisers use that number and
Speaker 5:  you, you end up with like a flawed but transactable standard
Speaker 5:  that, that people work with. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  At least it's like more or less apples to apples, right? Yeah. I feel like
Speaker 2:  everyone with Nielsen always agreed like it's not perfect, but it's at least
Speaker 2:  sort of directly applicable from thing to thing and it's the close enough.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. But that, that world had all kinds of problems, but the rise of like,
Speaker 5:  you know, digital media brought along with it, this promise that of course
Speaker 5:  everything is gonna be tracked down to the second, we're gonna know so much
Speaker 5:  about what people are doing. Anyone who's written online for a long time
Speaker 5:  knows that like your publication knows how far people
Speaker 5:  scroll in every article that you, you write and it's, the numbers aren't
Speaker 5:  good. Like you just sort of Ignore that. You just pretend that people actually
Speaker 5:  finish your articles. But no one does like this. The amount of information
Speaker 5:  that you can collect directly now is huge. So people making media have
Speaker 5:  incredible amounts of information. There's total audience surveillance. Nothing
Speaker 5:  that you do or consume digitally is not tracked down
Speaker 5:  to the this like microscopic level. And yet we somehow
Speaker 5:  collectively know less about what's going on. Everyone treats
Speaker 5:  this information that they have as like a trade secret, which has the weird
Speaker 5:  effect of making it basically useless. If it's like, all right, we're all
Speaker 5:  gonna agree on tracking standards, we're gonna do this in a transparent way.
Speaker 5:  If there was some totally alternate history where everyone is
Speaker 5:  surveilling their audiences very closely, which is, you know, can of worms
Speaker 5:  too, but then sharing and comparing and auditing that data in a
Speaker 5:  transparent way, then you end up with like a very different kind of world
Speaker 5:  where there is like, there would just, it would just change the media landscape
Speaker 5:  a lot. People would know more about what people are doing and that would
Speaker 5:  create all kinds of different incentives and demands. And some would be worth
Speaker 5:  and some would be better. However, now we've just got nothing. We've got,
Speaker 5:  everyone has so much data, te petabytes of audience data
Speaker 5:  that is just like closely guarded and shared in the most misleading way possible
Speaker 5:  in tiny little fragments when Netflix is ready to be like, we actually
Speaker 5:  tracked, you know, 3 billion watch minutes for
Speaker 5:  squid game, which is the most we've ever tracked. And we started tracking
Speaker 5:  this last year and it's just like, what is that for? I mean it's obviously,
Speaker 5:  it's for marketing and it's, it's a sort of like flex in a particular
Speaker 5:  way to say that. Yeah, we are not just doing bullshit impressions, we're
Speaker 5:  we're tracking time and we wouldn't do that if it wasn't a lot, but it still
Speaker 5:  doesn't mean anything So. we just sort of like somehow managed to take more
Speaker 5:  and do less with it collectively, which is right. You know, kind of a nice
Speaker 5:  common story online these days.
Speaker 6:  Why do you think they treat it like these trade secrets? Because I, I totally
Speaker 6:  agree is is it because they think that, you know, the
Speaker 6:  numbers used to be bigger. The, the media was like much more a
Speaker 6:  smaller landscape. And so a show could have 20 million viewers that was a
Speaker 6:  really big deal and now the biggest shows have like 10 million. And so they
Speaker 6:  don't wanna be like, oh yeah, Wednesday is the biggest show on the platform
Speaker 6:  right now and actually it's got like 5 million viewers or something.
Speaker 5:  I think that's a really interesting question. And some of it probably just
Speaker 5:  comes down to like instincts like, oh my gosh, we have this thing, it's proprietary,
Speaker 5:  it's ours. There is a real tendency I feel across large
Speaker 5:  corporations, but one that I've observed more directly in tech companies
Speaker 5:  that I report on to just sort of treat everything like a trade secret. Like
Speaker 5:  you might as well. And you end up with these interesting collective
Speaker 5:  problems when you do that, that show up further down the road. But also,
Speaker 5:  like you said, with the streamers in particular, they've got kind of a different
Speaker 5:  problem from let's say Facebook, which is routinely racking up
Speaker 5:  just absurdly high numbers. Whenever they attack a metric to something like,
Speaker 5:  oh, a hundred million people watched a a viral video yesterday
Speaker 5:  and the day before and the day before that works for them. They can be like,
Speaker 5:  yeah, that's amazing. Look at these big numbers there. There's, it turns
Speaker 5:  out there's 20 billion people in the world and we, and we found a bunch more
Speaker 5:  of them and they all use Facebook, but Netflix, like you said,
Speaker 5:  is tracking this stuff from a very early stage, very
Speaker 5:  data-focused company. They use it to inform all their decisions. And they're
Speaker 5:  also, I'm sure seeing like, okay, we've licensed a
Speaker 5:  beloved old sitcom that, you know, when in its heyday was
Speaker 5:  getting like 20 million primetime viewers every week according to
Speaker 5:  Nielsen. And we just put it on here and like it's doing okay, but it's not
Speaker 5:  doing that. Or our new sitcom that we just released that everyone's talking
Speaker 5:  about, that's getting a lot of great coverage. Actually not that many people
Speaker 5:  watch it. And that's kind of flipped over time. Like there are genuine huge
Speaker 5:  streaming hits. It's not just like a media illusion that, I mean
Speaker 5:  everyone watches streaming now. That is how people watch tv. But
Speaker 5:  the precedent was set a long time ago just like, well, we're not gonna right
Speaker 5:  out of the gates like rush into some sort of mutual surveillance
Speaker 5:  with tons of disclosures and we're not gonna do that if we don't have to.
Speaker 5:  We don't have that need that people used to have when they
Speaker 5:  worked with Nielsen and depended on Nielsen for selling advertisements and
Speaker 5:  getting their ratings to know how many people are watching our stuff. We
Speaker 5:  know, we would love to know how many people watch other people's stuff, but
Speaker 5:  you know, they have, they have their ways of guessing. They, they, they seem
Speaker 5:  fine with not knowing how many people are watching like this H B O Max
Speaker 5:  reality show or whatever. Like Netflix is fine with that.
Speaker 2:  Well this is where we come back to my kind of like number nihilism and like
Speaker 2:  Cranz, you and I have talked about this a bunch, right? The, the case against
Speaker 2:  forcing all of these streaming companies in particular to share a lot of
Speaker 2:  really understandable apple's to apple's numbers is that one
Speaker 2:  thing it will do is make very obvious how many shows don't work right? And
Speaker 2:  it's great for the people who are making shows that are bigger than you think
Speaker 2:  and it's actually bad for the people making shows that are worse than you
Speaker 2:  think and not doing well. And it can, like, that stuff can have
Speaker 2:  real effects on people's careers. And it is anyway because like Netflix
Speaker 2:  knows the shows that don't work and it cancels those shows. So that's obviously
Speaker 2:  bad for people's careers. But like, if it starts to be out there, like
Speaker 2:  people used to be petrified of ratings every day because if, if the ra the
Speaker 2:  ratings decided your career and part of me wonders
Speaker 2:  whether what we need is better, more understandable metrics
Speaker 2:  or if part of what we need is like many, many, many fewer metrics and
Speaker 2:  maybe this place we've come to where really nothing means anything. If we
Speaker 2:  all can acknowledge that nothing means anything, maybe we're actually in
Speaker 2:  a better place. Well
Speaker 6:  I think the metrics don't mean anything even for the companies themselves.
Speaker 6:  'cause I, I can think of like at least two different shows in the last year
Speaker 6:  who did successfully were said to be successes on their
Speaker 6:  networks. Showed like, you know, like one of 'em was in the top 10 for Netflix
Speaker 6:  for the week it premiered and then they immediately got canceled. They got
Speaker 6:  canceled pretty quickly. One of 'em was a League of their own, which was
Speaker 6:  like a very successful show for Amazon, but very expensive show for Amazon
Speaker 6:  and not nearly the hit they had hoped it to be. And it had this
Speaker 6:  long slow cancellation death. That other one was Warrior Nun, which was like
Speaker 6:  another show did seemingly did very well and then was canceled the same
Speaker 6:  week. It like premiered. And so it left all those
Speaker 6:  fans who, you know, that was something John you mentioned fans are like
Speaker 6:  the most meticulous, they're, they're better than Nielsen when it comes to
Speaker 6:  figuring out ratings. Like they are so good at figuring
Speaker 6:  this stuff out. And they were just saying, well, numbers don't mean anything
Speaker 6:  'cause you published all your numbers which say this and we have all this
Speaker 6:  stuff we tracked that says this and you still went and did it. So what is
Speaker 6:  numbers? And it came down to it was expensive and they didn't wanna make
Speaker 6:  it right. Like they didn't wanna do a third season, 'cause third season would
Speaker 6:  increase the cost of the entire staff and the contract and everything that
Speaker 6:  how flex does it. And that was the real reason. And it was like, okay,
Speaker 6:  numbers are to blame.
Speaker 5:  Well this is something where I'm really kind of torn because I work in an
Speaker 5:  industry where people watch your numbers at work and see how many people
Speaker 5:  read what you do and it matters. And you know, it determines all kinds of
Speaker 5:  things about your job and also your sense of like what you're doing and why.
Speaker 5:  But there isn't a world where streaming companies aren't
Speaker 5:  like collecting and using this data or rather data in general
Speaker 5:  to like figure out what to do. And at streaming companies more than
Speaker 5:  at, you know, social media companies which have to depend on really direct
Speaker 5:  relationships between like viewership metrics and advertising and all this
Speaker 5:  stuff. But that's all very like very, very direct at streaming companies,
Speaker 5:  viewership metrics and, and their sort of internal ratings. They serve as
Speaker 5:  like a weird proxy, a sensible proxy for success in a way if
Speaker 5:  you're making tv. But what they actually survive on mostly for now, and
Speaker 5:  I guess this is, this is changing is subscription numbers. That's the
Speaker 5:  actual metric that matters. And so Netflix is like, all right, well we can't
Speaker 5:  tell that precisely. This is their version of the old
Speaker 5:  measurement problem. What is driving subscriptions? Like we have good
Speaker 5:  ideas, we notice that people stick around after they watch this or they
Speaker 5:  sign up and then watch that. Like they have some stuff, but what the ratings
Speaker 5:  do for them instead is just serve as like a way to value things that don't
Speaker 5:  actually, that aren't actually assigned a value in a very, very direct way.
Speaker 5:  And if they're gonna do that, I tend to think that like more
Speaker 5:  visibility is better and more transparency about what the numbers mean
Speaker 5:  because the people making the shows, the people watching the shows, if they
Speaker 5:  don't have that information and Netflix does, they're at some sort of
Speaker 5:  disadvantage. If you're a viewer that's sort of fuzzy. You're like talking
Speaker 5:  about fandom stuff. Again, if you're creating shows you have less
Speaker 5:  leverage to like ask for more money or you have less warning about when
Speaker 5:  you're gonna get canceled or you are missing part of the story if your show
Speaker 5:  does get canceled and you suspect that it was viewed by a lot of people,
Speaker 5:  but maybe there's something else going on. Like it's just being withheld.
Speaker 5:  And in the context of the strikes in Hollywood, generally writers
Speaker 5:  and other people who work in entertainment, they generally just want more
Speaker 5:  information. 'cause the information exists and it might be kind of bullshit
Speaker 5:  and it might be collected in a way that isn't super transparent. But if it's
Speaker 5:  gonna be used to make decisions, it's better that people who are trying to
Speaker 5:  make this stuff know it. It's not ideal that they have to obsess
Speaker 5:  about it. Like that's, that's a problem too. If there's a world where Netflix
Speaker 5:  becomes hyper metrics focused in a public way and
Speaker 5:  becomes in that sense more like YouTube, you have a different set
Speaker 5:  of problems. But you know, you've also got a system that is
Speaker 5:  somewhat more accountable, where in some small way
Speaker 5:  people who are doing creative work have a little bit more of a sense of like
Speaker 5:  where they stand. And that's not worth nothing. Especially when you're arguing
Speaker 5:  about like pay that is determined by basically metrics, which
Speaker 5:  again, to sort of like back way, way up are all fundamentally made up. You
Speaker 5:  have to like come up with a standard for measuring things. You have to
Speaker 5:  apply it with some level of rigor. Like there is every time you see a number
Speaker 5:  that purports to measure something down to like the most fundamental measurements,
Speaker 5:  you should wonder like how it works. Apply that a thousand times over
Speaker 5:  when you're looking at something attached to like a piece of social, social
Speaker 5:  media content. But still, if they're used, they matter. And if they
Speaker 5:  matter then I think people created, people should probably have more access
Speaker 5:  to them.
Speaker 2:  Alright, John, before we let you go, can we talk about your phone situation
Speaker 2:  for a minute here? Because the, the, the first cast audience needs to know
Speaker 2:  you wrote about the iPhone 15 Okay. Which I thought was very smart. We've
Speaker 2:  discovered in the course of doing this that you have an iPhone 12 mini that
Speaker 2:  is literally in the middle of exploding. As we are recording this,
Speaker 2:  tell us about your phone life and why you're getting a new phone this year.
Speaker 5:  So listen, I've been a gadget blogger for coming up on 15 years
Speaker 5:  here. I don't, I don't really have an excuse, but I love the mini, it's small.
Speaker 5:  It was never very good. Like the battery never lasted very long. All this
Speaker 5:  I have, I have little beautiful children, I wanna take pictures. They're
Speaker 5:  not, it's not great, but I dunno, I, I stuck, I stuck it out. I,
Speaker 5:  I I didn't want to give up this little thing. It did
Speaker 5:  overheat while we were recording.
Speaker 2:  It's on an ice pack right now, we should say. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  It couldn't, yeah, it's on a, it's on a little pink ice pack from my daughter's
Speaker 5:  lunchbox to kind of make it, make it to the end of the episode here, it couldn't,
Speaker 5:  couldn't handle wireless charging and talking on a video at the same time.
Speaker 5:  So in that sense, I'm so excited about the iPhone 15
Speaker 5:  for work purposes, for the purposes of content creation. I've got
Speaker 5:  numerous critiques and thoughts and and complications about this. However,
Speaker 5:  I can't wait to pre-order the phone. I don't care how big it is, as
Speaker 5:  long as it doesn't become like dangerously hot while I
Speaker 5:  attempt to do my job, I'll, I'll be, I'll be happy. So, you know.
Speaker 2:  Fair enough. Alright John, thank you so much for being on. This is really
Speaker 2:  fun Alex. Thank you. We, we all we're gonna need to do this again. The numbers
Speaker 2:  are not gonna stop being weird and you're gonna keep doing stuff we like.
Speaker 2:  So keep coming back on John
Speaker 5:  Anytime. Really a, a pleasure to join you.
Speaker 2:  Alright, we gotta take one more break and then we're gonna get to the Vergecast
Speaker 2:  hotline. We'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  All right, before we get outta here, let's answer a question from the hotline.
Speaker 2:  As a reminder, the hotline number is 8 6 6 Verge one one. We want
Speaker 2:  all of your best and weirdest tech questions and if you don't wanna call,
Speaker 2:  you can email Vergecast at The Verge dot com. That works great too, but it's
Speaker 2:  always fun hearing the hotline not gonna lie. Anyway, this week's question
Speaker 2:  sent me on kind of a tailspin, so let's just hear it.
Speaker 7:  Hey guys, this is Mark from Tampa. I got a question for you and you guys
Speaker 7:  seem like the right ones to answer it. It's a bit of a streaming and a
Speaker 7:  hardware question. So a few months back, during the
Speaker 7:  reveal of the Apple Vision Pro, Bob Iger came onto the stage and
Speaker 7:  mentioned that he was developing a Disney plus app for that
Speaker 7:  $3,500 monstrosity of a system.
Speaker 7:  However, I did notice that, you know, I have a couple of kids, we have
Speaker 7:  Nintendo switches, there's over 125 million of those
Speaker 7:  already sold and in hands everywhere. Do you guys have any
Speaker 7:  possible reason why Disney wouldn't have a Disney plus app already
Speaker 7:  on a platform that big? They've already have a a Hulu app
Speaker 7:  for it, so it would just seem like a slam dunk why they wouldn't have it
Speaker 7:  in hands of all the kids around. It seems silly to carry around an
Speaker 7:  iPad and a switch whenever we travel. So just curious if you guys have any
Speaker 7:  thoughts on it. Alright, have a great day, take care.
Speaker 2:  Okay, I should say upfront here that I am totally fascinated by this question
Speaker 2:  and I'm still trying to report it out. So hopefully I will have a firm Pat
Speaker 2:  a hundred percent answer really soon. But in the meantime I've been talking
Speaker 2:  to people and like putting yarn on a board with people's photos
Speaker 2:  to try and make sense of the situation. And here's what I've gotten so far.
Speaker 2:  I think there are three separate things going on here and I'll rank them
Speaker 2:  kind of in order of importance. The first thing is that with
Speaker 2:  the switch, Nintendo wanted to make a game console first and
Speaker 2:  foremost. We've had companies in the past, Microsoft, at the Xbox One probably
Speaker 2:  most famously try to do the game console
Speaker 2:  and entertainment system thing really well simultaneously, and it
Speaker 2:  just really doesn't work. And one of the things that Nintendo has done really
Speaker 2:  well over time is just make great games. It has had streaming
Speaker 2:  services in the past, but the reason people buy Nintendo products is for
Speaker 2:  great games and Nintendo knows that better than just about anybody else.
Speaker 2:  Just to name one example here is Reggie Fme, who was formerly the
Speaker 2:  Nintendo of America president and c o o talking in 2018
Speaker 2:  about how he was thinking about streaming services. The question was essentially
Speaker 2:  when are people gonna be able to watch Netflix on the switch? And here's
Speaker 2:  what he said. For
Speaker 8:  Those types of questions, we have to refer you to the folks at Netflix. What
Speaker 8:  we said when we launched Nintendo Switch was that we wanted to have
Speaker 8:  a gaming first platform. And that's what we've created and that's what enabled
Speaker 8:  us in the first 12 months in the United States to be the bestselling
Speaker 8:  home console in the history of video games. Right now we enable
Speaker 8:  Hulu on the platform. We've said that other services will come in due
Speaker 8:  time for us. We wanna make sure that we continue driving the
Speaker 8:  install base for Nintendo Switch, continue to have great games for the platform
Speaker 8:  in terms of, you know, what's next on the streaming side, you're gonna have
Speaker 8:  to talk to those individual providers in terms of where they stand and yeah,
Speaker 8:  and what they're working on.
Speaker 2:  That's a little bit of a cop out, but I think it's also true that
Speaker 2:  Nintendo knows that entertainment doesn't really move the needle.
Speaker 2:  People might watch stuff on their consoles, but nobody's buying a console
Speaker 2:  as a way to watch stuff, if that makes sense. And so I think if you're a
Speaker 2:  Nintendo and you're a company that does basically one thing very well
Speaker 2:  and you wanna keep doing it, that kind of focus really makes sense. The second
Speaker 2:  thing is that I think Disney would really like to have Disney plus on the
Speaker 2:  switch. When it launched Disney Plus in 2019, it did a big
Speaker 2:  show in front of investors about what was going on and it actually had a
Speaker 2:  slide of all the places that it wanted Disney Plus to be, and it included
Speaker 2:  a picture of the switch, like right there on the slide, big Red
Speaker 2:  Nintendo Switch. And as he was showing this slide here is what
Speaker 2:  Michael Paul, who's Disney's president of Streaming Services said at the
Speaker 2:  time
Speaker 9:  Right now we are securing distribution for Disney plus across
Speaker 9:  mobile devices and connected TV devices
Speaker 9:  including game consoles, streaming media players,
Speaker 9:  and smart TVs. With these device partnerships,
Speaker 9:  not only do we optimize our product for consumer experience,
Speaker 9:  we ensure that our service will be prominently featured in merchandise on
Speaker 9:  our partner platforms,
Speaker 2:  Right? Okay, so Disney wanted this. I don't think that was
Speaker 2:  smoke. That is Disney saying we want to be on all the platforms. I think
Speaker 2:  if it were easy and straightforward, Disney plus would probably be on the
Speaker 2:  switch. But that thing that Michael Paul said about being prominently
Speaker 2:  featured and merchandised, that's kind of the third thing we
Speaker 2:  think of these streaming platforms and the systems that they run on as
Speaker 2:  just sort of app stores, right? Build a thing, put it on the platform, everybody
Speaker 2:  wins, but that's not actually how it works. This business is really
Speaker 2:  messy and when ads get involved and when
Speaker 2:  subscriptions get involved, everybody wants a cut. Everybody wants access
Speaker 2:  to user data. Everybody wants to be the first one featured in the store
Speaker 2:  and get prominent placement. And there are questions about who's in the search
Speaker 2:  and what happens when you search for streaming. Every part of this is like
Speaker 2:  relentlessly negotiated and there's a ton of money in it. It's how TV
Speaker 2:  makers make a lot of their money. It's how streaming platforms make a lot
Speaker 2:  of their money. This is a big and complicated business and the
Speaker 2:  thing about Nintendo is Nintendo just doesn't need to care about any of this.
Speaker 2:  If you remember, there was that email that Phil Spencer, the head of Xbox
Speaker 2:  sent about wanting to buy a Nintendo. He basically said that the bad
Speaker 2:  news for Microsoft at the time was that Nintendo and I'm quoting here,
Speaker 2:  is sitting on a big pile of cash and they have a board of directors that
Speaker 2:  until recently has not pushed for further increases in market growth or stock
Speaker 2:  appreciation. If you were in theory, super
Speaker 2:  interested in market growth or stock appreciation, one thing you might do
Speaker 2:  is hire a bunch of people and get really into the weeds of
Speaker 2:  negotiating these deals with streaming services such that maybe you become
Speaker 2:  a streaming platform. But Nintendo's good. I don't think Nintendo needs
Speaker 2:  the hassle. It's very happy making the smash hit
Speaker 2:  games, making a console every once in a while. It seems to be a good business.
Speaker 2:  It seems to be working for Nintendo and my guess is it just
Speaker 2:  doesn't need the nonsense that comes with being a really successful
Speaker 2:  streaming platform. Put all of that together and I, I think that might be
Speaker 2:  it. I think Nintendo just doesn't want this that badly. And so
Speaker 2:  here we are. I think frankly it might be a miracle that we got Hulu and
Speaker 2:  YouTube and Crunchy Roll rather than a problem that we don't have the rest
Speaker 2:  of the services. But that said, if there is a smoking gun
Speaker 2:  here, I'm gonna find it. And if you know the answer and you want to tell
Speaker 2:  me why Netflix and Disney Plus and Max and all these other
Speaker 2:  services are not on the Nintendo Switch, call the hotline. Eight six six
Speaker 2:  Verge one one or email us Vergecast to The Verge dot com. Tell me all
Speaker 2:  your answers.
Speaker 2:  Alright, for now, that is it for The Vergecast. Thanks to everyone who came
Speaker 2:  on the show, and thank you as always for listening. There's lots more on
Speaker 2:  all of this stuff, especially the shutdown of DVD dot com. Yanko Rutgers
Speaker 2:  wrote a great piece for us about how that service worked, which is very cool.
Speaker 2:  We'll put a bunch of links in the show notes, but as always, read The Verge
Speaker 2:  dot com. It's a cool website. The last thing, this is probably the last call
Speaker 2:  for this, but if you have questions about The Verge or The Vergecast that
Speaker 2:  you want us to answer on our Meta Vergecast episode, get them in now. We're
Speaker 2:  recording that episode really soon. We have a ton of fun stuff. It's gonna
Speaker 2:  be a really fun episode. This show is produced by Andrew Moreno and Liam
Speaker 2:  James. Brooke Miners is our editorial director of Audio The Vergecast is
Speaker 2:  Verge production and part of the Vox Media podcast network. Neli Alex Nile
Speaker 2:  will be back on Friday to talk about Meta Connect, the Code Conference and
Speaker 2:  whatever else happens this week because everything just keeps happening.
Speaker 2:  We'll see you then. Rock and roll.