# Transcript
ID: 91336c00-84fb-4831-85b3-4f129372c091
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Threads' big moment, and Sony's big controller
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/7621078025903263507/4035274543483780467/s93290-US-5138s-1694799816.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, David Pierce, and Richard Lawler discuss Threads' new web app, Sony's Playstation handheld, NFL 4K streaming, AI music copyright, and a whole lot more.
Speaker 1:  Support for this show comes from American, Express, Business If. you
Speaker 1:  are a small business owner. you wanna partner with someone that can help
Speaker 1:  make your day to day a rewarding experience. That's where American
Speaker 1:  Express can come in. American Express business cards are built for
Speaker 1:  your business with features and benefits like the ability to earn membership
Speaker 1:  rewards, points on select cards, the power to pay for big business
Speaker 1:  purchases, and 24 7 support from a business specialist
Speaker 1:  built for your business. Amex business terms apply.
Speaker 1:  learn more at American Express dot com slash business cards.
Speaker 3:  Support for this episode comes from Zelle. You'd never
Speaker 3:  fall for an online scam, right? You use
Speaker 3:  two-factor authentication. Ignore calls from everyone named
Speaker 3:  spam risk and never use the password.
Speaker 3:  Password.
Speaker 3:  But scammers are getting more sophisticated and more active,
Speaker 3:  which means they're finding millions of new victims every single
Speaker 3:  year. The good news is that there's a lot you can do to protect
Speaker 3:  yourself on the wild, wild web. For starters, Zelle
Speaker 3:  wants to remind you only send money to people You know and
Speaker 3:  trust. Zelle is available to United States bank account holders only
Speaker 3:  terms and conditions apply.
Speaker 2:  Hello
Speaker 4:  And welcome to our cast, the flagship podcast of Sub 10
Speaker 4:  Micron Build Tolerances. If you can't outdo a Coke can get out of this
Speaker 4:  company. I'll explain what that means in a little bit. Hi, I'm Neli. I'm
Speaker 4:  your friend. David. Pierce is here.
Speaker 5:  Hi. Do you ever wonder what your own build tolerances are? This is like,
Speaker 5:  like you could go down that rabbit hole and it could cause you a lot of existential
Speaker 5:  dread if you let it.
Speaker 4:  Human beings notoriously have absolute shit build tolerances.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. We are poorly designed and horribly built. And honestly,
Speaker 4:  I, we could do a whole hour on the evidence that we are alone
Speaker 4:  in this world just based on how our knees work. You know, it's like fine.
Speaker 4:  But on the flip side, we are very good at making things with very tight build
Speaker 4:  tolerances. Or are we Richard? Lawler is here to answer that question. Hey
Speaker 4:  Richard, how are you?
Speaker 6:  Hey, the only thing I wanna talk about is how the human a c l disproves any
Speaker 6:  theory of intelligent design. See,
Speaker 4:  This is where I was not going and Richard just, he'd gotten in that cyber
Speaker 4:  truck and he drove right off that cliff just paddled to the metal four wheels
Speaker 4:  spinning ev drive triangle in the night. Yes.
Speaker 4:  No, I, I also believe that's true.
Speaker 5:  I mean, it's, it's fantasy football season, which means for the next three
Speaker 5:  weeks everyone is a doctor. Yeah. And an injury expert.
Speaker 4:  It's
Speaker 5:  Coming. It's, it's gonna be really great.
Speaker 4:  It's coming. Alex, Crans on vacation. Wish her well, but we got Richard.
Speaker 4:  She's amazing. People love Richard. So let's start, there's a, it's, it's
Speaker 4:  one of those summer weeks. Like I keep threatening The Verge team
Speaker 4:  with the concept of September. Like we have meetings and
Speaker 4:  I'm like, September is coming. 'cause if you just look, once September
Speaker 4:  begins, it is stacked So. we, we assume there will
Speaker 4:  be an Apple event. There's a Microsoft event, there's an Amazon event,
Speaker 4:  there's Google is going to court about bundling on search
Speaker 4:  that the code conference is at the end of September. It is just
Speaker 4:  relentless the second September begins. But here in late August,
Speaker 4:  there's just the looming threat of September and then kind of just a grab
Speaker 4:  bag of news, right?
Speaker 5:  Well that's the thing. This is, this is like the biggest change I have noticed
Speaker 5:  over the years I've been covering this is like this time of year used to
Speaker 5:  be dead, like dead, dead, dead. Nothing happened. And we would sit around
Speaker 5:  and be like, have you heard of gadgets from the nineties? Let's make
Speaker 5:  a podcast about that. And now it's like, what has happened is that every
Speaker 5:  company knows that basically as soon as we get past Labor Day, the
Speaker 5:  news is just like destroyed by the gadget onslaught of the next three months.
Speaker 5:  And so if you have like relatively small news that you like,
Speaker 5:  still want to get out in the world and tell people about it, turns out like
Speaker 5:  mid to late August is when to do it. So there's been like a flood of news.
Speaker 5:  It's just that none of it is above like a six out of 10. Like the fact that
Speaker 5:  like Python is coming to Excel, which is like a big deal
Speaker 5:  for some people, not nearly a big enough deal to have been as popular on
Speaker 5:  The Verge dot com as it has been this week.
Speaker 4:  Wait, no, I disagree with you. Yeah, you're alone on that take. You're the
Speaker 4:  one who's, who's all in on Excel world championships. Oh. Oh.
Speaker 4:  You add Python to that mix. These people have like bionic
Speaker 4:  capabilities now. Oh
Speaker 5:  Yeah. No, it's the, you're gonna be able to build a cyber truck in Excel
Speaker 5:  pretty soon. Like that's just where we're headed.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. On the calendar it says this is a LG briefcase TV kind of week.
Speaker 4:  That's exactly right. There is some news. Sony announced the Playstation
Speaker 4:  Portal. We'll talk about that. Microsoft killed the connect again, which
Speaker 4:  is pretty good. The first spawn con of the LG suitcase TV
Speaker 4:  has arrived. It's delightful. There's a whole bunch of, I wrote about Google
Speaker 4:  and copyright law because quite honestly, I'm an addict and that's,
Speaker 4:  that's how I get my fix So. we have a lot of stuff to talk about, but I,
Speaker 4:  I actually wanna start with some reader feedback. So, we have asked people
Speaker 4:  to send us pictures of their childhood computer rooms.
Speaker 4:  And boy, have you delivered, like, they're so good. These are the best emails
Speaker 4:  we have ever received in the history of The Vergecast. It, it has been 10
Speaker 4:  years and I have never seen the volume or quality of emails
Speaker 4:  like this. Keep sending them to us. We're gonna blow 'em out. We've been
Speaker 4:  posting some of them on social media and on the site and quick posts and
Speaker 4:  stuff like that. But I, I wanna do a big blowout feature and just talk about
Speaker 4:  computer rooms because it turns out a lot of people have very
Speaker 4:  fond memories of these rooms in these setups. And the photos are just
Speaker 4:  incredible. The one thing I'll say, I would like to see some more diversity
Speaker 4:  in the photo submissions. So if you're thinking about it, just do it. 'cause
Speaker 4:  I, I wanna show an array of people and how they came up with computers and
Speaker 4:  right now, probably not surprising. It looks like one class of people.
Speaker 4:  Yes. So I, if you're listening to this, you even half thought about
Speaker 4:  send us in. 'cause I wanna show that like this was a, this was a time, this
Speaker 4:  was a moment. Like we all experienced the same kind of place, which
Speaker 4:  I think is an important thing to to point out. And they're also, also the
Speaker 4:  photos are just incredible. I mean like, it's just, it's photos of a bunch
Speaker 4:  of cute kids and then adults talking about what it was like to be a kid with
Speaker 4:  a computer. Like it's incredible.
Speaker 5:  Well, it's super funny to me because like the, there's a generation
Speaker 5:  that talks about like gathering around the radio on a
Speaker 5:  Friday night to like listen to the You know War of the Worlds or whatever.
Speaker 5:  And then the next generation like gathered around the TV when the TV was
Speaker 5:  a piece of furniture and they were like, what the hell do you mean you would
Speaker 5:  like lie on the floor and listen to the radio? That's ridiculous. And then
Speaker 5:  there was a generation of people who like had TV or who had computers in
Speaker 5:  their living room for whom that was like a destination and a place. And now
Speaker 5:  the idea of like having to go to a computer is absurd.
Speaker 5:  And it just, it just like makes me think like I keep looking around at all
Speaker 5:  of the other gadgets in my house and being like, what of these is like another
Speaker 5:  generation from now gonna think is totally insane that this is how it
Speaker 5:  works. Like the idea that you couldn't like fold up your television and put
Speaker 5:  it in your pocket. Like is that gonna seem crazy in 20 years? I don't know.
Speaker 5:  But it's like these rooms all have the same vibe. Have you guys noticed this?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It's like insane. The
Speaker 6:  Thing that I noticed was what's something that Dan Seaford actually pointed
Speaker 6:  out that Neli asked for pictures of computer rooms. What he actually asked
Speaker 6:  for was pictures of binders. Binders full of paper. They're everywhere.
Speaker 6:  They are near everyone's computer. We all had them and now they're just gone.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, just don't do that anymore.
Speaker 4:  My niece nephew are headed off to college and they went to buy school supplies,
Speaker 4:  which is hilarious thing like You know they, they did the target run for
Speaker 4:  your freshman dormant. And I was like, oh, did you buy Mead five star
Speaker 4:  notebooks? And they were like, what are those? Oh, and I instantly turned
Speaker 4:  into like Stone. I was like, no, these are the only notebooks. And I
Speaker 4:  mailed them to them and they were like, thanks grandpa. Like whatever.
Speaker 4:  But it is true, A lot of these photos feature an enormous amount of paper.
Speaker 4:  Anyway, please send us more. We wanna blow them out, just send them in.
Speaker 4:  These are again, the greatest emails we've ever received. And I don't know
Speaker 4:  why people keep calling them the childhood battle stations. This is a theme.
Speaker 4:  This is like emergent behavior inside the email, which is
Speaker 4:  incredible. But it's great. We love it. Please keep sending us photos of
Speaker 4:  your childhood computer rooms with that weird office. Max
Speaker 4:  Wood. I mean it's just, there's just something great about these photos.
Speaker 4:  Okay, second update. I also asked for people to send me
Speaker 4:  examples of real world five G experiences
Speaker 4:  and the, the one I gave was that if you look at the Taylor
Speaker 4:  Swift Eras tour, the network capacity at NFL
Speaker 4:  stadiums is incredible. Like everyone is in the state. A hundred
Speaker 4:  thousand people in some of these stadiums streaming video from
Speaker 4:  the ERAS tour, that's a meaningful five G. Now is that
Speaker 4:  a consistently reliable five G movement? Like does this happen to people
Speaker 4:  every day? No, but it is kind of, that's it, that was the promise
Speaker 4:  it was delivered on. That's the only one I can think of.
Speaker 5:  It's also like really good wifi. I would just, I would just say it's like
Speaker 5:  even that might be giving five G too much credit.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. If they had just done really good wifi, maybe they would've gotten
Speaker 4:  there. But it, but it is true that most of these stadiums massive investments
Speaker 4:  in in five G from the various partners of the NFL, mostly Verizon and it's
Speaker 4:  working. That's great. Like we fine, I asked for
Speaker 4:  other ones. We got some that were like my fr I have a pixel
Speaker 4:  on L T e and my friend has a pixel that has five G and where I
Speaker 4:  live, he has better service than I do all the time. And the LT network is
Speaker 4:  congested, so I'm gonna get a five G fund. And we've gotten a bunch of those.
Speaker 4:  I would just say that that is not a five G experience, that's just your
Speaker 4:  carrier choking you out of your network. So you have to upgrade to a more
Speaker 4:  expensive plan. So that doesn't count, in my opinion. That doesn't count.
Speaker 4:  That's just someone came to your house and and clipped the ignition wires
Speaker 4:  to your car and said, Ooh, I think you need a better car. Like send me more
Speaker 4:  of those. I I'm looking for meaningful five G experiences, not just download
Speaker 4:  speeds, but stuff like errors to where that could not happen on LT In the
Speaker 4:  best case scenario, the one thing more people have
Speaker 4:  sent me than anything else is a video of a
Speaker 4:  banana getting stitches like a robot surgery.
Speaker 4:  Like it's a da Vinci robot.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, no, to be clear, that was a perfect description. Like anyone who is
Speaker 5:  like, oh, what is he talk like? No, it's just, it's that, yeah, like the
Speaker 5:  thing you're picturing at Banana, getting stitches.
Speaker 4:  So, so there is a very famous robotic surgery device called the Da Vinci
Speaker 4:  robot. If you are someone who's been paying attention to this stuff for a
Speaker 4:  long time, da Vinci videos are very familiar, but they all kinda look the
Speaker 4:  same. And it's been around for a long, long time. And so there
Speaker 4:  famously, there was a meme of one of these robots doing surgery on a grape
Speaker 4:  and people said they did surgery on a grape. I dunno if you recall this,
Speaker 4:  this was like, this was a real meme that occurred on the internet. So everyone
Speaker 4:  is sending me a video. It's the same video, same, it's the same exact
Speaker 4:  kind of video, but it's a banana and there's a caption
Speaker 4:  on it that says A surgeon in London did
Speaker 4:  surgery on this banana located in California over five G. And I
Speaker 4:  have received 50 versions of this video in this caption.
Speaker 4:  I'm not, I'm deep into reporting the story. I will
Speaker 4:  tell you that that is not true. I will break this story wide open.
Speaker 4:  This is the most investigative reporting I've ever done in my life. But I
Speaker 4:  know this story is not true. I'm almost there. But that's not it.
Speaker 4:  It's that did not happen over five g I promise you.
Speaker 5:  So this is just not a five G experience. This
Speaker 4:  Is somebody bootlegged a video, added a caption and
Speaker 4:  got views on, on Elon Musk's Twitter, and then it went viral like
Speaker 4:  over and over again in that horrible cycle where people just started writing
Speaker 4:  about a viral thing without ever checking to see if it was true. And now
Speaker 4:  everyone believes that in the five G robot surgery banana. And I'm just here
Speaker 4:  to tell you that shit's not true. And I'm gonna win my first
Speaker 4:  Pulitzer Prize breaking this story wide open. You can't stop
Speaker 4:  me
Speaker 5:  So. we had a meeting earlier today and Neli came on, it was like
Speaker 5:  a couple minutes late as Neli is to all of our meetings and was like, sorry
Speaker 5:  guys, I've been really busy. There's a lot going on. And what he apparently
Speaker 5:  meant was banana surgeries.
Speaker 4:  This
Speaker 5:  Is, we all thought you meant like You know the code conference is coming
Speaker 5:  and there's a lot of work to do in summers and no, you just meant bananas.
Speaker 4:  I will say that I, I checked one of my inboxes today. I saw, I got a notification,
Speaker 4:  it was in the middle of another meeting and I, my immediate thought was,
Speaker 4:  I bet this is the banana surgeon. And it was not. But that's my, at least
Speaker 4:  half of my brain is on banana surgery right now. But I'm telling you that's
Speaker 4:  not it. There has been a surgery done over five G in China
Speaker 4:  that has happened. But if you're sending me this banana, I just want You
Speaker 4:  know the hammer's coming and by this time next week I will, I will have broken
Speaker 4:  this story wide open. You won't, you can't stop me. This is, this is what
Speaker 4:  we're here for.
Speaker 4:  All right. Speaking of Elon, I, I dunno why this is true. You, you all tell
Speaker 4:  us you don't want the Elon news and Then. we look at our own statistics and
Speaker 4:  boy do you So we're gonna do in Elon lightning round. Richard's gonna
Speaker 4:  take it this week. Richard give us this week in Elon in 90 seconds
Speaker 6:  Because Elon Musk can't chill. He has been up to things.
Speaker 6:  Let's see, what has he done? He said that Twitter or X or whatever you wanna
Speaker 6:  call it, might not let you block people anymore. What does that mean? Only
Speaker 6:  Elon really knows. And Lindy Aino, apparently the c e o of Twitter, in case
Speaker 6:  you forgot that he's not the c e O of Twitter anymore, they said that something
Speaker 6:  better than blocking is coming. It sounds like an enhanced mute.
Speaker 6:  Now can they pull blocking? A lot of people have pointed to the app store
Speaker 6:  policies from Apple and Google that say that you probably can't. Elon doesn't
Speaker 6:  care. We'll see how that works out. Other things that happened, they
Speaker 6:  wiped out all the pictures and links that people tweeted before December, 2014,
Speaker 6:  just randomly a thing that included the tweet that was the most retweeted
Speaker 6:  tweet ever. The selfie from Ellen at the 2014 Oscars.
Speaker 6:  It's now back. Some of those old images are back, some of them are not. They
Speaker 6:  said they fixed it and that it will fix itself over the next couple of days.
Speaker 6:  Other things that have happened, they've said they're gonna remove headlines
Speaker 6:  from news articles. The D O J is suing SpaceX for saying that they
Speaker 6:  won't hire people without green cards and not replying to the D O J when
Speaker 6:  the D O J asked them to not do that. And Elon continuing to tweet that they
Speaker 6:  are doing it even though they're not supposed to be doing, to have that policy.
Speaker 6:  Pretty hard to deny it at that point. We've got more pictures of the cyber
Speaker 6:  truck showing the inside of it. Elon also emailed all the staff at Tesla
Speaker 6:  and said that parts for the cyber truck need to be designed and built to
Speaker 6:  sub 10 micron accuracy. Sounds difficult, but they're gonna need to do it
Speaker 6:  because if they get it wrong at all, those metal panels will look terrible.
Speaker 6:  And there there was a thread about You know people seeing a carrier loaded
Speaker 6:  full of cyber truck going down the road that looked really bad and that might
Speaker 6:  be all of them soon. Also, Elon said that news organizations can get a share
Speaker 6:  of those advertising revenue splits. So You know we could get those
Speaker 6:  Elon bucks whenever they show up. Has he done anything else in the next,
Speaker 6:  in the last five minutes that I missed? No,
Speaker 4:  I think that's it. Mercifully
Speaker 5:  No, what's what's great about that is that was both a lot of
Speaker 5:  things and genuinely actually nothing. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  At least two of those things happened and then un happened. And
Speaker 5:  Then un
Speaker 4:  That that's, that's just the Elon news cycle. And I promise you we have
Speaker 4:  a conversation. It's like, are we going to, should we just wait for this
Speaker 4:  to unh and Then we get incoming. It's like, are you gonna
Speaker 4:  talk about the thing that happened
Speaker 4:  revealed preferences. This is the secret to all economists brains
Speaker 4:  is they say the market will act rationally and they know that when they actually
Speaker 4:  measure people's revealed preferences are are ridiculous.
Speaker 4:  That's Elon traffic.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, well and Elon knows that fact better than anybody, right? Like it is,
Speaker 5:  we we are as guilty of this as anybody. We continue to sit around and be
Speaker 5:  like, Elon says a lot of nonsense. Most of it is nothing. We shouldn't take
Speaker 5:  it that seriously. And then every time he says anything it's like, oh crap,
Speaker 5:  it's Elon Musk. We should probably do something about this.
Speaker 4:  No, but I'm saying we're in the customer service business here. Yeah. When,
Speaker 4:  when we start getting the incoming, it's like, oh fine, what we need is another
Speaker 4:  button on a mouse that's literally labeled hate click. So I can just
Speaker 4:  measure that intent specifically. Maybe we should start adding
Speaker 4:  two links to every story on the front page. One is just like regular
Speaker 4:  click and the other one is goddammit. And like, so you can finally measure
Speaker 4:  what what's what. That's the cycle we're in with Elon. I know in
Speaker 4:  my heart that most of those clicks are goddammit clicks.
Speaker 5:  We just need our website to be able to turn on people's microphones so that
Speaker 5:  when you click we can hear you go Ah. And that
Speaker 5:  we register as a hate click every time. All
Speaker 4:  Right, well this is my favorite feature of iOS 17 is the always on tap
Speaker 4:  monitoring and the microphone that measures that much here. Sighing and despair,
Speaker 4:  but only for The Verge but only for the version. And
Speaker 5:  We, we promised to only use your data for good.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. We're it's, it's all happening locally on device. We're just, we're
Speaker 4:  just men measuring grunts per click and then that gets hashed into
Speaker 4:  differential privacy and sent to us So. we can figure out how cover Elon
Speaker 4:  Musk. Alright, that's enough Elon. There's other news in
Speaker 4:  the world of social media that I think is important to talk about. It's hard,
Speaker 4:  it's also hard to calibrate it. Right. And we we're, we're getting similar
Speaker 4:  feedback here and this, this is Threads Instagram Threads. We're obviously
Speaker 4:  covering Threads a lot. It's fun to cover the launch in birth and development
Speaker 4:  of a new social platform. Especially one done by
Speaker 4:  Meta, which hasn't done a new one in quite a long time. They're being really
Speaker 4:  transparent about it, which makes it fun to cover. It also seems like
Speaker 4:  they've adopted the very clever strategy of not shipping obvious
Speaker 4:  features, letting people beg for them and then delivering them like it was
Speaker 4:  their idea. Like it, it's like if you ran a McDonald's and you're like, we
Speaker 4:  don't have french fries. And then like six months later you're like, based
Speaker 4:  on overwhelming customer demand, we've launched french fries.
Speaker 5:  No, it would be like if, if every time you asked for french fries the
Speaker 5:  cashier went, oh what a good idea. We should have french fries.
Speaker 5:  And then six months later they launched french fries. That's what it, they're
Speaker 5:  like French
Speaker 4:  Fries are a very complicated, we have, we have a number of thoughts about
Speaker 4:  french fries.
Speaker 5:  We're testing french fries internally.
Speaker 4:  Exactly. But it's smart 'cause everyone is happy all the time 'cause
Speaker 4:  they're getting exactly what they want, which is clever. So this week
Speaker 4:  slowly rolling out, I think by the time you listen to this rolled out to
Speaker 4:  everyone, web Threads is here and it's pretty bare bones, but it
Speaker 4:  works.
Speaker 5:  It's a timeline you can post. It seems fine. You
Speaker 6:  Can post, but you can't quote post True. If you try to do it, you'll get
Speaker 6:  a little coming soon. Message
Speaker 4:  Dunks coming soon. The feature that destroyed
Speaker 4:  Twitter coming soon,
Speaker 5:  But I don't know if you guys went through this, but I had to change, like
Speaker 5:  it wouldn't let me in with my Instagram password because the way I log into
Speaker 5:  Instagram is by logging in through Facebook. And the way I log into Facebook
Speaker 5:  is with like a meta account. So I wound up having to change every single
Speaker 5:  one of those passwords all the way up the stack. Wow. Just to be able to
Speaker 5:  log into Threads on the web. It was, it was a scene and now I don't
Speaker 5:  know what my Facebook password is and I can't reset it because it goes to
Speaker 5:  my Instagram password, which would log me out of all my accounts. It's, it's
Speaker 5:  bad times. I'm officially done with Facebook I think forever and ever,
Speaker 5:  but I'm into, I'm into Threads on the web, but I feel like we're still in
Speaker 5:  this position of like existential debate about whether
Speaker 5:  Threads is working. And we went through this weird thing where Threads
Speaker 5:  got You know this, this record setting number of users grew really fast
Speaker 5:  and then went back down really fast because everybody joined it, found out
Speaker 5:  it was You know it, I don't know, it hadn't like solved world hunger all
Speaker 5:  at once and then left because that's what people do when they join these
Speaker 5:  new things. And then the narrative of Threads is
Speaker 5:  like a cool, vibrant place changed really fast. And there was that data
Speaker 5:  that said the installs had gone down and the daily active users had gone
Speaker 5:  down. And there are a lot of reasons not to necessarily trust that data Exactly.
Speaker 5:  But it, it does feel like the hype cycle of Threads
Speaker 5:  happened in like record time. And I'm very curious
Speaker 5:  how you guys think about it right now. Like is Threads working
Speaker 5:  generally?
Speaker 6:  I think the answer is no. For the most part it does not work. It doesn't
Speaker 6:  do a lot of things. And I think a lot of the discussion about Threads
Speaker 6:  when, especially when it launched right after you had people seeing all these
Speaker 6:  influencer accounts, all these brand posts, and I think there was a lot of
Speaker 6:  discussion and hand wringing about what does this mean? What is meta trying
Speaker 6:  to do to the social experience? Because they want to only show us influencers.
Speaker 6:  And I think the truth was Threads really didn't work. It just couldn't show
Speaker 6:  you the post that you wanted to see because it could not work. It couldn't
Speaker 6:  show you the posts of people you follow. It couldn't do anything. And they're
Speaker 6:  very slowly You know kind of as, as you said, as as Nila said, beat by
Speaker 6:  beat adding small things that will actually make it work. But the people
Speaker 6:  who registered accounts, they're not opening the app because when you open
Speaker 6:  the app, you can't see anything half the time, half the time the fetus blank.
Speaker 6:  It doesn't have people you follow, it doesn't have the topics that you're
Speaker 6:  actually interested in. So they actually do need to get some content that's
Speaker 6:  going to get people coming back there. But I think that people should measure
Speaker 6:  their impact and interest in Threads with the knowledge that it
Speaker 6:  basically doesn't work. It's barely held together. The app is
Speaker 6:  semi-functional and, and we're start, we're starting there. We're starting
Speaker 6:  at the bottom.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I think a good example was last night during the Republican primary
Speaker 4:  debate, which was a shit show just like flatly was
Speaker 4:  it shit show. I mean that if you were a conservative or a liberal and you
Speaker 4:  watched that and you came out with any, any takeaway other than wow that
Speaker 4:  was a shit show. Like I know what you're doing because it was basically just
Speaker 4:  a bunch of people yelling insults at each other, which is prime
Speaker 4:  Twitter material. Yep. Like most of it, if you just take
Speaker 4:  one step back, take the politics out of it. These people were trying to make
Speaker 4:  tweets, that's what they were doing. Like they were yelling insults at each
Speaker 4:  other to get the social media clip that went viral that people would tweet
Speaker 4:  about. Like, that is our politics for better or worse. And like
Speaker 4:  Threads was just not capable of generating that work. Like it, it was not
Speaker 4:  happening real time. I found myself opening X to see what was going on there.
Speaker 4:  And that was really weird because most of the journalists that I follow for
Speaker 4:  that stuff have not paid for X premium or whatever. And so
Speaker 4:  it was like a bunch of weird Bitcoin scams instead very confusing top to
Speaker 4:  bottom. I think Threads has that opportunity. They need to
Speaker 4:  build out a bunch of stuff. So a really simple one is right now when you
Speaker 4:  actually make a thread on Threads, the replies are down ranked. So
Speaker 4:  it like, it doesn't work as well. And like I like your,
Speaker 5:  Your second thread in a line, if you reply to your own it down ranks it.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And this is something that You know if you're a long time Twitter user, this
Speaker 4:  is has become a very natural way of expressing yourself on Twitter, right?
Speaker 4:  You write one tweet, then you reply to the tweet and your crap tweet and
Speaker 4:  you got three tweets and they're kind of all like out in the world doing
Speaker 4:  their thing, getting boosted and promoted. And then people can see the whole
Speaker 4:  thread on Instagram. It's like the first one gets and the rest are, or
Speaker 4:  they might as well not exist. I know the Threads team knows this. They have
Speaker 4:  posted about it and they said they wanna fix it and make replies and Threads
Speaker 4:  first class citizens on the platform. That's the basics
Speaker 4:  beyond even where the button to switch from the for you
Speaker 4:  feed to the following feed is located. It's like, does this algorithm surface
Speaker 4:  all the content or just some of it? And right now it's like just some of
Speaker 4:  it, the moments that Threads are, are gonna be good for the moment that Twitter
Speaker 4:  was good for was live coverage of things. What is going on right
Speaker 4:  now? Right. That Twitter was amazing at this event shows sports the
Speaker 4:  NFL season is coming if Threads doesn't have a bunch of features for this
Speaker 4:  upcoming NFL season, if they're not ready for opening day. But that's a
Speaker 4:  huge miss, right? So I, I think they gotta, they gotta rush through it. I
Speaker 4:  think this is why the desktop version is here somewhat unfinished. Like they
Speaker 4:  know a bunch of NFL beat writers are gonna want a place to
Speaker 4:  post at kickoff. They better have a version that works in
Speaker 4:  laptops. Like even if it's kind of broken, they, they need that thing for
Speaker 4:  that kind of moment. But it's definitely like to, I think to Richard's point,
Speaker 4:  it's just like not there. Like it's still kind of dead. I think a bunch of
Speaker 4:  reporters and journalists and people who are sitting at work with their laptops
Speaker 4:  now that they can post on the web, they will start and hopefully that fixes
Speaker 4:  it in some way. But as of this moment, yeah,
Speaker 4:  it's still, it's still just like waiting to be seen what happens here.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I think the, the thing that has changed for me is at the beginning
Speaker 5:  of Threads, I mean really for the last like 12 months,
Speaker 5:  it's kind of been like, okay, there the debate is Twitter
Speaker 5:  slash x losing its luster, right? And there were a lot of people who were
Speaker 5:  like, yeah, it sucks now I'm leaving the platform's bad. It's been overrun
Speaker 5:  by all of the people who say things that Elon likes to meme about.
Speaker 5:  It's a disaster. And then there are other people who are like, no, it's still
Speaker 5:  pretty much the way that it is. I think to me the You
Speaker 5:  know Twitter is still, Twitter argument doesn't hold at all
Speaker 5:  anymore. No. Like the, the thing, the Republican debate is a perfect example
Speaker 5:  of that. Like, that platform felt dead in a way that I don't remember the
Speaker 5:  last time it felt dead. And part of it is, I'm sure there was stuff happening.
Speaker 5:  I literally can't see it. Like I don't pay enough
Speaker 5:  money to be able to see that stuff happening. And it's
Speaker 5:  just, there are fewer people. They're posting less the the stuff is happening
Speaker 5:  in weirder places. It's being surfaced in less effective ways. Like
Speaker 5:  that platform I think is pretty clearly dying.
Speaker 5:  But I don't, it doesn't seem like it is sort of one-to-one
Speaker 5:  Threads the other way, right? Like you would sort of assume that as X
Speaker 5:  drops Threads would go up. Because I think at this point Threads is like
Speaker 5:  the leader in the clubhouse to be the next thing. If there's going to be
Speaker 5:  a next thing, it's
Speaker 4:  Sure not Blue sky. It's,
Speaker 5:  It's definitely not Blue Sky. Macon apparently had a good
Speaker 5:  week. Like I'm still very bullish on this space as a whole. Like the open
Speaker 5:  social web is gonna be great. I wish it were more mature than it already
Speaker 5:  is. By the
Speaker 4:  Way. We are trying to get Jay from Blue Sky and Yugen from Masson come to
Speaker 4:  the code conference. I'm just putting that vibe in the world. We, we've sent
Speaker 4:  the emails. If You know him, you have a line to him. Tell him
Speaker 4:  to come on stage. I I wanna talk about social media with him.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, it'd be good. I'm into it. We
Speaker 4:  Will find a way to, to code is the same day as Meta Connect also happening
Speaker 4:  in September. But we have some ideas and I'm bringing those,
Speaker 4:  those folks onto our stage. I won't spoil them at this time. What
Speaker 6:  David said makes me think of two things. One thing is, first I like
Speaker 6:  having like eight different social media apps to open and see different things.
Speaker 6:  It's, it's, it's cool when I'm, when I'm sick of TikTok, I can go to Blue
Speaker 6:  Sky when I'm sick of Blue Sky, I can go to Macon when I'm sick of Macon,
Speaker 6:  I can go to Threads, then I can go back to Twitter and see what's going on.
Speaker 6:  Do You
Speaker 5:  Know what I love about this Richard return? I genuinely cannot tell if you're
Speaker 5:  serious.
Speaker 4:  Oh. I'm like,
Speaker 5:  I sincerely don't know whether you, that was like full sarcasm
Speaker 5:  or earnest honesty.
Speaker 4:  What is happening right now is that David and I have children and Richard
Speaker 4:  doesn't, and Richard's like You know what is sick is bar hopping. And both
Speaker 4:  of us are like, we're too tired. That is, that is a hundred percent the dynamic
Speaker 4:  that just happened on the show. Richard's like, I like waking up on a Sunday
Speaker 4:  and going to five different bars and just checking it. I'm like, I can't,
Speaker 4:  I'm so sleepy, man.
Speaker 6:  Like who doesn't just have unlimited time to open every single app on their
Speaker 6:  phone over and over and over again. Is is that not, is that not your experience?
Speaker 6:  Look,
Speaker 4:  I I, when I was in Chicago, I was inveterate bar crawler. I understand
Speaker 4:  You know you got drumming bass at one, you got house at the other and you
Speaker 4:  gotta just feel the vibes through the night. Maybe you're gonna link You
Speaker 4:  know anything could happen here on this internet. And then you get older
Speaker 4:  and you're like, I can't be doing this anymore. And
Speaker 4:  I think for a lot of people that is the social media experience of
Speaker 4:  2023 is like, well I'm just like, just tell me which one's cool, like
Speaker 4:  which one has onion rings and my friends are gonna be there. Like, I'll be
Speaker 4:  at that one.
Speaker 5:  First of all, it's not onion rings, it's free pizza in the back. Like that's,
Speaker 5:  that's the thing. Yeah. But also, wait, Richard that was thing one. What
Speaker 5:  was thing two? Thing
Speaker 6:  Two is that, yes, it feels like Twitter's been hollowed out. I I follow like
Speaker 6:  7,000 people, which is not the normal experience and always use the,
Speaker 6:  the chronological feed. So I kind of see a lot of different communities and
Speaker 6:  how how people are talking and a lot of very important voices, like you said,
Speaker 6:  either don't post at all or just don't post on that platform anymore.
Speaker 6:  But there's still people who do. So I think for Mo for a lot of people, the
Speaker 6:  thing that has, that they've experienced on Twitter or X or whatever you
Speaker 6:  wanna call it, is that it has always been so bad that if you use it, there's
Speaker 6:  nothing that it could do that could make it so bad that you won't use it
Speaker 6:  anymore. They've all, they've already run off everyone who isn't an addict.
Speaker 5:  That's fair. So,
Speaker 6:  So there's just nothing they can do at that point. Right.
Speaker 4:  But the, and those folks are the most addicted. So getting them to
Speaker 4:  come to Threads and post at the same rate requires that feedback loop.
Speaker 4:  And Threads does not have enough people yet. And that's the chicken and egg
Speaker 4:  problem. And again, I think the, the moments for Threads
Speaker 4:  are gonna look like NFL season when a lot of people start
Speaker 4:  tweeting the N B A finals award season. Like all the
Speaker 4:  live events that Twitter used to capture, more presidential debates,
Speaker 4:  election season, all of those moments are moments for this
Speaker 4:  particular kind of social, like these are not TikTok moments. No
Speaker 4:  one's watching the debate and like opening TikTok to get
Speaker 4:  live reactions. Like you are a psychopath if you're doing that. I tried doing
Speaker 4:  it last night and I was like, I feel like a psychopath. Like this is crazy.
Speaker 4:  'cause it's, it's not there yet. And like it's too fast. Like these are live
Speaker 4:  logs, right? That that's kind of what you want outta this. We make a lot
Speaker 4:  of live logs. Like that's how I, how I've always thought about this. And
Speaker 4:  Threads isn't quite ready for that yet, especially with its
Speaker 4:  bizarre insistence on the algorithmic feed. And then t Twitter
Speaker 4:  isn't either,
Speaker 5:  This is the moment Threads kind of has to figure out what it wants to be,
Speaker 5:  right? Because like Moser and that whole team have been saying all along,
Speaker 5:  they don't want to be a place for politics and a place for news. And
Speaker 5:  it's like, do You know how you become Twitter is by being a place for politics
Speaker 5:  and a place for news. Like you can't have it both ways. The only
Speaker 5:  things that get people that excited are politics and news and like,
Speaker 5:  I'm defining news broadly as just like things that are happening in real
Speaker 5:  time, right? Like the
Speaker 4:  Weather is news and that
Speaker 5:  Includes sports. Like sports is news in a very real way, right? Like
Speaker 5:  it's, it is a thing that is happening right now that we all are talking about.
Speaker 5:  Like that's what it's, and for them to say this is
Speaker 5:  a place for text, but that isn't designed to be
Speaker 5:  this kind of like real time up to the moment thing. I'm just not sure I know
Speaker 5:  what that is. And so it, it does feel like it's gonna be interesting to see
Speaker 5:  what it looks like on a football Sunday because that's a relatively sort
Speaker 5:  of low stakes and unproblematic version of this problem.
Speaker 5:  But this question of like, how do you stay that fast?
Speaker 5:  How do you surface stuff like this in real time? As somebody is tweeting
Speaker 5:  a hundred times during or somebody is posting a hundred times during a
Speaker 5:  single game, what is the Threads algorithm gonna make of that?
Speaker 5:  And how is like the open question for me about what the next
Speaker 5:  You know six months are gonna look like? And I just have no idea. I'll
Speaker 4:  Give you one very specific example I have tweeted in my life
Speaker 4:  during any number of Packers games. Just the words.
Speaker 4:  Oh no. Mostly in relation to Mike McCarthy
Speaker 4:  just in general. Oh no. Right. Like in Twitter
Speaker 4:  was very good at somehow f finding the people who
Speaker 4:  understood what I was saying that it was, there was a football game going
Speaker 4:  on. I had been tweeting about it. Here's this like totally context free oh
Speaker 4:  no. In the middle of a Sunday and everyone kind of understood what was going
Speaker 4:  on. That is kind of magic, right? That felt like a hive
Speaker 4:  mind moment. Yeah. Like you're in a community, you're all just sort of like
Speaker 4:  chatting in this weird way Instagram Threads right now takes that, oh no.
Speaker 4:  And like seven hours later delivers it next to
Speaker 4:  like a John Cena tweet. Like that makes no sense what is going
Speaker 4:  on there. And that is is which is classic Facebook. Yeah. And I and that
Speaker 4:  Yes. And they, they want to get away from context collapse and it actually
Speaker 4:  turns out that the chronological feed provides all the context. And so like,
Speaker 4:  I think they have to make some big decisions, especially if they want, I
Speaker 4:  get why they're saying they don't want politics and news like one, they all
Speaker 4:  personally have bad experiences with that. Adam Ary ran the
Speaker 4:  Facebook news feed. He has a bad experience with politics news. I get it.
Speaker 4:  News second in Canada and Australia and all these other places, the governments
Speaker 4:  are saying you might have to pay for links to news sites.
Speaker 4:  Like they gotta solve that problem. They're not launched in the eu, which
Speaker 4:  is gonna have its own weird rules. So I get why they're like, You know what
Speaker 4:  this isn't, we're not headed straightforward. We're gonna start with like
Speaker 4:  fashion Instagram stuff, but they're just gonna quickly
Speaker 4:  arrive at void when it's Biden and probably Trump
Speaker 4:  in a debate. If you are competitive at all with Twitter,
Speaker 4:  you need that experience to happen on your platform and not Twitter. Otherwise
Speaker 4:  you're just not gonna have the volume, you're not gonna have the interest
Speaker 4:  and you are certainly not gonna have the impact, which is what we have talked
Speaker 4:  about in the show several times now. Meta runs gigantic platforms that make
Speaker 4:  more money than their rivals, but often have no cultural impact.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And I think this platform lives and dies on its impact.
Speaker 5:  And we really like, so let's see, Threads launched at the beginning of July,
Speaker 5:  right? And we really haven't had
Speaker 5:  a sort of everybody on the internet moment
Speaker 5:  since then, right? Like there just hasn't been a thing that all of a sudden
Speaker 5:  out of nowhere everyone was talking about. Has there been one I can't, like,
Speaker 5:  I can't think of. There was
Speaker 6:  A viral N f T post that went around and that that was the most, and that
Speaker 6:  alone tells you
Speaker 4:  Richard's talking about viral N f t posts on shut this time. Oh, come on.
Speaker 4:  I you need to buy bored eight yacht club.
Speaker 4:  I'll stop.
Speaker 5:  This is not investment advice. The first cast is not investment
Speaker 4:  Advice. It's because right now you're buying low. There's there's nowhere
Speaker 4:  else to go. All right. There has been one, I'm saying last night
Speaker 4:  the debate should have been one and it wasn't one.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. But we're, we're about to get 18 months of moments
Speaker 5:  where people, people care about are going to have to choose
Speaker 5:  which platform they spend their day hammering away on.
Speaker 5:  And like the, the fight is coming in a really real way. And
Speaker 5:  I wonder if Threads like even Infrastructurally is ready for it.
Speaker 5:  I think the web thing is a big deal, but there's still, like you guys have
Speaker 5:  been saying a lot of work left to do. Alright
Speaker 4:  Everyone, we're gonna take a break. Everyone check on your N F T wallets.
Speaker 4:  See if Richard has stolen from you.
Speaker 5:  Richard will buy your bored Apes, he told me that right before we started
Speaker 5:  recording.
Speaker 6:  Click any link I send you. It's fine. All right.
Speaker 4:  Please don't click links from Richard. We'll be right back.
Speaker 8:  Support for this show comes from Global Citizen. On
Speaker 8:  September 23rd, the Global Citizen Festival will gather thousands of people
Speaker 8:  who took action to end extreme poverty. Join the Red Hot Chili
Speaker 8:  Peppers, Ms. Lauren Hill, ook and Anita as they take the
Speaker 8:  stage with world leaders and activists to demand action for
Speaker 8:  equity for the planet, for food and for jobs.
Speaker 8:  Download the Global Citizen app today and earn your spot at the festival.
Speaker 8:  learn more at Global Citizen dot org slash box.
Speaker 9:  Wait, are you gaming on a Chromebook? Yeah,
Speaker 10:  It's got a high res 120 hertz display plus this killer R G B
Speaker 10:  keyboard and I can access thousands of games anytime, anywhere.
Speaker 9:  Stop playing what? Get outta here, huh? Yeah. I want you
Speaker 9:  to stop playing and get outta here so I can game on that Chromebook.
Speaker 10:  Got it.
Speaker 11:  Go down, discover the ultimate cloud gaming machine.
Speaker 11:  A new kind of Chromebook.
Speaker 4:  All right, we're back. Like I said, a lot of little news this week.
Speaker 4:  Do you wanna start with the, the Playstation Portal or do you wanna start
Speaker 4:  with all the streaming stuff? Let's
Speaker 5:  Do the Portal. This is the thing I am most flummoxed by
Speaker 5:  and Richard as the gamer of the three of us. I would say,
Speaker 5:  I'm curious to know, a, you should probably explain what this thing is because
Speaker 5:  I think it, it's actually harder to explain than it seems like it should
Speaker 5:  be. But then I want you to convince me that this is actually a thing that
Speaker 5:  needs to exist in the world because I'm not sure
Speaker 6:  I will do that. But I'll start by apologizing because it's basically my fault
Speaker 6:  that everything Sony announced this week exists. And I'll, I'll explain.
Speaker 6:  I I'm sorry I did this to the world. I will have to re repay them somehow
Speaker 6:  perhaps in tokens that you could invest in on my blockchain, but
Speaker 5:  Click every link Richard sends you.
Speaker 6:  So they have introduced the Playstation Portal, this is something You know,
Speaker 6:  they kind of hinted at it. They that it said that it was coming earlier this
Speaker 6:  year. It is a screen in the middle of a, a dual sense controller. That's
Speaker 6:  it. It plays PSS five games over wifi from your PSS five.
Speaker 6:  You can't really do anything else. It's $200. You cannot connect Bluetooth
Speaker 6:  headphones to it. If you want to use You know if you wanna use some wireless
Speaker 6:  headphones with it, you need to buy some of their new audio gear.
Speaker 6:  They have $200 wireless earbuds. Oh wait,
Speaker 4:  I just wanna underline that means they cost as much as the Playstation Portal.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Like your full kitted out price. Yes, they do. For a
Speaker 4:  Portal in headphones is $400
Speaker 4:  because it doesn't have Bluetooth. At least
Speaker 5:  You know three 50 if you want the, the the cheaper crappier
Speaker 5:  headphones. But it's, it's, I wanna come back to
Speaker 5:  Playstation link because I think it is preposterous.
Speaker 4:  I just wanted to underline that price. Yes.
Speaker 6:  The reason why you can't just use your regular headphones or perhaps Sony's
Speaker 6:  other headphones that they introduced. They just released the new XM five
Speaker 6:  earbuds not that long ago. They don't have the Playstation link
Speaker 6:  audio technology that lets you get lossless audio and low latency audio,
Speaker 6:  which of course is important for gaming, but I I think people use Bluetooth
Speaker 6:  headphones with their steam decks and whatnot. Yeah, you
Speaker 4:  Compare Bluetooth headphones to a switch, it's fine. It's fine. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  But yeah, Sony has said no, you will use our headphones,
Speaker 6:  these specific Playstation headphones or you won't use anything at all. I
Speaker 6:  guess. But the reason why this is my fault is I take
Speaker 6:  a look at my desk at the table that I have sitting next to my couch in my
Speaker 6:  living room and there's a lot of gamer headsets on there that costs way too
Speaker 6:  much money and I've just bought too many of them.
Speaker 5:  How, how many does one person need
Speaker 6:  More
Speaker 4:  Welcome to The Vergecast? Everybody
Speaker 6:  Like there there's, there's always another one. There's always a new feature.
Speaker 6:  There's always, there's always something else. You know. There's always You.
Speaker 6:  know what? I think the reason why I lost that match is because my headset
Speaker 6:  wasn't good enough. Which it, it just, it's, it's
Speaker 6:  logical. It makes sense. If
Speaker 5:  You'd been able to hear them sneaking up on you in spatial audio, you would've,
Speaker 5:  you would've gotten I got you. I understand.
Speaker 4:  Can I, can I say the most old man thing like game wear headsets? Yeah. So
Speaker 4:  I mostly only play on them games with my Ashe actual friends and we have
Speaker 4:  all discovered that it's easier to make speakerphone calls on our phones
Speaker 4:  than to fuck with headsets. So I just have my phone
Speaker 4:  with FaceTime audio on a conference call just like on my,
Speaker 4:  on the coffee table. It works so much better than
Speaker 4:  gamer headsets.
Speaker 6:  But that's only because you guys can't figure out Discord. That's
Speaker 4:  True. I was
Speaker 5:  Just gonna say, you just described the whole origin story of Discord.
Speaker 4:  I'm just saying, which
Speaker 5:  Is a bunch of nerds on team speak and conference calls trying to make this
Speaker 5:  stuff work.
Speaker 4:  Like I'm saying, if I can avoid software in my life, I do it and that that's
Speaker 4:  my solve anyway. Continue Richard with your headphone purchasing Odyssey.
Speaker 6:  Yes. I convinced Sony that this was a good idea because they saw how many
Speaker 6:  headsets I bought and they said we can sell headsets to idiots all day.
Speaker 6:  This is just money that we're missing. We need to have more audio gear for
Speaker 6:  gamers. The other part is they introduced this handheld, why is this
Speaker 6:  my fault? Do You know how many switches I've purchased a lot of them
Speaker 6:  and almost untold number. I do not play the Nintendo Switch. I do not. Why
Speaker 6:  do you have one? I I bought them for other people. My wife has two. Okay.
Speaker 6:  I, I bought her one then I bought a switch OLED and I thought that I would
Speaker 6:  get one of them, but it turns out that she has two Nintendo switches now.
Speaker 5:  That's cool.
Speaker 6:  And I think there are a lot of people like that where like they have multiple
Speaker 6:  ones. They have one for this room, they have one for that room, they have
Speaker 6:  one to take, one to go. And that's what play what Sony is chasing with this
Speaker 6:  device, I think is that you've got a Playstation and you wanna play it in
Speaker 6:  another room and you don't have a briefcase TV because you didn't buy the
Speaker 6:  $2,000 briefcase tv. Yeah. So what are you gonna do? Are you just gonna play
Speaker 6:  games on your iPad? Like a normal, it
Speaker 4:  Makes sense for lots of like families, right? You got a PS five
Speaker 4:  downstairs, you might have it connected to the big TV speakers, whatever
Speaker 4:  that is. Like you don't want another PSS five and TV rig upstairs.
Speaker 4:  Moving the games back and forth sucks. Like here's this thing you can just
Speaker 4:  like go play in your bedroom. You just like give one to your teenager, they
Speaker 4:  can play in the bedroom. That seems to make a lot of sense. Does
Speaker 4:  it allow you to simultaneously play on the PSS five and remotely?
Speaker 6:  I don't think so. I don't, I don't think it works like that. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  That seems, I mean that's the miss.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. So
Speaker 5:  Thi this is my thing with this device is like the one use case I, I
Speaker 5:  agree. Makes sense, right? Like there are times I want to play games sitting
Speaker 5:  in bed or on the couch. Like my Playstation is hooked up to the
Speaker 5:  same monitor that I'm on right now on my computer and there are other times
Speaker 5:  I wanna play games elsewhere. Moving my Playstation is annoying. Completely
Speaker 5:  get that. There are so many other things this thing could have done.
Speaker 5:  Sony has game streaming that it could have done on the Portal.
Speaker 5:  Sony has some really cool old systems through which you can
Speaker 5:  emulate old Playstation games that it could have done on the Portal. Sony
Speaker 5:  could have done so many things that would've made this device cooler and
Speaker 5:  better. It could have had streaming apps. So you can watch movies and things
Speaker 5:  when someone else is on your Playstation. There's just a million ways it
Speaker 5:  could have gone and it picked none of them except like the minimum
Speaker 5:  viable least thing this device could possibly be. And that just kind of
Speaker 5:  drives me nuts. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  They picked the things that didn't require a processor, right? Basically.
Speaker 4:  I mean that's like kind of what it feels like. Basic, basic. They made it
Speaker 4:  as cheap as possible, but limiting the amount of local
Speaker 4:  processing that is happening here and saying all of that's gonna happen on
Speaker 4:  your PSS five.
Speaker 5:  I will say the, the only case in which that argument holds
Speaker 5:  is if the battery life is as good as supposedly it
Speaker 5:  might be. And I think Sony said to cnet, I think that the plan is to have
Speaker 5:  the battery last as long as the dual sense controller, which is like eight
Speaker 5:  or nine hours. That's pretty good. If I can sit there and play games on it
Speaker 5:  for eight hours on a charge, like that's legit. It's still not enough.
Speaker 5:  I still I would trade two hours of that battery life for more things to
Speaker 5:  do. But it's something, yeah,
Speaker 4:  Guess I would also point out, right? In one of the use cases here, what are
Speaker 4:  you doing? You're on a trip, you're in a hotel room, you wanna play
Speaker 4:  your PSS five at home, your hotel has reasonably good wifi, you need what,
Speaker 4:  15 megabits? That's the, that's sort of the recommended speed. You can get
Speaker 4:  that in a, a lot of hotels nowadays. Great. You're playing You know what
Speaker 4:  you can also do is just bring a dual sense controller along and open the
Speaker 4:  app on your iPad. And it's maybe not as seamless,
Speaker 4:  but it also just like, I have friends who just like do this all the time.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, it works like it really, it's a, it's a totally
Speaker 5:  valid gaming system. Like that's what I do right now in my house. And I have
Speaker 5:  always thought that like some when, like when they first announced this as
Speaker 5:  the project queue, I was like, okay, add a, add a Switchy thing
Speaker 5:  to my Playstation rig and I'm golden. This solves all my problems. This
Speaker 5:  now just is like a slightly less wonky version of
Speaker 5:  the system I already have. No,
Speaker 6:  They they didn't build a switch. They built the weu, which yeah. Was
Speaker 6:  not popular, so that's not a great sign. But I think
Speaker 6:  the thing that's happens from Sony's perspective is that yeah,
Speaker 6:  sure you could just hook up your dual sense to an iPad and play that way,
Speaker 6:  but then you wouldn't pay Sony $200.
Speaker 4:  That's true. Which
Speaker 6:  Makes it, it less good for for them. And they don't wanna do more cloud streaming
Speaker 6:  or anything because that would encourage you to buy fewer PS fives and they
Speaker 6:  don't wanna do that either. It's
Speaker 4:  True You know. You can also just do what I do, which is I bought a second
Speaker 4:  power cable and a second H T M I cord and I set them up
Speaker 4:  in the Oh, that's smart sunroom where there's a projector and I just move
Speaker 4:  my PSS five around and literally the only inconvenience of that is
Speaker 4:  I have to remember to turn it off all the way.
Speaker 6:  It will scream at you if you do not do that.
Speaker 5:  Oh, does that awful it? Yeah. I hate that. It doesn't like it. No,
Speaker 4:  But yeah, but I, I move my PSS five from the basement to the
Speaker 4:  outside to play Madden on the, on the projector all the time. It's fine.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. That's smart. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  That's, that's what my series SS is for. It's my, when I wanna play Xbox
Speaker 6:  somewhere else. Yeah, I got it.
Speaker 4:  I love how Richard has just multiples of every console. I know there's an
Speaker 4:  Excel spreadsheet. It both Microsoft and Sony. It's just labeled like
Speaker 4:  Lawler margins.
Speaker 6:  No, I, you can pretty much predict what products people are going to come
Speaker 6:  out by what I have six of because they're, they're gonna release
Speaker 6:  more of those very soon. I think the other thing is that this signals that
Speaker 6:  there's gonna be another PSS five pretty soon. Yeah, we, we saw that shell,
Speaker 6:  the slim leak of the slim thick whatever it is. The slim,
Speaker 6:  if you look at it, you can see that they've released these audio gear that
Speaker 6:  doesn't work with the PSS five without a U S B dongle, which You know we
Speaker 6:  love the dongles. They don't Yeah, they're gonna need to release the system
Speaker 6:  with that. They're gonna do something. So we'll maybe have more clarity
Speaker 6:  early next year, mid next year when we, when we get another PSS five and
Speaker 6:  see how it all works together.
Speaker 4:  All right. This means we now have to talk about Playstation link. This is
Speaker 4:  ridiculous that it doesn't have Bluetooth. Yes. It's ridiculous that these
Speaker 4:  headphones are so expensive. Don't work with the existing PS five
Speaker 4:  and Sony's claim is what? Just lower latency? Yeah,
Speaker 6:  That that's about it.
Speaker 5:  Something, something higher audio quality to, and they claim it's
Speaker 5:  easier to switch between devices. Which is
Speaker 5:  funny because one of the things that Sony's headphones are notoriously
Speaker 5:  not great at is switching between devices. So I don't know that I have a
Speaker 5:  ton of faith in that, which is a thing you can do over Bluetooth and Sony
Speaker 5:  does poorly. But yeah, in theory there are like, they have a list
Speaker 5:  of reasons and I don't find a single one of them compelling. And I, I think
Speaker 5:  Playstation link as a thing is just like totally outrageous.
Speaker 4:  I mean this is the sort of thing, and Marques Brownley made a video about
Speaker 4:  this. This is the sort of thing that if Apple did it with the iPhone, like
Speaker 4:  I would lose my mind. Like I accused Apple of wanting to do this when they
Speaker 4:  released the AirPods and they took the headphone jack off the iPhone, right?
Speaker 4:  Like we're gonna get everyone used to wireless audio, then we're gonna build
Speaker 4:  a proprietary wireless audio protocol and you can only use our headphones.
Speaker 4:  And this is true in phones, like all over the place. And
Speaker 5:  I will say a not small portion of that Apple has done
Speaker 4:  Right and so is Google and so is Samsung. Yeah, everyone's phones now,
Speaker 4:  they've all taken the headphones Jacks away and they have Bluetooth and then
Speaker 4:  they have Bluetooth plus proprietary extensions that only their
Speaker 4:  headphones can use. So the AirPods obviously bunch of features only AirPods
Speaker 4:  can access on an iPhone. If you have a Samsung phone, there's a bunch of
Speaker 4:  features that Samsung Buds can do. If you have a pixel, the
Speaker 4:  pixel buds have custom extensions. That's all shitty over
Speaker 4:  there. But the reality is like most of those features aren't very good.
Speaker 4:  Like, oh no spatial audio, like whatever.
Speaker 5:  Also, I don't, I don't necessarily hate that as a thing like to, to
Speaker 5:  say we support the standards, right? Like it's, it's what Apple does with
Speaker 5:  iMessage too. They're like, if you wanna send SMSs, that's fine, we'll support
Speaker 5:  it, it works. But if you want to exist in our system,
Speaker 5:  everything is better. And like, do I wish the world was not that way? Yes.
Speaker 5:  But like that's how it is. And that's roughly fine as long as you're
Speaker 5:  in a position where you can still fail sort of gracefully. This is like if
Speaker 5:  Apple had just said no more SMSs ever.
Speaker 4:  Well, so it, the, the, the Playstation Portal does have a
Speaker 4:  3.5 millimeter headphone track, which presumably has
Speaker 4:  low latency. It's, it's just, it's we, it doesn't have the middle
Speaker 4:  thing, right? It doesn't have Bluetooth. So if you wanted
Speaker 4:  to, you could get one of those like air pods, Bluetooth
Speaker 4:  dongles that you use on an airplane seat back and plug that into
Speaker 4:  your Playstation Portal and then pair your air pods to that You know
Speaker 4:  we're gonna make Sean Hollister make that video one day. I can see it coming
Speaker 4:  like a train in the night. But it is like, it's weird that you would build
Speaker 4:  wireless radios that support your proprietary thing you would have a headphone
Speaker 4:  jack and then not the most common thing,
Speaker 6:  But it isn't weird. It's the most classic Sony thing ever. Making a weird
Speaker 6:  proprietary thing that doesn't work with anyone else's stuff. The the problem
Speaker 6:  that you point out is that it doesn't work with their own headphones. Like
Speaker 6:  I, I have a bunch of XM headphones here and none of them have it. Why? Why
Speaker 6:  is that? Like, you
Speaker 4:  Get the feeling You know. I I love talking about an org chart. You get the
Speaker 4:  feeling that when like people walk into the Sony office, it's, it's a little
Speaker 4:  bit like memento it. Like they're just constantly introducing themselves
Speaker 4:  to each other. Like, oh, you work on headphones? I didn't know we did headphones
Speaker 4:  here.
Speaker 5:  You make headphones.
Speaker 4:  It's
Speaker 6:  Like no one knows who the boom speaker guy is.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. They're like, oh, we do, we do PlayStations. We should maybe
Speaker 5:  The one party speaker guy is just in the back just jamming the whole time.
Speaker 4:  He's just like livid. He's like super base. You know and like the mega
Speaker 4:  base team is like, what the fuck? You know. Like
Speaker 4:  that's just Sony all the time.
Speaker 5:  True. Well, and the Playstation team seems to be especially that way, like
Speaker 5:  the, the Playstation team seems to not have to
Speaker 5:  play by any of the other Sony rules and just kind of does whatever it
Speaker 5:  wants at all times.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. The Memento comparison I think is a little dark. It's more like Dorian
Speaker 4:  Finding Nemo
Speaker 5:  Every time it turns around it's like,
Speaker 4:  Who are you? Like I don't think everyone, it's Sony is heavily tattooed and
Speaker 4:  trying to solve a murder that would at least, I think give them a little
Speaker 4:  more purpose. This is much more like, hello, who, who are you?
Speaker 5:  You seem nice. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  That was the Phil Harrison and Sony. That was a few generations ago.
Speaker 4:  There's actually a lot of other gaming stuff going on. Qualcomm has
Speaker 4:  sort of a portable device. We've described it as a battering. The Quest three,
Speaker 4:  which we're expecting to see at Meta Connect is leaked out. People are unboxing
Speaker 4:  it. There's a new Atari 2,600, which is very good.
Speaker 4:  Samsung TVs are getting cloud gaming. There's just like a kind of a lot going
Speaker 4:  on.
Speaker 5:  I think the, the Qualcomm thing to me is the most exciting, which is basically
Speaker 5:  like Qualcomm is making a big bet on handheld gaming as a thing.
Speaker 5:  And this is kind of what Qualcomm does, right? They sort of look around and
Speaker 5:  they say, okay, we really only know how to make one thing. What
Speaker 5:  other industry can we make it for? And they've like, they've done this with
Speaker 5:  cars. They got really into wearables. They got super into headphones for
Speaker 5:  a while and now the thing that they're trying to figure out is how to do
Speaker 5:  like custom chips for gaming handhelds. And so they, they
Speaker 5:  came out with three different like tiers of chips. There
Speaker 5:  was the G one, the G two, and the G three X gen two,
Speaker 5:  which basically ladder all the way up from like, as far as I can tell, basically
Speaker 5:  like a phone level thing to like a steam deck level thing.
Speaker 5:  And I just think that's awesome. Like the, there are lots of problems with
Speaker 5:  this, starting with the fact that they run Android and there aren't that
Speaker 5:  many good games for Android. The game gaming ecosystem is not that great,
Speaker 5:  but game streaming is gonna help solve some of that problem. And so like
Speaker 5:  the idea that we might be about to get a run of different
Speaker 5:  versions of these devices because they're gonna get easier and cheaper to
Speaker 5:  make and source parts for, I think is super exciting. I don't know
Speaker 5:  that I love the idea that they should all look like a screen in the middle
Speaker 5:  with two halves of a controller on either side, but that seems to be where
Speaker 5:  we're aligning as a world on what these things are supposed to look like.
Speaker 5:  But I don't know, Richard, are you gonna end up buying 15 different versions
Speaker 5:  of handheld gaming consoles? Like, I'm excited about this thing. I'm not
Speaker 5:  a hundred percent sure why all the time, but I am excited about it.
Speaker 6:  No, they predict that you'll go outside, that you'll use them places and
Speaker 6:  I don't touch grass, so no, not, not not gonna do it.
Speaker 5:  Listen, if you use all your Nintendo switches indoors, you can use these
Speaker 5:  indoors also.
Speaker 6:  But I don't play the Nintendo Switch. Oh
Speaker 5:  Yeah. All right. Fair enough. Let's get your wife on here. What does she
Speaker 5:  think?
Speaker 6:  Okay, she, she might have a few.
Speaker 4:  All right, So, we have long asked for emails from people
Speaker 4:  who buy Android phones to play games, pro gaming phones,
Speaker 4:  the potential customers of the Razor Edge or this Qualcomm thing. I'm
Speaker 4:  just looking, I I just searched The Vergecast inbox for Android gaming. This
Speaker 4:  one is spam. This leaves us with six
Speaker 4:  emails, one of which is not about gaming at all on Android,
Speaker 4:  but I'll just read some. I this one starts out with, I do not own an Android
Speaker 4:  gaming phone. So you can see good start. What this call for
Speaker 4:  reader feedback is is like, but they own an Android gaming handheld called
Speaker 4:  the Ax Portal. I bought it specifically for one game Gentian
Speaker 4:  Impact, so I could play it on the go. I wanted to be able to play it with
Speaker 4:  the controller, which is not supported on an Android but doesn't iOS It works
Speaker 4:  okay, but you can get controllers to press the virtual buttons. So that's,
Speaker 4:  this is like, this is why people buy Android gaming devices. Like I wanna
Speaker 4:  play one game that supports controllers on one platform and not
Speaker 4:  another. And this thing, let me do it. This person actually bought a razor
Speaker 4:  edge. This is a quote, there are a few games optimizer controllers on Android
Speaker 4:  and most are pretty good. I use the Edge to emulate games. I definitely
Speaker 4:  own in other forms. Definitely emulators up to PS two, three
Speaker 4:  Ds and Switch. And then this is a very important line. I'm
Speaker 4:  one of the people who have more fun getting something to work than actually
Speaker 4:  having the thing which is after my own heart. I am absolutely that person.
Speaker 5:  These are our people.
Speaker 4:  And then he finishes with this explains where the next thing I bought was
Speaker 4:  an RG ally.
Speaker 5:  Fair emulators are are not a small piece of this though.
Speaker 5:  I think like the, the deeper I get into this world, the more
Speaker 5:  I realize there is like a vast ecosystem of
Speaker 5:  weird ways to play games that are at least 20 years old all
Speaker 5:  over Android especially. And I think that's very cool. Yep. But yeah,
Speaker 5:  I mean we're, we're due for like what happened with Android tablets, right?
Speaker 5:  Like everybody's gonna beg Google to care about this and push
Speaker 5:  things along and make them try new things. And then Google will be like,
Speaker 5:  we think Android gaming is the future. And then eight years from now
Speaker 5:  we'll be somewhere.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. We got one last one. This person likes to play Freeda
Speaker 4:  play games on their phone. He says, I've had legitimately rewarding gaming
Speaker 4:  experiences, mobile, especially puzzle games, like very little nightmares
Speaker 4:  where shadow somewhere in Monument Valley and then they finish by saying,
Speaker 4:  I live in Minnesota and anyone who says water is a good windshield, fluid
Speaker 4:  is a monster. Which is an important callback to our other reader
Speaker 4:  feedback. But I just wanna point this out like we have been asking on the
Speaker 4:  show, if you are a hardcore Android gamer, let us know.
Speaker 4:  And this is a pretty good gestalt of what the responses have been.
Speaker 4:  Like. I a big nerd and I like to tinker, which again,
Speaker 4:  you were listening to the right podcast, we love you here. I want to play
Speaker 4:  one game and solve one problem. And Android helps me solve that problem very
Speaker 4:  directly. That is just straight Android stuff. Like iOS is not
Speaker 4:  like we want to help you solve a problem that you've made up. iOS is like
Speaker 4:  welcome to a world, right? Like we've issued you a blazer,
Speaker 4:  Andrew's like whatever you want. And so like that makes sense. And then the
Speaker 4:  third one is like, I'm able to do things over here with emulators and I wasn't
Speaker 4:  able to do somewhere else. That all makes sense. Yeah. But there's not the,
Speaker 4:  I don't think there's a, a culture of like with gaming PCs, right? There's
Speaker 4:  a gaming PC culture. I it the Razor Edge does
Speaker 4:  not have that kind of culture around it. I think the steam deck is getting
Speaker 4:  there, but that feels like a whole different kind of thing.
Speaker 6:  Well there has to be two sides to it because you have to have the culture
Speaker 6:  and you also have to have the working business model. And the problem for
Speaker 6:  Android gaming is that you don't really have a business model that makes
Speaker 6:  someone make a great game for Android. So the best game that you can play
Speaker 6:  on your Android gaming device is a 15 year old Playstation game. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Which is fun. Great for you if you have one. It's just not like there's no
Speaker 6:  business in that. Well
Speaker 4:  They robot to release all that rema the middle gear games and boy are they
Speaker 4:  gonna get that money from me again.
Speaker 4:  They're super gonna get that money from me again. Let's end by switching
Speaker 4:  gears a little bit. It, we've talked about football season a bunch already
Speaker 4:  on the show. It's coming so it's just a couple weeks away here. And the tech
Speaker 4:  platforms that are invested in football are starting to to do stuff. So NFL
Speaker 4:  Sunday Ticket obviously is a big YouTube deal. They're doing pricing
Speaker 4:  promotions for college students, which is a Sunday Ticket mainstay
Speaker 4:  lying to the NFL about where you live to get cheaper Sunday Ticket, I think
Speaker 4:  a cultural phenomenon under reported. But you can
Speaker 4:  do it and, and it's getting more integrated into the Google TV Homescreen.
Speaker 4:  And then Amazon is like You know we had the c e O of a
Speaker 4:  W S on decoder a couple weeks ago and he was like, we advertise in the NFL
Speaker 4:  because it shows off the capabilities and the
Speaker 4:  decision makers of big companies are like know who we are. Which is,
Speaker 4:  I always wonder like if you're in the market for a W Ss, why do you need
Speaker 4:  to know about it? How do you not know about it?
Speaker 6:  The I B M Super Bowl
Speaker 4:  Ad. And it turns out like a lot of people don't know about it and like next
Speaker 4:  gen stats powered by a w s makes it easier for people to go to
Speaker 4:  their boss and say, we would like to work with a w s. Incredible,
Speaker 4:  incredible that that is still the case in 2023. But they are rolling out
Speaker 4:  an awful lot of additional next gen stats on Thursday. Football.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I spent some time earlier this week with some of the folks working
Speaker 5:  on this stuff and it's super interesting to hear them talk about it because
Speaker 5:  like we're all football fans and the thing that we know as
Speaker 5:  football fans is that if you in any way
Speaker 5:  mess with football, people freak out. Yep. Like
Speaker 5:  anything where like if you, if you move the camera angle that it's at
Speaker 5:  when they snap the ball, people freak out.
Speaker 4:  Oh yeah. If the scoreboard display.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, exactly. Like if it was, if it's up here versus down at the bottom
Speaker 5:  of the screen, people have really strong opinions. Like it's, it's that stuff
Speaker 5:  matters to people. And if there is one media property on
Speaker 5:  the planet that you don't mess with in general for lots of reasons
Speaker 5:  right now it's the NFL but now Amazon, like they did Thursday night football
Speaker 5:  last year, it went pretty well. They didn't have any like huge
Speaker 5:  disastrous errors. Ryan Fitzpatrick wore like a lot of weird
Speaker 5:  shirts during the halftime shows, but like it was fine. And so this year
Speaker 5:  Amazon is like, okay, we have some confidence and we, we know we can
Speaker 5:  do this. The numbers were pretty big last year. They weren't as big as linear
Speaker 5:  TV numbers have typically been for Thursday night football, but they were
Speaker 5:  bigger than everybody expected for streaming. And so they're like, okay,
Speaker 5:  what wild new stuff can we do? And they've invented some
Speaker 5:  genuinely cool stuff. We'll see if it works in actual
Speaker 5:  You know live games. But in the stuff they've been testing, like they have
Speaker 5:  a thing, they call it defensive alerts where it'll actually
Speaker 5:  onscreen in real time flag players that thinks they're likely to
Speaker 5:  blitz. And the idea is, is it essentially teaches
Speaker 5:  the viewer how to read the field like a quarterback does. So you see a player's
Speaker 5:  body language or how they move before the snap or what they're saying to
Speaker 5:  each other and it'll actually register like this player is likely leader
Speaker 5:  blitz, keep an eye on them. So it's like, it's a cool way to watch but also
Speaker 5:  invites you like into the strategy of the game. And
Speaker 5:  again, I suspect we're gonna see this go really haywire a lot of ways. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  In the way that all of these large language models systems go
Speaker 5:  haywire, which is gonna be deeply hilarious. But it's a
Speaker 5:  cool idea and as like a kind of stat
Speaker 5:  nerd on top of just liking watching football, it's gonna be super fun. I'm
Speaker 5:  kind of into it.
Speaker 6:  But the danger is that you build fox tracks, which we all, which we remember
Speaker 6:  for the wrong reasons, which is how much people hated it. First of all, they
Speaker 6:  were right. The puck is hard to see on tv or at least it was back before
Speaker 6:  high definition.
Speaker 5:  No, it was the right thing. They sh yeah, Fox should have stuck that out.
Speaker 5:  Maybe
Speaker 6:  Not the right application, but they they were correct. They, they identified
Speaker 6:  the problem and they dealt with it help helping you follow the puck around
Speaker 6:  during N H L games. But as you said, messing with football, people
Speaker 6:  have been watching football their whole lives. They know how to watch football.
Speaker 6:  They decided how they wanna watch football again. I do not watch the Lions
Speaker 6:  anymore because I like to have happy Sundays filled with joy and Mirth.
Speaker 6:  But if I did watch the
Speaker 4:  Lions, she's wandering the streets gonna bar after bar
Speaker 6:  And my TV told me which Blitzer the
Speaker 6:  lions quarterback is not seeing coming because of course he isn't because
Speaker 6:  he plays with lions. So he sucks. He's not going to remake the correct
Speaker 6:  read. This is rough. Every single time I would, I would stop watching Lions
Speaker 6:  games again. So I don't, I don't know. This might not work.
Speaker 5:  So what you're saying is knowledge is knowledge is rage in this, in this
Speaker 5:  case. But
Speaker 4:  Here's what I'll say. Amazon historic last season with original
Speaker 4:  football, Amazon had the worst games in NFL history. Like yeah, some of the
Speaker 4:  worst games I have ever seen. And like maybe that's luck and maybe
Speaker 4:  that's Schedule A, who knows? They were all like uniform, like the
Speaker 4:  broadcasters were like what are we doing? Like Al Michaels
Speaker 4:  is like, I'm like You know audibly opening his flask
Speaker 4:  just trying to get through it. You can hear them like swiping on
Speaker 4:  FanDuel themselves, like looking for prop bets to talk about like, and so
Speaker 4:  like just maybe all the stuff just makes that stuff
Speaker 4:  slightly more interesting to watch if you're not betting on the outcome
Speaker 4:  of the game. Which is currently why people watch NFL games to the
Speaker 4:  end.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Yeah. I mean the thing that was not in Amazon's plans that I
Speaker 5:  expected were fantasy or gambling. 'cause the,
Speaker 5:  I mean that's the two places everybody's going, right? Like you watch football
Speaker 5:  either because you have a fantasy team or you have betts on it. And like
Speaker 5:  E S P N is now into betting, which we've talked about. Like that is where
Speaker 5:  all of this is headed and it's where all the money is. And
Speaker 5:  Amazon, it's a long deal. It has like 10 more years if there's internet football
Speaker 5:  to do, I suspect we'll get there. But yeah, none of that
Speaker 4:  Yet. 10 more years of bottom of the barrel teams kind of not scoring
Speaker 4:  any points.
Speaker 5:  Oh, and wait, before, before we go we should take a break and stop talking
Speaker 5:  about football. But the, it's not in four K and I, I mentioned
Speaker 5:  twice in the story that I wrote about it that it's not in four K, which was
Speaker 5:  just little tiny nods to Neli Patel each time. That's
Speaker 4:  Me. They failed. How?
Speaker 5:  How angry are you that it's not in four K?
Speaker 4:  So they're all doing this thing where they all promise that they've
Speaker 4:  invested in four K delivery. So like the cameras are four K now
Speaker 4:  cameras are actually high resolution 'cause they like being able to punch
Speaker 4:  in and they're like hd, which is
Speaker 5:  Why they like the twice a game. They show that thing where you get like the
Speaker 5:  tons of Boca on the shot and everybody's like, this is amazing. It's like,
Speaker 5:  yeah, they could do that the whole camp. It'd be amazing.
Speaker 4:  No. So those ones are, that's actually, that's something different that that
Speaker 4:  shot. They've started using basically prosumer level
Speaker 4:  DSLRs and this was like a whole invention like oh my God, like NFL
Speaker 4:  broadcast teams are using Sony A seven R twos like great. And, and
Speaker 4:  people got lost their minds and thought it was ak and we all had to be like,
Speaker 4:  no, those are seven 80 sevens. Like that's every YouTuber has this camera.
Speaker 4:  Fair enough. But they're already shooting at higher resolution 'cause they
Speaker 4:  like to be able to zoom, right? And they shoot those pretty crisply. So they've
Speaker 4:  built these like four K H D R workflows and then to go out to
Speaker 4:  all of their additional partners who are not
Speaker 4:  four K enabled, they bring it down to 10 80 p and then
Speaker 4:  You know if you're Fox, you then re upscale it to four K at the AT
Speaker 4:  delivery, which is insanity, right? It's like, it's so frustrating.
Speaker 4:  And they have all landed on this line that says we're gonna do H
Speaker 4:  D R because people, that's what people can see. And I'm
Speaker 4:  like, you are nuts. Like what people can see
Speaker 4:  is more detail. If you're like, look at how much brighter it is.
Speaker 4:  I, I believe you, right? People are, every year Marquez does
Speaker 4:  the photo comparison bracket and every year the brightest photos
Speaker 4:  win regardless of quality. Like I believe you that people can see brighter
Speaker 4:  stuff. But in the context of an NFL football game,
Speaker 4:  there is actually so little dynamic variation
Speaker 4:  because the whole field is a wash in lights. There are
Speaker 4:  no dark parts of an NFL football game. They
Speaker 5:  Do that on purpose.
Speaker 4:  It's like, yeah, they're, they're trying very hard to make everything bright
Speaker 4:  regardless.
Speaker 5:  Even in the, the like promo material that Amazon has for this,
Speaker 5:  the thing that is the most different between S D R and H D R is
Speaker 5:  the sky. Yeah. And it's like fine. Like how many of the, for
Speaker 5:  the four establishing shots that they do every game of
Speaker 5:  like the city that they're in, it'll look great. But I don't know what this
Speaker 5:  gets me for football. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  It's just, it's it's bananas to me. Especially. 'cause Amazon owns it end-to-end,
Speaker 4:  right? It's their broadcast, their distribution,
Speaker 4:  their app. They should be, they should at least be able to do it. And they,
Speaker 4:  they still haven't, Fox still hasn't done it. It's been years now since we've
Speaker 4:  been dunking on Fox. We're not doing it. C b s, God bless them,
Speaker 4:  they were at least they're at 10 80 p where Fox is at seven 20 and E S
Speaker 4:  P is at seven 20. Like that's horrible. But they've all adopted this
Speaker 4:  middle ground of H D H D R instead of Q H D H D R,
Speaker 4:  which is crazy. It's like horrible. Like, just stop it. Like
Speaker 4:  it's especially galling because everywhere else in the world, like
Speaker 4:  the Premier League is in just full, like you can just get it in
Speaker 4:  true four K across England You know who has the Premier League
Speaker 4:  in England? Is it nbc, Amazon Prime video? Is it Amazon Prime video? It is
Speaker 4:  Amazon Prime video. I I thought N B C had it. It's a, it's a mix, but Amazon
Speaker 4:  streams it of course, right? And it's in true four K in Japan every year
Speaker 4:  that the Olympics come out. And N H K in Japan is like,
Speaker 4:  we're doing a test, a first ever test. And last year it was like a first
Speaker 4:  ever test of native over the air eight K broadcast,
Speaker 4:  which just worked. And like next year, like 24 k native over the air broadcast
Speaker 4:  and we're here with 10 80 p h there. This is why David didn't bring it up.
Speaker 4:  And I'm gonna stop now. What are they doing? These are the most
Speaker 4:  lucrative sports rights in America. Just do it. Neil Mohan, if
Speaker 4:  you're listening to me, man, who runs YouTube, I've sent him this email.
Speaker 4:  Why won't YouTube just pay to do this in four k? I will pay them more money.
Speaker 4:  And he was like, that's a, that's a good idea. That's as far as I've gotten.
Speaker 4:  I'm doing the Lord's work. That's a good idea. We're
Speaker 6:  The Detroit Lions of resolution
Speaker 4:  Richard. The lions are good now.
Speaker 6:  I'm totally over it. It's fine. They, they haven't hurt me.
Speaker 4:  We'll talk about that while we're at break fly hard.
Speaker 4:  We'll take a break. We'll be back.
Speaker 12:  We
Speaker 13:  Cannot separate capitalism from racism.
Speaker 14:  Market capitalism is not a religion. You'd have to be a
Speaker 14:  fool to worship it.
Speaker 15:  I'm so sick of living in a capitalist society.
Speaker 12:  Everyone's talking about capitalism and
Speaker 12:  they all seem like they're mad.
Speaker 12:  They say that they hate it and they contest and debate it,
Speaker 12:  but they all agree it's bad.
Speaker 16:  Every Friday for the next four weeks, a new today explained series,
Speaker 16:  blame Capitalism on
Speaker 12:  Today. Explain. We'll listen
Speaker 12:  to their complaints to find out
Speaker 12:  what is going on.
Speaker 15:  Everything comes with a price even peace of mind.
Speaker 16:  Blame Capitalism. A four-part series from today explained every
Speaker 16:  Friday in September.
Speaker 12:  Hey,
Speaker 17:  It's Casey Newton, founder and editor of Platformer, a publication about
Speaker 17:  tech, social media and democracy. And I wanted to let You know that
Speaker 17:  applications are still open for this year's code conference. It's hosted
Speaker 17:  by me and my friends, Neli Patel from The Verge and Julia Borson from
Speaker 17:  cnbc. We're gonna be taking the stage with x slash Twitter, c o
Speaker 17:  Lindy Aino, GM, C E O, Mary Barra, Microsoft
Speaker 17:  cto, Kevin Scott, and many more of the biggest names in tech and
Speaker 17:  business. It's all happening soon, September 26th and 27th and
Speaker 17:  spots are filling up fast. So apply now at Vox
Speaker 17:  media.com/code. That's Vox
Speaker 17:  media.com/code. We'll see you there.
Speaker 4:  All right, we're back. Is this a lightning round? Is that what this is gonna
Speaker 4:  be? We're already over,
Speaker 17:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  We're gonna do this one fast because because you, you specifically Neli,
Speaker 5:  look at me.
Speaker 5:  The thing you picked for the lighting round,
Speaker 4:  This was a sign to me.
Speaker 5:  I That's true. I picked it for you because you wrote about it for the website.
Speaker 5:  I feel the urge to like set a timer that like lights your house on fire
Speaker 5:  after several minutes.
Speaker 4:  All right, I'll just do this.
Speaker 5:  Okay.
Speaker 4:  So, we, so you might remember our friend AI Drake, can we get a little laser
Speaker 4:  bong
Speaker 4:  Ai Drake is an existential threat to
Speaker 4:  the music labels, to YouTube to everyone because you cannot copyright a voice.
Speaker 4:  Can't do it. That's, and if you want do likenesses in publicity,
Speaker 4:  that's state law. There's no federal law. So Google this week
Speaker 4:  announced a deal with Universal Music Group, which represents Drake
Speaker 4:  and the weekend saying we're gonna figure out some sort of something,
Speaker 4:  something or the other. We're gonna have a a, a working group called the
Speaker 4:  YouTube AI Music Console. Like Frank Sinatra's children will be in
Speaker 4:  it. Ryan Tetter from One Republic. He can always be
Speaker 4:  drafted into making consequential music. It's gonna be fine. So they have
Speaker 4:  a council like figure out some AI stuff that's good. And then this line,
Speaker 4:  we will figure out how to expand content ID to cover generated music.
Speaker 4:  YouTube content ID is not a perfect system. It is
Speaker 4:  necessary for YouTube to exist. So YouTube in the early
Speaker 4:  days, right, full of like South Park clips that were unlicensed, Viacom Sues
Speaker 4:  YouTube, this is existential YouTube full of pirated music or
Speaker 4:  music without licenses. Parents are uploading videos of their kids dancing
Speaker 4:  to Prince. You can't sue YouTube section two 30.
Speaker 4:  So that labels sue the parents for posting videos of their kids dancing
Speaker 4:  to Prince. This is a real case. I went to the appellate courts in this country
Speaker 4:  for that to be ruled fair use bananas situation. So
Speaker 4:  YouTube over many years has built the system called Content id, which
Speaker 4:  I promise you most kids in this country think is the
Speaker 4:  law. This like automated content identification
Speaker 4:  system that only operates on YouTube. Like whenever you see
Speaker 4:  YouTubers thinking about copyright law, they're not actually thinking about
Speaker 4:  copyright law. They're thinking about YouTube's system that it built to enable
Speaker 4:  itself to exist in the face of existential copyright threats.
Speaker 5:  Which is not a crazy assertion. I mean for all intents and purposes it is
Speaker 5:  the law. Like yeah,
Speaker 4:  It's the, it's the thing that, it's the enforcement mechanism of the platform
Speaker 4:  that pays a lot of people their money. Sure. It, it is close to law and it
Speaker 4:  has a relationship to the law, which is really important, right? If you are
Speaker 4:  ever in the middle of a content Id dispute, if you make a piece of
Speaker 4:  film credit, we were talking about this last week. If you make a piece of
Speaker 4:  film criticism and it gets flagged by content ID and a
Speaker 4:  studio gets a hold of it and they say, take this down, it's not fair use
Speaker 4:  YouTube doesn't step in to say no, we think it is.
Speaker 4:  YouTube says, well you guys talk to each other. And then after a minute of
Speaker 4:  that it says, well you you should go to court. Like that's
Speaker 5:  And let us know how it goes. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Basically like let us know how it goes. Like let whatever, because it has
Speaker 4:  the whole legal system to fall back on. Because fair use
Speaker 4:  for that kind of stuff is like, well within the law, what they're gonna do
Speaker 4:  with universal music, I promise you this will happen, is one
Speaker 4:  next year Google io will get a video of Ryan Tedder
Speaker 4:  being like, make me some beats and like Google part making a beat. And
Speaker 4:  Ryan will be like, this is great for creativity, that video is coming a hundred
Speaker 4:  percent coming and then next to it, content ID will be expanded.
Speaker 4:  So that if you are using the AI generated voice of Drake in a song,
Speaker 4:  universal Music Group can push a button and take that video down
Speaker 4:  or monetize it for themselves. I guarantee you this is where they're going.
Speaker 5:  That second point I think is, is the one, right? Because if I, what Universal
Speaker 5:  is gonna say is like we, we don't want to pick this fight, we just want to
Speaker 5:  make the money off of it, right? Like it's if Universal and the other labels
Speaker 5:  can play this correctly, it's all upside. Like they've just infinitely
Speaker 5:  scaled the amount of Drake music there can be in the world and they'll get
Speaker 5:  paid for all of it, right? Like
Speaker 4:  Maybe So, we don't know what the rates are gonna be, right? They they just,
Speaker 4:  they've just set it enough to suggest this is
Speaker 4:  what they're gonna do. They haven't yeah, done it yet. We dunno the details,
Speaker 4:  but You know, they put out blog posts. One was Neil Mohan and the other one
Speaker 4:  was Lucian Grange, the CEO of Universal. And they put out like paired blog
Speaker 4:  posts on the YouTube blog and they also sound very proud of themselves. You
Speaker 4:  could just see that this is what they're after, right? If you train a bunch
Speaker 4:  of ais on Drake and then it can wrap like Drake Universal's, like you
Speaker 4:  should pay us. And I, I, I think a lot of people say, okay,
Speaker 4:  common sense that makes sense. The flip side of that is that is not anywhere
Speaker 4:  in the law. So if you get that notice from YouTube that
Speaker 4:  says, content ID has flagged fake Drake, we flagged laser bong take
Speaker 4:  it down or blah blah blah, and you're like, no, I disagree. And they're like,
Speaker 4:  go to court and you show up in a court and the courts seem like, what the
Speaker 4:  hell are you talking about? So like that out doesn't exist. So then YouTube
Speaker 4:  has to make decisions and it's gonna be like you Drake
Speaker 4:  Universal Music Group in YouTube. And I just feel like I know
Speaker 4:  who's definitely gonna lose. I don't know who's gonna win, but I know who
Speaker 4:  loses in that situation. I also know that content 90 notoriously
Speaker 4:  overzealous, right? It's too protective of copyright material
Speaker 4:  on YouTube YouTubers know this, our own audience, we got some
Speaker 4:  emails last week after we talked about it. They know that the YouTubers are
Speaker 4:  all trying to dance around it to just do film criticism. What happens when
Speaker 4:  it's just a kid trying to wrap like Drake, no ai, just an
Speaker 4:  impersonator of Drake. Do they get taken down? Like there's no law
Speaker 4:  that distinguishes that. There's no AI system that can reliably at a
Speaker 4:  hundred percent success rate distinguish between ai, Drake, and a kid who
Speaker 4:  just is really good at sounding like Drake. Who's gonna lose that one? I
Speaker 4:  don't know the answers to this, but I do know that in order to keep
Speaker 4:  YouTube going and in particular competitive with TikTok,
Speaker 4:  which has huge influence for the music industry, Google has to like
Speaker 4:  invent some kind of additional licensing scheme for the labels.
Speaker 4:  The labels are gonna get paid for this or they're gonna take their music
Speaker 4:  away and Google can't have that,
Speaker 5:  Right? Yeah, it's, I mean I was trying to think about this after you wrote
Speaker 5:  this story and the number of industries out there
Speaker 5:  that have this kind of leverage over YouTube, I think it's just
Speaker 5:  one, it's just music. Like if, if, if the movie industry decided
Speaker 5:  it hated YouTube, that would be bad, but not like
Speaker 5:  crush the creator economy bad. But if you suddenly
Speaker 5:  lose access to music for creators to do stuff in shorts, like there goes
Speaker 5:  shorts, it's done kill
Speaker 4:  That product. Dance is on shorts, it's all done.
Speaker 5:  YouTube music goes away. A huge percentage of
Speaker 5:  YouTube's views are music videos. Like there's literally the
Speaker 5:  Mr. Beast just set a record for the most views in 24 hours for a
Speaker 5:  non-music video. Like that is a, that is, that is how big music videos are.
Speaker 5:  And I think it's pretty clear that the
Speaker 5:  music industry knows. Yeah, it is this powerful over YouTube.
Speaker 5:  They
Speaker 4:  Definitely know. And so you can just see what YouTube is forced to do a couple
Speaker 4:  of blog posts saying, we're all friends, here's the AI council, we're gonna
Speaker 4:  build some tools together. Ryan Tedder, get in here, You know, just
Speaker 4:  do some Ryan, you'll you'll do anything for money. I what do
Speaker 5:  You, what do you think gets Ryan
Speaker 4:  Tedder? I just don't like one
Speaker 5:  Republican. Are you just like mad that he's wr wrote so many good songs?
Speaker 5:  Is that what it is? Is it,
Speaker 4:  Is that, is that how you describe them? Someone today described that
Speaker 4:  new Addison Ray record to me is like the return of the Kia commercial music.
Speaker 4:  It's, it's just like that's where we are in music history. The hamsters.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, that's, it's, it sounds like royalty free car, commercial music,
Speaker 4:  like a lot of music sounds like royalty free car commercial music right
Speaker 5:  Now. Yeah, and it's all because Ryan Tedder invented it, so you're welcome.
Speaker 5:  I
Speaker 4:  Couldn't see he's, he's an innovator. He is right up there with slash
Speaker 5:  Exactly.
Speaker 4:  Eddie Van Halen slash Ryan Tedder. That's the pantheon
Speaker 4:  of rock music Anyhow you. But you can see what they're doing with the music
Speaker 4:  industry, right? They're making nice, they're gonna, we're finding ways to
Speaker 4:  work together and they're gonna invent a revenue stream for them. The flip
Speaker 4:  side of that with Google in particular is Google
Speaker 4:  is looking at the whole web. No one has leverage over
Speaker 4:  Google when it comes to the web and they're saying, oh, this is ours now.
Speaker 4:  And so if you allow Google search callers to look at your website,
Speaker 4:  you are training Bard and there's, and you are training the search generative
Speaker 4:  experience. And there's fundamentally zero difference
Speaker 4:  between, I'm gonna hoover up all the songs in the world to make it
Speaker 4:  Frank Sinatra ai and I'm gonna hoover up all of the
Speaker 4:  articles about bikes to make the search generative experience answer
Speaker 4:  questions about bikes. That is the, it's the same thing. And Google
Speaker 4:  on the one hand is saying, okay, these, this partner's important So, we
Speaker 4:  gotta build custom copyright private law on YouTube for them so they can
Speaker 4:  get some money and be happy. And then to the entire rest of the
Speaker 4:  internet, they're saying, if you want search traffic, we're taking your shit.
Speaker 4:  And I, I like you just wa you are watching this play out in like absolutely
Speaker 4:  Bananas ways and I think they're gonna come around
Speaker 4:  to signing some deals. I think Open AI is gonna come around to signing some
Speaker 4:  deals. Google has some kind of deal with the New York Times. They won't talk
Speaker 4:  about the terms. OpenAI has some kind of deal with the ap. They won't really
Speaker 4:  talk about the terms, but you can just see like their choices are either
Speaker 4:  a decade of fair use litigation. Some of these cases are already going from
Speaker 4:  Sarah Silverman and others, or we're gonna pay the biggest and
Speaker 4:  richest players to participate in our experiences
Speaker 4:  and like compete that way. And all of that just feels like, oh, we're just
Speaker 4:  kinda like getting back to a o l, right? Where like a o l had a bunch of
Speaker 4:  media partners and you would like get a o l in there. And then there were
Speaker 4:  like some forums that you could like also go to or like you could dump out
Speaker 4:  to the internet You know through a o l, but like really like AOL's Media
Speaker 4:  partners were the thing. And it just seems like that's where everyone is
Speaker 4:  going because to solve the AI training copyright problem,
Speaker 4:  you're either betting on a decade of litigation with our current court
Speaker 4:  system, I'm gonna make a multi-billion dollar bet on how
Speaker 4:  Clarence Thomas feels in five years. Woo. Or
Speaker 4:  you can pay a bunch of money to the New York Times and I'm just watching
Speaker 4:  this play out and it's like, oh this is all kind of icky. Like
Speaker 4:  it's important to take a step back and just be like, this is what's happening.
Speaker 4:  Like copyright law is so broken and weird that on the one hand,
Speaker 4:  the estate of Frank Sinatra gets paid whenever
Speaker 4:  there's a Frank Sinatra impersonator on YouTube weird.
Speaker 4:  And on the other hand, most websites have to give all their shit to Google
Speaker 4:  for free or basically commit suicide by not getting any search traffic.
Speaker 4:  Weird.
Speaker 5:  And either way, anybody who doesn't have the sway to pick and win that fight
Speaker 5:  gets hosted. Like if you're a, if you're an independent artist,
Speaker 5:  Google's not signing that deal with you for YouTube and isn't signing that
Speaker 5:  deal with you for S G E and you just have to bank on the fact that that
Speaker 5:  what it supposedly delivers you is worth it. But anyway, Neli, you went about
Speaker 5:  six times longer than you were supposed to. Sorry on that one. So
Speaker 4:  I can keep going.
Speaker 5:  No, listen, if this were banana surgery, I would say you can have as long
Speaker 5:  as you want, but
Speaker 4:  The whole hour next week is banana surgery.
Speaker 5:  I'll go next. Mine's quick and then Richard you, you can go last. Mine is
Speaker 5:  just mostly a, a shout out to my father-in-law who I think was
Speaker 5:  the last subscriber to DVD dot com Nice. Which is
Speaker 5:  what Netflix's DVD system has been called for the last bunch of years.
Speaker 5:  And obviously DVD dot com is going outta business and p ss a
Speaker 5:  to anyone who has DVD dot com Netflix is both sending
Speaker 5:  out a bunch of random DVDs. It just seems to have like a warehouse full that
Speaker 5:  it's just shipping to its subscribers and anything you
Speaker 5:  have when the system goes away, you get to keep, so
Speaker 5:  I told this to my father-in-law over the weekend and without one word, he
Speaker 5:  ran into their computer room, which they have nice sat down and managed
Speaker 5:  his cue to put all his favorite movies at the top because he is like, okay,
Speaker 5:  now I'm gonna get a bunch and the system is gonna think these are the movies
Speaker 5:  I wanna watch. So maybe they'll ship 'em to me at the end. So if you have
Speaker 5:  DVD dot com now is, now is your time. You're gonna get a bunch of free movies.
Speaker 5:  It says
Speaker 4:  DVD dot com ship Blue Rays. I got I I gotta go.
Speaker 4:  This
Speaker 5:  Shows over. I'm just saying this is the
Speaker 4:  Time. Yeah, I got some work
Speaker 5:  To do. I'm here for you.
Speaker 6:  And there's so much, there's so much stuff that has never been released digitally
Speaker 6:  that you can't get streaming video on demand anywhere and it's just on disk
Speaker 6:  and this is a pretty good chance to get it.
Speaker 5:  Like take your five favorite movies between now and
Speaker 5:  September 29th that are probably never gonna come to streaming. Make
Speaker 5:  it happen. Pump
Speaker 4:  Up the volume. There you go. It's never coming. The music rights are too
Speaker 4:  hard.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. All right, well now we've lost Neli to his DVD Q. So Richard, what
Speaker 5:  do you have?
Speaker 6:  The only thing that any of us should be talking about Samsung release or
Speaker 6:  Samsung has announced a price and a release window for their 57 inch dual
Speaker 6:  U H D gaming monitor.
Speaker 5:  I'm assuming you have like four or five of these already.
Speaker 6:  I'm looking at an Odyssey G nine monitor right now, the 49
Speaker 6:  inch one, which I feel like many people think that is too
Speaker 6:  much to have essentially like You know 2 14 40 p displays.
Speaker 5:  People are saying that as one people say that
Speaker 6:  Giant curved display that takes up most of your room, I
Speaker 6:  now feel like it's too little because they, you can get a 57 inch that is
Speaker 6:  like two four K displays in one giant curve screen
Speaker 6:  and in the US it'll be available in October for about 2,500 bucks.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I need that steal
Speaker 5:  At any price, man. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  The bad news is You know having had the G nine, it's not great for gaming.
Speaker 6:  Like you think that like you can play games that's gonna wrap around you
Speaker 6:  and you'll feel very immersed. Basically no games support 32 by
Speaker 6:  nine aspect ratio
Speaker 5:  Surprise,
Speaker 6:  Which You know one guest, everybody's vaping spend
Speaker 6:  a lot of time developing for this aspect ratio that no one uses. And the
Speaker 6:  games either stretch in bad ways or they just take up the middle of the
Speaker 6:  screen. Other stuff like that. So it's not great for gaming, but like if
Speaker 6:  you, I don't know, maybe run news for a website and you have a billion
Speaker 6:  tabs open, you can just, you can just have, you can have all the tabs, you
Speaker 6:  can have so many tabs on the 57 inch screen.
Speaker 5:  So I'm thinking game in the middle, slack on the left,
Speaker 5:  browser on the right and you just yep, just crush
Speaker 5:  the internet. You describe Head and Fools all day.
Speaker 5:  I'd love this. $2,500 actually is less than I thought this was gonna cost,
Speaker 5:  which is like an insane thing to say out loud, but I was pretty sure
Speaker 5:  Samsung was gonna be like, this thing is five grand. What are you gonna do
Speaker 5:  about it?
Speaker 4:  Here's what I want you to do. If you watch the video where they introduce
Speaker 4:  this thing, the monitor is Elysium, like it's a spaceship
Speaker 4:  flying over a city that's in the curved monitor. And I don't
Speaker 4:  know that they watched Elysium because that, that truly implies the
Speaker 4:  monitor passes a deeply inequitable class system.
Speaker 4:  Well
Speaker 6:  It's not, it's not Elysium, it's, it's Halo. And when you visited the ha
Speaker 6:  the Ring world and Halo, everything was fine, right? That's how that story
Speaker 6:  went.
Speaker 4:  And I would just say in general, ring Worlds not
Speaker 4:  great in fiction.
Speaker 4:  I'm getting one of these. Look, I gotta kid out a new podcast here. We're
Speaker 4:  moving So, we get a new hat, we gotta figure it out. So I'm fully in the
Speaker 4:  market for like gamer lights, crazy displays. This is
Speaker 4:  gonna be a good time. I
Speaker 5:  Think there, there's gonna have to be a Vergecast series
Speaker 5:  of Neli doing his new podcast room just
Speaker 4:  Installing gamer lights.
Speaker 5:  If you're an interior designer or have ideas about what Neli needs to
Speaker 5:  put in his new studio, email them to us. Vergecast The Verge dot com.
Speaker 5:  We
Speaker 6:  Didn't talk about the gamer standing disc. Oh man, of course
Speaker 4:  They're, this thing looks ridiculous. I love it. I love it. The only
Speaker 4:  thing that would be better if it, if the top was a true patch bay with like,
Speaker 4:  like quarter inch plugs,
Speaker 5:  This to me is like if you took the, the r slash battle stations subreddit
Speaker 5:  and like fed it into mid journey and then just said, show me a
Speaker 5:  desk, this is what it would spit out. It's like it's got a
Speaker 5:  bunch of monitor holders, it's got two different lights,
Speaker 5:  there's speakers everywhere. It has a stream deck, it has
Speaker 5:  a thousand different places to hang things. It loves a pegboard, it's got
Speaker 5:  some controllers. It's like, it is just the perfect average
Speaker 5:  of every insane gamer system you've ever seen. And then, I mean that as a
Speaker 5:  compliment, I'm kind of in love with this thing
Speaker 6:  And that's great, but like they invented a workbench and a pegboard.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, it's good. I mean it's, we started the show with show us your your
Speaker 4:  vintage computer rooms and we're ending the show with like, there's a motorized
Speaker 4:  standing desk with a pegboard.
Speaker 5:  This is the new computer room. This is like all the old office Max Hutches
Speaker 5:  have been replaced by Yeah. Sit stand desks and
Speaker 5:  pegboards.
Speaker 4:  I'm into it. Maybe I'll get maybe this. I'm, I'm gonna build my new podcast
Speaker 4:  studio around this thing. There you go. No, I don't know if I'm gonna do
Speaker 4:  that. We'll see, I gotta look at this more carefully. All right, we gotta
Speaker 4:  end this show. We're way over. This is for a show Slow News Week. I don't
Speaker 4:  even know how we, how we pulled this off and there's like stuff we didn't
Speaker 4:  even get to, for example, a full hour on Python and Excel
Speaker 4:  just didn't happen. One thing I want to call out, this is one of the funniest
Speaker 4:  things that has happened to me today. Our friend Ashley Carmen
Speaker 4:  Verge Expat now at Bloomberg, she's their podcast and music
Speaker 4:  reporter at Bloomberg. She wrote a story about white noise podcasts on
Speaker 4:  Spotify in which there aren't many. And Spotify freaking out
Speaker 4:  because they're official, like white noise license streams make more
Speaker 4:  money than the podcast. So they're like, we have a $38 million white noise
Speaker 4:  podcast problem, which is just the most capitalism
Speaker 4:  thing. Oh, that's amazing. Be like this white noise. If we move it from this
Speaker 4:  bucket to that bucket is $38 million is ridiculous. So
Speaker 4:  our friend Charlie Harding, who you might know is the creator of Laser Bong
Speaker 4:  on the show and the co-host switched on pop. He
Speaker 4:  made an entire series of white noise podcasts. We'll link them in the
Speaker 4:  show notes and
Speaker 5:  Now he's worth $700 million
Speaker 4:  My goal. And they all have like just truly ridiculous names.
Speaker 4:  They're called Sonic Spectrum. They're all colors. He made chat, G b T write
Speaker 4:  the descriptions of them, venture into the vastness of white noise,
Speaker 4:  encompassing every frequency. Like it's all great. My goal
Speaker 4:  is that we make this a real thing. We get some wellness blogs to cover it
Speaker 4:  in a serious way. And if we can just get to the point where
Speaker 4:  Aaron Rogers is listening to Sonic Spectrum
Speaker 4:  pre-game 'cause he loves crystal healing, I'll be very happy.
Speaker 4:  Make this happen for me. This
Speaker 5:  Eli's end games always end with either Aaron Rogers or Mariah Carey. Those
Speaker 5:  are the two, the two long cons,
Speaker 4:  The Mariah Carey. Long con's, very different. I gotta upend my family for
Speaker 4:  that one. This one is very direct. Just share Sonic Spectrum as much as
Speaker 4:  you can and see if we can make it a thing. It's, I mean, it's, these descriptions
Speaker 4:  are some of the funniest chat G B T shit I've ever read. And then it's just
Speaker 4:  white noise. It's very good. We'll have a link in the show notes. There's
Speaker 4:  a quick post in the site. Go check it out. It's a very, very funny. Okay,
Speaker 4:  that's it, David, what's in, in this taller this week? Anything good?
Speaker 5:  A bunch of good stuff. Actually, the, the Playstation Portal will be in there.
Speaker 5:  Spoiler alert. But I found a new app for organizing all your crap
Speaker 5:  online, which I am of course deeply obsessed with. And there's a bunch of
Speaker 5:  new like creator stuff and YouTube stuff. And I found this was
Speaker 5:  a surprisingly good week for like random things appearing on the internet.
Speaker 5:  So it's gonna be a good one.
Speaker 4:  I like it. Okay, that's it. That's Vergecast back roll.
Speaker 19:  And that's a wrap for Vergecast this week. We'd love to hear from you. Shoot
Speaker 19:  us an email at Vergecast at The Verge dot com. The Vergecast is
Speaker 19:  a production of The Verge and the Vox Media Podcast network. The show is
Speaker 19:  produced by me, Liam James, and our senior audio director, Andrew Marino.
Speaker 19:  Our editorial director is Brooke Miners. That's it. We'll see you next week.