# Transcript
ID: 29c928e9-4ceb-403a-a745-d21165a641c5
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Gadget tips for your next upgrade | Vergecast Hotline
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/6730405518505982826/-2538023517510884650/s93290-US-3778s-1690357260.mp3
Description: Today on the flagship podcast of answering machines:
We answer your questions from The Vergecast Hotline!
01:51 - LDAC and other audio codecs
06:21 - Samsung TV
07:58 - Smartwatches for marathons
16:38 - iPhone upgrades
23:09 - Threads
29:52 - Security cameras
40:46 - Laptops
39:13 - Google Pixel
50:54 - Android phones
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we love hearing from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Disabled
Speaker 2:  Welcome to The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of answering machines.
Speaker 2:  I'm your friend David Pierce and I'm on vacation as you're listening to this.
Speaker 2:  I'm probably in an Airbnb in the woods of
Speaker 2:  Pennsylvania pretending to read all of those books that I bought. But ultimately,
Speaker 2:  probably just scrolling through TikTok, watching videos of outtakes from
Speaker 2:  the office because that's what I end up doing on most of my vacation. And
Speaker 2:  honestly, no complaints. It's not a bad life vacation or no vacation, though
Speaker 2:  we still have a great show for you today. We've been really enjoying getting
Speaker 2:  to answer a question from the Vergecast hotline every week. But the truth
Speaker 2:  is we get so many good voicemails to just do one a week.
Speaker 2:  So today we're gonna do a whole bunch right in a row. We're gonna answer
Speaker 2:  your questions about iPhones and pixels and Threads and Instagram
Speaker 2:  Max and Windows Security cameras, and lots more. Turns out a lot of
Speaker 2:  people have buying questions, so we're gonna just tell you some stuff to
Speaker 2:  buy. As always, the Hotline number is 8 6 6 Verge one one,
Speaker 2:  and you can also email all of your questions to Vergecast at The Verge dot
Speaker 2:  com. Thank you truly to everyone who calls and emails, hearing from you is
Speaker 2:  my absolute favorite thing. And doing the Hotline is frankly my favorite
Speaker 2:  part of the show. Lots of Hotline coming up in just a second, but first I
Speaker 2:  gotta go watch more office bloopers. Have you seen the ones about the plasma
Speaker 2:  TV from the dinner party episodes where he's just pushing it into the wall?
Speaker 2:  It never ever fails to make me laugh. It's the greatest thing.
Speaker 3:  I guess what surround sound means is that right over here. Tim,
Speaker 3:  check this out. Falls folds
Speaker 3:  the wall.
Speaker 2:  This is The Verge Cast. We'll see you in a sec.
Speaker 4:  Barbie has been around for almost 65 years, but Barbie's
Speaker 4:  aesthetic, you could argue it's been around even longer
Speaker 5:  When you kind of put up like a timeline of the history
Speaker 5:  of fashion Barbie. Coy has always kind of been there, we just
Speaker 5:  didn't call it that. Mm, And I. Think by the time you hit
Speaker 5:  like clueless superstars like Paris Hilton and Nicole Richie
Speaker 5:  it, it became more of a a, a present
Speaker 4:  The enduring appeal of Barbie fashion. This week on
Speaker 4:  Intuit Vultures pop culture podcast
Speaker 6:  Support for this podcast comes from Slack and they're looking to help make
Speaker 6:  you and your team work better. Slack is a productivity platform that connects
Speaker 6:  all your team members together instantly. It's built to help your team with
Speaker 6:  a host of features like huddles for quick check-ins and clips for recording
Speaker 6:  and sharing video. Slack also makes it easy to search and find the right
Speaker 6:  information you need. You can even integrate the apps you use in your normal
Speaker 6:  workflow like your calendar or project management tools. So stay connected
Speaker 6:  on the work that matters and get more done. Learn more at Slack
Speaker 6:  dot com slash productivity.
Speaker 2:  All right, we're back. Let's get to the Hotline. Our first question might
Speaker 2:  be the wonkiest question we've gotten in a while. And. I. Love it. For that,
Speaker 2:  it comes from Clay in Cincinnati.
Speaker 7:  Hey Vergecast, this is Clay from Cincinnati. Last week I bought a pair of
Speaker 7:  Sony WF 1000 XM four headphones and
Speaker 7:  today I figured out that their LDAC audio codec is not enabled
Speaker 7:  by default. So I turned that on And I think there's an incredible difference.
Speaker 7:  So my question is, what's your all's favorite audio codec or
Speaker 7:  do you think that worrying about Codex is more? Hi-fi snake oil stuff.
Speaker 7:  Thanks a lot. Bye.
Speaker 2:  Okay, I brought in Chris Welch to answer this question. Chris, I assume you
Speaker 2:  know why you're here.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, love to talk audio codex. Oh man, there's a lot to unpack
Speaker 8:  there.
Speaker 2:  Okay, hit me with it.
Speaker 8:  Well, timing is everything. Clay, I hope you held onto your receipt because
Speaker 8:  by the time you hear this, Sony will have announced the new wf thousand x
Speaker 8:  m fives and you can read my review on the site. They're great.
Speaker 8:  They're not that different. They're a bit smaller, a bit lighter in your
Speaker 8:  ears sounds a bit better. So if you can do an exchange, it's gonna be
Speaker 8:  worth it. As far as the codex go, it's not snake oil, but people
Speaker 8:  spend way too much time worrying about this stuff. you know, like how your
Speaker 8:  headphones are tuned and like designed factors in just as much as like what
Speaker 8:  codex they have. But I do like Leck if you can turn it on so it can
Speaker 8:  hit 990 kilobits a second in theory, but most phones don't ever
Speaker 8:  do that. Like when you pair Sony headphones or earbuds with your phone, by
Speaker 8:  default it usually goes for like six 60 kilobits per second, which is still
Speaker 8:  better than like, you know, Spotify or whatever else. So if you've got
Speaker 8:  Apple Music or Amazon Music or Title or QO Buzz,
Speaker 8:  I never know how to pronounce that one.
Speaker 2:  That's not a real thing. I refuse to believe that's a real name you just
Speaker 2:  said.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, I swear it is. There's a very passionate community, they all serve
Speaker 8:  very high resolution audio. So if you pair that with an leck capable earbud,
Speaker 8:  there's aptex hd, same kind of thing, they can hit similar
Speaker 8:  bit rate and you can hear it different. Some people, not everybody, again,
Speaker 8:  it just kind of comes down to your ears. But if you had those earbuds, you
Speaker 8:  might as well use the feature and enjoy it and get the most from your purchase.
Speaker 8:  But yeah, I think we spend a lot of time just kind of worrying about the
Speaker 8:  ins and outs of, of these codecs too much these days.
Speaker 2:  I think that's right. So one thing I've always wondered is kind of where
Speaker 2:  on the ranking of important things the codec is, right? Because
Speaker 2:  obviously if you're gonna spend a lot of time worrying about your codec,
Speaker 2:  but you're gonna wear like AirPods that only halfway fit in your ear, like
Speaker 2:  you're, you're worrying about the wrong problem, right? Yeah. And if you're
Speaker 2:  buying a $15 pair of headphones at C V s and
Speaker 2:  you're worried about like the quality of the stuff coming from your streaming
Speaker 2:  service, you're also worried about the wrong problem. So kind of where along
Speaker 2:  the line should I start to worry about the codec? Like the very first thing
Speaker 2:  is the headphone quality, right? Like seems like worry about that before
Speaker 2:  you worry about anything else. The second thing would be basically like
Speaker 2:  quality of what your streaming service can theoretically provide,
Speaker 8:  Right? And if you have a Spotify, all this is still for N 'cause they still
Speaker 8:  don't even do lossless. We hear it's happening finally sometime soon. It'll
Speaker 8:  probably cost more money than it does now. So if you have Spotify, I wouldn't
Speaker 8:  worry about it period. But if you've got say Apple Music or Amazon Music,
Speaker 8:  then you can start to kind of factor that into your buying decision.
Speaker 8:  Okay, And I. Think it's also like budget. If you're spending below a hundred
Speaker 8:  dollars, I can't imagine like that it really matters that much Codex
Speaker 8:  versus if you spend like 200, $300 on a set of earbuds, you want to
Speaker 8:  know it checks all the boxes just because you're spending that amount of
Speaker 8:  money. So why not?
Speaker 2:  That's fair. But at least in my experience, these Sonys are good enough that
Speaker 2:  our friend, I don't think this is pure placebo. I think to some extent you
Speaker 2:  turn on, like you flip the switch that says make the audio fancy and
Speaker 2:  you're definitely like primed to hear the fancy audio, right? Yeah. But I
Speaker 2:  think we have enough quality in those Sony headphones that they will do
Speaker 2:  enough of a different thing on the better codec that you might actually
Speaker 2:  notice it, right? This is not pure nonsense. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  No. Okay. Not at all. If you've got the ear for it, go for it.
Speaker 2:  What is the verdict on the m fives by the way? How do you feel about them?
Speaker 2:  Good.
Speaker 8:  They're not that different from the m fours, which I'm sure Clay will be
Speaker 8:  happy about if he's stuck with m fours. But they're lighter, smaller sounds
Speaker 8:  a bit nicer, slightly better at some noise cancellation on streets and like
Speaker 8:  voices and things like that. But there's no like new tent pole feature. They're
Speaker 8:  just a much sleeker version of the m fours. Alright
Speaker 2:  Clay, I hope that helps. Welch, before you go, I got an email this morning
Speaker 2:  that I did not tell you about, but I wanna read to you And. I want you to
Speaker 2:  respond to it because it makes me very happy. Okay. This email comes from
Speaker 2:  Matt in Switzerland. And, I'm, I'm gonna paraphrase because this is a very
Speaker 2:  long and very lovely email, but it takes a while. Basically our friend Matt
Speaker 2:  says this week I had to say goodbye to my great OLED four K tv. I it's,
Speaker 2:  it was one year old, I spent hours comparing and analyzing and
Speaker 2:  then the cat jumped into the TV and destroyed it. So Matt says we are on
Speaker 2:  the market for a new tv. My boyfriend wants to prove to me he can do it.
Speaker 2:  It scares the hell out of me. I've heard him say Samsung several times. We
Speaker 2:  are already using Samsung for phones and watches, but dot Samsung
Speaker 2:  TV. Question mark And I would like to know your thoughts. Samsung TV question
Speaker 2:  mark.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, there are two ways to go with Samsung. I think people love the frame.
Speaker 8:  That's obviously this huge hit these days 'cause people don't like how headiest
Speaker 8:  TVs are most of the time. So if that's a concern, the frame is great. It's
Speaker 8:  gotten a lot better over the last few years. It's got a matte screen now
Speaker 8:  it looks like artwork on your wall. And then Samsung also makes some nice
Speaker 8:  ole TVs over the past couple years if you wanna spend a lot more money. Yeah,
Speaker 8:  in some ways they're better than lgs. Very sorry to hear about the fate of
Speaker 8:  your one year old ole. That's rough. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  What losing your one year old four K lead is a tough, tough
Speaker 2:  beat.
Speaker 8:  You buy it, you think I'm gonna have this for the next like decade at least.
Speaker 8:  And then oof Cats,
Speaker 2:  Do you have any tips on cat resistance for televisions?
Speaker 8:  Mount it? I guess I mean that's, yeah though cats are pretty nimble
Speaker 8:  so who knows? There's no there's no shore fire solution.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Yeah. Just don't have cats. That's, that's my answer.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I think the Samsung answer seems to be, Samsung makes good TVs but
Speaker 2:  you probably are going to pay too much for them is kind of my, my read on
Speaker 2:  Samsung TVs most of the time
Speaker 8:  Cost a lot of money in the softwares, eh? So just plug in your
Speaker 8:  preferred streaming box and pay no mind to it.
Speaker 2:  Fair enough. All right Chris, thank you as always.
Speaker 8:  It's been a pleasure.
Speaker 2:  Next up, because I think every time we do this we have to talk about the
Speaker 2:  Apple watch at least somewhat. We have a question about the Apple watch from
Speaker 2:  Ben. Let's hear it.
Speaker 9:  Hi, my name is Ben and this is a question for V I'm training for my first
Speaker 9:  marathon and my five-year-old Garmin watch is getting long in the tooth.
Speaker 9:  I'm tempted to switch to an Apple watch but I'm concerned about battery life.
Speaker 9:  Can I get away with an Apple Watch series eight or would I need to go with
Speaker 9:  the ultra to go that route? Am I going to need to baby the battery life and
Speaker 9:  turn off useful features to get through a long run? Thank you very much.
Speaker 9:  Hope to hear from you soon. Bye.
Speaker 2:  Alright V song, our expert is here to answer this question. V i I assume
Speaker 2:  you're wearing all of these watches right now as we talk about this.
Speaker 10:  I I am wearing a Garmin And I am wearing the Apple Watch ultra. So I feel
Speaker 10:  qualified to answer this question but also congrats then
Speaker 10:  on training for your first marathon. Yeah, that is a huge
Speaker 10:  accomplishment You can get away with using the
Speaker 10:  series eight battery wise for an entire marathon.
Speaker 10:  You just are going to have to be a lot more mindful about charging
Speaker 10:  and charging schedule. So you are gonna have to go like oh before you go
Speaker 10:  on a run, make sure that's topped off and it has fast charging so that's
Speaker 10:  not bad for that. But it is a little annoying because
Speaker 10:  you do have to be more conscious of the battery if you do go for the eight
Speaker 10:  than you would be if you went for the Ultra. Do
Speaker 2:  You think it makes you run faster? Like is it, is this like a useful motivational
Speaker 2:  tactic where like I have to finish this race before my battery dies.
Speaker 2:  You get to mile 22, it's like got 15% left. Like it's go time
Speaker 10:  I think. I think if you're at mile 22 and you're bonking, you're just not
Speaker 10:  gonna give a crap about your watches battery. Like it, it might
Speaker 10:  actually be better if it does die on you because then you can be like, well
Speaker 10:  I have no idea how much time is left. I'm not gonna be just speaking from
Speaker 10:  personal experience. You're not gonna be going like, oh my God I only went
Speaker 10:  0.5 miles. Are you kidding me? Like oh my
Speaker 2:  God, I think the rule is you finish the marathon when your battery dies,
Speaker 2:  that's whatever, whatever the time was then that's your marathon time.
Speaker 2:  Congratulations. Yeah,
Speaker 10:  It also, I'm gonna say it depends on what carbon then is coming from.
Speaker 10:  Because if you are coming from a Phoenix or
Speaker 10:  if you're coming from one of the really higher end forerunners,
Speaker 10:  I just think you're gonna have a more analogous experience if you do go
Speaker 10:  with the Ultra because the Ultra has, it just has more,
Speaker 10:  it's bulkier too, so you might just have that same comforting weight.
Speaker 10:  But in terms of just like the actual metrics you're gonna be getting, you
Speaker 10:  know the health and fitness app are basically the same for either watch.
Speaker 10:  It's just mostly that with the Ultra you are going to get better G
Speaker 10:  P s so if that matters to you then yeah you, you are gonna want that
Speaker 10:  because you have multi-band G P s which you know, all the higher end
Speaker 10:  garments are doing at the same time now. So yay great.
Speaker 10:  But the other thing I'm going to say is that there is a low power
Speaker 10:  mode and then there's an ultra ultra low power mode and so
Speaker 10:  you're not really gonna have to give things up if you decide to use low
Speaker 10:  power mode with the series eight just because it's all it's gonna
Speaker 10:  do is turn off your notifications, turn off all that stuff and
Speaker 10:  you don't want notifications in the middle of training anyway so it's fine,
Speaker 10:  it's just kind of gonna be a little more annoying 'cause it's not gonna
Speaker 10:  wake up quite as quickly and all of that stuff. But you are still going
Speaker 10:  to be getting continuous G P s and heart rate unless you go into the super
Speaker 10:  low power mode, in which case it's gonna take it less frequently. So that's
Speaker 10:  totally up to you. That's really more for ultra
Speaker 10:  marathoners, you know the super DC rainmakers of the world who are
Speaker 10:  just like make you feel real bad about yourself. You see their training
Speaker 10:  regimens, any Apple watch like base level Apple watch, it's gonna last you
Speaker 10:  a marathon provided that you're earning this marathon in like the six hour
Speaker 10:  range, six hour or less, which is most people like a fast marathon. A
Speaker 10:  fast marathon runner is gonna do sub four, which I think good, good
Speaker 10:  for you guys. I don't have that long capacity but yeah like my marathon
Speaker 10:  time, I haven't run one but my projected one according to Garmin is
Speaker 10:  like five hours, 45 or something like that.
Speaker 10:  Something obscene, And I have you know, friends who have run marathons with
Speaker 10:  Apple watches been totally fine. You just have to be more conscious of the
Speaker 10:  battery. So if that's not you, if you don't wanna baby it, if You don't
Speaker 10:  wanna think, don't wanna think too hard about the battery, go for the Ultra
Speaker 10:  I I I use the Ultra as my daily driver and in
Speaker 10:  running And I am, I'm a big fan of it so There you go.
Speaker 2:  I like it. I do think the low power mode thing is a good hack because
Speaker 2:  a, for the exact reasons you described it actually turns off a lot of things
Speaker 2:  you're gonna want off when you're running anyway. Yeah like this is true
Speaker 2:  on the iPhone as well. It's actually a pretty good sort of quick
Speaker 2:  make my phone bother me less button 'cause it just turns down a lot
Speaker 2:  of background processing. It doesn't pull for notifications as often. It
Speaker 2:  doesn't ping your email as often. It just sort of calms your device down
Speaker 2:  a little bit and that's useful both on the phone and the watch And it at
Speaker 2:  least in my experience purely anecdotally does a ton for battery life.
Speaker 2:  So that's a big win.
Speaker 10:  And you know like how EVs have range anxiety, Smartwatches marathons
Speaker 10:  have battery anxiety when you are doing continuous G P s
Speaker 10:  exercise. So if that really is a concern, I am gonna say the Ultra's gonna
Speaker 10:  give you a good time. 'cause I ran a half marathon in
Speaker 10:  very slow three hours it was, it was not my best half
Speaker 10:  marathon time but I only lost
Speaker 10:  15% battery. Not on low power mode. Nothing,
Speaker 10:  nothing done. So wow I only lost 15%. It was the whole 13
Speaker 10:  miles. So take what you will from that. You just won't have to
Speaker 10:  think about it, you won't have to worry. So if it's quote unquote just
Speaker 10:  a marathon either will be fine but the Ultra will
Speaker 10:  alleviate that concern for you a lot more confidently.
Speaker 2:  Got it. Okay. And the, the other thing I'm wondering is the, this switch
Speaker 2:  from, I've been using Garmin for a while, I'm make thinking about making
Speaker 2:  the switch to Apple Watch. What do we think about this idea? Good idea, bad
Speaker 2:  idea. I feel like if our friend Ben was calling and saying I run marathons
Speaker 2:  every weekend, I'm thinking about making the switch. I feel like I would
Speaker 2:  actually try to talk him out of switching to the Apple Watch.
Speaker 10:  I, I would like, so the main question I have for Ben
Speaker 10:  to think about is how much do you want the smart features because
Speaker 10:  Garmin, it has a better training platform. It's
Speaker 10:  very information dense. Do you need all that information? No. Even the professionals
Speaker 10:  don't need everything that garment is going to get you. But it is
Speaker 10:  a lot more comprehensive. I find that the daily suggestive workouts
Speaker 10:  on the garments that I test, they, I find them really helpful 'cause I'm
Speaker 10:  like, oh crap, I don't know what to train for. Oh you're telling me to do,
Speaker 10:  you're telling me to do 31 minutes at a slower pace base. Base pace,
Speaker 10:  cool, great. And it helps you kind of track your recovery a lot more
Speaker 10:  effectively than an Apple Watch will an Apple watch. You have to be more
Speaker 10:  hands on with your training, which may be something that you want. The data
Speaker 10:  is gonna be a lot more streamlined, which I find helpful.
Speaker 10:  Like what's not helpful is me saying that I think the best of both worlds
Speaker 10:  is to use both and string with both of them at the same time.
Speaker 10:  But yeah, if you are super hardcore into the data, the Garmin is gonna be
Speaker 10:  better for you. But if you want apps that work, if you want
Speaker 10:  better connectivity with your phone, if you want greater control over what
Speaker 10:  notifications are going to annoy you all day, then the Apple Watch does
Speaker 10:  make a lot of sense and is the smarter choice because the, the number of
Speaker 10:  notifications I get on this Garmin that do not matter, it's
Speaker 10:  it's very high. It's very high. Do you want a smart experience then yes
Speaker 10:  this makes sense. But if you want the fitness first experience, the Ultra
Speaker 10:  is great. It's just not gonna be as who raw
Speaker 10:  as the Garmin And I know people who are making the switch in both directions
Speaker 10:  going from Apple to Garmin super happy and then going from Garmin to Apple
Speaker 10:  super happy. So it's just a matter of what your priority is.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, they do, they do land in surprisingly different places.
Speaker 2:  It's like the, the Garmin is better for the things that it does, but the
Speaker 2:  Apple Watch does more things. Yeah, right. Like it's, it's a pretty, and
Speaker 2:  the thing is it seems to be mostly self-selecting. So I feel like Ben, if
Speaker 2:  you know you want an Apple watch, totally cool lean in. But
Speaker 2:  also garments are very good also. V before we go, I just want you to know
Speaker 2:  that Buzz Aldrin tweeted a picture of himself the other day on the
Speaker 2:  54th I think anniversary of the Apollo 11 launch day. And
Speaker 2:  he's sitting there eating a plate of steak and eggs and he has three watches
Speaker 2:  on. Oh and all I could think literally my first
Speaker 2:  immediate thought upon looking at this picture was v's probably wearing four
Speaker 2:  watches. I just want you to know this is, this is your legacy V congratulations.
Speaker 2:  Yeah,
Speaker 10:  Double wristing, double watch hands. That's how you know I'm, I'm the real
Speaker 10:  deal. Double watch stands year round. There we go.
Speaker 2:  It's, it's a life. All right, well Ben, let us know how the marathon goes.
Speaker 2:  Good luck with the training V. Thank you.
Speaker 10:  Thank you. Bye.
Speaker 2:  Next up we have a question that has actually made me think a
Speaker 2:  lot of things and feel a lot of feelings over the last few days. It's from
Speaker 2:  Dave, who I promise is not me throwing my voice. Let's hear it.
Speaker 11:  Hey, so I'm a dad now you can call me Dave. My
Speaker 11:  family budget's pretty tight. Food has gotten very expensive. I've always
Speaker 11:  wanted the latest and greatest but I've been rocking an iPhone 12 pro
Speaker 11:  for a couple years now and it's great the
Speaker 11:  battery needs to be replaced. But anyway, I'm debating about whether to
Speaker 11:  just get like a free iPhone 14 and get the 15
Speaker 11:  and have payments and all of that. And I'm really feeling like
Speaker 11:  there's a pretty significant argument to be made for getting a free iPhone
Speaker 11:  14 except you know, the 36 months of waiting
Speaker 11:  and what happens after that. So I don't know, I would love
Speaker 11:  the for to spend.
Speaker 2:  All right Alison Johnson, welcome to the show. Thank you. You can
Speaker 2:  just feel what, what Dave is going through here, right? Yes. Like there's
Speaker 2:  a lot of emotions wrapped up in this decision. I've been thinking a lot about
Speaker 2:  this And I have come to, I have a pretty strong opinion on the right answer
Speaker 2:  here, but before I rant and rave about what I think Dave should do,
Speaker 2:  I want to know what you think is the right answer here.
Speaker 12:  Yeah, this is a tough one. I do see the argument for the
Speaker 12:  free 14, especially a 14 pro.
Speaker 12:  The way I see the 15 and the 15 pro is kind of,
Speaker 12:  you know, based on the rumors, like the regular 15 is just kind of
Speaker 12:  getting in line with what the 14 pro offers. What it
Speaker 12:  sounds like we're gonna get the higher resolution camera dynamic
Speaker 12:  island. You're not gonna get like a nicer screen, but that's Apple. And
Speaker 12:  then the 15 pro it sounds like is gonna be more fancy things.
Speaker 12:  Telephoto Periscope camera,
Speaker 2:  Potentially U S B C
Speaker 12:  U S B C. That is the big exciting one. Dave already
Speaker 12:  has some lightning cables around so you know,
Speaker 12:  probably that's a, a wash. But yeah, I, I kind of went back and
Speaker 12:  forth. I think a free 14 pro would be
Speaker 12:  a smart move. It all just depends on what carrier deal
Speaker 12:  you can find. You are gonna sell your soul to your carrier either way.
Speaker 12:  So yes, I'm curious what, what your answer is.
Speaker 2:  So my stock phone buying advice is
Speaker 2:  buy the best phone you can possibly afford and keep it as long as you possibly
Speaker 2:  can. Right. So by that advice the answer is wait for
Speaker 2:  the 15, right? We've hit the point of the year where anyone who's like, what
Speaker 2:  phone should I buy? I say none wait until September. Right? Because there
Speaker 2:  will be, there will be new Samsung phones, there will be new iPhones. You
Speaker 2:  can make a much more rational and informed decision
Speaker 2:  at like the end of October about the whole phone landscape. If you know you
Speaker 2:  want an iPhone wait until mid-September they'll come out, there'll be a new
Speaker 2:  iPhone by that one. And especially now I feel like the normal
Speaker 2:  age I would expect a phone to be is probably like four years. I think if
Speaker 2:  you've had a phone for four years, years, you can consider that phone to
Speaker 2:  have like lived its best life time to upgrade by the best phone you can and
Speaker 2:  plan to have it for four more years. That said, I believe
Speaker 2:  firmly and strongly that the correct thing to do is get a free iPhone 14.
Speaker 2:  Yeah A because it clearly sounds like money is an object and a free
Speaker 2:  iPhone 14 is going to be a terrific phone that probably will still last you
Speaker 2:  four years. But B, I think this U S B C
Speaker 2:  transition is gonna take a while. I think back to when we all went away from
Speaker 2:  like the 30 pin ports in the iPhone that took a while, everybody
Speaker 2:  had docks. There was all this stuff in like the hotels going to
Speaker 2:  Lightning was annoying for a couple of years and you had to have dongles
Speaker 2:  and you had to buy all kinds of new stuff and eventually the world transitions
Speaker 2:  and it works. I kind of don't want to be at the very front of
Speaker 2:  that change if I don't have to be you. And I will be because this is
Speaker 2:  what we do for a living and we're like phone sickos. But for most people,
Speaker 2:  like you have cables, you might have a doc like your phone probably
Speaker 2:  connects via a certain cable to your car and lots of
Speaker 2:  other things. And I think actually the next phone
Speaker 2:  a after this one that you buy this year is gonna be the one you wanna try
Speaker 2:  a bunch of new stuff with. And granted there might be things in the iPhone
Speaker 2:  15 that we don't know about that are amazing and cool and blow everybody's
Speaker 2:  minds. But rumors that I've seen about the pro are basically like new chip
Speaker 2:  titanium frame, which could look cool. There might be an action button
Speaker 2:  like on the Watch Ultra, which I'm very excited about. But the U S B C port
Speaker 2:  is the thing, right? Like that's gonna be the big shift and that strikes
Speaker 2:  me as something to actually be a couple of years late on instead of being
Speaker 2:  super early. So I've come down really aggressively on the get the
Speaker 2:  free iPhone 14 and be very happy with it for a while inside of this.
Speaker 12:  I like that. Yeah. And you may have the right cables for
Speaker 12:  your phone, but like what are you gonna encounter in the rest of the world?
Speaker 12:  So yeah, let the dust settle on U S P C for a little bit,
Speaker 12:  you know, get that good carrier deal for the 14 pro I
Speaker 12:  traded in my iPhone 11 for a 13 mini this year. so
Speaker 12:  like I'm all for getting an an older iPhone and just like
Speaker 12:  coasting as long as you can get your money towards it.
Speaker 2:  Just my, my only real advice is don't buy an iPhone mini. That's like whatever
Speaker 2:  you do, do not buy an iPhone mini,
Speaker 12:  Don't be a sicko like me for small phones. R i p
Speaker 12:  Battery life.
Speaker 2:  If you want a phone that's gonna last a few years, don't buy the one with
Speaker 2:  the tiniest battery and worst processor of the punch.
Speaker 12:  But it's so wonderful.
Speaker 2:  I know it does. It just fits, it fits nicely in your hands. It's
Speaker 12:  In my, it fits in my pocket, but yeah, it's settled. Get a free
Speaker 12:  14.
Speaker 2:  There we go. Done. And it is true, I will say if you want a 15
Speaker 2:  wait until like, what would you say early
Speaker 2:  20, 24 and all this stuff starts going on crazy sales anyway. Yeah. And
Speaker 2:  there's a decent chance that whatever free offer you're getting
Speaker 2:  now for the 14, you'll probably get for the 15 at some point. Yeah. So if
Speaker 2:  you can, if you can hold off and really want the 15, but price is the question,
Speaker 2:  would he say wait nine months if you can and you'll probably get it.
Speaker 12:  Yeah. Yeah. I would say hold off, like if the battery's holding up, just
Speaker 12:  keep an eye out for the deals. Hold onto it as long as you can.
Speaker 12:  I think the, the deal I got on the 13 through Verizon
Speaker 12:  was like halfway through this year they just sort of were like,
Speaker 12:  wow, we have these phones. You might, you guys might as well have a free
Speaker 12:  one, so hold on.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I like it. All right Allison, thank you. Let's take a break
Speaker 2:  and then we're get get some more questions.
Speaker 13:  Hi everyone, this is Kara Swisher. And I. Just interviewed Fran Drescher,
Speaker 13:  a K a, the nanny or more Pertinently the president of SAG
Speaker 13:  aftra, which is the actor's union that's on strike. I think you'll wanna
Speaker 13:  hear it. She's got a lot to say. Here's a taste.
Speaker 14:  We stand at a time when
Speaker 14:  big business feels like it's
Speaker 14:  okay to marginalized
Speaker 14:  people and systematically squeeze them
Speaker 14:  out of their livelihood while those at the
Speaker 14:  top are fat cats and the people
Speaker 14:  that are the shareholders and major and minor
Speaker 14:  investors are also getting rich off of the
Speaker 14:  backs of the people that actually are the
Speaker 14:  product.
Speaker 13:  Listen to our full conversation now. Just search for on with Kara Swisher
Speaker 13:  wherever you get your podcasts.
Speaker 1:  Support
Speaker 6:  For this podcast comes from Slack. Some of you might remember work before
Speaker 6:  the internet. Some of you might not. Either way. Work today relies on the
Speaker 6:  internet and if your team hasn't made the switch to Slack, you might find
Speaker 6:  it just as vital a tool for staying connected and getting work done. It's
Speaker 6:  built to make work simpler and more connected. Not to mention more Pleasant.
Speaker 6:  Slack is a productivity platform that connects all your team members together
Speaker 6:  instantly. It's built to help your team with a host of features like
Speaker 6:  huddles for quick check-ins and clips for recording and sharing video.
Speaker 6:  Slack also makes it easy to search and find the right information you need.
Speaker 6:  You can even integrate the apps you use in your normal workflow like your
Speaker 6:  calendar or project management tools so you can stay focused on the work
Speaker 6:  that matters and get more done. So if you wanna make sure your team has all
Speaker 6:  the tools they need to work well then check out Slack learn more at Slack
Speaker 6:  dot com slash productivity.
Speaker 2:  All right, we're back more Hotline questions. We have a couple on
Speaker 2:  Threads because everyone wants to talk about Threads. Neli Patel is here
Speaker 2:  to talk about Threads. Hi Neli. Hey, I love talking about Threads. You're
Speaker 2:  my, you're my Threads guy. This is, this is what we do. So we, we got two
Speaker 2:  emails that are both about Threads, And, I, wanna talk about 'em. So the
Speaker 2:  first one is from Steven. It says the honeymoon phase of Threads will be
Speaker 2:  over soon enough and ads are inevitable. So I ask do you think Threads would
Speaker 2:  do a plus subscription where we pay two to $3 a month to go ad free
Speaker 2:  to sweeten the deal? Threads Plus could also give us extended time to edit
Speaker 2:  more pins and the ability to schedule Threads and masterly slash archive
Speaker 2:  them. Your thoughts please. Basically the question here is like Threads blue
Speaker 2:  question mark
Speaker 15:  Twitter Blue has ads, right? I
Speaker 2:  True.
Speaker 15:  A huge part of the problem for all these companies is they make so much
Speaker 15:  money on ads that paying money to go ad free almost never
Speaker 15:  makes economic sense. But paying money to see slightly fewer ads makes a
Speaker 15:  lot of sense, right?
Speaker 2:  I do think you'd have to pay more than you think, generally speaking to not
Speaker 2:  see ads on the internet.
Speaker 15:  Well it's a weird problem. So the answer to your question Steven,
Speaker 15:  is yes, but not ad free. Yeah, meta is already doing paid
Speaker 15:  verification on Instagram. You can see how they might just extend it
Speaker 15:  and put some features behind a paywall. And I think all these companies
Speaker 15:  are interested in revenue and if they can actually make thread successful,
Speaker 15:  I think Meta is better at saying, Hey, pay us money for features than Elon
Speaker 15:  Musk and Twitter are at this moment in time. But there's just a weird
Speaker 15:  problem in the business model where ad targeting works If you can target
Speaker 15:  someone who's likely to buy something and they're hard to reach, right?
Speaker 15:  That's what sets your ad price. So if you have ads for everybody,
Speaker 15:  that's great. You have a lot of people you're, you're likely to hit who
Speaker 15:  you wanna reach. If you let some people turn off ads, you're letting the
Speaker 15:  people with the most money turn off ads 'cause that's who's gonna pay the
Speaker 15:  money. So you, you like reduce the pool of your ads if you let the people
Speaker 15:  pay money to see slightly fewer ads, you've reduced supply and the price
Speaker 15:  of those ads goes up. So there's just a weird problem in the
Speaker 15:  pricing curve where getting to add free doesn't make any sense, but getting
Speaker 15:  to add light makes a lot of sense. And I bet one of these social networks
Speaker 15:  is gonna figure that out soon.
Speaker 2:  That's really interesting. It also seems like, I feel like there's a weird
Speaker 2:  thing that happens when you get rid of ads or let people pay to get rid of
Speaker 2:  ads where you're sort of tacitly acknowledging that ads are worse than no
Speaker 2:  ads And, I think Meta in particular goes way out of its
Speaker 2:  way to never acknowledge that ads are bad, right? Like it is, it is a foundational
Speaker 2:  belief of that company that ads are good. Yeah. And so I think even the idea
Speaker 2:  of letting you do that and sort of pay for the privilege sends
Speaker 2:  messages that company does not wanna send.
Speaker 15:  Also truly given how Threads is right now, what is an ad free Threads, even
Speaker 15:  me, it's like the brands are there, man. That's true.
Speaker 15:  The commercial messaging is happening there. It's like it's down to whether
Speaker 15:  it can be, you can pay money to target it. Better not right? Whether it's
Speaker 15:  there at all.
Speaker 2:  Can the Nugget account pay money to have even more posts in my feed?
Speaker 15:  Yeah, exactly. Alright,
Speaker 2:  Next one. This email is from Dewey. Dewey says, I find it endlessly
Speaker 2:  fascinating that Threads is a project helmed by a subsection of the Instagram
Speaker 2:  team. Moser, rather than having it be overseen by any other team at Meta
Speaker 2:  or their own product team. Any ideas why it's a product overseen by Instagram
Speaker 2:  and not Facebook or Messenger? I assume it can't be its own team yet because
Speaker 2:  it's still unproven. Do you think that would change if it actually does become
Speaker 2:  a Twitter killer or will it always be under threat of being absorbed in Instagram?
Speaker 15:  That's a lot. That's a, that's like a good decoder question just from a
Speaker 15:  jump. It's just an org chart question. Yeah. You can also ask why isn't
Speaker 15:  it part of Facebook, the combination of Instagram and Threads right now,
Speaker 15:  now is the Facebook newsfeed.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, it really is
Speaker 15:  And and it is just like kind of funny that they've, they've split it apart
Speaker 15:  and made two products instead of Instagram that recapitulates the original
Speaker 15:  product. Yeah, here's what I'll say I, it's part of Instagram because the
Speaker 15:  code base of Threads itself is Instagram, right? So if you look at the version
Speaker 15:  number of the Threads app, I think it's like 2 91 or something and
Speaker 15:  Instagram is at 290. Hmm. It's some number like that don't, the exact number
Speaker 15:  might be wrong, but it's, it's some increment of the Instagram version number
Speaker 15:  because the all underlying code base is Instagram then I think it's a
Speaker 15:  small team inside of Instagram because that's where you can insulate it.
Speaker 15:  If you made it its own team, it would have to sync or swim without
Speaker 15:  the resources of the larger thing. And I think Instagram is where
Speaker 15:  the kids are. Instagram doesn't already have it text posting
Speaker 15:  feature in this way. If you made it part of Facebook, people will be like,
Speaker 15:  I can already post a Facebook. You make it part of Instagram, you get the
Speaker 15:  cooler younger brand and you're adding what feels like a new
Speaker 15:  feature to celebrities who are already using that product in that way.
Speaker 15:  And, I think fundamentally you want, you want that team to be as focused
Speaker 15:  on the product itself and not is this a business? Do we have to
Speaker 15:  add all these other features to make it a business? You're just take what
Speaker 15:  you need from Instagram and and start from there is a much smarter decision.
Speaker 15:  I
Speaker 2:  Also think if you're gonna pick a meta social graph to start with,
Speaker 2:  Instagram is the right one. And we've talked about this on the show, right?
Speaker 2:  But I think my Facebook account is just like a
Speaker 2:  morass of people I haven't talked to in a decade because that's kind of when
Speaker 2:  I stopped using Facebook. But people still sort of actively
Speaker 2:  engage with their Instagram graph in a way that I think a lot of people don't
Speaker 2:  on Facebook, And I don't have data to back this up. But it certainly feels
Speaker 2:  true that if you just wanted to pick a list of people
Speaker 2:  and things and brands, I'm likely to find interesting betting on Instagram
Speaker 2:  as that sort of startup moment is much smarter than betting on Facebook.
Speaker 2:  And I suspect that's true for most of the people. Instagram and Meta would
Speaker 2:  like to have on Threads at this moment.
Speaker 15:  Yeah, Instagram and Twitter for that matter are one to many
Speaker 15:  broadcast, right? You are LeBron James, right. And people follow
Speaker 15:  you. That's true. Yeah. And that's it. Like there's no
Speaker 15:  reciprocal following and Facebook is all supposed to be all about your friends,
Speaker 15:  right? And so you, yeah, you already have that graph and you already have
Speaker 15:  that user behavior that's like, here is where celebrities and brands will
Speaker 15:  talk to me, which is what happens on Instagram.
Speaker 2:  I will say if it hits you know, a billion users, this team will get much
Speaker 2:  bigger and it will probably separate from Instagram in some meaningful way.
Speaker 2:  But I, I suspect that's an org chart thing more than anything. Like most
Speaker 2:  people will notice over time.
Speaker 15:  Yeah I don't know. you know, it's their first from the ground up social
Speaker 15:  network that is successful in quite some time. Yeah. And I since
Speaker 2:  Facebook
Speaker 15:  And I think the fact that it's part of Instagram
Speaker 15:  means that Instagram stays relevant, which is a very important to Facebook.
Speaker 15:  Like what, what, what you don't wanna do is like let billion user social
Speaker 15:  networks quietly die over time. Right? You wanna keep them them alive and
Speaker 15:  keep them relevant and Instagram is the one that has been the most relevant
Speaker 15:  for the longest time next to YouTube.
Speaker 2:  So reels are coming to Threads sometime soon.
Speaker 15:  There's gonna be, I think there, I think they'll get closer together rather
Speaker 15:  than farther apart.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, fair enough. Alright Neli, thank you. Let's get some more questions.
Speaker 2:  Our next question is an email and it comes from, I
Speaker 2:  believe it's pronounced Ade, I'm sorry if I get this wrong. Jen Tui back
Speaker 2:  from vacation. Welcome back to The Vergecast.
Speaker 16:  Hello. Always happy to be here. Best way to restart my working week.
Speaker 2:  There you go. Let me read you this email because I actually think this is
Speaker 2:  a really interesting one and matches a question you And I have talked
Speaker 2:  a little bit about on this show before, but let's just get into it. So the
Speaker 2:  email says I'm in the process of buying a few indoor Security cameras for
Speaker 2:  my home. Nothing too fancy, mostly just for when I'm on holiday or have the
Speaker 2:  cleaning lady come by, which I actually argued by the way is like the perfect
Speaker 2:  way to describe what an in-home security camera should before anyway.
Speaker 2:  As you can imagine this feels a lot like inviting someone into your home.
Speaker 2:  So choosing a brand can be difficult. I have to mention I'm from Europe,
Speaker 2:  so some of the US brands, albeit with seemingly good offers, sadly lack the
Speaker 2:  app support here. Do you have any clear suggestions? I'm mostly concerned
Speaker 2:  on the privacy slash security front then Tai has a bunch more
Speaker 2:  questions about UFI and Xmi in particular. But
Speaker 2:  I think the big question here is like if I'm coming at the camera question
Speaker 2:  from security first, what should I do? What do you think?
Speaker 16:  Yeah, well And I can relate to this question because having just come back
Speaker 16:  from vacation, I did set up a few cameras before I left because
Speaker 16:  normally my recommendation is not to put Security cameras
Speaker 16:  inside your house. Personally, I feel like they're great on the outside,
Speaker 16:  but inside can get a bit dubious unless you follow a
Speaker 16:  few practices and be concerned here about privacy and security.
Speaker 16:  So that the good thing is there are a lot of solutions to this particular
Speaker 16:  problem. The straightforward answer about security and remember, so there's
Speaker 16:  two sides here. There's the privacy and there's the security. Now the security
Speaker 16:  very much focused on which company you buy from. Do you trust
Speaker 16:  their security practices, you know, high profile, well-known
Speaker 16:  companies. Ones that are going are the ones that are under a lot of SEC
Speaker 16:  secure scrutiny. So generally I think you can feel quite
Speaker 16:  comfortable buying from a well-known company.
Speaker 2:  So are you talking about like the, the Apples and Rings and
Speaker 2:  Googles of the world, like the simply safe kind of folks, right?
Speaker 16:  You know, and for Europe in particular, you've got, I think most it's,
Speaker 16:  it's interesting that he said that there were a few that he couldn't go
Speaker 16:  for from America because he's in Europe. A lot of the big security
Speaker 16:  companies, camera companies do come, you can get in both countries. So rings
Speaker 16:  available in both TP links, brands, TAPO and Cassa
Speaker 16:  are available in both Arlo, Google Nest. So you've got a
Speaker 16:  pretty broad option and then you've got UFI and there's also a Cara
Speaker 16:  which is one of the Xmi brands. So there are a lot of good options
Speaker 16:  here. And I would say any of these you know that are from well-known companies,
Speaker 16:  do not go and buy a no-name brand of Amazon for $20 or
Speaker 16:  20 pounds or 20 euros and stick it in your house. That's just not a
Speaker 16:  good idea. But you know, there's a few key things you should look for. You
Speaker 16:  want to always look for a a camera that has two factor of authentication
Speaker 16:  so that if there is any social engineering or hacking or anything
Speaker 16:  going on that you know someone's trying to get into your camera feed, you're
Speaker 16:  getting, you're gonna get an alert or a warning. So that's you know, key.
Speaker 16:  But then the other thing is end-to-end encryption. Especially if you are
Speaker 16:  concerned about the potential for a company to
Speaker 16:  view your videos. Obviously this is one of the big issues that has been
Speaker 16:  around Ring and also Google with the police
Speaker 16:  partnerships and the potential for you know, your footage to be
Speaker 16:  subpoenaed. If that's something that concerns you, end-to-end encryption
Speaker 16:  is something else. You definitely wanna look for security as a whole
Speaker 16:  though. I mean These big companies have security researchers, you know,
Speaker 16:  banging on their doors trying to figure out holes and they should, you know,
Speaker 16:  and fix and patch and that's why if you do get a security camera, always
Speaker 16:  update your firmware, you know whenever there's an option. And most cameras
Speaker 16:  nowadays will have the option to turn on automatic updates so you don't
Speaker 16:  even have to worry about it, it'll just keep updating in the background.
Speaker 16:  But from from a European perspective. And if you want a smart security
Speaker 16:  camera that is entirely private and you know local
Speaker 16:  doesn't go to the cloud 'cause that's kind of the cloud is where you start
Speaker 16:  to enter that attack vector because your data is being streamed
Speaker 16:  outside of your home. There is one really good company that
Speaker 16:  I would recommend, which is Netatmo. Their kind of focus is
Speaker 16:  entirely on privacy and security. There is no cloud involved
Speaker 16:  whatsoever. It's all done locally. It's all processed locally on the device.
Speaker 16:  It is not, does not have as many of the bells and whistles as some of the
Speaker 16:  other cameras might have and it's not as high resolution, it's a slightly
Speaker 16:  older camera. But if all you're interested in is checking on your cleaning
Speaker 16:  lady and the potential of someone coming into your house when you are not
Speaker 16:  there, it's a great, it's got a great feature, it has facial
Speaker 16:  recognition and you can set it so that it will only record if it's
Speaker 16:  sees someone it doesn't know. So it's on all the time, but it will only
Speaker 16:  record when it sees someone it doesn't know or you can set it to only record
Speaker 16:  if it sees your cleaning lady so that it does record your cleaning lady
Speaker 16:  though if you want to record your cleaning lady, you might need to have
Speaker 16:  a conversation with her.
Speaker 2:  Yes, tell your cleaning lady. Yes.
Speaker 16:  So I mean I, and you can also use your own, you can use cloud with
Speaker 16:  an attack mode but it's your own cloud so you can upload to Dropbox or
Speaker 16:  an F T P server or iCloud. It does support HomeKit
Speaker 16:  secure video which would be my next suggestion here. HomeKit
Speaker 16:  Secure video is one option that gives you a cloud, gives you
Speaker 16:  some of the features of cloud video recording but is
Speaker 16:  end-to-end encrypted because all of the device, all of the data that
Speaker 16:  needs to be processed in the cloud, that's why a lot of camera companies
Speaker 16:  send their data to the cloud. So for people recognition or to
Speaker 16:  tell you whether it's a dog or a plastic bag that's caused a
Speaker 16:  emotion alert on your camera with Apple Home Kit secure video that's all
Speaker 16:  processed on your Apple Home Hub. So it's all processed in your home, not
Speaker 16:  in the cloud but you need an iPhone for that. So if You don't have an iPhone
Speaker 16:  home kit, secure video's not not gonna work for you. But Home Kit Secure
Speaker 16:  video does work with a number of different manufacturers including
Speaker 16:  Logitech has a camera, UFI has some cameras that a HomeKit secure
Speaker 16:  video and also a car which is the z AMI brand
Speaker 16:  Eve and Netatmo. So there's quite a few options there.
Speaker 16:  Overall though I think if you are really concerned about
Speaker 16:  security and privacy you want to record locally, that's the thing to look
Speaker 16:  for. So if none of those brands kind of float your boat, there are a lot
Speaker 16:  of brands that you can just record to a micro SSD card on the camera
Speaker 16:  and a Cara is one that has that option. Tapo and Ca Casa
Speaker 16:  also you can do that Google Nest and Ring. There is some local
Speaker 16:  element to those but not as straightforward as just a little micro
Speaker 16:  SSD card wise has that option. Not sure you can, I don't think you can get
Speaker 16:  wise cameras in Europe though. But in terms of a smart home security
Speaker 16:  camera for indoor, as I mentioned, I'm not a big fan of them but one thing
Speaker 16:  I would recommend strongly if you are going to do that is get
Speaker 16:  one, he mentioned getting lots. I feel like that's, you know, it's
Speaker 16:  a little weird just to have cameras all around your house. A good
Speaker 16:  solution is a pan and tilt cam so that you know, you put it in a central
Speaker 16:  place and it can pan and tilt around.
Speaker 16:  So a Kara again has a, a good option there. UFI has
Speaker 16:  one too, a Kara one is really cute, it looks like a little cat and you have
Speaker 16:  the option in the app and there's a number of cameras that have this option
Speaker 16:  to just turn off the camera remotely and it just is little
Speaker 16:  eyes close and the camera rolls away. So that's
Speaker 16:  another good option to look for if for an indoor camera one that you can
Speaker 16:  shut off remotely and automatically have it turn off
Speaker 16:  say when you come home and then turn on when you leave so that
Speaker 16:  way you're not gonna end up with random pictures of you walking around in
Speaker 16:  your underwear. So if there was the concern about security,
Speaker 16:  if there was, you know, you may have bought from a brand that you trust
Speaker 16:  but then they have a major security breach or a data breach, you don't have
Speaker 16:  to worry that your private footage that you care about is
Speaker 16:  likely to be exposed. You've got, you know, hopefully only recorded
Speaker 16:  when you weren't home. So, and most good Security cameras these days have
Speaker 16:  some feature like that that will turn off when you come home, turn on
Speaker 16:  when you leave. The downside of that is if you're at home
Speaker 16:  asleep and someone comes into your house, your camera's not recording.
Speaker 16:  So this is why I like that tap mode one that I mentioned at the beginning
Speaker 16:  because it's always recording it, sorry, it's always scanning, it's always
Speaker 16:  looking but it only records when it sees someone. So, which is
Speaker 16:  a really neat feature.
Speaker 2:  You answered all of my questions. I think the one other thing I was thinking
Speaker 2:  is does it make sense if you're gonna do an indoor camera to
Speaker 2:  have it sort of disconnected from the rest of your smart home system? Because
Speaker 2:  I'm just thinking that is like the most high stakes thing that would be in
Speaker 2:  your smart home. So I almost don't want to connect it to anything
Speaker 2:  else in my smart home just as an another sort of way of walling it
Speaker 2:  off from everything else that if you're gonna have a whole bunch of stuff
Speaker 2:  on a Nest system, I'm like screw that. Buy a ring for this and
Speaker 2:  just run it on a completely separate version of your smart home
Speaker 2:  just to kind of air gap it as much as you can from everything else. Does
Speaker 2:  that make any sense?
Speaker 16:  Well I'm not sure that it would necessarily that your, the camera
Speaker 16:  itself is going to do something to the rest of your smart home I mean, I
Speaker 16:  think the biggest concern about the camera really would be the footage,
Speaker 16:  right? So that's what you don't want people seeing. One thing I have seen
Speaker 16:  people do, especially when you use HomeKit Secure video is so
Speaker 16:  the way HomeKit Secure video works with Apple is you can just put your camera
Speaker 16:  into your Apple Home app and in some cases not use
Speaker 16:  the company's app at all that it came from. But in the case of
Speaker 16:  UFI and the Cara, I believe you have to or at least get most
Speaker 16:  better benefit from using their app as well. But people, a lot of people
Speaker 16:  don't wanna do that, they just want it all processed locally. So what you
Speaker 16:  can do in go into your router and turn off the wifi
Speaker 16:  access for the camera so that it can only go through Apple's
Speaker 16:  servers and there's no chance of it using a separate server.
Speaker 16:  And so that's e especially if you're using local recording or some kind
Speaker 16:  of NAS device or something and you want to know that it's only
Speaker 16:  in your home and it's not being sent off somewhere into to someone's
Speaker 16:  servers, you can, you know, disable its wifi access.
Speaker 16:  That's a pretty, you know, that is somewhat requires a little bit of technical
Speaker 16:  expertise but not a lot. Especially if you have a, a mesh router that gives
Speaker 16:  you the option to pause internet to certain devices. You
Speaker 16:  can also get devices that monitor traffic from your smart
Speaker 16:  home so you could see if a camera was talking to
Speaker 16:  its cloud. So that, that's a good option.
Speaker 2:  Okay, we need to take one more break and then I think we can do a few more
Speaker 2:  questions before we get outta here. We'll
Speaker 17:  Be right back.
Speaker 18:  You are the man who gave them the power to destroy themselves
Speaker 18:  and the world is not prepared.
Speaker 17:  Oppenheimer opens in theaters today. Christopher Nolan's feverishly
Speaker 17:  anticipated film about the brilliant but troubled father of the
Speaker 17:  atomic bomb. Do you guys ever think about dying?
Speaker 17:  Yeah, no I don't wanna talk about Oppenheimer today. You can go back to
Speaker 17:  your regular life or you can know the truth about the universe.
Speaker 17:  The choice is now yours. The first one. Okay ladies,
Speaker 17:  let's do this. And I like the, let's do this
Speaker 17:  flip on those heels fall off your roof. We're having a giant blowout party
Speaker 17:  with planned choreography and a bespoke song and we're gonna sleep over
Speaker 17:  tonight because, because we're girlfriend, boyfriend, it's today. Explain
Speaker 17:  and it's the best day ever and so is yesterday and so is tomorrow. And
Speaker 17:  every weekday at 2:00 PM when we drop a new episode of Today Explained.
Speaker 2:  All right, next up we have a laptop question. Monica Chin is here to answer
Speaker 2:  laptop questions. Hi Monica.
Speaker 20:  Hey
Speaker 2:  I feel bad for just dragging you in here constantly to help people buy laptops
Speaker 2:  but the people need to buy laptops so we're, we're gonna keep doing this.
Speaker 2:  This person did not give us their name I don't think. But let's, let's hear
Speaker 2:  the question real fast.
Speaker 7:  Hey David. Hey rest of The Vergecast. My question, and you
Speaker 7:  probably get a lot of these is, so I have a 2019 MacBook
Speaker 7:  Air, it's got a I five processor, I got the base model, which
Speaker 7:  I think was a terrible idea four years in. So I'm
Speaker 7:  trying to figure out where I'm gonna upgrade computer wise. I have
Speaker 7:  a basic like pc but I'm, I'm on the fence. I like Mac
Speaker 7:  but I just feel like for my money I want something to where it has more
Speaker 7:  processing power. So as a person that's trying to like possibly
Speaker 7:  go back to school, And, I need a little bit more computer with computational
Speaker 7:  capabilities, what MacBook is it that I should go
Speaker 7:  for? And my budget's probably around like I think the Max I could probably
Speaker 7:  do is like three grand. And then PC wise, what
Speaker 7:  options do I have? Like I know you can get a lot of PC for under
Speaker 7:  $2,000, so like in your guys' perspective, what's a good
Speaker 7:  like laptop to go for? 'cause I, I like all the bells and
Speaker 7:  whistles. I do like the damn rainbow keyboards, they're so cool. But
Speaker 7:  I want something to where it works with my lifestyle to where I can do casual
Speaker 7:  stuff. And, I can take it on the go but it also has like good battery
Speaker 7:  life as well. And if I need to do some stuff at Excel, it's full
Speaker 7:  transparency. I am in accountant, it can actually do what
Speaker 7:  I needed to do Anyways. That's a mouthful. I hope you guys are able to
Speaker 7:  answer my question. Thanks and have a great one.
Speaker 2:  This question is a lot And I love it for being a lot but I
Speaker 2:  feel like what this boils down to is kind of like everybody's computer question,
Speaker 2:  which is basically like I need a computer that's like as good at everything
Speaker 2:  is possible. $3,000 is a pretty big budget actually.
Speaker 2:  So I'm curious like let's start on the PC side 'cause I think that's probably
Speaker 2:  the trickier question to answer. Where would you send our friend here?
Speaker 17:  Well
Speaker 20:  What I would actually say is, this is a little bit of a tough question to
Speaker 20:  answer because I don't actually have a great sense of what you're doing
Speaker 20:  with it. And so if I had you in front of me, I'd be asking you like what
Speaker 20:  exactly are you doing? What I get from what you want is Excel. That
Speaker 20:  was like the main thing that you mentioned that you would need like
Speaker 20:  quote unquote computational power for. And for that I would honestly say
Speaker 20:  I mean if you're already using a MacBook Air and you wanna stick with,
Speaker 20:  you wanna be under 2000. If you're, if you're trying to go back to school,
Speaker 20:  you probably want something portable. You're gonna be carrying that to and
Speaker 20:  from school. You want battery life as you mentioned that it's really hard
Speaker 20:  to find on the C PC side. We can into that shortly. But my honest
Speaker 20:  recommendation with the, the only info I have about your, your lifestyle
Speaker 20:  being you need it for spreadsheets. I think you stick with what you know,
Speaker 20:  I think you get the air, I think the M two air like that can do your
Speaker 20:  spreadsheets. Like I had a actually a very similar conversation with my
Speaker 20:  dad about this a couple a couple months ago. 'cause he was like, he's in
Speaker 20:  a similar reason. He's like I need to do spreadsheets. you know, I just
Speaker 20:  dunno if the MacBook Air can do my spreadsheets. And I was like, dad get
Speaker 20:  the MacBook Air, it can do your spreadsheets. He got it, it can do his spreadsheets.
Speaker 20:  He loves it. He has no issue.
Speaker 2:  That is true. And especially if you're coming from a 2019 I five, the
Speaker 2:  jump to the M two is gonna like blow your mind. Yes.
Speaker 20:  That is really slow. If you like have tried, had
Speaker 20:  tried the M two before and like found that it was a limitation. And
Speaker 20:  you, and you were wondering like that might be a case where I'd say,
Speaker 20:  okay, you might wanna think about going up to the M two PRO or M two Max,
Speaker 20:  but that is such a jump in price and it's such a loss of
Speaker 20:  portability. I mean if you're, again, if you're going to school like back
Speaker 20:  and forth, you're going to classes, you're like sitting around the cafeteria.
Speaker 20:  Do you really wanna be carrying that like 16 inch or I mean that's just,
Speaker 20:  it's so much heavier. It's really not that much fun to lug around.
Speaker 20:  I really don't see a reason not to get the air that is sort of what your
Speaker 20:  answer is, is screaming at me
Speaker 2:  That tracks. But let's say in theory we want to go windows
Speaker 2:  here.
Speaker 20:  So if you wanna go windows, it is hard to find battery life on Windows these
Speaker 20:  days. Especially if you're looking for what you call computing power.
Speaker 20:  Like if you, if by that you mean you want something with a discreet G P
Speaker 20:  U for under 2000, my best recommendation is
Speaker 20:  gonna be the Zephyrus G 14. That's a gaming laptop. I know you didn't say
Speaker 20:  you wanna play games, but in all honesty, if you're looking for battery
Speaker 20:  life like that is some of the best you're gonna get. It's like really
Speaker 20:  ironic that's a gaming laptop, but that's just how it is in the current
Speaker 20:  landscape. The Zephyrs D 14 is some of the best, is is one of the
Speaker 20:  few devices that has like real G P U power
Speaker 20:  that also has all day battery life. So that is what I would be looking at.
Speaker 20:  It does not have an R G B keyboard, but it does have a backlit keyboard
Speaker 20:  that you can do some like fun effects with. And you probably can't
Speaker 20:  get this for under $2,000, but if you end up going above that, you
Speaker 20:  can get a lid that has some fun little lights on it that can do kind of
Speaker 20:  cool stuff. So if you're looking for bells and whistles, it does have that
Speaker 20:  option. It is gonna be a little pricier.
Speaker 2:  It did say they like the funny, the fun colors. So get some fun colors.
Speaker 2:  There
Speaker 20:  Are a few laptops as fun as Zephyrs G 14. But again, that model is
Speaker 20:  really, is gonna be a little over the budget that you gave us. But even
Speaker 20:  under that budget, you know, the keyboard is still, it's a fun keyboard.
Speaker 20:  you know, it's got, it's got a fun little font, it's got some fun keys on
Speaker 20:  it. You can get G fourteens that come in different little designs.
Speaker 20:  There's like an Allen Walker model that comes with a DJ deck. There's some,
Speaker 20:  there's some fun special additions that you can, you can look at.
Speaker 20:  They're gonna be a little more expensive. But I think 'cause they're, you
Speaker 20:  might be able to get some for under two grand if you do a little bit of
Speaker 20:  digging on Best Buy.
Speaker 2:  So yeah, I think the more we talk, the more I think you're right that the,
Speaker 2:  the M two air is the safest choice. And I agree that there
Speaker 2:  are, we've definitely reached the point of like, I'd like to be able to ask
Speaker 2:  some follow-up questions because it's like, if you want extra power, it's
Speaker 2:  like, okay, well are you more likely to want that or to want the thing to
Speaker 2:  last, you know, eight or 12 hours. But here is my last question.
Speaker 2:  And I think this, this is important. And I forgot until just now when I was
Speaker 2:  trying to spec this thing out that this matters 13 inch or 15 inch air because
Speaker 2:  now you get to choose.
Speaker 20:  Yeah, that's a, that's a good question. Honestly, the difference in power
Speaker 20:  between them is not huge. Like it's a, there's a, the 15 is
Speaker 20:  like a little than a little better or benchmarks. I don't know if the kind
Speaker 20:  of spreadsheet you're doing is gonna make a huge difference. I think that's
Speaker 20:  honestly, it's gonna come down to how big of a screen do you want for your
Speaker 20:  spreadsheet fair. And you know, there's, there's, there's a
Speaker 20:  non-negligible weight difference between the two as well. So you may wanna
Speaker 20:  factor in, you know, how much are you gonna be carrying this around, you
Speaker 20:  know, on campus or to other places that you go during the
Speaker 20:  day. The 13 inch is certainly more portable
Speaker 20:  if you're gonna be on the move. The 15 inch is not
Speaker 20:  like, it's not not portable, but it is heavier. I'm a little less happy
Speaker 20:  when I have to put in my backpack. There's a little bit of a difference.
Speaker 20:  And so though there's some trade-offs that are ultimately up to your preference.
Speaker 20:  The one other thing, if you're looking at Windows and You don't want, if
Speaker 20:  the ze D 14 is like too clunky for you and you want something a little bit
Speaker 20:  thinner, the other thing to look at would be the Dell X P S 13
Speaker 20:  that is much more on the portability side. That's a very thin, very light
Speaker 20:  one. you know, you have like a backpack full of all your school books and
Speaker 20:  whatever. It's really easy to slide that in. That's gonna be much closer
Speaker 20:  to carrying around a MacBook Air than it is to be carrying around a Zephyr,
Speaker 20:  which is gonna be a little bit thicker. That battery life
Speaker 20:  for me is like close to all day, but not quite all day. For you, it might
Speaker 20:  be different depends on your workload, but that is some of the better battery
Speaker 20:  life you can get as well. It is not close to the battery life they'll get
Speaker 20:  from the MacBook Air, but if you're looking for like a MacBook Air
Speaker 20:  size, but with Windows, that is what I would point you to.
Speaker 2:  Okay. Yeah, I just went in while we were talking. And I specked out a 13
Speaker 2:  inch M two MacBook air with 16 gigs of Ram
Speaker 2:  and a one terabyte s s d 1800 bucks way under
Speaker 2:  your budget. I suspect you will be thrilled with that computer coming from
Speaker 2:  an I 5 20 19 air. Yeah, I think that's the one,
Speaker 20:  Especially if battery life is your priority, that it's, it's gonna be really
Speaker 20:  difficult to beat that combination of like portability and battery
Speaker 20:  life and pretty much any other line for the, with the budget that you have
Speaker 2:  And it will crush your spreadsheets. Don't even worry about it.
Speaker 20:  Like I, I have a MacBook, I use it for spreadsheets all the time. I wouldn't
Speaker 20:  worry too much about it, but you, if you, if you're worried you could add
Speaker 20:  in some extra ram extra extra stuff to make sure that that can
Speaker 20:  handle it. Totally
Speaker 2:  Awesome, Monica, thank you. Appreciate it as always. Thank
Speaker 20:  You.
Speaker 2:  All right, let's get to our next question. Alison, welcome back. Thank you.
Speaker 2:  It's good to be back. We got so many more questions. The people keep having
Speaker 2:  questions about phones. Alison, I love
Speaker 20:  It. I'm here.
Speaker 12:  I'm literally here for it.
Speaker 2:  I love it. All right. You have not heard either of these Uhuh, so let me
Speaker 2:  play you the first one and then we'll go from there. Okay.
Speaker 21:  Hello, this is Trani from India. I just do want to know that I am
Speaker 21:  using a Pixel six A. So is it auto upgrading to Pixel
Speaker 21:  seven A or I will wait for Pixel eight A
Speaker 21:  or nine something. Thank you.
Speaker 2:  We love an upgrade question here on The. Vergecast. Oh,
Speaker 12:  I love it.
Speaker 2:  This is a good one, right? 'cause we just spent a bunch of time saying like,
Speaker 2:  if you have an old phone, here's when you should get a new phone. But this
Speaker 2:  is, this is last year's phone and this year's phone worth the upgrade.
Speaker 12:  I, I say hold onto to the six A unless you are like
Speaker 12:  a wireless charging stand. Hmm. Because that's in my mind, that's
Speaker 12:  the big upgrade with the seven A. Like there's a lot of other stuff,
Speaker 12:  but no, I think that six A is gonna be solid for like
Speaker 12:  a couple more years at least that's my hot take. Don't buy a new phone.
Speaker 2:  I like it. And, I think Google has done a pretty good job of
Speaker 2:  keeping these phones updated for a while. So I think you've, you've got at
Speaker 2:  least another couple of years of solid updates and the thing will
Speaker 2:  continue to work and Google's so invested in the software anyway that it
Speaker 2:  feels like the pixels have been kind of the rare phones that do a good job
Speaker 2:  of getting appreciably better over time. Yeah. And so I I I
Speaker 2:  feel good I'm kind of with you. Yeah, that is good. Stick with the six A,
Speaker 2:  I think it's the right call. Here's hoping Google Caress about the Pixel
Speaker 2:  long enough to make an eight A please. All right, let's get
Speaker 2:  to our next one, which is substantially more philosophical than the other
Speaker 2:  one.
Speaker 22:  Hey guys, this is Mark from Houston. Some comment that David
Speaker 22:  made a, it was like a week ago on Vergecast and he talked about how
Speaker 22:  he felt that the nothing phones too sort of represented
Speaker 22:  a sort of shift back into maybe like the old days of Android where there's
Speaker 22:  a lot of different competition in a lot of different interesting
Speaker 22:  phones. And, I was wondering, I feel like a really big part
Speaker 22:  of what made phones interesting in the mid 2010s were
Speaker 22:  really the fact that we had a ton of like, you know, Chinese phones
Speaker 22:  and even Indian phones. And so I assumed that with a change
Speaker 22:  of administration that we'd maybe see, you know, some sort
Speaker 22:  of movement on that front. But I was wondering are we ever gonna get
Speaker 22:  any phones from Huawei or Xiaomi or APO back here
Speaker 22:  in the US or is that sort of just doomed to never come back?
Speaker 22:  Because I really do feel like with providing an interesting sort of
Speaker 22:  competition here. So anyways, I was just wondering if you guys
Speaker 22:  have any updates or if you guys could maybe show us or talk to us about
Speaker 22:  that.
Speaker 2:  So I like this question in part because it references things that I said
Speaker 2:  on The Vergecast, so congratulations to me. But I think this is really
Speaker 2:  interesting. What I don't wanna do is like make political predictions, right?
Speaker 2:  Because so much of this is wrapped up in, in politics and things change really
Speaker 2:  fast. I would say if you like forced me to guess, I would say the
Speaker 2:  relationships with China are not going to get immediately better. Better.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 12:  But
Speaker 2:  The world changes quickly. Who knows? But I do think one of the things we
Speaker 2:  talk about, I think not enough on this show is the
Speaker 2:  fact that the US as a phone market is so much less
Speaker 2:  interesting in a lot of ways than all of the rest of the markets in the world
Speaker 2:  for exactly the reason that they're describing And. I. Do wonder if
Speaker 2:  you think about it that way, like is it, is it a bummer that we
Speaker 2:  don't get kind of the full breadth of what's out there and is available to
Speaker 2:  us and is there a chance that like more American companies might try to
Speaker 2:  do in this market? What is happening in other markets around the world?
Speaker 12:  I have so many feelings about this. Yeah. Like it is a
Speaker 12:  bummer. There are so many, especially in foldables,
Speaker 12:  like there's so many more options. Thinner, you know,
Speaker 12:  cheaper that we basically have two foldables here and they're
Speaker 12:  expensive is all hell. Yeah. So I think there's a few things
Speaker 12:  going on. Like obviously the relationships with China, And
Speaker 12:  I, I don't see that changing anytime soon either. The,
Speaker 12:  it's also the carriers I think have, yeah, have the
Speaker 12:  manufacturers kind of under their thumb and it's really
Speaker 12:  a bummer. I feel like it just has resulted in like
Speaker 12:  we get the kind of phones that Verizon and T-Mobile and at
Speaker 12:  t think they can sell, you know, at every price point. And
Speaker 12:  that's kind of all there's room for, and you've seen things like even when
Speaker 12:  LG left the mobile space and they didn't have like massive market share,
Speaker 12:  we were kind of like, oh, now's their chanting. Maybe APA will come in here
Speaker 12:  and Samsung just like shut that shit right down.
Speaker 12:  And we are exactly where we were before, but with
Speaker 12:  less lg.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I, I do think it's, I forget about the carrier things sometimes just
Speaker 2:  'cause like I live in the US and I'm sort of used to the way that it is.
Speaker 2:  But it is so unlike the rest of the world in that basically like the
Speaker 2:  way most people buy phones is they walk into their carrier store and they
Speaker 2:  trade in their existing phone and they get a new phone and they leave. And
Speaker 2:  that's, that's why people by and large don't switch ecosystems. It's why
Speaker 2:  people mostly don't change brands. And it's why a couple of companies, namely
Speaker 2:  Apple and Samsung have been able to essentially just corner off
Speaker 2:  the market for themselves. Whereas other places you can just like walk into
Speaker 2:  a store, stick your sim card in and poof you have a new phone.
Speaker 2:  I wish the world worked more like that in the United States, but it really
Speaker 2:  doesn't seem like there's any chance of that getting better. And we even
Speaker 2:  talked about this with Carl Pay, like these companies are
Speaker 2:  desperate to find a way to make like unlocked phones work in the
Speaker 2:  US And I just don't see any way that's gonna happen anytime soon, do
Speaker 2:  you?
Speaker 12:  No, I I think it's a mess for them. And, I sympathize,
Speaker 12:  you know, when coming into the US and trying to like
Speaker 12:  sell an unlocked phone, you know, without the benefit of those
Speaker 12:  carrier deals, the trade-ins that they can do the marketing.
Speaker 12:  Like it is just such an uphill battle and yeah, I'm,
Speaker 12:  I'm rooting for more options in the us And
Speaker 12:  I think the carriers could do better. Like going to a Verizon store is
Speaker 12:  literally like here's the iPhones, here's the Samsung phones, there's
Speaker 12:  a few other phones like over here and ah, it stinks.
Speaker 2:  I agree. Are there any, as you, as you look out across sort of the rest
Speaker 2:  of the world, if you could hand pick a couple of phones to bring to the us
Speaker 2:  does anything come to mind? Is there anything you like lust after as an
Speaker 2:  American that you can't have?
Speaker 12:  Yes. The X Me kind of Flagship phones. I think like
Speaker 12:  the 13 Ultras, the latest one, they have that one inch camera
Speaker 12:  sensor and just fully embrace the
Speaker 12:  like camera ness of the phone. I have this photography kit that
Speaker 12:  you like attach all the stuff to it, like a shutter button. It's, it's
Speaker 12:  fun. I mean, is it the best idea? Is it something a lot of people are gonna
Speaker 12:  buy? No. Right. I would call out Xiaomi, but
Speaker 12:  there's a ton of stuff out there.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, well and that, that exact thing is kind of the thing that I think
Speaker 2:  the US market is missing the most, which is different ideas about phones,
Speaker 2:  right? Like At this point, it's pixels, it's galaxies and it's iPhones and
Speaker 2:  basically those are all the same thing, right? They have slightly different
Speaker 2:  ideas, but they are functionally the same devices, doing the same things
Speaker 2:  the same ways. At this point, And I kind of wish there was somebody
Speaker 2:  out there doing what like Nokia did a bunch of years ago being like, what
Speaker 2:  if we just made an enormous way too big camera and that was your phone.
Speaker 2:  Like is that anything? Or if somebody was like, what if we put a TV antenna
Speaker 2:  on your phone? Is that anything? And then lgs like what if it had wings?
Speaker 2:  Is that anything? And? I. Just so much of that still happens in
Speaker 2:  the rest of the world and we don't get any of it here because everybody is
Speaker 2:  just making these kind of like lowest common denominator. How can we sell
Speaker 2:  three phones to 300 million people kinds of decisions. And
Speaker 2:  the smartphone market is much weirder than us people would
Speaker 2:  know and that kinda makes me sad.
Speaker 12:  Yeah, we're missing out.
Speaker 2:  So let's just all move to Europe. Yeah, we won't get to have Threads, but
Speaker 2:  we'll get to have cool phones.
Speaker 12:  Well that works for me. No one's talking to me on Threads anyway.
Speaker 2:  All right Allison, thank you again, appreciate you coming back.
Speaker 12:  Thank you.
Speaker 2:  Alright, that's it for the show. Thank you to all of my ve friends for helping
Speaker 2:  answer questions. Thanks to everyone who called and emailed and thank you
Speaker 2:  as always for listening. If you have thoughts, questions, feelings or devices
Speaker 2:  you also wanna upgrade, but want to know how to do it, you can always email
Speaker 2:  us at Vergecast at The Verge dot com or keep calling the Hotline 8 6 6 Verge
Speaker 2:  one one. We'll probably do another full Hotline episode before too long
Speaker 2:  because we keep getting these great voicemails and emails, but also we're
Speaker 2:  trying to answer at least one question every single week on the show, so
Speaker 2:  keep 'em coming. Also, speaking of the Hotline, we're getting an episode
Speaker 2:  ready all about cybersecurity and we're gonna do a full on call in show
Speaker 2:  answering your questions. So if you have a cybersecurity thing you can't
Speaker 2:  figure out big, small, whatever, or you have some crazy mystery you
Speaker 2:  can't solve, which is even more fun, call the Hotline eight six six Verge
Speaker 2:  one one or send us a voice memo to Vergecast at The Verge dot com
Speaker 2:  and we'll get back to you if we think we can help. This show is produced
Speaker 2:  by Andrew Marino and Liam James. Brooke Minsters is our editorial director
Speaker 2:  of Audio The Vergecast is The Verge production and part of the Vox Media
Speaker 2:  podcast network. I'm out the rest of the week, but the rest of The Vergecast
Speaker 2:  crew will be back on Friday to talk about all of the big news of the week,
Speaker 2:  including weather. Threads is still gonna be a thing when I get back from
Speaker 2:  vacation. See you then. Rock and roll.