# Transcript
ID: a4b5f264-eb00-436f-9386-72eb97765e3d
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: The great Pixel 8 camera debate
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/8697035540414822973/3210311571309025029/s93290-US-5633s-1696584628.mp3
Description: The Verge’s Nilay Patel, David Pierce, and Alex Cranz discuss the announcement of Google’s Pixel 8 phone, along with the new AI tools that raise lots of questions.
Speaker 4:  Hello and welcome to Our Chest, the flagship podcast of extra
Speaker 4:  large cups and bowls.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, you never know when you need one.
Speaker 4:  No. You always know when you one, which is always, yeah. All right, look,
Speaker 4:  here's what happened before we started the show. David held up his new Ember
Speaker 4:  mug, which is gigantic. It's huge. It's, it's so big. It
Speaker 5:  Weighs so much. It was so much work to hold it up just now,
Speaker 4:  Our own James Vincent, who's currently on book leave again, he
Speaker 4:  wrote an entire book called Beyond Measure
Speaker 4:  about the Pol, essentially the politics and culture of measuring
Speaker 4:  things. This is one of the Verst Verge ideas that anyone has ever had. And
Speaker 4:  it's obviously, and you should go read this book, it's called Beyond Measure.
Speaker 4:  Go read it. And it occurred to me as we were talking about David's
Speaker 4:  comically large electric cup. That's what it is. Let's be
Speaker 4:  honest that I have no idea how much a cup of coffee is like,
Speaker 4:  not price like volume. Right. And David pointed out to me
Speaker 4:  that the word cup has a third additional
Speaker 4:  secret meeting in the context of coffee.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So when you, when you have a coffee maker
Speaker 5:  and you see the lines on the side that's like this many cups of coffee, you
Speaker 5:  would think that would be like a cup, like a measuring cup cup.
Speaker 5:  It's not. It's a coffee cup, which in most cases is
Speaker 5:  defined to be either five or six ounces. So what you're getting
Speaker 5:  is not eight cups measured by mugs or eight cup
Speaker 5:  me measured cups. You're getting eight cups by this random
Speaker 5:  measure of a tiny amount of coffee that no one actually wants.
Speaker 4:  This is another book, a whole other book.
Speaker 1:  How many, how many cup cups of coffee do you
Speaker 4:  This is okay. The problem with the history of Europe, oh boy, is that
Speaker 4:  a bunch of kings got to invent a bunch of Right. And now we just
Speaker 4:  live in their world. King Harold was like, I don't know, it's this many
Speaker 4:  whatever. All I'm saying is you should get extraordinary. The biggest
Speaker 4:  coffee cups you can, the biggest mugs. And then we bought
Speaker 4:  gigantic bowls at our new house. Yeah, they're, they're so big.
Speaker 4:  They make an average amount of soup look like not a lot of soup.
Speaker 1:  You've consumed a lot of soup. You
Speaker 4:  Move into new place, you're like, what? What large format foods when you
Speaker 4:  fill it, can we acquire so we don't have to think about this for the next
Speaker 4:  several weeks
Speaker 1:  When you fill it with ice cream, is there any ice cream left in the carton?
Speaker 4:  I prefer not to answer that question this time. This
Speaker 5:  Makes me think of like, so my wife and I eat cereal as a lot of people do,
Speaker 5:  and her definition of a bowl of cereal is just whatever the
Speaker 5:  size of the receptacle is. So like if you give her, yeah, that's right. Like
Speaker 5:  a relatively small human sized bowl, she'll fill
Speaker 5:  it with the, the You know normal amount of Cheerios, put some milk in and
Speaker 5:  move on with her life. If you give that woman like a bucket, she'll fill
Speaker 5:  the bucket with Cheerios and be like, this is a serving of Cheerios. So like,
Speaker 5:  I love a big bowl. It's, they're, they're better than plates at everything.
Speaker 5:  Including No, just everything. It's just all the things. But if I give
Speaker 5:  my wife a large bowl, she will, she will eat like a deathly amount of
Speaker 5:  Cheerios. And I can't do this.
Speaker 4:  I want you to know there's a trend in plateware where the, the plates are
Speaker 4:  becoming bowls and they're like, they're half bowls. There's a designer out
Speaker 4:  there who invented this who's furious that they're being ripped off.
Speaker 1:  It's fiestaware, my fiestaware bulls. Are you
Speaker 4:  Just, you just randomly said the word fiestaware. It's huge. The bulls are,
Speaker 4:  okay, we gotta stop this. There's actual tech news. I'm just saying if you
Speaker 4:  wanna write the inside story of how plates are becoming
Speaker 4:  bulls there, there's but one publication that will be like, yes, that's correct.
Speaker 4:  Yes. This belongs to us.
Speaker 5:  And if they're temperature regulated like my ember mug, all the better.
Speaker 4:  If your bowls, it's very have wifi in them. Call me.
Speaker 4:  There's a lot of tech news this week, by the way. I'm your friend Neli. Hello.
Speaker 4:  David Pierce is here. Hi.
Speaker 5:  Me and my mug. We're both here.
Speaker 4:  Electric mugs. I drink the coffee too fast. I wanna be, I've always wanted
Speaker 4:  an ember mug and there's just no hope for me. Like
Speaker 5:  Why? Oh, I'm the opposite. I drink the first five sips really fast and then
Speaker 5:  the last two thirds, six and a half hours later, this is why this thing is
Speaker 5:  perfect for me.
Speaker 4:  Alex Francis is here. Yeah,
Speaker 1:  I'm with her Fiesta. I'm I'm, I'm still thinking about the Fiesta wear bowls.
Speaker 1:  They're huge. I've eaten so much. Chill
Speaker 4:  Is Fiesta wear the radioactive ones?
Speaker 1:  The old ones. Okay. I don't think mine are very
Speaker 4:  Good.
Speaker 1:  We'll see you in a couple of months.
Speaker 4:  If You know why I just said is Fiestaware the radioactive ones. That's a
Speaker 4:  little Google adventure for you today. Yeah, that's a good one. That's a
Speaker 4:  little Wikipedia hold that you could fall down on a service we provide here
Speaker 4:  on The Vergecast stuff to Google. You're
Speaker 1:  Gonna have a great time. Welcome
Speaker 4:  To our newest segment. How to Google about old plates. Alright,
Speaker 4:  there is a lot of tech news this week, like absurd amount
Speaker 4:  of tech news. There are some philosophical quandaries. A bunch of people
Speaker 4:  are mad at me on Instagram threads for suggesting that words have meanings.
Speaker 4:  It's a lot. There's just a lot going on. There is The Pixel event that had
Speaker 4:  Android 14 The Pixel Watch two new Pixel Buds price of every
Speaker 4:  Streaming service is going up and the actors are still on
Speaker 4:  strike. Lots going on there. And then we have a
Speaker 4:  deeply hilarious lightning round just of things,
Speaker 4:  just people continuing to make choices. We should obviously start with The
Speaker 4:  Pixel. David, what? What happened to this event? Sure.
Speaker 5:  So this event as ever with Google recently has been
Speaker 5:  absolutely leaked to death. So we kind of knew what was going on coming in,
Speaker 5:  but basically we got two new phones, The Pixel eight and The Pixel eight
Speaker 5:  Pro, which have a lot in common but
Speaker 5:  are differentiated, especially along camera lines. It's a little bit like
Speaker 5:  the way Apple does it, but Google split it in a bunch of ways that I don't
Speaker 5:  think make a lot of sense. But anyway, new tensor chips normal
Speaker 5:  sort of upgrades over time. The screens got better, especially on the, on
Speaker 5:  the eight Pro. But the camera is the thing and we're gonna talk a lot about
Speaker 5:  the camera, so I'll leave that for now. We also got The Pixel watch two,
Speaker 5:  which seems to have much longer battery life, which is awesome. It seems
Speaker 5:  to also have better performance, which is exciting. This seems like
Speaker 5:  kind of The Pixel watch. We knew Google was
Speaker 5:  gonna make after the first one, which is last year's was like cool first
Speaker 5:  try like call us when you've sort of finished the job. This one feels potentially
Speaker 5:  closer to having finished the job. It has some good safety features, new
Speaker 5:  sensors. I think a heart rate thing for the first time or
Speaker 5:  some like zone training in your heart rate, which is a good thing. And then
Speaker 5:  the other one is, if I'm not mistaken, not new Pixel
Speaker 5:  Buds Pros, but new features for The, Pixel, Buds Pro, some cool
Speaker 5:  software stuff to make your calls sound better. There's the conversation
Speaker 5:  ducking thing, which is like when you start talking, it'll lower the volume
Speaker 5:  and turn on transparency mode, which I hate and think absolutely everyone
Speaker 5:  should turn off because it doesn't work on anything. It's a disaster of a
Speaker 5:  feature. Cool idea, bad feature, terrible. Hopefully Google got it right
Speaker 5:  and some Bluetooth super wideband, which is obviously a thing we have to
Speaker 5:  talk about today on the first cast. And yeah, again, just a bunch of new
Speaker 5:  software stuff coming and I feel like software was sort of the story of
Speaker 5:  this event. Like Google still makes phones and still makes watches and still
Speaker 5:  makes headphones, but is increasingly taking all of the stuff that happens
Speaker 5:  on those devices and moving it somewhere else. A lot of the camera
Speaker 5:  stuff that happened is not happening on the camera, it's happening in Google
Speaker 5:  Photos and that's not nothing. And there's a lot of cloud stuff
Speaker 5:  happening and they talked a lot about assistant with Bard and Android
Speaker 5:  14 came out and it's getting generative AI stuff like Google is really leaned
Speaker 5:  into this idea that it can basically make you a decent piece of hardware
Speaker 5:  with a whole lot of stuff happening in the cloud. And that
Speaker 5:  that's the correct balance from now on. And
Speaker 5:  I'm deeply fascinated to see if that turns out to be true.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, and and this is obviously the flip of Apple's approach, right? Where
Speaker 4:  everything is happening locally on the phone and the phone processors are
Speaker 4:  the fastest processors in human history. And how dare you even suggest that
Speaker 4:  other processors may be faster at any time.
Speaker 5:  Yeah,
Speaker 1:  Nothing's faster.
Speaker 4:  Do You know what makes the iPhone Pro Pro? It's really good at games
Speaker 5:  Freight tracing baby. It's the most pro
Speaker 1:  Feature.
Speaker 4:  Very confusing. Google has always kind of walked this line though, right?
Speaker 4:  How much is happening on your phone? How much is happening on a Google service?
Speaker 4:  You know people have been sharing all these home screens lately, and I think
Speaker 4:  David, somebody shared one to you and me on Threads and it was their entire
Speaker 4:  home home screen was Google apps and you're like, You know Android exists.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Wasn't
Speaker 1:  That a coworker of ours?
Speaker 4:  No. I mean I'm sure it's many coworkers of ours are like that, but
Speaker 4:  I think Google recognizes this, that a lot of people have iPhones that are
Speaker 4:  just vessels of Google services and Google can just sell you a phone.
Speaker 4:  That is that thing.
Speaker 1:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I will say it doesn't give me great confidence in Google wanting to
Speaker 5:  continue to make hardware for a long time, but I already
Speaker 5:  didn't have great confidence in that. So whatever
Speaker 1:  I kind of feel like we need to start and by we Google, not
Speaker 1:  us. I think we're pretty realistic about it. Be realistic about the fact
Speaker 1:  that these are always gonna be like the surface. It's always a
Speaker 1:  device to show OEMs what they can do with the, the stuff that's
Speaker 1:  available and the software that's available.
Speaker 4:  I disagree with that.
Speaker 1:  Really fight me nuts.
Speaker 4:  I think that might've been, I mean we've been through 50 rounds of what is
Speaker 4:  a Pixel phone for? That's what the Nexus line was for. Yeah. Like a piece
Speaker 4:  of reference hardware billion years ago that might've been
Speaker 4:  what the first Pixel phones were for. But there's only one
Speaker 4:  o e m in Android world that matters.
Speaker 1:  That's fair.
Speaker 4:  Right? They're Samsung. Yeah. Yeah. And so I, I think the idea that
Speaker 4:  Google needs to show Samsung how to do it is
Speaker 4:  just not reality. I think Google needs to show Samsung that if Samsung
Speaker 4:  screws up or steps out of line, that it will go and get
Speaker 4:  the marketing deal with Verizon.
Speaker 1:  But did it do that to,
Speaker 4:  Well, I think, I think Samsung has stayed in line. Okay,
Speaker 5:  Wait, Neli, go with me here. Google is to Samsung.
Speaker 5:  What binging is to Google like a, a substantially less
Speaker 5:  successful thing that exists both to try and be a good product,
Speaker 5:  but mostly as a check on the other thing, just saying if you blow
Speaker 5:  it, we will come for you.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Only the, the slight difference is that
Speaker 4:  if Samsung didn't exist, Android would not be as important
Speaker 4:  as it is.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, that's fair.
Speaker 4:  At least in this country and in in, in Europe, in
Speaker 4:  India and Africa, like Android is a big deal all on its own.
Speaker 4:  Like my favorite thing about the Indian smartphone market is that like 14
Speaker 4:  phones get released every single week. And people in Android there
Speaker 4:  is expressed very differently. Like Android is globally important. Whether
Speaker 4:  or not Samsung does it in this country, Android doesn't exist
Speaker 4:  without Samsung. That's right. Which is just at, at least in smartphones,
Speaker 4:  that's crazy. Right. And I think a lot of The, Pixel is
Speaker 4:  there to just repeatedly show Samsung,
Speaker 4:  Hey, we can do it too. Right? And so if you pull, if you put ties in
Speaker 4:  on your phone, which they've threatened to do. Yeah. Or you skin the phone
Speaker 4:  too hard, which they have done and like there's a whole history there. You
Speaker 4:  know Google's there. So I, I think The Pixel is just different than the service.
Speaker 1:  So you're saying The Pixel is basically Google just staring Samsung
Speaker 1:  in the eye and saying try it. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Like just to some
Speaker 4:  Extent uncomfortable to some extent. I think they also need a vessel for
Speaker 4:  their services. They wanna show people what it would be like. They also want
Speaker 4:  to compete head on with Apple. Right. There's a, there's a lot there, but
Speaker 4:  what is the thing it accomplishes the most? It's not sales. Right? It's
Speaker 4:  true. It is a lot of interest from phone nerds.
Speaker 4:  It is crazy to me the disproportionate amount of traffic we get
Speaker 4:  on Pixel coverage versus Samsung coverage. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  And I think that's why I think of it like the surface devices. 'cause it's
Speaker 1:  the same thing. Like people care about the surface devices and the way they
Speaker 1:  do not care about a se unless it's appearing in court.
Speaker 1:  But yeah, like, like that's that's really because people really
Speaker 1:  passionately like the Googled devices. Yeah. But it's a very
Speaker 1:  small group of people according to sales. Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 4:  And the answer, right? We are not, we're fully into talking about this is
Speaker 4:  the thing with talking about Pixel. It's more fun to talk about the, the
Speaker 4:  concepts and the ideas embedded in The Pixel line. But there was cool stuff
Speaker 4:  than the phones. There
Speaker 1:  Was cool stuff this time. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I don't know. I mean the thing that really stuck out to me was
Speaker 5:  how much the people who were otherwise primed to like
Speaker 5:  a phone like these did not like it this year. Like typically
Speaker 5:  the, the overwhelming reaction I've seen, and I'm sure this is not true of
Speaker 5:  everybody, and I'm sure there are people who are excited about it, and I
Speaker 5:  think there are cool things worth getting excited about, but like a bunch
Speaker 5:  of people on like the Android blogs were mad about
Speaker 5:  the, the sort of perceived lack of interesting stuff Google did. Here are
Speaker 5:  commenters, were not psyched about this in a big way. The general
Speaker 5:  feeling of this launch that I got was a lot of people kind of
Speaker 5:  being like this. Like that's, they seem like fine phones, but like that's,
Speaker 5:  that's all you got. And I kind of agree like Google made a good phone
Speaker 5:  here that really doesn't seem to make a particularly interesting case for
Speaker 5:  itself outside of some of the camera stuff.
Speaker 4:  And they also raised prices by a hundred bucks.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. It's, it's like a boring looking phone.
Speaker 1:  Extraordinarily boring. But the the Magic Editor thing is cool. Right.
Speaker 1:  All right.
Speaker 4:  We, we, we, the camera is such a six hour, I I
Speaker 1:  Know I wanna just go talk about it.
Speaker 4:  Can you just read the specs of the phone? So we've done, we we've,
Speaker 4:  we've done our job, we've talked
Speaker 5:  Sure, I can do this. Okay. So main things to know. The Pixel
Speaker 5:  eight starts at 700 bucks. The Pixel eight Pro starts at a thousand dollars.
Speaker 5:  They both run Android 14. The Pixel eight has a 6.2 inch
Speaker 5:  screen. The Pixel eight Pro has a 6.7 inch screen that's
Speaker 5:  also a little better. 12 gigs of Ram on the Pro eight gigs of Ram on
Speaker 5:  the eight more storage options in the high end on the pro you can get I
Speaker 5:  think five 12 and a terabyte, which you can't get on The Pixel eight. They
Speaker 5:  both have U S B C. They both do more face unlock
Speaker 5:  stuff than they have in the past, which I think is interesting. Google's
Speaker 5:  like letting you do more with face unlock but didn't really explain if it
Speaker 5:  has made face lock unlock more secure, which I thought was interesting. A
Speaker 5:  million outrageously complicated differences in the
Speaker 5:  camera. Allison Johnson made a spreadsheet of which features are coming
Speaker 5:  to which that even now doesn't make any sense. But basically
Speaker 5:  the Pro has four cameras that you can
Speaker 5:  use. It has the 50 megapixel main camera,
Speaker 5:  48 megapixel ultra wide, 48 megapixel telephoto. And the
Speaker 5:  10 and a half megapixel camera on the front. The Pixel eight has the same
Speaker 5:  main camera. A 12 megapixel ultra wide, no
Speaker 5:  telephoto, and the same selfie cam. And then again, there's a million software
Speaker 5:  features. Fundamentally The Pixel eight Pro is like a dramatically better
Speaker 5:  phone in the way that I think it's kind of like comparing,
Speaker 5:  not like the iPhone Pro and the pro Max, but it's kinda like comparing the
Speaker 5:  base iPhone to the iPhone pro Max. It's like none of the things versus
Speaker 5:  all of the things. And it's a $300 price difference, which I guess You know
Speaker 5:  belies that, but that's essentially the rundown. Like they have the same
Speaker 5:  chip, which has been very important to Google, to have all of this stuff
Speaker 5:  kind of on the same generation of tensor as much as possible to do the AI
Speaker 5:  stuff they wanna do. But then it just gets real chaotic from there. And they
Speaker 5:  come in a bunch of cool colors that are actual colors. Like
Speaker 5:  Google didn't do the thing Apple did and just put like one drop of
Speaker 5:  color dye near the phone and call that a color. They actually colored the
Speaker 5:  phone. It's very exciting.
Speaker 4:  All right, so we talk about the camera. Yeah,
Speaker 1:  Let's talk about the camera Magic editor. Neither
Speaker 5:  Of you were listening to that. Were you, you were just sitting there going
Speaker 5:  shut up so I can talk about the camera. I get it. I was
Speaker 1:  Reading along
Speaker 4:  Along, if we don't, if we don't say the spec, like when I was a little baby
Speaker 4:  gadget blogger, I was told for just get the specs in the price out of the
Speaker 4:  way. And you can say whatever you want, but if you don't deliver those up
Speaker 4:  front, people are gonna get mad. 'cause all anybody cares about, so now you
Speaker 4:  have the specs here of the price I was talking about the camera
Speaker 1:  Magic editor. Magic editor.
Speaker 4:  So this is like a, this is a, I think a watershed moment in these
Speaker 4:  cameras and it isn't at all at the same time.
Speaker 4:  And I, I wanna be clear on that. There's a tension here because of what David
Speaker 4:  said earlier, the features are built into
Speaker 4:  Google's cloud services and their apps. But the
Speaker 4:  way they are marketing this camera, the way they're showing it off on
Speaker 4:  stage, the the the thing they want you to think it can do is
Speaker 4:  lie to you. Like I, there's no other word
Speaker 4:  for it. The camera has generative AI tools
Speaker 4:  not built into it, but parked on the front lawn. Sure.
Speaker 4:  You know what I mean? Yeah. It's like, it's not, it's not, they're not the
Speaker 4:  same. They're not, it's not in the house. Yeah. You know,
Speaker 1:  It's like a Photoshop editor,
Speaker 4:  But you can open the window and and yell at the generative AI tool and it
Speaker 4:  will definitely hear you. Eventually the gap is gonna close. So
Speaker 5:  You're, you're talking about Magic Editor, right? Like essentially there's
Speaker 5:  a lot, a lot of features, but that's the one,
Speaker 4:  That's the one. And in particular in Magic Editor, the one I am talking
Speaker 4:  about is the one where you can take a bunch of frames of people
Speaker 4:  altogether and it will assemble a composite. You can pick the faces of the
Speaker 4:  people that like, I don't care if you lie to me, we'll call it the
Speaker 4:  Skies You know, like whatever, it's green you Yeah. The sky's green.
Speaker 4:  You great. You're you're crazy. Like I know man. Like you have all
Speaker 4:  the right, you, you moved a salt shaker from the left to the right of the
Speaker 4:  picture. That's great. I'm glad that happened For you You know, be you're
Speaker 4:  an artist, you start changing the way people look at
Speaker 4:  each other in photos. You are playing with fire
Speaker 4:  like in the realist way.
Speaker 5:  You're, you're like, you're kidding about the line there. But I actually
Speaker 5:  think the line there is really important and I want you to tease out why
Speaker 5:  that bothers you in the way that the sky doesn't. Because if the, if your
Speaker 5:  fundamental problem is these cameras and their editing
Speaker 5:  software let you lie about what you're seeing in front of you, I
Speaker 5:  think that's like slightly sort of chicken little sky is falling ish
Speaker 5:  about the world. But also, like I can understand that take, I can also understand
Speaker 5:  the take that just says, most people take photos of their family
Speaker 5:  and would like everyone to be smiling. And that's basically fine. I
Speaker 5:  can also see that, but you're trying to find this middle that I don't
Speaker 5:  necessarily know how to find, where it's like changing
Speaker 5:  certain things is fine. Are you okay with the thing where you
Speaker 5:  can like move stuff over in the scene where like if you shot them
Speaker 5:  off center, you can slide them over on the bench to be in the center? Like
Speaker 5:  where does this go from silly changes to like, you're lying
Speaker 5:  to me.
Speaker 4:  I mean first of all, all of it's lying to you. Sure. Like, did this actually
Speaker 4:  happen? Is now a threshold question for
Speaker 4:  smartphone photography. If you look at a photo that came off a smartphone,
Speaker 4:  a good question you can ask is, did this happen?
Speaker 4:  Did this look this way? Sure. We've been doing what is a photo on the
Speaker 4:  show since, for years now, since the first Pixel
Speaker 4:  since the, what's the iPhone 11 did was the first one with H D
Speaker 4:  R and it looked kind of bad You know, like we've been talking about what
Speaker 4:  a photo is for a long time because the, what
Speaker 4:  most people believe a photo to be is you open
Speaker 4:  a shutter, a bunch of light hits a sensor, the shutter closes, and that's
Speaker 4:  the end of that.
Speaker 5:  Right? And the, the goal is how accurately did this capture reality? That's
Speaker 5:  the, like, that's the metric of success,
Speaker 4:  Right? And there's a whole other brand of photography and we can get into
Speaker 4:  it that's like very creative where you are trying to manipulate light and
Speaker 4:  textures and you're proposing people, like all this stuff is happening, you're
Speaker 4:  doing wild edits in Photoshop. But the, the thing that we rely
Speaker 4:  on photography to be is an accurate
Speaker 4:  representation of light in a moment. And that You know those moments can
Speaker 4:  be long or short, you can do long exposure, but whatever, it's like this
Speaker 4:  light occurred, like these things happened and you
Speaker 4:  get to a place with computational photography where it's where it's at even
Speaker 4:  now, before you start moving faces around with ai where you're like, man,
Speaker 4:  we're like right at the boundary of this.
Speaker 1:  I, I think I, I think I know where the boundary is. I think I I think I got
Speaker 1:  it. Yeah, I think so. We've always been able to manipulate,
Speaker 1:  manipulate photos, right? Like you've been able to manipulate photos since
Speaker 1:  the first person took the photograph. Like they were, they were putting
Speaker 1:  fairies in in photos in the 18 hundreds and saying, yeah, it's a real fairy.
Speaker 1:  And it's like, no, it's a person wearing a stupid outfit. What? That's always
Speaker 1:  shocking. I know, but that's always been there. But the, it
Speaker 1:  was hard to do, like in order to do the stuff that you can now
Speaker 1:  do on a phone in Photoshop 20 years
Speaker 4:  Ago, wait, no back up. You're about to make, you're about to make the argument
Speaker 4:  that Google's making, which is like, we just made the tool more accessible.
Speaker 4:  Let me just back up No. Saying up for one second.
Speaker 1:  I'm saying, I'm saying this, the accessibility itself is the line.
Speaker 4:  No, no, no, no. I disagree. You disagree. That's like, that's basically Google
Speaker 4:  slide, to be honest, that's like what Google is saying, right? It's, and
Speaker 4:  it's our piece. I just wanna back up for a second. Even if you stop moving
Speaker 4:  faces around, the thing that we are doing now with basic H D R and
Speaker 4:  phones where you're doing complicated exposure stacking to make
Speaker 4:  things look better is right on the blurry edge of the
Speaker 4:  line because it never looked that way. Right?
Speaker 4:  Like, and like the goal is to make it like look
Speaker 4:  even or even out the tones or expose everything evenly and like, that's not
Speaker 4:  how your eyes work. And like, this is a very philosophical, very abstract,
Speaker 4:  very Vergecast conversation about like, okay, it's a photo
Speaker 4:  and like, it's not, maybe not what you saw or maybe not what old film looked
Speaker 4:  like and You know. We've had Mark LaVoy from The Pixel team on the show talking
Speaker 4:  about what artists The Pixel was meant to evoke. And every year the art,
Speaker 4:  like we've done it and that's just exposure,
Speaker 1:  Right?
Speaker 4:  Right. We've done years of conversation about
Speaker 4:  computational exposure, manipulation, And, what
Speaker 4:  that means for photography and that's smart hdr r and the iPhone and
Speaker 4:  that's pixel's, computational photography and all of that is just,
Speaker 4:  boy, should there be shadows and photos. Yes. And literally
Speaker 4:  years of conversation about the blurry line of computational and
Speaker 4:  photography and ex and exposure. And I still
Speaker 4:  dunno the answer. Like I I I think that's very subjective. I think
Speaker 4:  You know it hit the mainstream. Like the New Yorker, Kyle Chika had a piece
Speaker 4:  in the New Yorker about iPhone photos not looking real and there being
Speaker 4:  backlash against it. That's crazy. The, the, the just exposure,
Speaker 4:  computational manipulation of exposure Okay. Is now a,
Speaker 4:  a mainstream conversation about what photography means. So that, that
Speaker 4:  the line already is blurry before we get to adding various in the 18
Speaker 4:  hundreds. Yeah. Now I'm gonna tell you that inside the new phone, inside
Speaker 4:  The Pixel eight, it is marketed having a tool where you can take a bunch
Speaker 4:  of shots. It won't just stack exposure, it will change people's faces
Speaker 4:  at your discretion to create a reality that never existed.
Speaker 1:  I just
Speaker 4:  Like a thing that never happened
Speaker 1:  And I still see that as Photoshop. I still see that as the exact same
Speaker 4:  Fine. But this is where the accessibility, this is where your thing about
Speaker 4:  accessibility comes in. Yeah. Okay, fine. That's Photoshop. But the
Speaker 4:  camera is marketed as that thing. So I, I spent the morning on the train
Speaker 4:  in coming up with like very silly examples.
Speaker 1:  Go through 'em. Let's hear 'em
Speaker 4:  Like very silly examples.
Speaker 1:  I'm, I'm, so, I talked about fairies. It's okay. Okay.
Speaker 4:  You are at a chiefs game and you see the box
Speaker 4:  with Taylor Swift and Ryan Reynolds and Blake Lively and whoever
Speaker 4:  else. Hugh Jackman. Thank you. Can erase Hugh Jackman from this, please.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, he was there. He was right. Okay. It looks like Travis Kels gonna score
Speaker 4:  a touchdown. So they're all cheering, but then he fumbles in your and they
Speaker 4:  all, they're all sad. Yeah. All right. Well now you can just tweak
Speaker 4:  the faces. So you got happy Hugh. Happy Ryan.
Speaker 4:  Happy Blake. Sad Taylor.
Speaker 1:  But I can do that in Photoshop. You
Speaker 4:  Can do that in Photoshop. But you wouldn't like the
Speaker 4:  accessibility is the thing. Yeah. Like now you can lie more easily right
Speaker 4:  off your phone and send it. Right. Okay. Should there be some
Speaker 4:  norms about whether or not that tool should be widely available to you,
Speaker 4:  to anyone? I think
Speaker 1:  There should be,
Speaker 4:  Should it be built into the camera? Should it be so close to the camera
Speaker 4:  that the camera is marketed? The line is best take uses of
Speaker 4:  photos you did take to get the photo you thought you took. Mm. That
Speaker 4:  is the marketing of this camera. That is the positioning of this camera.
Speaker 4:  And it's like, yes, you can do anything in Photoshop. You could have done
Speaker 4:  this a hundred years ago in Photoshop. But the effort to do
Speaker 4:  it, the effort to lie was high. It was a barrier
Speaker 4:  to entry. So lowering the barrier to entry to
Speaker 4:  now they're not photos, they're just memories. And we all know how infallible
Speaker 4:  memories are. It's like, oh, you're gonna change the very nature of photography
Speaker 4:  to make it so you can't trust any pictures. And in my my mentions on threads,
Speaker 4:  it's a lot of people saying, well, you could never trust pictures.
Speaker 1:  See, that's where I, I'm, I won't put there my
Speaker 4:  Back. Okay. When I say it's a watershed moment in cameras, this is the camera
Speaker 4:  that is making people say you cannot trust pictures.
Speaker 1:  I I don't think that, I think, I don't think, I think there was a bunch of
Speaker 1:  memes about sharks swimming through the streets of Houston that said I
Speaker 1:  can never trust pictures.
Speaker 4:  But those, but those people were like, but that it's like so obviously silly.
Speaker 4:  Yeah,
Speaker 1:  Yeah, that's true.
Speaker 4:  This is like, the camera is just, it will be sold to you
Speaker 4:  so that when you take a bunch of frames of your family, it will
Speaker 4:  synthesize a thing that never happened by
Speaker 4:  design. And that is a selling point of the camera, let me off and the
Speaker 4:  market will not correct this. The market will say, that's great because I
Speaker 4:  want better photos of my family. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  It does feel very like,
Speaker 4:  Let me offer you this other very silly example. I love it. And this is like
Speaker 4:  based on a, a meme that I saw today. I'm
Speaker 1:  So excited.
Speaker 4:  It's really bad. You're you're gonna, can you pre forgive me for this? Okay.
Speaker 4:  It's a camera and it takes a photo and ingests the photo.
Speaker 4:  It processes the photo and throws the original photo away. Yeah. And so it's
Speaker 4:  gone. You can never recover that photo. Yeah. And at the other end, everyone
Speaker 4:  in your photo just has huge boobs.
Speaker 4:  The market buys this, this is the most successful camera in human history.
Speaker 4:  I
Speaker 1:  Would do that all the time. Everyone's got big naturals.
Speaker 4:  I'm just saying
Speaker 1:  Just across the
Speaker 4:  Board. I don't know. I think you probably have some sliders. Look, it doesn't
Speaker 4:  matter. My point is the market does
Speaker 4:  not reject this camera. Like the people of the United
Speaker 4:  States are like, that's the camera we want.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. 'cause big natural
Speaker 4:  Jesus Christ. I should have agreed not to get mad at you.
Speaker 4:  I,
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Sorry David. We're all
Speaker 4:  Judge. No, just like, if you just think about this like people want lies,
Speaker 4:  they want pleasing lies.
Speaker 1:  I didn't realize it gets rid of the old photo. Like
Speaker 4:  No, this is my hypothetical saying.
Speaker 1:  Oh yeah. 'cause like terrifying.
Speaker 4:  This is just a made up example. I have
Speaker 5:  You're also dead wrong about that by the way. Just like that thing you just
Speaker 5:  described. No one want, they're like four horny teenagers on
Speaker 5:  the internet. Who would be psyched about that? There's
Speaker 4:  A Kickstarter for that camera right now. I guarantee you. And I want to cut.
Speaker 4:  All I'm saying is if you But the market isn't gonna correct for truth. I,
Speaker 4:  I made it that example. 'cause it's silly and it honestly, I wanted to see
Speaker 4:  how I should react to it.
Speaker 1:  It's my favorite idea. But
Speaker 4:  Like in general, in the information ecosystem, we are
Speaker 4:  in the, the market. The free market is not like truth
Speaker 4:  is important to us. It's more like pictures of sharks. Yeah. Well,
Speaker 4:  right. And so now you ma you've made this thing. Google
Speaker 4:  has made this thing, the company that wants to organize the world's information
Speaker 4:  has made a camera where right next to it camped out on the front lawn
Speaker 4:  marketing the phone with we will synthesize pictures. That never
Speaker 4:  happened. It never happened. We are gonna make you images that
Speaker 4:  never occurred without a seconds hesitation
Speaker 4:  on how that might go completely sideways for them. I mean,
Speaker 1:  They're not just doing it with photos though, right? Like they're doing it
Speaker 1:  across the board with generative ai.
Speaker 4:  I mean, but this is like, when you talk about the AI apocalypse Yeah. Like
Speaker 4:  the AI misinformation apocalypse is right on their front door. It's on
Speaker 4:  YouTube. Deep fakes are on YouTube. Right. And at the same time, the argument
Speaker 4:  is, well, we're just making, these tools are already available. We're just
Speaker 4:  making them widely accessible to everyone. It's like, yeah, letting people
Speaker 4:  lie at scale is actually, I dunno if you've been around the past five or
Speaker 4:  10 years.
Speaker 5:  Well, and
Speaker 4:  It's, it's, it's something great.
Speaker 5:  It's very funny to watch this happen as you see companies like open AI
Speaker 5:  start to deliberately pull back on the thing that their
Speaker 5:  stuff can do. Like Yeah. OpenAI put out the, the
Speaker 5:  image recognition thing that you can, you can upload a picture to chat G
Speaker 5:  P T and it'll try to sort of guess what you want from it and query it. And
Speaker 5:  the thing you would want from that is the thing that you keep talking about
Speaker 5:  Neli the thing where I'm just like, who is this person that's like, that's
Speaker 5:  the feature. It won't do that. It could do that, but it won't because they
Speaker 5:  know that that's a bad idea. That asking an AI chatbot about
Speaker 5:  a person is a real bad idea. And it's just very funny to
Speaker 5:  watch Google of all companies, the company that is like preaching You know,
Speaker 5:  bold, but responsible. Just pull all of that apart. Wait,
Speaker 4:  Where where in this camera is responsible?
Speaker 5:  Nowhere. That's my point. Yeah. Just full bold. But if
Speaker 5:  Photoshop was doing this and not Google Photos, and it was just as easy and
Speaker 5:  just as good, but you had to pay for a creative Cloud membership to have
Speaker 5:  it, would you have a problem with it? It,
Speaker 4:  So it isn't effectively in Photoshop,
Speaker 5:  It's this much harder in Photoshop, but not that much harder.
Speaker 4:  It's it's that much harder. There's face swap exists on, I
Speaker 4:  You know there's a million of these things that exist, but
Speaker 4:  the image pipeline from camera to editing software to
Speaker 4:  distribution is important. Right. Because the thing you
Speaker 4:  need to trust is the camera and Google is right on the
Speaker 4:  blurry edge. The camera's still fine. The camera's still just doing h D R
Speaker 4:  as far as I can tell. Right. And maybe it's like recovering some detail.
Speaker 4:  But if you just look at how they're talking about the camera, the
Speaker 4:  features in Google, Photos in Google's marketing are
Speaker 4:  integral to the experience of the camera. That's weird.
Speaker 4:  And when I say the line is blurry, yes. And a, on a very basic
Speaker 4:  technical level, some features are in one app and some features are in another
Speaker 4:  app. But then on a much more like
Speaker 4:  intuitive level, Google Photos is the gallery app on your phone.
Speaker 4:  Like, it's just like the, when you look at the photos, it's like, do you
Speaker 4:  wanna edit them? Do you wanna combine these? Like it's driving you towards
Speaker 4:  these choices in a way that having Photoshop
Speaker 4:  is like, I'm intentionally gonna go do this thing. Okay. I don't know. I
Speaker 4:  it's because
Speaker 1:  It's suggesting rather like, like it's removing that intention.
Speaker 1:  That's kind of, it feels like where the issue is, right?
Speaker 4:  You it, it is. Right. Google to its credit. Right Google, I know
Speaker 4:  that they're thinking about this and they've made this choice in another
Speaker 4:  year. Another Android, o e m,
Speaker 4:  which is either less responsible, more aggressive, or however you wanna say
Speaker 4:  it, is gonna build it right into the shutter button of the phone. Right.
Speaker 4:  And they're gonna say, take a bunch of pictures and we will AI generate everyone
Speaker 4:  looking at, at you right away. And, and we will throw away the original
Speaker 1:  And you're gonna look super hot.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. That's the camera that would sell
Speaker 4:  In one, in one specific way. Alex, if that's what you're into. My, my
Speaker 5:  Other question is, I think this, this question of like taking a bunch of
Speaker 5:  photos that exist in order to make one that never did, there is
Speaker 5:  something there that is sort of icky, but if, if that was just saying
Speaker 5:  like if Google said we're gonna do the same thing, but we're gonna treat
Speaker 5:  it essentially as like merging burst mode where we're not going to use a
Speaker 5:  single picture that wasn't captured. We're just gonna use the best Pixel
Speaker 5:  in every part of the photo. From the 10 images that you took, would you still
Speaker 5:  have a problem with that? Every Pixel of that is real. It's just not all
Speaker 5:  at the same time.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Everything happened, but not all at the same time. Travis Kelsey never
Speaker 4:  looked at Taylor Swift, but we've invented a photo. No,
Speaker 5:  That's what I'm saying. Travis Kelsey looked at Taylor Swift, but not at
Speaker 5:  the same moment. Hugh Jackman was also making that funny face.
Speaker 4:  Right. But so now we've now, but now we've created a moment that does, this
Speaker 4:  is dangerous
Speaker 5:  Territory. You're but go with me here philosophically. Go with me here. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  If, if that last step of, we've used all that data cr to create a
Speaker 5:  thing that never happened,
Speaker 1:  But every single bit of that
Speaker 4:  Data, so what you're gring by the way is just, this is just composite photography.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. The number, again, the number of people that I mentioned who are just
Speaker 4:  like recapitulating the history. I, I know, right? I, I know that all these
Speaker 4:  ideas have existed and all these tools have existed before. Right. But if
Speaker 4:  you
Speaker 5:  Take composite photography and make it that easy and that accessible, do
Speaker 5:  you have the same problem with it? Yes.
Speaker 4:  Like, without question. Interesting. Okay. Because your expectations
Speaker 4:  of these images are different. You have to change
Speaker 4:  society's norms and maybe the norm is never trust a
Speaker 4:  photo again. Yeah. Okay. Big decision. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Just putting that out there. Huge decision. Have you been
Speaker 4:  around, have you looked at the internet and how quickly and easily people
Speaker 4:  will believe photos. Okay, I need you instead
Speaker 4:  of tweeting at me to go talk to all of them. Let me know when you're done.
Speaker 4:  Right. Like fine. Like I, that's a huge
Speaker 4:  norm shift in society. It is not as simple as waving it away by saying you
Speaker 4:  shouldn't trust anything. If you would like to get to a place
Speaker 4:  where no one trusts anything, then you should play that all the way out.
Speaker 4:  And so You know the flip side of this is, I think this is fine for creative
Speaker 4:  use. I think this is probably fine for family photos. Like where the
Speaker 4:  stakes of the images are low, probably fine.
Speaker 5:  Which is the vast majority of images. The vast majority
Speaker 4:  Maybe like, I don't know. I just, we, we now create,
Speaker 4:  when you say the vast majority, we create so many photos as a people
Speaker 4:  that like the vast majority of everything in all photos is nothing
Speaker 5:  Fair. But I mean, think about even your own life, right? Like the, the number
Speaker 5:  of pictures in your camera roll. And I suspect this is true of most people
Speaker 5:  that will be viewed by frankly just you and no one else ever,
Speaker 5:  or you and 10 or fewer people ever
Speaker 5:  is Sure. All practically all of them. Yeah. And you're a pretty
Speaker 5:  public person in the scheme of things, right? Like Yeah. Right
Speaker 4:  Now most of the photos in my camera roll are of like light switches that
Speaker 4:  I need to rewire and I just need to remember what colors are going on. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And it's like, boy, I hope The Pixel doesn't lie to me about that. That seems
Speaker 4:  like a fire hazard. Like You know, like whatever. You're, you're not wrong.
Speaker 4:  I'm just saying like, it'd be crazy, right? Like
Speaker 1:  The idea is like You know what that red light like cable, that's not pretty.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 4:  Yellow. What are we, oh, what? Break that up a little bit. Sorry. Black
Speaker 4:  wire. No, no, no. Right. Like it's not gonna do that. Fine. The
Speaker 4:  revolution in photography is that more people use the tool
Speaker 4:  than ever before in phones. Right? That, that's just so you
Speaker 4:  have this like shared understanding, worldwide
Speaker 4:  cultural understanding of how the camera works. First time
Speaker 4:  in human history, that you have had a tool where everyone is using
Speaker 4:  it the same way to make the same thing. And then
Speaker 4:  importantly closing the loop, consuming it on the same device.
Speaker 4:  That piece is really important. We talked about that with the vision pro
Speaker 4:  and spatial photos the other day. Like it breaks a chain for Apple where
Speaker 4:  you're taking pictures on a phone that you can't view. 'cause they're designed
Speaker 4:  for the vision Pro right now with phones, the chain is, the loop is complete.
Speaker 4:  You, you have a tool, you can take photos, you can look at photos other people
Speaker 4:  took on largely the same tool on on your, that's very important. That's a
Speaker 4:  shared. So if you break that for people and you say
Speaker 4:  you understand how unreliable your tool is, right?
Speaker 4:  That you can, you are often using this tool to make things that never
Speaker 4:  happened. Well then you change everyone else's understanding of everyone
Speaker 4:  else's tools. And that is like a long process, a slow
Speaker 4:  process, ideally a very considered process.
Speaker 4:  And like here we are on the doorstep and Google's answer is, well, we put
Speaker 4:  some metadata in it and sort of everyone else's response is, well you could
Speaker 4:  always do this with Photoshop. And it's like, yes, I could always lie.
Speaker 4:  What I did not do is culturally recontextualize the very
Speaker 4:  nature of lying spread across every phone in existence. Sure.
Speaker 4:  And like that's this moment. Like we should just be honest
Speaker 4:  with ourselves. The next phone or the phone after this
Speaker 4:  is gonna have it in the shutter button. And when it's in the shutter button,
Speaker 4:  the camera becomes totally unreliable and unreliable narrator of
Speaker 4:  the events. And we are now just producing memories and not photographs
Speaker 4:  and all of the norms around photos about what is acceptable editing,
Speaker 4:  how much skin smoothing is acceptable. I, I don't know what should,
Speaker 4:  what should people, like people with darker skin tones, what should our complexions
Speaker 4:  look like? All those norms get tossed away in favor of well, what
Speaker 4:  did you want? Yeah. And this camera will not Neli deliver you what you want
Speaker 4:  instead of what is true. I mean,
Speaker 1:  We've been seeing that for a while now in, in phones in China where they
Speaker 1:  would lighten skin and smooth everybody out automatically and you couldn't
Speaker 1:  escape it. I think even one of the early iPhones did that, right? No. So,
Speaker 4:  So this has been a conversation that I've had with the various
Speaker 4:  photography teams. Yeah. All these, again, we've been having this conversation
Speaker 4:  about something as simple as exposure for a long time,
Speaker 4:  like for 10 generations of the phone. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Like exposure, just how bright and light are
Speaker 4:  things. And then you add on top of that skin smoothing And, what you have
Speaker 4:  found, what we have all found, what the major companies have found is
Speaker 4:  the Chinese market and the South Korean market want built-in beauty
Speaker 4:  filters. And the American market thinks that is a moral
Speaker 4:  catastrophe. And it probably is, I don't know. It
Speaker 4:  is. That hasn't doesn't stop the people on TikTok from using them all the
Speaker 4:  time, but like Yeah. Whatever. And so they've had to split the difference.
Speaker 1:  But I'm saying that gives us like a framework as we go into this next
Speaker 1:  phase with Google and, and, and people who follow after Google is we kind
Speaker 1:  of have that framework. We've seen how it happens in China. We've seen how
Speaker 1:  it happens in South Korea. Yeah. To some extent.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. We'll see, I mean like, should, again, this is my point.
Speaker 1:  I mean, I, I, this
Speaker 4:  Is my point about my fake camera. Like the market in this country,
Speaker 4:  the market rejected the idea of aggressive skin smoothing.
Speaker 4:  Right? That's actually like, maybe not what you would've expected.
Speaker 4:  And you have another, you have a counter example with a market in Asian countries
Speaker 4:  actually wanted it. And You know Samsung basically gives it to them.
Speaker 4:  Apple kind of doesn't You know. Like they're, they're like, you can get the
Speaker 4:  apps. Like that's more or less their answer when you ask them like, You know
Speaker 4:  we face two, we see face two and like all this stuff exists. And they're
Speaker 4:  like, you can just get it. We have blue bubbles. We're good. Right? I don't
Speaker 4:  know what the market is gonna say about the camera can swap faces around.
Speaker 4:  I mean, I, I don't, I thought
Speaker 1:  It was kind of terrifying. And there's a video on our TikTok right now
Speaker 1:  of Allison and Becca using it and it's
Speaker 1:  horrifying if You know Allison because her face just keeps switching
Speaker 1:  but her body doesn't change. And you're like,
Speaker 4:  Right. So here's some important caveats to this entire conversation. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  One, we haven't reviewed the phones. I don't know how good this stuff is.
Speaker 4:  I have a sense of how good it is. Two, I've said nothing about like the audio
Speaker 4:  filters where like n video, it just makes people's voices stand out against,
Speaker 4:  I'm like, that's great. You know. Like I maybe I'm morally compromised in
Speaker 4:  that front too, and it's not built into the camera and Photoshop exists and
Speaker 4:  all this stuff and like whatever. I'm just saying there's not a lick
Speaker 4:  of introspection here. There's Google saying we put some shit in the exif
Speaker 4:  data to market as edited. And it's like, guys,
Speaker 1:  Well it's really funny that this is coming from Google who's been very vocal
Speaker 1:  about like, we're doing ai, but Right. And it's like, okay, but you just,
Speaker 1:  how is this any different than the gen like putting out a generative
Speaker 1:  text AI that can just lie. Well, yeah,
Speaker 5:  That's what I keep coming back to during this conversation is like the, the
Speaker 5:  thing we're describing here is what's happening with everything everywhere
Speaker 5:  on the internet, right? Like this idea that it's, we've made it trivially
Speaker 5:  easy to lie to a lot of people is like the story of the social era on
Speaker 5:  the internet. Yes. And first it was easy to lie in a text
Speaker 5:  post and then it was easy to lie by making a website that looked like a news
Speaker 5:  post. And then it was easy to lie because you were associated with the Russian
Speaker 5:  government and now it's easy to lie in photos.
Speaker 5:  So like, I think the, the arc of that is not that different, it's just
Speaker 5:  that it's getting sort of higher fidelity. And we're gonna go through this
Speaker 5:  with video in a very real way at some point very soon too, as
Speaker 5:  all of these image generators get better. I mean, we should be talking about
Speaker 5:  Dolly three and the fact that it's able to do things that look like photos
Speaker 5:  now, like we are now past the point where you can quickly glance
Speaker 5:  at a generated image that is wholly generated and immediately go, oh,
Speaker 5:  that's ai. Like we, we are past that. You can no longer do that unless
Speaker 5:  somebody wanted it to not look like a photo. And all, all of this
Speaker 5:  is I think, wrapped up together. And I think like the means of
Speaker 5:  creation in in Dolly three is in a lot of ways easier than, I
Speaker 5:  don't even have to buy a Pixel to do that. I can just go to a, I go to Bing
Speaker 5:  and I can just do that. Right. So I think yeah, these big questions of like
Speaker 5:  trust and rules, and I think, I think you posted about this earlier, but
Speaker 5:  like I've been going back and rereading like the APS rules about
Speaker 5:  how they do photos and Getty's rules about how they do photos. And like for
Speaker 5:  people who take the kinds of high stake photos that you're talking about,
Speaker 5:  there have always been rules about what you're allowed to edit and how.
Speaker 5:  And basically like you can like crop and you can vignette and
Speaker 5:  that's essentially it. And you can't even really mess with things
Speaker 5:  to make them more beautiful. The idea is like you took the photo, that is
Speaker 5:  what it looked like. We are going to publish that.
Speaker 4:  If you look at the, the New York Times and, and sort of their
Speaker 4:  feature photography, the vignette is out of control because it's,
Speaker 4:  it's the one knob that they can turn.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And so I think you're gonna start to see these folks, like in the same
Speaker 5:  way that we have more and more people being more and more outspoken
Speaker 5:  about things that they're using, like Ja G P T people are coming out with
Speaker 5:  policies about how they do and don't use it. I think you're gonna start to
Speaker 5:  see the same thing with images. I do wonder if the question is going to be
Speaker 5:  like we're going from everything is now possible on a smartphone to like,
Speaker 5:  I wonder if smartphone photos get outlawed from some of these rules
Speaker 5:  over time for exactly the reason you're describing.
Speaker 4:  So you brought up Getty. So You know these high stakes image pipelines. You
Speaker 4:  can't solve it in technology. You have to solve it by getting a bunch of
Speaker 4:  people to agree that this is what will happen. You norms, right? You
Speaker 4:  will do this, you will not do this. So if you are a Getty News
Speaker 4:  photographer, you, you just agree these are the guidelines and all we
Speaker 4:  can really do is crop and all we can really do is maybe a little dodging
Speaker 4:  and burning. I think Getty allows you to remove sensor dust or the AP allows
Speaker 4:  you to remove sensor, but then they're like, but only if it doesn't change
Speaker 4:  the photo. And if you have a question like ask us. So
Speaker 4:  you can't enforce cultural norms in software. You just
Speaker 4:  can't. You can influence them. You can, you can do some stuff, but
Speaker 4:  at the end of the day, it's just a bunch of people that have to agree on
Speaker 4:  how things work. So that's the news side of it. On the creative side, I think
Speaker 4:  it's like wide open. Do whatever you want. Have Photoshop's great. Generate
Speaker 4:  a cat, like have all the time. That's what they, that was the demo they did
Speaker 4:  with us on, on stage at code. Like fine, I think that stuff is exciting
Speaker 4:  on the high stakes. Are you representing the truth to a lot of people?
Speaker 4:  Is Donald Trump looking at the protesters or is he looking at his shoes and
Speaker 4:  did you remove like this matters, right? These like really some of these
Speaker 4:  images really matter what they say. There is an entire like
Speaker 4:  ecosystem of talkers who just look at pictures and tell you what Taylor Swift
Speaker 4:  is thinking. Yep. It matters what the pictures say. Okay. So
Speaker 4:  on those high stakes pipelines, you have to set some rules. So I, you mentioned
Speaker 4:  Getty. Getty, c e o, Craig Peters was on the code stage with me talking about
Speaker 4:  AI last week. I just hit him up and said, Hey, did you look at The Pixel
Speaker 4:  slate? What do you think of it? Would you ever like ban a camera?
Speaker 4:  And he said, he obviously did not answer The Pixel lady. He's like, I haven't
Speaker 4:  played with you yet. He said, we will largely continue to navigate along
Speaker 4:  the following lines within our editorial coverage. This is the
Speaker 4:  editorial coverage at Getti, the news coverage, strict avoidance
Speaker 4:  of any modifications to the image. Camera manufacturers are already making
Speaker 4:  some adjustments to light on the sensor, but we are as strict the image as
Speaker 4:  possible. So that's, that's it. No changes. And then he said
Speaker 4:  within creative, the sort of artistic side of Getty, we allow for a bunch
Speaker 4:  of stuff. He said, I see us allowing things within creative context,
Speaker 4:  but we will not allow misrepresentation. So then my next question to him
Speaker 4:  was, if there's a hypothetical phone
Speaker 4:  that just like aggressively smooth skin outta the box, is that
Speaker 4:  allowed? And he said, we might, there aren't any, we we don't
Speaker 4:  have this problem today, but if things move in that direction, we could.
Speaker 4:  So even like Getty is at the point where they're like, we're watching it.
Speaker 1:  So theoretically they could be like, next Pixel phone. No, you can't submit
Speaker 4:  Phone or whatever. Unnamed You know o e m
Speaker 4:  makes a phone and their big camera feature is like, you, you're always beautiful.
Speaker 4:  I'm not gonna say it. Big naturals, god dammit, You know. Like Getty would
Speaker 4:  be like this, this camera, this pipeline is not acceptable to us. Yeah. And
Speaker 4:  I think just the fact that one, I can ask the c e o of Getty that question
Speaker 4:  and he's like, this is the answer. Like, we are considering it.
Speaker 4:  That's why I'm saying this is a watershed moment. I'm not saying this phone,
Speaker 4:  I'm not saying you need to be outraged about this phone. I'm not saying you
Speaker 4:  shouldn't buy the phone seven years of software updates. You know, buy It
Speaker 4:  seems nice, have a time, but go nuts. Yeah. I'm saying that in the context
Speaker 4:  of what is a photo Google has decided
Speaker 4:  that they don't make photos anymore. That they make memories. That's the
Speaker 4:  quote they gave to Allison Johnson in her interview about with a Google
Speaker 4:  PM about this, these tools. And they're like, these are memories.
Speaker 4:  Mm. And I'm just would remind people that
Speaker 4:  memories are famously fallible, famously unreliable,
Speaker 4:  not actually allowed in many objective contexts where people need to
Speaker 4:  know what happened. Like that's crazy right? To, to make that
Speaker 4:  rhetorical shift. Yeah. It's not to say photos don't lie. It's not to say
Speaker 4:  photos can't be biased. It's not to say photos can't be added. It's this
Speaker 4:  one camera. Okay. We should probably start having a really
Speaker 4:  serious conversation about AI and cameras and how they
Speaker 4:  collide and whether or not we as a culture, as a
Speaker 4:  society expect our photos to be representations
Speaker 4:  of moments in time. Whether we expect cameras to produce that. And if we
Speaker 4:  don't, we don't think that's true, then we should
Speaker 4:  probably have a huge conversation about how we start need to start training
Speaker 4:  children from a young age to never believe their own eyes.
Speaker 1:  I mean, I think we should do that anyway, but
Speaker 4:  Yeah, fine. I mean if you wanna like, look in the end, we're all gonna be
Speaker 4:  in headsets. I'm,
Speaker 1:  I'm have a real seminar for five year olds. It's gonna be great.
Speaker 4:  But, but that's like, those are the stakes. You know, and, and I, I think
Speaker 4:  there's a lot of people kind of like doing nihilism in
Speaker 4:  my mentions that are like, well, nothing was any or anything like this is
Speaker 4:  just, and it's like, no, there's actually stakes. Like the, it means something
Speaker 4:  to give everyone the tool. Yeah. If I was like, I'm just making guns easier
Speaker 4:  to buy, you wouldn't be like, well, everyone's always been able to buy. Like
Speaker 4:  no, it actually means something to give everyone the tool where they can
Speaker 4:  lie at scale and it to brush it off is these aren't photos, these are
Speaker 4:  memories. And if that's what you wanna say, then okay, you haven't made a
Speaker 4:  camera. But it's, it's, I'm not, not like outraged.
Speaker 4:  I'm, we've been doing what is a photo for so long that I'm just like, oh,
Speaker 4:  this is, this is the culmination of my life's work
Speaker 1:  And we're gonna keep going. We got, we
Speaker 4:  Got reviews now, by the way, now I have to buy a Pixel eight. Yeah. Like
Speaker 4:  I have to have one just to be like, this is a watershed. We should all buy
Speaker 4:  Pixel, eights, Pixel eight sails through the roof. And when people are like,
Speaker 4:  why? We're like, because this phone is philosophically important to
Speaker 4:  the nature of imagery, not because it's any good.
Speaker 1:  Honestly. That, that made me wanna go buy one.
Speaker 4:  I mean that, can you imagine if like ver Verizon had a meeting
Speaker 4:  where they're like, Pixel eight sales are through the roof. And they're like,
Speaker 4:  have we done any audience data? And people, and they're like, it's it's,
Speaker 4:  is it battery life? Is it performance? And people are like, no, it's philosophical
Speaker 4:  quandary. Boy, have we gone over? Sorry David, he knew this was happening.
Speaker 5:  I did. I I walked right into this and I'm okay with it.
Speaker 4:  We barely talked about that. The phone has a screen.
Speaker 5:  It does You
Speaker 4:  Know you can pay dollars for it. A hundred more than last year.
Speaker 1:  Tens are three.
Speaker 4:  All right, we'll stop. Can
Speaker 5:  I just say one more cool thing about the, the phones or about the Google
Speaker 5:  announcement and then we should move on. Google did this weird thing where
Speaker 5:  they announced that Bard, the, the l l m powering Bard is gonna be
Speaker 5:  powering Google Assistant. And they did it in this very sketchy way that
Speaker 5:  made it seem like they had like, just thought of this idea five minutes before
Speaker 5:  the end event started. But that's a super big deal.
Speaker 5:  And Alex, you and I were at the Amazon event when they started talking about
Speaker 5:  the putting LLMs underneath Alexa to do more stuff. And
Speaker 5:  I think if, if voice assistants are ever going to be good,
Speaker 5:  this is the moment we're gonna start to see it. And the hope these
Speaker 5:  people have is super high. The case for why this
Speaker 5:  can work and why it can understand context better and why it can be more
Speaker 5:  reactive is real. Like the chat g p t voice stuff is like
Speaker 5:  alarmingly good. And so I think if, if suddenly this becomes baked
Speaker 5:  into Google Assistant in a way that is like accessible and cool
Speaker 5:  and useful and has the same control over your phone and access to the internet,
Speaker 5:  that's all gonna be really cool. They were super sketchy about the announcement.
Speaker 5:  I have no idea how any of it's gonna work or when any of it's gonna come,
Speaker 5:  but I think it could be a really big deal.
Speaker 1:  I'm very excited, especially if it can answer the cup question Neil, I had
Speaker 1:  earlier, like if it knows the difference between the cups for you.
Speaker 1:  Oh my God, it's impossible. God. Game changer.
Speaker 4:  When you ask Google Assistant, like, hey, hey,
Speaker 4:  I'm trying, I'm trying to be kind to the audience. Yeah. When you ask Google
Speaker 4:  Assistant how much is a cup, it's so confidently not useful. Like in
Speaker 4:  the context of a coffee machine, it's just like a cup is an ounce. It's like,
Speaker 4:  no, I know that's not the answer. Yeah,
Speaker 1:  It's gonna give you the real one.
Speaker 4:  Alright, we're gonna take a break. We're gonna come back and we're gonna
Speaker 4:  do another two hours on the conceptual nature of photography.
Speaker 4:  We're not gonna do that, but if you send me but one email asking us to do
Speaker 4:  it, we'll definitely do it. We'll be right back.
Speaker 4:  All right, we're back. There's other stuff at the, at The Pixel event. There
Speaker 4:  was Android 14 got released, there's Pixel Watch two. All that stuff
Speaker 4:  isn't gonna be in the review cycle, so we will go into that stuff in
Speaker 4:  detail when we've actually used it. I just can't resist it.
Speaker 4:  What is a photo? I like still want to, I'm like ready to keep talking to
Speaker 1:  It. Just like we could do another four hours
Speaker 4:  Anytime you want. That's what we, that's why we made the website. Hey,
Speaker 5:  Like guess what? Netflix is more expensive now. Oh
Speaker 4:  My God. All right, pivot. It's to Streaming and Alex talked the whole time
Speaker 4:  here. Alex, what's up with your Plex server?
Speaker 1:  It's, it's doing fine. I watched Top Hat on it this weekend. It was lovely.
Speaker 1:  Nice.
Speaker 5:  Alex. Your pl server is like famous on the internet, by the way. I posted
Speaker 5:  something on Threads the other day basically saying like, the only possible
Speaker 5:  response to the the unending stream
Speaker 5:  of Streaming price hikes is just to delete all your Streaming services and
Speaker 5:  buy box sets of your four favorite TV shows that solves all your problems.
Speaker 5:  And I mean, a dozen different people we're like, or just get on Alex
Speaker 5:  Cranz Plex server.
Speaker 4:  Yeah,
Speaker 1:  Look, it's a, I I worked really hard on that server. I'm not gonna
Speaker 1:  lie. I, I worked really hard when I was unemployed.
Speaker 4:  Are you in like our home lab? There's, oh, we, you gotta get, you got into
Speaker 4:  it. It's gonna be bad. We, we gotta get you like a rack mount sonology situation.
Speaker 4:  Oh God.
Speaker 1:  That's what I want so bad. Yeah, I have to figure out where to put it.
Speaker 1:  But what I'm not gonna be doing is subscribing to Netflix.
Speaker 1:  No, that's not true. I continue to subscribe to Netflix because I
Speaker 1:  I like it and there's a bunch of shows on it I like and I obsessively consume
Speaker 1:  media. But Netflix is, there's a rumor that Netflix is gonna be raising its
Speaker 1:  prices again. It's waiting until after the,
Speaker 1:  the sag after strike is resolved, which everybody
Speaker 1:  on both sides seems pretty confident is gonna happen, happen fairly soon.
Speaker 1:  So that's lovely to hear. The reason it's doing that is not because, oh,
Speaker 1:  they signed all these new contracts and they're spending way more money on,
Speaker 1:  on actors and writers. They're spending a little bit more money on actors
Speaker 1:  and writers, like a fraction Tiny, tiny fraction. The reason is because they
Speaker 1:  were always gonna have to raise the prices. Yeah. Because like
Speaker 1:  0% interest rates are gone and, and you have to pay for things,
Speaker 1:  so they need money. So, so yeah. It's, it's happening
Speaker 1:  again. And, and David and I were talking about this beforehand. We, we've
Speaker 1:  seen a bunch of price hikes this year and, and we're gonna keep seeing some,
Speaker 1:  we saw another one this week. In fact, the ad free version of Discovery Plus
Speaker 1:  is also getting a big price hike. Sorry, David, one of the
Speaker 1:  few people I know that subscribes.
Speaker 5:  It's okay. How are you feeling? I'm fine. We, we have finally moved all of
Speaker 5:  our Streaming to Max, so Okay. We just, we just leave
Speaker 5:  inside of Max Now. Wait,
Speaker 4:  Leave her alone. I said she's fine. She's in
Speaker 4:  elementary school now. She's gonna
Speaker 1:  Let her own Plex server.
Speaker 4:  She's got her own, she's got a little raspberry pie, like a little, a little
Speaker 4:  five-year-olds size. Er, it's
Speaker 5:  Just bluey on the server all day. Just frozen.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, it's just, just Bluey. No, right now we're, it's Minecraft videos
Speaker 4:  on YouTube. She, this kid has taught herself, she's like building Oh wow.
Speaker 4:  In Minecraft. Yeah. And it's all because of Minecraft videos on YouTube kids.
Speaker 4:  And I, it's like, I, I'm worried about it. You know. It's, it's fine.
Speaker 4:  It's like, is my child gonna fall on the radicalization funnel? But like
Speaker 4:  right now it's like she's building houses, so that's
Speaker 1:  Fine. My godson wants to be a dictator because of YouTube. It's fine.
Speaker 4:  Look, there's an argument that we would be better served. He
Speaker 1:  Said he would be a gentle dictator.
Speaker 4:  He'd be like, don't trust photography.
Speaker 1:  He would like you get in early with him, you'll be fine.
Speaker 4:  He'll all the rules. Anyway. Continue. You why wait, everything's on Max.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Have you watched The Naked Show? No.
Speaker 5:  I, it just, naked Attraction is not family friendly for my 10
Speaker 5:  month old.
Speaker 4:  I watched one episode for
Speaker 5:  Journalism.
Speaker 4:  Becky and I were like, sat there and we watched it together just, and we
Speaker 4:  both were like, do you want to, do you wanna keep going? You can stop you,
Speaker 4:  you want going?
Speaker 5:  No, it's okay. Anna and I are currently deep in the ultimatum on Netflix
Speaker 5:  and the Golden Bachelor on Hulu. So like, we'll, we'll get around to Naked
Speaker 5:  Attraction. But the the thing
Speaker 4:  Then don't No, no, no, no, no. Don't run,
Speaker 5:  Run. Yeah. I will say the Golden Bachelor makes me feel a lot of feelings
Speaker 5:  about the world, but that's for a different podcast. The, the Streaming prices
Speaker 5:  thing. So I went back and like I, I made a story stream for us just like
Speaker 5:  compiling all of the recent stories about the price hikes and like,
Speaker 5:  man, it's brutal. It's just everywhere you look, it's just like one, two,
Speaker 5:  $3 more expensive all the time. And I've been
Speaker 5:  trying to figure out there one of two things is happening and I'm
Speaker 5:  trying to figure out which either all of these companies are just testing
Speaker 5:  to see how high they can go. And eventually
Speaker 5:  they're hoping that you'll cancel everybody else and stick around with them,
Speaker 5:  which will make your price flexibility higher for that one platform that
Speaker 5:  you like best. And they'll be able to get away with charging you $30 a piece
Speaker 5:  or everyone thinks ad plus cheap
Speaker 5:  subscription is the future. So they are just going to keep pricing ad-free
Speaker 5:  services through the roof until you go to the ads because they've realized
Speaker 5:  that that's how they're gonna make their money.
Speaker 4:  This is my theory that think
Speaker 5:  That's
Speaker 1:  The one that's the right one. Yeah, that's the one. This entire business
Speaker 1:  was entirely ad dependent until like that
Speaker 5:  15 minutes ago. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Like everybody was onto ads. And it's really, really
Speaker 1:  funny in the last couple of months you've really started to see Netflix take
Speaker 1:  a backseat as it's trying to roll out ads. And Max is taking a backseat as
Speaker 1:  it tries to roll out ads. Max famously like this comes from HBO o that was
Speaker 1:  not a very advertiser heavy, like heavily subsidized place,
Speaker 1:  but a bunch of the other parts of that thing and a bunch of things that David
Speaker 1:  Zalo did before this was very advertising place and you watch
Speaker 1:  like Paramount Plus and everything that they're doing right now and those
Speaker 1:  guys know ads that was c b s. Yeah. Those were, that was like the biggest
Speaker 1:  network and it was really, really good at taking all of your
Speaker 1:  money and, and, and wants to do that again and watching
Speaker 1:  this like sleeping giant slowly get out of bed
Speaker 1:  because he's old. Sorry. No. Watching him slowly get out of bed
Speaker 1:  and like go out and, and, and start to win back all those eyes. As,
Speaker 1:  as this, this whole landscape starts to shift from
Speaker 1:  gotta be on Netflix to gotta have my own service to, oh God, we're just inventing
Speaker 1:  cable again and now we have to figure out what part of cable we are Paramount's
Speaker 1:  gonna crush in this because that's what it's done for years and it knows
Speaker 1:  how to do it.
Speaker 5:  Alex that continues to be your craziest Streaming take. I just want you to
Speaker 1:  Know it's my crazy thing.
Speaker 5:  Paramount Plus is good is your single wildest stance in the
Speaker 5:  Streaming war.
Speaker 1:  But then what did they do this week on TikTok Super?
Speaker 5:  I don't know because who care? Oh, they're the ones who did, okay, nevermind.
Speaker 5:  I take it back. Paramount's good again.
Speaker 1:  See? See, you're seeing it. You're seeing it.
Speaker 5:  You should explain what happened. But you're right. I take it all back. What
Speaker 4:  Did they, okay, so,
Speaker 1:  So Paramount this week uploaded all of mean girls to TikTok, right?
Speaker 1:  And so you can watch it in little sections because that's how everybody's
Speaker 1:  been watching old shows is they'll go on TikTok.
Speaker 4:  No, I've watched so many movies in
Speaker 4:  what is essentially the Plex, Alex's plex server of TikTok.
Speaker 1:  You just watch, I've watched Sully Land
Speaker 4:  That I watched Whiplash at what is obviously two x speed. I also watch, which
Speaker 4:  makes that movie, right? It was everywhere. It was like, oh we're gonna,
Speaker 4:  JK Simmons is gonna be a dick. But super fast. The only one that didn't
Speaker 4:  get me was Inception where I was like, I didn't know what was happening in
Speaker 4:  this movie when I was watching it in real time on a big screen. And I certainly
Speaker 4:  do not know what is happening on TikTok that was
Speaker 1:  So smart of Paramount to do because everybody does it that way. That's the
Speaker 1:  new like TV street. Like you go and you sit in front of your TV and you flip
Speaker 1:  the channel,
Speaker 4:  But they took it down, they took mean girls off at TikTok. It was just a
Speaker 4:  one day marketing style. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  They did it as a one day marketing thing and that's a really smart marketing
Speaker 1:  thing. Like
Speaker 4:  Did they make any money on Paramount Plus? But it's
Speaker 5:  Mean Girls
Speaker 1:  Day. But it was all about the memes. Yeah, it was Mean Girls Day. 'cause
Speaker 1:  October 3rd and that's when he talked to her. It was
Speaker 1:  October 3rd. So I watched that movie a lot.
Speaker 4:  Clearly.
Speaker 1:  I unfortunately,
Speaker 4:  Oh also almost all of the Ocean's movies. Ocean's 11.
Speaker 4:  Ocean's 12 Ocean's almost fully. I think I watched all of Ocean's 11
Speaker 4:  on TikTok.
Speaker 1:  Your F Y P is much nice. Mine was just the s sully
Speaker 1:  landing the plane and then young Sheldon. Oh
Speaker 4:  No, that's worse. Yeah, that's a lot. I watched so much young
Speaker 4:  Sheldon. So mine is people complaining about the lack of
Speaker 4:  switch options for Philips Hu which I, I'm gonna start making these tos.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, it's
Speaker 1:  Like
Speaker 4:  On it and, and like movies
Speaker 1:  Way more entertaining. Yeah. But yeah, I I think, I think Paramount's on
Speaker 1:  to it
Speaker 4:  That this is crazier than the time you said big naturals 50 times. Gotcha.
Speaker 4:  I dunno what naturals,
Speaker 5:  I just like the, the tags we're gonna get on, like
Speaker 5:  everybody does like automated transcriptions of these podcasts and we're
Speaker 5:  just gonna instantly get banned from every podcast platform. Like we're toast.
Speaker 5:  But I think the thing that's so funny about this to me is everybody has discovered
Speaker 5:  how good a business cable was. And, and like a bunch of people have been
Speaker 5:  talking about this recently with the way the economics changed that have
Speaker 5:  led to a lot of the stuff in the writer strike is they made money
Speaker 5:  from you twice. You paid a lot of money for your cable bill and then
Speaker 5:  they showed you ads and that was, that was the deal we made and
Speaker 5:  agreed to for decades. And then a bunch of people thought
Speaker 5:  it was a super good idea to just take one of those revenue streams away.
Speaker 5:  And they did that and it seemed very smart in a time when you could get
Speaker 5:  infinity investment because you just kept showing user growth.
Speaker 5:  And then we come to the last two years and all of a sudden it's like, you
Speaker 5:  have to start making money again. And they're like, well how did we make
Speaker 5:  money the last time? And it's like, oh, by making money twice
Speaker 5:  and they're just going to do the same thing again.
Speaker 5:  Except instead of paying one $70 bill and seeing nine
Speaker 5:  minutes of ads every half hour, I'm gonna pay ten seven dollars bills
Speaker 5:  and see nine minutes of ads every half hour. But the user experience is gonna
Speaker 5:  be worse. We're literally in the middle of rebuilding worse cable and it's
Speaker 5:  starting to drive me totally nuts.
Speaker 1:  Wait, but we don't have to deal with a cable box. I don't know that
Speaker 5:  That's better.
Speaker 1:  Oh, I do. Instead
Speaker 5:  I get to deal with my Roku tv, which sucks.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I just want to Yeah, there's a cable box in there. It's a Roku,
Speaker 1:  It's an Apple tv. It has, that's like go get a better, get better system,
Speaker 4:  Whatever. It's still 95,000 different user experiences. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And a series of video players that are not very good. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  And I think that's what we're like at some point
Speaker 1:  they're gonna have to start reckoning with is right now everybody's big way
Speaker 1:  of getting you on their service is, well we've got this sport or we've got
Speaker 1:  this, this TV show you really wanna watch or this movie you wanna really
Speaker 1:  watch. Max has been very clear about we're gonna sell our stuff.
Speaker 1:  So you're seeing a whole bunch of Max products on Netflix this week. And
Speaker 1:  if you log into Netflix this week, it feels like old school Netflix. You're
Speaker 1:  like, oh, I can watch Dune. Yeah, I can just do that. That's nice.
Speaker 4:  So Casey boy is on stage a code and he was like basically saying what David
Speaker 4:  is saying is, oh, we used to sell our things like a lot of times.
Speaker 1:  And, and that's everybody's wanting to get back to that. They
Speaker 4:  Wanna get back. He called syndication the brass
Speaker 5:  Ring.
Speaker 1:  Syndication was huge. Syndication was what everybody worked
Speaker 1:  for and they haven't had to do it in the last few years. And now they're
Speaker 1:  realizing, wait, no, this is like all the writers and actors realize it.
Speaker 1:  All of the, the directors and producers realize it. Everybody wants to make
Speaker 1:  as many much money as possible, dipping as many times as they can
Speaker 1:  and just going all in on any one like form is
Speaker 1:  dumb. Yeah. The,
Speaker 4:  The big difference with cable and I, it's, I think
Speaker 4:  it's important to say this out loud, there was value
Speaker 4:  pre-internet in paying money for cable. One,
Speaker 4:  it had all this stuff. Yeah. And you couldn't get the stuff at all
Speaker 4:  unless you paid for cable. Like the cable channels were not available to
Speaker 4:  you in any way, shape or form unless you paid for cable two.
Speaker 4:  And I, I think we forget that this is where this industry came from. They
Speaker 4:  were better than antennas. Yeah. Right. The
Speaker 4:  like the, the wild west of the early cable industry
Speaker 4:  was a bunch of people who got in trouble from broadcast networks
Speaker 4:  Yeah. For setting up big antennas and then running wires to everybody's
Speaker 4:  houses. You know they used to call it cable Cat tv, C A T V, it was
Speaker 4:  like community access television. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  That was the good shit.
Speaker 4:  Right. And this, there's like, there was a thing under there where they were
Speaker 4:  like, we will centralize the hard part, which is getting the signal off
Speaker 4:  the broadcast towers and then we'll, we'll make it good.
Speaker 4:  And you were paying for that thing very specifically.
Speaker 4:  Like DirecTV used to advertise that it was higher quality video
Speaker 4:  than cable operators. Right. That's gone. This is gone. It's like
Speaker 4:  no one gives a shit about that part anymore. So the part where you're paying
Speaker 4:  twice is like you're paying for access and then you're getting ads. Like,
Speaker 4:  we should just demand that the access be great.
Speaker 1:  Well, and the other part of this is cable didn't just die because Netflix,
Speaker 1:  like Netflix certainly participated in the death of cable that is still
Speaker 1:  currently happening, but YouTube is a mu was a much bigger impact. Sure.
Speaker 1:  Right. And and YouTube hasn't gone away. YouTube is still here. So these
Speaker 1:  people are all gonna be out here recreating cable, but
Speaker 1:  they still aren't gonna be, they're not gonna get the audience back. The
Speaker 1:  audience is so fractured now. You're not getting that little audience back
Speaker 1:  the days where you could go and watch. I remember like my favorite example
Speaker 1:  is Grey's Anatomy because Grey's Anatomy season two, that was still when
Speaker 1:  cable was really strong and
Speaker 5:  When Grey's Anatomy was still really strong,
Speaker 1:  It's still really strong. Which is terrifying. Mm. No. Like it does well
Speaker 1:  in the Nielsen still. Oh
Speaker 5:  Well sure. It's a bad show, but it still does well.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, yeah, yeah. So like, so the Nielsen's back in like
Speaker 1:  2006, 2007 for most watched episode would be like
Speaker 1:  30 million people tuned in. Nowadays, Grey's
Speaker 1:  Anatomy still a major success, considered a major success for a, B, C still
Speaker 1:  making a lot of money. Average episode gets like 6 million
Speaker 1:  people. And it's, that's good. That's considered good. Like we saw a
Speaker 1:  huge drop off in audience and all that audience went and watched stuff elsewhere
Speaker 1:  and that's not coming back. And that's the thing that the streamers are actually
Speaker 1:  gonna have to reckon with. And I think that's why the prices are gonna keep
Speaker 1:  going up even past where we think is reasonable
Speaker 1:  because they're having to compete with YouTube where everybody makes the
Speaker 1:  content for quote unquote free. That's gonna be hard for them.
Speaker 5:  I think that's right in the sense that there's only like 24 hours in a day.
Speaker 5:  Right. And, and the idea is where are people spending their time? And like
Speaker 5:  the younger you get, the less likely you are to be even spending that time
Speaker 5:  on Streaming services. Like I, I spent a bunch of time this past
Speaker 5:  weekend with my nephews, it was homecoming weekend, so I was like
Speaker 5:  talking to him and all his friends and we're talking about all the stuff
Speaker 5:  they watch and he was like, yeah, I used to like sit and watch tv, but then
Speaker 5:  I realized I was just looking at TikTok the whole time. So now I don't even
Speaker 5:  turn the TV on, I just sit and watch TikTok. And I was like, that is telling
Speaker 5:  my friend like, your second screen is the television. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  This is how I ended up buying a Frame tv. This is like, I, I've
Speaker 4:  talked to people like TV installers and then like some Samsung people
Speaker 4:  who are like, the frame is a hit because people know that it will be off.
Speaker 4:  They're just gonna leave it off. And then I bought one because I
Speaker 4:  was like, it'll be in our bedroom and we'll just leave it off. But I now
Speaker 4:  it's currently our tv. Yeah. And I'm just like, this is not even local dimming.
Speaker 4:  Like why did I buy this tv?
Speaker 1:  I really want one for my bedroom just because it's pretty.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. We're gonna eventually be in the bedroom and You know Becky will watch
Speaker 4:  comedy specials on it. I
Speaker 5:  Have always wondered they like, all of the advertising material you see for
Speaker 5:  the frame is when it's off. And I've always wondered like, is this, is this
Speaker 5:  a good TV when you like turn it on? 'cause at some point you're gonna turn
Speaker 5:  it
Speaker 4:  On. No, I wanna be very clear. No, no. Okay.
Speaker 4:  It's the, the mat screen is like really cool.
Speaker 4:  It's it really cool. And we have one in the other studio here and
Speaker 4:  when it has like art on it with like detail, it's so convincing.
Speaker 4:  So cool. Yeah. And then you turn it on and you're like, all right, it's just
Speaker 4:  one big ass l e d backlight. Like it's 1956
Speaker 4:  viewing angles.
Speaker 1:  How's the bloom?
Speaker 4:  The whole thing is bloom. It's just, there's just like one
Speaker 4:  flashlight behind the Just I,
Speaker 1:  It does not know the color. Black.
Speaker 4:  It's just gray baby. It's gray. Yeah. Why did I watch Whiplash on my phone?
Speaker 4:  Phone can do True Blacks.
Speaker 5:  Well the good news is it's really expensive. So you got that going for you.
Speaker 4:  No, it's not. They're actually, the little ones are cheap. I think this is
Speaker 4:  the other re because it's a cheap panel. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  That's fair. So
Speaker 4:  It's all priced on margin, which means they get discounted like crazy.
Speaker 5:  Okay, fair enough.
Speaker 4:  I, but, but, but I was like, we should buy, I should buy a gallery series
Speaker 4:  LG like a G two. It's real nice, very thin. You can mount it just like a
Speaker 4:  frame, but it doesn't have the math screen doesn't, you can't do the art.
Speaker 4:  I was like, crap, well buy this thing. And then I'm looking at it, I'm like,
Speaker 4:  why did I buy it? Why, why do I have a, a single
Speaker 4:  backlight L L C D in my home?
Speaker 1:  You can put it as a background for your podcast. Right.
Speaker 4:  It's gonna be great when it's on the wall in the bedroom and we never watch
Speaker 4:  it. Yeah. Which is an insane thing to say about a tv. It'll be great when
Speaker 4:  we stop watching it. Just
Speaker 1:  Pictures of Max.
Speaker 4:  It's gonna be pictures of Max and it's gonna look great. Yeah. It's gonna
Speaker 4:  be great at that thing. But as an actual
Speaker 4:  television, it's like Samsung got me again. This is the second time I've
Speaker 4:  bought a Samsung tv 'cause it's beautiful. And I've been like, like what
Speaker 4:  am I looking at and why do I on this? And I'm gonna have it for 15 more
Speaker 4:  years.
Speaker 1:  Gotta go
Speaker 4:  LG. No, we're gonna buy, we're I'm waiting to buy. Okay. I think you can
Speaker 4:  get them now. But the official on sale date is the Sony A 95 L.
Speaker 4:  It's so expensive. It's pretty. But we're gonna, it's gonna be on the wall
Speaker 4:  for 15 years, so I'm like, I I should spend the money. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And it's gonna, it's gonna be great. It's, it better be great because after
Speaker 4:  this frame experience, I don't know if I can take it all. Sorry David.
Speaker 4:  We were talking about the future of Streaming.
Speaker 5:  All I know is I have the, I have a T C L TV back here.
Speaker 5:  It's 40 some inches because I accidentally clicked the wrong button on
Speaker 5:  Amazon. So You know what it is. Is it's fine. It is
Speaker 5:  just fine.
Speaker 1:  I'm, I'm still on my LG. B seven.
Speaker 4:  No, see I have a B six
Speaker 1:  2007. Yeah. Yeah. I
Speaker 4:  Have a B six. Yeah, it's, it's
Speaker 1:  14. Whatever this is years ago. 2017. That's
Speaker 4:  Right. 17. 'cause I bought the B six and 16. Okay. I was like,
Speaker 1:  Wow, my TV's only
Speaker 4:  TV's great, but it's gonna be there forever. I'm like, I should upgrade.
Speaker 4:  I'm like, why spend the money? There's one thing you should spend the money
Speaker 4:  on. It's a nice TV in a, you're gonna have it forever.
Speaker 5:  I do actually agree with that.
Speaker 4:  This is the problem with Streaming is I'd rather talk about the TVs than
Speaker 4:  the content. Good
Speaker 5:  Teaser for Monday's Vergecast, by the way, before we take a break, which
Speaker 5:  we should do, we're, our whole episode is with a person who would like to
Speaker 5:  give you a television for free.
Speaker 4:  Ooh. It's coming. I cannot wait for this episode. That's great. All right.
Speaker 4:  You're right. We should take a break. We should do a lightning round and
Speaker 4:  we should get outta here. And then after this we'll have a bonus round of
Speaker 4:  six more hours talking about the nature of photography. We'll be right back.
Speaker 4:  All right, we're back landing around, we we're like already over.
Speaker 4:  It's craziest episode in a long time. People
Speaker 1:  Sitting in their cars waiting for us to finish
Speaker 4:  The the phone is good. It's a piece of har it's
Speaker 4:  not just a bundle of philosophical quandaries, but it
Speaker 1:  Is also that. But you buy it because it is that. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Speaker 4:  Please. I'm telling you, if you have the money, go to your local wireless
Speaker 4:  carrier and be like, I want to, I want you to mark down that
Speaker 4:  I am buying this phone because it is a philosophical dilemma.
Speaker 4:  I want it move the needle. Right. It's not speed,
Speaker 4:  it's not camera. It's I want to, I want to be horrible at parties.
Speaker 4:  All right. Lightning round, David.
Speaker 5:  Okay. I have two because sometimes I'm allowed to do that. My first
Speaker 5:  one is, it appears we've now seen the entire Humane
Speaker 5:  ai Pin. It was at Paris Fashion Week and Naomi
Speaker 5:  Campbell. And then I think a couple of other people were wearing it on their,
Speaker 5:  on their sort of breast pocket area.
Speaker 4:  Loggerfeld the shit out of this thing. So we
Speaker 5:  Have now seen what it looks like. I think it was John Gruber who described
Speaker 5:  it as an iPhone. You would get in a happy meal.
Speaker 5:  We still don't know anything about what this device does. Their original
Speaker 5:  launch date was the 14th, which is just next week. But there's been some
Speaker 5:  reporting out there that says that has slipped to November. So I'm not exactly
Speaker 5:  sure what's going on there, but we've now seen the Pin. Is it real? Does
Speaker 5:  it do anything? Who's to say? We have had many questions about this for a
Speaker 5:  very long time. I think if they, they had a couple of videos
Speaker 5:  from Paris Fashion Week where it was another one of those like projecting
Speaker 5:  it onto their hands as they were doing stuff, kinds of videos. I have
Speaker 5:  never had so many questions about what something is than I do
Speaker 5:  about this, but I find it deeply fascinating.
Speaker 4:  Again, I just, I'm gonna start with a baseline question. There's a look at
Speaker 4:  our post and we'll go look at the post It's in the show notes. Pull over
Speaker 4:  in your car and I want you to look at the picture of the, of it mounted on
Speaker 4:  the lady's pants. Okay. How much does this thing weigh?
Speaker 4:  'cause it is not pulling on this fabric because
Speaker 1:  She's got her hand in her pockets. No,
Speaker 4:  I don't know. No,
Speaker 1:  That's, she's got her hand in her pockets.
Speaker 4:  You think she's holding it up? She's
Speaker 1:  Ke she's keeping it. She's keeping up Because look at the, that fabric that's
Speaker 1:  not,
Speaker 4:  Have you ever worn so much as like a, a boutin air Yeah. To like
Speaker 4:  high school and you're like, oh, this is kind of saggy. Yeah. Right.
Speaker 1:  Well, you have to think about it.
Speaker 4:  I'm just saying, have you ever anything like has any weight it's gonna pull
Speaker 4:  and here it's not doing. And you think she's pulling that fabric taut?
Speaker 1:  Oh yeah, she's too. She's pulling, pulling it t because you look at the other
Speaker 1:  ones, it's on a, it's on a suede jacket. Yeah. And then it's on this, this
Speaker 1:  white shirt where she's also the
Speaker 4:  Lapel.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. It's on the lapel. And, and and she's also, again, styling imposing
Speaker 1:  herself. And this was all coming from the CAPI show, which caper
Speaker 1:  apparently loves to, to do some little fashion stuff. So like, their, their
Speaker 1:  previous, a recent show was like all the robot dogs. Yeah. Running
Speaker 4:  Around
Speaker 1:  On the stage pretty good. Like my dogs. So like they, they love to do
Speaker 1:  like weird tech stuff. Our reporter Mia Sato
Speaker 1:  is a big fashion nerd. And I was like, oh, Kearny's doing it. She's like,
Speaker 1:  oh, of course it's confirmed. That would do the Humane thing.
Speaker 4:  I still have a number of questions. For example, how do you load contacts
Speaker 4:  into this phone? Is there a phone app? Real, real question. How do you
Speaker 1:  Interact with it?
Speaker 4:  Well, you, you just talk to it with your hand out in front of you. Okay.
Speaker 1:  Well you got no hand.
Speaker 5:  I just, to me it was very funny that this came out the same week that Apple
Speaker 5:  announced it's no longer supporting and repairing the
Speaker 5:  $17,000 Apple Watch. And it's like those two things. It's like the, the
Speaker 5:  beginning of one thing in the end of a very similar thing. It's like
Speaker 5:  you can just see Humane trying to go this like, cool
Speaker 5:  fashiony make this a luxury item route. Which is
Speaker 5:  a thing I think people try to do before they have a product. That's good.
Speaker 5:  I
Speaker 1:  Was like, how did that work for Google Glass?
Speaker 5:  Badly. It works pretty badly for everybody because it
Speaker 5:  turns out it's very hard to make something fashion.
Speaker 4:  I just, I want to take you back to the photo of the lady in
Speaker 4:  the pants. Every time I look at this product, I have more questions.
Speaker 4:  Okay. We've seen how the thing works, right? You can call Bethany,
Speaker 4:  you hold that, where if you have it mounted on your pants,
Speaker 1:  You can see her knuckles,
Speaker 4:  Whatever, whatever it Look, wait aside, I I still don't know
Speaker 4:  how this works. Yeah, I think, I think there's cardboard in the pants is
Speaker 4:  what I'm trying to say. Let's say this is an acceptable mounting position
Speaker 4:  for the Humane eye. Pin
Speaker 1:  Not a dorky one.
Speaker 4:  Well, let's say, let's say this is where they think you should have it. Okay.
Speaker 4:  And you need to call Bethany. Where are you gonna put your hand?
Speaker 1:  You like squatting? Yeah. You're like, you're holding down here. Hand out
Speaker 1:  down here. Yeah. All
Speaker 4:  Right. Hold it out. Just the basics of this product or so confusing to me.
Speaker 4:  Maybe you pop
Speaker 1:  A squat and maybe that's like part of their, their Oh,
Speaker 4:  You're like, you're like doing fashion rap squats
Speaker 1:  And they're like, pop a squat. Call your friend, pop a squat.
Speaker 1:  Check your mail. The
Speaker 5:  Humane marketing slogan is pop a squat. I'm all in.
Speaker 5:  All in.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. All right. Right. I'm just saying look at the photo
Speaker 4:  with the late where it, where it's on the pants and just be like, how would
Speaker 4:  you just run? Just run that to its logical
Speaker 4:  conclusions. You have to, one of the ways in which you use it is
Speaker 4:  that you talk to it and it talks to people. You're,
Speaker 4:  you're just like, and suddenly it's, you're like, da da da. And it's like
Speaker 4:  in French from your, your pants pocket,
Speaker 1:  From your crotch. Basically
Speaker 4:  What happens when you sit down?
Speaker 5:  Does French sound like the adults in Charlie Brown? Is that what that just
Speaker 5:  was?
Speaker 4:  Try not to be racist.
Speaker 5:  All right. Just checking.
Speaker 4:  You know. There
Speaker 5:  You go. My other lightning round thing real fast is this weird
Speaker 5:  kind of scandal about the iPhone 15 overheating. A bunch of
Speaker 5:  people noticed that their iPhone fifteens were getting really hot and draining
Speaker 5:  the battery super fast. Apple basically came out and said it's the App's
Speaker 5:  fault. Which is like a, a delightful follow onto, you're holding it
Speaker 5:  wrong from You know all those years ago, apple then released
Speaker 5:  an iOS update that it said, quote addresses an issue
Speaker 5:  that may cause iPhone to run warmer than expected, but also
Speaker 5:  said that it was the app's fault and a bunch of apps updated and
Speaker 5:  supposedly solved the problem. So what is going on
Speaker 5:  here? It's whatever it is. It seems like it's been fixed. Terrific. The o
Speaker 5:  the overheating problem from some of these apps that were running wild seems
Speaker 5:  to be solved, but whose fault was this and how did they fix it? We
Speaker 5:  don't know. And it's driving me nuts. I just want know what's going. It's
Speaker 5:  very weird. Yeah, because it's a point update that doesn't, like, ordinarily
Speaker 5:  when Apple adds new features in like a 0.0 0.3
Speaker 5:  update, it's like little bug fixes and security updates and stuff. Like this
Speaker 5:  is not a moment you do much, but they named this
Speaker 4:  One. Well 'cause I think they, there was a new cycle around it, but I guess
Speaker 4:  my guess here is that with iOS 17 there came some new frameworks that Instagram
Speaker 4:  and Uber and a bunch of other apps relied on. They updated to use those
Speaker 4:  frameworks that was causing the problem. So they then they
Speaker 4:  could blame it on Instagram. And now here we are where they've updated the
Speaker 4:  thing, they've updated the oss that was maybe using the framework. They've
Speaker 4:  updated the framework that the apps are using. The apps can't do it anymore.
Speaker 4:  It, I, my guess is that it's much more innocent
Speaker 4:  it seems. But it is, it is very funny that they're like, I don't know
Speaker 4:  Instagram.
Speaker 1:  Everybody made a boo booo.
Speaker 4:  All right. Cranz, what's yours?
Speaker 1:  LG is dropping ATSC 3.0 from its TVs next year.
Speaker 1:  I, I got a lot of, a lot of messages about this over the weekend. This is
Speaker 1:  the r
Speaker 5:  I p Cranz story of the week.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. And I think it was telling LG was one of the
Speaker 1:  first to adopt the technology and put it in its TVs and now it's one of the
Speaker 1:  first to drop it. Yeah. And it's because nobody's adopting ATSC
Speaker 1:  3.0. Like the stations aren't, aren't converting over to it.
Speaker 1:  So
Speaker 4:  I had a conversation with a fancy person that code Okay.
Speaker 4:  To about television. Yeah. Not the person who was on stage. Not by Allen,
Speaker 4:  who by the way, a superstar at Code overshadowed by Lindy Yacker You know.
Speaker 4:  But he was like, here's what I'm doing. I'm suing McDonald's 'cause they're
Speaker 4:  racist. Every french fries are racist. Like it was crazy. But he's trying
Speaker 4:  to buy a B, C. Yeah. And one of the reasons that he was trying to buy a B,
Speaker 4:  C is he thinks CS stations are poorly managed this whole thing. He's trying
Speaker 4:  to buy a bbc. So I was at code talking to other people about that
Speaker 4:  conversation 'cause it was a, a superstar performance at code.
Speaker 4:  And they were like, we keep trying to work with local
Speaker 4:  stations to make them better. There's a lot of things we wanna do. Particularly
Speaker 4:  if you're interested in sports rights. All the big streamers are interested
Speaker 4:  in sports. There's a lot of local broadcast deals to, to make any sort of
Speaker 4:  upgrades. So get sports in four K for example, that the local stations
Speaker 4:  have to do it. Yep. And they won't. Yep. They just will.
Speaker 4:  Like there is not a single less innovative part of
Speaker 4:  the media. It's ecosystem.
Speaker 5:  Nobody wants local
Speaker 4:  Television stations.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. And everybody who's been buying up the local stations, 'cause they're
Speaker 1:  largely a couple of different monopolies that that own the majority of them,
Speaker 1:  they have no interest in it. They, they are effectively like private equity
Speaker 1:  did to journalism where they're like, we wanna just buy it and
Speaker 4:  Milk and run the See
Speaker 5:  If we get out. Yep.
Speaker 1:  Run it to the ground. In some places, like in New York, it's, it's pretty
Speaker 1:  expensive to, to put up the towers and stuff for ATSC 3.0
Speaker 1:  and a lot of the, I guess a lot of the buildings around here don't wanna
Speaker 1:  deal with that. Yeah. And deal with the leases and everything like that.
Speaker 1:  So it is, it's challenging. And it was just a bummer. 'cause like at S
Speaker 1:  three, 3.0 is cool technology. Like the technology itself is
Speaker 1:  super, super cool and it could do a lot and it could really,
Speaker 1:  really democratize access to a lot of stuff.
Speaker 1:  But no one wants to actually do it. So it's
Speaker 1:  all just kind of a bummer. And it's like, I don't blame LG for not wanting
Speaker 1:  to spend the time and resources to continue to use this. If nobody's adopting
Speaker 1:  it. Like You know, come back in a couple of years, but by then
Speaker 1:  broadcast TV will effectively probably be dead. So that's a,
Speaker 1:  it's just a real bummer
Speaker 4:  Right at the end. The text.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. It's all over. Yeah. They they got it. They're like, we, we made it.
Speaker 1:  And I was like, yeah, you're 10 years too late. You should have done this
Speaker 1:  a while back.
Speaker 4:  But this is You know there's a, there's a balance here. Remember Vizio took
Speaker 4:  the tuners out of its TVs and there was huge backlash and they put them back
Speaker 4:  because that was
Speaker 1:  Too soon. If they did it now, nobody would care. I think
Speaker 4:  That's right. I know.
Speaker 1:  I mean, well they, Vizio was cheap though. Visio, that, that was the whole
Speaker 1:  get of Vizio is you'd get a really good TV for really inexpensive price.
Speaker 1:  That's changed a little nowadays. But like, so I get like their
Speaker 1:  audience probably did use tuners a lot more than they thought. And most people
Speaker 1:  probably don't actually. Especially LG. Like somebody going out to buy the
Speaker 1:  nice LGS just
Speaker 4:  Right to us. I need to know the answer. We're both guessing. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  We're guessing.
Speaker 4:  I'm, I think a lot of people still use our tuners a lot. Especially our audience.
Speaker 1:  Our audience does that is because I use my tuner still.
Speaker 4:  Yep. That's why I said it. But we, the audience a small asked us to talk
Speaker 4:  about ATSC 3.0. I have a feeling. I
Speaker 1:  Know. I'm sorry guys. I I want it too. No, but I don't think we're getting
Speaker 1:  it
Speaker 4:  At S 3.0 is going to perform upstate. It's gonna be very happy there.
Speaker 4:  It's gonna
Speaker 1:  Be really closed.
Speaker 4:  All right. I have two as well, but my two are like the same thing. Okay.
Speaker 4:  So one X the platform formerly known as Twitter announced
Speaker 4:  deal with Paris Hilton. I would just, I would describe this
Speaker 4:  press release as calorie free. It contains no
Speaker 4:  information. It's a lot of words. It's so many words. And one thing I learned
Speaker 4:  about Lindy Aino is she loves words. Just
Speaker 4:  loves word. And you can see why she was a great marketing executive at N
Speaker 4:  B C. 'cause she had N B C, she had the Olympics.
Speaker 4:  And if you just wanna wander around talking about how people feel inspired
Speaker 4:  and communities are brought together and look at the world and
Speaker 4:  here's a young girl singing and bio Amex, N B C is a great
Speaker 4:  platform to be that personality. When you have Twitter, it's like,
Speaker 4:  what are you talking about? Like, you've got
Speaker 4:  nothing. And it's all the same sort of like hopey changing
Speaker 4:  language for lack of a better word. So anyway, so they've announced the Seal
Speaker 4:  Paris Hilton, which she will, she will post on X, they'll work together to
Speaker 4:  create four original video content programs per year. That includes live
Speaker 4:  shopping across, along with a host of other activations across
Speaker 4:  all surfaces of X. The live shopping experience will allow you to browse
Speaker 4:  through a catalog of products and then click through the site to make a purchase
Speaker 4:  via the in-app browser. Okay.
Speaker 1:  This could be cool. And I'm gonna give you the
Speaker 4:  One caveat unless Paris Hilton is, is actually selling ecstasy
Speaker 4:  on this platform? No, because zero people will buy anything.
Speaker 1:  Paris is super into radios. This is like the, the lore
Speaker 1:  about Paris Hilton. Is she super into to traditional radios? Can I CB
Speaker 1:  radio? What if she one of the stores is just CB radio stuff. All right.
Speaker 1:  That would
Speaker 4:  Be cool. If Paris Hilton does a CB radio activation, that'd be great. X
Speaker 4:  will work to secure brand sponsorship to support each of the activations.
Speaker 4:  So they're paying Paris, they dunno how they're gonna pay for paying Paris.
Speaker 4:  Very good. X will also support amplifying other efforts that
Speaker 4:  1111 Media, which is our company 1111 Media in Paris Hilton will be involved
Speaker 4:  in throughout the year. This is nothing.
Speaker 1:  What is it?
Speaker 4:  So I, the only reason I say it's the same thing is, my second thing is
Speaker 4:  there's a little bit of an existential crisis on threads this week because
Speaker 4:  it's the heart of the N F L season. The government shut down all this stuff
Speaker 4:  is speaker, the house is getting fired. This is the stuff you you would
Speaker 4:  use Twitter for, right? Like these moments
Speaker 4:  where, where Twitter, there was a flood in New York. Do You know what Twitter
Speaker 4:  is great at telling people who don't care about the weather in New York City?
Speaker 4:  What exactly is happening with the weather in New York
Speaker 4:  City? Yeah. And Threads has, I would say flatly failed to live up
Speaker 4:  to any of these occasions as a real-time new service. Yep. I've, I've tried
Speaker 4:  and I'm rooting for Threads. It's the one I use. And everyone gets mad at
Speaker 4:  me when I'm like, threads is bad. They're like, you, what's the one I'm using?
Speaker 4:  It's, I believe in activity. The whole thing. It's not good
Speaker 4:  at this stuff. Watching football with threads is
Speaker 4:  like not watching football with anything. Like, it's the
Speaker 4:  opposite of watching football with threads. So there's been just a lot of
Speaker 4:  consternation about threads and whether they care about news and meta is
Speaker 4:  they, there was a report in the information that Meta is doing, creator councils,
Speaker 4:  whether they're gathering all the creators together to see what they want,
Speaker 4:  which is historically in the history of social platforms,
Speaker 4:  a thing you do right before you die. But You know on the flip side, You know
Speaker 4:  beta does have Instagram and like they, they they have a they have a thing
Speaker 4:  there. Yeah. But You know, it's like they're, they're doing committees to
Speaker 4:  figure out what they should do to, to kick threads back in the gear. And
Speaker 4:  it's like, oh, you don't need a committee,
Speaker 1:  Do news.
Speaker 4:  Just do Twitter. Just do what Twitter was good at, which is realtime news.
Speaker 4:  So I posted on threads. It feels like they need to make every
Speaker 4:  mis they were so burned by news. Adam er was so burned by news. 'cause he
Speaker 4:  used to run the newsfeed. He was so burned by news. They have to try everything
Speaker 4:  else first. And so Missery actually wrote back to me, we are not
Speaker 4:  anti news. News is already in threads. We're simply trying to avoid
Speaker 4:  overpromising and under-delivering to an incredibly powerful group, which
Speaker 4:  is a mistake we've made as a company many times in our past on its face.
Speaker 4:  This is a totally reasonable thing to say. Right? We don't want the news
Speaker 4:  media to think that threads will save it. Yeah. So we're, we're not gonna
Speaker 4:  pretend two things about this. One, one
Speaker 4:  solution to this problem is to make promises and keep them
Speaker 4:  just putting that out there. Little one as, as somebody who lived through
Speaker 4:  something called the pivot to video, not lying about metrics and
Speaker 4:  actually developing revenue.
Speaker 5:  It's a concept
Speaker 4:  I think that would've solved your problems. Yeah. It's just a, it's just
Speaker 4:  a thing. So I get where that's coming from. Like everyone yelled at him,
Speaker 4:  but that's
Speaker 5:  Not what people
Speaker 4:  Asking. But he's saying like, we didn't keep our promises, so we don't wanna
Speaker 4:  make any promises this time. Which is like backwards fine, but like fine.
Speaker 4:  Like I I actually understand it. Yeah. Like one rational
Speaker 4:  response to that is to say, we are making no promises. Sure. Great.
Speaker 4:  The problem is you're using emergency going down. So good luck. Like
Speaker 5:  Forget being burned by making bad decisions. Hasn't meta learned that
Speaker 5:  caring about the news business is actually just all downside.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Right. And th and the regulators are there. And You know Canada's gonna
Speaker 4:  make you pay for links. And an Australian person's going to You know
Speaker 4:  Rupert Murdoch is gonna be like, are you willing to pay for my links? Like,
Speaker 4:  I think like it all happens. There's a law in this country that would make
Speaker 4:  him do, it's all bad, but the product isn't
Speaker 4:  sticky because what you desperately need is people posting about
Speaker 4:  the news on a product that looks like Twitter.
Speaker 5:  Okay. Yes. Except Twitter was a bad business was
Speaker 5:  always a bad business and was a bad product that most people didn't use.
Speaker 5:  And the people who did hated themselves for it. Like, I'm not sure you
Speaker 5:  actually should look at Twitter and be like, let's do what Twitter did. True.
Speaker 5:  That's how you get a bunch of like psychotic maniacs like us who spent
Speaker 5:  all together too much time for 15 years on Twitter. Like,
Speaker 4:  Oh, my brain is healed. I I feel I'm a new person now that I'm not doing
Speaker 4:  it. Mine's like I have threads in my phone. I don't even open it. Like
Speaker 4:  I forgot. I, I like threw a bomb on threads. I was like, this camera's a
Speaker 4:  liar. Like walked away
Speaker 5:  To me. I think, I think the thing threads will regret
Speaker 5:  more than not being more like Twitter is
Speaker 5:  positioning itself against Twitter the way that it has. Yeah. 'cause what
Speaker 5:  they did, mark Zuckerberg and Adam is Harry both did this like
Speaker 5:  aggressively and sort of loudly at the beginning was say in as
Speaker 5:  many words, we want to be better Twitter. And we all kind of internally
Speaker 5:  understand what that might be. And that comes with certain things and certain
Speaker 5:  ideas. If they had just said, we think it's time for a new
Speaker 5:  kind of text-based social networking for sharing.
Speaker 4:  They sort of did
Speaker 5:  A little. But you, if you say the first thing, everybody's gonna hold you
Speaker 5:  the first thing. Right. Like, I, I I think it's true. But also if you, if
Speaker 5:  you say like we, we think the world deserves Twitter that is sanely
Speaker 5:  run. Like in essentially that many words. People are going to hold you to
Speaker 5:  Twitter standards. But I think like meta's out here to build a big thing
Speaker 5:  that makes money and Twitter was never any of those things. Well
Speaker 4:  Actually we have like 10,000 disclosures. So the first one is criticism of
Speaker 4:  the current. Twitter is in no way praise for the previous administration
Speaker 4:  of Twitter. I think it's important to say they were bad at this. There is
Speaker 4:  an argument to be made now. I think that that
Speaker 4:  was the best. It could be sort of chaotic, horrible.
Speaker 4:  Right. Was like the best.
Speaker 5:  It certainly was the best it has been. Yeah. Maybe,
Speaker 4:  Maybe they had stumbled into a sort of steady state of misery.
Speaker 4:  Like, I don't know. Maybe. So I mean like the, this is a company that sold
Speaker 4:  itself for $44 billion at 54, 20 a share. 'cause it
Speaker 4:  could not figure out a way to get to 54 20 a share on
Speaker 4:  the open market. Like they're like, I don't know. That seems high. Take the
Speaker 4:  money. Like we got nothing like our, we not, is it, it we're, we're gonna
Speaker 4:  let more people tweet like whatever. And
Speaker 5:  Now the new report said that it's worth $8 billion. So everybody's doing
Speaker 5:  great over there.
Speaker 4:  So there's I just that. And then the other dis discussion we talked about
Speaker 4:  Streaming and cable. So Comcast and invest in our company. Whatever. They
Speaker 4:  don't, they're not into me. We didn't say news. I'm I'm a Netflix producer.
Speaker 4:  That's a real thing. That's true. I have at t as my personal phone service.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I, I Verizon. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Alex Cranz watches every Star Trek show on Paramount Plus it's
Speaker 4:  True broadcast tv. RF energy is flowing through our bodies right
Speaker 4:  now.
Speaker 1:  That's
Speaker 4:  A real thing that's happening to you too.
Speaker 1:  Grey's Anatomy's going right now. Hey
Speaker 4:  Look that the, the five G alert went off. Huh? All of
Speaker 4:  you are Aaron Rogers. Now I wonder to saw, I dunno what that means, but it
Speaker 4:  sounds great. Come back around to threads. I'm just saying if they had solved
Speaker 4:  the smallest problem, f they're all I know a bunch of them are F one fans.
Speaker 4:  'cause I see them posting about f one days after they've posted because of
Speaker 4:  the algorithmic feed. But I see 'em doing it. If they had just solved, we
Speaker 4:  wanna make this great, they, they would've solved it. They wanna make it
Speaker 4:  great for watching football. The problem is that solving those
Speaker 4:  problems necessarily makes you great at, oh, there's a government shutdown,
Speaker 4:  liming, oh, the speaker of the house got fired or whatever. Right. And that
Speaker 4:  means they're good at news. And I don't think that they have a plan to square
Speaker 4:  that circle. It cannot be that a bunch of famous, you, you're gonna pay
Speaker 4:  Paris Hilton some money to post about radios in
Speaker 4:  her shop. It's coming. That's not gonna do it for you.
Speaker 1:  You don't know. Or
Speaker 5:  That you're just gonna block some topics entirely the way France has done
Speaker 5:  with Covid. Right. Like you can't just, you can't just write certain things
Speaker 5:  off and then be like, come hang out. But only about the nice things like
Speaker 5:  I I think you might be right that what Twitter was might be the best of all
Speaker 5:  the bad outcomes. And maybe they're all bad outcomes. Well,
Speaker 1:  'cause it was, it was like the NC 17 social media and threads is like
Speaker 1:  seriously
Speaker 4:  Legitimately the NC 17 social media.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. And, and this is like G rated, this
Speaker 5:  Is Pixar Twitter
Speaker 1:  And this is not G
Speaker 4:  Rated. I just don't think, like, even if, again, I I I would just come back
Speaker 4:  to some of the stickiest things that Twitter did for me that weren't news.
Speaker 4:  Like hard news, like political news sports, watching sports
Speaker 4:  with Twitter open is great or was great. Now it's weird because
Speaker 4:  like half people aren't there and then they're doing the weird programmatic
Speaker 4:  insertions of like, ads for buying gold. It's like, I
Speaker 4:  love gold. I don't love any of this and I don't have the app on my phone,
Speaker 4:  so it's on the web, whatever. It's not great. I would love to switch to threads
Speaker 4:  for this. It's just not there. And again, I'm rooting for threads
Speaker 4:  because I want a company at Meta Scale to bet on
Speaker 4:  federation and interoperability and push all of that forward.
Speaker 4:  They seem super committed to it. I am totally in support of that.
Speaker 4:  I just think they've lost sight of what makes it sticky,
Speaker 4:  which is actually real-time information. And like, I don't know that you
Speaker 4:  can solve that without accidentally solving news. And I think they're paralyzed
Speaker 4:  for that. Yes. Right. That sounds a hundred percent right. On the other hand,
Speaker 4:  Twitter's paying Paris Hilton money. The fact that
Speaker 5:  Linda Ya Carino had to tweet the word SL is just,
Speaker 5:  it just makes it all worthwhile. It's slaving.
Speaker 4:  Is it? S slaving. Slaving. I always say slaving. Slaving.
Speaker 5:  While, while we're living. Nila is slaving. Guys,
Speaker 4:  That's I'm slaving while we're right out the door. All right. I think that's
Speaker 4:  it. We're way over time. I just wanna point out this episode of the verse
Speaker 4:  has started with coffee cups. It, it did philosophical quandaries. And
Speaker 4:  we ended with slicing. When people say we don't have the range, this is,
Speaker 4:  we made a whole publication for ourselves. Yeah. For this. This
Speaker 4:  is where we live. All right. That's it. I got some things to call out. We
Speaker 4:  have a partnership with Dbrand. You should go buy the skin. They're really
Speaker 4:  cool. They're cool. They're sick as hell, actually. They look beautiful.
Speaker 4:  And then speaking of cameras, Becca's video, a thousand Photos with the
Speaker 4:  iPhone 15 Pro Max, one of the best videos we've ever done. It's on
Speaker 4:  YouTube. Lots of photos. Becca has lots of thoughts about this camera. She
Speaker 4:  compares it to the first iPhone camera. Cool. Which is actually, it is more
Speaker 4:  complicated than you might think. Again, just exposure,
Speaker 4:  philosophical quandary on these phones. Go watch that video. Okay. That's
Speaker 4:  it. That's Vergecast Rock Roll.
Speaker 8:  And that's a wrap for Vergecast this week. We'd love to hear from you. Shoot
Speaker 8:  us an email at Vergecast at The Verge dot com. The Vergecast is a
Speaker 8:  production of The Verge and the Vox Media Podcast network. The show is produced
Speaker 8:  by me, Liam James, and our senior audio director, Andrew Marino. Our
Speaker 8:  editorial director is Brooke Miners. That's it. We'll see you next week.