# Transcript
ID: 8a520f80-b28d-11ed-87da-0b4250b179e6
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: PSVR 2 review, and the best multiroom audio gadgets
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-8676521286878712456/5882579793244405715/s93290-US-4521s-1677055647.mp3
Description: Today on the flagship podcast of not-yet-announced Sonos speakers:
Adi Robertson and Sean Hollister discuss their review of the PSVR2, and how it ranks among the other VR options today, along with its predecessor.
PSVR 2 review: love on a leash
We plugged the PSVR2 into a PC, and here’s what it does
Meta is improving Quest hand tracking so you can touch buttons and type on virtual keyboards
Alex Cranz, Chris Welch, Chris Person, and Jennifer Pattison Tuohy discuss the world of multi-room audio devices to play music. How do smart speakers like Sonos, Amazon Echo, and Google Home compare to audiophile gadgets like the WiiM Mini and the Raspberry Pi?
WiiM’s Mini and Pro are the Chromecast Audio’s real replacement
Exclusive: these are the new Sonos Era speakers
Amazon’s Alexa app gets more Sonos-y with new multiroom audio controls
How to set up multiroom music playback with Google Home speakers
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com, or call the Vergecast Hotline at 866-VERGE11, we'd love to hear from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Disabled
Speaker 2:  Hello and welcome to the Vergecast, the flagship podcast
Speaker 2:  of not yet announced Sono Speakers. That's right. We've got a bunch of
Speaker 2:  stuff on the side about it. You should go read it. I'm your friend Alex Kranz
Speaker 2:  and I just realized I haven't used my Oculus Quest two in like
Speaker 2:  four months. I'm probably gonna blame the Steam deck for that lack of playing
Speaker 2:  time because Boulder Skate three is really, really good. But I also think
Speaker 2:  it's because I'm getting tired of that form of VR and all the the
Speaker 2:  Metaverse junk and I want something different, which is why I have selfishly
Speaker 2:  brought Addie and Sean onto the show to talk about the psvr too, because
Speaker 2:  it feels more like what I want, which is, you know, to play games in
Speaker 2:  vr. Also, to carry on that theme of things I want, the other thing we're
Speaker 2:  gonna be talking about on the show today is the state of Multiroom audio.
Speaker 2:  It's not just Sonos anymore and I've got two Chrises and a gin
Speaker 2:  tui coming on to explain things. So stay tuned. Moore's coming up right after
Speaker 2:  this.
Speaker 2:  Okay, welcome back. Sony's new VR headset. It's out.
Speaker 2:  The PSVR two is available right now, almost anywhere. I
Speaker 2:  think you can buy Sony game stuff and my good friends and yours, Addie
Speaker 2:  Robertson and Sean Hollister have been playing with this thing for a while.
Speaker 2:  So we sat down to talk with them about what's working, what's not working,
Speaker 2:  and why it's not backwards compatible with the games from the original
Speaker 2:  psvr. Let's go straight to the conversation because it is a lot of fun.
Speaker 2:  Okay, Addie, Sean, what's it like being back in the real world?
Speaker 3:  Very high fidelity,
Speaker 4:  Better field of view?
Speaker 4:  And
Speaker 2:  You, you guys were using the Sony PlayStation VR too, that's the
Speaker 2:  name, right?
Speaker 3:  Yeah, we've had it for over a week now. We had myself,
Speaker 3:  Addie and Tom Warren all got to spend lots of time in this thing
Speaker 3:  shooting bows and flailing around with our octopus tentacles. It was
Speaker 2:  Great. You guys had both used the original psvr too,
Speaker 2:  and I, I know that both of you used a lot of vr Addie, I think you've been
Speaker 2:  photographed with almost every VR headset the VER has ever used.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I think that's right.
Speaker 2:  So you guys did this awesome, awesome video. You did this great review about
Speaker 2:  the product and I was kind of surprised because I found
Speaker 2:  myself, even though I have a Quest two and I love my Quest two and I
Speaker 2:  occasionally use my Quest two for things like supernatural and games and
Speaker 2:  stuff. I kind of wanted this one. Can you explain to me why I suddenly want
Speaker 2:  this, even though you made it very clear, it is very expensive, it only
Speaker 2:  does games and there were a lot of drawbacks.
Speaker 3:  I think it's kind of this perfect middle point between
Speaker 3:  something like an Oculus quest and spending ridiculous
Speaker 3:  amounts of money on a Windows computer to get your thing running. Now if
Speaker 3:  you've already got a ridiculous Windows gaming computer, sure, maybe you
Speaker 3:  wanna take a look at the valve index, but even then, Addie, I think you were
Speaker 3:  telling me that you think that this is a better piece of
Speaker 3:  kit in many ways than like the highest N PC headsets we've seen. Right?
Speaker 4:  For one thing, the highest N PC headsets are like four years old now. Like
Speaker 4:  the FinTech came out in 2019. So just super
Speaker 4:  high res, like fancy panels were not as ubiquitous. Eye tracking was
Speaker 4:  not as common at this point. I, I don't know, it's partly the headset,
Speaker 4:  but it's also, it's just that it's easy. Like I've done so much PC v
Speaker 4:  r and so much steam vr, like fiddling around with settings and trying to
Speaker 4:  make sure that I have the right cables for the right things. And it is just
Speaker 4:  kind of a joy to be able to grab a single cable and plug it into
Speaker 4:  a thing and enter a code or buy a game and be like,
Speaker 4:  I understand that this is going to work.
Speaker 3:  I was blown away, blown away by the ease of use. Like even even with an Oculus
Speaker 3:  quest, you're like, okay, this is self-contained. It does everything. It's
Speaker 3:  this lightweight wireless headset that, you know, meta will sell me. Even
Speaker 3:  with the Quest, you still have to sign up for your account, log
Speaker 3:  into the thing, make sure it's charged up and has enough battery life.
Speaker 3:  And with this, it just you, you plug it into the front of the PS five, you
Speaker 3:  already own. There are no updates to download. It already happened
Speaker 3:  that it's completely compatible with the thing. You get these instructions
Speaker 3:  on your TV screen, how to put it on your head, make sure your controllers
Speaker 3:  are paired and then you're in. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  Like I think that was what kind of really was compelling to me. Listen, watching
Speaker 2:  the video, reading the review from you guys was that my quest,
Speaker 2:  if I don't use it for a couple of weeks and I go and I turn it on one,
Speaker 2:  will it have enough battery life or as my battery like discharged over
Speaker 3:  The last, the answer is no, it will, it will not.
Speaker 2:  It will not have enough battery. And then two, I will almost certainly have
Speaker 2:  to do at least like an update to the the OS and an update
Speaker 2:  to whatever game I want to play. And so what it should be like takes me two
Speaker 2:  minutes to get into the game. I'm now looking at 10 to 15
Speaker 2:  if the battery happens to be charged, if the battery doesn't have to be charged,
Speaker 2:  I'm looking at, I'm putting this away and going attempt it another day.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. And, and a properly set up PS five, we'll do all of that in the background.
Speaker 4:  I also just think that Meta has put so much emphasis on social lately
Speaker 4:  that like every time you try to get in at this point, if you're not using
Speaker 4:  it constantly, like they're just constantly trying to add new social stuff.
Speaker 4:  Like now you create a, you don't have to have a Facebook account, but you
Speaker 4:  need a meta account. You need to like make your avatar. Hello, would you
Speaker 4:  like to see things with your avatar? Would you like to be in social? No,
Speaker 4:  I, I wouldn't. I just wanna play games.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And the vr, the killer app for VR
Speaker 2:  continues to be games and this thing is just games.
Speaker 3:  I don't know when it's not gonna be just games, but we haven't found
Speaker 3:  any metaverse experiences that are particularly compelling yet.
Speaker 3:  We've discussed this on previous podcasts, but games have have always been
Speaker 3:  this, you know, I want to be inside this world that I
Speaker 3:  already enjoyed with my 2D flat screen, you know? Yeah. And
Speaker 3:  this does that in a variety of ways. But
Speaker 3:  the game catalog, it was kind of the weak spot in our review too.
Speaker 3:  There are some really interesting experiences in here, but almost
Speaker 3:  everything for the headset is being poured from somewhere else.
Speaker 4:  I'm impressed by how little Sony cared about
Speaker 4:  whether we cared about its launch lineup. They gave us like three games
Speaker 4:  and then we got some codes from other like developers.
Speaker 4:  But we really, it's not just that the launch line was is sort of limited,
Speaker 4:  it's that we got access to just a tiny fraction of the launch line. The
Speaker 4:  game codes are like now rolling in
Speaker 3:  Like every morning, every morning at a Tom and I would be
Speaker 3:  in Slack, Fran frantically big. Like, are we gonna have any games today?
Speaker 3:  Are we actually going to know whether this PlayStation VR two headset
Speaker 3:  has enough games or we just going to have to say we get to try enough of
Speaker 3:  the games. And so the reality is there is one really
Speaker 3:  good interesting title that is maybe I, I think Eddie
Speaker 3:  said it's like 85% of a full game called Horizon Call of the
Speaker 3:  Mountain. And then there's a whole bunch of ports from other VR headsets,
Speaker 3:  decent, maybe even good ports like Star Wars Tales from the
Speaker 3:  Galaxy's Edge is definitely higher fidelity and smoother
Speaker 3:  on psvr two. Even though it's originally from
Speaker 3:  Oculus Quest, it was designed to run on a mobile headset. Not a lot of brand
Speaker 3:  new stuff. But then there's a handful of stuff that we haven't gotten to
Speaker 3:  try yet that we know players are gonna be very interested in. On
Speaker 3:  Launch day there will be an update to Grand Charisma seven that will let
Speaker 3:  you play almost the entire game in vr. There will be an update to Resident
Speaker 3:  Evil Village that will let you play at the entire game in vr. No thank you.
Speaker 3:  As well as one for No Man's Sky. And, and yeah, I don't know if we're gonna
Speaker 3:  love that, but as of today we can't tell you
Speaker 4:  Re an evil four in VR rule
Speaker 3:  Re Evil four, the Game Cube Game so good in vr,
Speaker 2:  But no Man Sky is coming to it. The Horizon zero
Speaker 2:  dawn kind of spinoff game seems to be gorgeous. Like
Speaker 2:  every, every piece of footage I've seen from it, I'm like, oh, that looks
Speaker 2:  like a regular game. Not a VR game, which tend to be like
Speaker 2:  flat, like kind of ugly most VR games.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, this is the first like AAA made for VR
Speaker 3:  game in a while. Like we talk about it in the same breadth as Halflife Alex.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Which was the flagship title for the the Valve
Speaker 3:  index VR headset for PCs. And now you're getting that kind of PC
Speaker 3:  graphics without having to buy a pc because the PlayStation five is
Speaker 3:  basically a pc, right? It's, it's huge. It's powerful. It
Speaker 3:  does those things. But I don't think, we think it's
Speaker 3:  quite on the level of half-life, Alex, right?
Speaker 4:  I think that Alex was a game, Alex was a thing that they designed and they
Speaker 4:  were like, this will be challenging, this will be fully featured. This is
Speaker 4:  has a bunch of mechanics that we are willing to put into a thing that
Speaker 4:  maybe people will fail in. This just felt like a game where they were really
Speaker 4:  scared that people might have to restart a segment or something. And so there's
Speaker 4:  all these climbing sections that could be really amazing if they were like
Speaker 4:  the thing they are very clearly lifting from, which is crytech the climb.
Speaker 4:  But you just, you don't have any of the mechanics that make them hard.
Speaker 4:  And then there's combat. That's a bow and arrow combat that I really love,
Speaker 4:  I think is great, but you get it a couple times a level. It makes me
Speaker 4:  so mad cuz it's so good when it's good. But unlike Alex,
Speaker 4:  it just, it doesn't feel like they were willing to quite commit to be being
Speaker 4:  a game game instead of like a VR game.
Speaker 3:  I was really impressed by Horizon, I think probably because it set me up
Speaker 3:  to be disappointed. I started the game and I'm like, okay, I'm definitely
Speaker 3:  not Aloy and I'm sitting in this boat going on this awesome
Speaker 3:  dinosaur safari just going down this creek seeing all these
Speaker 3:  giant dinosaur robot things, step over me. It was great.
Speaker 3:  And then I'm like, okay, this is just me a Disneyland ride ride, right? And
Speaker 3:  then all of a sudden you can like walk and you can pull out a
Speaker 3:  bow and you can climb things and it feels very immersive
Speaker 3:  and everything looks beautiful and at some point you realize that all the
Speaker 3:  climbing and shooting is very easy and and like, like Eddie says, in her
Speaker 3:  review of the game, they've kind of sanded off all the edges because they're
Speaker 3:  scared and probably the same reason they're not letting you play as Aloy,
Speaker 3:  but it's very impressive. I do think that anybody who picks up this
Speaker 3:  headset should get the game. And so if anybody's reading this planning to
Speaker 3:  buy the headset, you should probably get the bundle that comes with the game
Speaker 3:  for $10 less then you would pay if you bought it separately. But it's not
Speaker 3:  quite like as much of a game as half-life Alex.
Speaker 2:  Okay. So this is one of our first headsets where we're getting eye tracking
Speaker 2:  and I think in climbing games oftentimes I get a little nauseous playing
Speaker 2:  those partly because it's not tracking my eyes usually, right? And so I'm
Speaker 2:  having to like crane my head and stuff. Do you have that? Like not a lot
Speaker 2:  of nausea with this game? Not a lot of moments where you're like, oh I don't
Speaker 2:  feel good. It felt pretty like the movements and stuff felt pretty real.
Speaker 3:  I get sick in VR if the VR is bad. I have,
Speaker 3:  I have what's known as simulator sickness. Many people will get simulator
Speaker 3:  sickness. It's just simply if I am being pointed in a
Speaker 3:  direction in the game that I have not turned to pointed in the real world,
Speaker 3:  I can get kind of sick cuz my vestibular system doesn't match up. There are
Speaker 3:  other kinds of ar sickness you can get as well. But this one, this game,
Speaker 3:  all of the walking, all of the climbing, all of the turning around,
Speaker 3:  I was able to do, I can turn with my real body, I can move my real head and
Speaker 3:  the directions that I wanna move and the game respects all that. It doesn't
Speaker 3:  force me to use joysticks to turn around or anything like that.
Speaker 3:  And so it was comfortable. The only exception was there were a few times
Speaker 3:  I would get into a part of the game where it takes control
Speaker 3:  from you because it wants to do a katini like thing. Like hey,
Speaker 3:  you are sneaking down into these bushes to ambush a robot dinosaur
Speaker 3:  and now you're going to point you in a certain direction. And I would
Speaker 3:  come outta that cut scene and I would suddenly not be facing the same way
Speaker 3:  that I thought I would be facing. And that's a little weird, but it didn't
Speaker 3:  happen often enough. I played multiple hours and didn't really get sick.
Speaker 4:  I tend to get sim sick and I was actually really surprised at how well the
Speaker 4:  free motion worked. I usually end up doing teleportation just cause I find
Speaker 4:  it more comfortable. But yeah, you do this sort of, you're swinging your
Speaker 4:  arms to move and you look very, very, very silly I imagine.
Speaker 4:  But it totally worked.
Speaker 2:  It does. So you're like swinging your arms in real life. It's
Speaker 3:  Hilarious. It looks hilarious.
Speaker 2:  I love it. Looks like you're both running in place.
Speaker 3:  No, I, I would, I would do this with old VR games too, like this. This is
Speaker 3:  a known technique that like VR developers and, and folks who
Speaker 3:  researchers have studied for a while, if you get your body moving, it helps
Speaker 3:  your vestibular system calm down or, or whatever. I'm totally butchering
Speaker 3:  the medical terminology anyhow. I would raise and lower my feet to
Speaker 3:  like fake walk when I was playing early VR games and it would
Speaker 3:  help me. And so it's cool to me to see that they have internalized
Speaker 3:  that and made that like the actual games intentional locomotion. I
Speaker 3:  like it.
Speaker 2:  It sounds like this is a very polished experience. And that was one of the
Speaker 2:  things, like you guys, I reviewed the, the psvr, the original one back in
Speaker 2:  the day. And one of the things I really liked about it was there was like
Speaker 2:  a good amount of games and it was clearly intended for the general masses,
Speaker 2:  not just for like us nerds who, who wanna be at the cutting
Speaker 2:  edge. And we were like, yeah, sometimes we'll feel like we wanna throw up
Speaker 2:  and that's fine because we're, we're at the cutting edge and most people
Speaker 2:  don't actually want to do that, which is shocking to me. And it sounds like
Speaker 2:  this is for those people,
Speaker 3:  A lot of the VR fair is very simple and many
Speaker 3:  of them, if not all of them, but definitely many of the ones we tried would
Speaker 3:  ask you at the beginning, do you want to be seated? Do you want to be standing?
Speaker 3:  One of the my favorite games so far in the system other than
Speaker 3:  Horizon is what the bat, which is a game where you
Speaker 3:  are a girl whose arms have been turned into baseball bats, but that doesn't
Speaker 3:  really matter. The plot doesn't matter. What matters is that you have baseball
Speaker 3:  bats and you have to do all kinds of in name tasks, like pick up
Speaker 3:  a piece of toast and drop it into a toaster or smack
Speaker 3:  baseballs into your neighbor's windows and break them. Yes, I got turned
Speaker 3:  into a tiny baby with, with bats for arms and I needed to splash my
Speaker 3:  rubber ducky out of the tub with my, with my bat hands. And you could do
Speaker 3:  all of that like pointed one direction without moving the rest of your body
Speaker 3:  at all and just swinging your arms. And it is hilarious fun.
Speaker 4:  What did you call this genre? You called it the, the things for arms genre.
Speaker 4:  It's that tentacular,
Speaker 3:  There are a number of games it it VR historically that will be like, we're
Speaker 3:  just going to turn your arms into something else and you're gonna love it.
Speaker 3:  And it works very well that in the, the diorama genre where
Speaker 3:  it's like, yeah, you are going to be interacting with something that is very
Speaker 3:  miniature and cool looking like Moss where you,
Speaker 3:  where you're controlling this mouse that's running through the forest and
Speaker 3:  you can look up and there's these, you know, giant trees all around you.
Speaker 3:  But what you're looking at is the tiny nature scene unfolding beneath you
Speaker 3:  in the bottom of the forest. So it's like this, you know, you're looking
Speaker 3:  into this little world. I like that kind of genre too.
Speaker 2:  The, those kind of games are meant to get around that locomotion problem
Speaker 2:  we were talking about, right? Like if you're looking down at the diorama,
Speaker 2:  that's just like how you would look down playing a board game or something
Speaker 2:  rather than being in the board game.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, it was one of the, the early games, like the first Rift games
Speaker 4:  did it, it was the remnant from the Ashes team. Kronos
Speaker 3:  Kronos. And there was, which Blade Wild Back was, was a great
Speaker 3:  side scrolling rift game that was like, everything is this, you know,
Speaker 3:  you're looking into this diorama. It was, it was a lot of fun. A bunch of
Speaker 3:  games like that exist for VR and, and Moss are the flagship
Speaker 3:  ones for the PlayStation VR two funny thing is that they are are
Speaker 3:  original PlayStation VR games that I believe you'll have to buy
Speaker 3:  again. In some cases a number of original VR PlayStation VR
Speaker 3:  games are coming back to the PlayStation VR two. But the PlayStation VR two
Speaker 3:  is not natively compatible with a P S VR titles. So their
Speaker 3:  developers have to remake remaster everything to use the different
Speaker 3:  controllers upscale to the graphics that are available with PSVR two,
Speaker 3:  all of that. So we are seeing a few games we'll have
Speaker 3:  you get the PS five copy for free with your old PS4 copy.
Speaker 3:  We're seeing somewhere like Thumper, which is a, a lovely
Speaker 3:  rhythm game.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It's one of those non VR games that's really great in
Speaker 3:  Vr. That one's a $5 upgrade. Res infinite is like a $10
Speaker 3:  upgrade if you want the PS five PSVR two version.
Speaker 4:  Sean, what's your take on why they didn't try to make any of it backwards
Speaker 4:  compatible? Because it's not like Sony hasn't done that. Like they've actually
Speaker 4:  historically been quite good at it. Often
Speaker 3:  I am a little bit torn here. Like I I kind of buy their
Speaker 3:  explanation, which is that, you know, the control system is totally
Speaker 3:  different in that like the original PlayStation vr, if you wanted to
Speaker 3:  do anything with it, you basically had to hook up a webcam, right?
Speaker 3:  You had to plug the PlayStation VR two camera, that camera was tracking your
Speaker 3:  head movements and your controller movements and, and Ken had to see
Speaker 3:  all these things and then it would translate that into movement. Whereas
Speaker 3:  this is inside out cameras and tracking where the headset is, the cameras.
Speaker 3:  And so it is telling the system where it is in
Speaker 3:  3D space by mapping the world routed and saying, okay, I moved this much
Speaker 3:  to the laughter, this much to the right. That's how much I turned, that's
Speaker 3:  how much I moved. So that's where I am. Okay.
Speaker 4:  But Oculus made that same transition between the Rift and the Rift and they
Speaker 4:  still maintain compatibility. They didn't, it was like never even a question
Speaker 4:  that they were gonna break all their games because they suddenly switched
Speaker 4:  from outside into inside out.
Speaker 3:  Right. And I would think that whatever game engines these are running
Speaker 3:  on, you could just feed whatever that real time position of your head is
Speaker 3:  and and just have the system correspond to that. I don't understand why not.
Speaker 3:  I guess some of these games are trying to like
Speaker 3:  have representations of your controllers in there. A few of them, but I,
Speaker 3:  I don't think that would be a big deal to swap out like iconography and
Speaker 3:  shit like that.
Speaker 4:  Honestly, my conspiracy theory, which is, is that they had a bunch of games
Speaker 4:  in their original catalog that were not particularly good because they were
Speaker 4:  techs, they were, this was like kind of just a flyer for them and that
Speaker 4:  they didn't want to have to deal with people going back to them. Could
Speaker 3:  Be, could be rights issues.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. It feels like we don't wanna have to pay to get all of these games
Speaker 2:  working on this new system and they weren't that good anyway. So we're not
Speaker 2:  gonna waste the time. But if you wanna do, if you wanna go and take your
Speaker 2:  game and and redo it for our system, great. And if you want to charge people
Speaker 2:  because we're not gonna pay you more power to you, that feels
Speaker 2:  kind of like probably what the conversation was behind the scenes. Right.
Speaker 4:  It doesn't mean we're gonna lose the out the only from software VR game ever
Speaker 4:  made as far as I can tell.
Speaker 3:  Dere scene,
Speaker 4:  Yes, dere scene.
Speaker 3:  I'm hoping some developers will tell us what it was like to port the games
Speaker 3:  from PSVR to PSVR two. Cause I imagine in some cases it's gonna be really
Speaker 3:  easy for them, particularly if if they're, if they're using like a standard
Speaker 3:  engine that allows you to output games to vr like an
Speaker 3:  unreal engine or a Unity, I, I would think that those just have selectors,
Speaker 3:  hey now make the PSVR two version of my game now make the ocul
Speaker 3:  version of my game. I've definitely heard that from, from developers in the
Speaker 3:  somewhat distant past. That would be relatively easy
Speaker 2:  Like that. And this system also is allowing you
Speaker 2:  to just play regular games on it too, like in a theater mode, right?
Speaker 2:  Yes.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, it, the cinematic mode. When you put on the headset,
Speaker 3:  what you see is you see a flat virtual
Speaker 3:  television in front of you that's, that's the interface it, it looks exactly
Speaker 3:  like the PlayStation five interface when you put it on. The only difference
Speaker 3:  is you're not looking at a real tv, you're looking at the fake virtual TV
Speaker 3:  inside your headset. Two, that TV can get bigger or smaller if you
Speaker 3:  want it to. You can stretch it out to a giant like movie theater
Speaker 3:  experience. Like you're sitting five or six rows away from
Speaker 3:  a movie theater screen or you can get it as small as like
Speaker 3:  the 55 inch TV on your wall from your couch. You're seeing
Speaker 3:  the regular PlayStation five interface. You pick the games like any other
Speaker 3:  game, it's got the same settings, menu, all that kind of stuff. When you
Speaker 3:  launch a VR game of course then you transition into the
Speaker 3:  360 degree stereo 3D view of whatever your game is.
Speaker 3:  But you don't have to, you can do those 2D games if you are playing a normal
Speaker 3:  PlayStation five game or a normal PlayStation four game on there,
Speaker 3:  what you're looking at is you're looking at a 10 80 p image on that screen
Speaker 3:  so it's not as sharp as 4k. And also you're getting
Speaker 3:  a little bit of screen door effect because you're looking at magnified
Speaker 3:  pixels of the PlayStation VRS screen that's inside. That's, you know, that's
Speaker 3:  how it VR works. And so it's a little bit grainier than
Speaker 3:  it would be on your regular tv, particularly if you got a 4K TV
Speaker 3:  with games like the original Horizon zero dawn on PlayStation
Speaker 3:  four. I found that it was like very granny and very muddy and I
Speaker 3:  didn't like it and I wouldn't have wanted to do more of that. But with PlayStation
Speaker 3:  five games I played, I played a bunch of eternal in there.
Speaker 3:  I was like this is great, this is fine. Maybe it's not as crisp as my regular
Speaker 3:  tv but totally playable and now it's on this giant screen
Speaker 3:  and I've got this movie theater experience. And you can do that for movies
Speaker 3:  too. And you can do that for Netflix shows and you can do that for whatever
Speaker 3:  other streaming apps are available in the PlayStation five. They don't have
Speaker 3:  any limits there.
Speaker 4:  I've played Outer worlds on it, which I was surprised at how well it worked
Speaker 4:  because it's a very texty game.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Text and VR games can sometimes not be super
Speaker 3:  sharp in the 360 degree stereo 3D
Speaker 3:  environment. But on the 2D theater screen it's seemed pretty legible.
Speaker 2:  And that's because this is one of like the higher resolution
Speaker 2:  screens we've had on a VR headset in a while, right? I think
Speaker 4:  It's a bit over average. It's F two K
Speaker 4:  per eye roughly. It's not a billion times
Speaker 4:  higher than average, but it's a really vivid panel.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. It's not at much higher resolution than the Oculus quest too, which
Speaker 3:  is like closer to like 1800 per eye versus 2000 per eye. But like, like
Speaker 3:  Eddie's saying, like the panel is oad like the original PlayStation
Speaker 3:  vr mind you but oh let's come a long way since then. The colors
Speaker 3:  are really deep. The blacks, you can get
Speaker 3:  nearly perfect black in this headset, which is not true of most
Speaker 3:  headsets, including headsets that were previously using OD
Speaker 3:  because you'd also get something with, with OD screens called
Speaker 3:  God rays, where you've got these, like these shafts of light that are kind
Speaker 3:  of like coming into your eyes because of the lenses. A lot of
Speaker 3:  headsets would use fornell lenses which have
Speaker 3:  ridges in them. They've got a whole like array of different prisms inside
Speaker 3:  to make them lighter weight. They don't use as much glass as inside so they
Speaker 3:  can be lighter weight, not as heavy as other headsets, but the tradeoff is
Speaker 3:  that each of those ridges can catch some light. And Sony actually
Speaker 3:  has a patent on the custom fornell lenses that they put in the
Speaker 3:  PlayStation to VR two where they've kind of like cushioned each
Speaker 3:  of the ridges. You'd have to take a look at the patent to see what I mean.
Speaker 3:  But they've kind of like cushioned each of the ridges so that the beams
Speaker 3:  don't come at those angles that they hit your eye as much. The black
Speaker 3:  mixer, deeper blacks. Oh
Speaker 2:  That's fascinating. Yeah, I think that's one of the things that kind of keeps
Speaker 2:  me from wanting to watch movies and stuff in VR is I'm very conscious of
Speaker 2:  the fact that my iPad's gonna be a better visual experience nine,
Speaker 2:  nine times outta 10, right? Even on a plane with the person sitting next
Speaker 2:  to me clearly able to watch my iPad, I'm usually more okay with that than
Speaker 2:  having to sit there and be like, I'm consciously looking at like a small
Speaker 2:  screen that's getting the hell magnified out of it with the God raises.
Speaker 2:  Literally. So this one, it seems like they've, they've kind of done that
Speaker 2:  work there. They've kind of fixed, they've done the work to make it not quite
Speaker 2:  as obvious to your brain that you're just looking through magnifying lenses
Speaker 2:  at screens.
Speaker 3:  I wish that was a hundred percent but
Speaker 4:  You're still gonna get the screened do door effect and you're still gonna
Speaker 4:  get the kind of slightly goly your field of view is about on average.
Speaker 4:  Yeah,
Speaker 2:  But
Speaker 4:  It just, the, the colors are great. I just, I love them
Speaker 3:  Les God raises deeper, blacks better colors. But also there's this
Speaker 3:  other thing about the lads and all of us, Adam you saw this, Tom saw
Speaker 3:  this, I saw this. The sweet spot is really small.
Speaker 3:  There's a tiny circle at the center of those fornell lenses where
Speaker 3:  you see brilliant, you know 4K resolution
Speaker 3:  through that two, two 2000 per eye and it's super crisp. And then
Speaker 3:  if you turn your eyes or if the headset you know, settles a little bit on
Speaker 3:  your head and pulls it down a tiny amount, you get knocked out of that sweet
Speaker 3:  spot very easily. It has one of the smaller spots, sweet
Speaker 3:  spots among the VR headsets we've tried and so we were, all
Speaker 3:  of us were like regularly adjusting the headsets on our heads so that we
Speaker 3:  could get the sharpest image. I would probably do it maybe every five to
Speaker 3:  10 minutes while I was playing.
Speaker 4:  That seems right. Yeah, it's
Speaker 3:  Not terrible. I got used to it but like it's a lot, you
Speaker 2:  Know? Yeah, that's a lot. And none of you guys wear, were wearing glasses
Speaker 2:  while doing it, right? Like
Speaker 3:  Yeah, none of us were wearing glasses.
Speaker 2:  The glasses is one of those things that we still run into with vr. I'm wearing
Speaker 2:  glasses right now and sometimes I'm like okay my glasses are getting fogged
Speaker 2:  cuz I'm playing supernatural and it's all sweaty but also it's hard to fit
Speaker 2:  'em in there and then it does affect that sweet spot with the glasses cuz
Speaker 2:  you're suddenly having to do a lot more magnification
Speaker 3:  And stuff. I imagine there'd be some knock on effects there while none of
Speaker 3:  us used glasses. Scott Stein at CNET has some of the
Speaker 3:  thickest glasses I have ever seen. I used to work with him there, I've seen
Speaker 3:  'em in person and they are, they are big honking glasses and he says
Speaker 3:  this is the best headset for glasses that he's tried.
Speaker 2:  Oh that's a, that's
Speaker 3:  Wonderful. There's a lot of room in the iBox. Unlike, unlike, you know,
Speaker 3:  Alex, you reviewed the original PlayStation vr. This is one of the very few
Speaker 3:  headsets that allows you to slide the whole iBox in and out on
Speaker 3:  rails.
Speaker 2:  Yeah,
Speaker 3:  The closer you get it to your eyes, the more field of view you get, the further
Speaker 3:  away the less, but you can still see through it no matter how far in or out
Speaker 3:  it is. And that means that you can have room to fit your glasses in there
Speaker 3:  and between that and the lenses, it does a pretty decent job for him. So
Speaker 3:  I, I was really happy that he managed to test it because he, he would know
Speaker 3:  more than almost anyone else.
Speaker 2:  Okay. It sounds like it's much more comfortable for glasses wearers,
Speaker 2:  but I do know that Eddie, you kind of knocked on its comfort. Part of that
Speaker 2:  was because it sounds like the headset wasn't just physically as comfortable
Speaker 2:  as the original PSVR headset and part of that was because you had a big old
Speaker 2:  honking cord.
Speaker 4:  So the headset weighs less than the original psvr
Speaker 4:  but it also, it just feels balanced differently because this
Speaker 4:  one has a bunch of front facing cameras, which is just a generational thing.
Speaker 4:  I think we have an entire generation of VR headsets that just kind of pull
Speaker 4:  down the front of your face. Inevitably it was still like
Speaker 4:  definitely on the higher end of things that are comfortable. I could wear
Speaker 4:  it for just really long stretches at a time after the last headset I reviewed
Speaker 4:  was the pro which the meta quests pro, which was just misery, like
Speaker 4:  the original psvr. You would put it on someone and they'd be like, wow, I
Speaker 4:  didn't know VR could be this comfortable. This wasn't quite like that. This
Speaker 4:  was more, it was good, it was above average and then yes that Heather, I
Speaker 4:  hadn't realized how much I had gotten used to wireless headsets. This is,
Speaker 4:  I, I'm disappointed that the rumors that it was gonna be wireless didn't
Speaker 4:  pan out.
Speaker 3:  All of us got tangled in the court like none of us tripped and fell on our
Speaker 3:  faces or anything. But like every one of us had to get, would turn
Speaker 3:  one direction, be like, oh there's something wrapping around my legs and
Speaker 3:  have to turn the other direction to get out of it. Which is not something
Speaker 3:  you want to happen in the middle of an intensive game. Not that we played
Speaker 3:  so many intensive games, but like when I, when I start playing pistol whip
Speaker 3:  with this and we just got the codes today, I'm wondering whether I'm
Speaker 3:  going to get tangled in this thing and pull my PS five off the shelf because
Speaker 3:  there is no strain relief or like quick detach feature
Speaker 3:  at the end with the PS five. Like if you yank on that thing, it will
Speaker 3:  pull your PS five.
Speaker 4:  Fortunately the court is quite long long. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  It's 14, 14.7 feet long. So it's, you know, this room
Speaker 3:  that I'm in now I can walk anywhere in this, this medium sized room
Speaker 3:  and be connected fairly well and not have to worry about it too much unless
Speaker 3:  I'm like turning around and around. But it's something worry about
Speaker 2:  As an owner of a large dog, I would be probably a little worried about
Speaker 2:  using it because large dogs love to be, they do not see courts.
Speaker 2:  I've had like a PS three and an Xbox 360 get just ripped
Speaker 2:  off of a shelf because of dogs in courts. So this seems like
Speaker 2:  potential disaster.
Speaker 3:  The PSVR two has a really cool pass through system. You know, if you walk
Speaker 3:  outside of your guardian boundary, just like with an Oculus quest with
Speaker 3:  a meta quests, it'll, it'll like show you, oh you're outside, here's what
Speaker 3:  your real world looks like again. But it does not
Speaker 3:  have any feature that shows you when someone
Speaker 3:  has come into your bubble, if a pet or a person
Speaker 3:  walks into your space, the cameras do not see that. They do not look for
Speaker 3:  that. They do not like, oh hey you should stop. There's something going on.
Speaker 3:  You just keep on playing until they smack into you or vice versa.
Speaker 4:  You gotta play defensively. Be ready to punch someone in the face at all
Speaker 4:  times. Fortunately with the cable, no force on earth could move the
Speaker 4:  PlayStation five. I actually, I had to borrow one with the kit because I
Speaker 4:  didn't own one. I didn't realize how big they were.
Speaker 3:  I really hope they do wireless for the headset and they do have a way to
Speaker 3:  do it. So Sony did this teardown their own teardown
Speaker 3:  of the PlayStation VR two and they showed that the entire headband
Speaker 3:  is easily detachable from the I box section up front. It has
Speaker 3:  a detachable cable, the whole rail system that slides the headband out, it's
Speaker 3:  detachable and the headband is where the USB cord plugs
Speaker 3:  into. So theoretically they could take the screen and all
Speaker 3:  the, the, the components of the PSVR two and plug them into a new different
Speaker 3:  headband that could have a battery inside and wireless. They could do it.
Speaker 3:  They have the technology.
Speaker 2:  How much would they charge us for that? Because the head, the headset itself
Speaker 2:  costs what,
Speaker 3:  550 for the headset, 500 for your PS five and probably
Speaker 3:  another 500 for the band. Right?
Speaker 3:  150.
Speaker 2:  How does, how does the price feel on this? Because one of the super
Speaker 2:  compelling things about the Quest too, and I think one of the reasons it
Speaker 2:  was adopted so quickly was because of the price, but the PSVR was also
Speaker 2:  for years it was like the best selling VR headset because it
Speaker 2:  was easy to use. Are they kind of gambling on the people are
Speaker 2:  gonna find that that ease of use to be good enough that they'll pay
Speaker 2:  that extra money?
Speaker 4:  I can't tell cause it's, look, it's cheaper than PC v r headsets were for
Speaker 4:  years before inflation. Like the original Oculus
Speaker 4:  Rift was I think more expensive than this at the time. The problem is
Speaker 4:  nothing can compete with the Quest because the Quest has been subsidized
Speaker 4:  so heavily for so long. Like HTC
Speaker 4:  would, would like for a while just kind of get mad at you if you asked them
Speaker 4:  because they'd be like, it is ridiculous. They are subsidizing this thing
Speaker 4:  through advertising. You are the product here. That is why this is affordable.
Speaker 4:  I don't know that it's sustainable for anybody else to go as low as the quest
Speaker 4:  too. But it also, yeah, the fact remains, this thing is a chunk
Speaker 4:  of change.
Speaker 3:  I think this would look really, really damn expensive compared to
Speaker 3:  the Quest. If the Quest was still $300 to start but they
Speaker 3:  raised their price by a hundred bucks and so now
Speaker 3:  $400 a starting price for request. And so if you
Speaker 3:  want to get into VR and you have nothing, no pc,
Speaker 3:  no PS five, maybe you look at the Quest and you're like okay this is most
Speaker 3:  of the same games, most of the games I wanna play are here. It's, you know,
Speaker 3:  I don't have to buy all this other hardware, it's wireless great, but if
Speaker 3:  you already have a PS five sitting around and this is
Speaker 3:  one of the best selling look, it's on track to be one of the best selling
Speaker 3:  consoles of all time. Certainly with the fastest selling consoles of all
Speaker 3:  time, then it's a lot easier to say 150 bucks more than a
Speaker 3:  Quest. And I get way better graphics and I get, you know, I
Speaker 3:  tracking and I get this beautiful screen and I do not
Speaker 3:  get meta trying to sell ads against my eyeballs
Speaker 3:  and whatever else. You know, you worry that meta might do and if you don't
Speaker 3:  have a PS five and you got a pc, well we really wish that this could
Speaker 3:  plug into a PC too because it, it can electrically,
Speaker 3:  you plug this thing into a pc, it'll show up as a 10 80 p panel for your
Speaker 3:  pc. It'll show that you've got some unrecognized USB
Speaker 3:  devices. The controllers show up at speakers. Don't ask me why my PC
Speaker 3:  thinks the sense controllers aren't speakers, but it does. That's
Speaker 4:  Basically what happened with the psvr, right? That you could end up adapting
Speaker 4:  it to be a PC headset.
Speaker 3:  Tom looked into this. Yeah, it didn't take long within the first
Speaker 3:  three, four months I wanna say at the PlayStation vr it was already
Speaker 3:  a, a Windows headset but they had apparently a lot of
Speaker 3:  issues with controller tracking and maybe still do.
Speaker 3:  So it does require like some thought
Speaker 2:  Because the move controllers
Speaker 4:  Sucked. I mean the move controllers were miserable. Speaking of the
Speaker 4:  controllers, I I just, I have to say I really like the plastic of these.
Speaker 4:  I like how solid they feel.
Speaker 2:  I think we're gonna use the Quest two as our comparison here cuz that's the
Speaker 2:  controller. A lot of people have probably used. How do they shape up? How
Speaker 2:  do you compare the
Speaker 4:  Two? See actually I feel like they're just really solid plastic. I also,
Speaker 4:  I think that face buttons are way tighter. That is the main thing I've noticed.
Speaker 4:  They're also a little hard to put on though because I'm not used to the fact
Speaker 4:  that you, they feel upside down because you have to put this ring around
Speaker 4:  the bottom of your wrist instead of over your knuckles.
Speaker 2:  Do you like put your hand through the ring to grab
Speaker 4:  It? Yes. You put your hands through the ring. It's very sci-fi. Oh
Speaker 3:  Boy. The one thing I don't like is the grip buttons. So
Speaker 3:  it's got the grip buttons under your middle fingers, just like the oculus
Speaker 3:  quest too. But the Oculus quest too, it's like, it's like a rest for your
Speaker 3:  entire middle finger. That gently pillow like
Speaker 3:  depresses into the grip and once it's held down there's
Speaker 3:  basically no spring pressure on your finger. It's such a tiny amount
Speaker 3:  that you feel like you could hold it that way indefinitely with the
Speaker 3:  PlayStation it's like a firm button and see I'm holding down this firm button
Speaker 3:  but I wanna let it go fairly quickly. So any game that requires me to hold
Speaker 3:  an object for a long time or any game where I get really, really
Speaker 3:  greedy and just wanna hold like five guns at once cause
Speaker 3:  that's a thing we do. I feel like I wanna let go. It's, it's annoying. How
Speaker 2:  About the, the space this takes up in your cabinet, like the PS five takes
Speaker 2:  up already a lot of space in the cabinet. Were you really hunting for a place
Speaker 2:  to put this thing when not in use bold of You would assume that I
Speaker 2:  ever store things.
Speaker 3:  That's basically where I'm coming from too. I have no idea where this thing
Speaker 3:  goes. It's just lying in a pile on a shelf every time I put it away.
Speaker 2:  Well good luck Sean and and thank you guys both for taking the time to chat
Speaker 2:  about the psvr. Everybody who's listening, you gotta go read
Speaker 2:  the review, go watch the video. That was like the best way to start my morning
Speaker 2:  the other day was watching that video. So thank you guys so much.
Speaker 2:  We're gonna take a quick break and when we're back we're gonna get really,
Speaker 2:  really nerdy and talk for a really, really long time about multi-room audio.
Speaker 5:  Hey there, I'm Josh Mucci, host of the Pitch, A show where
Speaker 5:  real entrepreneurs pitch real tech investors for real money
Speaker 5:  and this season gets a little saucy.
Speaker 7:  We knew that we were not going to join the same old sauce
Speaker 7:  game. We were gonna disrupt 130 billion industry
Speaker 7:  we're coming after Hines.
Speaker 5:  We meet founders pitching everything from a better ketchup
Speaker 5:  to a solution for one of the biggest problems today,
Speaker 5:  energy
Speaker 8:  In the future, the vehicles and garage. It's gonna be like a giant
Speaker 8:  power plant that could be used to reinforce a power grid, substitute
Speaker 8:  fossil fuel power plants and allow more renewable energy on the network.
Speaker 5:  This season 14 founders with 12 ideas
Speaker 5:  big enough to change the world. If the investors invest,
Speaker 5:  I would like to invest in this round $300,000 new episodes
Speaker 5:  every Wednesday. See you in the pitch room.
Speaker 2:  Okay, we're back. I'm very, very excited because we went really long on this
Speaker 2:  one and it is a lot of fun cuz Chris Welch, he's been like a scoop
Speaker 2:  machine lately and he's reporting on all those new Sonos speakers that are
Speaker 2:  supposed to come out like in the next month or so. But Sonos isn't the only
Speaker 2:  multi-room audio speaker out there right now. While it's still
Speaker 2:  the gold standard, there are a lot of competitors. So I've
Speaker 2:  gathered Chris who knows everything about Sonos even when they don't want
Speaker 2:  him to know everything about Sonos. I do
Speaker 9:  Enjoy the products but I also enjoy scooping
Speaker 2:  Them. Jen Tuey, who is our expert on smart speakers from Amazon,
Speaker 2:  apple, and Google,
Speaker 10:  I'm definitely gonna help you out here with how they work on a daily basis
Speaker 10:  because I use them all
Speaker 2:  In Chris person who recently wrote about his love of a new audio
Speaker 2:  device on the scene, the whim, which is like this little puck
Speaker 2:  that gives your old speakers multi-room audio superpowers, it's
Speaker 2:  cool,
Speaker 11:  It's a puck. You get on Amazon for
Speaker 2:  $80. Each of them have their own opinions and I'm gonna make them fight it
Speaker 2:  out and this is gonna be really, really fun.
Speaker 2:  So I think the first question I wanna ask
Speaker 2:  is why Sonos? Why Whim? And then
Speaker 2:  Jen you go first. Me, Wyatt, apple,
Speaker 2:  Alexa and Google.
Speaker 10:  So I do use all three of the voice assistants in
Speaker 10:  my home and, and a couple others. So we have Alexa with its Multiroom music,
Speaker 10:  Google Assistant with its multi-room music and then
Speaker 10:  Apple's Siri over Airplay. So Airplay is
Speaker 10:  their multi-room music and you can control it with Siri. I think the most
Speaker 10:  important thing to start out with when you're talking about multi-room music
Speaker 10:  is this is a proprietary mess. There is no
Speaker 10:  simple solution. As crisp person found out
Speaker 10:  there's ecosystem lock in hard in this space. A few of the
Speaker 10:  companies have tried to expand and provide much
Speaker 10:  more sort of flexibility, but ultimately you end up
Speaker 10:  with the best experience if you stick with the hardware of the
Speaker 10:  manufacturer. For example with Amazon's multi moon music,
Speaker 10:  if you have all echo devices. And to be fair to them, and this is
Speaker 10:  probably the biggest selling point, there are so many variations and so
Speaker 10:  many different ways you can play through an echo speaker. You've got the
Speaker 10:  small speakers, you've got the little echo dots, you've got the Echo big
Speaker 10:  round echo, fourth gen, you've got fire TVs. There are so many
Speaker 10:  that work great. And when you set up Multiroom music you can look in your
Speaker 10:  app and it's like, oh look at this. I have like 10 speakers in my house.
Speaker 10:  I can have this great multi room music experience. They do work
Speaker 10:  with a few, with quite a few third party speakers as well. I've actually
Speaker 10:  managed to get my multi-room music playing through my smoke alarm, which
Speaker 10:  is really exciting. Ooh. And my thermostat.
Speaker 10:  So it works with the OneLink smoke alarm and it could be thermostat if you
Speaker 10:  enable Alexa. So you know there's a lot of options there. The problem I
Speaker 10:  have always found with Amazon's, I'm trying not to say the name, to set
Speaker 10:  off everyone's devices with Amazon's multi-room music using voice
Speaker 10:  is there are issues with mesh networks. It seems like when you have a
Speaker 10:  mesh wifi network and you use multi-room music, it's very hard to
Speaker 10:  get all of your devices working together. This is something that Amazon
Speaker 10:  can't really control although, and this is even using like their own Arrow
Speaker 10:  network. I've had the I Mesh network and I will set up multi room music
Speaker 10:  with multiple speakers but only like three will show up and then
Speaker 10:  you select another one and the other three show up.
Speaker 10:  You can't get them all on one because they're on different nodes. I may
Speaker 10:  be going in the weeds a bit here, but that's basically one of the biggest
Speaker 10:  issues I've had using Amazon's multimillion music. But when it
Speaker 10:  does work it's probably one of the easiest to use. It's the easiest
Speaker 10:  nomenclature to get it going. You can say, hey Amazon's assistant
Speaker 10:  play me the latest Taylor Swift album and away it
Speaker 10:  will go with Google. That is not the case. Oh, so Google
Speaker 10:  has the same sort of basic setup. So you can use any
Speaker 10:  Google speaker. So you've got the Nest hub, the Nest max,
Speaker 10:  the next Nest Mini, the Nest audio and then some of the older
Speaker 10:  Google Home speakers, any Chromecast enabled speakers. So third party
Speaker 10:  speakers from like Lenovo, if you still have Chromecast
Speaker 10:  audio, all of those devices, they'll all work with multi-room music.
Speaker 10:  The problem I have with using the Google system with voice
Speaker 10:  is if I ask, say for the same thing, say play me
Speaker 10:  some Taylor Swift, I just this morning tested it out on one of my Nest
Speaker 10:  hub maxes and instead of playing the music everywhere as I asked it to,
Speaker 10:  it showed me a YouTube video of Taylor Swift. So
Speaker 10:  the nomenclature is the issue there, you know, and there's different ways
Speaker 10:  of using multi room music. If the voice isn't your preferred option, of
Speaker 10:  course you can do it through an app and this is where the sort of ecosystem
Speaker 10:  locking comes in. Spotify lets you play to any of these speakers
Speaker 10:  so you, if you have a Spotify account you can use Alexa multi room music,
Speaker 10:  you can use Google's multi room music, you can use Sonos and that works
Speaker 10:  fine but you're locked into Spotify. It's just a bit of a mess
Speaker 10:  right now. I think people like flexibility, especially in their
Speaker 10:  home, especially if you have more than one person in your home, you might
Speaker 10:  want a different speaker in your room or you might want different speaker
Speaker 10:  in your kitchen. And right now it's so hard to find a simple
Speaker 10:  solution that works reliably with multi room music. That's been
Speaker 10:  my experience and this is why I was so excited about Chris Person's article.
Speaker 10:  In fact, when it came out I tweeted it to my followers and I was like, I
Speaker 10:  think some of you might have been looking for this. And there were a lot
Speaker 10:  of positive responses because it's just a frustrating space.
Speaker 10:  And just to wrap up the, the smart home side, and I know
Speaker 10:  Chris Welch will will help weigh in on this too cuz we just finished testing
Speaker 10:  the home pods together. Obviously Apple has its airplay
Speaker 10:  system and that is one of the systems that actually works the most
Speaker 10:  reliably across speaker platforms. So you can use a number of
Speaker 10:  different speakers without problems. So you can have your
Speaker 10:  Sonos, you can have bows, you can have your Apple Home Pods
Speaker 10:  and Apple TV so your TV speakers can kind of get in on the game
Speaker 10:  but it's less intuitive to control and you really relies on your
Speaker 10:  iPhone. You can use the voice assistant but it is not as
Speaker 10:  intuitive in terms of you know, commands to get it
Speaker 10:  working.
Speaker 2:  It can get real dumb when when I asked it to play music sometimes
Speaker 2:  it's like no you don't wanna listen to Pippen. And I'm like, I do, I'm the
Speaker 2:  one person that wants to listen to Pippen and it's like we're gonna play
Speaker 2:  you some rock. And I was like that's that's cool I guess. No,
Speaker 10:  I know it's, it's, it's quite funny what each of the smart assistants will
Speaker 10:  come up with when you ask for a specific audio.
Speaker 2:  They all have opinions and they're not good.
Speaker 10:  And then the final piece of the puzzle of course is you can use Sonos with
Speaker 10:  Amazon's assistant but only Sonos speakers.
Speaker 10:  So you can set up a Sonos group in your Amazon Alexa app
Speaker 10:  and play music using one of your Echo speakers but
Speaker 10:  only to sono speakers. So you can't, I'm almost a hundred percent certain,
Speaker 10:  correct me if I'm wrong, but my experience you can only group
Speaker 10:  sono speakers together using Alexa. You can't also add in like
Speaker 10:  your Echo studio if you have one with your Sonos Beam.
Speaker 10:  So that's kind of again that kind of frustrating like ah I've got these
Speaker 10:  speakers and I wanna be able to do this but it's hard and I don't know,
Speaker 10:  I mean technically whether this is difficult thing to fix to make or whether
Speaker 10:  it's just the different companies are like locking in
Speaker 10:  their proprietary systems and making it impossible to share.
Speaker 10:  And I'm sure Chris Welch could probably fill us in on
Speaker 10:  that.
Speaker 2:  We need to go to Chris Welch because that's the beauty of Sonos, right? It
Speaker 2:  is super proprietary. It is all one thing but when it works,
Speaker 9:  When it works, it works really well. And I'm not a big voice service person
Speaker 9:  so I don't like use like their own voice service. I don't use Alexa and Sonos
Speaker 9:  devices, I just use Sonos as its own thing. It's for music, it's for entertainment,
Speaker 9:  it supports like all the services under the sun and they have speakers
Speaker 9:  for like so many use cases how Jen was saying Amazon has a ton of like different
Speaker 9:  price points and sizes, but Sonos has like different use cases, right? Like
Speaker 9:  I've got the Sonos Roam for the shower, which you can't really do with any
Speaker 9:  home pod or any kind of other gadget. I've got the Sonos arc for my
Speaker 9:  living room, which sounds great, playing music as well. And I've got the
Speaker 9:  Sonos play five on my desk for you know like proper sitting and listening
Speaker 9:  to music and enjoying it and I've got the move if I wanna like go outside
Speaker 9:  and and play mu music there. So like that kind of versatility of Sonos like
Speaker 9:  it doesn't work great. Some people hate the app. I don't really mind it after
Speaker 9:  all these years I've gotten used to it. But yeah when it works it's just
Speaker 9:  like, it just feels boundless in terms of like what you can do with it and
Speaker 9:  I think that's been the main draw to me.
Speaker 2:  But when it breaks,
Speaker 12:  Yes
Speaker 2:  I just watched Chris person like yes it does rise up but
Speaker 2:  Welch first to you then we'll go to person.
Speaker 9:  So I'd say for me it's been like 85% not consistent, which is
Speaker 9:  good average, but when you do have like let's say cutouts or kind of issues,
Speaker 9:  some people swear by plugging one of your Sonos speakers into ethernet
Speaker 9:  directly and that creates like a small little private network for all of
Speaker 9:  your Sonos gear. And so they do tend to talk to each other a lot better when
Speaker 9:  you do that. So if you're having cutouts, try plugging in. If that doesn't
Speaker 9:  fix it then I guess it's time to pursue something else. I
Speaker 2:  Know a lot of people were really challenged when Sonos moved from S one to
Speaker 2:  S two. They had two versions of the app and originally they were like if
Speaker 2:  you are using the old app, all of the speakers on it will only work with
Speaker 2:  the old app and will be dead to the new app. Then everybody was like Sonos,
Speaker 2:  do you know how much we spent? Absolutely not. And so they said okay, if
Speaker 2:  you've got the S two, your old stuff will work with it, it might be a little
Speaker 2:  different. And most people I think have migrated to S two are
Speaker 2:  using it. I've used it. I honestly, I use Airplay with my Sonos
Speaker 2:  speakers more than I used the Sonos app at this point. Yeah. Which is why
Speaker 2:  I was also very interested in Chris's story
Speaker 2:  where cuz that's what you're doing doing with the whim.
Speaker 11:  So yeah like I dunno, my attitude towards Sonos is that I don't doubt that
Speaker 11:  they're good devices and I've seen them around and they seem nice but it's
Speaker 11:  kind of like, do you remember the episode of the Simpsons when Kirk Van
Speaker 11:  Howden gets divorced and he's like, I sleep in a race car bed and I'm like,
Speaker 11:  I sleep in a big bed with my wife. It's like
Speaker 11:  okay this is our generation's bows wave, which was a great sounding
Speaker 11:  device but if you talk to audio files at the time they were like, I'm not
Speaker 11:  using that cuz that's for children, you know what I mean? Like and like
Speaker 11:  here's the thing and I don't wanna be come off as like too condescending
Speaker 11:  or something like that. It's just that I have a very specific thing where
Speaker 11:  like I actually do have a couple of HomePod minis. I think they're pretty
Speaker 11:  good if, if you want to get whatever today's equivalent of a clock radio
Speaker 11:  that you put in your kitchen is they, they're great. You know what I mean?
Speaker 11:  They're great. Airplay two works, it also works really well cuz they broke
Speaker 11:  it, nerds hacked it, so now you can use it with everything. If Apple
Speaker 11:  was, I don't wanna say smart, but like cool they would do what
Speaker 11:  they've been doing with MagSafe devices and just say okay everybody gets
Speaker 11:  airplay too. You know what I mean? Because that would just solve a lot of
Speaker 11:  this so too would fixing it with Matter. I have a bunch of
Speaker 11:  speakers already. I don't need to buy new speakers, I don't need to buy
Speaker 11:  new speakers that have a thing in them that might not work in six years
Speaker 11:  that has like a wifi chip that sucks in five years. I don't need that
Speaker 11:  powered speakers are even like me kind of cheating. The
Speaker 11:  idea should be that like you create something that just
Speaker 11:  gets audio to go to different places and it should be something that we
Speaker 11:  all agree works with each other and the fact that none of these
Speaker 11:  companies could do this is indicative of what they want to sell
Speaker 11:  you, which is their own little gated community, their own little
Speaker 11:  tiny weird castle town that they live in.
Speaker 11:  And and I, and I hate that crap. I'm sorry I, it's it, it makes me, it drives
Speaker 11:  me up the wall. So basically, yeah I started off like, okay, how do I do
Speaker 11:  this? Okay. Chromecast used to be good. I knew people who used to like hoard
Speaker 11:  airplay express twos because those actually got updated to Airplay two for
Speaker 11:  a really long time. So people were using like an Apple router
Speaker 11:  that like had an ox out
Speaker 2:  That nobody's used in
Speaker 11:  Years that nobody's used in years because it was the only thing
Speaker 11:  that they had for a really long time that just was like Airplay two plus
Speaker 11:  optical audio app. That's all people wanted. And like Chromecast audio was
Speaker 11:  pretty good for a while and then they're like, we're not going to use this
Speaker 11:  anymore. And I wondered if that was like because Sonos got
Speaker 11:  lawy with them or if that had anything to do with it at all. But like, this
Speaker 11:  is the thing is like I think Sonos, the use case for Sonos long term
Speaker 11:  isn't terribly strong. People are figuring this stuff out. What
Speaker 11:  do they have that is special? And the answer is nothing. The way that Bose
Speaker 11:  didn't have anything particularly special with its with its thing other
Speaker 11:  than the fact that it made kind of nice speakers that were good for most
Speaker 11:  people because they were simple and like that. That's it.
Speaker 2:  Now Welch fight him
Speaker 13:  Dinging.
Speaker 9:  I mean, I think the simple option goes a long way. Like it always hasn't.
Speaker 9:  It always will. Bo still sends a ton of products. You know, Sonos is doing
Speaker 9:  very well. They're very defensive of their ip. I will admit that they've
Speaker 9:  had a lot of settlements over the years and there's another child with Google
Speaker 9:  starts in May.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Cuz they were supposed to have the Google assistant.
Speaker 9:  They do still have the assistant, but it's kind of like a, it's just a tense
Speaker 9:  relationship and like you can use their voice thing and you can use Alexa
Speaker 9:  at the same time. You can't do that with Google Assistant because Google
Speaker 9:  apparently will not let anybody build like a multi kind of voice system with
Speaker 9:  assistant. But yeah, Sonos can be kinda lawy because I think they see this
Speaker 9:  as like their whole thing.
Speaker 2:  You know, Chris, you said it kind of sucks. You kind of feel like it's for
Speaker 2:  the bows. I think in both cases though, I knew a lot of people who use
Speaker 2:  the bows. I, I own the Sonos now and I own the Sonos because I was like,
Speaker 2:  oh, I wanna do all this big stuff. Oh, I don't have the time and energy
Speaker 2:  to figure out all of the big stuff. Sure. And so I went Sonos because it
Speaker 2:  just works. Like it just works. That's it. Will I one day
Speaker 2:  replace my, my Sonos play base and my two ones with like
Speaker 2:  actual towers and an amplifier that cost three times as much, but sound
Speaker 2:  three times better. A hundred percent. If anybody has suggestions,
Speaker 2:  please email me. But it also just worked. I plugged it in and it like
Speaker 2:  went. But it sounds like you, like it took you a very long time to kind of
Speaker 2:  settle on on this system that you, you have now. Did it
Speaker 2:  take you a long time to set up that system?
Speaker 11:  The whims? No, it takes like two seconds. It, it works really
Speaker 2:  Well. Oh no, Sonos.
Speaker 11:  No, no. That's the funny part is that it works really well. It takes two
Speaker 11:  seconds to like set up, it's like a little glitchy but it never does the,
Speaker 11:  like I was at a party with someone and they were
Speaker 11:  DJing and the, the Sonos was involved and something bad
Speaker 11:  happened and man it was not fun. It like
Speaker 11:  kind of stopped the party for like 15 minutes while he had
Speaker 11:  to like dig through cables and shit. You know, like plug it in and plug
Speaker 11:  it out like a router. The wind just works. I mean like that's the funny
Speaker 11:  thing is that like part of the weight through this path was me
Speaker 11:  being like, all right, I can currently buy a raspberry pie,
Speaker 11:  which is not something you can do right now. Just walk
Speaker 11:  into a Microcenter and buy Raspberry Pie. Let me see if somebody has hacked
Speaker 11:  something together. Cuz I know Nerds, I've been on GitHub like today
Speaker 11:  they, they, they figured this stuff out and the answer is like they're in
Speaker 11:  as much of a pickle as I think us. Like there's a, there's one like called
Speaker 11:  Snap cast that sorta worked. It was this like long thing where I had to
Speaker 11:  like follow what was functionally an Instructables page to be like all right,
Speaker 11:  first you're gonna do this and then you're gonna get this hat for it. And
Speaker 11:  like it sort of worked and then that eventually I moved on to doing,
Speaker 11:  somebody actually hacked Airplay two to work with these things and that
Speaker 11:  kind of worked, it got me sort of where I needed to go, you know what I
Speaker 11:  mean? And then like a year goes by, I'm kind of okay with this.
Speaker 11:  Also airplane two is not like ideal because it's, it's not
Speaker 11:  audio file quality in terms of what it's doing. It caps at
Speaker 11:  44 1 I think, which most people won't hear that's CD quality,
Speaker 11:  whatever. But like for me, I have very specific reasons why I don't want
Speaker 11:  that that involve like toss link timing and crap like that.
Speaker 11:  But like, you know, it, it does the thing you're talking about And like
Speaker 11:  that's the thing is like I'm more amenable to the HomePod Mini because it
Speaker 11:  knows what it is. It's pretty straightforward, it's simple to use. It integrates
Speaker 11:  with the system that I have, including the weem. Like you're saying Airplay
Speaker 11:  two is very, even though it's like still proprietary kind of compatible
Speaker 11:  with other things, it plays well with other things. And that's the thing
Speaker 11:  that I think people are sort of moving to and I like hope we see with like
Speaker 11:  Matter and stuff like that. Like Matter TV we've pointed out is like a video
Speaker 11:  codec but it doesn't look like anybody's like aching to like make and
Speaker 11:  matter audio. But that would solve this
Speaker 10:  Amazon's aching too. No one else is though
Speaker 11:  By the way. I did look it up. The WEEM has the like Amazon Ultra
Speaker 11:  HD audio, you know that stuff works with it. Like the other thing is like,
Speaker 11:  yeah Spotify Connect, the only thing it doesn't have I think is like Chromecast
Speaker 11:  in the WEEM Mini doesn't work but it doesn't the pro and then like,
Speaker 11:  I don't know Apple ar Apple music is just like proprietary. Although they
Speaker 11:  would be smart to put it on other devices, you know what I mean? But like
Speaker 11:  that's the thing is like this thing can play music for my server. It can
Speaker 11:  play at like 1 92 kilohertz, 24 bit like
Speaker 11:  streaming flax. Like if you want that real pervert stuff,
Speaker 11:  multiroom, you can do it with an $80 device.
Speaker 2:  Silver wifi.
Speaker 11:  Well no the pro has a, has ethernet connection so you can do it through
Speaker 11:  that way too. You know what I mean? Although I, my wifi is strong enough
Speaker 11:  to support this, you know, I've made it, I have made it so
Speaker 2:  I love
Speaker 11:  This. And the other option is roone, which is like for guys on audio
Speaker 11:  science review. Like literally for guys that post on audio forms and Roone
Speaker 11:  is really good but they, you are paying money.
Speaker 2:  Roone is an app, right? It's
Speaker 11:  A service. It is a service you pay money for and it, they are really
Speaker 11:  good. Like that's the thing people wouldn't pay money for this guys on audio
Speaker 11:  forms wouldn't pay money for this if it, if it wasn't as good as they thought
Speaker 11:  it was. Which is like 3 86 kilohertz, you know, completely
Speaker 11:  uncomplex. Like Lossless, they have their own thing called Rat, R A A
Speaker 11:  T, which is a, their own audio transport. Kodak, that's like
Speaker 11:  peerless, you know what I mean? And like does the job, it works with Chromecast
Speaker 11:  weirdly, like they got it to work with the Chromecast audios and works with
Speaker 11:  raspberry pies, but it does metadata cataloging cloud
Speaker 11:  stuff and then like multi-room audio and it does it really
Speaker 11:  well And that's why guys that own really fancy high-end speaker
Speaker 11:  systems pay money for it because it's like if Plex samples good.
Speaker 9:  Yeah that sounds like the service for movies where you can like pay to watch
Speaker 9:  movies that are in theaters that like uncompressed
Speaker 11:  Quality. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Yeah we are like pucks they're they're pucks and you plug them into your
Speaker 2:  speakers.
Speaker 11:  Yeah there's a puck and then there's a big box and the box is 150.
Speaker 2:  So Roone, you go and you get a raspberry pie, you put a software on it, you
Speaker 2:  plug that into speakers, you pay roone a lot of money and it gives you like
Speaker 2:  almost that Sonos experience. If it just works
Speaker 11:  It, it's like if Sonos was good. Yeah and
Speaker 9:  Sonos subreddit is gonna be very
Speaker 11:  Upset. I'm sorry man. They're like, you go, you go, you go defend ru
Speaker 11:  go defend Sonos on like an audio forum and see where that gets you. I mean
Speaker 11:  like there's a couple of people, these people are sick. They, they love
Speaker 11:  Logitech media server, they love like all of like d n la
Speaker 2:  This is like when I go on the, the headphones servers with the
Speaker 2:  AirPods. Yeah I'm happy with my AirPods. I like
Speaker 11:  AirPods. But that's the thing, that's the weird thing. It's this middle
Speaker 11:  ground that I don't like. So like Apple I'm fine with cuz they're experiencing
Speaker 11:  a pretty good hardware renaissance. They like, you know, it's fine. Your
Speaker 11:  mom asks straight, I get there like yeah sure it's fine. It's not, it's
Speaker 11:  not like a fire device or a Google device. It's like the, the one smart
Speaker 11:  home speaker I kind of think is okay and you can get 'em on sale at Costco
Speaker 11:  or like the really perverted stuff where you get the thing you're supposed
Speaker 11:  to get. But the middle ground where you pay a lot of money for something
Speaker 11:  that isn't the thing you want is the thing that I have objections to.
Speaker 11:  Especially if it only plays with itself.
Speaker 10:  Well and that's the main space. Yeah, that's the main space right now, isn't
Speaker 10:  it? And that's, and we were talking about this on the last time I was on
Speaker 10:  the Verge cast with with Neli because the problem is these speakers do so
Speaker 10:  many different things and they have all these different radios in them and
Speaker 10:  that obviously is not an ideal environment for audio. But ultimately
Speaker 10:  things like the E Echo speakers and the Nest audios and the
Speaker 10:  minis, the HomePod minis, they're really designed for the person that just
Speaker 10:  wants to be able to get their music quickly and you know, in their kitchen
Speaker 10:  or in their bathroom or and played around the house. They're not really
Speaker 10:  designed for the audio file. But we have been given this
Speaker 10:  great experience like Amazon came out with with the
Speaker 10:  multi-room audio with its speakers really early on and
Speaker 10:  everyone was like, this is great and these are cheap compared to what we
Speaker 10:  had to do with Sonos. And so we were offered this great experience but the
Speaker 10:  follow through has not really been there. So now we are stuck with what's
Speaker 10:  kind of a messy complicated situation and
Speaker 10:  we need simple solutions and Chris's solution
Speaker 10:  sounds actually really simple but I don't think it's the type of thing that
Speaker 10:  most people are gonna go out and buy just because it's an extra step. People
Speaker 10:  want the simple, like I have my speaker, why doesn't it do exactly what
Speaker 10:  I want? I mean not saying that multi-room audio never works cuz it does.
Speaker 10:  But there are many, I said in my experience with Amazon's,
Speaker 10:  like I was just testing it all out before we came on just to kind of refresh
Speaker 10:  my memory on things. And I had it play music throughout the house, couldn't
Speaker 10:  get it to work on every speaker within three minutes. It had just stopped
Speaker 10:  for no particular reason. And that happens all the time. I
Speaker 10:  think it may be wifi based because it's mesh, I don't know, I'm not
Speaker 10:  an network engineer but neither are the people that this is marketed to.
Speaker 10:  It needs to just work and Chris person mentioned matter at least
Speaker 10:  three times. So I need to jump on the matter bandwagon again here
Speaker 10:  because this, and I've spoken to both Chrises about this. This is
Speaker 10:  something that potentially could be solved with matter. There is
Speaker 10:  a casting in the matter spec casting
Speaker 10:  protocol. Amazon has jumped on it. We wrote about it a while ago. In fact
Speaker 10:  very recently there's actually a certified device
Speaker 10:  from Amazon that uses this matter spec, but they won't tell me
Speaker 10:  what it is. But we assume it's something to do with fire TV
Speaker 10:  because there's two parts of this to casting. It can, it can be casting
Speaker 10:  your video to your TV or your audio
Speaker 10:  to your speakers and obviously Amazon needs a video casting
Speaker 10:  solution because it doesn't have one and its competitors do. But it could,
Speaker 10:  in the same vein, this casting spec could work across
Speaker 10:  all of the speakers that you have that are matter enabled and all,
Speaker 10:  you know what the one common thread is of every major tech
Speaker 10:  manufacturer's hubs that are in matter right now, they are
Speaker 10:  also smart speakers. So it seems like, you know, we, we already
Speaker 10:  have the infrastructure there, but there are two major roadblocks. The first
Speaker 10:  is that smart speakers are not a matter device and the second is there
Speaker 10:  is a smart speaker working group in the matter system in
Speaker 10:  the CSA and it involves Sonos and Bose
Speaker 10:  and a few other big audio names. And I'm assuming also Apple
Speaker 10:  and Amazon and Google are involved in that because they're very much sort
Speaker 10:  of running matter.
Speaker 2:  They love
Speaker 10:  Matter apparently according to an unnamed source.
Speaker 10:  That group has yet to actually do anything.
Speaker 10:  They're just a group in name. There has been no impetus
Speaker 10:  behind this group to, to actually move forward and
Speaker 10:  theorizing. Having spoken to the Chris's about this, is that for
Speaker 10:  what's the benefit right now for Sonos or Bose to
Speaker 10:  give away any of their proprietary tech? I mean Apple did
Speaker 10:  contribute home kit to matter, right? That's one of the basic
Speaker 10:  foundations of the new matter spec. So you know, in theory
Speaker 10:  maybe they could also contribute Airplay or Sonos could contribute
Speaker 10:  its proprietary tech. But again this, there's a lot more money
Speaker 10:  involved when it comes to speakers and music streaming services than there
Speaker 10:  is smart plugs. Yeah. And the person I spoke to said
Speaker 10:  ultimately what's gonna shift Sonos and bows is consumer
Speaker 10:  pressure. So the more people complain about, you know, not being able to
Speaker 10:  use their other speakers with their fancy Sonos speakers, the more
Speaker 10:  consumer pressure there is, the more likely these companies are to sort
Speaker 10:  of have to start coming along playing the game. But you know, whether it
Speaker 10:  ever, ever happens, I think, you know, matter's got a lot of other things
Speaker 10:  to sort out first.
Speaker 2:  Okay. I've gotta interrupt the multi room audio discourse because we've gotta
Speaker 2:  take a break and then we'll be back to talk more about the matter situation
Speaker 2:  and dive even deeper on Sonos.
Speaker 2:  Okay, we're back. Chris Welch, you, you have a, a
Speaker 2:  keen inside knowledge over there at Sonos. You, you, you have an ability
Speaker 2:  to just kind of figure out what they're working on. Are they thinking about
Speaker 2:  matter or you, are you seeing anything from them that suggests that they
Speaker 2:  have any interest in kind of changing their, their business model?
Speaker 9:  I think they last, they were taking a look at it. I think they're on the
Speaker 9:  group or in the group, right? You know, they're, they're they're present.
Speaker 9:  They haven't really just made any promises about you know, what's coming
Speaker 9:  or, or any of that. I think like we're also seeing talking about pressure
Speaker 9:  that like might not really exist cuz like how many people own like several
Speaker 9:  different platforms of these speakers, right? If you buy a Sonos, you're
Speaker 9:  gonna, that you're gonna lean Sonos when you want a soundbar, when you want
Speaker 9:  a portable speaker, you're gonna buy the room. And so like once you commit
Speaker 9:  to one, like the odds of you straying from that and starting on like a
Speaker 9:  home pod is kind of strange. Yeah
Speaker 2:  It kind of feels like Sonos is in this space where Apple was for a very long
Speaker 2:  time where Apple was very, very expensive versus everybody else. So you,
Speaker 2:  right, you had to have enough money to actually afford it and but then when
Speaker 2:  you did it, it just worked. And so you're like, okay, well it just works
Speaker 2:  so I'm gonna, I've got enough money to afford it so I'm gonna stay in this
Speaker 2:  ecosystem and, and Sonos seems super
Speaker 2:  comfortable doing the same thing. Being like, look we, we've really, we did
Speaker 2:  one that is Atmos now there's a rumor that they might be doing more
Speaker 2:  speakers that fire upwards, more Atmos enabled speakers. Like
Speaker 2:  they recognize there's the demand and they're gonna meet it
Speaker 2:  but at their pace and with their app,
Speaker 9:  Right? Like I would argue for the last few years, last year at least they
Speaker 9:  were focused on like the lower end with the Sonos Ray and the Rome. Over
Speaker 9:  the past couple years they've been trying to like slide downward and now
Speaker 9:  this year they're going back upward toward the high end. So we're gonna see
Speaker 9:  some new speakers in the next few months and I'm sure we're gonna have the
Speaker 9:  audio file conversation all over again. Like is this audio file quality?
Speaker 9:  Who knows? I think the Sonos five is like the best sounding speaker among
Speaker 9:  all the tech players at least. Like it's better than a home pod. It's better
Speaker 9:  than any studio from Amazon, the Echo Studio. So like in terms of like
Speaker 9:  they're a pretty small company to like do that and to like have that footing
Speaker 9:  is pretty decent.
Speaker 11:  Honestly the smartest thing they've done to me was other stuff with Ikea.
Speaker 11:  Like they have a bunch of really solid Ikea smart home stuff and being
Speaker 11:  like, hey we want a foothold in what is very clearly an
Speaker 11:  affordable ecosystem that, that you are selling at like bulk
Speaker 11:  for pretty, you know what I mean? Like
Speaker 9:  Start young as college students and get 'em book on Sonos right away.
Speaker 11:  That's a smart move. But it also traps you into that ecosystem. And I think
Speaker 11:  a lot of those are probably two devices too, which is also nice, you know
Speaker 11:  what I mean? I don't necessarily want to own an IKEA speakers but they're
Speaker 11:  like apparently pretty okay. You know what I mean? Like they're not bad.
Speaker 11:  I do think the question of like, you know, consumer pressure
Speaker 11:  is one of like how frustrated is your mom gonna be when she, when one of
Speaker 11:  these breaks and then she has to buy another one Or like, you know, I think
Speaker 11:  it's like the smart bulb thing. I mean that's the reason why you're seeing
Speaker 11:  matter is cuz it's like you have like people who don't pay enough attention
Speaker 11:  to this who get something like home and then they're like, oh but
Speaker 11:  this is a wifi bulb, shouldn't it work? And then they're like, no, you have
Speaker 11:  to get this other one. And it's like, that's more frustrating to me.
Speaker 11:  Like that is an actual point of pain for like normal consumers and
Speaker 11:  it goes against the whole, it's just easy. It's like, yeah, it's just easy
Speaker 11:  but you have to get a thing that you use all the time and like it, it's
Speaker 11:  that that's, I'm sorry, I I'm done with that. I'm re I really, and
Speaker 11:  I do think that like the very fact that that it took this long to get this
Speaker 11:  little puck says a lot that it does this a lot cuz it's something that like
Speaker 11:  upwards of decades that it was just like, I just want a thing that you plug
Speaker 11:  into a speaker and it works and it's, and it works over wifi has been like
Speaker 11:  upwards of a decade of just people being like, oh you can get that, but
Speaker 11:  it's like you gotta get this like blue node amp and like it's expensive
Speaker 11:  but it works. And it's like, it's just more niche
Speaker 11:  versions of that. And then like somebody was like, oh okay here's a Texas
Speaker 11:  instrument stack we put with in like a Nordic instruments within an Nordic
Speaker 11:  instruments chip or whatever. It's like it's very, it wasn't that hard and
Speaker 11:  the fact, and it's like clown carve stuff to me it's like all these people
Speaker 11:  trying to like do solve all these problems when there was this one demand
Speaker 11:  that people wanted. And when I posted that article, somebody responded with,
Speaker 11:  I just did my system entirely Sonos and now I am regretting it
Speaker 11:  because this is what I wanted because they were funneled into it.
Speaker 10:  Yeah, that's exactly why I think, I mean, Chris, you're right people now
Speaker 10:  when they buy Sonos, they go Sonos. But because you kind of have to, I
Speaker 10:  think Sonos would actually open itself up to a wider market, which is what's
Speaker 10:  happened with Matter. That's why everyone got together with Matter because
Speaker 10:  they're like, I think this is gonna bring the smart home to a wider market.
Speaker 10:  But if you could, if you already have five decent
Speaker 10:  speakers around your home, like a few echo dots and maybe an Echo studio
Speaker 10:  and you want a soundbar, you're not gonna go buy a Sonos because
Speaker 10:  it's not gonna you, you're not gonna able to connect it with your other
Speaker 10:  speakers in the same way in this multi room audio way. But if Sonos worked
Speaker 10:  with those other speakers, you might go buy it. So, you know, I feel like,
Speaker 10:  I mean, right, it works great for people that are happy to either do an
Speaker 10:  entire system in Sonos or swap out what they already have and get Sonos.
Speaker 10:  But if you wanna add to what you have or if you wanna start small and
Speaker 10:  build but wanna have options, you can't really do that. I mean you can to
Speaker 10:  some extent, but it's not easy as we've illustrated. We, we know the technology's
Speaker 10:  there and we just, I feel like the companies, I understand
Speaker 10:  that they've got their proprietary technology or their, you know, they want
Speaker 10:  to kind of keep you in their system but giving consumers choice is never
Speaker 10:  gonna be a bad thing in the long run. I think if you've got a good enough
Speaker 10:  product, they will come to you if you give them that flexibility.
Speaker 10:  You know, at the end of all this, I have probably 20
Speaker 10:  smarts because in my house and I've, and paid for an
Speaker 10:  entire Sono system because my husband loves it
Speaker 10:  and because it just works and he gets so frustrated with stuff that doesn't
Speaker 10:  work and he, I remember when I first started working at The Verge, he's
Speaker 10:  like, does that mean you're not gonna get to test any cool audio equipment
Speaker 10:  anymore? I'm like, no. I said, if you want that, you're just gonna have
Speaker 10:  to move in with Chris
Speaker 10:  because,
Speaker 10:  And so, you know, for Christmas I got him the beam and then this Christmas
Speaker 10:  I got him the big sub thing and he loves it and it just
Speaker 10:  works.
Speaker 2:  I'm gonna say this like, you know, we can rag on on Sonos audio
Speaker 2:  quality compared to like similarly price dumb
Speaker 2:  speakers, but that sub is mighty good.
Speaker 11:  Put a sub in two play fives together.
Speaker 10:  A whole house shakes
Speaker 2:  So much money on that sub. Well it's good because like a lot of times subs
Speaker 2:  could be kind of, I guess the word it's floppy, right? Like the base is there,
Speaker 2:  but it, it overwhelms and it's a good tight, like it's, it's a, it it really
Speaker 2:  controls its base really, really nicely. So it never overwhelms
Speaker 2:  but it still gives you that kind of like in your chest rumble when
Speaker 2:  whatever's happening in Dune is happening.
Speaker 9:  So we covered the S one and S two stuff. I think they handled that poorly.
Speaker 9:  They could've handled that better, but like they still have the S one app
Speaker 9:  available. Like, so think of Apple or Amazon maintaining the old version
Speaker 9:  of their service, like just to keep old hardware running. It's kind of
Speaker 9:  unthinkable, right? So like, I think like they only cut off actually one
Speaker 9:  or two like ancient speakers. Like even the play three, I just died outta
Speaker 9:  the office yesterday. That's on S two that's got, you know, like all the
Speaker 9:  current stuff.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, the, the play base was kind of their first weird
Speaker 2:  attempt at at a, at a speaker, right? A flop, different kinda
Speaker 2:  soundbar. I know
Speaker 9:  That's still fully supported
Speaker 2:  And it's fully supported and that was one of those things that like has kept
Speaker 2:  me on Sonos as long as it has is because it, that is supported. I, I'm not
Speaker 2:  having to look the minute that stops working because of
Speaker 2:  of, you know, something happens at Sonos, I'm out of that ecosystem cuz it's
Speaker 2:  like right, I I now know that the whim exists and if I go and
Speaker 2:  I get my own speakers and I plug them into the whim, I can have that same
Speaker 2:  experience that with Sonos I would have to go and get all my own speakers
Speaker 2:  and then plug it into, is it the
Speaker 9:  Connect and the amp too?
Speaker 2:  Yep. Yeah and the amp you can add all of your audio stuff but it's
Speaker 2:  cost like four or $500 and the whim cost. How much Chris?
Speaker 11:  It's 80 or 90 I think. I think they may have, they it was
Speaker 11:  on sale and then they like uns sailed it while I bought the article. So
Speaker 11:  it's like eight or 90.
Speaker 10:  I bet they did.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, they're like, excuse
Speaker 11:  Us. Yeah, yeah, yeah. I'm sorry but like, yeah, no, it's, it's cheap, you
Speaker 11:  know what I mean? And if it, it's cool because like even though it has like
Speaker 11:  it has an okay d you know what I mean? It's like, it's like just a ti chip
Speaker 11:  it Carly costs like five bucks or something like that. Yeah. But like, because
Speaker 11:  it has optical audio, if you have, if you're the kind of person who wants
Speaker 11:  their own deck, you just put the optical into whatever
Speaker 11:  good deck you have and then it will do the conversion there. Which is part
Speaker 11:  of the reason why guys on forms like it's cuz it's bit perfect and it
Speaker 11:  transfers it without recoding it just straight up like this is the
Speaker 11:  file here, you go to whatever DAK digital to
Speaker 11:  audio converter you have and like yeah, it's, it's a component. It's a part,
Speaker 11:  you know what I mean? Like I guess this is also like, I don't like sound
Speaker 11:  bars. Like I'm, I'm, I'm anti soundbar for the same
Speaker 2:  Reason. I'm shocked that you don't like sound bars
Speaker 11:  But it's the same thing. Yeah, of course. But like, but it's the
Speaker 11:  same thing where it's this like too clever by half thing, right? Where it's
Speaker 11:  like either I'm going to listen to my TV with the speakers that are inside
Speaker 11:  of it or I'm going to get real speakers, you know? Yeah. Like
Speaker 11:  it's it's it's one or the other even though I understand the form factor.
Speaker 10:  No, I mean and Sonos does have a, like you point out though, they do have
Speaker 10:  a good ecosystem. Like I bought the original Is it s what
Speaker 10:  what's the original little small speaker that's now the sl?
Speaker 2:  It's the one
Speaker 10:  Yeah, just the one originally. Yeah. Yeah. So I have two of those that are,
Speaker 10:  they're my rear and then I bought the, is it the Beam is the most expensive
Speaker 10:  or is the arc
Speaker 9:  Dark? The
Speaker 10:  Arc. So we have the arc samba and then we added the, the big boom boom
Speaker 10:  boom. But those two ones I've had since like they
Speaker 10:  came out what like in the early two thousands. I mean how long have they
Speaker 10:  been around? So that is great. You are able to use all those parts
Speaker 10:  together and that they haven't deprecated them. But as you say, if that,
Speaker 10:  that time comes, which is the problem with all of these
Speaker 10:  speakers though, I mean we hit hard on this in the version we should, but
Speaker 10:  you know, we need to know the lifespan of our technology. Like when you
Speaker 10:  buy it, there should be like an expiration date you, so you can be aware
Speaker 10:  of how long you're gonna have this product in your house. So that helps
Speaker 10:  you figure out whether it's actually worth spending, you know, $800 on a,
Speaker 10:  on an arc. Because there's been too many instances recently of companies
Speaker 10:  coming up saying, oh well we've decided that's just gonna last for another
Speaker 10:  year and then you're out of luck. And, and that's another one of the consumer
Speaker 10:  frustrations and this is another area where Matter could help because
Speaker 10:  you know, you could more easily replace a device, not have to spend the
Speaker 10:  same amount of money and still have the same experience. So
Speaker 10:  it, it's a tricky situation and there is no, unfortunately right now
Speaker 10:  I don't feel like there is the perfect solution.
Speaker 11:  I think we've got it
Speaker 10:  Though. Yeah. But I just don't honestly see a lot of regular people going
Speaker 10:  out and spending 80 or $90 on this. I can't see my parents
Speaker 10:  buying this and figuring out how to use it even if it is really easy.
Speaker 11:  But that's, this is the thing, it's like it's, it's, I've used it, it has
Speaker 11:  a really nice app. It's not that more more difficult. It's just the idea
Speaker 11:  of like we, I'm, I'm sorry this is just baked into the concept of the
Speaker 11:  all-in-one. Like I don't know, I go on gov deals a lot, which is like
Speaker 11:  government auction sites and I just see all the technology waste going like
Speaker 11:  you know like I walked into an e e-waste recycling center recently and it
Speaker 11:  was just racks and racks of Apple TVs and like you know these
Speaker 11:  things that like people like buy and then they're like oh
Speaker 11:  it's broken, what do I do with it? And like the more all in one you make
Speaker 11:  it the more waste you're gonna make. That's just how it works. You know
Speaker 11:  what I mean? Because we don't live in a culture anymore where these things
Speaker 11:  can be discreet and we don't live in, in a thing where it's prioritized
Speaker 11:  that like you know, you're gonna have a speaker and if the speaker breaks
Speaker 11:  well you go and get it fixed. You know, or you fix it yourself ideally,
Speaker 11:  which is what I would love is just people learning how to fix their own
Speaker 11:  stuff. Like the more all in one you make something, the worse
Speaker 11:  it's gonna be for the environment. Just generally speaking, the worse it's
Speaker 11:  gonna be for people because they're gonna throw shit away and they're gonna
Speaker 11:  like no, just just get back to like having a thing that does a thing and
Speaker 11:  then a thing you can add to a little system and simplify it for people.
Speaker 11:  And I think that there is a use case for that. Don't make it so that like
Speaker 11:  there are these virtual things like even if you accept the all in one element
Speaker 11:  of it, don't make it so that you also have to make it so that people throw
Speaker 11:  stuff away cuz it doesn't work with their other stuff. Cuz that's a thing
Speaker 11:  that a mom will do is just throw it away cuz it doesn't work with their
Speaker 11:  thing and they're like, well what's this then I'll give it to Goodwill or
Speaker 11:  something.
Speaker 10:  Chris Welch, what do you, what is your ultimate system? What do you use
Speaker 10:  for multi room music? Like when you aren't testing stuff?
Speaker 9:  I mean I've got a pretty small apartment here in Brooklyn so I've got the
Speaker 9:  Sonos five on my desk play five. I bought that several years ago. It still
Speaker 9:  sounds amazing. I've got the arc for my soundbar. I think so many people
Speaker 9:  just want pretty good, like Chris said, there's like a low end and a super
Speaker 9:  high end at the middle. I think Sonos also shoots for the pretty to very
Speaker 9:  good range with the arc. Like there would be no market for a $900 Sonos arc
Speaker 9:  if it didn't sound pretty good, there would be no market for a $1,400
Speaker 9:  Sennheiser soundbar that I'm, that I'm testing right now if they didn't like
Speaker 9:  actually blow people away in some sense. So I think, yeah so
Speaker 9:  I've got that and I've got the room for the shower and so I like my
Speaker 9:  shower tunes and the move, if I go work in the backyard on a nice day,
Speaker 10:  I feel like no one's really cracked the shower.
Speaker 9:  Sonos has said they're gonna be in four new product categories over the next
Speaker 9:  few years so maybe a shower, shower head speaker.
Speaker 11:  I do agree though that like that that is probably the most compelling app.
Speaker 11:  The the, the room is actually probably the, the thing that like works the
Speaker 11:  best cuz like the HomePod minis don't you have to plug into a wall
Speaker 11:  and like some people just like have one plugged into the wall in their bathroom
Speaker 11:  or something. Like they have little mounts for them and stuff which is
Speaker 10:  Yeah I've seen there's like mounts in the ceiling.
Speaker 11:  Yeah or like you can just do weird stuff like that. But like I do agree
Speaker 11:  that like airplane two devices that work
Speaker 11:  well that are battery powered is a, a thing that
Speaker 11:  I'm surprised Apple has not tackled yet but in part because it probably
Speaker 11:  messes with their HomePod demographic but like and also like there's plenty
Speaker 11:  of Bluetooth speakers, they don't need to like make another one unless it
Speaker 11:  has like a really strong use case but they are making that weird mirror
Speaker 11:  and that weird or that weird. What is it like iPads that are
Speaker 11:  like for the kitchen? I think they were, that was reported on.
Speaker 2:  Oh yeah, that's the, that's the rumor I think is that there's gonna be like
Speaker 2:  a HomePod with an iPad attached to it and we're all gonna
Speaker 2:  have 'em in our kitchen to make the best pies ever Apple presumably.
Speaker 10:  I do think the battery power is an interesting, like Amazon got out of the
Speaker 10:  battery powered speaker space. They had the tap which was, I love that thing
Speaker 10:  and the Bowes portable speaker is very good but very
Speaker 10:  expensive
Speaker 9:  So, but the Sonos move like you can buy a battery pack and swap it out
Speaker 9:  so when that battery builtin dies you can like keep it going so that's kind
Speaker 9:  of nice. Not something you see very often. So I think they do a
Speaker 9:  pretty decent job of like guaranteeing a pretty long lifespan for most of
Speaker 9:  their products. I dunno how the room's gonna be doing in like two years after
Speaker 9:  the battery's been charged a hundred times. But
Speaker 2:  Yeah I think that'll be a really interesting one for Sonos to deal with.
Speaker 2:  That's cuz it's their first battery based product, right?
Speaker 9:  Yeah that and the move, but you can swap out that battery. But yeah, I'm
Speaker 9:  pretty excited for what's gonna be coming up cause they just bought a company
Speaker 9:  in 2020 called Matt or Mate that makes like super small
Speaker 9:  transducers that put out big sound in a really small design
Speaker 9:  and we haven't seen the fruits of that purchase yet but maybe this
Speaker 9:  year.
Speaker 2:  Okay, well it sounds like we've kind of, we've kind of gotten gotten a lay
Speaker 2:  of the land. We know there's all this stuff like they're the smart speakers
Speaker 2:  and, and they're all doing their thing and they're doing it pretty well.
Speaker 2:  There is Sonos who does it really, really well if you are willing to spend
Speaker 2:  a lot of money. And then there is the whim and Roone audio, which
Speaker 2:  honestly sounds like Sonos. But for me, I am gonna go be basic and spend
Speaker 2:  money on it maybe. But it sounds like there's a lot of solutions out there.
Speaker 2:  Nothing's perfect. Please go fix matter,
Speaker 2:  Sonos and, and Bose if you hear this, get your guys in the room
Speaker 2:  with the other matter folks, let's, let's get on this, let's fix this.
Speaker 11:  Give airplay two away Apple cuz what are you doing with it? Yes,
Speaker 11:  that would be the other solution. It would literally only benefit you to
Speaker 11:  open that ecosystem up. I'm not joking.
Speaker 2:  Okay, that's it for the vergecast today. Thank you for listening. There's
Speaker 2:  a whole lot more stuff from this conversation on the verge.com and we put
Speaker 2:  a bunch of links in the show notes and if you have thoughts, feedbacks, feelings,
Speaker 2:  tips, you can always email us@vergecasttheverge.com
Speaker 2:  or you can call the hotline eight six six Verge 11, that's
Speaker 2:  eight six Verge 11. We may answer a question you have on a
Speaker 2:  future episode. This show is produced by Andrew Marino and Liam James.
Speaker 2:  Brooke Min is our editorial director of audio. The Vergecast is a
Speaker 2:  verge production and part of the Vox Media podcast network. We are gonna
Speaker 2:  be back on Friday with some more of the Verge crew to talk about all of the
Speaker 2:  biggest tech news of the week. So I'll see you then.