# Transcript
ID: 55d4bcdd-9352-4b1c-a006-8bede660dbcf
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Mythical computers and super apps
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/7305208835961661272/-5377100665432246571/s93290-US-4566s-1692777344.mp3
Description: Today on the flagship podcast of payment processing fees:
04:36 - The Verge's David Pierce travels to meet Keegan McNamara, an artisan who is making unique computers for more purposeful use cases.
A visit to the one-man computer factory
27:11 - Liz Lopatto and Alex Heath join the show to discuss the future of "super apps" in the United States — notably the one Elon Musk is trying to build with X, formerly known as Twitter.
Everything Elon Musk told Twitter employees in his first company meeting
Can Elon Musk turn Twitter into an ‘everything app’?
Here’s what Elon Musk wants to do with X, his ‘everything app’
1:09:54 - Keep listening for this week's Vergecast Hotline question.
What is a custom feed and how do I make one? – Reddit Help
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com, we love hearing from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Disabled
Speaker 2:  Welcome to The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of payment processing fees.
Speaker 2:  I'm your friend David Pierce and I am sitting here organizing my entire life
Speaker 2:  in Spotify. I think for the first time ever, I've been using this app for
Speaker 2:  over a decade and this is the first time I think I've ever done a full
Speaker 2:  reorganization of my life in here. And I'm doing it because there's
Speaker 2:  this one thing that has annoyed me about Spotify for forever, which is that
Speaker 2:  I have the music that I listen to when I'm in the car or I don't know,
Speaker 2:  at a barbecue or out with friends or just hanging out at home making dinner.
Speaker 2:  That's the music I would call like my music taste. And then
Speaker 2:  there's the music I listen to all day every day while I work. That's
Speaker 2:  the like Feelingsy instrumental music. It's a lot of movie
Speaker 2:  scores, it's a lot of kind of ambient bands that I like.
Speaker 2:  I play it a ton, but I wouldn't call that the music that I like and like
Speaker 2:  really want Spotify to tell me more about. And yet every year at the
Speaker 2:  end of the year, Spotify gives you that playlist with all your favorite songs
Speaker 2:  and it's like you listened to the Batman soundtrack
Speaker 2:  650,000 times, maybe you'd like to hear that again.
Speaker 2:  And I'm just like, that's not really what's going on here. And I kind of
Speaker 2:  always wanted Spotify to separate those things. Then when I had a kid
Speaker 2:  it got even worse because now I spend You know eight hours a day listening
Speaker 2:  to Elmo's song and I don't really want that in my algorithms either.
Speaker 2:  So I googled around and was like, this has to be a solvable problem. Spotify
Speaker 2:  has to have figured this out. And it turns out they kind of did. There was
Speaker 2:  this feature that Spotify rolled out in February of this year where
Speaker 2:  you can go into any playlist and you tap or click on the three
Speaker 2:  dots in the menu and you go to exclude from your
Speaker 2:  taste profile and you click it and it pops up this menu that says listening
Speaker 2:  to this playlist will have less impact on your taste profile and recommendations.
Speaker 2:  I don't know less means, but this is good news. This means I can dump
Speaker 2:  all the stuff that I wanna listen to all the time but don't want Spotify
Speaker 2:  to make recommendations based on into one place. So that's
Speaker 2:  essentially what I've been doing. I now have this monstrous playlist called
Speaker 2:  Music to Work to in Spotify that is just several hundred
Speaker 2:  songs so far of all the music that I play on repeat all
Speaker 2:  day every day while I work. And now I have another one called Kid
Speaker 2:  that is just kid music and I can just basically put that on and shuffle
Speaker 2:  it and do the same with my work music all day and neither one will get in
Speaker 2:  the way of what's in my on Repeat or my Discover Weekly or my Spotify
Speaker 2:  raps every year. This is the dream. I can't believe Didn didn't know about
Speaker 2:  this sooner. Oh my gosh, it's so much work to move all of my stuff around
Speaker 2:  in playlists, but I think it's gonna be worth it. Anyway, we have an awesome
Speaker 2:  show coming up for you today. I'm gonna tell you a story about a guy I met
Speaker 2:  in LA who's making a really different kind of computer
Speaker 2:  and then after that we're gonna talk about super apps because they're kind
Speaker 2:  of lingering in the news all the time. Everybody is trying to build
Speaker 2:  the one app in which you live your entire life and it turns out
Speaker 2:  it's really hard and really complicated. Elon Musk wants to do it now
Speaker 2:  and I just don't think it's possible all that is coming up in just a second.
Speaker 2:  But first I just realized I have like a decade worth of monthly
Speaker 2:  playlists. I've just been saving songs I like every month and now I have
Speaker 2:  a chance to actually put all of those together. I have so many playlists,
Speaker 2:  my Spotify is a disaster. I don't recommend ever actually trying to
Speaker 2:  solve this problem unless you really wanna solve this problem, but it's making
Speaker 2:  me feel better already. This is The Vergecast. We'll be right back.
Speaker 3:  This podcast is supported by Humans versus Machines, a new series
Speaker 3:  about the promise and perils of artificial intelligence with cognitive
Speaker 3:  scientists and AI entrepreneur Gary Marcus. For all
Speaker 3:  AI's progress in the last 70 years, fraud detection, speech
Speaker 3:  translation, chat, G P T. Do we know how to build ai? We can
Speaker 3:  trust humans versus machines. Digs into the AI history, present
Speaker 3:  and future, bringing to life some of the biggest breakthroughs and failures
Speaker 3:  along with the ways we might change it. Humans versus Machines with Gary
Speaker 3:  Marcus is available now. Wherever you listen.
Speaker 3:  Support for this episode comes from Siren Marine, a Yamaha company
Speaker 3:  At this point. smart Home Technology is everywhere and for good reason Well
Speaker 3:  with siren, marine boat owners can take advantage of the same high tech
Speaker 3:  convenience. Their smart boat monitoring system makes it easy to monitor
Speaker 3:  your vessel's, vital signs from anywhere. With a simple app that offers realtime
Speaker 3:  information about battery levels, exact location, and so much more.
Speaker 3:  It all adds up to a connected boat that's more secure than ever before. Siren,
Speaker 3:  Marine Your home is smart. Your boat should be too To. learn more.
Speaker 3:  Visit Siren Marine dot com slash Verge.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. I wanna tell you about this computer I saw a few months
Speaker 2:  ago, which is unlike any other computer I've ever seen.
Speaker 2:  I first saw it in a picture on Twitter in March of this year, but a
Speaker 2:  couple of months later I got to see it in person. The, Verge, VE and Pavich
Speaker 2:  and I went to LA, got an Uber up this windy Canyon
Speaker 2:  Road kind of near the U C L A campus in Westwood and we
Speaker 2:  went into this cool two story house right up against a canyon
Speaker 2:  and we met a guy named Keegan McNamara. I'll tell you more about Keegan
Speaker 2:  in one second, but first I have to tell you about this computer.
Speaker 2:  Keegan calls it the mythic one, Roman numeral one. It's all very
Speaker 2:  fancy and he built this thing himself like every single part of it.
Speaker 2:  I
Speaker 5:  Was pitching it as like something that looks very different from a normal
Speaker 5:  computer. It's made outta wood and it's functionally like very limited
Speaker 5:  compared to a MacBook. It's like a a limited computational experience.
Speaker 2:  The computer is in fact made out of wood, walnut and
Speaker 2:  maple to be specific. Keegan bought big blocks then sod
Speaker 2:  and chiseled them into a shape. I can really only describe as a
Speaker 2:  sports car typewriter. You have a slightly inclined tray
Speaker 2:  in the front where there's a mechanical keyboard with some white keys and
Speaker 2:  some beige keys and a brown leather palm rest. Then the
Speaker 2:  whole thing slopes dramatically upward. Like you're going up a cliff,
Speaker 2:  there's an eight inch screen in the middle, three little lights on the left
Speaker 2:  side and a keyhole and an ignition switch. Seriously on the right,
Speaker 2:  the slope goes up to this Peak just above the screen and then sort of
Speaker 2:  curves back down in the back. It looks like a retro
Speaker 2:  futuristic design from the 1950s. Like in the era when
Speaker 2:  TVs were in those huge wooden cabinets, this would fit
Speaker 2:  right in.
Speaker 5:  What my method was was like just look at a bunch of
Speaker 5:  really pretty things, You know things that I find to be beautiful or interesting
Speaker 5:  for aesthetic reasons. Read what people think about them, read about how
Speaker 5:  they were designed and like the people that designed them just sort of You
Speaker 5:  know, take it all in for a while. And then after doing that for like a month,
Speaker 5:  two months, three months, you kind of sit down and try to start doing the
Speaker 5:  the sculptural aspect of the drawing aspect And like things just
Speaker 5:  come. It's very weird. You don't, they're just kind of there in the
Speaker 5:  background and you're not thinking about them. Like the unconscious is a
Speaker 5:  very strange domain. You know, like I had a friend
Speaker 5:  come over and he was like, oh so you made a car computer And I was like,
Speaker 5:  you, I kind, I kind of made a car computer. But like also it's different
Speaker 5:  in strange ways. You know, like it's just kind of a confluence of a bunch
Speaker 5:  of the the things that I find to be beautiful.
Speaker 2:  My absolute favorite thing about this computer is how you turn it on.
Speaker 2:  You put a key into that hole next to the screen and turn it to the right.
Speaker 2:  As soon as you do a red light turns on on the left side, then
Speaker 2:  you reach up and flip the ignition switch and the lights on the left blink
Speaker 2:  yellow and then green and then the computer turns on turning on. This
Speaker 2:  computer feels like launching a missile from a submarine in an old spy movie.
Speaker 2:  Commence underwater search it rules
Speaker 2:  the whole thing is powered by an intel nook, which is basically an
Speaker 2:  all-in-one configurable mini computer.
Speaker 5:  I mean the easier option would've been just like a raspberry pie. They expose
Speaker 5:  a bunch of pins and You know, make it make it super easy to like make stuff.
Speaker 5:  But I've experimented with raspberry pies in the past and I, I just in
Speaker 5:  general found 'em to be like rather underpowered. And this was something
Speaker 5:  when you're, when you're making something that's like luxurious and it feels
Speaker 5:  beautiful, you don't want it to be like stunted by the electronics. You want
Speaker 5:  it to feel like blazing fast. And I think that like modern intel processors
Speaker 5:  are You know modern like ram amounts, all this kind of stuff. They are
Speaker 5:  unbelievably whip fast when you're doing something relatively simple, right?
Speaker 5:  The only reason that they ever get bogged down is by something like Google
Speaker 5:  Chrome, which has just an unfathomable amount of complexity
Speaker 5:  in the software. But yeah, when you're doing like Unix C stuff, my God
Speaker 5:  and like an I seven from 2020 is gonna be
Speaker 5:  unreal.
Speaker 2:  There's also eight gigs of ram in here and 250 gigs of storage.
Speaker 2:  Both are in a certain sense massive overkill because this
Speaker 2:  computer doesn't run chrome or games or anything complicated at
Speaker 2:  all for Keegan, it's pretty much a text editor.
Speaker 2:  It runs an operating system called Nix oss, which is a version of Linux
Speaker 2:  that's designed to be super modular and configurable. If you want
Speaker 2:  tons of apps and UI stuff, nix OSS can do that. But
Speaker 2:  the way Keegan's computer runs, it's much closer to just a command line.
Speaker 2:  Keegan says he just wanted his computer to be a text editor for writing and
Speaker 2:  reading, not a full fledged computer in the way that we've come to think
Speaker 2:  of it with all the power and options and apps and distractions that come
Speaker 2:  with it. He has a MacBook that is great for MacBook things
Speaker 2:  with this. He wanted something else.
Speaker 2:  Oh and in case you're wondering about what kind of keyboard he would put
Speaker 2:  into a computer designed entirely for typing. Oh boy did that ever
Speaker 2:  send Keegan down a rabbit hole?
Speaker 5:  This is a god tier mechanical keyboard. Like this is like two different
Speaker 5:  key cap sets and they're P B T keys. 'cause I like the th of that and like
Speaker 5:  this is a a hot swap p c b underneath and like I have
Speaker 5:  like foam padding and an aluminum plate because I like a little bit of ping
Speaker 5:  this but not the pings of brass and like You know I'm, I mean you can, you
Speaker 5:  get, you're welcome to type on it here. I
Speaker 2:  Would very much like to what? Oh man,
Speaker 5:  The switches are hand lubed glorious pandas.
Speaker 2:  I mean these, these feel fantastic. Not wild about the arrow keys, but I'll
Speaker 2:  get you some. I should be clear here. He didn't build this thing
Speaker 2:  to like start a computer startup. It was more like a summer project
Speaker 2:  starting in the summer of 2022. Keegan was a few years out
Speaker 2:  of college and had done a couple of tech jobs but was kind of
Speaker 2:  disillusioned with the whole space and was trying to figure out what he
Speaker 2:  wanted to do next. And then one day he went to the Metropolitan Museum of
Speaker 2:  Art in New York City and happened upon an exhibit called Arms and Armory.
Speaker 5:  It's hard for me to explain it this way because it feels weird to say it
Speaker 5:  feels like it doesn't actually happen to people, but I literally had like
Speaker 5:  a light bulb moment. The main thing that occurred to me was like, these are
Speaker 5:  functional objects. They're guns, they shoot projectiles out of a
Speaker 5:  tube. You know it doesn't have ornamentation, it's not made out of like exquisite
Speaker 5:  materials, it doesn't have gold inlay, You know stuff like this. But there
Speaker 5:  were people 3, 4, 500 years ago that thought it was
Speaker 5:  worthwhile to add that additional layer of like, I don't know,
Speaker 5:  I think the right word is beauty onto a merely utilitarian object.
Speaker 5:  And I was like, man, nowadays that just doesn't really exist. Like, and
Speaker 5:  especially it doesn't exist for computers. I'd been thinking about
Speaker 5:  computers prior in like a, a philosophical sure way.
Speaker 5:  And so it was just, it was very natural for me to be like, that's the object
Speaker 5:  that is most tractable for me personally to work on.
Speaker 5:  And You know, I went home and sat down on my MacBook and I You know I like
Speaker 5:  you're like examining every single facet of the MacBook and like how it's
Speaker 5:  machined and what the choices are. And one of my gripes always with the
Speaker 5:  MacBook is like when you put it on a table and you rest your wrists on it,
Speaker 5:  there's like this, there's like this sharp edge that like digs into your
Speaker 5:  wrist like okay, there's something off here You know like and even
Speaker 5:  just the shape of it, it's like a metal rectangle. Sure, it's like a very
Speaker 5:  well machined metal rectangle, but it is just a metal rectangle and compared
Speaker 5:  to the sort of like form experimentation and engraving and all this kind
Speaker 5:  of stuff that that I saw in the guns, I was like yeah, this is just a completely
Speaker 5:  different design philosophy and I really, I think it's the design philosophy
Speaker 5:  of Johnny Ive right and You know I respect him like he's a good industrial
Speaker 5:  designer, but there's something about modern industrial design that feels
Speaker 5:  like very cold and inhuman to me. Whereas working with materials like wood
Speaker 5:  and leather You know, it can kind of seem like catch up front maybe. But
Speaker 5:  I think that what you end up having in terms of like the felt
Speaker 5:  weight and the psychological weight of the object after, after it's created
Speaker 5:  is just like it's warmer, it's nicer, it feels more personal,
Speaker 5:  it feels just like better overall.
Speaker 2:  Keegan became kind of obsessed with finding this ornate
Speaker 2:  beauty in these everyday objects. He got really into learning about
Speaker 2:  luthier the people who make and fix one of a kind guitars in their
Speaker 2:  workshops. He went to the house Ray and Charles Eames used to build the famous
Speaker 2:  Eames furniture in, which is now a museum.
Speaker 5:  When I went in I, I was sort of imagining too like what, what would
Speaker 5:  a computer that actually fits inside of this very eclectic, strange house
Speaker 5:  look like and You know. I think that this is perfect. Like I think that this,
Speaker 5:  this would match the aesthetic almost perfectly. Like maybe it's not quite
Speaker 5:  rectangular enough but it's really close and the materials are spot
Speaker 5:  on and I think it would fit really well in there too.
Speaker 2:  He also got really into fancy cars, not as a car guy but as a
Speaker 2:  design guy. What can you learn from the shape of a Bugatti?
Speaker 2:  What does the ultra high-end leather in a pagani make you
Speaker 2:  feel that's different from the other things that drive down the highway?
Speaker 2:  All that stuff, all those shapes and materials and feelings
Speaker 2:  swirling around in his brain went into what became the mythic
Speaker 2:  one.
Speaker 5:  This back curve right here that's like straight out of, out of
Speaker 5:  an Italian sports car. Okay, You know that's like the, the rear hip is something
Speaker 5:  that you, that you really don't see anywhere except for in Italian sports
Speaker 5:  cars, which I think that comes from big cats
Speaker 5:  like tigers and leopards and You know all these sorts of things.
Speaker 2:  Keegan's other thing is that he only works with hand tools.
Speaker 6:  Sorry,
Speaker 2:  I wish I, he's had some practice in woodworking. He learned a bunch from
Speaker 2:  his dad growing up and took a guitar making class in college, but he also
Speaker 2:  just kind of decided to figure it out as he goes. Again, summer
Speaker 2:  project, not startup founder here, he uses a hand saw to cut the
Speaker 2:  wood into kind of its rough shape and then a mallet and chisel to do the
Speaker 2:  curves and then a spoke shave and a card scraper to get everything just
Speaker 2:  right. It's super, super, super tedious. But he says he loves
Speaker 2:  the actual process of woodworking but also what it means,
Speaker 2:  and this in our whole time together is where he got the most
Speaker 2:  philosophical about how he thinks about this stuff and he revealed
Speaker 2:  I guess what you might call the unified theory of Keegan McNamara
Speaker 5:  In Shintoism. There are these spirits called Kami that will come to
Speaker 5:  reside in objects that are made in the right way and You know the right
Speaker 5:  way is a, it's open to interpretation, but my personal interpretation and
Speaker 5:  just from like using power tools in general is that you're like
Speaker 5:  marring something and yeah, that's something that I care about in general
Speaker 5:  is like trying to, especially when it's in my own hands, crafting objects
Speaker 5:  that a KA could come to dwell in, in this, in this Shinto
Speaker 5:  spiritual understanding.
Speaker 2:  I asked him right after that if he felt like there was Kami in the computer
Speaker 2:  he made,
Speaker 5:  Yes, to me this feels like it has been crafted correctly. Like I You know
Speaker 5:  if I, if I were Shinto I would say, yeah, there's a commun in here. Like
Speaker 5:  for sure there's a commun in there. I love that it's, it's been crafted with
Speaker 5:  with care and under my understanding of the right way, which even if it's
Speaker 5:  wrong, I think has some importance.
Speaker 2:  Does all that sound sort of ridiculous and high minded to you? Like a
Speaker 2:  kid who made a computer just trying to tell you some mystical story
Speaker 2:  about it. If it does, trust me, you're not the only one. When
Speaker 2:  Keegan finished the computer earlier this year, put the key in the ignition,
Speaker 2:  booted it up, everything worked, all the lights, he was very excited.
Speaker 5:  Top 10 Keegan life moments kind of kind of thing. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Then like you do, he decided to post about this new computer in a bunch of
Speaker 2:  places. He uploaded pictures of the mythic one to Reddit and Twitter all
Speaker 2:  with the same caption. I wanted a beautiful computer and couldn't find one
Speaker 2:  so I made my own. the whole thing went kind of viral on Twitter and
Speaker 2:  Reddit. Most people were really nice. They liked the throwback design and
Speaker 2:  the retro futuristic vibe. They liked the idea of making
Speaker 2:  computers that last and they loved, they loved the key
Speaker 2:  ignition. Some people actually wanted a mythic computer of their own, but
Speaker 2:  not everyone saw the world the way McNamara did. He pointed me to
Speaker 2:  a hacker news thread, which is the developer focused site where people talk
Speaker 2:  about stuff and it was brutal. Lemme just read you a few of these.
Speaker 2:  Oh Lord, another hipster. I think that's the top ranked comment here.
Speaker 2:  Another one says Hooray for their four years of instant mastery.
Speaker 2:  One says the pseudo intellectual tradd vibes were overwhelming. And then
Speaker 2:  another one says it's really cool that this 25 year old invented PC
Speaker 2:  case modification. There are a bunch like that.
Speaker 2:  Ultimately Keegan says he figures a lot of the backlash was to his writing
Speaker 2:  style. He'd also posted an essay about how and why he built
Speaker 2:  the mythic one. And to be fair, it does sound kind of pretentious.
Speaker 2:  Like here's one section. Despite little improvement in overall user
Speaker 2:  experience quality, there has been a colossal rapid growth of new applications
Speaker 2:  over the last three decades. Modern personal computers are like 1,001.
Speaker 2:  Multi tools made from plastic people deserve one in one tools made from high
Speaker 2:  grade steel. A good exercise here is considering the net impact of various
Speaker 2:  types of applications on individuals and societies. I mean you can
Speaker 2:  see how that might piss off some tech types You know what I mean? Say this
Speaker 2:  for Keegan though. I think he really does believe what he says. I
Speaker 2:  don't think he hates technology per se. He said that that to me a few times.
Speaker 2:  It's just that he believes there are better ways or at least other
Speaker 2:  ways to do things and it turns out that at least a few people
Speaker 2:  agreed with him enough to reach out and see if maybe Keegan might make them
Speaker 2:  a mythic computer.
Speaker 2:  One of those people was Max Novan Stern who has been around Silicon Valley
Speaker 2:  circles for a while and who is probably best known as the co-founder of
Speaker 2:  World Coin, the crypto company that wants to scan your irises and Max
Speaker 2:  had actually been rethinking his own relationship with technology recently.
Speaker 7:  Computers are these like tools for
Speaker 7:  liberation and also like tools for enslavement.
Speaker 7:  You know it's pretty bifurcated, right? Phones
Speaker 7:  kind of make you feel like shit, right? Right. Computers aren't very
Speaker 7:  productive or it's like hard to do productive work at your computer. It just
Speaker 7:  is.
Speaker 2:  A couple of weeks before Keegan posted about the mythic computer, max had
Speaker 2:  tweeted about wanting something basically exactly like it. This was his
Speaker 2:  tweet. It says, give me an e-reader with a chat bot and note system and nothing
Speaker 2:  else. Give me a typewriter with the same strip computers of their
Speaker 2:  dopamine faucets leave their crystal balls. Max and Keegan started
Speaker 2:  talking. They knew each other a little bit already actually, and then
Speaker 2:  reconnected about these shared device dreams and Max ended up giving
Speaker 2:  that same prompt to Keegan. No dopamine faucets, just crystal
Speaker 2:  balls.
Speaker 5:  So what are the dopamine faucets of a computer? Well, I think most of the
Speaker 5:  dopamine faucets actually just come from the internet. Pragmatically, you
Speaker 5:  can get like most of the stripping of the dopamine faucets by just
Speaker 5:  like heavily restricting internet access. In this case it's completely gone,
Speaker 5:  but in the case of the one that I'm building for him, there'll be like a
Speaker 5:  couple IP addresses that can get through the firewall, namely the ones to
Speaker 5:  like interesting open AI products
Speaker 2:  Chat. G P T was one of those crystal walls that Max was talking about.
Speaker 2:  Ultimately he landed on four things that he wanted in a computer. He wanted
Speaker 2:  a really good experience for writing and reading text. He wanted speech to
Speaker 2:  text transcription with the whisper AI so he could just pace around his office
Speaker 2:  and dictate to his computer. He wanted chat G B T integration and he wanted
Speaker 2:  a receipt printer so he could quickly print off a grocery list or a piece
Speaker 2:  of text and take it with him.
Speaker 7:  It's like a typewriter, a secretary you could dictate to
Speaker 7:  and then a researcher who can, you could ask questions
Speaker 7:  and they'll give you in plain text answers to those questions.
Speaker 7:  And so that's a word processor rhythm and cap board, whisper
Speaker 7:  transcription and then Chachi. BT
Speaker 2:  At first Keegan balked at some of this. His mythic one doesn't connect to
Speaker 2:  the internet at all and that's kind of part of his ethos. Again, this is
Speaker 2:  supposed to be a a quiet, serene kind of computer, but talking to Max
Speaker 2:  convinced him that if you could essentially boil the whole internet down
Speaker 2:  to a interactive text interface, that that felt more
Speaker 2:  right more in the spirit of what he was trying to do. And in the future as
Speaker 2:  more and more of the AI power can be run locally without any
Speaker 2:  connection at all, a computer like this could be just as powerful and not
Speaker 2:  ever need to be online. Eventually Max and Keegan agreed
Speaker 2:  on a design and a price. They didn't want to tell me the price on the record,
Speaker 2:  but think more like used Car money rather than MacBook Money.
Speaker 2:  Keegan spent the next few months on that computer and he finished it in late
Speaker 2:  July. He ended up calling it the Mythic two and he personally
Speaker 2:  drove it up to the Bay Area and delivered it to Max's house. Max is
Speaker 2:  unfortunately away on vacation for a while, so he hasn't used it yet. So
Speaker 2:  I don't know how he feels, but I know he was very excited to get it. Having
Speaker 2:  built two of these now and talking with folks about more commissions,
Speaker 2:  Keegan told me he's hoping this might be something like his career for a
Speaker 2:  while. He can be a computer luthier in a certain way
Speaker 2:  and in the process he seems to hope that he might help change the
Speaker 2:  way we think about computers altogether.
Speaker 5:  I can imagine a world where there are like You know eight different guys
Speaker 5:  spread out all across the place that like each are very interested in one
Speaker 5:  specific portion of like the metallurgy basically of a computer. You
Speaker 5:  got the guy who's doing the processors in his garage and you got the guy
Speaker 5:  who's like figuring out how to do e ink in his garage and then you got the
Speaker 5:  guy who's like doing the woodworking. I guess that's me. You know there's
Speaker 5:  like, there are different components that can be figured out in their entirety
Speaker 5:  sort of from scratch at like less capability than what is like industry
Speaker 5:  standard nowadays. But a lot of the time you don't need the
Speaker 5:  modern capabilities like you can get away with having worse,
Speaker 5:  worse hardware.
Speaker 2:  I've been thinking about this kind of philosophy for months and personally
Speaker 2:  I like my MacBook a lot, but I like the idea of a computer
Speaker 2:  that by design doesn't do everything, that does a couple of things
Speaker 2:  really well that feels more like a well made single purpose
Speaker 2:  tool than a kind of janky Swiss army knife. And I
Speaker 2:  especially like the idea of bringing the tech industry back to a place
Speaker 2:  of experimentation and ideas. It's a bummer that
Speaker 2:  everyone converged on metal rectangles for laptops and big candy
Speaker 2:  bar slabs of glass for phones. Those can't be the only ideas
Speaker 2:  or the right answers. I don't think there have to be right answers. When
Speaker 2:  I was talking to Max, he compared what Keegan is doing to the whole idea
Speaker 2:  of the resurgence of dumb phones. You know these devices
Speaker 2:  that make calls and send texts and really don't do much else.
Speaker 2:  I've been fascinated by these things like the light phone and the punked
Speaker 2:  for years because I think it's a really interesting and complicated thing.
Speaker 2:  How do you sell people? What is an objectively worse phone?
Speaker 2:  It's weird, right? And what does it actually need in order to be useful?
Speaker 2:  You think about it, right? Phone calls good texts, good. You probably need
Speaker 2:  Google Maps. You want something to play music, but do you add Snapchat? Do
Speaker 2:  you add TikTok? Do you add Instagram? Do you add a web browser? At what point
Speaker 2:  have you just rebuilt the thing? Only slightly worse? I
Speaker 2:  agree that these do everything all in one devices have tipped a little
Speaker 2:  too far, but it's really hard to figure out where the middle ground is.
Speaker 2:  Ultimately. The thing I've come around to is that actually maybe the answer
Speaker 2:  is lots of answers. Maybe we need to go back to a time where
Speaker 2:  instead of a smartphone that does everything, we should incorporate a few
Speaker 2:  specific tools back into our lives that do one thing and do it really well.
Speaker 2:  I'm not saying I'm trying to get rid of my laptop or smartphone because I'm
Speaker 2:  not, I'm really not. But I buy the idea that the industry should be big enough
Speaker 2:  to support lots of shapes, lots of sizes, lots of ideas about what these
Speaker 2:  things are supposed to do and how they're supposed to work. And as these
Speaker 2:  components get easier to source and even make from scratch and as more people
Speaker 2:  get familiar with how they work and how to use them, I think we
Speaker 2:  might be headed back to that. I don't know that I'd ever want a computer
Speaker 2:  made of wood, but I guess I'm glad somebody's making one.
Speaker 2:  All right, we gotta take a break and Then we're gonna come back and talk
Speaker 2:  about a very different, maybe completely opposite way of thinking about
Speaker 2:  interacting with technology. We're gonna talk about super apps. We'll be
Speaker 2:  right back.
Speaker 3:  This episode is supported by humans versus machines from the
Speaker 3:  producers of the world. As You know it, human versus Machines is a new podcast
Speaker 3:  series about the promise and perils of artificial intelligence With
Speaker 3:  host Gary Marcus, we've seen massive progress in artificial
Speaker 3:  intelligence over the last 70 years. Computers can now beat world
Speaker 3:  chess champions at chess when on jeopardy detect fraud, read
Speaker 3:  x-rays better than some radiologists and maybe even write like Shakespeare.
Speaker 3:  But how do we build an AI we can trust? The potential benefits of
Speaker 3:  AI are great, but so are the risks. In this special edition series,
Speaker 3:  Gary Marcus, cognitive scientists, bestselling author and AI
Speaker 3:  entrepreneur digs into AI history, present and future, bringing
Speaker 3:  to life some of the technology's most significant breakthroughs and failures.
Speaker 3:  He interviews engineers, scientists, philosophers, and journalists working
Speaker 3:  at the forefront of AI to explore how we got here and lays out
Speaker 3:  the vision of where we need to go next. Humans versus Machines with
Speaker 3:  Gary Marcus is available now wherever you get your podcasts.
Speaker 8:  Support for this show comes from American Express business. Running
Speaker 8:  a business is no easy feat. American Express business cards are
Speaker 8:  here to help. Whether you're a small business owner ready to expand
Speaker 8:  into new markets or your business is just taking off. American
Speaker 8:  Express business cards are built for businesses like yours. Let's talk
Speaker 8:  about investing in your business. American Express understands that every
Speaker 8:  penny earned is another penny that can go towards taking your business further
Speaker 8:  with a host of select benefits and features available like a flexible spending
Speaker 8:  limit. They're more than just a business card. They're a partner who
Speaker 8:  works with you to help your business thrive. And if there's ever
Speaker 8:  an emergency, their 24 7 support is ready to help. No
Speaker 8:  matter the time of day. American Express business cards are built for
Speaker 8:  your business with features and benefits like the ability to earn membership
Speaker 8:  rewards, points on select cards, the power to pay for big business
Speaker 8:  purchases and more built for your business.
Speaker 8:  Amex business terms apply. learn more at american
Speaker 8:  express.com/business cards.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. The idea of a super app has been around in tech for a
Speaker 2:  really long time because it's really not that complicated a
Speaker 2:  concept, right? Basically what if you could do everything you needed
Speaker 2:  in one place instead of needing a million apps for a million different things?
Speaker 2:  And really there are two flavors of Super app. There's the kind that tries
Speaker 2:  to bundle a bunch of similar stuff into one app like Uber
Speaker 2:  trying to do ride sharing and food delivery and public transit tickets
Speaker 2:  all in one place. That's all You know, moving things from one place to
Speaker 2:  another. So they sort of make sense to put in one place that's a
Speaker 2:  semi super app I guess. But imagine if Uber also tried
Speaker 2:  to get you to video chat with your friends in the Uber app or book
Speaker 2:  doctor's appointments in the Uber app or watch your favorite shows in the
Speaker 2:  Uber app and look for an apartment in the Uber app. Now that
Speaker 2:  would be a true super app. Lots of companies have tried to build
Speaker 2:  a super app like that and only one has actually succeeded. We'll get to that
Speaker 2:  one in a minute. But more recently, Elon Musk has been talking about how
Speaker 2:  he wants to turn X the platform and company formerly known as Twitter
Speaker 2:  into a super app in its own right. Personally I think that is just
Speaker 2:  straight up impossible for a bunch of different reasons, but I figured I
Speaker 2:  should check that theory with a couple of people who know this space and
Speaker 2:  Elon Musk really well. So I brought in the verges, Liz Lipato and Alex
Speaker 2:  Heath to talk through it all. Alex Heath. Hello. Hi Liz
Speaker 2:  Lipato. Hello.
Speaker 9:  Hello.
Speaker 2:  That's a lot of energy for The Vergecast. Yeah,
Speaker 8:  Liz really won the Hello
Speaker 2:  There. Listen
Speaker 9:  Man, I'm hype
Speaker 2:  Whenever you tell Liz she gets to talk about PayPal, it all, it all just
Speaker 2:  falls apart, Which is actually okay, so I, I've been trying to figure
Speaker 2:  out where I wanna start with this because as we talk about super apps and
Speaker 2:  Elon, Musk and X and all this stuff, there are a lot of places we could go
Speaker 2:  but Liz, you have a very old book that you were just telling us about that
Speaker 2:  makes me think we should actually start about 25 years ago
Speaker 2:  with the first time Elon Musk tried to make X happen. You
Speaker 2:  are like deep in the history of this man and PayPal and
Speaker 2:  if you go back to the nineties, all the stuff Elon is trying to do now
Speaker 2:  he was kind of trying to do, or at least thinking about trying to do
Speaker 2:  back then, right? Like build the sort of one app that runs the
Speaker 2:  universe.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. So I guess one of the things that I just wanna like You
Speaker 9:  know, if you can think back into like the mys of time, if
Speaker 9:  you will, back to 1999, it was a very, very
Speaker 9:  different time on the internet as all of us who are online recall and
Speaker 9:  those of you who are not online due to not yet being born, I'm
Speaker 9:  sorry, Musk is one of the sort of original internet
Speaker 9:  entrepreneurs and he founded this business called
Speaker 9:  x.com in 1999, which was when he
Speaker 9:  thought it would be like a really cool idea to do
Speaker 9:  electronic payments, checking accounts, stock trading,
Speaker 9:  mutual funds and like I wanna be real, a lot of these ideas
Speaker 9:  seem pretty ahead of their time. At that point, nobody had
Speaker 9:  really figured out how to use an email address for payments, which is something
Speaker 9:  that like we all do now, right? And so part of what
Speaker 9:  what went on there was there was this unbelievable cash burn. Customers got
Speaker 9:  like a $20 bonus on a cash card when they signed up and like $10 for everybody
Speaker 9:  they referred. And then there were also all of these problems around
Speaker 9:  verification where they would give credit cards to just anybody who wanted
Speaker 9:  them up to like a $10,000 credit limit. And You
Speaker 9:  know Musk's sort of idea was just to onboard as many people as possible because
Speaker 9:  he wanted to have like a million people using the new credit card by the
Speaker 9:  end of the year. And like this is like by the way Peter Thiel's retelling
Speaker 9:  of this, the million people. And so there were a lot of
Speaker 9:  bad checks, there were You know banks that wouldn't allow people to
Speaker 9:  have checking accounts. Who were you signing up for this card? They
Speaker 9:  had something like a 50% chargeback rate, which is completely wild.
Speaker 9:  There was just like a lot going on and there was a second startup called
Speaker 9:  Infinity that was Peter Thiels that ended up merging with
Speaker 9:  x.com because they were both burning money really fast and the VCs
Speaker 9:  involved were like, these are similar businesses, let's like see if we put
Speaker 9:  them together, if something good happens, let's burn
Speaker 2:  Money together, let's
Speaker 9:  Burn money together. And Infinity had this very popular
Speaker 9:  product called PayPal. Part of what went on there
Speaker 9:  is there was a conflict around PayPal, Musk
Speaker 9:  wanted to rename it to X and use a different kind of
Speaker 9:  software to run it or a different kind of code rather. And nobody
Speaker 9:  else wanted that. And so Elon Musk went on his honeymoon and
Speaker 9:  there was a palace coup and he was thrown out of x.com which
Speaker 9:  became known as PayPal and was is still successful today sort
Speaker 9:  of despite these sort of rocky beginnings,
Speaker 2:  Right? And if I remember right, even then they had this thesis
Speaker 2:  that like we want to do all this money stuff and
Speaker 2:  we think that if we can be sort of the conduit through which money flows
Speaker 2:  on the internet, we can solve everything. It's like there's a little bit
Speaker 2:  of like what people talked about with crypto that they're like if we can
Speaker 2:  fix internet money, we can, we can change everything about how everybody
Speaker 2:  does everything just through the money. Like were they talking about that
Speaker 2:  in the nineties or is everybody just like t conning that back into Elon
Speaker 2:  musk's history of x.com?
Speaker 9:  I mean I, I think that that was, that was sort of the primary goal because
Speaker 9:  if you think about how the internet works, it does seem to be missing a
Speaker 9:  protocol and that protocol is money. And so You know there have been a lot
Speaker 9:  of attempts to create a money protocol online and crypto
Speaker 9:  is one of them. But I think that was part of what these guys were thinking
Speaker 9:  about And when I say these guys, I mean both Musk and Teal when it came to
Speaker 9:  PayPal and like if you You know were listening to sort of my description
Speaker 9:  of x.com, it does sound a lot like what is called the quote unquote super
Speaker 9:  app that seems to be Musk's ambition now with Twitter.
Speaker 9:  And I do think that there is something pretty powerful about the idea of
Speaker 9:  having sort of a unified money protocol.
Speaker 9:  But the other thing that maybe is worth mentioning is that here in the US
Speaker 9:  banks got involved and so You know I, I have my banking
Speaker 9:  app on my phone, I can upload paper checks to my
Speaker 9:  checking account if I so choose by You know taking photos and things. And
Speaker 9:  so there are, I already have that particular offering and then on
Speaker 9:  on top of that, You know there's PayPal, there's Venmo, there's all of this
Speaker 9:  competition around ways that you can send money and ways that you can transmit
Speaker 9:  money online and then You know you think another layer you think about crypto
Speaker 9:  if you're involved in the crypto world, there's You know wallets, all sorts
Speaker 9:  of other ways to send money. So it's, it's a highly competitive space
Speaker 9:  much more so than it was in 1999. Right.
Speaker 2:  Which I think is why Alex, I'm curious how you have seen this space over
Speaker 2:  the years. 'cause I think you and I have both been covering the consumer
Speaker 2:  internet for a long time and I think it was like the mid 20
Speaker 2:  teens I think where somewhere along the way everybody who
Speaker 2:  made any kind of successful messaging or social
Speaker 2:  networking app started talking to me about wanting to be a super app
Speaker 2:  in which you could do everything. And I think it's for the reason Liz just
Speaker 2:  described, which is basically like money on the internet got
Speaker 2:  like pretty easy and there were lots of ways to do it. And so everybody was
Speaker 2:  like, okay, how, what are, what is our lock in? And it was like okay, this
Speaker 2:  is where people hang out with each other. What else can we build on top of
Speaker 2:  that? And I feel like 20 like 15 everyone I know
Speaker 2:  was telling me that they were building a super app. Was that your experience
Speaker 2:  too?
Speaker 10:  Yeah. Were you in the audience when Facebook had its annual conference
Speaker 10:  in 2016? Do you remember the messenger chat bot craze?
Speaker 10:  Oh
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I do remember that.
Speaker 10:  So that was actually David Marcus at the time who was the former
Speaker 10:  president of PayPal was trying to bring this very
Speaker 10:  super at Vision that we'll get more into that Elon wants to do to
Speaker 10:  to messenger. And Messenger had 900 million monthly
Speaker 10:  actives already at this point. It was huge and they made this big
Speaker 10:  You know concerted effort to get developers to build these chatbots
Speaker 10:  inside Messenger. And the thinking was that you would do all kinds of things
Speaker 10:  besides talking to your friends, you would talk to businesses, you would
Speaker 10:  do customer support that way. And it bombed. I mean it,
Speaker 10:  it totally bombed And You know we can go many directions here,
Speaker 10:  but many years later, WhatsApp, Meta's other app is
Speaker 10:  actually probably the closest thing to what is a true global super app.
Speaker 10:  But that's been a much longer road and it's become that
Speaker 10:  in countries that are not the US or Western Europe for very
Speaker 10:  important reasons as well.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, no I think that's right. Well and I think we should, before we get
Speaker 2:  to WhatsApp, I think we should talk about WeChat just Yeah, briefly and I'm,
Speaker 2:  I'm curious as from both of your perspectives how you think about
Speaker 2:  WeChat because WeChat, as we talk about super apps, the like one
Speaker 2:  piece of software in which you live your entire life, WeChat is
Speaker 2:  the absolute smashing success story. It is like
Speaker 2:  every app you can think of all shoved into one app called WeChat that is
Speaker 2:  also where you talk to your friends and I feel like everybody I've talked
Speaker 2:  to for the last 10 years is just trying to do what WeChat
Speaker 2:  is doing. And that is like everybody's end goal. It's every what every VC
Speaker 2:  wants to fund, it's what everybody wants to build. Like this is the future
Speaker 2:  of everything Liz. Do you see a line between those
Speaker 2:  things? Like is the thing that PayPal was trying to do, what
Speaker 2:  WeChat managed to pull off? Obviously in China it's a very different country
Speaker 2:  with a very different evolution of the internet. Like did they kind of get
Speaker 2:  it right? Did did WeChat finish the job there?
Speaker 9:  So I think it's worth lingering on the differences between China
Speaker 9:  and the United States for a moment for sure because WeChat is
Speaker 9:  actually bigger than what the sort of vision originally
Speaker 9:  for x.com was. Because x.com didn't have the sort of social media
Speaker 9:  component where you can like post statuses, there was no idea of
Speaker 9:  finances being a kind of social media. Even though I think as everyone who's
Speaker 9:  used Venmo knows it is and in fact You know if you think about the dollar
Speaker 9:  bill that is actually media, right? You know it's, there's literally a photo
Speaker 9:  on it or not a photo I guess, but a print Well
Speaker 2:  And in the same way that all these other apps have started with something
Speaker 2:  else and sort of worked their way down to buying stuff. I think realistically
Speaker 2:  like if, if this had worked the way they wanted it to, you get to the point
Speaker 2:  where all of your money is moving around and then they start to look and
Speaker 2:  it's pretty easy to like pull lines out of that into let's let
Speaker 2:  people send each other money and talk about it and let's let them buy stuff.
Speaker 2:  Why don't we bring the store in here? Like you can see how you would arrive
Speaker 2:  at the same place even from the exact opposite direction.
Speaker 9:  That's exactly right. And so one of the things that I think is worth mentioning
Speaker 9:  about WeChat is specifically the Chinese Communist Party
Speaker 9:  which engages in a great deal of surveillance. So WeChat is
Speaker 9:  a very good way for Chinese authorities to keep an eye on what people are
Speaker 9:  doing, where they're sending money, who they're talking to and what
Speaker 9:  they're reading. Okay? And this is by the way, the downside of every
Speaker 9:  super app is that it is a one-stop shop for surveillance. And I don't mean
Speaker 9:  to suggest that the US government isn't surveilling us because as we all
Speaker 9:  know from Edward Snowden it is sure, but it's a little bit of a pain
Speaker 9:  to put together all of our various social media streams and like the stuff
Speaker 9:  that they're getting from wherever else and like this is like a one-stop
Speaker 9:  shop for the Chinese surveillance state. So
Speaker 9:  that's one way of thinking about these super apps and it's one way of thinking
Speaker 9:  about WeChat. Like it's very, very powerful both for the users and in
Speaker 9:  terms of social control. And so one of the things that I think is maybe
Speaker 9:  interesting here is that in a lot of places where these super
Speaker 9:  apps have traction, there are conditions that are very different than the
Speaker 9:  conditions in the United States. Either the banking industry isn't as developed
Speaker 9:  there and didn't get online as quickly, or there is a level of social
Speaker 9:  control from the government that there isn't here in the us.
Speaker 9:  And so I can see why Silicon Valley VCs
Speaker 9:  would love to have something like WeChat because that would be very powerful.
Speaker 9:  You know it would make you a lot of money and you, there's all sorts of things
Speaker 9:  you can do with all that data. But I don't know from a user perspective
Speaker 9:  why that's necessarily something you would want, especially knowing
Speaker 9:  that it really could ramp up surveillance, it really could do
Speaker 9:  things
Speaker 9:  that are maybe not in your interests. And again, like
Speaker 9:  this is just a basic difference between China and the us besides the fact
Speaker 9:  that there is a lot more competition here because the US government allows
Speaker 9:  a lot more competition around financial services.
Speaker 10:  And to put a finer point on what Liz is saying about WeChat in China, I
Speaker 10:  mean WeChat literally is an extension of the government in China. You can
Speaker 10:  have your government ID managed and
Speaker 10:  accessible inside WeChat. It is a sensor
Speaker 10:  apparatus for the government. And the reason WeChat became so
Speaker 10:  successful inside China when it did is because not only
Speaker 10:  does the government there censor from within, it also censors
Speaker 10:  out things from other countries. And so there was a vacuum where there were
Speaker 10:  not any other You know social networks, the most of which were getting created
Speaker 10:  in the western world allowed to even exist in China
Speaker 10:  officially. So WeChat became, You know the blessed service
Speaker 10:  by the CCP continues to be to this day and to Liz's other point
Speaker 10:  about money and about it being incredibly lucrative, it is. But
Speaker 10:  historically, and you can look at WeChat as a perfect example. It's owned
Speaker 10:  by Tencent, which is a mega cap tech conglomerate,
Speaker 10:  kind of similar to an Apple or an Amazon in China. WeChat
Speaker 10:  as a business actually doesn't make Tencent the majority of its money,
Speaker 10:  the majority of Tencent's money comes from its gaming business. They have
Speaker 10:  a cloud division, they're starting to do a bunch of AI stuff. These super
Speaker 10:  apps buy themselves are not wildly profitable. It's when you
Speaker 10:  attach them to these conglomerates that also have You know
Speaker 10:  historically the blessing of, of the government that that they operate in
Speaker 10:  the country they operate in. So it's, it's a very unique situation for for
Speaker 10:  WeChat.
Speaker 2:  Right? And so given that all of what you both just said, which is basically
Speaker 2:  there are like these giant systemic differences between these two
Speaker 2:  countries that would allow an app like that to work in China that would almost
Speaker 2:  certainly not allow an app like that to work somewhere like the United States.
Speaker 2:  And yet every tech company of a given size has this exact
Speaker 2:  ambition. Alex, you wrote a story a couple years ago looking particularly
Speaker 2:  at Snap, which you thought right was was kind of headed down this road and
Speaker 2:  had a, a real shot at pulling off some if
Speaker 2:  definitely not all, but some of that. Like
Speaker 2:  why did everyone get so obsessed with this if it's not a particularly good
Speaker 2:  business and there are a million really good reasons it's never gonna work
Speaker 2:  anyway.
Speaker 10:  Well, You know, Facebook meta has basically cornered the ads market for
Speaker 10:  these social apps. It's incredibly hard and Snap is living proof of this
Speaker 10:  with where their stock price still is today to compete with a scaled
Speaker 10:  digital ads business like that. It's really meta and Google and that's it.
Speaker 10:  No one's been able to take a meaningful share out of that. And so if you're
Speaker 10:  a Snap or you're a Discord or you're one of these kind of up and coming
Speaker 10:  growing social networks, you're looking at other ways to, to build a business.
Speaker 10:  And the Super App thing is, it's a, it's a sexy idea, right?
Speaker 10:  It's, it's also about time spent. If you're a social media site, you want
Speaker 10:  as much time spent in your app as possible and a super app is something
Speaker 10:  that people use all day every day. And so the thinking is can we bring more
Speaker 10:  activities? So like for example, snap tried a whole gaming platform, snap
Speaker 10:  Minis inside the app and they shut it down because they couldn't make money
Speaker 10:  from it and You know why they couldn't make money from it. Apple, this is
Speaker 10:  a thing that we don't talk about really as it relates to these digital apps.
Speaker 10:  The power that Apple as the distributor of these apps to the app store and
Speaker 10:  the way the app store rules work is extremely powerful. And guess what?
Speaker 10:  Apple doesn't like, they don't like app stores that compete with their own.
Speaker 10:  And so eventually you get down this, this road if you're building a super
Speaker 10:  app where you're a store within a store kind of idea.
Speaker 10:  And the only app really at scale that is allowed to get away with
Speaker 10:  this is WeChat. And there's been some reporting on this over the years that
Speaker 10:  basically, and I I believe this to be true, apple
Speaker 10:  knows that it will not sell iPhones in China without WeChat.
Speaker 10:  And so it's let WeChat do things that it will not let any other app of that
Speaker 10:  scale do. And that's why Snap's kind of mini
Speaker 10:  stuff failed. It's why You know Facebook has never been able to build its
Speaker 10:  own kind of store within Facebook. They've tried many times. This is starting
Speaker 10:  to loosen with some of the EU regulations specifically that will
Speaker 10:  allow competing app stores soon. But Apple is, is the main
Speaker 10:  hindrance I would say actually to building a super app outside of China
Speaker 10:  right now.
Speaker 2:  And is that just because a huge part of the business case there is is
Speaker 2:  just payment fees. Like if we can, if we can get shopping in our app, if
Speaker 2:  we can get people sending each other money in the app and we can take even
Speaker 2:  a relatively small percentage of it, that there's a whole lot of money to
Speaker 2:  be made doing that. And if you can't get any ad money, which you can't, that's
Speaker 2:  one way to potentially make a lot of money here. I
Speaker 10:  Don't know I would be curious to hear Liz talk about this because my understanding
Speaker 10:  is that payments businesses are not wildly profitable
Speaker 10:  businesses. They're actually pretty commoditized. The tech is
Speaker 10:  fairly standardized at this point. There's many competitors. There's Stripe,
Speaker 10:  there's a a n in Europe, the banks all have their own competing rails at
Speaker 10:  this point. The big ones, I'm not actually sure Payments is in and of itself
Speaker 10:  a a big business like Liz. I would actually, we could just get into actually
Speaker 10:  right now kind of what Elon wants to do with
Speaker 2:  X. I was just gonna say this is a perfect segue into this is a bad idea.
Speaker 2:  No one will ever do it. There's no reason to do it. And so Elon Musk is trying
Speaker 9:  Actually guys, I I wanna, I wanna pause here 'cause everything Alex is saying
Speaker 9:  is true. Payments is like not the most lucrative thing on
Speaker 9:  earth, but there is a brand new competitor that I do wanna talk about that
Speaker 9:  went live on July 20th of this year called Fed Now.
Speaker 9:  And it lets you as an individual or businesses if
Speaker 9:  they so choose, send instant payments through your
Speaker 9:  depository institution account, which is like usually a bank
Speaker 2:  Liz. I straight up thought you were just lying to me, like I thought this
Speaker 2:  was like an elaborate bit you were doing. I just googled this, this is real.
Speaker 2:  Sorry, keep going. Yeah,
Speaker 9:  It's from the Federal Reserve. They've been working on it for several years
Speaker 9:  now and it's potentially very, very powerful. It's a
Speaker 9:  brand new set of payment rails that we just, we haven't seen
Speaker 9:  how it's going to be used, used yet. You know there's, we have the first
Speaker 9:  release of it, there's like fraud prevention tools. There's a number of
Speaker 9:  support capabilities and I think that if you're
Speaker 9:  thinking about payments in a very serious way, the US federal
Speaker 9:  government has just given you some competition.
Speaker 9:  So that's, that's maybe also worth keeping in mind.
Speaker 10:  Liz I would love for you to just react to this. So, so Elon held his first
Speaker 10:  meeting when he took over Twitter in November. I got an audio
Speaker 10:  recording of the entire conversation and put the full transcript on The
Speaker 10:  Verge at the time. And there's a section kind of in the middle of the meeting
Speaker 10:  where he gets into the, the payments ideas that he wants to implement at
Speaker 10:  Twitter before it was X. And there's this one line
Speaker 10:  that I think really gets to the heart of what he thinks the reason people
Speaker 10:  will want to transact through Twitter will be. And he says, if you can
Speaker 10:  simply have one balance on Twitter that can simply go positive or negative.
Speaker 10:  And when it goes positive, the interest rate is better than you could receive
Speaker 10:  elsewhere. And when it goes negative, the interest rate is lower than you
Speaker 10:  see elsewhere. Now you have a much simpler system. Is that actually
Speaker 10:  a compelling reason to do any of this? And is this something that is gonna
Speaker 10:  get people to transact in Twitter? I I don't think so, but he seems
Speaker 10:  to think it is.
Speaker 9:  It doesn't sound simpler, does it? Like is
Speaker 2:  That even anything?
Speaker 10:  Well he's saying like they're gonna com and you write about this on the
Speaker 10:  side all the time. Liz like he's saying they're gonna compete like so much
Speaker 10:  goes back to interest rates and he's saying we're gonna focus on better
Speaker 10:  interest rates on the positive and negative end so that we're the compelling
Speaker 10:  place to store your money. Can he actually do that? I don't think so.
Speaker 9:  Well You know, there have been a number of people who have been trying, most
Speaker 9:  notably Goldman, which has been offering a product both with Apple
Speaker 9:  and also on its own. It's just a savings account. You can't, like there's
Speaker 9:  no debit, you can't withdraw, it's all electronic so you have to
Speaker 9:  withdraw to another bank account in order to get cash out. But the idea of
Speaker 9:  like high interest savings accounts, like those are not especially new either.
Speaker 9:  And it's something that we've seen a lot of banking institutions move into
Speaker 9:  with mixed results. So You know, I I I understand wanting to
Speaker 9:  compete on interest rates, but the other thing that I'm gonna say is that
Speaker 9:  like, I think about this stuff on a pretty regular basis and I
Speaker 9:  don't pretend to to be an expert You know, I certainly don't have an econ
Speaker 9:  degree or anything like that. But I do, I am interested and I talk about
Speaker 9:  interest rates with You know friends and family and they don't
Speaker 9:  understand them. Yeah, they don't think about them. And so like
Speaker 9:  if you are offering a consumer product as many
Speaker 9:  institutions, by the way do, it needs to be simple enough to be understood
Speaker 9:  by most consumers because I, I do remember during the era of low interest
Speaker 9:  rates, I had people who were telling me to get certificates of deposit, which
Speaker 9:  didn't make any sense given You know that the interest rate was almost nothing
Speaker 9:  and I would've been earning less on a CD than I was losing an inflation.
Speaker 9:  So there are like, there just seems to be like a, a basic lack of
Speaker 9:  I would say financial literacy that would preclude
Speaker 9:  something like that making intuitive sense to a consumer. So that's
Speaker 9:  problem one. Problem two is that it sounds pretty complex.
Speaker 9:  So if he's saying You know if your balance is positive, you, you get a better
Speaker 9:  interest rate and if your balance is negative, you get a worse interest rate.
Speaker 9:  That's a lot more complexity than just having one fixed interest rate
Speaker 9:  that you can sort of rely on and do math around. So it sounds
Speaker 9:  like he has some ideas that don't translate
Speaker 9:  easily to a consumer audience. And if you're
Speaker 9:  thinking about a, a super app, if you're thinking about some of these, these
Speaker 9:  kinds of payment apps like, like Venmo or PayPal, which mostly make money
Speaker 9:  on the float, what you're thinking about is a consumer audience. What you're
Speaker 9:  thinking about is people need to transact without thinking too hard. They
Speaker 9:  need to You know they go out to dinner or one person pays the bill and everybody
Speaker 9:  else sends them You know some amount of money for the bill. That's what they're
Speaker 9:  thinking about. And so You know in that sense, like maybe social media
Speaker 9:  can be useful because You know you have your connections with friends. But
Speaker 9:  I also think about the people who I talk to online most often and they're
Speaker 9:  not the same people I see in everyday life and You know
Speaker 9:  with all, all love to my internet friends like David and Alex
Speaker 9:  'cause we don't live in the same cities. You know the people who I'm going
Speaker 9:  to be sending payments to because we split dinner are not the same people
Speaker 9:  as the people who I'm talking to on Twitter all day.
Speaker 10:  You're saying your friends at dinner are, they're not all on X all the time.
Speaker 10:  No.
Speaker 9:  It turns out that I have a bunch of friends who like have jobs that mean
Speaker 9:  that they're not on the internet all day.
Speaker 2:  I genuinely don't even know what that means. That doesn't, that does not,
Speaker 2:  that doesn't track to me at all. But I just wanna say one more thing about
Speaker 2:  the consumer business side of this, like this has also not
Speaker 2:  been a good business. It turns out that like, like to your point about the
Speaker 2:  Apple Goldman Sachs thing, like Goldman Sachs is by all accounts trying
Speaker 2:  desperately to get out of that business because providing simple,
Speaker 2:  understandable ways for people to make sure they pay their credit card bills
Speaker 2:  actually turns out to be a really crappy business. And when you're Apple,
Speaker 2:  that's all fine and good and I get a notification every month telling me
Speaker 2:  to pay my Apple card. Turns out that's not making Goldman Sachs any money,
Speaker 2:  which is a real bummer for Goldman Sachs. So yet again, this is the kind
Speaker 2:  of thing that seems like it ought to be a good business because you get to
Speaker 2:  be in the middle of people moving their money around between each other and
Speaker 2:  it just might not be.
Speaker 10:  I'll play devil's advocate just for one second for Musk please. Okay. You
Speaker 10:  know how many apps people download per month on average? Take a wild guess.
Speaker 10:  Zero. Zero. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  Zero. Yeah. So this is the case for the super app? Yeah. Yeah, that's the
Speaker 2:  whole thing.
Speaker 10:  So You know if you're in the US though, the apps on your phone
Speaker 10:  already do all the things he's trying to build. So that's obviously the
Speaker 10:  thing that wouldn't support his vision here. But he's got one of the last
Speaker 10:  scaled You know social media platforms with You know
Speaker 10:  hundreds of millions of monthly users at least. At least some portion of
Speaker 10:  those are real users. We're not sure how many, but it's got its sizable
Speaker 10:  You know user base of real people. We think there is something to be said
Speaker 10:  for like make it a stickier product for the people who are using it. You
Speaker 10:  can see kind of him putting the pieces together with the creator payments
Speaker 10:  that they've started doing, right? So if you're verified, you're starting
Speaker 10:  to get like, I think it's actually now bi-monthly just payments
Speaker 10:  to your Stripe account. I think it's deeply funny by the way that
Speaker 10:  he's using Stripe for all this right now. Like he, they're building it all
Speaker 10:  on the fly. They have none of this like in-house yet. So he is using Stripe.
Speaker 10:  But yeah, You know, say you're a creator, you're getting these payments
Speaker 10:  which are basically some undescribed rev share of the ads that run against
Speaker 10:  your tweet after certain million plus impressions that
Speaker 10:  balance. What if that just starts earning interest for you in your X account?
Speaker 10:  And that's, that feeds into the, the money that you can send through the
Speaker 10:  system. And he's talked in in internal all hands about You know we have
Speaker 10:  to be backwards compatible with the existing financial system so
Speaker 10:  they're going to have credit cards and debit cards for x as wild You know
Speaker 10:  as wild as that says, as wild as that sounds, that's
Speaker 10:  gonna happen. He's gonna offer lending so it's gonna become
Speaker 10:  this full kind of bank thing. And he's been wanting to do it forever and
Speaker 10:  it's just kind of, it's remarkable that it's like so similar to the
Speaker 10:  early vision, like the late nineties vision that Liz started this
Speaker 10:  conversation talking about. And he seems to just not
Speaker 10:  care that the world has changed and think that I've got a big enough user
Speaker 10:  base that I can make something interesting here and T B D
Speaker 10:  if that will work. But that's, that's what he's doing.
Speaker 2:  You also just perfectly described why I think the super app
Speaker 2:  discussion is so fascinating because it just makes
Speaker 2:  logical sense every single time, right? No matter which company you are,
Speaker 2:  whether you're, you make You know WhatsApp or Snap or Uber
Speaker 2:  which is kind of trying to do this or any number of other companies, it's
Speaker 2:  like okay well we have this one core competency. People are spending their
Speaker 2:  time inside of our app doing a thing. What if we do this like slightly adjacent
Speaker 2:  thing and then if that starts to work, what if we do this other slightly
Speaker 2:  adjacent thing and over and over and over, you can talk yourself into
Speaker 2:  every company has to be some kind of like financial juggernaut
Speaker 2:  because that's what powers a lot of the rest of this. And then you talk yourself
Speaker 2:  into not only do we want to be a social media app, we also want to
Speaker 2:  be a chat app and Then we have to do some entertainment stuff but then people
Speaker 2:  are gonna wanna like get around So, we should probably be a rideshare company.
Speaker 2:  And it's like you can talk yourself into trying to be all things to all people,
Speaker 2:  which is a terrible idea in perfectly rational way as one step at a time.
Speaker 2:  And I feel like we've watched these companies do this for like 15 years and
Speaker 2:  it's so funny and so bizarre every single time. And now we're just watching
Speaker 2:  Elon Musk do the same thing but at like record speed
Speaker 9:  You know David, I also wanna just point out something 'cause we've, we've
Speaker 9:  been dancing around interest rates for a minute. I understand, I sound like
Speaker 9:  a broken record, but post 2008
Speaker 9:  there was a very long period of very low interest rates and that
Speaker 9:  was part of the reason why we wound up with people trying to do blitz scaling.
Speaker 9:  It was part of the reason why we found people You know moving into
Speaker 9:  related businesses that didn't totally always make sense.
Speaker 2:  We work opening a preschool will forever be my favorite example of that.
Speaker 9:  That's right. And so You know, if you think about it in a way
Speaker 9:  it was easier to experiment with this kind of thing because there weren't
Speaker 9:  a lot of places to park money that would earn you
Speaker 9:  interest. And so that meant that there was a lot more money available for
Speaker 9:  investing. And if you think about what's been going on over the last
Speaker 9:  two-ish years, the Fed has been raising interest rates. And so that is
Speaker 9:  no longer true separately from the fact that You know the yields on
Speaker 9:  bonds are pretty high right now, relatively high. There's also
Speaker 9:  just a, a variety of financial instruments that have suddenly become much
Speaker 9:  more attractive than they've been for about a decade. And that's a problem
Speaker 9:  for VCs generally because all of that VC scaling
Speaker 9:  like Blitzscaling stuff, You know typified for instance by Uber
Speaker 9:  that relied on there being a lot of cash available so that you could pour
Speaker 9:  it all into the market corner, the market and then You know jack up the prices,
Speaker 9:  which is essentially what Uber has done. Again, we may not be in conditions
Speaker 9:  for that to continue to occur anymore. And one of the things that has been
Speaker 9:  a real question for me when it comes to Elon Musk and it's an
Speaker 9:  open question, is that a lot of his success happened in this low interest
Speaker 9:  rate era. A lot of You know what we think of as being
Speaker 9:  Tesla's success for instance happened when it was easy to get
Speaker 9:  ahold of money and even then Tesla almost went outta business a couple times.
Speaker 9:  You think about SpaceX, You know it's still private, it's
Speaker 9:  very much venture backed and it's a valuable company. You know it does a
Speaker 9:  lot of important things for the US government. I don't mean to suggest that
Speaker 9:  it's You know smoke and mirrors or anything like that, but again, conditions
Speaker 9:  have changed. You think about some of the other projects that Musk has been
Speaker 9:  working on, the sort of more farfetched stuff like the boring company in
Speaker 9:  Neuralink and you wonder how far they're gonna go in this new
Speaker 9:  environment. And you think about Twitter, which You know
Speaker 9:  Twitter has never been an especially successful business. True
Speaker 9:  even though it's been a particularly influential one. And
Speaker 9:  you think about all of the debt that Musk loaded it up with in order to buy
Speaker 9:  it. And you think about the new environment we're in, which we
Speaker 9:  haven't seen You know in quite some time. And you just wonder
Speaker 9:  if Elon Musk is prepared for this era of
Speaker 9:  normal interest rates. Like there just seems like a lot of the things that
Speaker 9:  he has done has been to spend as much money as possible and worry about the
Speaker 9:  risk later. And I'm kind of wondering if it's, if we've reached the moment
Speaker 9:  where it's later and you should be worrying. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Alex, what have you heard from folks over the last couple of years? 'cause
Speaker 2:  I think like I, I Liz I agree with you almost a hundred
Speaker 2:  percent, but also the other thing that is happening is that all these companies
Speaker 2:  tried this when there was unlimited money to throw at it and it kept not
Speaker 2:  working still, right? Like Facebook couldn't make dating
Speaker 2:  happen and all these companies have tried to expand into this like do
Speaker 2:  more things with your life outside of just these sort of
Speaker 2:  core competency of our app. But Alex, I'm curious what you've seen like have
Speaker 2:  folks pulled back on this ambition because of sort of the the
Speaker 2:  like larger economic changes here that we're talking about
Speaker 10:  From a product perspective? No, I actually wrote a piece in The Verge
Speaker 10:  2021 predicting that there were gonna be more of these super apps
Speaker 10:  attempts around the world. I wasn't specifically talking about the US
Speaker 10:  but just broadly for a number of reasons. But because
Speaker 10:  a lot of the kind of scaled big
Speaker 10:  independent apps that do one or two things, like they worked as a
Speaker 10:  business in a model where you could track people across the
Speaker 10:  internet and that increasingly is not happening anymore thanks to Apple
Speaker 10:  and regulation. And so you have this incentive for all of these
Speaker 10:  companies that make money by how much time people spend in their services
Speaker 10:  to bring more of that activity inside
Speaker 10:  their walled garden so to speak. So you have like TikTok
Speaker 10:  doing shopping right, where you can like buy a a a
Speaker 10:  thing you see in a video without ever leaving TikTok that wouldn't have
Speaker 10:  happened five years ago because you didn't need to because you could still
Speaker 10:  track who made the purchase where if they went somewhere else it just wasn't
Speaker 10:  worth the effort. So I do think there's a natural kind of business
Speaker 10:  incentive at play here for all of these kind of time spent based
Speaker 10:  companies to become more like super apps. And the TikTok shopping
Speaker 10:  thing is actually a great kind of very, very fresh example. They're
Speaker 10:  testing like a storefront that looks like Amazon right next to the video
Speaker 10:  feed and TikTok. So to Liz's point about You know
Speaker 10:  the broader kind of macroeconomic climate here and the fact that
Speaker 10:  it is You know capital is more expensive. You can't just like You know Tesla's
Speaker 10:  not gonna become a trillion dollar company on pure mania
Speaker 10:  anymore, right? Like that era has passed. That's
Speaker 2:  Definitely true. Yeah,
Speaker 10:  Sure. But like, I mean from everything Musk has been saying since he bought
Speaker 10:  Twitter, he seems to be painfully aware that things are changing.
Speaker 10:  Like every time he talks to people internally it's like we have got to prepare
Speaker 10:  for a recession. You know I reported on meetings like when he first bought
Speaker 10:  the company where he was talking about the fact that he thinks of very bad
Speaker 10:  recession is coming. Looks like that may not be the case now, but he's
Speaker 10:  definitely been thinking You know things are shifting. I don't think he's
Speaker 10:  totally oblivious to it. I mean he is, he is the richest person in the world.
Speaker 10:  Like I, I think he probably has pretty good data, he's very focused on cutting
Speaker 10:  costs on You know. I think SpaceX just had its first
Speaker 10:  profitable quarter I just saw in a media story in in like Q one.
Speaker 10:  So he is actually kind of like leading the charge so to speak in Silicon
Speaker 10:  Valley of like cutting companies down to the bone to try to make them profitable
Speaker 10:  and get away from this kind of hypergrowth era. So I don't know,
Speaker 10:  I don't know if the things are, I don't know if that's, that means that
Speaker 10:  he's gonna succeed here. But I do think he seems to be at least aware that
Speaker 10:  things are changing.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I do think to go back to WeChat for a second, one of the things WeChat
Speaker 2:  was able to do that worked so well was essentially just
Speaker 2:  pour money and energy and effort into getting people into the app.
Speaker 2:  Like Liz what you were talking about with the early days of PayPal where
Speaker 2:  they're essentially just heaving money at people to use PayPal
Speaker 2:  or x.com or whatever the heck it was. WeChat was able to do that kind of
Speaker 2:  thing for a long time and just work so hard and grow
Speaker 2:  so much that it kind of had won the market before
Speaker 2:  anybody really noticed. And then you get into that sort of escape
Speaker 2:  velocity and it becomes very hard to lose because people decide it's smarter
Speaker 2:  to just build inside of WeChat than build their own thing because they don't
Speaker 2:  have the money to compute with it and like on and on and that's who you win.
Speaker 2:  And that in this era becomes much harder to do, right? Because there's no
Speaker 2:  free money to just throw it growing
Speaker 10:  David, it becomes easier to win when you have the full backing of the ccp.
Speaker 10:  I mean like that's sure that's to get to our early point like and, and
Speaker 10:  this can maybe kind of bring it full circle a little bit like to what Liz
Speaker 10:  was talking about earlier. Like do we really want Elon Musk who
Speaker 10:  already has a ton of power, especially through like starlink and
Speaker 10:  how that relates to how physical wars are playing out in in Ukraine.
Speaker 10:  Do we really want someone with all these different businesses in power to
Speaker 10:  have something like a WeChat and he has a business in
Speaker 10:  China that is very important strategically to Tesla.
Speaker 10:  He's got a lot of pressure points that can be pushed
Speaker 10:  around the world by different governments and do we want something like
Speaker 10:  a super app where we transact and do all these things to be managed by
Speaker 10:  one person who let's be clear controls his company's companies
Speaker 10:  completely, right? So it's like this isn't like a, a
Speaker 10:  normal governance situation. So there's there's a lot to be concerned about
Speaker 10:  there.
Speaker 2:  Liz, I have a strange feeling. I know your answer to Alex's question.
Speaker 9:  There are a lot of reasons I don't want Elon
Speaker 9:  Musk's super app managing my money
Speaker 9:  and all of the things that you guys have have mentioned are are part
Speaker 9:  of it. Part of it is also You know I'm a reporter who
Speaker 9:  reports on Elon Musk and like, do I necessarily want him to be able
Speaker 9:  to like look into my bank account from God view?
Speaker 9:  Do I
Speaker 2:  I feel like it is though. Like you, you like you a little bit just like root
Speaker 2:  for chaos at all times and like that is chaos.
Speaker 9:  It's true. And like honestly I, he's gonna find out that I spend
Speaker 9:  far too much money on my cat
Speaker 9:  but You know like as you think about these things, the other thing to think
Speaker 9:  about is Elon Musk's history of implementation and it's sloppy
Speaker 9:  and You know the, some of that is like the panel problems that we saw with
Speaker 9:  with Tesla You know and and various other sort of implementation
Speaker 9:  problems. But even if you just narrow your
Speaker 9:  focus to Twitter slash x, there's just been a lot of
Speaker 9:  sloppiness there from the X sign to not getting the X
Speaker 9:  handle until after the name had already been changed
Speaker 9:  to the various sort of problems that we've had around
Speaker 9:  the service where we were being rate limited abruptly for a
Speaker 9:  while. And like this kind of like slap dash
Speaker 9:  mentality is an old Silicon Valley mentality, it's You know
Speaker 9:  usually thought of as like move fast and break things. And that does make
Speaker 9:  sense in certain contexts. You know like the Twitter fail
Speaker 9:  fail whale was a thing because, because sometimes the
Speaker 9:  service went out 'cause there were too many people on it. But You know I
Speaker 9:  if you think about the things that you don't want from banks, I'm just gonna
Speaker 9:  list some of them. Abrupt, frequent service changes,
Speaker 9:  regular service outages, new fees added at random
Speaker 9:  white supremacists, difficulty with verification, spam and
Speaker 9:  fraud. You know, like these are all things I don't want any anywhere near
Speaker 9:  my money. Yeah. And if you just look at how Twitter is operating right
Speaker 9:  now and you think about it is like, hmm,
Speaker 9:  do I trust Elon Musk to to to actually handle my money in a way that makes
Speaker 9:  sense, right?
Speaker 10:  It's like all these crypto scam ads that I see in my feed every day, it's
Speaker 10:  like, oh, all I want is to be able to actually send money to those ads,
Speaker 10:  right?
Speaker 2:  With one click. They just have your bank account now. That's what everybody's
Speaker 2:  looking for, right?
Speaker 10:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  So, okay, last thing and Then we should go is I, I think if you imagine
Speaker 2:  somebody Elon Musk or Mark Zuckerberg or somebody from a product
Speaker 2:  perspective manages to build this thing, they they accrue
Speaker 2:  all of the value, all of the user data, all the everything to
Speaker 2:  like be the the WeChat of America.
Speaker 2:  Could anyone pull that off from a regulatory standpoint? Like would would
Speaker 2:  Lean Con in the F T C just throw their bodies in front of one
Speaker 2:  company having this much, this is an argument I've heard and I genuinely
Speaker 2:  don't know where I'd land on. Like could you even in theory pull
Speaker 2:  this off under the US government's nose?
Speaker 10:  No there's no chance. I mean Facebook, are we old
Speaker 10:  enough now to where we don't remember in just 2019
Speaker 10:  Facebook tried to create a global currency.
Speaker 2:  Libra
Speaker 9:  Like I remember Libra, I love Libra.
Speaker 10:  Yeah. And honestly Libra was a pretty smart idea for a
Speaker 10:  global currency that had a lot of benefits and was gonna be managed by a
Speaker 10:  trust et cetera. Like they thought through a lot of the potential blowback,
Speaker 10:  guess what they, it still got shut down. I would say there's next to zero
Speaker 10:  chance that anything like this happens in the US for all
Speaker 10:  the reasons you just said David. I mean if Facebook can't buy
Speaker 10:  Giphy, do you really think like that Congress,
Speaker 10:  especially all the members of Congress who have strong feelings about Musk
Speaker 10:  already are gonna let him build a financial superpower that potentially,
Speaker 10:  potentially like has more power than the US government? No. Like no,
Speaker 10:  absolutely not. I
Speaker 9:  Wanna pile onto this because it isn't just an antitrust
Speaker 9:  issue, although it's a very sexy antitrust issue.
Speaker 9:  What you're talking about is essentially somebody who's managing the digital
Speaker 9:  dollar and I feel like the Fed and the Treasury both wanna be involved with
Speaker 9:  that. And so not only are you looking at an antitrust issue, you're looking
Speaker 9:  at dealing with other major government agencies
Speaker 9:  and You know there are people out there. Circle is one of them that are interested
Speaker 9:  in being the purveyor of the digital dollar that are interested in doing
Speaker 9:  that kind of work that have talked publicly about wanting to work with
Speaker 9:  the Fed, with the treasury to to have a digital dollar.
Speaker 9:  And that's a very, very different proposition than what we're hearing about
Speaker 9:  with these super apps. And like again, if you go back to something like Fed
Speaker 9:  now, there is like a reality where it turns out
Speaker 9:  like maybe your competition is the United States
Speaker 9:  because it turns out the dollar is a really, really important part
Speaker 9:  of why the US is so powerful. The dollar is something that a lot of people
Speaker 9:  transact in around the world. It's a really, really important part of the
Speaker 9:  US' soft power and wherever the dollar goes, US law goes as
Speaker 9:  well. So whenever you're talking about this kind of like super app
Speaker 9:  when you're talking about these kinds of big payment companies, you are inevitably
Speaker 9:  also talking about something much more powerful. And Elon,
Speaker 9:  Musk already has a lot of sway in the federal government because his You
Speaker 9:  know starlink is very important because he sends
Speaker 9:  a lot of satellites up for various US military missions.
Speaker 9:  And so there is like this question of how much more power
Speaker 9:  we as You know the United States want to hand over to him.
Speaker 9:  Like he's already like doing all of these things for the military. Do you
Speaker 9:  want him handling the US dollar as well? And I feel like the answer is probably
Speaker 9:  not.
Speaker 2:  It's a real, like no one man should have all that power kind of situation.
Speaker 2:  It's it's just where I land. Yeah, I, I don't know. I kind of hope
Speaker 2:  somebody gets further down this road and we can actually have this fight
Speaker 2:  in a real way. 'cause I think Meta never had a chance because of all the
Speaker 2:  other stuff going on with meta. The F T C was just like the whole US government
Speaker 2:  would've stopped Libra if it came to it. I don't think Elon Musk is
Speaker 2:  gonna to even get close, but it's, it's gonna be fascinating to see if someone
Speaker 2:  can get well enough down the road that we actually have to have this fight
Speaker 2:  for real. But I'm not convinced forever gonna see it. Alex who would you
Speaker 2:  bet on? Do you still think it's Snap could snap do it?
Speaker 10:  No, I, I don't think this is happening and not, not in the US I do think
Speaker 10:  it will happen in other parts of the world where countries are kind of more
Speaker 10:  willing to embrace something like this. But I think the US is so
Speaker 10:  against big tech right now and there's so many established players
Speaker 10:  doing things really well at scale like banking that I just don't see how
Speaker 10:  this happens. But You know could be my famous last words.
Speaker 2:  No, I tend to agree. I think instead of a super app we got like the whole
Speaker 2:  internet and I think that's probably a better trade
Speaker 10:  And like that's okay. Like it's actually yeah, I love it's capitalism. Like
Speaker 10:  I free market whatever. Like I, I love having apps competing for my,
Speaker 10:  my services and my attention and to have options is a good thing.
Speaker 10:  Like we shouldn't be like necessarily wanting one company doing everything.
Speaker 10:  Totally.
Speaker 2:  Alright, well we gotta take a break. But thank you both for, for doing this.
Speaker 2:  I appreciate it and I will, I will ex both of you some money for being here.
Speaker 2:  Thank you.
Speaker 10:  No you won't. All right. See you guys.
Speaker 1:  Bye.
Speaker 11:  Support for this show comes from Global Citizen. On
Speaker 11:  September 23rd, the Global Citizen Festival will gather thousands of people
Speaker 11:  who took action to end extreme poverty. Join the Red Hot Chili
Speaker 11:  Peppers, Ms. Lauren Hill, Megan Thee Stallion, and
Speaker 11:  Anita as they take the stage with world leaders and activists to
Speaker 11:  demand action for equity for the planet, for food and for jobs.
Speaker 11:  Download the Global Citizen app today and earn your spot at the festival.
Speaker 11:  learn more at global citizen.org/ Vox.
Speaker 11:  Support for this show comes from Global Citizen. On
Speaker 11:  September 23rd, the Global Citizen Festival will gather thousands of people
Speaker 11:  who took action to end extreme poverty. Join the Red Hot Chili
Speaker 11:  Peppers, Ms. Lauren Hill, Megan Thee Stallion, and Anita
Speaker 11:  as they take the stage with world leaders and activists to demand
Speaker 11:  action for equity for the planet, for food and for jobs.
Speaker 11:  Download the Global Citizen app today and earn your spot at the festival.
Speaker 11:  learn more at global citizen.org/ Vox.
Speaker 2:  All right, we're back. Let's get to The. Vergecast Hotline. As a reminder,
Speaker 2:  the Hotline number is 8 6 6 Verge one one. You can call and ask us
Speaker 2:  absolutely anything about tech, anything on your mind, we wanna hear it all.
Speaker 2:  You can also email us Vergecast at The Verge dot com if you don't wanna call.
Speaker 2:  This week's voicemail comes from Daniel.
Speaker 12:  Hey, this is Daniel. I always have this question of why
Speaker 12:  social media doesn't recognize the fact that like people
Speaker 12:  are more than just one thing. Like why can't I
Speaker 12:  have a whole collection of subreddits for each of my like quote
Speaker 12:  unquote modes. Like sometimes I'm in productivity mode where I
Speaker 12:  just wanna see You know how to be optimally product
Speaker 12:  productive I guess, and do spreadsheets and that kind of
Speaker 12:  stuff. And then sometimes I'm into my hobby interest mode and I just wanna
Speaker 12:  see stuff about like video games or whatever. The only way I've ever found
Speaker 12:  to do this is to actually have totally separate social media
Speaker 12:  profiles, which is just super annoying to maintain. But why
Speaker 12:  doesn't any social media recognize that that's a thing that pretty much,
Speaker 12:  much every person has. Anyway, tell me your thoughts. Bye.
Speaker 2:  Okay, I have answers to this question for once. I have a, I have a small
Speaker 2:  thought and a big thought. The small thought is that for Reddit, this is
Speaker 2:  actually a thing you can do Reddit sort of berries this, but it does actually
Speaker 2:  exist. It used to be called Multi Reddits and now it's called custom
Speaker 2:  feeds. And basically the idea is you can pull a bunch of different
Speaker 2:  subreddits into one thing that you see all as
Speaker 2:  a single Reddit timeline. So like I have one ironically for
Speaker 2:  productivity, that's all of my like productivity nerds, subreddits. And then
Speaker 2:  I have one for all the sports teams I care about. So like I have the
Speaker 2:  Arsenal subreddit, New York Giants Subreddit and the Yankees subreddit all
Speaker 2:  in one place. This is a great thing that Reddit does. I don't know why
Speaker 2:  they don't share it more. It's kind of awkward to find, I'll put a link in
Speaker 2:  the show notes on how to set up a custom feed on the web and in the apps.
Speaker 2:  But it is possible and you should do it and it's great. The bigger picture
Speaker 2:  thing here is I think this is a good idea and I think we're gonna get
Speaker 2:  towards it. I think one of the things we've talked about a lot with the social
Speaker 2:  web and activity pub is this idea that there are going to be lots of
Speaker 2:  new ways to sort and filter and display the same kinds
Speaker 2:  of content. So you've heard Elon, Musk and others talk about this idea of
Speaker 2:  like open sourcing the algorithm so that you can get different versions
Speaker 2:  of the same experience depending on what you want. So you could show up and
Speaker 2:  say I'm in the mood to just go on TikTok and watch bloopers
Speaker 2:  from TV shows that I like. And that's actually an instruction. You might
Speaker 2:  be able to give an app like that over time or to say I'm in work
Speaker 2:  mode or I'm in school mode or whatever and actually have these
Speaker 2:  things work separately. It's hard work and it means having
Speaker 2:  different algorithms and systems and it also means making users do
Speaker 2:  more, which most of these apps don't like to do. But I do think that's actually
Speaker 2:  a place that we're headed with some of these tools. The other thing is that
Speaker 2:  I wouldn't underrate how useful it is to have multiple accounts because the
Speaker 2:  other thing is when you're interacting on these, when you're liking stuff
Speaker 2:  and you're commenting and you're posting, having all of that stuff kind of
Speaker 2:  live together in a separate account works really well. So even if we get
Speaker 2:  to the point where you can customize your algorithms or like I have custom
Speaker 2:  feeds on Reddit, I'm still posting as me and so kind of
Speaker 2:  my interactions in my life all live in the same place.
Speaker 2:  And a lot of these companies, Instagram I think does this better than almost
Speaker 2:  anybody make it really easy to switch from account to account. But I'm a
Speaker 2:  big fan of having multiple accounts. I have lots of accounts on lots of different
Speaker 2:  services and it occasionally gets like awkwardly cross pollinated 'cause
Speaker 2:  you forget what you're logged into. But having a Reddit that I go to when
Speaker 2:  I'm just looking for sports stuff and wanna like yell about
Speaker 2:  sports that is separate from where I comment as like a person who people
Speaker 2:  know on the internet is really useful. And if you wanna shit post, you should
Speaker 2:  have an account just for shit Posting is my personal and professional opinion.
Speaker 2:  So the point Daniel, is I think we're headed somewhat towards the
Speaker 2:  world that you described, but also custom feeds on Reddit will instantly
Speaker 2:  make your life better. I hope that helps. Alright, that is it for The
Speaker 2:  Vergecast today. Thank you to everyone who's on the show and thank you so
Speaker 2:  much for listening. As always, there's lots more from everything we talked
Speaker 2:  about, including mythic computer at The Verge dot com. We also made a cool
Speaker 2:  video. We have some really fun stuff on the website. Go check it all out.
Speaker 2:  It's good stuff. If you have thoughts, questions, feelings, or sick
Speaker 2:  custom computers that you made and want to tell me about, you can always
Speaker 2:  email us at Vergecast to The Verge dot com or call the Hotline
Speaker 2:  eight six six Verge one one. We love hearing from you and speaking of the
Speaker 2:  Hotline, one thing we're going to do at some point in the very near future
Speaker 2:  is an entire Vergecast episode all about The Verge. We're calling
Speaker 2:  it the Meta Vergecast episode. So if you have questions about how we make
Speaker 2:  The Verge, how we make The Vergecast, what Eli's favorite food is, why
Speaker 2:  Alex Kranz has so much weird stuff on her walls, send us all of your questions,
Speaker 2:  call in with all of your questions. We're gonna do a whole episode about
Speaker 2:  it. It's gonna be awesome. This show is produced by Angel Moreno and Liam
Speaker 2:  James Brooke Minter is our editorial director of Audio The Vergecast is
Speaker 2:  Verge production and part of the Vox Media podcast network, NELI Alex, and
Speaker 2:  I'll be back on Friday to talk about the connect the drama about open AI's,
Speaker 2:  web crawler, all of your computer rooms, which has been so fun to see and
Speaker 2:  lots more. We'll see you then. Rock and roll
Speaker 13:  Support for the show comes from Gold Peak Real Brew Tea.
Speaker 13:  There's a time of day about an hour before sunset where the
Speaker 13:  rays feel warm and the breeze feels cool,
Speaker 13:  but that hour of golden bliss is always gone. Too soon
Speaker 13:  you might rekindle that feeling with a bottle of gold Peak made with high
Speaker 13:  quality tea leaves it's smooth taste transports you to golden hour
Speaker 13:  at any hour. Gold, Peak, Tea. It's
Speaker 13:  got to be gold.