# Transcript
ID: d58197b4-a9be-4594-84cb-a3533ac4cc9f
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Apple events, SEO, and other fights
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-6450270579055852755/-3225079799523419930/s93290-US-5086s-1699012901.mp3
Description: The Verge's Nilay Patel, David Pierce, and Alex Cranz discuss the takeaways from Apple's Mac event, the problem with SEO on the internet, streaming news, and much more.
Speaker 1:  How you show up on social is important, and your name is perhaps the most
Speaker 1:  important of all. So don't take username unavailable for an answer.
Speaker 1:  Take control with a dot. Social web address.social is a
Speaker 1:  domain extension that does something really special. It gives you one consistent
Speaker 1:  name you can use across emerging social networks like Blue Sky,
Speaker 1:  Macon and more. Learn more at name.com/social
Speaker 1:  and use the code Verge 25 to get 25% off your first year
Speaker 1:  of your.social web address. That's name.com/social
Speaker 1:  because you should be you no matter where you go.
Speaker 1:  Support for this episode comes from Sonos Experience fully immersive
Speaker 1:  sound with the new era 300 smart speaker from Sonos. It's a spatial audio
Speaker 1:  speaker that doesn't just surround you with sound. It puts you inside your
Speaker 1:  music. Plus you can pair two era three hundreds with a Sonos arc or Beam
Speaker 1:  soundbar for the ultimate in home theater experience. The ERA 300 is easy
Speaker 1:  to set up and even easier to use with the Sonos app, your voice and Apple
Speaker 1:  airplay too. Unlock the most innovative spatial listening experience with
Speaker 1:  the ERA 300. Visit sonos.com to learn more and find thoughtful gifts
Speaker 1:  for everyone on your list.
Speaker 3:  Hello and Welcome. To Vergecast. The flagship podcast of the Touch Bar.
Speaker 4:  It's
Speaker 3:  Good. Only one of us thinks that Alex,
Speaker 1:  It's,
Speaker 4:  It's
Speaker 3:  True. Two
Speaker 3:  I, okay. One thing that is true is that I became friends with a
Speaker 3:  very famous record producer on Instagram because of the Touch Bar.
Speaker 4:  That was the best humble brag I've heard a lot. That's
Speaker 3:  Pretty good.
Speaker 4:  Who?
Speaker 1:  Who? Okay. So Neli and David gta are best friends.
Speaker 3:  No. Oak Felder. You should follow him on Instagram. He's Oak Orchestra. Oh
Speaker 3:  yeah, he's, he's super cool. Okay. They're just like dad friends. We just
Speaker 3:  like, like pictures of each other's kids now of this for you. But he did
Speaker 3:  a video with us just about how to make music with a Mac during one of our
Speaker 3:  music video series. And he was like, I, and he was using the Touch Bar on
Speaker 3:  his computer and I was like, what are you doing? And he was like, I
Speaker 3:  love this thing. And he was like swiping through logic on the Touch Bar and
Speaker 3:  we just started. Wow. That's it. That's the beginning of a beautiful friendship.
Speaker 3:  That's
Speaker 4:  Beautiful. Yeah. I should have talked to
Speaker 3:  Him. A beautiful dad friendship. Yeah. He doesn't post about the Touch Bar
Speaker 3:  on his Instagram. It's mostly like him doing recording artist stuff and
Speaker 3:  pictures.
Speaker 4:  I think if more people had it probably wouldn't have gone away. Yeah. If
Speaker 3:  More Grammy award winning musicians were like the Touch Bar rules, I think
Speaker 3:  we'd be in a very different spot in America in 2023
Speaker 4:  Only. It would only be on the 16th. Hi,
Speaker 3:  I'm your friend. Neli Alex. Cranz is here.
Speaker 4:  Hi. I'm your friend who loves the Touch Bar and the Texas Rangers who are
Speaker 4:  now have a World Series pin. It. I don't know how the World Series works,
Speaker 4:  but I've been waiting 30 years. It's awesome.
Speaker 3:  You've been waiting 30 years and learned none of the vocabulary of
Speaker 4:  It along the way. None of it. None of it. I learned who Nolan Ryan and Jose
Speaker 4:  Sseko were in 1993. Nice. And nothing until this year.
Speaker 4:  And apparently the Rangers rule you
Speaker 5:  Didn't miss that much between the two to be fair. Yeah. Yeah. I think I'm
Speaker 3:  Okay. I follow one of those threads accounts. It's like freezing cold sports
Speaker 3:  takes. And they had one about the Rangers and it was like, I don't know who
Speaker 3:  any of those names are or what baseball is David. Pierce is
Speaker 5:  Here. What's up guys? I'm in my sick gamer YouTube channel
Speaker 5:  set up. David's
Speaker 3:  In our DC office, the Vox Media DC office, which is
Speaker 5:  Aka a our Sik Gamer YouTube channel set up. I feel like I said that already.
Speaker 3:  That office is mostly populated by like the corporate staff of the company
Speaker 3:  and then vox.com. And a little bit of estimation, I think.
Speaker 3:  And of course when you think of vox.com, you think of gamer lights. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Obviously, I will say I'm here because I lost power
Speaker 5:  today just out of nowhere. On a sunny day in the middle
Speaker 5:  of an interview for The Vergecast with two of the people who made
Speaker 5:  Planet Earth three. We were having an unbelievable time
Speaker 5:  talking about cool drone photography in caves, which someday,
Speaker 5:  Lord willing you will hear on The Vergecast. And my power just
Speaker 5:  disappeared. And now I'm here. I hate it. It's been a day.
Speaker 3:  I took a meeting with a, a developer who's making a cool app
Speaker 3:  the David was supposed to be on, and I said, David lost power. And he looked
Speaker 3:  at the weather and said, it's not raining out there. Yep.
Speaker 3:  Very
Speaker 5:  Good. It's not
Speaker 3:  Bunch of news. This week there was an Apple event, which we, we should talk
Speaker 3:  about. A lot of people have a lot of feelings about this event and particularly
Speaker 3:  how it was shot. Oh, oh my. Sometimes The Verge,
Speaker 3:  you're on a publication, you're lucky if everyone's talking about one story.
Speaker 3:  We had like three different groups of people sort of like up in arms
Speaker 3:  about three different stories this week. And I was like, oh, we are the only
Speaker 3:  tech site that remains on the internet. There's, there's no one else to yell
Speaker 3:  it but us. But Apple Event, new Max, we should talk about those.
Speaker 3:  We published the next installment of our big Google package about
Speaker 3:  sort of where we are on the web and what's going on with search. Now
Speaker 3:  AI is coming. I would say that really
Speaker 3:  got a lot of people going. And those people happen to be search engine
Speaker 3:  optimization experts. So their comments are impeccably
Speaker 3:  formatted for discoverability. That's true. It's a
Speaker 5:  Nice reminder every once in a while. Like, do you have those moments where
Speaker 5:  like a, an a corner of the internet wakes up in response to something
Speaker 5:  and you're like, oh, I didn't even know you were there. Yeah. Yeah. It's
Speaker 5:  like, like when, when the knitters get really angry, you're just like, oh,
Speaker 5:  all the people who love to knit, they just hang out together. That's so cool.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  That's not a win. That's a permanent case with the knitting c that is
Speaker 5:  Just constant rage pit at all
Speaker 3:  Times. They're holding needles in their not afraid to use them, sir.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. But it was just like, it was like we, we accidentally walked into the
Speaker 5:  SEO bar this week.
Speaker 3:  No, we bared into it and said, you all suck.
Speaker 5:  That's,
Speaker 3:  That's what we did. That's fair. And I, I don't want to, that's shy away
Speaker 3:  from it. We'll get to that
Speaker 3:  more Google News. They're about to go to trial and the antitrust case with
Speaker 3:  Epic. David was in the other antitrust
Speaker 3:  trial this week. Sundar Phai testified. We gotta talk about that. There's
Speaker 3:  some spicy documents from Apple that were revealed in that case. That's pretty
Speaker 3:  good. Spicy
Speaker 5:  Documents. I love a spicy document.
Speaker 3:  I love a spicy document. Eddie Q's like, put some hot sauce on
Speaker 3:  that before you send it out. It's just the little, the little salt in the
Speaker 3:  cold storage for the prosecutors to find 10 years from now. And then there's
Speaker 3:  a bunch of streaming news. Yeah. People are buying things. Prices are inevitably
Speaker 3:  going up. And we got a lightning round, which is still not sponsored. And
Speaker 3:  I implore you major American ship maker
Speaker 3:  to call our financial sac, our business, our business development
Speaker 3:  person. Make it happen.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, there's, there's some good stuff in line too. Okay, let's start with
Speaker 3:  the Apple event. Scary fest. I would say
Speaker 3:  I was very disappointed. There were not more Halloween jokes.
Speaker 3:  There were a, you
Speaker 5:  Were also just wrong. Like we should just call this what you were, you were
Speaker 5:  wrong. And I feel like this is, this is the time when you should atone for
Speaker 5:  how wrong you were about what Hale was doing here. Yeah. Where's your scary
Speaker 5:  costume today, Eli?
Speaker 3:  No, thank you.
Speaker 3:  I did dress, I dressed, my parents were here for trick free. I dressed them
Speaker 3:  up as a witch in a warlock, which means I put hats on them. Yes.
Speaker 3:  And that's, and and then my dad was like, oh no, I lost the hat.
Speaker 3:  What a surprise. My prediction, if I recall this correctly, would just be
Speaker 3:  like over the top TV production, they're gonna compete with money at football.
Speaker 3:  Craig Federighi doing a Vampire Voice the whole time. That did
Speaker 3:  not happen. And I want to make it clear I was wrong about that, but also
Speaker 3:  that I was right in that it should have been what happened because the
Speaker 3:  actual announcements were so lackluster that Craig Federighi
Speaker 3:  doing a vampire voice, I think would've been more fulfilling to people. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Right. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Nila, you posted at one point on threads, I think something to the
Speaker 5:  effect of Apple has lost the plot of why people actually watch these things.
Speaker 5:  What did you mean
Speaker 3:  This one in particular? So if you go back
Speaker 3:  and watch a Steve Jobs Apple event, he was the
Speaker 3:  master of making you feel like, one,
Speaker 3:  he understood the problem and two, only he could solve it.
Speaker 3:  And three, the product was cool as hell. Right? th and that here is the solution
Speaker 3:  to the product. And that first part I understand the problem
Speaker 3:  is the, I I think is a person who came up covering these
Speaker 3:  events and watching them unfold and watching them grow to what they are now.
Speaker 3:  That's the part that's gone. But it's also the thing that was the most fulfilling.
Speaker 3:  Everyone knows the first iPhone event, right? The problem is all these buttons
Speaker 3:  down here, so we're gonna make a touch screen. Like any put up
Speaker 3:  the problem. He was like, here's a picture of other people's idiot problems
Speaker 3:  and I'm gonna fix it for you. And this is how smartphones are gonna work.
Speaker 3:  Now he did that like all the time. And Apple traditionally kind
Speaker 3:  of does that, right? They like identify the problem and they're like, here's
Speaker 3:  how we're gonna solve it. And this one in particular, I just
Speaker 3:  felt like identified no problems. It was like our,
Speaker 3:  the problem we're solving is that the chip is even faster,
Speaker 3:  Right? And then, and then you look at how they were trying to sell it. They
Speaker 3:  were like, this one is for creative professionals. If you're coming from
Speaker 3:  an Intel Mac, it'll be 11 times faster. They just weren't
Speaker 3:  solving any problems with the products. It was just like
Speaker 3:  pure marketing. There's just a moment in the middle of it. I actually didn't
Speaker 3:  put it on threads. I just said that to you privately. You doxxed me,
Speaker 3:  my bad, whatever. I'll say, I'll say it now. There was just a moment in that
Speaker 3:  where I was like, this could be any company. Like this is how basically every
Speaker 3:  company markets their products now. They're just like, look at how good it
Speaker 3:  is.
Speaker 4:  It was just an AMD keynote. AMD also loves to do an
Speaker 4:  evening keynote. Everybody loves to wear all black. There's usually some
Speaker 4:  leather involved, but not in a fun way. And then they talk about a bunch
Speaker 4:  of processors and show a bunch of charts.
Speaker 3:  So Qualcomm had an event the same week, ALS and Johnson was in Hawaii
Speaker 3:  for the event. She wrote a great piece about it. Festival of Marketing. And
Speaker 3:  the piece is basically about the festival of marketing. Qualcomm's processor
Speaker 3:  graphs are the same as Apples. They're the same unlabeled graph. And you
Speaker 3:  could argue that they're just copying Apple or Apple's copying Qualcomm or
Speaker 3:  there's a long history of these graphs. But just from the perspective of
Speaker 3:  are these events different? Do these companies act differently? The answer
Speaker 3:  is, oh, they're converging. They're all converging on the same sort of marketing.
Speaker 3:  I don't mean to say that the products are bad. I have a 16 inch M one Pro
Speaker 3:  MacBook Pro. It is the best computer I have ever owned.
Speaker 3:  You, you put a better chip in it. You do some software tweaks to make it
Speaker 3:  600 knits instead of 500. I'm happy as long as the battery life lasts, as
Speaker 3:  long as this one does. The problem is they've so fundamentally solved the
Speaker 3:  problem.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  That they're, they're just going, they're kind of reverting to marketing
Speaker 3:  and
Speaker 4:  It, they've been doing it honestly for a little while now. Like it's, it's
Speaker 4:  been a couple of years of they're not really solving a problem. They're inventing
Speaker 4:  problems to solve on stage. And So I think we see that a lot
Speaker 4:  with, with with a lot of the camera stuff they're doing. They're like, don't
Speaker 4:  you hate that you can't see every fiber of a sweater? And it's like
Speaker 4:  three people hate that, but most people are fine. and it it,
Speaker 4:  I I do agree with you that in the beginning it really felt like there was
Speaker 4:  a problem and they were solving it. And in some cases it was the
Speaker 4:  problem was Apple's own making. 'cause Apple was at that time, like a pretty
Speaker 4:  crummy company and it got better. And now it's just like, okay, you're at
Speaker 4:  the top of your game. What do you do next? And they're like, we do it at
Speaker 4:  night. Right.
Speaker 3:  And that's not enough. And mostly they're mostly the, we have solved a problem
Speaker 3:  involved the introduction of a new category. Right. So they the iPod
Speaker 3:  that watch the iPod launch event, right. He's like a thousand songs
Speaker 3:  in your pocket.
Speaker 4:  Creative Jukebox in the audience Furious.
Speaker 3:  Right. He put up a picture of that thing and it was like, this thing sucks.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Like he really did. He was like, here's the MP three players of the
Speaker 3:  of the day. Here's the ones that are flash memory, here's the hard drive
Speaker 3:  ones. These suck. I made a good one. Yeah. And, and then every iPod every
Speaker 3:  year after he invented a reason, well that was like why they were bad
Speaker 3:  and they like fix it. Whatever the iPad,
Speaker 3:  if you watch the iPad one, it is remarkable
Speaker 3:  actually. 'cause he is like, you have a phone and a laptop and there's some,
Speaker 3:  there's space in between.
Speaker 5:  He brought like a comfy armchair Yeah. On stage. Like that was, that was
Speaker 5:  the thing. It was the armchair computer. Right? Like that was he he did such
Speaker 5:  a good job of that. Yeah. He
Speaker 3:  He had a show to put on for you in You know whatever Steve Jobs
Speaker 3:  was Steve Jobs. I'm just saying that was the thing. And I think Apple
Speaker 3:  has now gotten to this place where these are in, it's an infomercial. We
Speaker 3:  all sat around and watched a 23 minute infomercial the other night. It was
Speaker 3:  produced like one, it was shot like one. I understand people have a lot of
Speaker 3:  feelings about that, but it was a TV show. Yeah. They should have done more
Speaker 3:  vampire voices. I will. Tim Cook kind of did one
Speaker 3:  with the first Good Evening and Johnny Shreeji was like, Welcome To my
Speaker 3:  lab. And he was clearly, if they had let him, he would've done the whole
Speaker 3:  thing in the Voice. Yes. But those are the only two I got out of it. There
Speaker 3:  were some eyes blinking in the background, whatever. All the, all I'm saying,
Speaker 3:  and this is the most minor criticism because we should talk, actually talk
Speaker 3:  about the products, the show of it, ever since it's become a
Speaker 3:  TV show has veered into just sort of regular
Speaker 3:  marketing and not the Apple will identify
Speaker 3:  a thing that everyone is frustrated with or has never thought of and show
Speaker 3:  you something. The Vision Pro is arguably that product right now.
Speaker 3:  Right. It's the new category. It's the new use cases,
Speaker 4:  But they didn't have a problem to solve for it.
Speaker 3:  That's, I would say is the problem. Yeah. And. what?
Speaker 3:  We'll see how it goes. But yeah, I don't, we don't need to over index on
Speaker 3:  whether the 23 minute, last minute Mac infomercial was like the
Speaker 3:  best Apple keynote of all. I'm, when I say they've lost the plot on why people
Speaker 3:  watch these, it's if you just watch them now, the only problem they have
Speaker 3:  to solve is like, five years ago you bought an Intel Mac and now you should
Speaker 3:  buy a new one. And that's not a great problem to solve. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Which I think is why they're leaning ever harder into
Speaker 5:  pros. Right. And that's like, that was so much of what this event was about.
Speaker 5:  I just keep thinking about when they launched the Mac Pro and we were getting
Speaker 5:  demos of it and seeing how things worked, the demo was literally
Speaker 5:  avatar. Yeah. That it's like, this is, these computers are so good.
Speaker 5:  Imagine if you were making the most complicated movie ever made in history,
Speaker 5:  you would need this Mac Pro and you're just like, All. right. Sick. Like
Speaker 5:  how many Chrome taps can it handle? Like what I just is they,
Speaker 5:  they, we've just gotten into these tiny niches where this stuff, especially
Speaker 5:  having to do this every year, right? Like if Apple only had to tell this
Speaker 5:  story every five years, it wouldn't be that hard telling everybody who bought
Speaker 5:  a computer in 2018, why the M three MacBook Pro is gonna blow your mind
Speaker 5:  is not complicated. But they have to keep telling this story
Speaker 5:  year after year after year. And, and it does, you can just see it
Speaker 5:  get sort of smaller and smaller and smaller. The people who are sort of actually
Speaker 5:  meaningfully going to notice the thing over the last year. And again, in
Speaker 5:  a lot of ways that's a really good thing. Like these are great super mature
Speaker 5:  products. It just, it just makes this particular job much
Speaker 5:  harder, I think. Yeah. I
Speaker 4:  That's why Qualcomm does it in Hawaii is because
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Seriously. 'cause they, they ran into the same issue. Like all of the processor
Speaker 4:  companies have been dealing with this for a very long time. And Apple's now
Speaker 4:  having to reckon with it too, where like, yeah, these speed improvements
Speaker 4:  are nice, but they're mainly nice for when you look back five years.
Speaker 4:  And most people in our industry don't care about that. And a lot of our readers
Speaker 4:  probably don't care about it. Like my brother who has a five-year-old computer
Speaker 4:  might care. But, but tho those people who, who tune into these
Speaker 4:  events to see the next big thing don't care about a small
Speaker 4:  speed bump. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  I will say that there was one problem that they created that they solved
Speaker 3:  to grade acclaim, which was the Touch Bar and the butterfly keyboard.
Speaker 3:  The
Speaker 4:  Butterfly keyboard
Speaker 3:  Don't give, and the utter lack of ports on the MacBook Pro.
Speaker 3:  And they, they fixed that a couple years ago. Yeah. Again, best computer
Speaker 3:  I've ever owned. And then this year was the end of the 13 inch
Speaker 3:  MacBook Pro with the Touch
Speaker 4:  Bar. Yeah. Yeah. I I feel like we, we've kind of been memorializing it
Speaker 4:  since it stopped getting a lot of the same updates as everybody else. It
Speaker 4:  was kind of sitting off in the corner by itself, clearly on its last legs.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. But this year they were like, no, we're done.
Speaker 3:  We're
Speaker 4:  Out. Yeah. We're putting the stake in the heart. We're we're salting the
Speaker 4:  earth. We're Closing the door. We're done with it. And it's a bummer.
Speaker 3:  Good vampire imagery. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Oh, I, I'm bringing it. Apple didn't, but I did.
Speaker 4:  I I, I still liked the concept of the thing. I
Speaker 4:  still wish they had like, leaned in on the Touch Bar, but the Touch Bar
Speaker 4:  was really a placeholder for the, the M one,
Speaker 4:  like the Touch Bar came out because they wanted to show everybody they cared
Speaker 4:  about laptops because in 2016 they didn't care about laptops.
Speaker 4:  They were running all the MacBook posts had, has wells in 'em from like 2014
Speaker 4:  or 2013. And, and they were like, no, no, we care. We care. So
Speaker 4:  look, we've got this cool new way of thinking about computers. We're putting
Speaker 4:  a Touch Bar in it. And everybody's like, cool, what can we do with it? And
Speaker 4:  they're like, we'll get back to you. Yeah. But it's cool. And then a few
Speaker 4:  years later they're like, we've got them one and this is really cool. And
Speaker 4:  everybody's like, oh, that is cool. I want that. And So I always
Speaker 4:  feel like it was just a placeholder to keep people invested in Apple
Speaker 4:  laptops until the real deal showed up a few years later.
Speaker 3:  I That's a very kind way of thinking about the touch force.
Speaker 4:  I was just You know when you, when you care about something that deeply,
Speaker 4:  you're always looking for the good. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I think they made a giant mistake and refused to admit it for several
Speaker 3:  years. That honestly, I think they, that that was the period where
Speaker 3:  they thought the future of computing was the iPad and they were pushing
Speaker 3:  everyone towards the iPad. And then Mac was languishing. Yeah. And they're,
Speaker 3:  and everyone thought you need to put a touchscreen on the Mac. And they were
Speaker 4:  Like, no, they're
Speaker 3:  Still, maybe some people kind of do, there's a Bloomberg report, by the way,
Speaker 3:  this week or the week before where Germin said a forthcoming
Speaker 3:  touchscreen Mac. Oh,
Speaker 4:  What?
Speaker 3:  Wow. This is a real thing. Who knows? We
Speaker 4:  Yeah. One day.
Speaker 3:  But Robert wrote, right, this was the height of what you might call Apple's
Speaker 3:  Touch era. And they, they weren't gonna do it on the Mac 'cause they didn't
Speaker 3:  want to cannibalize the iPad in anyway. So they're like, you want a touchscreen
Speaker 3:  on the Mac? Here's a weird little one. Also, the keyboard
Speaker 3:  is garbage and it has no ports. And people resolutely
Speaker 3:  refuse to let the Mac die until they re-upped the MacBook Air. And then
Speaker 3:  eventually M one came out. And then the weird thing was
Speaker 3:  they did the good MacBook Pro, the 14 inch MacBook Pro,
Speaker 3:  they did the MacBook Air, the MacBook Air got all the way to M two and this
Speaker 3:  weird dumb 13 inch MacBook Pro at the Touch Bar just
Speaker 3:  persisted. I wanna, it's, it's like two years beyond
Speaker 3:  its expiration date at least. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I wanna know who, who are the people who, were the people still buying it
Speaker 4:  there at the end?
Speaker 3:  Some people,
Speaker 5:  I don't know man. We, we wrote a story a couple of weeks ago about somebody
Speaker 5:  who bought a weu the other day. That's fair. There's people out there That's
Speaker 5:  fair. There's there's people out there doing stuff. But no, I think, I think
Speaker 5:  Apple made two mistakes with the Touch Bar, which I do not
Speaker 5:  believe still to this day was a fundamentally bad idea. It
Speaker 4:  Is a good concept.
Speaker 5:  Mistake number one, look down at your laptop right now and if you're in your
Speaker 5:  car, if, imagine a laptop.
Speaker 3:  If you're in your car and you have the ability to look down at your laptop
Speaker 3:  right now, pull over in your car
Speaker 5:  And also call The Vergecast hotline because you are our people. Do you
Speaker 5:  see, do you see how you have all the function buttons on your, on your laptop?
Speaker 5:  Do you see how there's still some space above it between the, where there's
Speaker 5:  just space Put the Touch Bar there. That's the
Speaker 5:  answer. Like they said, what if we took away a bunch of buttons you
Speaker 5:  love and replaced it with mostly nothing. Like that's terrible. Yeah. That's
Speaker 5:  not, that's not anything. I still believe to this day that if the first version
Speaker 5:  of the Touch Bar had kept the escape key, the Touch Bar had like a 60%
Speaker 5:  chance to be successful, but it was because it didn't have the escape key.
Speaker 5:  And all of a sudden this very basic thing that professional computer users
Speaker 5:  do all day every day became harder because your finger couldn't
Speaker 5:  find it anymore. Like instant disaster. Yeah. That's mistake number one
Speaker 5:  was getting rid of keys people use to add this weird thing that
Speaker 5:  no one ever asked for. Mistake number two was
Speaker 5:  stopping investing in it. Like Apple has a good history of
Speaker 5:  saying we care about this thing. And thus you developers should figure out
Speaker 5:  what to do with it. And if it does that long enough, it usually works. And
Speaker 5:  on the Touch Bar for like 15 minutes, they were like, come build cool apps.
Speaker 5:  And then they were like, ah, nevermind. We're probably gonna bail on this
Speaker 5:  idea.
Speaker 3:  No. So they had a huge problem here. They do this all the time. The best
Speaker 3:  example is iPhone, right? They bring a, a high-end feature to an iPhone Pro
Speaker 3:  and the next year the regular iPhone gets it and then everyone has it. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  And then developers are like, wow, look at all this cool stuff Apple made.
Speaker 3:  I've got some ideas they need too. They never brought the Touch Bar out of
Speaker 3:  the MacBook Pro.
Speaker 5:  Exactly. Or, and even
Speaker 4:  Out
Speaker 3:  Of the, because they knew it was bad. Aw. They were watching
Speaker 3:  all these pro users stare at their horrible keyboards
Speaker 3:  and they thought to themselves, we cannot give this to the general public.
Speaker 5:  Hence mistake number one. Yeah. Like you can't get rid of the function
Speaker 5:  keys. Yeah. It's like if Apple was like, look, we built this
Speaker 5:  cool Touch Bar, but also we just scrambled all your letter keys around like,
Speaker 5:  no, don't do that.
Speaker 3:  Look, it's dead here, here. It's amazing to me that we've spent this much
Speaker 3:  time in the Touch Bar, which I finally vanquished. They announced like three
Speaker 3:  new processors and four new computers. No, it's,
Speaker 5:  We talked about all that on Wednesday. Who cares? You know
Speaker 4:  What we talked earlier about how they didn't solve a problem during this
Speaker 4:  event. They did. They got
Speaker 3:  Rid of the Touch Bar not having enough processors.
Speaker 4:  No, they got rid of the Touch Bar. They solved a problem if they had led
Speaker 4:  with that. Like
Speaker 3:  See, that's a good Halloween show. Yeah. Tim Cook dressed up as the
Speaker 3:  grim reaper chasing Eddie Q in a Touch Bar outfit
Speaker 3:  down the hallway. I would've watched two hours of that. That's pretty good.
Speaker 3:  I probably would've That's good. I would've put pre-ordered at the end.
Speaker 4:  I don't wanna watch that show. But I would've watched gifs of it. I would've
Speaker 4:  watch the TikTok clips
Speaker 3:  Pronounced gif.
Speaker 3:  So if you wanted the deep dive on the main announcements, the Wednesday show
Speaker 3:  is there for you quickly. They basically spec bumped the 14 inch and
Speaker 3:  16 inch MacBook Pro. They spec bumped the
Speaker 3:  iMac. They did not do a bigger screen size. They spent an like an
Speaker 3:  inor amount of time saying that 24.5 inches,
Speaker 3:  4.5 K display was perfect.
Speaker 4:  Sounded a lot like the Touch Bar is gonna revolutionize.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. It was just a lot of like, this is the perfect size in between four
Speaker 3:  K and five K and it's like, is it, or is it just the size in
Speaker 3:  between four K and five
Speaker 5:  K? It's just the one you already made a lot of. That's
Speaker 3:  It. I am, I'm dying because I
Speaker 3:  really wanted a new 27 inch iMac to replace my, my
Speaker 3:  20 15 27 inch iMac that I already
Speaker 3:  rescued from its planned obsolescence in our studio. Couldn't
Speaker 4:  You just get like a Mac studio and slap it on the end? But
Speaker 5:  Then I have to
Speaker 3:  Yeah. But then I have to like buy a new monitor, all this stuff. Anyway,
Speaker 3:  we, they just sent me a new USB audio interface
Speaker 3:  for recording at home. 'cause my old one is kind of flaking out. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  I'm, I'm aware
Speaker 3:  It's A-U-S-B-C only. So I've got, I gotta get
Speaker 3:  a new Mac So I was like, I'll just buy the new 27 inch Trimm Mac have to
Speaker 4:  Get a new Mac. That's the only solution. I gotta
Speaker 3:  Do something now. But now, now, but I'm not gonna buy this little
Speaker 3:  baby
Speaker 5:  Mac. Yeah. My in-laws had a 27 inch iMac from
Speaker 5:  I think 2011, possibly even like 2009. They had
Speaker 5:  this thing forever and it finally got to the point where it's like they tried
Speaker 5:  to load the tax website and it just didn't, it was like this, this computer
Speaker 5:  is a security risk. Like we can't do this anymore guys. So they've
Speaker 5:  been asking me for like a year and a half. When is the 27 inch iMac coming
Speaker 5:  out? And I kept saying, I went from, I think
Speaker 5:  it's gonna happen. Give it a minute to, I don't think this is gonna happen.
Speaker 5:  'cause the Mac studio and the studio display or the answers So, I got them
Speaker 5:  to buy a Mac mini and a monitor, which I actually think is a
Speaker 5:  cheaper combo and works just as well. But setting this thing up
Speaker 5:  for them gave me like a real new understanding of why the
Speaker 5:  iMac is great. Yeah. Because I had to buy them a webcam. We had
Speaker 5:  to go through this whole crazy rigmarole with their keyboard because you
Speaker 5:  can't set up a Mac without a keyboard and you can't connect a keyboard without
Speaker 5:  setting up your Mac. So you need a wired keyboard, which no one has because
Speaker 5:  it's 2023. No way.
Speaker 3:  And that
Speaker 5:  Be right. I'm not a PC gamer. That's real. It's,
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It does not like Bluetooth. I always have to scramble.
Speaker 5:  The advice they give you on the internet is keep a wired keyboard around
Speaker 5:  just in case you have to set up a computer. Full chaos.
Speaker 5:  So I went through this whole thing and like, we eventually got it set up
Speaker 5:  and I was like, boy, it would've been really nice if I could've just like
Speaker 5:  pulled a thing out of a box, plugged it in and turned it.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Look, I'm an iMac person, that's why. Yeah. Although
Speaker 3:  my iMac has all this stuff plugged into it, including an ancient flaky USB
Speaker 3:  audio interface that needs to be replaced. So
Speaker 5:  You gotta buy a new Mac,
Speaker 3:  So I. Gotta buy a new Mac.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. That's how you do it. It's called VERGE Logic right there. It,
Speaker 3:  It really makes a lot of sense when you think about it. I'm just gonna buy
Speaker 3:  like a 2017 iMac with USBC. This is my idea.
Speaker 3:  All. right. Let's talk about shot on iPhone for two minutes. Okay.
Speaker 3:  So at the end of the event, apple puts up a label. It says shot on iPhone.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I wanna, I I know why they're able to do this now. We will come to
Speaker 3:  that. And then a little bit later they release some behind the scenes and
Speaker 3:  they show massive production. Like
Speaker 3:  cool, like cool
Speaker 4:  Stuff. Big lenses bolted to the front of iPhones and stuff like that. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Big lights, big lenses. You know, there's like drone shots and CGI,
Speaker 3:  it's a tv. They made a TV show. Yep. Apple is a TV company.
Speaker 3:  It's like a high
Speaker 5:  End one. They
Speaker 3:  Made that, they made a TV show. Great. So we have a story that's like,
Speaker 3:  here's what they mean when I say shot on iPhone and the story, it contains
Speaker 3:  almost no take. There's I, I will get to it,
Speaker 3:  but it contains almost no take. It's just, here's all the stuff, here's the,
Speaker 3:  if you wanna do this, it costs us much money. People are freaking out that
Speaker 3:  we're like accusing Apple being liars. and it's like, no,
Speaker 3:  this is just at the end of the video. It doesn't show you the stuff. It's
Speaker 3:  just a shot on iPhone. Yeah. Yeah. And the very obvious thing that they want
Speaker 3:  you to think is that you can do this with an iPhone and then
Speaker 3:  it's cool. They show you behind the scenes of what you need to do if you
Speaker 3:  just wanna do an iPhone. They, and they did the same thing with Olivia Rodrigo,
Speaker 3:  right? She has a music video they shot on iPhone. They're running national
Speaker 3:  ads during football games showing the thing in a gimbal.
Speaker 3:  Like they're not hiding the ball. But shot on iPhone
Speaker 3:  is meant to make you feel good about the iPhone not
Speaker 3:  make you consider the production. It it's
Speaker 3:  just marketing. Yeah. I don't, I feel great about iPhones. I don't know,
Speaker 3:  I I bear no ill will towards the iPhone because they put it in a gimbal.
Speaker 3:  But the point of it is like, look how cool the iPhone is. If
Speaker 3:  you had an iPhone, you too could be some combination of
Speaker 3:  Vampire Tim Cook and Olivia Rodrigo. That's how I feel every
Speaker 3:  time I pick up my phone. That's
Speaker 5:  The dream. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Whatever. I, I think people are upset about this
Speaker 3:  for like the, I'm smarter than you reason,
Speaker 3:  like You know it ins, like if you're a Verge reader, You know instinctively
Speaker 3:  that Apple has a lot of lights. Right. And when they shoot the thing on the
Speaker 3:  iPhone and the idea that other people would know that
Speaker 3:  and that would be surprising to them and make them feel feelings about Apple
Speaker 3:  just made a bunch of Apple people mad. That's like basically my summation
Speaker 3:  of this controversy, whatever. It's like
Speaker 4:  All it did was make me realize that all of those shot on iPhone photos
Speaker 4:  might also
Speaker 3:  Have, have had lights. Have had lights and lights. So here's the thing you
Speaker 3:  can do. If you give me enough lights, I can make any camera look good.
Speaker 3:  Actually, not me. If you give Becca enough lights, you can make any
Speaker 5:  Yes.
Speaker 3:  That's great. Like, that's well known. Any person who has played with
Speaker 3:  photography knows like, give me enough lights and lenses and stuff. You
Speaker 3:  can pretty much make any camera look good. I think the reason they're able
Speaker 3:  to shot on iPhone with the iPhone 15 Pro Max or whatever is not
Speaker 3:  the camera system. It's that they can get the footage off the
Speaker 3:  phone at US BBC speeds. Yep. and it shoots in
Speaker 3:  log, which is software. I bet. I, I bet if Apple wanted to write a custom
Speaker 3:  version of iOS that could shoot in log that could do it. But the 15 can now
Speaker 3:  do it for everybody and it has a, the
Speaker 3:  hardware capability of getting the footage off the phone. And so
Speaker 3:  these are two things that are very important for pros and apple's shutting
Speaker 3:  off. Like, look, this sensor and this thing, and the the thing is good enough
Speaker 3:  where you can replace a professional camera in some context if you have enough
Speaker 3:  lights and professional things. But that's like a very hard thing to communicate.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Like we, we've changed the port to USBC,
Speaker 3:  so now you can shoot a professional production on the phone and you don't
Speaker 3:  have to wait six days to get the files off the phone. I would say
Speaker 3:  not the world's greatest marketing message shot an iPhone. Very good.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I think to me the, the challenge is always that when we talk about
Speaker 5:  smartphone shooting, it's, it's kind of
Speaker 5:  two different things that actually are totally different, but
Speaker 5:  everybody kind of wants to have the best of both worlds. So on the one side
Speaker 5:  you have something like this, which is like a very high-end production. And
Speaker 5:  basically all they did was take out a
Speaker 5:  fancy camera. Like they, they took out a Cannon camera and put in an iPhone.
Speaker 5:  Otherwise, the whole setup is essentially the same. And that's actually what
Speaker 5:  they say in the behind the scenes videos that one of the coolest things about
Speaker 5:  it is how little of the process they had to change. They can still see the
Speaker 5:  footage and all their monitors, they can still do the stuff in real time.
Speaker 5:  They can get all the stuff that they need, like plug and play
Speaker 5:  into an otherwise very expensive professional setup is one side of thing.
Speaker 5:  Right. The other thing we talk about with smartphone photos and video is
Speaker 5:  that it lets you do stuff you couldn't do otherwise. Right. Like, I remember
Speaker 5:  Anthony Bourdain's team used to talk about this, that like when they started
Speaker 5:  shooting with iPhones and restaurants instead of big TV cameras,
Speaker 5:  it changed the vibe and you can just get places you couldn't otherwise.
Speaker 5:  Like nature photographers talk about this too, that like, you can get up
Speaker 5:  close to things with a phone in a way that you can't with a giant camera,
Speaker 5:  with a giant lens. And so we have this idea that when we say things like
Speaker 5:  shot on iPhone, the the mental image is like a person holding a phone
Speaker 5:  up in front of their face. That's obviously not how It works. Like
Speaker 5:  no professional anything is actually shot that way. But
Speaker 5:  the mental image that I think Apple and everyone else wants you to have when
Speaker 5:  you, you think about that is that it's essentially Tim Cook standing there
Speaker 5:  and like, I don't know Craig Federighi standing there just like standing
Speaker 4:  His eyes on me. Tim,
Speaker 5:  If you think about it for one and a half seconds. Yeah. That's obviously
Speaker 5:  not what's going on. But like, and
Speaker 3:  This is what I'm saying, I think this is what people are, they're like mad
Speaker 3:  about is they've thought about it. And sometimes when
Speaker 3:  other people learn something, a reaction of people on the internet is to
Speaker 3:  get very mad about that.
Speaker 4:  I mean, I do that anytime someone says, have you heard of this film? Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I get so annoying.
Speaker 3:  It's just, it's just weird. It's like, yeah,
Speaker 5:  I've heard of all the films,
Speaker 4:  Every film
Speaker 3:  I, it's, I I think it's very human. I'm not blaming anybody for this reaction.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I'm just saying, I think I, I'm identifying a thing that is happening
Speaker 3:  that has nothing to do with whether marketing all aligns the difference between
Speaker 3:  a professional camera shoot and Craig Federighi holding up. Like of course
Speaker 3:  the marketing elides the difference between those two things. It's an ad
Speaker 3:  like I'm, yeah, it's the richest company in the world is making ads like,
Speaker 3:  duh,
Speaker 4:  I really want Craig to shoot the next iPhone keynote. Just only
Speaker 4:  Craig.
Speaker 3:  He's just, he's just chasing Olivia Rodrigo around while she crashes Cars
Speaker 3:  in a vampire outfit. All. right? That's that. Whatever you can feel however
Speaker 3:  you want. I hope you enjoy your iPhone. Please shoot more music videos and
Speaker 3:  send 'em to us. Olivia
Speaker 4:  Rodrigo,
Speaker 3:  The other group of people that was really mad at us this week that I mentioned
Speaker 3:  in at the top of the show was SEO professionals who, again, I really
Speaker 3:  encourage you to one, go read our piece by a man of Chicago Lewis about the
Speaker 3:  culture of SEO, which no one ever writes about. And we can get to
Speaker 3:  the piece, but then read the comments from the angry SEO people because the
Speaker 3:  comments are some of the best formatted, most, or like,
Speaker 3:  if they could have put h twos in the comments for better search discoverability,
Speaker 3:  they would have.
Speaker 3:  It is amazing. The keywords are impeccable. It is. The funniest thing about
Speaker 3:  this whole situation is the SEO professionals being mad at us, but doing
Speaker 3:  perfect SEO by instinct in all of the places where they're yelling at us.
Speaker 3:  Ah, chef's Kiss. So we have this big package all year. It's been the
Speaker 3:  running theme of our year. If you care about AI and
Speaker 3:  you think AI is transformative, which I, I think a lot of people do, and
Speaker 3:  you are looking at the canon of c plus AI
Speaker 3:  generated content that is being fired at every platform in the world.
Speaker 3:  You're like, oh boy, the web's gonna be weird. Oh boy, what's Google
Speaker 3:  gonna do? What's Google gonna do when it starts doing more of the
Speaker 3:  generated answers instead of just 10 blue links? What's Apple gonna do
Speaker 3:  when Google starts doing that? And their search revenue deal changes in
Speaker 3:  big ways. Like if you, if you undo search in any way,
Speaker 3:  the knock on effects are gigantic. It is the architecture of the
Speaker 3:  web. So we're just like writing about it.
Speaker 5:  Did we talk about the melting egg thing? No. On this show yet? Did you guys
Speaker 5:  see this? This is just the tiniest little version of this thing and it's,
Speaker 5:  it's just my favorite. So Quora, the question and answer
Speaker 5:  website has been doing work with AI generated
Speaker 5:  answers to people's questions. It's possible that I'm misremembering this,
Speaker 5:  but I don't think so. There was a question on Quora that said, can you melt
Speaker 5:  an egg? And so chat
Speaker 5:  GPT through Quora answered, yes, you can melt an egg, which you
Speaker 5:  obviously cannot Google indexes Quora
Speaker 5:  because it's a higher ranking site full of good user generated content. So
Speaker 5:  now if you Google, can you melt an egg? Google says yes, you can melt an
Speaker 5:  egg even though that's not true. So then a bunch of news outlets pick up
Speaker 5:  this story about being able to melt an egg, which feeds more data back
Speaker 5:  into these generative systems. And so now there's all kinds of data
Speaker 5:  on the internet in which phrases like you can melt an egg exist
Speaker 5:  on high ranking websites. And so we got to the point where the question
Speaker 5:  can you melt an egg became like absolute certainty to Google
Speaker 5:  through all of the signals that at once about how things should work. Because
Speaker 5:  one little tiny AI system said so
Speaker 3:  They fixed it.
Speaker 5:  They have fixed it since. But that's like, there are going to be, I, I
Speaker 4:  Don't know if they
Speaker 5:  Did literally an infinity of examples like that because
Speaker 4:  I just Googled it and apparently the most common way to melt an egg is to
Speaker 4:  heat it using a stove or microwave. That's from
Speaker 4:  t nnn support.com.
Speaker 3:  It's good trusted
Speaker 4:  Source for egg
Speaker 3:  Melting. Okay. So if you, good, good example everyone,
Speaker 3:  we did it.
Speaker 3:  If you think that these things are worth talking about, you
Speaker 3:  might direct your resources at covering the present state of Google
Speaker 3:  and the web and how we got here. Google search so that you might
Speaker 3:  be better positioned to cover what happens next, which appears
Speaker 3:  to be a snake eating its tail of melted eggs.
Speaker 4:  Delicious.
Speaker 5:  Pretty soon we will all be melting eggs thanks to Google.
Speaker 3:  These are just crazy outcomes. Right. And they're culture shaping outcomes.
Speaker 3:  A real reason that the flat earth conspiracy has as much
Speaker 3:  traction as it does is because every time another NBA player
Speaker 3:  says they believe in a flat earth conspiracy, people Google it
Speaker 3:  and then a million websites see that in Google Trends and they write about
Speaker 3:  flat earth stuff. Yep. And that is just a feedback loop
Speaker 3:  that has made more people be like, flat Earth is a reasonable debate
Speaker 3:  to have because I see it in the information ecosystem.
Speaker 4:  People are stupid.
Speaker 3:  We've written that story. We'll put it in the show notes. So it was just
Speaker 3:  one of the weirdest things. I was like, I'm go explain how search made the
Speaker 3:  flat earth happening. and it, we did,
Speaker 4:  It's kind of weird that people forgot that the Google bomb exists.
Speaker 3:  So we wrote that story. So in our package, right? Yeah. We wrote an entire
Speaker 3:  story about how the culture, our broader pop culture for a minute,
Speaker 3:  the algorithm at the center of it was the Google search algorithm. Ryan
Speaker 3:  Broder wrote that story for us. Yeah. And now the algorithm at the center
Speaker 3:  of the culture is the TikTok algorithm. Maybe three years ago the, the algorithm
Speaker 3:  at the center of the culture was the YouTube algorithm. There's a brief enduring
Speaker 3:  moment where it's the Instagram algorithm that provided you the
Speaker 3:  Kardashians just you open Instagram. It's like, do you, here's another one.
Speaker 4:  I just watched them on E
Speaker 3:  Yeah. But the, the E But they, they were like masters of one platform.
Speaker 3:  They haven't jumped to another. That's true. Right. And it's just, I think
Speaker 3:  it's important to look at the search algorithm and say this thing once ran
Speaker 3:  the culture, it's still how information is organized around the world.
Speaker 3:  Everyone writes to it.
Speaker 4:  I mean, I think about SEO like it's not my Roman empire, but it's up
Speaker 4:  there.
Speaker 3:  What a phrase. See that's a, that's a TikTok phrase. Yep.
Speaker 3:  The algorithm at the center of the culture is, is it's ever changing, but
Speaker 3:  you can almost always identify it. So writing all these pieces, we'll link
Speaker 3:  to all of them. Last week we had a piece about restaurants naming themselves
Speaker 3:  near me. Mia wrote it. It's incredible. It's great. Thai food near me is
Speaker 3:  a real restaurant you can go to in New York. Food's actually quite good.
Speaker 3:  Mia says, so we'll link to that. We've got a bunch of these this week it
Speaker 3:  was Amanda Chicago, Lewis writing about the culture of people who practice
Speaker 3:  SEO, not technical SEO tips
Speaker 3:  of which this piece contained none. I and I,
Speaker 3:  everyone's like responding to it as though this is how to do SEO.
Speaker 3:  No, no, no. This is a piece about the, the culture of the people
Speaker 3:  who practice it professionally and the conferences they go to and how they
Speaker 3:  talk about Google
Speaker 4:  And a five and a half foot long alligator
Speaker 3:  Into five and the conferences they go in Florida. Yeah. Generally Florida
Speaker 3:  is a concept, is in this piece quite a lot. And, what is, I would
Speaker 3:  just point out to everyone, this is like a well-known thing you can do.
Speaker 3:  You can say we're sitting in the financial district in New York. I would
Speaker 3:  like to write a piece about the culture of finance. Pros is like a real thing
Speaker 3:  many magazines do all the time because they, they're
Speaker 3:  cartoonish and then
Speaker 4:  They make movies about it and they star Leonardo DiCaprio And
Speaker 3:  True. And very rarely do the movies contain technical
Speaker 3:  explanations of what the finance pros are doing all day long. How to do finance.
Speaker 3:  You can, right. Like many television shows are about the culture
Speaker 3:  of being a lawyer. Very rarely does suits
Speaker 3:  ever get any part of the law. Right? I can't watch this show. It's so bad.
Speaker 3:  It's everywhere. The algorithms just want to make me watch the
Speaker 4:  Torres
Speaker 3:  It. But this is just a thing, right? The the culture of a profession is
Speaker 3:  a reasonable thing to write about. Yeah. So our piece is about the culture
Speaker 3:  of the profession and like how they feel about
Speaker 3:  doing a thing that scammers do to make money and that other people do
Speaker 3:  to just get you to go to their doctor's office or whatever. Right. Piece
Speaker 3:  is great. and it is, it's a bunch of characters because
Speaker 3:  the people who are best at SEO make a lot of money and they have
Speaker 3:  silly cars and they buy alligators for their conferences
Speaker 3:  and they're just loud characters. And one of the central points of this
Speaker 3:  story is the guy at Google who used to sort of manage the SEO
Speaker 3:  industry. It was a guy named Matt Cots who talked to us for the story. Matt
Speaker 3:  has been outta Google forever. He went to the US digital service under
Speaker 3:  Barack Obama. So he was in the government, he was ACTO, I think the USTS
Speaker 3:  and Google to replace him. Hired a whole bunch of people. One
Speaker 3:  of those people was a guy named Danny Sullivan. Danny Sullivan used to be
Speaker 3:  a journalist. He ran a site called Search Engine Land. I used to be a regular
Speaker 3:  reader of search engine land. Now he's a guy who works at Google and sort
Speaker 3:  of interfaces with people who wanna do SEO.
Speaker 3:  The people in our story are like, things changed when one guy left and another
Speaker 3:  guy came in, which is a totally reasonable thing to say, right? The
Speaker 3:  posture of the company changed when this sort of ad hoc guy
Speaker 3:  in 2009 was doing it. And then he left and they built an entire function
Speaker 3:  to replace him in the face of that function. Is this guy,
Speaker 3:  Danny's been doing this a long time. I, I think
Speaker 3:  having, I know a lot of people who have reported on search, we've done a
Speaker 3:  lot of stories about search. I think the scrutiny of Search And
Speaker 3:  what it is and how It works is frustrating to people at Google
Speaker 3:  who are in general idealistic about what it should do.
Speaker 3:  Right? There's a trial like David this week published the list of
Speaker 3:  the, was it top 10 most lucrative search terms in 2018?
Speaker 3:  Yep. And the idea that search has a deeply commercial business
Speaker 3:  really rankles Google, but it is their entire business.
Speaker 5:  I don't think that's true. No, I don't like, I actually don't think Google
Speaker 5:  is like afraid of the idea that it makes money from search. Like I
Speaker 5:  actually think that that's one step too far. I think what Google believes
Speaker 5:  earnestly, like at its corporate center
Speaker 5:  is that what's good for Google is good for the web. Yeah. Yes.
Speaker 5:  And by making Google better and giving more people more access to Google,
Speaker 5:  Google has made the web better. Like Sundar just said that in court
Speaker 5:  this week. I genuinely believe that that is a thing that Google as a
Speaker 5:  company believes. And so for us to come in and say
Speaker 5:  essentially that what you've done is you've created a game to be won
Speaker 5:  And. what everybody is doing is doing these things in order to win it. And
Speaker 5:  by doing so, they're ruining the internet. Essentially what we're saying
Speaker 5:  to Google is like, and I I I think it's true. I think you look at the internet
Speaker 5:  and it is like proably true at this point. But what we're saying is Google,
Speaker 5:  by trying to grow Google, you've not only grown the web, you've re
Speaker 5:  incentivized the web Yep. To make it worse in order to serve
Speaker 5:  you better.
Speaker 3:  Right. If I was to say to you, how do you win the Instagram algorithm?
Speaker 3:  You have a mental model in your head. Yeah. Absent reels or whatever. But
Speaker 3:  like in that, in the moment of Instagram's greatest power, you have a mental
Speaker 3:  model of how that incentive structure worked. If I was to say to you,
Speaker 3:  how do you win the TikTok algorithm, you may or may not have a mental model.
Speaker 3:  How do you win the Logan Paul era YouTube
Speaker 3:  algorithm? You probably have a mental model, right? It's not a good one,
Speaker 3:  but Yeah. But it's there, right? Like you do a bunch of pranks with your
Speaker 3:  Bross, like it, whatever, all those things change and they come and go.
Speaker 3:  But the idea that there's an algorithm that can be gamed, people try to game
Speaker 3:  it, that leads to a type of content or a culture of those creators.
Speaker 3:  When we go talk to the platform companies, the idea that we're doing a story
Speaker 3:  like this never surprises them. It never rankles them and ever irritates
Speaker 3:  them. It's just the thing that we do. Right? When you, when we have been
Speaker 3:  going to do it with search, Hey, you, there's an algorithm that creates
Speaker 3:  a bunch of incentives and there's a bunch of creators out there who are trying
Speaker 3:  to game the algorithm. And that means the culture of the web and the content
Speaker 3:  we create looks like it responds to your incentives.
Speaker 3:  That's where I think Google is very frustrated.
Speaker 5:  Oh, I think that's right. Yeah. I think because I think what Google would
Speaker 5:  tell you is that it is designed to reflect
Speaker 5:  the best of the web. Yeah. And in reality, what it did was decide what the
Speaker 5:  best of the web is and then force everyone into that specific
Speaker 5:  box.
Speaker 3:  Right. And the particular thing that Danny
Speaker 3:  read our piece, he doesn't like it because he is characterized as being somewhat
Speaker 3:  unhappy with our reporter on the piece. And we link to Danny's
Speaker 3:  response on, on the homepage. You can read that too. But where he and I have
Speaker 3:  been going back on, on threads is Google
Speaker 3:  keeps saying, we publish all of these guidelines and we tell
Speaker 3:  people not to do the things that the guidelines don't say. Like the response
Speaker 3:  to every one of our pieces about Google search this year has been, that's
Speaker 3:  not what the guidelines say,
Speaker 4:  Which is just
Speaker 3:  Thousands of pages. And then also in the next breath, they're like, the best
Speaker 3:  thing to do is not read the guidelines.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Just make great content. Just
Speaker 3:  Make great stuff. And it's like, well, why do you publish all these guidelines?
Speaker 3:  Right. If you don't want anyone to read them. And there's a real tension
Speaker 3:  in there. Like if you are a person who builds a website, our
Speaker 3:  website, a lot of the schema of our website is designed for
Speaker 3:  Google. Like the, the underpinning of the layouts of our pages
Speaker 3:  are designed to be predictable for Google. Okay. Like, I don't
Speaker 3:  feel bad about that. I, I want our stuff to be searchable and discoverable,
Speaker 3:  but I also don't want us to write headlines for the Google search robot.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I want us to write headlines for people. And like, there's a real tension
Speaker 3:  there. And one of the things that makes that tension worse, I think for on
Speaker 3:  the web in general is Google
Speaker 3:  doesn't like recognize that tension exists. So when the people, when
Speaker 3:  scammers write headlines to fool Google, they win. Right. Or when
Speaker 4:  A company I like, like we see this a lot in, in our industry and every
Speaker 4:  elsewhere. I think we all think about SEO a lot. And that is one of the reasons
Speaker 4:  this story means a lot to people at The Verge is because we have to think
Speaker 4:  about SEO. It's important and we have to think, okay, well how far do we
Speaker 4:  go? How, how, how. Because there is that way where you can win the web. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And you can show, prove everyone that you can melt an egg. We
Speaker 3:  Are six months away from one of our major competitors
Speaker 3:  emerging is like a totally AI written content
Speaker 4:  Form. Exactly.
Speaker 3:  I i I feel it in my bones that that is the thing we'll compete against with
Speaker 3:  next year for search traffic. Yep.
Speaker 4:  And, and I mean that, that's exactly what's happening. We're seeing our major
Speaker 4:  competitors go down that road after we already watch them go and do things
Speaker 4:  like You know say, Hey, check out the hands-on for the new iPhone
Speaker 4:  15 Pro two weeks before it was announced. Just so they can
Speaker 3:  Gain Wait, can can we just do some SEO scam rundowns? Yeah. Our competitors
Speaker 3:  have, real competitors have done. Yes. So the, the one Alex is talking about,
Speaker 3:  we have a lot of competitors who a month before a device, any devices
Speaker 3:  released, they will put up a page
Speaker 4:  And it's a hands-on page. It's basically a holding page. The headline at
Speaker 4:  the top, a lot of the copy is about the hands-on. And then it'll be like,
Speaker 4:  come back on this day to check it out.
Speaker 3:  This is just an SEO game. Like I, I think that's Fake. And now we have covered
Speaker 3:  this a lot too. We have big competitors like Geo
Speaker 3:  Media and CNET and others who are running trials of AI generated
Speaker 3:  content. And their staffs are furious about this. They're not happy. The,
Speaker 3:  the people who make the work are not happy about this, but the corporations
Speaker 3:  are doing it and they all say the same excuse, which is, we have to learn
Speaker 3:  how to use this stuff. And it's like you're learning nothing. Yeah. What
Speaker 3:  have you learned?
Speaker 5:  Well, the other one, I think my, my guess would be one a lot of people have
Speaker 5:  encountered is when you search for some kind of coupons on the internet,
Speaker 5:  the number of sites that you would not expect to have a sneaky hidden
Speaker 5:  coupons page for Bed Bath and Beyond that nevertheless has a sneaky hidden
Speaker 5:  coupon page for Bed Bath and Beyond is like alarming.
Speaker 3:  And it's, I just look, I just bought a solo stuff. I took the coupon right
Speaker 3:  from wire.com. There you go. That was a totally weird experience, but I was
Speaker 3:  like, I'm supporting my friends.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And it's, I mean, this is a thing we've talked about a lot on this
Speaker 5:  show, right? There is like a, there's an internet for humans and there's
Speaker 5:  an internet for robots and Google is the robots. Yeah. Like
Speaker 5:  it's, it's AI is becoming the robots, but Google has been the robots
Speaker 5:  for a really long time and it has demanded a lot of people's time and energy
Speaker 5:  because at the end of it, it's the discovery engine for the internet.
Speaker 5:  And Google, like really would love you to believe what they always say,
Speaker 5:  which is just do good stuff and we'll help people find it. And I think
Speaker 5:  anyone who has ever tried to do good stuff on the internet can tell you it's
Speaker 5:  not, it's just not nearly that simple. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Anyway, so that's the dispute. You can all evaluate the
Speaker 3:  disclosure. We have a website. There are people at our
Speaker 3:  company that professionally do SEO. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And if you Google things, you might find our website. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Our, our website is designed to be surfaced in Google search. I I think about,
Speaker 3:  oh, there's one part. Can I, can I tell this story? Sorry. Yeah. Sorry,
Speaker 4:  I didn't mean to No, no, no. I was just gonna say, I love SEO. I, I want
Speaker 4:  people to read my stuff.
Speaker 3:  All, right? Maybe not that far. Maybe, maybe Alex is like running chat. Bt
Speaker 3:  in the corner to replace us all.
Speaker 3:  There's one, Danny calls out when we were redesigning the site. He
Speaker 3:  says, Neil, I emailed me and wanted to know about some SEO question, which
Speaker 3:  is true. I emailed him and said, we're gonna have these quick posts. We're
Speaker 3:  redoing this thing. Our internal SEO team we're having a debate about whether
Speaker 3:  to index the quick posts. This is a true thing. I say, Danny is the search
Speaker 3:  liaison. I know him. I emailed him and said, Hey, I've got this question.
Speaker 3:  And he was, he was like this, read the guidelines that's what Danny said,
Speaker 3:  which is the thing that he is supposed to do. Yeah. Professionally, what
Speaker 3:  he says to everybody is read the guidelines, no special treatment for anyone.
Speaker 3:  And I was like, I don't think the guidelines are helping me here because
Speaker 3:  they are designed to tell people who spam affiliate links not.
Speaker 3:  They'll get down ranked and our quick posts aren't that, but they're also
Speaker 3:  very short and like the folk wisdom of SEO is that short things are bad.
Speaker 3:  You know, like there's all this stuff and we just Don the answer. And his
Speaker 3:  answer was like, do what's best. Great. Like that I, that's a totally,
Speaker 3:  I presume a totally reasonable interaction.
Speaker 3:  And then we didn't index the quick post because we didn't want to tank the
Speaker 3:  traffic to our other pages by having something that might be whatever. Okay.
Speaker 3:  That's like a normal sort of like business conversation that you might have.
Speaker 3:  We didn't have any terms, it was just advice. Right? Like I'm
Speaker 3:  operating to the search liaison. It's not a commercial conversation. It's
Speaker 3:  not the wrong side of the house. And I know Danny, so
Speaker 3:  he calls us up as if to say like us caring
Speaker 3:  about SEO somehow negates us from criticizing the
Speaker 3:  practice of SEO.
Speaker 4:  In fact it makes us more like qualified
Speaker 4:  to critique it. I feel much more qualified than Yeah. We like
Speaker 3:  Do the thing.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Like I do it all the time. I'm feeling very
Speaker 3:  Qualified also and and we have a lot of commenters who are like, but you
Speaker 3:  have yeah. Posts that I want, we want you to reads,
Speaker 4:  Read our website.
Speaker 3:  Do you want you to read our website but also just like, just turn the knob
Speaker 3:  all the way. I will concede that we are the worst SEO scammers on the internet.
Speaker 3:  The worst we're gonna find you and we're gonna sell you some car insurance
Speaker 3:  tomorrow. You looking for a wireless plan?
Speaker 3:  Get that solo student. That would be great if we sold wireless plants. We're
Speaker 3:  like don't buy any of them.
Speaker 3:  None of these will let you do surgery on a grape.
Speaker 3:  It, I'll concede it to you all the way. That doesn't change the idea that
Speaker 3:  people who practice SEO have a culture anyway. You can tell that I care about
Speaker 3:  this a lot. Yeah. David, I wanna come back to a thing that you said real
Speaker 3:  quick and then we can wrap this up. Like Google doesn't care. If you think
Speaker 3:  about search for the business, you were in the courtroom this week
Speaker 3:  where literally the CEO of Google was talking about Google search
Speaker 3:  as a business, And what it means and how It works in this big deal with Apple.
Speaker 3:  What's going on there?
Speaker 5:  It was really interesting 'cause the deal with Apple has been
Speaker 5:  the story of this trial so far. Like fundamentally, if you really wanna boil
Speaker 5:  this entire antitrust trial down to one question, it's
Speaker 5:  is it anti-competitive for Google to give Apple what
Speaker 5:  we now know to be $18 billion a year in order
Speaker 5:  to be the default search engine in Safari? Like that's it. That's the whole
Speaker 5:  question. Because even if that one deal goes away,
Speaker 5:  everyone else testifying is saying that blows the search market
Speaker 5:  wide open. But so sooner Petre gave this like long
Speaker 5:  mostly uns spicy testimony. Like Satya Nadella was very spicy,
Speaker 5:  Sundar less spicy. But essentially what he argued over
Speaker 5:  and over is that like Google is a business, it's a
Speaker 5:  competitive business. There are a lot of things out there. Part of Google's
Speaker 5:  line is that like everyone is coming for search all the time. Provo Raghavan
Speaker 5:  who runs search for Google, talked a lot about TikTok and vertical search
Speaker 5:  engines and this idea that like people look for information in lots of places
Speaker 5:  and that's fundamentally what Google does. It's very competitive on and on.
Speaker 5:  And sooner Pro I just kept saying, look, we give all these companies
Speaker 5:  all this money because it's it, it makes us more money.
Speaker 5:  And like it's just that simple. Like Google wouldn't give Apple
Speaker 5:  $18 billion a year if Google didn't make more than
Speaker 5:  $18 billion a year as a result. Right? Like John sch fit line, the
Speaker 5:  the lawyer for Google asked him about like, you have a fiduciary duty to
Speaker 5:  shareholders to make money, right? And sooner I was like, yes. Like I,
Speaker 5:  we do these deals because they are good value and Google is a business and
Speaker 5:  when people use our search engine, we make money from it. Like that fact
Speaker 5:  is not unclear to anyone. Right. I think if you wanna talk
Speaker 5:  about the ways in which Google's search has gotten worse over time, which
Speaker 5:  many people perceive that it has. If you wanna talk about whether there are
Speaker 5:  too many ads or Google hides the fact that their ads or AI is gonna
Speaker 5:  ruin the quality of your search results. Like that's all really interesting
Speaker 5:  questions. But Google's coming out here and basically saying like, we
Speaker 5:  are a business, we make an awful lot of money.
Speaker 5:  What do you want from us? Like the, the idea that Google
Speaker 5:  started out as this company at in the relatively early days of the web and
Speaker 5:  said, we are going to bet on the web, we are going to bet that we can be
Speaker 5:  essentially infrastructure for the entire web and that if we
Speaker 5:  help more people do more stuff on the web that will accrue value back
Speaker 5:  to Google. That has been one of the great bets of business Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Of all time. Like, holy God was that a good idea from Google 25 years
Speaker 5:  ago? And the question in front of Google and it was kind of
Speaker 5:  put to sooner or a bunch of different ways is like, has that turned like,
Speaker 5:  are you no longer good for the web because you're so big, because you're
Speaker 5:  so powerful because you're so sort of singular
Speaker 5:  in your power as that infrastructural layer. And that's obviously a more
Speaker 5:  charger question to answer. And obviously Sundar is not going to say, yes,
Speaker 5:  we're too big, it's a huge problem. But that
Speaker 5:  thing that they bet on the web and the web got to take over the world. And
Speaker 5:  so did Google is like the central tension of all of this
Speaker 5:  because it's like at what point does that go from, I think
Speaker 5:  we all rooted for Google for a really long time because it was true that
Speaker 5:  I think we
Speaker 3:  Have, I think a lot of our listeners are still rooting for Google for
Speaker 5:  Sure. Like it's, it was, it was a company that believed in
Speaker 5:  the internet. Yeah. At a time that I think it was good to have a company
Speaker 5:  that believed in
Speaker 3:  Internet in many ways when we interact with people from various companies,
Speaker 3:  the people from Google are easily the most sincere.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And they want the web to be a good place full of good things
Speaker 5:  that people can access and use. Like I think that rules, when does that
Speaker 5:  turn on you? And you become, you have to tamp
Speaker 5:  down the web to keep it the way that you want it. That's the question. And
Speaker 5:  like has Google tipped over that line? Was what Sundar was kind of being
Speaker 5:  asked indirectly over and over and it was just, it was fascinating to see
Speaker 5:  it distilled down. I would
Speaker 3:  Point, we were gonna link to this too, David wrote a story about Google Amp
Speaker 3:  is part of our Google package when Google clearly went over the line. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  And had to roll it all back. But that's
Speaker 5:  Such a fun example, right? Because Google is like, okay, if we don't do this,
Speaker 5:  Facebook will, right? Like it's a they, that's a response to a real threat
Speaker 5:  from a company that was like actively trying to destroy the open web. Like
Speaker 5:  that's just like naked aggression against you and web. And so Google
Speaker 5:  did what it decided to do I think
Speaker 5:  was way too far over the line. But to respond to that in some way and
Speaker 5:  say we have to preserve the open web not wrong and not
Speaker 5:  out of bounds with what Google had always said that it was, but it's just,
Speaker 5:  it's that same thing. It's like where do you go from what's good for the
Speaker 5:  web is good for Google and everybody wins to we have to keep
Speaker 5:  the web just like this so that Google can keep winning. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  And I think that the interesting thing about the sort of like dominant algorithm
Speaker 3:  theory is it's weird that the web is shaped
Speaker 3:  for search. That there's no other discovery engine. That there's no other
Speaker 3:  competing incentive. You can't just make a weird website and sort of like
Speaker 3:  assume Google will find it. Right.
Speaker 5:  And it's really telling that Google now is even struggling to do that. It's
Speaker 5:  trying to find all these new ways to show you stuff. It's trying to do the
Speaker 5:  more multimedia search and it's just like, I don't know. Have you found yourself
Speaker 5:  on one of those pages where you do a Google search and instead of getting
Speaker 5:  a bunch of links to stuff they just show you like vertical videos? Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. In a row. It feels bad. I don't like it. Yeah. I,
Speaker 4:  I click out every time. Especially if it's like I'm trying to figure out
Speaker 4:  how to grill something
Speaker 3:  You know. I know I so bad. It's because you don't know that you can ever
Speaker 3:  get back there. Yeah, that's, yeah. There's something really permanent about
Speaker 3:  doing a Google search and finding a page and be like All, right? I looked
Speaker 3:  through some of these, I'll come back to it or whatever. For
Speaker 4:  Me it was just, oh God, I'm gonna have to watch a video. I just wanna like
Speaker 4:  go and scan a,
Speaker 3:  I'm told the video is the highest
Speaker 5:  Band. Yeah. That's just 'cause you're old.
Speaker 4:  Sorry. Sorry, I'm just old. Old.
Speaker 5:  That nonsense.
Speaker 3:  Okay, we gotta take a break. I'll just say this at the very end we were getting
Speaker 3:  documents outta this trial. Apple had an internal presentation that said
Speaker 3:  Android is a massive tracking device and they signed a big deal with Google.
Speaker 3:  Fantastic. It's very good. All right? We'll grab back.
Speaker 7:  This podcast is brought to you by Meta Quest three, the new mixed reality
Speaker 7:  headset from Meta. Now you can expand your world in ways you never thought
Speaker 7:  possible with the new Meta Quest three, put on the sleek most powerful
Speaker 7:  question yet and jump into fully immersive games or blend virtual
Speaker 7:  elements into your physical surroundings with mixed reality. Instantly
Speaker 7:  Go from watching to playing the part in your favorite show with Stranger
Speaker 7:  Things vr Live the action and really feel what it's like to step into the
Speaker 7:  shoes of an assassin, an Assassin's Creed Nexus. Even turn your
Speaker 7:  couch into courtside seats with X stadium and watch your favorite
Speaker 7:  NBA team. With over 500 titles, it's easy to dive into
Speaker 7:  whatever you're into. Expand your world with Meta Quest three. See
Speaker 7:  child safety guidance online accounts for 10 and up certain apps, games and
Speaker 7:  experiences may be suitable for a more mature audience. Learn more@meta.com.
Speaker 1:  Support for this episode comes from Sonos. Me and the rest of The Vergecast
Speaker 1:  team are all audio professionals. And at The Verge we have an office full
Speaker 1:  of Sonos products. Personally I use the Sonos era 300 in particular
Speaker 1:  a lot. It's an all-in-one plugin smart speaker design for immersive sound
Speaker 1:  and spatial audio. Listening out loud, it's breakthrough acoustic design
Speaker 1:  projects sound from wall to wall and floor to ceiling, allowing listeners
Speaker 1:  to feel like the music and sound is all around them. No matter where you
Speaker 1:  are in the room or what you play, the listening experience is nothing short
Speaker 1:  of extraordinary. For a full immersive home theater experience, you could
Speaker 1:  take two era three hundreds and use them as your Dolby Atmos surround
Speaker 1:  speakers when paired with an arc or beam and my favorite feature, it
Speaker 1:  actually has a three and a half millimeter Jack So I can plug in literally
Speaker 1:  anything to this device. You can also connect the ERA 300 to a turntable
Speaker 1:  CD player or other audio device using the USBC port. Also know
Speaker 1:  speakers connect wirelessly over wifi so you can group speakers in different
Speaker 1:  rooms and experience the joy of multi-room listening. Visit
Speaker 1:  sonos.com to learn more about ERA 300 and find thoughtful gifts for every
Speaker 1:  listener on your list.
Speaker 3:  All right? We're back. We went very long talking
Speaker 3:  about Google search. Yeah, yeah. So we're doing, we're doing the back
Speaker 3:  half of the show is two lightning rounds. This one is the streaming lightning
Speaker 3:  round. Pew pew.
Speaker 4:  That was was my streaming.
Speaker 3:  Alex Alex Cranz. Take it away.
Speaker 4:  A lot happened this week. I'm gonna kick it off with Casey Boyz, who is
Speaker 4:  currently running HBO and during the early days of the,
Speaker 4:  the pandemic was a little too into his phone and was directing
Speaker 4:  people to direct interns to harass
Speaker 4:  or not to harass, but to Troll Critics online of
Speaker 4:  HBO shows
Speaker 3:  This like Warner Media classic move. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Hysterical. He has since apologized. Oh my. Because this, this all
Speaker 4:  came out because one of those interns is suing the company for wrongful
Speaker 4:  termination. So it all came out from that. It was in this big Rolling stone
Speaker 4:  piece all about the company. A lot of really good reporting in that piece.
Speaker 4:  She go track it down. But since then Kissy Boys has addressed it and he was
Speaker 4:  basically like, I was too into my phone and now I just
Speaker 4:  DM when I'm angry at Critics instead.
Speaker 3:  Oh my.
Speaker 5:  Is that, that's really, that's the, the You know huge
Speaker 5:  feat of self-realization that he's gone through
Speaker 3:  This. He just direct messages
Speaker 5:  You myself.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. So, so he's so he's DMing his criticism more. And
Speaker 4:  honestly I would rather, I would rather have Tim Cook come into my
Speaker 4:  dms, be like, that was a real rude thing you said about that phone. The
Speaker 3:  Flash was good. Yeah. I
Speaker 4:  Would, I I think I'd rather like prefer that
Speaker 3:  What he, what are you, what are you trying to say? Casey Blois.
Speaker 5:  Okay, I have two. I have two things to say to Casey. Blois Casey,
Speaker 5:  I know you're listening. So pull over your car, take notes. Yeah. Thing number
Speaker 5:  one is use your own burners man, come on.
Speaker 3:  Like
Speaker 5:  I'm all for having burners and NBA athletes do it.
Speaker 5:  Everybody has a burner that they use just for looking at accounts that
Speaker 5:  just in case they like one by accident. Everybody, everybody has burners,
Speaker 5:  but you gotta have your own burners. And if you're not gonna have your own
Speaker 5:  burners, at least like do it for real and get like a bot farm
Speaker 5:  You. know what I mean? Like he, he did this like half measure that. It's
Speaker 5:  like if you're gonna go for it, go for it. Otherwise just
Speaker 5:  pretend you're like a random stranger and defend yourself and you'll inevitably
Speaker 5:  get caught. And it'll be very funny. This is the weirdest, worst way
Speaker 5:  to do it. To like yell at your desistence to defend you on the internet.
Speaker 5:  Like don't do
Speaker 3:  That. Yeah. It's not great. No,
Speaker 4:  He says, he says it's much better now because he has, many of them are
Speaker 4:  gracious enough to engage with him back and forth. So it's much
Speaker 4:  better now instead of having the intern say you souk.
Speaker 4:  'cause that was, that was the gist of the ones they confirmed were coming
Speaker 4:  from, from this person.
Speaker 3:  I mean, okay, I'm gonna disagree with you. It's not even good. I want an
Speaker 3:  army of interns with burner accounts to tweet at our Critics.
Speaker 3:  And if you're interested in this job, you can just email us at Vergecast
Speaker 3:  at The Verge dot com and we'll see. We'll see what happens next. We'll
Speaker 4:  Pay you in merch.
Speaker 3:  Also, those Critics are not being very gracious 'cause they didn't know that
Speaker 3:  the army of anonymous interns was tweeting. You suck at them.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, because it was like, it wasn't like, it wasn't like Casey was like,
Speaker 3:  Hey, so all those weird anon accounts that have been tweeting
Speaker 3:  you suck at you. That was me. I prefer to start DMing now. And they're like,
Speaker 3:  oh yes, of course Casey come in like
Speaker 3:  no, he just started DMing them
Speaker 3:  All. right. Here's my, it's staying on HBO Max, here's my lightning round
Speaker 3:  one.
Speaker 3:  In the grand scheme of everything getting more expensive, if you're on
Speaker 3:  HBO Max and you had ad free, now they're gonna charge you more money for
Speaker 3:  four K. God dammit. If you get a legacy ad free account,
Speaker 4:  How much am I paying now? I miss this and I'm
Speaker 4:  very upset.
Speaker 3:  You have to go to 20 bucks a
Speaker 5:  Month. So if you're on the standard, if you're on the standard
Speaker 5:  ad free one that you used to get four K on, which I think is 16 bucks a month,
Speaker 5:  you're gonna lose four K. You have to upgrade the ultimate at 20 bucks a
Speaker 5:  month and then you get four K back.
Speaker 4:  I'm not gonna have any money for my children. I don't have any, did
Speaker 5:  We get,
Speaker 3:  Mine is named Max. I get nothing for this. I should get a
Speaker 3:  substantial discount. You should.
Speaker 5:  Where did we land on our, would you cancel your streaming services
Speaker 5:  before you gave up four K? A lot of
Speaker 4:  People agreed with me. That's, that's what I'm gonna say. Okay. Is a lot
Speaker 4:  of people agree that yeah, they would rather cancel than give up four K.
Speaker 4:  Yeah,
Speaker 5:  That was the most of the feedback I heard too. I think
Speaker 4:  Honestly the audacity of Max who was late to four
Speaker 4:  K and half-assed four K and is still half-assing four K
Speaker 4:  to expect me to pay more. I'm gonna do it, but I'm gonna be so
Speaker 4:  furious the whole time.
Speaker 3:  This is the problem with millennials. Alex. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  This is the same energy I
Speaker 3:  Bring you and your avocado coast. Your $20 a month of garbage. Four K no
Speaker 4:  Children. What am I doing with my life?
Speaker 5:  Do You know what I've realized recently? Yeah. So I've been sort of systematically
Speaker 5:  going and downgrading everything to the ad plans because I just want the
Speaker 5:  ads like I'm good. Give me, give me the ads. Four K
Speaker 4:  Ads. Yeah. You want that Myrtle Beach timeshare.
Speaker 5:  The strangest thing I have discovered is that I kind of love it because
Speaker 5:  it's a phone break. I now like four times an hour I get a phone break.
Speaker 5:  So. I. Don't look at my phone during shows anymore because I know that in
Speaker 5:  seven minutes I'm going to get three minutes to look at Reddit
Speaker 5:  or check my texts or whatever. And then we're gonna, it's perfect. It's just
Speaker 5:  like a tiny little intermission where whatever's happening on the TV happens
Speaker 5:  on the tv. But I get to look at TikTok.
Speaker 3:  Your house sounds horrible. You're watching like four 80 p survivor
Speaker 3:  on a garbage fast service. Oh yeah. Looking at your phone and for three minute
Speaker 3:  chunks,
Speaker 5:  Anna's sitting next to me doing spelling Bee and I'm sitting here.
Speaker 5:  I do connections during one, I look at Reddit during another one. I check
Speaker 5:  my email and Slack during another one and then it's the end of the hour and
Speaker 5:  I've watched the whole show. It's perfect.
Speaker 3:  I don't want this All. right. What's your lightning A one beyond your bad
Speaker 3:  idea about watching ads.
Speaker 5:  Ads. What if there was an ad break but just no ads. It's just silence on
Speaker 5:  the TV for two.
Speaker 3:  Everybody gets a phone break. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Exactly. Sponsored
Speaker 4:  By Intel.
Speaker 5:  Mine is Disney appears to be actually for
Speaker 5:  real about to own all of Hulu, which we've kind of known is coming for a
Speaker 5:  while. But it seems like approximately one minute after
Speaker 5:  Comcast was allowed to exercise the clause that would force
Speaker 5:  Disney to buy the rest of Hulu. It did. So now comes
Speaker 5:  the part where Disney and Comcast have to figure out what Hulu
Speaker 5:  is worth, which I think is gonna be really fascinating. They set it up in
Speaker 5:  such a way basically, and Alex, correct me if I'm wrong, but I think I understand
Speaker 5:  this right, which is that a bunch of years ago when they made this deal that
Speaker 5:  would allow Disney need to eventually buy all of Hulu, they valued Hulu about
Speaker 5:  $27 billion, which meant that the roughly third
Speaker 5:  of the service that Comcast owned was worth like eight and change billion
Speaker 5:  dollars. Now that's the minimum price Disney is gonna have to pay.
Speaker 5:  If the price has gone down since then. Sucks for Disney, they still have
Speaker 5:  to pay that money. I don't think it has, if that price has gone up, Disney's
Speaker 5:  gonna have to pay the eight and change plus
Speaker 5:  whatever percentage difference there is based on the new valuation of Hulu.
Speaker 5:  So the question now is what is Hulu worth in the market?
Speaker 5:  And we're about to find out. It's a deeply weird time in the Streaming world.
Speaker 5:  Streaming is both like ascendant and a mess. I have no idea.
Speaker 5:  But I think figuring out how much money this is, especially for Disney, which
Speaker 5:  is not in a super good position to be writing checks for eight plus
Speaker 5:  billion dollars at this moment in time. It's about to get really weird.
Speaker 4:  I think it's gonna force Disney to actually think about
Speaker 4:  what it's doing, And what its strategy
Speaker 3:  Is.
Speaker 4:  I don't think Disney's been doing that lately.
Speaker 3:  It is a weird time to announce this deal when the cover of Variety is,
Speaker 3:  is Marvel screwed? Yeah. Which is a piece worth reading.
Speaker 3:  Yeah,
Speaker 4:  It's a great piece. I, I wrote kind of an addendum to it. It's on the
Speaker 4:  site right now. They, they don't know how Marvel like,
Speaker 4:  like Marvel's just in a bad spot. And, and the piece was very kind of weird
Speaker 4:  because it refused to blame Kevin gy who, who runs Marvel
Speaker 4:  Studios for anything. But then everything seemed to quietly like, they'd
Speaker 4:  be like, yeah, there's someone at the top and we don't know what to do. And
Speaker 4:  it's like Weird story. But yeah, I I think Disney has to figure out
Speaker 4:  it's got these, it's got multiple services. For a long time it was like,
Speaker 4:  this is for adults and Disney Plus is for babies and maybe it's gonna
Speaker 4:  merge the two together. It's also got the Hulu live subscription and
Speaker 4:  there's a, a reasonable amount of subscribers there, but not as many as you
Speaker 4:  think Hulu is still way below Disney Plus and subscriptions. So
Speaker 4:  it's gonna be like they, they already own all of, they
Speaker 4:  own everything on it. 'cause it's all Fox in, in ABC shows. So they own everything.
Speaker 4:  It's just like, what do you,
Speaker 4:  I don't know. I I think that all the people who have to to figure this, the
Speaker 4:  price out are gonna fight like the Comcast and the Disney folks. I wanna
Speaker 4:  be in that room watching those two groups fight each other. 'cause that's
Speaker 4:  gonna be really cool. But
Speaker 3:  One assumes that Disney is planning to sell ESPN and Comcast
Speaker 3:  knows this and they would like some of that money to come back to Comcast.
Speaker 4:  That's
Speaker 3:  Fair disclosure. N BBC Universal division of Comcast
Speaker 3:  is a minority investor at Vox Media, our parent company. We produced a
Speaker 3:  Netflix show, which you should go watch. It's called The Future of, I was
Speaker 3:  the executive producer of that show. It's really quite good. But I'm hopelessly
Speaker 3:  biased in favor of that show, which
Speaker 5:  You should watch on Netflix.
Speaker 3:  Which you should watch. You should.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. That's it.
Speaker 5:  I think that's all for now. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  We all have televisions. I think those are the ones that are implicated in
Speaker 3:  this conversation. I do. Again, our site is discoverable
Speaker 3:  in search.
Speaker 3:  We have a TikTok account.
Speaker 3:  We
Speaker 4:  Use YouTube
Speaker 3:  Two more. We YouTube we won an Emmy this week. Hell yeah. We is
Speaker 3:  to won an Emmy. Yeah. For her YouTube series. Full frame. Big
Speaker 3:  bias in favor of winning Emmy's. Just know you can't trust anything we say
Speaker 3:  if it's not gonna win. It's an Emmy.
Speaker 5:  One more thing before we move on from the Streaming stuff. There was a big
Speaker 5:  debate in our comments on the Hulu Disney thing about whether, if you're
Speaker 5:  gonna com, if you're Disney and you're gonna combine all your streaming services,
Speaker 5:  should you call it Disney Plus? Or should you call it Hulu? I think this
Speaker 5:  is the most obvious question ever, but I'm curious what you two think.
Speaker 4:  Ooh, I think if if Disney knew what they were doing, they would call it Hulu.
Speaker 4:  No. Yes, a hundred percent. Because Disney itself has
Speaker 4:  a very specific brand identity and that's what
Speaker 5:  They're terrified. You mean the best brand identity potentially of any brand
Speaker 5:  anywhere on planet Earth.
Speaker 4:  But also
Speaker 5:  Disney is the good brand. That's literally what it is. Yeah. It's the good
Speaker 5:  brand. It's goodness and happiness and joy. I literally
Speaker 3:  Heard one of Becky's ants say out loud,
Speaker 3:  what is the difference between Hulu and Roku? And
Speaker 3:  I looked at her and I was like, You know what? That is a
Speaker 3:  surprisingly deep and meaningful and good question.
Speaker 4:  That's it's a good question. It's
Speaker 5:  It's
Speaker 3:  Right. I think
Speaker 4:  That's a good question.
Speaker 3:  Like it's just TV stuff. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  But the problem with Disney is that Disney is not just Disney. It's,
Speaker 4:  it's A, B, C. Well for now it's A, B, C. It's these, these
Speaker 3:  Are all solvable problems.
Speaker 4:  It's all of these things. And they're running into the exact same problem
Speaker 4:  as HBO or as Warner Brothers. And Warner Brothers obviously went with the
Speaker 4:  incredible Max
Speaker 4:  and here's the real opportunity for them to be like, we're not gonna do that.
Speaker 4:  Disney Plus was always kind of a stupid name because it was, and instead
Speaker 4:  we're just, we're just gonna click
Speaker 3:  To Hulu. Here's what they're gonna do. They're called the Everything app.
Speaker 3:  It's gonna be called X. It's gonna do payments. You can date Mini Mouse.
Speaker 3:  It's gonna be amazing. Elon will be, it's all gonna be great. All right?
Speaker 3:  We gotta take a break. We'll be right back with with Lightning Round part
Speaker 3:  two. We'll be right back.
Speaker 1:  Support for this show comes from Wix web agencies. You're gonna like
Speaker 1:  this one. Let me tell you about Wix Studio. The platform that gives agencies
Speaker 1:  total creative freedom to deliver complex client sites while still
Speaker 1:  smashing deadlines. How? First, let's talk about the advanced design
Speaker 1:  capabilities. With Wix Studio, you can build unique layouts with a
Speaker 1:  revolutionary grid experience and watch as elements scale proportionally
Speaker 1:  by default. No code animations at sparks of delight while custom
Speaker 1:  CSS gives total design control, but it doesn't stop there. Bring ambitious
Speaker 1:  client projects to life in any industry with a fully integrated suite of
Speaker 1:  business solutions, from e-comm to events bookings and more. And extend the
Speaker 1:  capabilities even further with hundreds of APIs and integrations. And You
Speaker 1:  know what else? The workflows, they just make sense. There's
Speaker 1:  the built-in AI tools, the centralized workspace, the on canvas
Speaker 1:  collaborating, the reuse of assets across sites, the seamless client handover.
Speaker 1:  And that's not all. Find out more at Wix dot com slash studio.
Speaker 8:  Support for this show comes from American Express business.
Speaker 8:  Resourceful small business owners know how to get value from the purchases
Speaker 8:  they already make for their businesses each month. That's why the enhanced
Speaker 8:  American Express Business Gold Card lets you earn up to
Speaker 8:  $395 in annual statement credits on
Speaker 8:  eligible business purchases at select shipping, food delivery, and retail
Speaker 8:  subscription merchants. The Amex Business Gold Card now smarter
Speaker 8:  and more flexible. That's the powerful backing of American Express
Speaker 8:  enrollment. For required terms, apply, learn
Speaker 8:  more@americanexpress.com slash business Gold Card.
Speaker 3:  Okay, we're back. Can I start with my favorite thing of the entire week?
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Yes,
Speaker 3:  Please. Absolute favorite thing of the entire week. It's not even a thing
Speaker 3:  we covered. Oh, it's a, it's a thing that TFL truck
Speaker 3:  covered on TikTok by the way. T Ffl Truck, one of my all time
Speaker 3:  favorite. They're just, it's just a website about trucks that they rule.
Speaker 3:  It's great.
Speaker 3:  There're some car show. The guy's like, I'm here with a Ford
Speaker 3:  F one 50 Lightning at the Borla booth and he goes to the Borla guy and he
Speaker 3:  is like, so you've built an exhaust system for the F one 50 Lightning.
Speaker 3:  And the guy looks at me and goes, it's really more of an aftermarket sound
Speaker 3:  solution.
Speaker 3:  And then he goes, it can play futuristic sounds too. It this, this is
Speaker 3:  a thing that happens in this video. I lost my mind. I've watched him
Speaker 3:  say it's really more of an aftermarket sound solution a thousand
Speaker 3:  times. Did he play it? The confidence?
Speaker 3:  It's really more of an aftermarket sound solution. What he means by
Speaker 3:  this is that there are speakers mounted under the
Speaker 3:  bumper of the truck. What? And then when he pushes the accelerator
Speaker 3:  down, it makes engine sounds remove and it's all very complicated,
Speaker 3:  right? He's like, look, we're plugged into the systems. The truck we're we're,
Speaker 3:  we're measuring the distance accelerator pedals pushed to the floor, the
Speaker 3:  load on the engine. We've got simulated gear shift sounds on
Speaker 3:  an electric truck. And then he's like, and there's,
Speaker 3:  there's buttons and knobs. So there's one knob switches between
Speaker 3:  four presets. The other one is the volume. You can change the presets on
Speaker 3:  your phone to futuristic sounds. It's really more of an aftermarket sound
Speaker 3:  solution. And then he is like, here's what you can set it to right now.
Speaker 3:  Mind you, this is a Ford truck. He's like a Chevy Silverado. What
Speaker 3:  a Dodge Charger.
Speaker 3:  And I'm like, there was a meeting that
Speaker 3:  the exhaust company, Borla is a famous exhaust company and they had a meeting
Speaker 3:  and they're like, this EV thing is killing us. No one's gonna buy
Speaker 3:  exhaust pipes from us anymore. Headers out the window. Yeah. We're not doing
Speaker 3:  this. What's our plan? And someone's like aftermarket
Speaker 3:  sound solutions. We're gonna put speakers on the trucks and we're gonna make
Speaker 3:  Ford trucks. Sounds like they have Chevy v eights in them.
Speaker 5:  How are they gonna roll
Speaker 3:  Calls? There was a meeting Alex.
Speaker 3:  I love it. Just go watch this video. It's not even our video. I just quick
Speaker 3:  posted a TikTok from another publication 'cause I can't get enough of this
Speaker 3:  guy saying it's really more of an aftermarket sound solution. There
Speaker 5:  Was a period of time like two months ago, I would say, where
Speaker 5:  Neli, you missed a couple of shows in a row. You were super busy.
Speaker 5:  You didn't do the iPhone review this year. You were doing code, you were
Speaker 5:  moving, A lot was going on. And we got a bunch of emails being like, is is
Speaker 5:  Neli leaving? Is he going off to like some big job? And I want everyone to
Speaker 5:  know that when Neli does leave, it will be to do the thing he just described
Speaker 5:  just now. Neli will leave us to go do aftermarket
Speaker 5:  sound solution truck TikTok. And that will be the end. That's the only thing.
Speaker 5:  If ever Neli disappears, look for him on truck TikTok. And that's,
Speaker 5:  that's what it will be.
Speaker 3:  I just got Go watch the video. Well it's just the confidence. It's really
Speaker 3:  more of an aftermarket sound solution. You're
Speaker 4:  Very like, I feel confident listening to you say it.
Speaker 3:  I just like, if you're buying
Speaker 4:  The way it
Speaker 3:  Just, the number of companies that are solving the sort of like
Speaker 3:  political culture, war of EVs by being like, here's what we're gonna do
Speaker 4:  Making
Speaker 3:  Loud. We're gonna have speakers on the car and we're gonna make 'em sound
Speaker 3:  like they burn gas and that'll fix it. Dodge is doing
Speaker 3:  this. They
Speaker 4:  Are,
Speaker 3:  They call it the fret sonic exhaust system. And they won't admit that they're
Speaker 3:  putting speakers under the car. At least Borla is like, yeah, it's a, what
Speaker 4:  Does it sound when it's like crossing water,
Speaker 3:  Like the speakers are drowning it.
Speaker 5:  That was very good actually.
Speaker 3:  It was really good. That's really
Speaker 5:  Good.
Speaker 5:  Did
Speaker 3:  You say, well you want us to drive your battery powered truck into some water
Speaker 3:  and make it bubble. Everyone very confident that that's a good situation.
Speaker 5:  Nila, did you say it's called Fret Sonic or Frat Sonic. Frat Sonic with
Speaker 5:  z Frat Sonic. That's that's fantastic. Frats.
Speaker 4:  That's
Speaker 3:  Whatever man. All. right? What's yours?
Speaker 4:  Okay. Mine is Chris person who friend of The. Verge has a great story
Speaker 4:  up on the site where he hacked a robot vacuum to make it
Speaker 4:  more like secure because robot vacuums You know they're
Speaker 4:  going around your house, you're hopefully wearing pants when they're going
Speaker 4:  around your house. Yeah. Always wear pants and, and they're
Speaker 4:  mapping your house. They're mapping everything. And then they're uploading
Speaker 4:  all of that to the cloud. And while it is typically pretty secure, it is
Speaker 4:  also a privacy potential. Privacy nightmare. Yeah. And, and so he
Speaker 4:  had to go use this, this project called Val Vale Tudo.
Speaker 3:  That's a great name. Bill
Speaker 4:  Tudo
Speaker 3:  Vale. Tudo
Speaker 4:  Vale Tudo. And, and so he, he used this project to hack
Speaker 4:  a robot vacuum and, and, and make it, disconnect
Speaker 4:  it from the cloud and still make it work and do all this stuff. and it worked.
Speaker 4:  But he You know he's hacking. This is not He's in just Yeah, he's he's in
Speaker 4:  the system. He's physically removing boards and adding new boards.
Speaker 4:  And he was working on this for a while and he was working with I believe
Speaker 4:  Danford and Dan would just be like, oh yeah, I'm just getting all these pictures
Speaker 4:  of robot vacuum guts. And you're like, how is going on over there?
Speaker 3:  Has he thought about adding an aftermarket sound solution to his robot vacuum?
Speaker 3:  Just full Silverado Vette powering through the living room.
Speaker 4:  It's gonna sound great, but, but the story is really cool and, and I
Speaker 4:  love the idea of it, especially as the other day, like I kept having
Speaker 4:  to stand in front of my robot vacuum cleaner and it would like bump into
Speaker 4:  me. And I was like, oh my God, none of these photos can ever like
Speaker 4:  be leaked. 'cause it's just the worst look for you.
Speaker 4:  They're just horrible. 'cause it's like, it's from your feet up. Yeah. So
Speaker 4:  it's like, it's, it's, it's basically even worse than that one where you
Speaker 4:  pull your phone out and you go to check something and the camera's facing
Speaker 4:  you and you're not expecting it. And you've got four chins. There's like
Speaker 4:  12 chins on your ass on your face. There's a lot
Speaker 4:  of chins happening. And, and nobody needs to see that. So I might, I feel
Speaker 4:  like I kinda wanna hack mine now.
Speaker 5:  My robot has become a super villain in my house. The noise
Speaker 5:  that the little like boop boop thing that it does right before it starts
Speaker 5:  scares the hell out of my dog for some reason. She like, literally
Speaker 5:  as soon as any the vacuum is, you don't have to move. As soon as she hears
Speaker 5:  that noise, which it for some reason will occasionally just make randomly
Speaker 5:  out of nowhere, she just goes flying upstairs and hides in the
Speaker 5:  bed under the covers and will not come back for hours. Aw. And our 11 month
Speaker 5:  old, he's now crawling like a maniac and he sees this little
Speaker 5:  glowing light and he presses the button 'cause that's fun. And then it
Speaker 5:  moves and it hits him. And he doesn't like that. No. And then it's like,
Speaker 5:  oh, well I have to get around this. So he, it just keeps moving a little
Speaker 5:  bit like an inch at a time and just bashing into his legs over and over.
Speaker 5:  So. I have to, I have to figure out a place to put the
Speaker 5:  robot vacuum that is somehow accessible to no one but can still vacuum my
Speaker 5:  floors. So if anybody has any like sneaky
Speaker 5:  hiding places for
Speaker 4:  Your vacuum vacuum places, I think you get a drone apparatus for your child.
Speaker 5:  Oh yeah. I'll get the ring flying camera. That'll go super good. Yeah. My
Speaker 5:  dog will love that. You get
Speaker 3:  Tougher.
Speaker 5:  That'll go really
Speaker 3:  Well. Every time I've ever bought an expensive vacuum, it's been shittier
Speaker 3:  than the like $30 vacuum we bought when we were like very young. We
Speaker 3:  were,
Speaker 5:  We were in a hotel in Tennessee a couple of weeks ago and
Speaker 5:  the the one vacuum that they had in there was this like,
Speaker 5:  piece of crap dust devil that weighed nothing. And all
Speaker 5:  anyone talked about all weekend was how nice it was because it was so light
Speaker 5:  and small. Yeah. It was like this piece of junk vacuum is like my favorite
Speaker 5:  thing I've ever used to clean floors because it weighs nothing. I have a
Speaker 3:  Thousand dollars LG vacuum with wifi
Speaker 3:  that empties itself into a stand. I thought this was so
Speaker 3:  cool. It looks so good, man. Ugh. I just like looking at it.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. We have a $30 shark that just
Speaker 3:  outperforms that thing. Yep. Coming and going. Yep. Just all that money
Speaker 3:  is in the wifi chip and not in the part that sucks up dirt.
Speaker 4:  It's, I I I haven't run four times a week and
Speaker 4:  that kind of helps. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I've
Speaker 3:  Never had any luck with robot vacuums and now I've heard about the ash chin
Speaker 3:  situation and I never will.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, don't, don't go look at the
Speaker 3:  Images. That's David. What's your lightning round item?
Speaker 5:  If we could title this episode of the podcast, the Ash Chin situation,
Speaker 5:  I would very much appreciate that.
Speaker 3:  That'd be great for SEO no one's Google and Ashton situations.
Speaker 5:  Mine is, I was picking between two Google things. One is that now you can
Speaker 5:  put the Chrome URL bar on iOS down at the bottom. Most controversial
Speaker 5:  decision on the internet for a while there, if you guys remember. But the
Speaker 5:  one I ended up choosing was Google is now selling
Speaker 5:  like in pre registries NG domains.
Speaker 5:  A fun fact about me is I'm obsessed with domain names. I find them totally
Speaker 5:  fascinating. And there was this thing like 10 years ago where ICAN was like,
Speaker 5:  we're gonna put out a million new kinds of domains. You can be pizza, you
Speaker 5:  can be restaurant, you can be online. And we're gonna reinvent the way people
Speaker 5:  think about web webpages. Instead of trying to be a.com, you can
Speaker 5:  just be You know Alfredo's Pizza and that's
Speaker 5:  your restaurant. That didn't work at all. And if you go to like
Speaker 5:  a messaging system or email or Slack or whatever, most of those don't even
Speaker 5:  show up as URLs, which I would argue is like pretty spectacular failure.
Speaker 5:  So now Google's out here trying to make IG happen and their thing is like,
Speaker 5:  if you want it to be You know, if you're a flight booking company,
Speaker 5:  you do book IG or Fly I Nng and
Speaker 5:  they're charging a ton of money for it. R dot i nng, which would be
Speaker 5:  ring obviously. It's like if you wanna, if you're Victoria, not Victoria's
Speaker 5:  Secret. If you're Tiffany's or whoever, $130,000 a year for this
Speaker 5:  domain name. And I just think, whoa,
Speaker 3:  Google
Speaker 5:  Has been way out in front of these. They're called top level domains or TLDs
Speaker 5:  and all these like alternate TLDs. Google has been out in front of for
Speaker 5:  forever. XYZ has actually been fairly successful as a kind of
Speaker 5:  catchall thing. AI had a moment, social has kind of had a
Speaker 5:  moment. And now Google is gonna try really, really, really hard to make
Speaker 5:  ing a thing.
Speaker 4:  I, I really want to have They see me roll
Speaker 5:  Ing. That's very good. Alex, but that's
Speaker 4:  Very good. I don't have i's
Speaker 3:  Like $200,000 a year.
Speaker 4:  Like Neli can, can I have some money?
Speaker 4:  I got an idea. Wait,
Speaker 3:  Didn't Google leave the domains business?
Speaker 5:  Google Domains business I had not even sold. I think just gave to Squarespace,
Speaker 5:  which some people are very mad about. Yeah. But it still has,
Speaker 5:  its like overarching TLD registry thing.
Speaker 5:  So it it like administers these domain names but it doesn't Gotcha. Do the
Speaker 5:  buying and selling and management of them, are
Speaker 3:  They gonna have message ing?
Speaker 4:  That's a good one.
Speaker 3:  They should just call it Gchat. Just put it, put the,
Speaker 3:  put full manifestation. Just call it Gchat. All
Speaker 3:  will be forgiven. The government will give up your, their antitrust trials.
Speaker 3:  We'll stop covering SEO. Just call it Gchat.
Speaker 4:  We're so easily bought.
Speaker 3:  That's that's your disclosure. If they just call it Gchat, we'll back all
Speaker 3:  the way off. Huh? Deal. No deal.
Speaker 3:  Last one I wanna call out. X had its first all hands with Elon and
Speaker 3:  Linda Yao. Alex Heath has the full transcript of that
Speaker 3:  meeting. You should go read it Just to witness
Speaker 3:  the wild vacillations of Elon making stuff up and
Speaker 3:  Linda having to pretend it was part of the plan. Yep. There's one point
Speaker 3:  where I don't remember exactly what he was saying, but Elon was like, I'd
Speaker 3:  like to start with this. and it was obviously a surprise to her and she was
Speaker 3:  like, I'd raise my hand to be a part of that. Perfect. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  perfect.
Speaker 3:  It's very good. That's what you want out of your CEO. Just complete
Speaker 3:  befuddlement and surprise
Speaker 4:  Love chaos.
Speaker 3:  That's a good piece. We got a bunch of good stuff on the site this week.
Speaker 3:  Liz. In addition to the things people are very unhappy about, Liz
Speaker 3:  has been covering the FDX trial. Sam Bankman Free was
Speaker 3:  on the stand. He is lighting himself on fire.
Speaker 3:  There's no other way to describe what is happening in this trial. That dude's
Speaker 3:  gonna jail. But you should read the coverage 'cause Liz is a great writer
Speaker 3:  and she's having the time of her life covering this trial.
Speaker 5:  And also it's probably gonna be over very, there's, there's a non-zero chance
Speaker 5:  that by the time you're listening to this, that a verdict has come in.
Speaker 5:  And we're gonna talk about that on the show next week for
Speaker 3:  Sure. Yeah. And
Speaker 3:  it's gonna be guilty.
Speaker 5:  I agree with that. It
Speaker 3:  Would be a shock if it was not. We have a great video
Speaker 3:  Andy Hawkins made about delivery robots, which is very cool. You should go
Speaker 3:  watch that. Like I said, Becca won an Emmy this week, which is incredible.
Speaker 3:  Go watch some full frame in celebration. And then like I said, we've talked
Speaker 3:  about this whole, we have a big feature this week on SE. You should go read
Speaker 3:  it. We'll link it in the show notes. And then speaking of Andy, he has
Speaker 3:  a great piece about the EV transition and the weird liminal spot it's in
Speaker 3:  right now where it seems like it's ready to start happening. But instead
Speaker 3:  cul culture, war instead culture, war America 2023.
Speaker 3:  Go read that. But it's also, the car makers have kind of blown it, right?
Speaker 3:  They assumed that all the demand for Teslas could be applied to their existing
Speaker 3:  business models. And so they made big stupid trucks
Speaker 3:  instead of like little EVs that people wanna buy like hundred
Speaker 3:  like Chevys. Like look at our a hundred thousand dollars Silverado instead
Speaker 3:  of look at our bolt. Which is I, it feels like an error.
Speaker 3:  Like the people who wanna buy EVs are not up there. Yeah. Anyway,
Speaker 3:  that's a great piece because you'll read it and there's also obviously some
Speaker 3:  coverage of charging networks in there. And lastly, before we break, we
Speaker 3:  wanna know how you feel about the Red Chest on YouTube, right? Watching it
Speaker 3:  on YouTube. Are you catching the Easter eggs in the background or are you
Speaker 3:  sticking with the podcast player? What do you like about the show on YouTube?
Speaker 3:  What don't you like? We know you want us to cut to more pictures of things
Speaker 3:  and add chapter, we'll do all that stuff. But beyond that, what do you want
Speaker 3:  from us on YouTube? We're growing on YouTube. It's great. It's fun to be
Speaker 3:  in the comments on YouTube, but we wanna make it better. Let us know what
Speaker 3:  you think in the comments on YouTube
Speaker 9:  Bringing the multiple Astons to
Speaker 3:  YouTube. Amazing. That's it. Thank you so much.
Speaker 3:  It's
Speaker 1:  And that's it for The Verge Cast this week. Hey, we'd love to hear from you.
Speaker 1:  Give us a call at eight six six Verge one. One The Vergecast is
Speaker 1:  a production of The Verge and Vox Media Podcast Network. Our show is produced
Speaker 1:  by Andrew Marino and Liam James. That's it. We'll see you next week.