# Transcript
ID: 04d9b30d-9316-47ee-a0d2-fa656b12121b
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: How the iPhone 15 could still surprise us
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/4414679834628314633/44463819305721240/s93290-US-5567s-1694168463.mp3
Description: The Verge's David Pierce, Alex Cranz, Richard Lawler, and Dan Seifert discuss what to expect at Apple's iPhone 15 event, the drama behind the scenes with Disney's CEOs, and some more gadget news.
Speaker 4:  Hey everybody, it's Neli. I am missing the show again this week. I'm so
Speaker 4:  sorry. We just moved. I would describe this move as a
Speaker 4:  real crash landing, but we made it, Max made it to our first day of
Speaker 4:  kindergarten, which is a real victory for us. Anyhow, I wanted to give you
Speaker 4:  my two quick predictions for the Apple event. One is a
Speaker 4:  vibes based. I think the vibe of this iPhone event will
Speaker 4:  be the most different of any we've had in a long time because
Speaker 4:  Apple has to keep the focus on the Vision pro. Somehow
Speaker 4:  iPhone sales are slowing down and the only real big
Speaker 4:  change is U S B C, which obviously Apple does not want to talk about too
Speaker 4:  much. So I think the vibes at this event are just gonna be
Speaker 4:  different and I'm excited to go there. I'm excited to see what it's like.
Speaker 4:  I'm always excited to go see New Tech, but I think the vibes of this
Speaker 4:  event are gonna be different. So that's prediction one. Prediction two is
Speaker 4:  that they're gonna completely gloss over U S B C on the iPhone 15 and spend
Speaker 4:  a long time talking about U S B C on the iPhone
Speaker 4:  15 Pro because that will reportedly be a thunderbolt
Speaker 4:  port, which is kind of a big deal for all the camera stuff. So
Speaker 4:  that's my big prediction. Gloss over U S B C on the on the 15, spend time
Speaker 4:  on it on the 15 Pro because I think pro photographers are gonna be super
Speaker 4:  stoked about using this camera over Thunderbolt. Not the world's biggest
Speaker 4:  prediction, but You know me. I'm excited about it. Alright, I'm sorry I'm
Speaker 4:  not here. I gotta go back to unpacking, but I'll be at the iPhone event with
Speaker 4:  everybody next week and I'll be on the show next week. I promise. Come hell
Speaker 4:  or high water rock and
Speaker 4:  roll
Speaker 2:  Welcome
Speaker 5:  To The Vergecast, the flagship podcast with the action button. I'm
Speaker 5:  your friend David Pierce. We have a whole crew here. We have a lot
Speaker 5:  to talk about. Alex Cranz is here. Hi Alex.
Speaker 3:  Hi. I'm your friend. Wondering how often you think about the Roman
Speaker 3:  Empire?
Speaker 5:  Not enough now that I think about
Speaker 3:  It. Not enough. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  You know every, every once in a while, like what would Caesar do? I have,
Speaker 5:  I had a bracelet that says that, but You know not enough. Richard Lawler's
Speaker 5:  here. Hi Richard.
Speaker 6:  Hi. I saw a viral tweet about the Roman Empire not existing, and I'm choosing
Speaker 6:  to believe that conspiracy theory.
Speaker 3:  Oh, I like that one.
Speaker 5:  Have you guys seen the one where the, it's the picture of the pyramids and
Speaker 5:  it says like, this is why they couldn't move the pyramids to museum. And
Speaker 5:  underneath it, it's just underground. The pyramids are like several hundred
Speaker 5:  feet deep also.
Speaker 3:  They're like the Titanic iceberg.
Speaker 5:  It's the best thing on the internet. Dan Seaford here. Hi Dan. Hello.
Speaker 7:  I have no interesting quips about the Roman Empire.
Speaker 5:  Dan, what's your favorite conspiracy
Speaker 5:  theory?
Speaker 7:  Dan, let's not not even go there.
Speaker 5:  There's no upside to you answering that question, Dan. We're just gonna,
Speaker 5:  I'm gonna save you from me and we're gonna move on here. We have a lot to
Speaker 5:  talk about this week. Neli is still moving and still not here. And
Speaker 5:  please shame him publicly for continuing not to be here. We have a lot to
Speaker 5:  talk about. There's an Apple event coming up next week. We're gonna spend
Speaker 5:  a bunch of time talking about that. There's a bunch of gadgets this week.
Speaker 5:  We are like firmly in gadget season. We have new stuff from Sonos, new stuff
Speaker 5:  from GoPro, new stuff from Sony, all kinds of stuff. There's some crazy
Speaker 5:  streaming news. The Bobs are fighting at Disney and we all have
Speaker 5:  a lot of feelings about this. It's,
Speaker 3:  I'm so excited. It's
Speaker 5:  Possible that that segment of this show is going to be nine and a half hours
Speaker 5:  long. So apologies. And Then, we have a lightning round full of fun stuff
Speaker 5:  at the end. But let's start with Apple. So we're recording this on Thursday
Speaker 5:  the seventh. The event is on Tuesday the 12th. It's gonna
Speaker 5:  be the iPhone 15. Dan, you're going rate me your
Speaker 5:  level of enthusiasm for the iPhone event this year.
Speaker 7:  So I hear there's gonna be a new iPhone, probably a new
Speaker 7:  Apple watch You know. I'm excited to
Speaker 7:  see if they can surprise us because at this point, with
Speaker 7:  any of these tech events, whether it's Apple or Google or Samsung or whoever
Speaker 7:  it is, the leaks have kind of tell all the story. The
Speaker 7:  everything basically comes out and we don't really have a ton of surprises
Speaker 7:  going into these events. And then also, this is the
Speaker 7:  15th iPhone by generation. Like it's not even the 15th iPhone, it's
Speaker 7:  like the 17th or something. But like it's, it's like the number 15 in this
Speaker 7:  line. And so like really what are they going to do? That's interesting. And
Speaker 7:  like there's a lot of rumors of like, I'm sure we'll talk through like the
Speaker 7:  action button and titanium and stuff like that. But like
Speaker 7:  ultimately the iPhone and the Apple Watch for that matter are like
Speaker 7:  known products.
Speaker 3:  So you're not hyped for Apple. Finally,
Speaker 3:  finally, finally truly embracing U S B
Speaker 3:  C.
Speaker 7:  I think it's good. Yeah, I can't remember the last time I plugged a cable
Speaker 7:  into my phone, but it's good
Speaker 3:  You went all in on a MagSafe.
Speaker 7:  I went all in on wireless charging like 10 years ago.
Speaker 3:  Even for your AirPods,
Speaker 7:  Every service and danced house is a cheap pad. Yeah, there's just like, I'm
Speaker 7:  just surrounded by cheap pads. Like I'm looking at my desk and there's like
Speaker 7:  four right in front of me. But I mean like I think for a lot of
Speaker 7:  our audience, it'll be a nice convenience thing when they need to like share
Speaker 7:  a cable and stuff like that. But ultimately, like there have been other ways
Speaker 7:  to charge your phone and nobody is syncing their phone with their computer
Speaker 7:  anymore, which is like the other reason you plugged a phone into a cable.
Speaker 7:  So
Speaker 3:  I always forget about that and then I'll plug my phone in and it'll be like,
Speaker 3:  you ready to sync? And I'm like, who are you? How did you get here? Get out.
Speaker 3:  I don't want you.
Speaker 5:  So I wrote a piece this week about Lightning and it was
Speaker 5:  basically the assignment from Jake. Our tech editor was like
Speaker 5:  right about the death of the lightning port. Like was it good, was it
Speaker 5:  bad? How was it? And the like overwhelming feeling that I
Speaker 5:  got going back and watching the old announcements, talking to folks who've
Speaker 5:  used it, is that like lightning was very good and
Speaker 5:  if wireless charging had existed back then or been any good
Speaker 5:  at all, it never would've existed because Apple is like desperate to make
Speaker 5:  wireless charging the answer. Which I think is so interesting. And like there
Speaker 5:  was this great interview that Phil Schiller gave in 2012, right after they
Speaker 5:  announced Lightning. It was with all things D and Ena Freed,
Speaker 5:  I believe it was asked like why no wireless charging. And Schiller
Speaker 5:  was basically like, oh we think that's just another thing you have to plug
Speaker 5:  into the wall. No one wants that. And then of course, fast forward five
Speaker 5:  years and it's 2017 and they're announcing wireless
Speaker 5:  charging and Phil Schiller is up there being like, pretty
Speaker 5:  soon every cafe you go to is going to have a chi charger
Speaker 5:  in every single table. Do you guys remember this when they were like, where's
Speaker 3:  My cafe table?
Speaker 5:  Every surface in the world is going to be a chi charger and
Speaker 5:  you're gonna be able to just put your phone down and charge it as if by magic.
Speaker 5:  And I bet my ongoing theory about this Apple event
Speaker 5:  is they're gonna spend like six seconds on U S B C. They're gonna be like,
Speaker 5:  look a port U S B C Europe and
Speaker 5:  then like three hours telling you how great bag safe
Speaker 5:  is.
Speaker 7:  I don't think they're gonna talk about Europe at all.
Speaker 5:  No, they're not gonna say Europe. They're not
Speaker 7:  Gonna say Europe at all. They're not gonna, they're not gonna make it seem
Speaker 7:  like they were forced into this. They're going to say how you now can use
Speaker 7:  the same charger for your iPad and your iPhone with the same
Speaker 7:  cable and we made it such convenience
Speaker 3:  And your AirPods
Speaker 7:  And your AirPods. Right. But yeah, I don't think it's going to be a lot of
Speaker 7:  discussion because there isn't a lot to say about it. It's a different port
Speaker 7:  to charge your phone.
Speaker 5:  Well I've been talking to a bunch of people who are like, so the, the thing
Speaker 5:  that happened when the iPad went from lightning to U S B
Speaker 5:  C was that all of a sudden there were You know new, new accessories that
Speaker 5:  could be supported. You could plug new things into it. You could get a a
Speaker 5:  bunch of ports in a dock. Like all new
Speaker 5:  computery things were suddenly possible. Some of those turned out to be very
Speaker 5:  cool. Most of them never really came to Frozen. And so I've talked to a bunch
Speaker 5:  of people who are like, oh I'm gonna be able to like plug my external storage
Speaker 5:  into my iPhone now. And I keep being like, you're not, you just
Speaker 5:  super aren't. Like I would be so shocked if Apple did
Speaker 5:  that. Apple
Speaker 6:  Decks is happening. I was
Speaker 3:  About to say Apple decks. Apple decks, like this is
Speaker 7:  The moment. I mean that is never gonna happen. We can, we can spend a whole
Speaker 7:  podcast on why that'll never happen. But it's worth like dissecting what
Speaker 7:  the rumors are saying about the U S B port. And so what they're saying is
Speaker 7:  U S B C port across the iPhones announced, which would be expect be the
Speaker 7:  iPhone 15, the iPhone 15 plus the iPhone 15 Pro and the iPhone
Speaker 7:  15 Pro Max unless they change the name to Ultra or something like that. So
Speaker 7:  they'll all share the same port but they won't all share the same capabilities.
Speaker 7:  The lesser models will still be U SS B 2.0, which means that you're not
Speaker 7:  attaching a bunch of accessories to it because it doesn't have the bandwidth.
Speaker 7:  And then the pro models will have maybe Thunderbolt capabilities or
Speaker 7:  U S B four capability so that it is a faster data transfer
Speaker 7:  seed. What is missing from that is will it support like
Speaker 7:  proper video out? You can do that with an iPad, but will it do that
Speaker 7:  on the iPhone and, and it'll probably will in the way that like you can plug
Speaker 7:  it in and watch a video on a bigger screen. But a desktop software
Speaker 7:  environment is never gonna happen. I
Speaker 3:  Feel like they're kind of gonna be obligated to do it. Not just because
Speaker 3:  everybody, if you've got this port, you should be able to do all this stuff
Speaker 3:  that you can do with other devices that use the exact same processor but
Speaker 3:  also because of accessibility reasons. Like
Speaker 3:  if I have a phone, I should be able to use it however I
Speaker 3:  want, however I need to be able to.
Speaker 7:  Sure. And to be fair, the Lightning iPhone supports that already. Like you
Speaker 7:  can plug an iPhone right into a TV to play. You can use
Speaker 7:  the the Lightning to H D M I adapter and stuff like that.
Speaker 7:  How
Speaker 3:  Many people have that adapter and have done that? Like I've got a U S B C
Speaker 3:  to H T M I cable.
Speaker 5:  How often do you use it?
Speaker 3:  Not since I got rid of the Sony imaging webcam. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  So what are we talking about? I like
Speaker 7:  It's a, it's a pretty niche use case for sure.
Speaker 5:  Alex, the thing you just described is like a true and lovely idea
Speaker 5:  about a company that believes that people should be able to choose how their
Speaker 5:  devices work and has just nothing to do with Apple as it exists in the real
Speaker 5:  world. No, no,
Speaker 3:  No. I I think like, I think Apple has a moral
Speaker 3:  obligation to make it accessible if they have
Speaker 3:  the port that accessible Apple
Speaker 7:  Would say use airplay.
Speaker 5:  I think Apple doesn't give one solitary shit about your moral
Speaker 5:  obligations. I think Apple is going to lock this port down in
Speaker 5:  every single imaginable way and they're gonna tell the same security
Speaker 5:  story that they tell about the App store and everything else. They're gonna
Speaker 5:  say, if we just let you plug in anything, all kinds of things could go wrong.
Speaker 5:  All your important data is on your iPhone. We can't just let you plug in
Speaker 5:  a random thing. Bad things could happen and that's just true enough that
Speaker 5:  Apple's gonna get away with it. And honestly, I don't care because I, I,
Speaker 5:  I think the number of people who are out there wanting desperately to like
Speaker 5:  plug A U S B keyboard and three terabyte hard drive into their iPhone
Speaker 5:  to do things is like basically non-existent. I think
Speaker 6:  There's like M K B H D and six other YouTubers who are like, oh my God, I
Speaker 6:  can finally get these high res files off my iPhone in extra fast
Speaker 6:  time. So there, there's, someone's going to be happy tomorrow with with their
Speaker 6:  pro
Speaker 7:  That customer is buying an iPhone Pro
Speaker 7:  Ultra whatever. They're not buying the base model iPhone for sure. Yep.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, it's fine. Okay, so that's, let's just run through some of the big
Speaker 5:  rumors here. So obviously U S B C is the big one and I would say like on
Speaker 5:  a scale of one to 10, how likely do we think that is? That's at least at
Speaker 5:  like a nine, right? Like I'd be shocked if that doesn't happen at this point.
Speaker 5:  Yeah,
Speaker 7:  That's a pretty safe, safe bet. I think. Yeah, I mean if they don't
Speaker 7:  do it, that'll be the whole story.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, that's really true. That's really true. They're like here's just an
Speaker 5:  action button and like someone will raise their hand and be like, what about
Speaker 5:  the U S B C port? Have
Speaker 7:  We, have you heard about Lightning?
Speaker 5:  The second one is the action button, which has been the rumor
Speaker 5:  thing again, I think potentially just on the pro and pro Max
Speaker 5:  models, but kind of like the Apple Watch ultra. There will be a customizable
Speaker 5:  button you can use to do things. Personally, I'm very excited about
Speaker 5:  this as someone who does the same set of things
Speaker 5:  over and over constantly all day on my phone. Can I pour
Speaker 7:  Cold water all over your excitement please? Oh
Speaker 3:  No,
Speaker 7:  The action button on the Ultra, the watch Ultra does
Speaker 7:  nothing. Oh yeah. It's like the most disappointing thing ever.
Speaker 7:  And it would not surprise me if this action button on the iPhone is
Speaker 7:  similarly annoyingly
Speaker 5:  Limited. It like only opens control center and it replaces
Speaker 6:  A switch, right? Like the switch that was already there.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, it's getting rid of the mute button. They're
Speaker 6:  Taking away a button and adding a A slightly different
Speaker 6:  button.
Speaker 3:  Yes,
Speaker 7:  Adding something that could for a lot of people or the right person be a
Speaker 7:  better experience. Because like personally, I can't remember the last time
Speaker 7:  just like I can't remember the last time I plugged in my phone to a cable
Speaker 7:  to charge. I can't remember the last time I flicked the mute switch on my,
Speaker 7:  the side of my phone. It's always on mute. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  We talked about this last week. It's because you're not a hundred years old.
Speaker 5:  Like everyone who lets their phone ring loudly, Dan
Speaker 5:  congratulations you did it.
Speaker 7:  But they're not switching it either. That's why it's always ringing. No,
Speaker 7:  no, no. 'cause they're not switching the mute.
Speaker 3:  So here's the deal. Last week I ranted about this button because I still
Speaker 3:  think it's stupid. 'cause all I'm gonna do is turn it into a mute button
Speaker 3:  because that's what I need it for. And somebody wrote back and was like,
Speaker 3:  you are stupid Cranz. And I always stop and pay attention when someone says
Speaker 3:  that this person seems they're right. Right? They might be. And this person
Speaker 3:  was like, every, it feels like every week I have to go and tell my
Speaker 3:  dad that he just has the mute button on and that's why he's not getting calls.
Speaker 3:  And I was like, oh, oh there, I forget that there are other people that use
Speaker 3:  technology that way. It was a nice thank you, it was a
Speaker 3:  nice reminder. I still think I'm right, but like I still think he's
Speaker 3:  wrong.
Speaker 7:  In a perfect world, I could set this button to launch the camera or
Speaker 7:  launch a third party camera app or switch focus modes
Speaker 7:  or whatever. Like I could customize it to my hearts content. I'm a
Speaker 7:  little reticent to get that excited that I'll be able to do all the things
Speaker 7:  I wanna do with it just because of the evidence with the Apple Watch
Speaker 7:  Ultra, even though the Apple Watch software is admittedly much more limited
Speaker 7:  in lockdown than the iPhones is even. So you're
Speaker 3:  Gonna be able to open control center, mute things, open
Speaker 3:  the fitness app so you can see all the new fitness
Speaker 3:  opportunities
Speaker 7:  Start a workout. I
Speaker 5:  Don't know, the thing that gives me hope is the You know the the triple tap
Speaker 5:  gesture on the back of the iPhone that you can do that's actually pretty
Speaker 5:  customizable. You can use it to do a bunch of different actions. You can
Speaker 5:  use it to open stuff. Like just take that and put it on the action
Speaker 5:  button. The triple tap thing for people who don't know is actually really
Speaker 5:  useful. And I turned it on expecting to get like a million false positives
Speaker 5:  and it would be really annoying, but it's not. It's great you should turn
Speaker 5:  it on. But I think if even just like that level of customizability where
Speaker 5:  it's like, let me open an app or do like a shortcut, I'm good. I'd be
Speaker 5:  happy and I think we might get it. Okay, so that's the other one. There are
Speaker 5:  a bunch of spec upgrades possible a 17 chips
Speaker 5:  wifi, six E potentially eight gigs of RAM
Speaker 5:  in the high-end phones or even potentially in all of them.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, the the thing about all the spec upgrades is they're all expected for
Speaker 7:  the pro models, right? So like the regular 15 is basically expected
Speaker 7:  to be a microwaved iPhone 14 pro
Speaker 7:  with the same level of specs there. Dynamic island will is rumored to
Speaker 7:  come to the 15 model. So the whole line will, will support the dynamic
Speaker 7:  island. Maybe they'll all support always on display, which was
Speaker 7:  something that was limited to the pros last year, which would mean that with
Speaker 7:  iOS 17 you could use the standby mode to its full extent regardless of which
Speaker 7:  iPhone you buy this year. But in terms of like performance increases, those
Speaker 7:  are really going to be limited to the 15 pro by all all
Speaker 7:  accounts, which
Speaker 5:  Seems like Apple's kind of move now. And I think it,
Speaker 5:  it really seems like Apple has just embraced this idea that there's no
Speaker 5:  chance you're upgrading from last year's phone to this year's phone. So what
Speaker 5:  they need is like every three years the upgrade should feel meaningful,
Speaker 5:  right? So if you start with the pro and trickle it down and then start with
Speaker 5:  the next year's pro and trickle it down that accrues over You know the three
Speaker 5:  or four year lifespan of your phone into something fairly meaningful. But
Speaker 5:  it does make every one of these upgrades like we used to be on that sort
Speaker 5:  of TikTok schedule of like big upgrade small improvements. It just,
Speaker 5:  it's just talks every year now. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. So I guess one thing, one note with this year's iPhones,
Speaker 7:  this is the iPhone 15, we're not really anticipating huge
Speaker 7:  design changes from the rumors. Maybe some rounding of corners,
Speaker 7:  maybe some rounded glass a little bit. But it's effectively gonna visually
Speaker 7:  look very similar to the 14, the 13 and the 12. So this would be
Speaker 7:  like the fourth year in a row of this design language if this
Speaker 7:  pans out, which to your point David is, is like kind of like these small
Speaker 7:  iterative updates and if you've held onto an iPhone 11
Speaker 7:  or an iPhone 10 s for five years, you'll
Speaker 7:  get a big upgrade with the iPhone 15. But even coming from a
Speaker 7:  13 to the 15, you might not get a huge upgrade
Speaker 7:  based on what we know so far at
Speaker 5:  Least. Yeah. I do wonder what amount of time Apple has in its brain
Speaker 5:  for how long they think the upgrade cycle is gonna be. 'cause to your point,
Speaker 5:  if you're coming from like an 11, let's say, this is gonna feel like a big
Speaker 5:  upgrade even if it's sort of the smallest version of what we need. But like
Speaker 5:  you said, if you have a, if you have a 13, which not that long ago would
Speaker 5:  be a perfectly normal sort of upgrade cycle, like every, every two years,
Speaker 5:  nothing in what we've heard so far makes me think this is going to be like
Speaker 5:  a meaningfully different phone experience. I guess the one thing could possibly
Speaker 5:  be there's been this rumor of the Parascoping telephoto lens
Speaker 5:  that might get you a bunch more zoom it be cool, that could be cool and exciting.
Speaker 5:  But in terms of like actual new things I can do on my phone, not that
Speaker 5:  much.
Speaker 3:  I, I know this is coming from the person who just said that Apple has a moral
Speaker 3:  obligation, who, who, who suggested
Speaker 3:  that? But how much of this is actually on Apple? Like,
Speaker 3:  like the tick, tick, tick because I, I feel like it's, it's not entirely
Speaker 3:  on Apple. I feel like just the whole technology, like all mobile
Speaker 3:  phone technology is kind of slowed down, right?
Speaker 6:  Are there features that we're looking at that the iPhone doesn't have that,
Speaker 6:  that we wish it had that other phones are, are using right now? Right?
Speaker 3:  Like and it's like, okay, what was the last big feature? Folding
Speaker 3:  phones, which that'll be cool when Apple eventually does it 12 years from
Speaker 3:  now and then the telescoping lens, which
Speaker 3:  might happen this year, like the Samsung SuperZoo, that's about
Speaker 3:  it, right? Like, I'm trying to think of other things where I'm like, oh man,
Speaker 3:  I want that on an iPhone. I
Speaker 7:  I You know. I I think that actually gives Apple kind of a pass. And, and
Speaker 7:  the reason I feel that way is Apple is such a trendsetter, you
Speaker 3:  Think they have a moral obligation to,
Speaker 7:  I think they have a moral obligation to push the envelope and
Speaker 7:  break us out of this boring smartphone malaise. But realistically
Speaker 7:  they are such a trendsetter in this industry because they are such
Speaker 7:  a taste maker in the industry. And so like the fact that like Apple
Speaker 7:  doesn't really seem to be, and like they argued this endlessly that
Speaker 7:  they are innovating out their eyeballs, but the
Speaker 7:  real impact is like the, the smartphone as we know it has been the same
Speaker 7:  for a long time to David's point. And so like if anyone's going to push this
Speaker 7:  forward and move us out of it, Apple's in a really great position to do that.
Speaker 7:  And it just like, they're such a conservative company.
Speaker 3:  I mean that's not Tim Cook's Apple, right? Right. Like he's busy with with
Speaker 3:  some other stuff. All the vr ar stuff. He doesn't have time to be pushing
Speaker 3:  the envelope on the thing that just prints him money every
Speaker 3:  year.
Speaker 7:  I I will say the one thing that is kind of a, maybe, maybe a little
Speaker 7:  bit exciting to me is the rumor that the 15 Pro Pro Max
Speaker 7:  will use titanium. And the reason that I think that is kind of
Speaker 7:  cool and exciting is because I think that the pro models have been way too
Speaker 7:  heavy for like five years and they've stuck with this stainless steel and
Speaker 7:  it weighs a ton and they feel like bricks and titanium would be slightly
Speaker 7:  lighter and I would like a lighter phone. I
Speaker 3:  I'm down for that. I
Speaker 6:  Think Dan's right. But I think that what we're seeing here, they admitted
Speaker 6:  that they don't have any new ideas for the phone. That's why they brought
Speaker 6:  out the Vision Pro because they can't guarantee that you will buy a new phone
Speaker 6:  every year and they need to sell you a different thing. They need to get
Speaker 6:  more money from you somehow. And that's why the Vision Pro is happening
Speaker 6:  because what are we gonna put in the phone to make you buy one?
Speaker 6:  Well,
Speaker 7:  Yeah, I mean we, we've had these conversations for years. What is the next
Speaker 7:  iPhone for Apple, right? The iPhone is the bread and butter of the company.
Speaker 7:  It's, it's, it's 75% of its revenue, et cetera, et
Speaker 7:  cetera. And, and this year the Vision Pro is it, a few years ago it was
Speaker 7:  the Apple Watch and a few years before that it was the iPad and neither of
Speaker 7:  them really were able to dethrone the
Speaker 7:  iPhone as Apple's main business. And so now we're onto
Speaker 7:  vr, but at the end of the day, okay, the iPhone is still Apple's bread and
Speaker 7:  butter. You
Speaker 6:  Didn't even mention Apple TV or Home Pod.
Speaker 7:  I'm
Speaker 5:  Sorry, I'll coach you. No, I I just think in a funny
Speaker 5:  way, I think a lot of what we're doing in the tech industry in general right
Speaker 5:  now is realizing that nothing is probably ever going to be as big as
Speaker 5:  smartphones. That like this idea that someone was going to
Speaker 5:  basically come up with one kind of gadget that every
Speaker 5:  single person on earth was going to dedicate their lives to was like a
Speaker 5:  maybe a bad idea and b probably
Speaker 5:  irreparable, right? Like there, I just don't see a world in which that
Speaker 5:  happens again anytime soon. That's because
Speaker 3:  You're not in Tim Cook's world looking at the VR
Speaker 3:  headsets. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  But he's selling 'em for $3,500. Right? He's perfectly happy to not have
Speaker 5:  everybody buy one at least for a very long time. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  I think you're right though. I I, I definitely agree with you. Like we, we've
Speaker 3:  hit this point where we all experienced one of the biggest shifts in technology
Speaker 3:  in like the history of the world and in some ways bigger even
Speaker 3:  than the personal computer, right? Like way more people
Speaker 3:  have phones than personal computers forever. And, and way more
Speaker 3:  people now have access to the internet. Like this was truly that window into
Speaker 3:  the internet. And now it's like, oh, you can't, you just can't replicate
Speaker 3:  that. Yeah, you're gonna try with ar, vr and, and new
Speaker 3:  weird laptops and folding phones and stuff, but like
Speaker 3:  we did it, it's like refrigerators. We had the big huge moment.
Speaker 3:  Now everyone's got one and now I update it every 10 years or when it makes
Speaker 3:  a weird loud noise in the middle of the night.
Speaker 5:  It's a life and when you do, it will start sending you push notifications.
Speaker 5:  Yes. So congratulations. No, I I, yeah, I think, I think it's
Speaker 5:  possible and I sort of expect to have
Speaker 5:  this thrown in my face, but I think it's possible that
Speaker 5:  Apple has something coming here that it has not
Speaker 5:  leaked yet. It just, this doesn't
Speaker 5:  seem like a whole story for Apple and it's the
Speaker 5:  iPhone 15 and Apple likes round numbers. It has
Speaker 5:  to Dan's point been a while since we got like a
Speaker 5:  meaningful big change. Maybe U Ss B C is that thing. But I
Speaker 5:  also feel like if I'm Apple and I'm looking at that thing and it's like,
Speaker 5:  okay, we're being forced to change our port, we have to like play along with
Speaker 5:  this new rules. Like let's take this as a moment to do something
Speaker 5:  unusual. What would that be? I don't know. This is the thing,
Speaker 5:  they already
Speaker 6:  Put satellite connectivity in the phone, which has admittedly it
Speaker 6:  folds in half, like saved a couple of people's lives. Not a small thing.
Speaker 5:  No. Yeah. The satellite stuff is real. I totally agree. I
Speaker 7:  I will say You know when we had this discussion last year ahead of the iPhone
Speaker 7:  14 Pro launch, the rumor mill was saying it was trying
Speaker 7:  to decipher what these cutouts on the screen would look like and nobody really
Speaker 7:  predicted what the dynamic island would be. And that is the one
Speaker 7:  area that Apple doesn't really leak Yeah. Is
Speaker 7:  the software side of things. And so if there are new
Speaker 7:  hardware features on the device, we don't
Speaker 7:  know how Apple will use it or integrate it into its software. And
Speaker 7:  we, we can, we can talk about how effective Dynamic Island is,
Speaker 7:  but it wasn't what anybody predicted. And
Speaker 7:  so maybe the, like you're saying, maybe there's something that like we just
Speaker 7:  can't see because we are only seeing based on the supply chain,
Speaker 7:  which can only see hardware components.
Speaker 3:  Do you think it's something around the button You
Speaker 5:  Know what would be awesome is if if with the titanium, we've been
Speaker 5:  trying to do this shatterproof glass thing for forever, if Apple has like
Speaker 5:  finally cracked the, like we have made you a phone that is like the
Speaker 5:  old, like Nokia 33 10, like you can't break it. Even if you try oh man and
Speaker 5:  Tim Cook just like gets on stage and just like hucks his phone into the ground
Speaker 5:  and then picks up. That would be the coolest iPhone launch of all time instantly.
Speaker 5:  That's not what I'm rooting for. I don't think it's happening, but that's
Speaker 5:  what I want.
Speaker 3:  I don't think it's happening, but I want this so bad. I want like the reverse
Speaker 3:  cyber truck reveal because
Speaker 5:  That's really what it is, right? Like if we're in, if we're in phones or
Speaker 5:  appliance mode, it's durability and it's battery life are the two
Speaker 5:  things that everybody should continue to press against because
Speaker 5:  that makes my existing phone life, which most people are fine with
Speaker 5:  meaningfully better immediately. I still see an alarming number of
Speaker 5:  people with broken phone screens just out in the world. It's crazy.
Speaker 3:  I just had to look to make sure mine was working. Right now it's
Speaker 7:  Apple could make things more repairable. It did that with iPhone 14, not
Speaker 7:  the 14 pro, but the 14 was designed to be more repairable. So maybe that
Speaker 7:  extends across the line. That would be a step forward. It'd be a small step,
Speaker 7:  but
Speaker 3:  Well and they just, they just really kind of embraced California's
Speaker 3:  repairability law a couple of weeks ago. Right. So like
Speaker 7:  Begrudgingly Yeah.
Speaker 3:  They
Speaker 7:  Are embracing U S B C Alex. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Exactly.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Where they like kick you when you use it. Like you're just gonna get
Speaker 3:  kicked to the pants every time you plug U S B C into this thing and every
Speaker 3:  time you order one of those, those like the the repair kits, somebody's gonna
Speaker 3:  come to your door and kick you in the pants and be like, you shouldn't be
Speaker 3:  using this
Speaker 5:  And then charge you $600. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  But it's one of those things where Apple being Apple, they could make a huge
Speaker 6:  gap between them and the Samsungs and the Googles and the whoever else is
Speaker 6:  of the world because they just can't control phone design and components
Speaker 6:  the way that they can to Yeah. Potentially make something more appealable.
Speaker 6:  As one last thing to note, what do you guys think of the rumors about the
Speaker 6:  price that You know the most expensive models will be maybe a hundred dollars
Speaker 6:  more expensive than they used to be or
Speaker 3:  It's stupid. It makes sense, but I hate it so therefore it
Speaker 3:  is stupid. I'm just talking you through my, my, my mind,
Speaker 3:  my processing here. Like does it really need to be more
Speaker 3:  expensive? I feel like no, is Titanium
Speaker 3:  really adding a hundred dollars to it, especially because the phone, like
Speaker 3:  the difference between how much it costs to manufacture it and sell it is
Speaker 3:  fairly large. It just feels like price creep.
Speaker 7:  Well it certainly is. I mean if Apple is nothing, if not very good at
Speaker 7:  preserving profit margins and providing or,
Speaker 7:  or convincing people in perceived value, and when you say it's titanium and
Speaker 7:  new materials and different, I don't think it's hard for them to jump a hundred
Speaker 7:  dollars in perceived value. We've seen across
Speaker 7:  the board technology getting more expensive at over the past few
Speaker 7:  years as inflation has gone up and as the supply chain issues and things
Speaker 7:  like that. Samsung's tablet s nine tablet line this summer is a hundred dollars
Speaker 7:  more across the board. And that is like kind of backwards from
Speaker 7:  how we want to experience technology and that it like gets cheaper over
Speaker 7:  time, but it's just kind of like the world we're in. I will not be surprised
Speaker 7:  for a second if they start at 10 99 now. And I also don't think it's going
Speaker 7:  to impact their sales much because most people are buying these on payment
Speaker 7:  plans over 24 or 36 months, whatever it might be. It's a buck or two a month.
Speaker 7:  They're not even gonna notice it. So I I don't think it's gonna make much
Speaker 7:  of it. It'll just make Apple more money. Well and
Speaker 3:  The pro isn't their bestselling model, right? Like it's the regular
Speaker 3:  iPhones?
Speaker 7:  Well yeah, I mean like the, the bestselling model I believe of last year's
Speaker 7:  round was iPhone 14, but the 14 Pro was close behind it and
Speaker 7:  nobody bought the 14 plus.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, the big cheap Screens theory really took a hit last year. It wasn't
Speaker 5:  cheap.
Speaker 7:  That was the problem. That's
Speaker 5:  True.
Speaker 7:  It was $900. Like, I mean you're, you are like looking at an iPhone 14
Speaker 7:  pro Max at that point. Like yeah, if they did it for less than that then
Speaker 7:  yeah, I, I could have seen that argument, but it wasn't cheap. That was a
Speaker 7:  problem.
Speaker 3:  I guess that's, that's one of the things they could change here, right? Like
Speaker 3:  the pricing schemes, because last year they did get really weird and it was
Speaker 3:  a lot of confusion and we immediately saw that reflected in what
Speaker 3:  got purchased and what didn't. And this year maybe if they raise those prices
Speaker 3:  on the most expensive ones, maybe they draw up the prices on the cheaper
Speaker 3:  ones to make that Delta significant. Yeah,
Speaker 7:  It makes if they could keep the 15 plus at that $900 price, but now
Speaker 7:  it's $300 to go to the 15 Pro Max and so that's like a
Speaker 7:  much more significant gap and so that that might be the move there. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  And and maybe people would more gravitate towards the 15 plus if they want
Speaker 7:  a big screen.
Speaker 3:  But no, we should demand they be cheaper, rise up. They have a moral
Speaker 3:  obligation. Have you
Speaker 5:  Considered the perspective of the Apple shareholder Alex?
Speaker 3:  They have a moral obligation? Well,
Speaker 7:  So well somebody think about the profit margins,
Speaker 5:  It really, it's such a cynical idea to think that instead of
Speaker 5:  making one thing cheaper in order to make the price differences more obvious,
Speaker 5:  they're just gonna make the other thing more expensive. But that's also a
Speaker 5:  hundred percent what's gonna happen. That's
Speaker 5:  rough. All right, let's see. So what else are we expecting? There's gonna
Speaker 5:  be, we think a new Apple watch, which by all accounts is going to be thoroughly
Speaker 5:  unexciting, teeny tiny upgrades on the old Apple Watch.
Speaker 7:  So I, I think what we're expecting of the new Apple Watch lineup
Speaker 7:  is a similar design, whether that's a series model, series nine or the
Speaker 7:  Ultra, but they are rumored to have a finally a
Speaker 7:  faster processor. Basically the Apple Watch has used the same
Speaker 7:  performing processor since I think the S six or series six. And there's just
Speaker 7:  been some small health sensors added to it with this
Speaker 7:  model. The rumors are saying that we'll actually get a faster performing
Speaker 7:  processor, which will be the first time in a while that we've had that
Speaker 3:  Will that translate to better battery life?
Speaker 5:  I have never once been like, my watch is slow. I think
Speaker 5:  my watch is stupid and doesn't do much and I wish Siri would talk to me less,
Speaker 5:  but it does not feel slow. Maybe the widgets thing
Speaker 5:  as this stuff gets more useful will make it feel slower
Speaker 5:  as you use it more. I I
Speaker 7:  Think if you have a recent model Apple Watch Yes. But if you had one of the
Speaker 7:  say series four or earlier Oh,
Speaker 5:  For Shark? Yeah, yeah,
Speaker 7:  Yeah. They, they got slow. The series three got to be a, the
Speaker 5:  Series the to give very slow. I agree with that. Yeah. And then I guess what
Speaker 5:  is it, next year, mark Germond at Bloomberg was reporting that there's potentially
Speaker 5:  a much bigger Apple watch redesign coming Yeah.
Speaker 7:  With new manufacturing using three D printing techniques and stuff like
Speaker 7:  that. But it doesn't seem like that is slated for this year's model. Okay.
Speaker 7:  And if I read it correctly,
Speaker 3:  But nothing on battery life, we haven't heard one way or the other improvements.
Speaker 7:  I I mean Apple's claimed the same 18 hours of battery life on the series
Speaker 7:  models for since like series one Yeah. Or
Speaker 7:  two. So I, I mean if you want more battery life, they have the
Speaker 7:  ultra that is, that is their, their pitch for battery life is the ultra
Speaker 3:  Yeah. That will never fit on this hand.
Speaker 5:  And Then we think probably, we think probably new AirPods too, right?
Speaker 5:  Potentially like just to put a u s BBC port on them. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  It'll be interesting to how this is handled. Like do we get all new AirPods
Speaker 7:  or just a air, a new case that they sell when Oh, that's interesting. Basically
Speaker 7:  the same AirPods with a new port and then you can buy the case separately.
Speaker 7:  They did that with the wireless charging way back when, I think it was the,
Speaker 7:  the AirPods two, they first launched without wireless charging and then you
Speaker 7:  could buy the case with wireless charging or you could buy it bundled
Speaker 7:  together. So it'll be interesting to see if that happens. This is one area
Speaker 7:  where like the supply chain leaks have not shown anything. And so like there's
Speaker 7:  been no new designs of AirPods released or leaked or anything like that.
Speaker 7:  So the idea being if they put U S B C on it is
Speaker 7:  they're, they're solely to match the fact that the iPhone has U S B C.
Speaker 7:  And so you use the same charging cable for both.
Speaker 3:  Is that gonna be the last of the lightning stuff? If they do, if they switch
Speaker 3:  both of those over still some iPads. Right?
Speaker 7:  So the base model ninth gen iPad, which
Speaker 7:  is the like cheapest iPad you could buy, is still being sold new by Apple
Speaker 7:  that's got a lightning, the magic keyboard for the Mac and the
Speaker 7:  magic truck pad for the Mac are still lightning.
Speaker 5:  Wait, the did we, did we fix the flip upside down mouse? Is that
Speaker 5:  finally No.
Speaker 7:  Out of commission? That's Oh yeah. The magic mouse is still lightning. Still
Speaker 7:  lightning?
Speaker 5:  Yes. Well, here's hoping they fix all that all at once.
Speaker 3:  That's gonna be the big surprise. That's gonna be the big splash.
Speaker 7:  There's also rumors for the October event of that Apple usually
Speaker 7:  holds that we will see M three Max and a new iMac with
Speaker 7:  an M three processor. And I think that's when we'll see U S B C ports on
Speaker 7:  the peripherals. The
Speaker 5:  Truly pettiest thing Apple could do if it really wants to get everybody into
Speaker 5:  wireless charging is put U S B C ports on everything, but
Speaker 5:  put them always in the most inconvenient place. Like in the same
Speaker 5:  way that on the Magic Mouse it's on the bottom put in in the middle
Speaker 7:  Of
Speaker 5:  The track. Yeah, put it on like the top left corner of the iPhone. They're
Speaker 5:  like, oh, you wanna plug it in? Knock yourself out. Great. Good. Good luck.
Speaker 5:  Congratulations. It's
Speaker 7:  In, it's in the dynamic
Speaker 7:  island.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, it, yeah. I love this. This is, this is my new favorite idea. Tim Cook,
Speaker 5:  if you're listening, please charge the dynamic island. I love it. Oh,
Speaker 5:  one more Apple thing actually that I'm curious what y'all think about. So
Speaker 5:  there was this announcement this week from Apple
Speaker 5:  that the Vision Pro app store for the headset presumably
Speaker 5:  coming next year will include by default
Speaker 5:  all iPhone and iPad apps that are compatible, which obviously has
Speaker 5:  some You know what compatibility means is difficult, but it means
Speaker 5:  by default if developers don't turn it off, a huge number of iPhone
Speaker 5:  and iPad apps are just going to be available for the Vision Pro on day one.
Speaker 5:  Is this a good idea or a terrible idea?
Speaker 3:  Great idea. Yeah. Can you, because you're gonna be able to go find that one
Speaker 3:  fart app that has just survived this whole
Speaker 3:  time and immediately be like in the
Speaker 3:  virtual space that's incredible. Like
Speaker 3:  $3,500 spent. Absolutely. I want a fart app.
Speaker 3:  Just
Speaker 7:  I, I think it's a necessary move to
Speaker 7:  give the people that are actually buying these for $3,500, something
Speaker 7:  to do on their headsets other than the five to 10 apps that are ready to
Speaker 7:  go at launch. Yeah. I don't think it's going to be a great experience for
Speaker 7:  the vast majority of apps. Everything that I've seen from developers playing
Speaker 7:  with them and things like that. I have said like if you have an iPad
Speaker 7:  app, it'll run, but you really should be redesigning it for this
Speaker 7:  spatial interface. Well
Speaker 3:  It's, I mean this is the same thing that happened with iPhone to iPad and
Speaker 3:  every time you accidentally open an iPhone app on your iPad, you're like,
Speaker 3:  oh Jesus
Speaker 7:  Instagram threads in the 2020 third year of our
Speaker 7:  Lord. You're
Speaker 3:  Just really upset. And so that's what's gonna happen for VR for, for
Speaker 3:  this headset only. It's gonna be for like the next three or four years.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, I think it, yeah, it's gonna take some time and then like it'll taper
Speaker 7:  off and You know if the platform is a success and it gets the developer interest
Speaker 7:  and the customer interest and all that, there will be more, more native,
Speaker 7:  just like the iPad took a couple of years to get really great native iPad
Speaker 7:  apps. Do you,
Speaker 3:  Do you think the visual design, so like You know when you, when you open
Speaker 3:  those iPad apps, oftentimes they feel like they're from
Speaker 3:  2008, they're from like the, the dawn of the iPhone. It's like
Speaker 3:  nothing's changed that isomorphic design and everything. Do you think like
Speaker 3:  the same thing's gonna happen with this new headset where you'll still
Speaker 3:  be like, like not only stuck because it's this giant blown up app,
Speaker 3:  but because like the design is so different, the UI
Speaker 3:  design is so different from whatever's coming.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, I mean I think, I think that is a part of it, right? And that's part
Speaker 7:  of the reason that like all the developers that I see posting on social about
Speaker 7:  it are saying they need to redesign it because the design language of, and
Speaker 7:  David, maybe you could speak to this more 'cause you've got firsthand experience
Speaker 7:  with it, but the design language of vision OSS is very different than iOS
Speaker 7:  and iPad oss. It's got a lot of transparency and layers and depth and things
Speaker 7:  like that. And like iOS is notoriously
Speaker 7:  flat.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I mean if you, if you just like think about the structure of a normal
Speaker 5:  iOS app, it's like there's a bar at the bottom with some stuff.
Speaker 5:  There's all your stuff in the middle, up at the top, there's probably a menu
Speaker 5:  button that opens things and then like the settings live off to
Speaker 5:  one side, right? Yeah. That's kind of the like standard structure of an iOS
Speaker 5:  app. If that's the best we can do in augmented reality,
Speaker 5:  like, boy did we blow it in the future, you You know the way
Speaker 5:  you use it is by using your fingers and you, you look at the
Speaker 5:  menu item that you wanna click on and then you click your fingers together
Speaker 5:  and that's how you do it. And if I have to sit there and be like,
Speaker 5:  okay, look up, click on the thing that goes to settings, then move my head
Speaker 5:  all the way over here, look at the thing with my name on it, click that,
Speaker 5:  look down a list, click that. Like, no, that's bad. We have blown it.
Speaker 5:  And then
Speaker 3:  Periodically having to make, make it big so you can actually find the button
Speaker 3:  and hit just Right.
Speaker 5:  Right. Exactly. Yeah. No, this is, this is a mess. And I feel like this
Speaker 5:  thing that Apple is trying to do where it basically seems
Speaker 5:  increasingly, like the iPad app is kind of the like atomic
Speaker 5:  unit of it. And then iPad apps can move to Mac where
Speaker 5:  they more or less work iPad apps are
Speaker 5:  increasingly in, have everything in common with iPhone
Speaker 5:  apps where things mostly work in both places even though the screen sizes
Speaker 5:  are different. And now they wanna put iPad apps in particular onto
Speaker 5:  the Vision Pro. And I just don't think that's gonna keep working
Speaker 5:  forever. Like you have this one rectangular
Speaker 5:  screen and you should be able to put that on all of your rectangular
Speaker 5:  screens. I'm just not sure that holds forever as much as Apple seems to
Speaker 5:  want it to. But I do agree it's a decent stop gap and like a
Speaker 5:  bunch of half functional apps are probably better than
Speaker 5:  no apps at all. At first,
Speaker 7:  Like, like if you wanna watch Netflix, like the iPad Netflix app will
Speaker 7:  be more than sufficient. Yeah. To play Netflix in front of your face in in
Speaker 7:  the, on the video, it
Speaker 3:  Just won't be as cool. 'cause you won't be in a little weird virtual
Speaker 3:  theater that's always empty and a little scary.
Speaker 5:  That's actually a really good example, right? Because there is the version
Speaker 5:  of it that it's just like it'll play in a window in front of you, but the
Speaker 5:  cooler version of that is something much more ambitious and has weird theaters.
Speaker 5:  Or you can like have it be the, the like Oculus Quest thing
Speaker 5:  where it's like you're in your home and it's playing on a TV in front of
Speaker 5:  you and there's a crackling fire. Like there are big ideas to be had
Speaker 5:  there, but like I'd rather have a thing that plays Netflix than nothing that
Speaker 5:  plays Netflix. So I guess I have seen a bunch of developers who are
Speaker 5:  not excited about this idea of it. Like even some who are like,
Speaker 5:  I'll, I'll eventually turn this on. But the idea of it being on by default
Speaker 5:  and people like discovering their apps for the first time through
Speaker 5:  this thing that is thoroughly unoptimized and untested for their app. They're
Speaker 5:  not fans. The
Speaker 7:  Same thing happened with the Apple Silicon Max, right? Like yeah, that's
Speaker 7:  right. Apple had initially pitched if I'm, I could be misremembering it,
Speaker 7:  but I believe the plan was to have all of the iPhone and, and iPad apps
Speaker 7:  just kind of work by default. And then they rolled it back because, and many,
Speaker 7:  many developers have opted not to make their apps
Speaker 7:  available on M one Max or, or Apple Silicon
Speaker 7:  Max because the experience really isn't great and they didn't design it for
Speaker 7:  that. And there's a handful that do, but it's very few and far between. And
Speaker 6:  I wouldn't be surprised that same thing happens that that between the time
Speaker 6:  of when we have this $3,500 Vision pro and whenever we get a Vision pro that
Speaker 6:  people actually can buy or want to buy, that policy
Speaker 6:  changes. And also hopefully by then they'll have enough apps to kind of satisfy
Speaker 6:  the people. But for the first initial buyers having
Speaker 6:  a huge app store full of apps that kind of don't work, but you have
Speaker 6:  everything to choose from is fine before you get to the general public actually
Speaker 6:  using this thing, it's
Speaker 5:  A hell of a sales pitch for a $3,500 headset.
Speaker 7:  Alright. Just to bring this full circle, do we think we're going to hear
Speaker 7:  anything about the Vision Pro next week? Yes,
Speaker 3:  A hundred percent. I, I like, I, I think David's right that they've got something
Speaker 3:  coming, but I think it's probably less about the phone itself and more
Speaker 3:  about the grand new vision for the next, the
Speaker 3:  future of how we window our ways into the internet. And
Speaker 3:  it's gonna be some stuff
Speaker 6:  When Tim Cook tells us that we can hold up the iPhone to our face, like heads
Speaker 6:  up style and have a Vision Pro right now for $1,099,
Speaker 6:  you're all going to buy one every single day. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Google Cardboard was a very successful program.
Speaker 8:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And it, it too costs a thousand dollars.
Speaker 3:  That's how much the Belkin headset will be.
Speaker 5:  The thing, the thing I've been surprised by is how forthcoming Apple has
Speaker 5:  been in like, letting developers talk about their experiences so
Speaker 5:  far. Like there have been people out there talking about how they've been
Speaker 5:  using it and they haven't said a ton, but they're able to at least like,
Speaker 5:  I think
Speaker 7:  Those are very gated experience for Oh for sure. Like, like, like
Speaker 7:  what? Like Apple produced a, a PR blast a few weeks ago Right. That had some
Speaker 7:  developers providing quotes and things like that and like that's all those
Speaker 7:  developers can say about it. Yes. And those like Apple PR
Speaker 5:  Approved quotes. That is true. That's definitely true. But like, it just
Speaker 5:  makes me think of like when the iPad came out, apple literally chained it
Speaker 5:  to people's tables and we'll probably get something like that, but I would
Speaker 5:  bet we're gonna get like a really fun montagey video of the
Speaker 5:  developers playing with the Vision Pro. And that's about all we're gonna
Speaker 5:  get. Alright. Yeah, that's fair. We need to take a break. Dan, can you stick
Speaker 5:  around for a little while longer and talk about some more gadget? Sure. Or
Speaker 5:  do you have to go
Speaker 7:  Happy to join?
Speaker 5:  Okay, good. All right, we're gonna take a quick break, then we're gonna go
Speaker 5:  back and talk about some other stuff. We'll be right
Speaker 5:  back.
Speaker 5:  All right, we're back. Before we get to the Bobs, which I have promised we
Speaker 5:  are going to get to very soon, let's just run through some of the other gadgets
Speaker 5:  that came out this week before we mercifully let damn go. Does anybody have
Speaker 5:  feelings about GoPro? Like I, I mean this sincerely as a question. GoPro
Speaker 5:  launched a new camera and promised other new cameras and
Speaker 5:  I find myself so just cold
Speaker 5:  thinking about the existence of a new GoPro camera. It'll
Speaker 5:  let you film for longer. It has a new vertical video thing that's all
Speaker 5:  fine, but I just like, does anyone care about
Speaker 5:  GoPros? David,
Speaker 6:  Is this, is this Ghost Pros problem or is this your problem? You're a few
Speaker 6:  years older than you were the last time they brought out a, a brand new
Speaker 6:  phone. Oh no,
Speaker 5:  It's GoPro's problem.
Speaker 6:  You maybe are a little less, okay, maybe I am a little
Speaker 6:  less sure that I'm going to be doing anything worth filming with a
Speaker 6:  GoPro. Like, like if you just made the list of things that you can do that
Speaker 6:  are worth filming with a GoPro like maybe six years ago I had some of those
Speaker 6:  things on the list. Now it's none. It's zero. It's never gonna happen. I
Speaker 6:  think
Speaker 7:  That is the lesson of action cameras in general. When they first came out
Speaker 7:  and first were being popular, everybody thought, oh, I could be lifelogging
Speaker 7:  or filming all these crazy adventures and things like that. And then they
Speaker 7:  realized that like, I don't really do anything all that interesting and I
Speaker 7:  don't really wanna deal with all this footage and I'm not a video filmmaker
Speaker 7:  or whatever. And so what are we up to? Hero
Speaker 7:  12, the 12, the 12th GoPro at this point. Like they are
Speaker 7:  products for a specific type of filmmaker who
Speaker 7:  is using them to either capture interesting angles
Speaker 7:  or interesting activities or whatever. They're just not
Speaker 7:  general consumer products like they might have thought they would've
Speaker 7:  been five to 10 years ago. Well,
Speaker 3:  I think that I the, like the phone made it hard for them to be general consumer
Speaker 3:  product because the phone camera got, 'cause for a while there you'd be like,
Speaker 3:  okay, well I don't wanna use my phone to film this because my phone's got
Speaker 3:  a crummy camera on it, but the GoPro's got a much nicer
Speaker 3:  camera so it makes sense. And maybe one day I really will go
Speaker 3:  skiing and be able to show everybody my videos. You won't. But like you,
Speaker 3:  you could, you could rationalize that, right? And I think was it, was it
Speaker 3:  like 20 18, 20 19 where suddenly their sales just
Speaker 3:  fell off a cliff because everybody was like, I have a GoPro and I'm not
Speaker 3:  as active as you wish I was GoPro and, and like they,
Speaker 3:  they really struggled. They, they, they had a lot of issues. It was around
Speaker 3:  the same time they released their drone that just like flopped because it
Speaker 3:  was busted. Well,
Speaker 6:  They'd gotten huge. You would go to the grocery store and they'd have an
Speaker 6:  end cap for GoPro at at every Walmart in Meyer
Speaker 6:  and whatever. And I'm like, are there that many people living these action
Speaker 6:  camera lifestyles? And it turned out there weren't, I
Speaker 5:  Think, I really think GoPro thought it was like the point
Speaker 5:  and shoot camera of the future. And it, what it
Speaker 5:  seems to me is that like every year the total
Speaker 5:  addressable market of GoPro just gets a little tiny bit smaller
Speaker 5:  because it doesn't have new ideas about how you can take
Speaker 5:  photos and video. Like one of the things this time is it's easier to sync
Speaker 5:  time codes if you're shooting with a bunch of GoPros
Speaker 5:  simultaneously. And it's like, that's for 12 people. That's
Speaker 5:  that. That's the number of people who care about that. But then I guess,
Speaker 5:  I dunno, there's a guy in my neighborhood who rides a like old
Speaker 5:  Schwinn bike to the train station every morning and he like has
Speaker 5:  on, he's like wearing business casual clothes and he has his messenger bag
Speaker 5:  and he clips a GoPro to his messenger bag and just films his ride to the
Speaker 5:  train station every morning. And every time I see this man, I just wanna
Speaker 5:  stop him and be like, why? Have you ever watched any of these videos? Is
Speaker 7:  He using it as a dash cam? It's a dash cam, yes. In case he gets hit by a
Speaker 7:  car.
Speaker 3:  Oh, that's for security. Okay. Yeah, it's a dash cam. Basically GoPros
Speaker 3:  are for people who don't wanna buy a ga dash cam because the dash cam
Speaker 3:  market is super confusing and scary. I definitely don't know that from
Speaker 3:  experience or cyclists who need it. So in
Speaker 3:  case the cop like gives them a ticket for riding in the bike lane, which
Speaker 3:  happens far too often here in New York City. And then
Speaker 3:  Veen like one of our people on our video team who actually
Speaker 3:  does use it for like cool stuff. He's always like, yeah, I'm snowboarding
Speaker 3:  this weekend. And I'm like, how do you have the energy,
Speaker 6:  The Thomas Ricker experience as as we call it? Yeah,
Speaker 3:  Yeah. The Thomas Ricker experience. There's like, it's those two
Speaker 3:  and then and then the folks who need it for a dash cam. And
Speaker 3:  that's the market.
Speaker 7:  I, I mean I think it is smart. If I was GoPro and I didn't really have an
Speaker 7:  idea to reinvent this camera or the idea as I tried in the past failed 360
Speaker 7:  video or drones, whatever, I think it's smart to lean into building
Speaker 7:  these higher end features for the niche that is still using the cameras and
Speaker 7:  is still gonna go out and buy them. And we'll sync five GoPro
Speaker 7:  angles together. I
Speaker 3:  Mean it's worked for like Sony, it's worked for kind of
Speaker 3:  red, like going, going more niche does work for cameras
Speaker 3:  particular go makes sense because camera nerds
Speaker 3:  be nerding.
Speaker 5:  I think my real issue with GoPro is that we treat it kind of like a
Speaker 5:  mainstream brand and it very much is a mainstream brand. Like their
Speaker 5:  brand recognition I'm sure is ridiculous when in reality, like you
Speaker 5:  said, Cranz, it is basically, it's red, it is a specific device
Speaker 5:  for a specific use case and that's fine and
Speaker 5:  that's all well and good, but it is so not how
Speaker 5:  GoPro wants you to think about it. That the dissonance of that I think has
Speaker 5:  just always kind of annoyed me.
Speaker 3:  I think they've also struggled with that, right? Like they had a lot of leadership
Speaker 3:  changes and stuff after, after the drone because they were also realizing,
Speaker 3:  oh wait, we're, we're having this turn in our, in our
Speaker 3:  company and we're not gonna be able to survive it if we don't fix everything.
Speaker 3:  And so it feels like they have kind of leaned into, we're here for the
Speaker 3:  niche market and I, I think a lot of us are just like, like
Speaker 3:  the p the the news from us was, was written by Verin who is part
Speaker 3:  of that market, right? Like, like I think while our friends and
Speaker 3:  family might still recognize GoPro, none of them have owned them in years,
Speaker 3:  have any desire to own them in years and GoPro is probably okay with that.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I think that's probably right. Alright, well that's enough about GoPro.
Speaker 5:  That's, that's all I want to talk about GoPro in the year 2023. Couple
Speaker 5:  more things here. So Google did what we talked about
Speaker 5:  last week and assumed it's going to happen just full leak to the
Speaker 5:  Pixel eight Pro Richard. What do we learn? What do we know about the Pixel
Speaker 5:  eight pro?
Speaker 6:  It continues to be a phone. They actually today posted You know you've
Speaker 6:  probably seen this by the time you're hearing this. They posted a couple
Speaker 6:  of videos of it, of the Pixel eight Pro and the Pixel eight, which notably
Speaker 6:  the Pixel eight should be quite a bit smaller than the Pixel seven and Pixel
Speaker 6:  six. So if you like small phones, you, you have a good option
Speaker 6:  so you can actually see it. Now we've got some comparisons there. They
Speaker 6:  showed off the second watch which looks a lot like the first watch,
Speaker 6:  but it seems like that's what we're gonna kind of get at the event. Google
Speaker 6:  always leaking it stuff. We, we have, we have had the hardware specs, we've
Speaker 6:  heard stuff about the software. They haven't said too much really about what
Speaker 6:  these things do, but we can see them. We can see the camera bar. It's still
Speaker 6:  there. They've, they've got lenses, it's not folding.
Speaker 7:  It's nice to see Google making progress on
Speaker 7:  the, the length of time between when it leaks its own product and its own
Speaker 7:  event. Like we're at one month to the event. That's pretty
Speaker 7:  good. You know a couple years ago it was like they would announce
Speaker 7:  their phone in May and not not launch it till October and
Speaker 7:  they're like, yeah, we got that Pixel five coming, we showed it to you.
Speaker 3:  Gotta get ahead of that iPhone hype train like Pixel fans. Don't forget it's
Speaker 3:  coming here it is. the whole thing. Just
Speaker 3:  wait a little longer.
Speaker 5:  Richard, I'm just seeing this video you're talking about now for the first
Speaker 5:  time the Pixel eight looks small.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it's like 6.1 ish inches is is what the we're
Speaker 6:  talking about. So yeah, small phones are back and we're calling 6.1 inches
Speaker 6:  small now, which
Speaker 5:  We have agreed on this show that is the perfect size for a smartphone as
Speaker 5:  Alison Johnson will say to anyone who asks that is the
Speaker 5:  correct size of smartphone. It's so good job. Google. Yeah that's
Speaker 5:  coming October 4th. I assume we will get six or 700 more
Speaker 5:  leaks before we let you go Dan, run me
Speaker 5:  through the two Bluetooth speakers that came out this week. The
Speaker 5:  Sonos move two and the UE epic boom.
Speaker 7:  Technically one of them's not really a Bluetooth speaker but sure
Speaker 5:  That's true. Fair enough. Two needlessly expensive wireless
Speaker 5:  speakers, both of which I wanna buy anyway. So here we
Speaker 5:  are.
Speaker 7:  So I'll tell, I'll roll that back a little bit. The the Sonos Move two does
Speaker 7:  support Bluetooth but it's primarily a wifi speaker and it's an update
Speaker 7:  to Sonos first portable speaker. It's got a battery built
Speaker 7:  into it. It's basically if you took the Sonos Arab 100 and stuck a battery
Speaker 7:  on the bottom of it, the improvements over the move one
Speaker 7:  are stereo sound now because it's got multiple tweeters and
Speaker 7:  double the battery life. It's also got a slightly different design on top
Speaker 7:  with the way you adjust volume or skip tracks and it comes in
Speaker 7:  green and if you read the site, you knew all of this a
Speaker 7:  month ago because Chris Welch leaked all of it and had gotten a huge scoop
Speaker 7:  on it. So, but now it's official, now you can order it, it's 450 bucks, which
Speaker 7:  means it's 50 bucks more expensive than last time. Ah. So how it goes, the
Speaker 7:  one weird quirk is it does not support Google Assistant for voice
Speaker 7:  commands because Sonos and Google, as we know and have discussed
Speaker 7:  probably many times don't get along anymore. So voice
Speaker 7:  control is only through Amazon's assistant and Sonos
Speaker 7:  own assistant, but you cannot use Google Assistant on it. I believe that's
Speaker 7:  coming out later this month. So that's coming real soon. We'll have a review,
Speaker 7:  all that fun stuff. And then the other thing is a
Speaker 7:  solar powered Bluetooth speaker. Yeah. That you in theory never have to
Speaker 7:  charge from the company that brought us solar powered over ear
Speaker 7:  headphones. It's the same kind of concept. John Porter reported on it
Speaker 7:  from EFA out in Berlin. It's pretty neat.
Speaker 7:  'cause if I know anything about any Bluetooth speaker I've ever owned, they
Speaker 7:  end in a drawer most of the time and then they're always dead when I want
Speaker 7:  to use it. So
Speaker 3:  Yeah, it's the best part of 'em.
Speaker 5:  This thing is not attractive. It
Speaker 3:  Looks like a coaster. It
Speaker 7:  Does, yeah. I don't think it's gonna be a banger speaker. No, it's small.
Speaker 5:  But I will say a solar powered Bluetooth speaker is actually like
Speaker 5:  kind of a perfect idea because it's the sort of thing you use outside all
Speaker 5:  the time. And so in the way that most solar gadgets are like you, you
Speaker 5:  have to like go out of your way to put them in the sun. This one actually
Speaker 5:  kind of tracks, I'm very into this. The one other speaker I would
Speaker 5:  add, and this is just because I am permanently obsessed with this company,
Speaker 5:  is UE Ultima Ears just came out with a new speaker called the Epic
Speaker 5:  boom. It's like 350 bucks, it's too expensive, it's
Speaker 5:  big. Youi has kind of like lost its mind with how large a Bluetooth
Speaker 5:  speaker should be. But I continue to think they are the best series
Speaker 5:  of speakers on the market for just like regular ass
Speaker 5:  Bluetooth speakers. I have, I have a wonder Boom, I have a boom, I
Speaker 5:  have a mega boom. They're wonderful. And so I am sure I will end up buying
Speaker 5:  this.
Speaker 7:  I just love how they, each one has to like one up the name. Like they started
Speaker 7:  with Boom, which is already like a, a big like powerful name. And then
Speaker 7:  they're like, whoa, where do we go from here? Mega boom. Now we're at
Speaker 7:  epic boom. I assume the next step is ultra boom
Speaker 5:  And then Apple sues them out of existence for using the ultra
Speaker 5:  name. Yeah, no, I just, everyone should buy Youi speakers.
Speaker 5:  This is, that's how I feel about, that's how I feel about all this. Alright,
Speaker 5:  we should move on. It's time to talk about streaming. Dan, you can stay or
Speaker 5:  you can leave and we will understand. If it's time to go before Bob,
Speaker 7:  I'm gonna let you guys have fun. Thank you for having
Speaker 7:  me.
Speaker 5:  Thanks buddy. All right, Dan is gone.
Speaker 5:  It's time for Bob Talk Alex
Speaker 5:  just set the scene here a little bit. We, we have a banger of a C
Speaker 5:  N B C story this week. We have a lot of Bobs to talk
Speaker 5:  about. Catch us up here.
Speaker 3:  So a couple of years ago, Bob Iger, then c e o of
Speaker 3:  Disney said, I'm gonna leave, I'm retiring, I'm gonna stay on as
Speaker 3:  executive chairman, but otherwise I'm, I'm gonna go and I'm gonna name this
Speaker 3:  new guy Bob Chapek who used, who's been running our parks and, and run like
Speaker 3:  home video and, and seems to really know the company. He's gonna be running
Speaker 3:  things. Bob Chapek came in immediately got
Speaker 3:  like Covid happened. They had to shut down the parks, got
Speaker 3:  into a huge fight with Ron DeSantis over whether or not people could say
Speaker 3:  gay in, in Florida. Like got in a
Speaker 3:  fight with Scarlet Johanssen about being paid
Speaker 3:  appropriately for Black Widow because they moved that to have it released
Speaker 3:  on Disney Plus at the same time as theaters. All of this
Speaker 3:  stuff happened. Everybody's like, Chapek seems like kind of a clown, why
Speaker 3:  is he in charge? And then Bob Iger returned and said, Hey, I'm
Speaker 3:  here. Don't worry, I'm gonna fix everything. And it seems like he really
Speaker 3:  had, and it was like, wow, what was this huge error in judgment? Who made
Speaker 3:  the decision to put Chapek in charge? And aren't we all glad
Speaker 3:  Iger is back? And it feels like this. What we found out from the C N
Speaker 3:  B C story was it was the same person that did both of those
Speaker 3:  things. Bob Iger, good job, Bob.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I I just wanna focus on like when he left, that was right at the time
Speaker 6:  that we were all kind of reckoning with the idea that, oh, COVID iss a thing.
Speaker 6:  This is, this is happening. And like just at the very
Speaker 6:  beginning of that, BA was like, I'm out.
Speaker 3:  Just like he like was at that meme of the kid just like turning into
Speaker 3:  ghost, like just peace.
Speaker 3:  And he was gone. Well,
Speaker 5:  And the, I remember even at the time the story was
Speaker 5:  basically Bob Iger is this like Legendarily
Speaker 5:  successful c e o his run at Disney is up there with
Speaker 5:  anyone's run at any company ever. He bought Pixar, he bought
Speaker 5:  Marvel, he bought Lucasfilm, Disney was booming, everything was going really
Speaker 5:  great. And he basically saw the writing on the wall that
Speaker 5:  was C O V I D and just, just peaced
Speaker 5:  out. But, but then what seems like happened
Speaker 5:  is our man never actually left and just
Speaker 5:  continued to be like sneaky shadow c e o. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  He sold the house and kept living in the attic. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  Yeah. He didn't even keep living in the attic. He kept living in the master
Speaker 3:  bedroom. He was like, this is not your, your private bathroom. This is
Speaker 3:  mine. But don't worry, you can have the run of the house. You've got everything,
Speaker 3:  but you need to talk to me every day. And if you don't continue to kiss my
Speaker 3:  ring, then I'm gonna be really upset. And then eventually you're gonna get
Speaker 3:  kicked out. Like this, this story from from Alex Sherman at C N
Speaker 3:  B C is just incredible because it is full of like Emma,
Speaker 3:  Emma for, for us rounded up all the petty moments in it because there
Speaker 3:  are so many petty moments. And what it all boils down to is if
Speaker 3:  you are ever in a position where the c e o of the company comes to you and
Speaker 3:  says, I'm gonna promote you to be c e o, but I am gonna be sticking
Speaker 3:  around as executive chairman and I'm not giving you my office, but it's
Speaker 3:  totally okay, you are in charge. Do not believe them.
Speaker 5:  Run. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Run. Don't take that as a bad job to take. And and that's
Speaker 3:  what happened. Like he took this job. Iger was micromanaging, he was in things,
Speaker 3:  Chapek was by no means like a saint in all of this. He, he
Speaker 3:  definitely screwed up quite frequently. He didn't know how to handle
Speaker 3:  talent, but we found out like the Scarlett Johanssen thing, we all thought
Speaker 3:  it was Chapek just blundering through because he doesn't know how to handle
Speaker 3:  talent. And it turns out he thought Iger was gonna do it
Speaker 3:  and Iger was like, no, no, no, I'm not gonna tell him I'm not gonna do it,
Speaker 3:  but I'm also not gonna do anything. And and then be like, why did you
Speaker 3:  fail Bob? What, what happened? It was just a lot of
Speaker 3:  moments like that where he'd be like, I got you, I got you. And then leave
Speaker 3:  Chapek out to dry and you're like, oh
Speaker 3:  buddy. Rough.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. He really just kept showing up at
Speaker 5:  every moment. There was like anytime somebody was to sort of collect an
Speaker 5:  award or like shake hands for doing a great job. Like there's Bob Iger in
Speaker 5:  a pressed white shirt doing so looking great. And anytime there was like
Speaker 5:  actual running of the company to do Iger was just nowhere to be found.
Speaker 6:  No, I'm I'm only here for the fun stuff. Yeah. He, he said, I I'm, I'm the
Speaker 6:  fun dad. And Chapek is the, the dad who
Speaker 6:  tells you that you can't go to spring break this year because of Covid.
Speaker 6:  Sorry.
Speaker 5:  I mean, and truly some of this stuff is like straight out of succession.
Speaker 5:  Like the metaphor about not leaving the house is like barely a
Speaker 5:  metaphor because one of the things in the story was that Iger
Speaker 5:  kept his office with a private bathroom and
Speaker 5:  made Chapek have a worse office. So like the
Speaker 5:  CEO's office was just Iger so that he could like shower in the
Speaker 5:  mornings and he
Speaker 3:  Was like, you don't want this, you don't like, like the, the story. They're
Speaker 3:  like, yeah. And then he was like, You know you don't need this office, this
Speaker 3:  don't worry. This is for handling talent. You don't do that. Don't worry.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And then Iger is like running around behind the scenes
Speaker 5:  tr like undermining Chapek to other executives. He didn't say his
Speaker 5:  name and his goodbye party. It's like all this stuff would be so
Speaker 5:  like petty and ridiculous if it wasn't like two of the most powerful people
Speaker 5:  in entertainment just publicly beefing with each other inside of their own
Speaker 5:  company. It's all so ridiculous.
Speaker 3:  The part where he, he finally says, I'm leaving as, as
Speaker 3:  I'm gone. I, I've given you the reins Chapek, I'm gonna go sit over
Speaker 3:  here next to my friend Steven Spielberg. You're gonna sit at the opposite
Speaker 3:  end of the table. And I am not gonna mention you
Speaker 3:  once when like just the
Speaker 3:  that's mean man. That's like Cole, I I absolutely
Speaker 3:  respect it. Bob Iger now terrifies me completely, but
Speaker 3:  like, oh, that was good. Poor Bob. I feel
Speaker 3:  poor Bob, you don't even know which Bob I'm talking about.
Speaker 5:  No, Bob looks good in this story. All the bobs lose. What's
Speaker 3:  Funny is the same thing kind of happened. So when Michael Eisner, who was
Speaker 3:  the c e o before Iger and he
Speaker 3:  originally came on and everybody was like, oh wow, he's gonna change the
Speaker 3:  whole thing. He was brought in by, by, by these guys, these investors in
Speaker 3:  the eighties and everybody was like, wow, he's gonna change Disney. And he
Speaker 3:  did not change Disney. And then he was like, I'm gonna name my own
Speaker 3:  successor who's gonna happen to have the exact same first name as me and
Speaker 3:  I'm gonna do exactly what Bob Iger would end up doing. And everybody at the
Speaker 3:  time was like, you cannot do that. You're dumb and we
Speaker 3:  all hate you. Please leave Michael Eisner as quickly as possible. And Bob
Speaker 3:  got to get got away with it because Bob Iger is so much
Speaker 3:  more charming and everybody's like, he got, he got us Marvel, he got
Speaker 3:  us Lucas Arts like, do whatever you want,
Speaker 3:  Bob. You want three more offices, we'll build them. That didn't happen in
Speaker 3:  the story, but I assume that's happening somewhere right now.
Speaker 5:  But now he's back, he just signed another contract to be
Speaker 5:  Disney, c e o through 2026. He has claimed he
Speaker 5:  will have his actual
Speaker 5:  successor You know solved by then. But I kind of feel like
Speaker 5:  Bob Iger is like in the middle of just ruining his own
Speaker 5:  reputation. Like he truly went out like a
Speaker 5:  plus c e o, like Mount Rushmore of good
Speaker 5:  entertainment business, CEOs Bob Iger. And I feel like now is
Speaker 5:  just like speed running his own demise in a lot of ways. He's
Speaker 3:  Pulling what was, there's the football player who just keeps
Speaker 6:  Going. Well I think the, the comparison is Jordan on the Wizards and, and
Speaker 6:  I think in a very, in a very specific way is that Jordan on the Wizards is
Speaker 6:  not Jordan on the Bulls for a lot of reasons, but Jordan on the Wizards is
Speaker 6:  still like 25 and eight and like still an all star
Speaker 6:  level player. And Bob Iger is still Bob Iger doing his his
Speaker 6:  things, but it's just not like it was before. He, you you, you're never
Speaker 6:  gonna go out on top with three pointer at the end of the game to win the
Speaker 6:  championship. It just does not happen again. Now you're the guy who's gonna
Speaker 6:  have to try and figure out a way to launch standalone E S P N and probably
Speaker 6:  sell Disney's cable channels and dismantle the whole thing that you built.
Speaker 6:  Congratulations.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Like retire Bob. But just, just let it go.
Speaker 3:  Let somebody else pick your successor because that, that was the other wild
Speaker 3:  part of this is that he didn't actually know Bob Chapek very well. He,
Speaker 3:  he, there was other people that they thought were were gonna be the next
Speaker 3:  c e o including the guy who was running Disney Plus. And everybody's like,
Speaker 3:  oh yeah, it's gonna be him. And so when he was announced Bob Chapek, everybody's
Speaker 3:  like, wait, the guy who runs parks, like that's
Speaker 3:  who you're going with. And then even he was realizing,
Speaker 3:  wait, who am I going with? 'cause he like had Bob, he was like, okay, we're
Speaker 3:  gonna fly down to this big meeting shareholder meeting. You're gonna talk
Speaker 3:  to a bunch of execs and stuff. It's gonna be great. You've never done it
Speaker 3:  before. The only time you've ever attended this event was at the invitation
Speaker 3:  of someone else and you sat in the audience, you're now gonna run the
Speaker 3:  entire thing. Why do you wanna go to the back and study and
Speaker 3:  read everything when you can just sit here and talk to me and I'll explain
Speaker 3:  to you how to do it all. And he got really upset because Chapek was like,
Speaker 3:  I'm gonna go study because Chapek is that kind of guy. And I think a lot
Speaker 3:  of people would be in that situation and Iger was like, but I am a font
Speaker 3:  of wisdom. Why do you not listen to me? And then he
Speaker 3:  like, after Chapek went back to study was like walking around the plane being
Speaker 3:  like, who is this guy? Like doesn't he get it?
Speaker 3:  And it's like, oh, you shouldn't be asking that question at this point in
Speaker 3:  the game.
Speaker 6:  He hired a nerd and then he was surprised that the nerd trusted the book
Speaker 6:  instead of the person.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Like
Speaker 6:  Could have told you that was gonna happen buddy.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Yeah. It was one of those things where it just feels like
Speaker 3:  Iger ego caught up.
Speaker 5:  What's interesting about this is this is a really consistent
Speaker 5:  story in the world. Like the number of CEOs who
Speaker 5:  have tried in various ways to detach and
Speaker 5:  then have found themselves unable to go away. I mean like this is the
Speaker 5:  story of Larry Page and Sergey Bryn who like
Speaker 5:  want to go away and just like be weird billionaires, but then every time
Speaker 5:  anything happens they're like, we have to start coming to the office again.
Speaker 5:  And like Mark Zuckerberg was starting to detach from a lot of day-to-day
Speaker 5:  running of Meta and then came way back in. It's really given me like
Speaker 5:  great respect for Jeff Bezos who just was like, Andy Chassis's in charge,
Speaker 5:  I'm gonna go to music festivals. And is just like, now he just goes to music
Speaker 5:  festivals, he's and has a yacht like he's doing it right and everybody else
Speaker 5:  should probably learn from Bezos.
Speaker 3:  I I hope Tim Cook re like, 'cause Tim Cook is coming up. We, we we're,
Speaker 3:  we're increasingly talking about who's gonna be the next c e o of Apple.
Speaker 3:  He's, he's starting to like make those noises. It's gonna happen in the next
Speaker 3:  few years and he just needs to read this story like four
Speaker 3:  times in a row to make sure this doesn't happen to him. Because
Speaker 3:  it's similar situation of this is one of the first CEOs coming
Speaker 3:  into a company that has largely been like managed by people who came up
Speaker 3:  with the company. And that makes it really, really
Speaker 3:  difficult. And so I'm just really, really curious
Speaker 3:  to see how we see some of these tech CEO e successions that are coming,
Speaker 3:  that are on the horizon happen after this Just disastrous
Speaker 3:  Disney one. Totally.
Speaker 5:  So is there a, do we have a leader in the Clubhouse for who would be
Speaker 5:  insane enough to be the next Disney c e o? Like part of me wants to
Speaker 5:  say no one in their right mind would be Bob
Speaker 5:  Iger next successor. Like it's, it's just a suicide mission. But then
Speaker 5:  like whatever Lindy Aino took the job as c e o of Twitter. Like
Speaker 5:  people will take jobs.
Speaker 3:  There's always someone hungry enough. Yeah. Like call me up. I, if somebody
Speaker 3:  called me today and was like, do you wanna be the next c e o of Disney? I'd
Speaker 3:  be like, yeah, all right, let's go. You get
Speaker 6:  To go to the parks for free, right? I'm in.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I was like, I get to go to the parks for free and do I get screeners
Speaker 3:  done? Cheapest. C e o they ever hired,
Speaker 5:  That's how You know you're qualified screeners and park passes. That's the,
Speaker 5:  that's the corporate perks Cranz is here for.
Speaker 6:  But that seems like that's how he picked Bob Chapek. He looked around and
Speaker 6:  he f and he found a guy, he was like, You know what? I think you're desperate
Speaker 6:  enough that you will not be independent. You will just do what I wanna
Speaker 6:  do. And he was wrong. Yep. And that was what made him
Speaker 6:  unhappy. That
Speaker 3:  Was the best part of it is like he really thought he was gonna just get a
Speaker 3:  yes man and not somebody who would actually go run the company in their image.
Speaker 3:  And then the guy immediately went and was like, I'm gonna turn, we're a tech
Speaker 3:  company, we have an enormous streaming service, I'm turning us into a tech
Speaker 3:  company. And everybody screamed and cried. Chapek to his
Speaker 3:  discredit did also put his old friend in charge
Speaker 3:  of all film and TV at the company. And the guy had zero
Speaker 3:  experience in that space. So like he was by no
Speaker 3:  means a saint. He he was definitely screwing up his fair
Speaker 3:  share of things without Iger intervention one way or the other. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  But he was also just being like subtly knifed every time he
Speaker 5:  did anything. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Like every time he like that was probably why he put that guy in charge is
Speaker 3:  he felt he had no one to trust, he had no authority. He was like, I
Speaker 3:  need some control. And so it just became this big power struggle.
Speaker 5:  I need someone to sit with in the executive dining room. He
Speaker 3:  Needed friends at the Iger going away party who would talk to him. Okay.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, exactly. Like, because Scar Joe wasn't going to,
Speaker 5:  This is true. Alright, we should just, we should blow through some more streaming
Speaker 5:  news here real fast. Can we just pour one out really fast for Quibi again,
Speaker 5:  which appears to be yet again
Speaker 5:  dead Roku did some layoffs and is
Speaker 5:  getting rid of a bunch of its streaming content, which in all likelihood
Speaker 5:  means Quibi shows.
Speaker 3:  I'm gonna miss the Gold Arms show.
Speaker 6:  Maybe some of them, and not all of them, the, the Gold Arm probably had it
Speaker 6:  for the chopping block, but there was a story by a variety today where they
Speaker 6:  said that they had some sources of whatever who said that the shows that
Speaker 6:  are getting chopped are the ones that weren't bringing in that like new subscribers
Speaker 6:  weren't watching. So stuff like the Kevin Hart show might stick around
Speaker 6:  or or other stuff that actually brought in that brought in some new viewers
Speaker 6:  is it's the the the long tail stuff that that's definitely going. So yeah,
Speaker 6:  quibi dies a thousand deaths.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. You can't, you can't fully kill Quibi because Quibi was never
Speaker 5:  fully alive You know what I mean? It's Yeah. But you
Speaker 3:  Can kill it repeatedly.
Speaker 5:  Right? You can, you can stab it over and over and over again.
Speaker 5:  YouTube is doing some interesting stuff.
Speaker 3:  The advertising stuff that YouTube is doing right now is interesting 'cause
Speaker 3:  it sounds like they just rediscovered tv.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Wait, get walk us through this. 'cause that was my read too. It's like,
Speaker 5:  oh, YouTube is just going to be a television channel, but like, explain what's
Speaker 5:  going on. YouTube
Speaker 3:  Is now experimenting with a longer block of
Speaker 3:  advertising in the middle of the video you watch rather than
Speaker 3:  like You know 15 second ads half cutting up the
Speaker 3:  video or one big ad at the beginning. And if you will recall, if you
Speaker 3:  are a person who still watches TV or have seen or TV
Speaker 3:  on TikTok, that ads happen
Speaker 3:  in the middle and we have ad breaks and that's when you go to the bathroom
Speaker 3:  and get more water and see how fast you can run. And,
Speaker 3:  and YouTube I guess is doing that. I love it. I, it just cracks
Speaker 3:  me up that YouTube was like, we did a whole bunch of research and,
Speaker 3:  and we, like, we looked at the data and apparently people
Speaker 3:  like regular scheduled breaks for advertisements
Speaker 3:  rather than chaotic random moments for
Speaker 3:  advertisements.
Speaker 5:  Who would've thunk knew
Speaker 3:  Who would've thought,
Speaker 6:  Except for everyone who has ever watched tv. The other thing that they announced
Speaker 6:  basically on the same day was that they are simplifying ad controls for
Speaker 6:  creators a k a, they're taking away a bunch of the options that creators
Speaker 6:  had for like placing where the ads would go in their videos, which does not
Speaker 6:  seem to be the same thing as this, but seems very closely linked because
Speaker 6:  it came at the exact same time and enables them to put the ads at regular
Speaker 6:  intervals wherever they want and not let you the person making the video
Speaker 6:  choose. So you're just gonna have to get used to it. You're gonna have to
Speaker 6:  get used to that like 18 minute t You know TV show. Oh, I
Speaker 6:  know when the ad is coming up. I know when the plot point in my three camera
Speaker 6:  drama is coming up because the advert, the ad is about to come in.
Speaker 3:  It's gonna be right now, it's gonna be like in a MrBeast video right before
Speaker 3:  the big reveal. It's gonna be a hold, do
Speaker 3:  you take Nutria or whatever, like just
Speaker 3:  right there. Just what, and it's gonna be great. And I think it, honestly,
Speaker 3:  I think that's great. Like it's super annoying when you're watching a
Speaker 3:  show on YouTube or on a lot of the streaming services who are doing the
Speaker 3:  exact same ad presentation that YouTube does where it's just like suddenly
Speaker 3:  in the middle. Like somebody would be like, I don't love, Hey
Speaker 3:  guys, do you need this? And you're like, what the hell are you? Like, pick
Speaker 3:  your moments. And TV was really good at picking those moments, even for
Speaker 3:  stuff that wasn't built for tv, they were still good at being like, okay,
Speaker 3:  we're gonna cut it, we're gonna take it at the right ad break right moment.
Speaker 3:  And it's like, yeah, every, you should all be doing that. Like, just tell
Speaker 3:  me where I need to put the ad break in my YouTube video. When I upload it,
Speaker 3:  I'll tell you where I want it. You put 40 minutes of ads in
Speaker 3:  there, you make money. I make money and the audience gets a nice
Speaker 3:  bathroom break
Speaker 6:  When, when I press play, I know when I'm going to be able to get up and and
Speaker 6:  do something else for a sec.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I I think that's like for for users it's really
Speaker 3:  good. You know you still have to watch ads. That sucks. But like for the
Speaker 3:  user, it's, it's, I think it's a much nicer experience and I hope
Speaker 3:  that the other streamers who are all experimenting like Netflix, come on
Speaker 3:  man, you gotta, you gotta get on this ad train and not just deliver 'em at
Speaker 3:  the most random moments possible because it's miserable, but it's gonna require
Speaker 3:  work. And I think it's like that's something that they typically shy away
Speaker 3:  from, right? Like they wanna avoid that labor. That's, that's why they're
Speaker 3:  there and not on TV and film. And so that, that
Speaker 3:  additional work, it's gonna be interesting to see who does that and how they
Speaker 3:  do it and how expensive it actually is.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I do wonder like we, we talk a lot about how these sort of platform
Speaker 5:  incentives change the way that content gets made. I suspect this is gonna
Speaker 5:  do that too. Like I think Richard what you were saying earlier is, is
Speaker 5:  like absolutely going to be correct that now if
Speaker 5:  there's one big mid-roll ad
Speaker 5:  or one set of mid-roll ads, what you as the creator have to
Speaker 5:  do now is set it up so spectacularly well that I
Speaker 5:  have no choice but to stick around through five minutes of ads in order to
Speaker 5:  get to the second half of the video. Because that's how you get paid. That's
Speaker 5:  how YouTube gets paid. That's how you juice the algorithm. Like the
Speaker 5:  cliffhanger stuff we're gonna start to see from people just to
Speaker 5:  get you through the ad break is gonna be so, so, so
Speaker 5:  intense. And it really is. It's very like 1990s
Speaker 5:  sitcom and Action Network TV show.
Speaker 5:  Like there's just gonna be something bonkers that
Speaker 5:  happens after eight minutes and then like
Speaker 5:  somebody's gonna be like, you're his father and then it's gonna be like
Speaker 5:  breaks.
Speaker 3:  I want that like soap opera, dun dun, like literally
Speaker 5:  Like that's, I think that's coming, yes, because it's, it's gonna be
Speaker 5:  so hard to get people through that, but that's where all the money is gonna
Speaker 5:  be, is in that middle ad break. Whereas now there's the You know, the, the
Speaker 5:  pre-roll stuff gets you some of the way and the mid-roll stuff happens at
Speaker 5:  these dynamic places. And so you can 15 seconds at a time, it's a little
Speaker 5:  easier to get people through, but it's like a five minute ad break or a two
Speaker 5:  minute ad break or even like a 92nd ad break in the middle of a YouTube
Speaker 5:  video is just an invitation to stop watching that YouTube video. And
Speaker 5:  so I think what folks try to do to get you through that is just gonna be
Speaker 5:  weird and fascinating.
Speaker 3:  I think it's gonna be also interesting for those of us who, like you sit
Speaker 3:  in bed and you're watching YouTube wind it down at night, even though you
Speaker 3:  should not be doing that, that's a terrible way to wind down. But you're
Speaker 3:  still doing it and you're like, oh, I gotta go to like go grab some more
Speaker 3:  water or something. I gotta go to like, I need to go do a, a little errand
Speaker 3:  right before I go to sleep. And now you'll be like, oh, ad break. Fling
Speaker 3:  your iPad across the, the bed, rush up and get your water, do your bed, like
Speaker 3:  brush your teeth, get it all done and then you're back and you can finish
Speaker 3:  watching your video. That sounds great. And you find out who is the father.
Speaker 3:  Hopefully
Speaker 5:  Every YouTube channel just becomes about who is the father. It's
Speaker 3:  Just mor ve every, it's just mor ve well
Speaker 6:  Be And I think that's the other part of it is not only do they need to have
Speaker 6:  kind of the the cliffhanger, but they also have to have the part leading
Speaker 6:  up. Like they have to have a video that you don't want to just skip through.
Speaker 6:  Like you have to watch the first, you have to want to watch the first five
Speaker 6:  minutes or however many until the break and then, and then stick around.
Speaker 6:  And that's just gonna be kind of a, a very different construction.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I wonder if that like that kind of style of YouTube
Speaker 3:  videos now where it's constantly going, constantly pushing because it has
Speaker 3:  to get you through all those tiny little 15 second ad breaks if that's gonna
Speaker 3:  soften. 'cause that pace is so frenetic and you're seeing like a whole
Speaker 3:  generation of people coming up and that's the pacing they're used to,
Speaker 3:  to the point where they're like, people talk too slow and stuff like that.
Speaker 3:  And I wonder if we're gonna, if that's gonna stop, if instead
Speaker 3:  like 40 years from now we're gonna be like, man generation alpha talks so
Speaker 3:  fast, what's up with that? We're all back in the, today they had 15 and
Speaker 3:  second ad breaks every two minutes.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And they're all watching videos at like 1.5 x speed. So they just learn
Speaker 5:  that that's how people talk. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. It's, and everybody else is gonna be like normal and these guys are
Speaker 3:  gonna be like, this is normal. Right. We're fine. That's my generation alpha
Speaker 3:  voice.
Speaker 5:  That was really good. And they're all holding a screen apparently, which
Speaker 5:  I liked.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, apparently. Well because the, the head, the headsets didn't take
Speaker 3:  off. I'm sorry. I'm sorry Tim.
Speaker 6:  Another part of what's changing is the way that these controls happen and
Speaker 6:  when you have these dynamically inserted ads, like the people who direct
Speaker 6:  these videos who are used to laying out the different pacing and where the
Speaker 6:  things go now, they don't necessarily have as much control over where the
Speaker 6:  ads pop up. So they're handing over control over to YouTube maybe
Speaker 6:  depending on the length, maybe depending on what ads YouTube has sold.
Speaker 6:  And they're gonna have to edit and direct these videos and then hope
Speaker 6:  that YouTube picks the right points that everything works out properly. So
Speaker 6:  they're
Speaker 3:  Gonna do like the cliffhanger and then they might get the cliffhanger
Speaker 3:  spoiled and then cut to ad break because it was
Speaker 3:  like two seconds too long and the algorithm was like, no, no,
Speaker 3:  no, no, it's gotta go here. Ooh, that's brutal. That's
Speaker 3:  brutal. Never. That's that's gonna make it rough. That's that's bad YouTube
Speaker 3:  don't do that. Yeah. I, I feel like that's a big tweak. Like
Speaker 3:  just tell people where their ad bricks are gonna go. Let them insert them
Speaker 3:  or
Speaker 5:  Let people choose. Right. You can, you can, right. Yeah. Build your own structure
Speaker 5:  if you have three or four ads and you can choose where they go as opposed
Speaker 5:  to just saying right in the middle there's going to be a large ad break,
Speaker 5:  build your whole thing around that. So it's like you only have sort of one
Speaker 5:  shape of thing you're allowed to make at that point. I do wonder if this
Speaker 5:  is gonna make people come up with lots of different new
Speaker 5:  ways of making money. I think a lot of these folks have, I mean
Speaker 5:  everybody still does the like branded videos and they'll have the one chapter
Speaker 5:  in their video. That's just where they talk about how cool their sponsor
Speaker 5:  is. It's particularly big on tech. YouTube has been my experience at least
Speaker 5:  where they're like, this video is brought to you by Skillshare. 'cause it's
Speaker 5:  always Skillshare and then they go back to telling you about You know whatever
Speaker 5:  weird stuff they brought on Temu this week. But maybe like, this is
Speaker 5:  how product placement comes in in an even bigger way. Maybe there are other
Speaker 5:  kinds of like built-in ad formats that people are gonna start to use. It's
Speaker 5:  gonna be really interesting to see how this goes. Also,
Speaker 5:  this continues to make me glad that I pay for YouTube premium because
Speaker 5:  ads are a nightmare and YouTube ads are a
Speaker 5:  particularly pernicious nightmare.
Speaker 3:  I didn't know I paid for YouTube premium for years 'cause I paid through
Speaker 3:  it through the weirdest of things. Google music.
Speaker 3:  Like I, I was a Google Music subscriber. There are
Speaker 6:  Dozens of
Speaker 3:  Us. Yeah, there were. It's just me and Richard just hanging out, share
Speaker 3:  the same two songs over and over again. We
Speaker 6:  Have comments now. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  I thought they closed Google Music
Speaker 6:  Or Well, on YouTube music.
Speaker 3:  Okay. Yeah. I didn't, I I I couldn't stand the switch. So when it was switched
Speaker 3:  over to YouTube music, I was like, I'm done. It's Google Music or nothing.
Speaker 3:  And, and I canceled it and then I was like, where did all these ads come
Speaker 3:  from on YouTube for like a full week. I was like, something's going on with
Speaker 3:  the algorithm. I'm seeing a lot more ads. No, I'm just down every
Speaker 6:  Time I open a YouTube video in the wrong window, I'm like, what
Speaker 6:  Advertisements
Speaker 5:  Awful.
Speaker 6:  They put these on YouTube. It,
Speaker 5:  It's crazy. I swear YouTube Premium gets like a dollar more expensive
Speaker 5:  every two weeks and I, I don't know what the number is, but I'll stop paying
Speaker 5:  it, but I'm still paying it now. I
Speaker 3:  Don't want you to find that number.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I don't either. Yeah. You two, please stop. I don't, I'm good. I
Speaker 5:  pay you enough money. We're we're cool. Alright, we gotta take one more break
Speaker 5:  and then we're gonna come back. We're gonna do a lightning round. We're already
Speaker 5:  long. We're gonna come back. We're gonna do lightning rounds then we'll get
Speaker 5:  outta here. We'll be right
Speaker 5:  back.
Speaker 2:  Alright,
Speaker 5:  We're back you guys. We have to do this lightning run really fast because
Speaker 5:  I have to go do daycare pickup. That's just a real thing. And if I'm late
Speaker 5:  they charge me money. It's very intense. We
Speaker 3:  We don't want that. We
Speaker 5:  Don't want that. No. So we're just gonna blast through this and get outta
Speaker 5:  here. Cranz, your lightning round choice happens to be a perfect transition
Speaker 5:  from what we were just talking about. So you go first. Yes.
Speaker 3:  Favorite thing. I'm talking about MrBeast all the time now because my godsons
Speaker 3:  are both really, really into him and I have very strong conflicted feelings
Speaker 3:  about that and spent a lot of time telling his mom, sending her like hit
Speaker 3:  pieces about MrBeast saying don't do it. But anyway, MrBeast has
Speaker 3:  a new YouTube face because he started doing AB
Speaker 3:  testing for the thumbnails and found that more people finished the
Speaker 3:  video when he closed his mouth in the thumbnail.
Speaker 3:  And I guess that's how statistics work. That's how he is treated.
Speaker 3:  Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Like I was just gonna say, is this science, this
Speaker 3:  Is one of those things where normally you would be like, that sounds like
Speaker 3:  a bad reason to do that. That is probably not the actual factor. But
Speaker 3:  notable here is MrBeast is really, really, really, really, really good
Speaker 3:  at juicing the algorithm, the YouTube algorithm. That is why he is like
Speaker 3:  the most popular YouTuber. He knows how to make that thing tick.
Speaker 3:  So he is probably like, he probably is onto something and we're probably
Speaker 3:  gonna see a lot less just wide mouth open
Speaker 3:  on YouTube. And I for 1:00 AM thrilled. So wait,
Speaker 3:  MrBeast, whatever you think about him. Great job. I've
Speaker 6:  Definitely seen the inside of enough people's mouths in YouTube thumbnails.
Speaker 3:  It just, you don't need the tonsils. Like just No, I don't need it. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  'cause there is, I mean everybody knows what you mean by YouTube face, right?
Speaker 5:  Like I, I can close my eyes and see it. It's the person in that
Speaker 5:  sort of like half smile, half scream face all the time.
Speaker 3:  You'll see us on The Vergecast sometimes, like when they do our art thumbnails.
Speaker 3:  You'll even see I'm doing it right now. You're gonna see it if you watch
Speaker 3:  it on YouTube.
Speaker 5:  It's either that or the furrowed brow where you're kind of like, Hmm, what
Speaker 5:  is this? That's the other YouTube face. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  They're great. So I hope we, we've moved slowly away from
Speaker 3:  that. Maybe we don't need extreme distorted faces to sell a YouTube video.
Speaker 3:  That'd be nice. That's my, that's my hope. We'll
Speaker 5:  See. I am forever fascinated by the like art and science of YouTube
Speaker 5:  thumbnails. Like in terms of things that directly correlate to
Speaker 5:  how much money you make. YouTube thumbnails are about as direct as it gets
Speaker 5:  on the internet and the things people do to build good
Speaker 5:  thumbnails and make them work is just bananas. And
Speaker 3:  They're so horrifying.
Speaker 5:  And you are right that like no one is better at solving this system
Speaker 5:  than MrBeast. So I'm, I'm more inclined to believe him than most, I guess.
Speaker 3:  And he seems very happy about it. He's, he's so happy that like he's gonna
Speaker 3:  have to brush his teeth more but he's not gonna have to show you his
Speaker 5:  Tonsils. Right. He's happy in like a closed mouth way, not an open mouthed
Speaker 5:  way. Yeah. Yeah. Just
Speaker 3:  Like back row smile. Exactly.
Speaker 5:  I'll go next and then Richard you can go My lightning round thing. Do you
Speaker 5:  guys remember the app Clubhouse?
Speaker 3:  Yes.
Speaker 5:  Did You know before this week that Clubhouse was still in business? Be honest.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, because periodically I check on it. Why? Just to be like you still
Speaker 3:  around because I would just wanna know. I, I like it can't still be around.
Speaker 3:  And so periodically, like three weeks ago I was like, Clubhouse. Oh
Speaker 3:  yeah. It's still there.
Speaker 5:  Just like what are the crypto Bross talking about today? Yeah. I'm
Speaker 6:  On Clubhouse every day selling my NFTs. Never stopped, never, never left,
Speaker 6:  never gave up on Clubhouse. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Richard's Clubhouse room is bumping y'all. It's
Speaker 5:  just, oh God. I have, I I have a whole music design for your Clubhouse room.
Speaker 5:  Richard. We got big plants. It's gonna be amazing. So anyway, so Clubhouse
Speaker 5:  just did a huge like pivot and redesign completely changed the
Speaker 5:  app instead of being the kind of public streaming
Speaker 5:  audio room, I guess is how I would describe it. It was like, what if
Speaker 5:  Twitch but audio sort of
Speaker 3:  That feels right and no games, nothing to watch.
Speaker 5:  Right? And all it was was people yelling about their NFTs and that was the
Speaker 5:  best case scenario anyway. Now Clubhouse us all in on voice
Speaker 5:  messaging. And so they've like built a bunch of tools where you can one
Speaker 5:  to one or in groups just send voice messages to your
Speaker 5:  friends. And I happen to think like in the abstract, this
Speaker 5:  is a very good idea. I've been like banging the drum that voice messaging
Speaker 5:  is a good idea for a long time and history is proving me right? And I feel
Speaker 5:  very vindicated about it, but I kind of think it's too late
Speaker 5:  for Clubhouse. I sort of hope I'm wrong. 'cause I think like the arc of that
Speaker 5:  company would be fascinating if it figured it out and came back. But I
Speaker 5:  just think like kudos to Clubhouse for being like, okay, we, we built an
Speaker 5:  audio app that everybody was into for three days when they had to be inside
Speaker 5:  and then instantly forgot about when they were allowed to go outdoors again.
Speaker 5:  And we're gonna find a new thing to do with it that actually feels kind of
Speaker 5:  honest and on brand with what we wanna be about. And the app
Speaker 5:  is actually really nice. Again, I don't know anyone who uses it. None of
Speaker 5:  my friends are there to listen to my voice messages. I must
Speaker 3:  Be like, is it?
Speaker 5:  But it's like as, just as a pure piece of like product design. It's really
Speaker 5:  nice. They did a good job. It looks nice. I will say, I don't like that you
Speaker 5:  hit the record button and then as soon as you stop it sends the message.
Speaker 5:  No, no,
Speaker 3:  No, no,
Speaker 5:  No. Anyone who's ever edited this podcast can tell you that that's not how
Speaker 5:  I roll.
Speaker 6:  The redesigned app I think is perfect for a
Speaker 6:  post-apocalyptic video game where you're experiencing the story through audio
Speaker 6:  logs that people left and they were all chatting in Clubhouse, leaving messages
Speaker 6:  for each other. Otherwise, I don't think I'm gonna use a specific app for
Speaker 6:  this. It's gonna be a feature that Facebook or whoever is gonna steal and
Speaker 6:  it's gonna be built into their apps just like they steal everything else.
Speaker 6:  So congratulations Clubhouse, but I don't think it's gonna do it. Have
Speaker 5:  You ever heard of the app Run Zombies? Yes.
Speaker 6:  Yes.
Speaker 5:  So
Speaker 3:  I tried it once.
Speaker 5:  Run Zombies was the most committed I have ever been to a
Speaker 5:  fitness app. Because basically the idea is you're a
Speaker 5:  runner who is trying to keep people alive in their
Speaker 5:  zombies. And when you run it just like tells you an audio story and you hear
Speaker 5:  messages from other people and you're running and then it says zombies and
Speaker 5:  then you run faster. It sounds ridiculous, but like it actually kind of works.
Speaker 5:  And Richard it is precisely what you just described. Like Clubhouse is
Speaker 5:  just what's happening in your brain in run Zombies only
Speaker 3:  Hopefully less depressing. Run zombies was too depressing for me. I was like,
Speaker 3:  I don't wanna run anymore.
Speaker 5:  Well if you're not running from zombies, what's the So you were just like,
Speaker 5:  just let the zombies take me. I don't care anymore.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I was like, it's okay. It's, there's what's left in the world. Why
Speaker 3:  should I jog Jogging's
Speaker 5:  Horrible. Death first. Death first. I actually, I I feel
Speaker 5:  that. All right. Richard, what's yours? Bunch
Speaker 6:  Of Chrome news this week. Like, like we're at like 15 years of
Speaker 6:  Chrome. So, so really good timing for them to change some things. they said
Speaker 6:  they're gonna be changing up the look a little bit, so pretty soon as always
Speaker 6:  with Google, you never really know when things are gonna hit. They're gonna
Speaker 6:  roll out to some people sooner, some people later. But we'll see some new,
Speaker 5:  They're rounding the corners. Google's rounding all the corners. Now
Speaker 6:  The corners are, are getting bumped. They're, they're gonna be round rounder.
Speaker 6:  The color palettes will be kind of more like you've seen on
Speaker 6:  Android. Like if, if you have seen Android in the last couple of years, you've
Speaker 6:  seen what Chrome will look like. Yep. With this material, you,
Speaker 5:  It looks nice. The material use stuff is nice into it. Yeah. I I
Speaker 6:  I like it. I think it'll be good across different devices. They also have
Speaker 6:  said it's a Privacy Sandbox that's supposed to replace third party cookies
Speaker 6:  has reached a, a milestone. It is now generally available. You've probably
Speaker 6:  gotten the popup that says, Hey, we're doing some Privacy stuff. And then
Speaker 6:  you clicked the button to make it go away and didn't think about it. If that
Speaker 6:  creeps you out. Some people have said that they feel like it's spyware in
Speaker 6:  the browser. Is it more private? Is it more control?
Speaker 6:  Depends on who you ask. But we have some instructions on how to disable it
Speaker 6:  if you wanna opt out of it. The new targeted ad tracking, Barbara
Speaker 6:  Krasnoff has the instructions for you to, to go ahead and turn that off.
Speaker 5:  That pop-up made a lot of people feel a lot of feelings and
Speaker 5:  it's a weird one, right? I'm, I'm genuinely torn on this because like I've
Speaker 5:  reached a point with all kind of browser data of just total
Speaker 5:  nihilism that it's like I'm in Chrome. Google already knows
Speaker 5:  what I'm doing in Chrome. That's not complicated. And You know who
Speaker 5:  else knows. What I'm doing in my browser is the millions of data
Speaker 5:  brokers who are just collecting and buying and selling data about
Speaker 5:  everything I do in the browser anyway. And in a lot of ways what Chrome is
Speaker 5:  doing and what Google is doing with this Privacy Sandbox stuff is designed
Speaker 5:  to combat some of that. And it combats it by saying no one is allowed to
Speaker 5:  have this data except for Google, which is like not great.
Speaker 5:  That's not the solution you would hope for. But is that better than other
Speaker 5:  solutions? Like instead of everybody and Google? It's just Google. Like Yeah,
Speaker 5:  it kind of is better.
Speaker 3:  It is a solution. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  So I don't know. I'm so torn. But it is very funny watching Google
Speaker 5:  be like, this is a Privacy preserving thing. And everybody's like, no it's
Speaker 5:  not. This is just letting you have data that you can give to advertisers.
Speaker 5:  Just like all the other data you have to give to advertisers. Just
Speaker 3:  Trust them. It's Google. They're not supposed to be evil.
Speaker 6:  This won't come up in an antitrust lawsuit in five years about how they lied
Speaker 6:  to you. Right?
Speaker 3:  10, 10 years
Speaker 5:  Or next week. Yeah, definitely not gonna happen. None of
Speaker 5:  that. But yeah, the new Chrome looks nice. Happy about that. That's
Speaker 5:  enough Vergecast for one day. Go turn off all your
Speaker 5:  Privacy settings. Just let chaos, rain, let everybody have all your data.
Speaker 5:  Don't even worry about it. What?
Speaker 6:  What if there was a targeted ad that you really needed to see? Think about
Speaker 6:  it. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  That's what I'm saying. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  That's why I have this little like funky ss. I got this little game
Speaker 3:  boy 'cause from a targeted ad. I was like, it was on TikTok. I was like,
Speaker 3:  yeah, that looks stupid.
Speaker 5:  That is somebody who successfully understands Alex Cranz. They,
Speaker 3:  They understood me and I went and I spent $50 and now I have a game Boy Sp
Speaker 3:  that is the size of a thumbnail and I don't know what I'm gonna play on
Speaker 3:  it, but I can play Siphon filter if I really wanted to.
Speaker 5:  It's amazing. Alright, we are very long. We should get outta here.
Speaker 5:  This is the beginning of lots of stuff. We have Apple. Next week we're gonna
Speaker 5:  have a special Apple show with all the folks who are gonna be there live
Speaker 5:  next week. Us versus Google starts next week. That's gonna
Speaker 5:  be fascinating. We have a bunch of D m A stuff in Europe that
Speaker 5:  we didn't really talk about. We're gonna get back to that in much deeper
Speaker 5:  ways over the next couple of weeks. Microsoft is coming. Amazon is coming.
Speaker 5:  Google is coming. Code conference is coming. We have all kinds of stuff going
Speaker 5:  on. Meta
Speaker 3:  Connect is coming. Meta
Speaker 5:  Connect is coming. We're gonna learn about the Quest three. There's
Speaker 6:  An open AI developer event chat. G B T. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  That's not till November Richard. I can't think about November yet. That's
Speaker 5:  It's Richard.
Speaker 3:  Richard.
Speaker 5:  It's football season is starting Sunday. Ticket is here, which I
Speaker 5:  get to talk about now 'cause it's on YouTube. So technology. That's great
Speaker 5:  news. Tons going on. We're starting an AI series
Speaker 5:  on Monday on The Vergecast. We're doing a bunch of really fun stuff about
Speaker 5:  AI music and AI voices and virtual assistants. We got all kinds of really
Speaker 5:  fun stuff coming up. It's gonna be a very busy next few months on The
Speaker 5:  Vergecast. It's all gonna be awesome. Our whole crew, I think including Neli
Speaker 5:  will be back next Friday. We will shame Neli
Speaker 5:  ruthlessly for not being here. We hope you help us do that.
Speaker 5:  Until then, thank you both. Thank you all. This is The Vergecast Rock and
Speaker 5:  roll.
Speaker 8:  And that's a wrap for Vergecast this week. We'd love to hear from you. Shoot
Speaker 8:  us an email at Vergecast at The Verge dot com. The Vergecast is
Speaker 8:  a production of The Verge and the Box Media Podcast Network. The show is
Speaker 8:  produced by me, Liam James, and our senior audio director, Andrew Marino.
Speaker 8:  Our editorial director is Brooke Miners. That's it. We'll see you next
Speaker 8:  week.
Speaker 10:  Support for this show comes from Global Citizen. On September
Speaker 10:  23rd, the Global Citizen Festival will gather thousands of people who took
Speaker 10:  action to end extreme poverty. Join the Red Hot Chili
Speaker 10:  Peppers, Ms. Lauren Hill, Megan Thee Stallion, and
Speaker 10:  Anita as they take the stage with world leaders and activists to
Speaker 10:  demand action for equity for the planet, for food and for
Speaker 10:  jobs. Download the Global Citizen app today and earn your spot at
Speaker 10:  the festival. learn more at global
Speaker 10:  citizen.org/
Speaker 10:  Vox.
Speaker 11:  Support for the show comes from Gold Peak real brewed
Speaker 11:  tea. There's a time of day about an hour before
Speaker 11:  sunset where the rays feel warm and the breeze
Speaker 11:  feels cool, but the hot hour of golden bliss
Speaker 11:  is always gone. Too soon you might rekindle that feeling
Speaker 11:  with a bottle of gold. Peak made with high quality tea
Speaker 11:  leaves its smooth taste transports you to golden hour
Speaker 11:  at any hour. Gold, Peak, Tea.
Speaker 11:  It's got to be gold.