# Transcript
ID: 3141d46f-4c40-4436-b6b8-deb56b4bcf20
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Title: Meta's AI headset future — and that X interview at Code
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/2711778954011913178/2524674413642354521/s93290-US-5522s-1696207809.mp3
Description: The Verge's David Pierce, Nilay Patel, and Alex Cranz break down an awkward interview out of the Code Conference from X (formerly Twitter) CEO Linda Yaccarino. Then, the crew gets into all the big news from Meta's Connect event where the Quest 3 and Meta Smart Glasses were announced.
Speaker 3:  At New York Presbyterian, our data scientists and doctors are
Speaker 3:  combining decades of medical experience caring for diverse
Speaker 3:  communities with the power of data science to one day get
Speaker 3:  ahead of a health issue before it becomes one. Stay.
Speaker 3:  Amazing. Today and tomorrow.
Speaker 3:  New
Speaker 3:  York
Speaker 3:  Presbyterian
Speaker 1:  Welcome
Speaker 4:  To The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of Surprise Interviews. I'm the friend
Speaker 4:  David Pierce. I didn't tell anyone we were doing this podcast. We're just
Speaker 4:  here. We're podcasting. Neli Patel is here. Hi Neli. Welcome
Speaker 4:  back.
Speaker 5:  Hi. I'm on the show. I, I know people have been very confused. I was just
Speaker 5:  doing The, Code, Conference. And what I said to David right before I started
Speaker 5:  is I've hosted enough things. So David, can you just drive
Speaker 5:  this? I'll just sink back into being a guest. Yeah, that seems
Speaker 5:  nice. Every people bring you m and ms. It seems nice. You know,
Speaker 4:  I like this for you. You've moved, you've done code. You get to like be a
Speaker 4:  person now. This is very exciting. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Just re blind reacting to things. This episode of the verse has it
Speaker 5:  many ways. The entire theme is Neli Reacts.
Speaker 4:  This episode's gonna be very fun. 'cause the first half is stuff that you
Speaker 4:  know about and the second half is stuff you don't know anything about. It's
Speaker 4:  gonna be great. Alex Cranz is here. Hi Alex.
Speaker 6:  I didn't know I was doing this podcast until about five minutes ago. I'm
Speaker 6:  very excited to
Speaker 4:  Be here. I knocked on both of your doors and I said, it's podcast time. And
Speaker 4:  here we go. I was
Speaker 6:  Like, okay, put on some pants. We're here. Let's go.
Speaker 4:  We a lot to talk about. This week Meta Connect was this week we got a bunch
Speaker 4:  of news about ai, all kinds of stuff going on. New Raspberry Pi, which I'm
Speaker 4:  weirdly excited about. macOS Sonoma is this week. We have more, by
Speaker 5:  The way, I just bought a Raspberry Pi for Did I'm fucking idiot, but like,
Speaker 5:  it'll be fine. It was, it was really cheap. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. As a like smart home sensor or whatever the four Will will do.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Like how you immediately guessed what I was using it for.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Listen, you just moved house. It's not unclear. We have big
Speaker 4:  trials going on all over the place. We're gonna talk a little bit about those
Speaker 4:  today and we're gonna talk a bunch about those next week. But let's start
Speaker 4:  with code. Code was the, we've been working up to code for months. There
Speaker 4:  was a ton going on. We booked a ton of guests. We talked a ton of people.
Speaker 4:  It got real weird right at the end. Oh yeah. Neli, you
Speaker 4:  co-hosted this thing. Congratulations. You made it through. You're back.
Speaker 4:  Seemed like it went really well. Should we start at the end? Can we start
Speaker 4:  anywhere other than Linda?
Speaker 5:  Look, we, here is my goal at Code. This is how I booked everybody. I
Speaker 5:  know everybody thinks about Kara when they think of code because Kara is
Speaker 5:  Kara and she has run the conference really well for the past couple of
Speaker 5:  years. The conferences I started going to is a little
Speaker 5:  baby that changed my career around, were
Speaker 5:  hosted by Walt in Kara. Right. All the, the
Speaker 5:  things Steve jobs on stage at Code, Steve Jobs and Bill Gates
Speaker 5:  on stage, which by the way has, its like a lore and drama behind
Speaker 5:  it. That's Walt I and like, I just don't like it's both of them.
Speaker 5:  And I don't mean to detract anything from like Kara, but there's a Walt component
Speaker 5:  there and like I'm on that coaching tree. Like,
Speaker 5:  just to be really clear, like Walt was my mentor. He,
Speaker 5:  we did the podcast together. He was on our staff. Like there's just a, a
Speaker 5:  piece of that that I was thinking about a lot as we were like doing the conference
Speaker 5:  and like making a conference, which is very challenging. And again, I know
Speaker 5:  like Kara did an amazing job with that. That's a high standard to live up
Speaker 5:  to. Yeah. I I'm not trying to detract from that. I'm just saying everyone
Speaker 5:  thinks about that. And I was thinking about the before
Speaker 5:  that, and what I really wanted on stage was to be a product
Speaker 5:  reviewer, was to talk about products. Right. The Walt side of the equation.
Speaker 5:  And we put a lot of products in that stage. I'm like very proud of that.
Speaker 5:  Right. Adobe launched Photoshop for the web. Mike Krieger from
Speaker 5:  Artifact launched what is effectively a Twitter competitor. There's a bunch
Speaker 5:  we can get to all that. Yeah. But that's like the part of
Speaker 5:  code that, you know, there's a lot of drama. But if you actually
Speaker 5:  look at our conference and you look at how much we talked about Nvidia H
Speaker 5:  100 GPUs on stage. Like we made a tech conference, like a tech
Speaker 5:  conference and that's pretty cool. And we
Speaker 4:  Got a true detective trailer like this is,
Speaker 5:  And we had a true detective trailer. Yeah. Yeah. Like there was a lot going
Speaker 5:  on at this conference. And then there was like one little bit of chaos, which
Speaker 5:  I will happily talk about,
Speaker 4:  But we should that first. 'cause that continues to be the thing on a lot
Speaker 4:  of people's minds right now. Partly because of
Speaker 4:  what Lindy Akre, the C e O of X talked about on stage. And
Speaker 4:  partly because of just the, I don't know, the scenery around
Speaker 4:  it. The interview you can watch in full on our YouTube channel or on the
Speaker 4:  Decoder podcast. I listened to it while walking my son in
Speaker 4:  a stroller this morning, which is a deeply weird,
Speaker 5:  Oh my, your son is a supervi now That's his Origin
Speaker 5:  story.
Speaker 4:  The like, cognitive dissonance of that was a very strange 45 minutes
Speaker 5:  When I was a wheel Ladd. I heard the sounds of Linda
Speaker 5:  Yaccarino emanating from my father's
Speaker 5:  headset. And now, now I have to destroy
Speaker 5:  humanity to save it.
Speaker 4:  You you can go listen to the interview. It's really interesting. But the,
Speaker 4:  like, the way the interview happened seemed to be as big a
Speaker 4:  thing as anything. 'cause Joel Roth, who used to be, what was his
Speaker 4:  job,
Speaker 5:  Tr head of trust and safety at Twitter. He
Speaker 4:  Was a sort of surprise guest early and talked about a lot of the things that
Speaker 4:  Twitter has struggled with over the years. I don't think he broke a huge
Speaker 4:  amount of new ground in terms of like problems we've known about on that
Speaker 4:  platform for a very long time. But then Linda was sort of forced to answer
Speaker 4:  for a lot of those in a way that she didn't seem super psyched about answering
Speaker 4:  for.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Look, Linda did a shit chop. She did. We can make a lot of
Speaker 5:  excuses and, and like Yol is like a very convenient excuse and like, that's
Speaker 5:  great. She sucked. Like what, what do, what do you want me to say? I interview
Speaker 5:  a lot of CEOs all the time. You can go listen to 'em. Yeah. You know, we
Speaker 5:  don't shy away from hard questions. You know what you get with Kara
Speaker 5:  Swisher, right? Like she did a bad job. Like, and like
Speaker 5:  I, I can talk about the setup there. I just don't want to give her the out.
Speaker 5:  I I think if you're the c e o of a, a major company that is the global town
Speaker 5:  square, da da da da da da, you better be ready. You
Speaker 4:  Should at least have some numbers I would say about how well you're doing.
Speaker 4:  Instead of, she spent a lot of time not answering questions about
Speaker 4:  how well are you doing? And instead talking about her feelings about how
Speaker 4:  well they're doing, which we've learned over the years is when you should
Speaker 4:  be really alarmed about how well something is doing. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Speaker 5:  Only get to the setup and Then, we can talk about that. But I, I don't want
Speaker 5:  to for one second, let anyone walk away from this
Speaker 5:  thinking that the setup or the chaos of Yol or whatever the surprise of
Speaker 5:  it should have is an
Speaker 5:  excuse. There. There are lots of choices you can make if you don't wanna
Speaker 5:  be, you could, she could just walked away and she might have, right? Sure.
Speaker 5:  But she chose to be on the stage and all she had to say she stayed
Speaker 5:  alone. She wanted to be on that stage, which is an important piece of puzzle.
Speaker 5:  So lemme just talk about the setup. So as virtual house listeners know, one
Speaker 5:  of our star guests was supposed to be G m C of Mary Bara. And she dropped
Speaker 5:  out because of the strike. And we made a lot of fun at her, the code stage
Speaker 5:  for dropping out because of the strike So. We, you know, there's like a last
Speaker 5:  minute scrambled to replace your guest So. we have, you know, people pay
Speaker 5:  to attend the conference who wanna put on a good good show for them. So.
Speaker 5:  we, we booked the c e o of Rivian, RJ CR, who was great and he was like
Speaker 5:  of she was great. The one-to-one replacement. And we can, I tried so hard
Speaker 5:  to make him talk shit about the cyber shock. We can talk about that. But
Speaker 5:  that's sort of one-to-one replacement. But everyone was like working hard
Speaker 5:  to replace him, including Kara Right. Who had no
Speaker 5:  obligations to this conference, really. But she, you know, she did it. So
Speaker 5:  she was gonna interview John Lovett and I was gonna be like the Kara
Speaker 5:  Comedy show in the middle of our thing to get Kara back on stage. But then
Speaker 5:  she asked y to do it and Yel said yes. And the history of Code and
Speaker 5:  Code is unlike every other conference, every other
Speaker 5:  conference. And David has worked at a lot of media companies. Every other
Speaker 5:  conference gets corrupted by advertising or
Speaker 5:  sales response, like the history of code. And before that, the all things
Speaker 5:  D conference, like Walton Care are like, we're doing whatever you want and
Speaker 5:  you can show up here. And they had the capital to do
Speaker 5:  it. And this is like a, again, like, these are people that I've worked
Speaker 5:  with and around who are my seniors? Me going to their
Speaker 5:  conference when I was like a $12 a post reporter at Eng
Speaker 5:  Gadget. Like that, that stuff is all in my brain. Like I'm taking over
Speaker 5:  this legacy. So our conference is the same, right? We
Speaker 5:  invite people, we say we, you know, we, we have a lot of conversations
Speaker 5:  about, you know, it's a show like to me, interviewing another person. There's
Speaker 5:  prep calls and we'd like chat about what they wanna say and what I wanna
Speaker 5:  say, but they don't get the questions ahead of time. In particular, the most
Speaker 5:  important part of code is audience questions, which Linda refused to
Speaker 5:  take. And there's just an element of chaos, like journalistic chaos that
Speaker 5:  makes code code. It's unlike any other conference for those reasons.
Speaker 5:  And I have texts in my pocket from Walt before the show and after the show
Speaker 5:  reminding me that that is what his conference is all about and what Kara's
Speaker 5:  conference
Speaker 4:  Is all about. Yeah. Yeah. He always used to say, the thing that we do here
Speaker 4:  is journalism,
Speaker 5:  Live journalism. That's the thing that they, and they both said it. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I just, again, I I I I'm just coming back to the foundations of code.
Speaker 5:  So whatever we are all trying to fill in for Mary Berra and put
Speaker 5:  on a good show and make it good. And so Kara's like, Yo's gonna do it and
Speaker 5:  that's great. Like fine. And so, and Linda knew this information, right?
Speaker 5:  Like there was a lot of consternation about what she would drop out or not.
Speaker 5:  We should tell her like obviously, so Kara knows her, she texted
Speaker 5:  her, she knew, she knew the entire day. And basically we spent the
Speaker 5:  day being like, is she gonna show up or not? Like who knows, maybe
Speaker 5:  she won't. That'll be its own news. She showed up. So that, that's like the
Speaker 5:  whole backstory. Yeah. And the like, I think
Speaker 4:  The, the backstory of it and the interview are sort of two different things.
Speaker 4:  And the interview itself actually for all of the drama around it is not that
Speaker 4:  interesting. Like Julia Borson did a really good job of trying to get her
Speaker 4:  to say something interesting and revelatory about what's going on at x.
Speaker 5:  Can I, can I just say something about Julia? Julia is incredible and like
Speaker 5:  watching Julia work up close was like, I was like, oh, I have a, I have a
Speaker 5:  long way to go. Like that's really how I feel. Like, oh, I've got a long
Speaker 5:  way to go. She over-prepared. She knows her shit cold. She knows
Speaker 5:  everybody. There's one thing when you're, you know, when you're like near
Speaker 5:  someone for a long time and you're like watching them work, you like notice
Speaker 5:  things about them. When Juliet is in the middle of an interview and she knows
Speaker 5:  that she has it, she smiles like it and like maybe it doesn't come through
Speaker 5:  on tv, but like in person, I was like, oh, I can see that she has it. It
Speaker 5:  was, it was incredible. It's
Speaker 4:  Like the the poker hand. Like I have, I have a good hand tell. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It's like the tiniest little tell and she's like, I'm holding a knife. It's
Speaker 5:  great. The, like, all that's great. The Lindy interview was pure chaos. Right?
Speaker 5:  And because of Yol and because Linda Dec had decided I
Speaker 5:  think inaccurately and inappropriately decided that she could blame all of
Speaker 5:  her problems on Yue, she kept going back to it, you know, and that's like
Speaker 5:  a sympathetic position. I I I understand why like, sort of intuitively
Speaker 5:  like I could just be like mad about you all and everyone in this room will
Speaker 5:  care about, but she knew. But if you watch Julia, all of her
Speaker 5:  like cable news anchor training, she's like, I
Speaker 5:  don't, I'm moving on. Like I'm not gonna let you do this. That part of it,
Speaker 5:  if you're like a journalism nerd, go back and watch that interview. Don't
Speaker 5:  pay attention to Linda, pay attention to Julia. And it is actually just
Speaker 5:  revelatory. Like again, I walked away thinking, oh, I've had a lot to learn.
Speaker 5:  I have a lot to learn about how to do this.
Speaker 4:  Just the ability to constantly say, can I finish my question is like a real,
Speaker 4:  it's a real skill. Can I finish my question, David? To do in front of a lot
Speaker 4:  of people, it's very impressive,
Speaker 5:  Right? There's a room full of people, some of whom
Speaker 5:  are not on any one side, right? They're just like there for the train wreck.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Some of whom are there. And they're very sympathetic to Linda and some
Speaker 5:  of whom are there and they're very sympathetic. Like whatever it's, or they're
Speaker 5:  mad at Twitter, whatever it is. And like the tension
Speaker 5:  in that room was out of control. Mm. And so for Julia to
Speaker 5:  stay locked in and focused on, I am going to ask
Speaker 5:  the questions again. Watch that side of it. 'cause it is
Speaker 5:  incredible.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And it's like hard questions about halfway through, she, she kind
Speaker 6:  of manages to get Linda off of blaming Yol
Speaker 6:  for all of her responses. Yeah. Which is like, like the first half
Speaker 6:  of it. She's, she, she makes a lot of remarks. Yeah. About like, yeah. No
Speaker 6:  one knew who was here today. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It's like every, I promise you, you know what, like we all
Speaker 5:  saw what app she had on her phone. Yoel was on the schedule.
Speaker 6:  Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Right. He was like listed publicly on the schedule. Yeah. We updated the
Speaker 5:  app like 50 times. 'cause we were, we were moving the things. 'cause she,
Speaker 5:  you know, Linda had first insisted on being last. She wanted cloak.
Speaker 5:  Right. And then she was like, no, I want to go before y'all. And then she
Speaker 5:  switched it back. So like, actually the schedule is moving all day. It's
Speaker 5:  like, you there, none of this was a secret. Okay. In fact, more of it should
Speaker 5:  have been a secret.
Speaker 4:  Fair. Yeah. Alex, you, you and I have both watched the interview since the,
Speaker 4:  the full thing got posted. Did you take anything of like substance
Speaker 4:  away from it? About x the company or platform?
Speaker 6:  I took a lot about it from the hostility towards
Speaker 6:  journalism that I saw in it. Like that was the main thing I took away was
Speaker 6:  we've seen that thread of hostility from the company since Elon
Speaker 6:  took over and saw it very apparently on stage. And knowing now that
Speaker 6:  like she knew because you watch it initially and you're like, oh,
Speaker 6:  she just found out. Yeah, I'd probably be that pissed on stage two. Like
Speaker 6:  no, if you knew the whole day.
Speaker 5:  And by the way, not to say anything about Yoel Yoel is great.
Speaker 5:  And you know, he, he's very compelling and he knows a lot of shit about trust
Speaker 5:  and safety. There was no content in his interview that
Speaker 5:  he had not shared before. Right.
Speaker 6:  Right. Like, like the things he was saying was things he said quite often
Speaker 6:  about the company that
Speaker 5:  He has put in the New York Times. But by the way, if, if, if you want like
Speaker 5:  a slightly more produced version of the Ill interview, you can go listen
Speaker 5:  to an episode of this American life that he did with Casey
Speaker 5:  Newton. Again, he's very compelling. I'm glad he was on stage. I'm glad that
Speaker 5:  audience, which you know, is a very powerful influential audience. Like
Speaker 5:  heard it. I think that's important. But if you
Speaker 5:  are Linda, there was nothing that you were reacting to that you had, you
Speaker 5:  hadn't already reacted to.
Speaker 4:  Right.
Speaker 6:  It was just like a very familiar, like, you, you see this kind of hostility
Speaker 6:  sometimes from people who, who don't want to give you the answers and they,
Speaker 6:  they have their narrative and they really don't wanna deviate from that
Speaker 6:  narrative. Yeah. And that just seemed to be the case here. And I was like,
Speaker 6:  okay, so I'm not gonna get necessarily something substantial from
Speaker 6:  Linda, but I thought it was a very revealing interview
Speaker 6:  even if it wasn't like a substantial one. Like it was super revealing
Speaker 5:  To me. Is there a scientific term for revealing nothing for like
Speaker 5:  the substance of something to be nothing
Speaker 4:  Press
Speaker 4:  releases?
Speaker 4:  No, I think, I mean, to me, even the things that she said, and this is the
Speaker 4:  thing that has really stuck with me about the interview, is even the things
Speaker 4:  that she said didn't seem like they were true. Like she
Speaker 4:  named, I think the number was 540 million monthly active users. And
Speaker 4:  she said that, or not monthly active users, just users.
Speaker 4:  So whatever that means. She said that number twice. So I'm inclined to believe
Speaker 4:  that is actually a number. But then she said, she said,
Speaker 4:  Julia asked about how many daily active users X has, which is actually a
Speaker 4:  really important number, right? Like we, there are a million external things
Speaker 4:  saying X is not doing well. Right? Like there are
Speaker 4:  engagement metrics that seem to be down that are all reported by third parties.
Speaker 4:  So, you know, grain of salt with that,
Speaker 5:  That people on the platform are experiencing, right?
Speaker 4:  It's way down on the app store. Like all of the vibes are bad, but the
Speaker 4:  number of people who log into Twitter every day is like potentially the
Speaker 4:  most important number. And I don't believe for one
Speaker 4:  second that she doesn't know that number to like the decimal
Speaker 4:  place. And instead she gets up and is like, oh, it's between 200 and
Speaker 4:  250 million people every day. And Julia followed up by
Speaker 4:  saying that it was 237 million when Elon Musk took it
Speaker 4:  over. And then Linda said at 1.2 25 and
Speaker 4:  there's just like, you don't have to tell anybody you're a private company
Speaker 4:  owned by one dude
Speaker 5:  At one point she pulled out her phone Yeah. To as though she was
Speaker 5:  going to check the number and then did not, and then
Speaker 5:  showed the phone to the audience and it was just her home screen. And
Speaker 4:  A lot of sleuthing has showed that X was not on her home screen.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It's a very confusing situation. Well,
Speaker 6:  And we just got a report this week about most
Speaker 6:  of the big companies daily, like daily active users.
Speaker 6:  And it was so far from that I think Twitter was like 56 million. Oh
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Twitter. Twitter's always, again, I and I, I've said this many times
Speaker 5:  and I I will say it again now very clearly for everyone to
Speaker 5:  hear me criticism of, of Twitter or ex's current
Speaker 5:  leadership is in no way praise for
Speaker 5:  the previous administration. Yeah. They were bad. And actually one
Speaker 5:  of the most interesting things about it is you can make
Speaker 5:  an argument that Twitter is so hard to run and it is such a
Speaker 5:  mess that that version of bad was
Speaker 5:  the only way to be. Like, they had entered a steady state of
Speaker 5:  horribleness, but they weren't growing, they weren't making any money. They,
Speaker 5:  this is why they sold it to Elon at an inflated share price because it's
Speaker 5:  board of directors had come essentially come to the conclusion that
Speaker 5:  nothing they could do would ever bring the company to that share price on
Speaker 5:  their own. That is like, if you look at the mirror, you
Speaker 5:  know, like, you know, like every kid wakes up one day and like realizes like,
Speaker 5:  I am not gonna pass chem. Like I'm just not gonna be a doctor.
Speaker 5:  You know, like maybe that was just me. But like, you know,
Speaker 5:  there's like those moments in your life where like, ah, I had better give
Speaker 5:  up
Speaker 6:  Me in sports.
Speaker 5:  Like Twitter as a company was like,
Speaker 5:  we're never gonna hit $44 a share. And they sold it to Elon. And
Speaker 5:  like, again, I just don't wanna say like, criticism of this administration
Speaker 5:  is praise. It does not imply that they were doing, they were doing a horrible
Speaker 5:  job such that they quit just flat out, they just quit. They couldn't figure
Speaker 5:  out how to do it on their own. They, and they, and they sold it to Elon 'cause
Speaker 5:  he showed up like a dummy to buy it. But it's not that he's now put in place
Speaker 5:  a team that will do a better job. He's put in place a team, a
Speaker 5:  C E O who doesn't appear to know what's going on. Yeah. I
Speaker 4:  Think to me, like the worst look for Linda in this
Speaker 4:  entire interview, which is a fairly high bar in this particular interview,
Speaker 4:  was when Julia asked about Musk's
Speaker 4:  tweet about going to a fully subscription model where
Speaker 4:  everyone using Twitter would have to pay for Twitter. And I'm,
Speaker 4:  I'm paraphrasing, but Linda was basically like, well she first asked to repeat
Speaker 4:  the question, which was bizarre. It was a very simple question. No,
Speaker 6:  I don't say, I don't think that was bizarre. I like, like everybody is like,
Speaker 6:  oh, she didn't know the answer.
Speaker 4:  Oh sure. It was a total filibuster.
Speaker 6:  She was straight up filibustering like, like let's, let's give her a
Speaker 6:  little, a little acknowledgement of that. At least she was, she
Speaker 6:  was doing something wasn't,
Speaker 4:  But then Julia rephrases the question and she
Speaker 4:  says, I think she says, did he say that's what we're doing
Speaker 4:  or that's what he's thinking about? And then Julia said, yeah, he said
Speaker 4:  that's the plan. So at this point it's now abundantly clear that Linda
Speaker 4:  doesn't know what's going on. And, and then she says essentially in response
Speaker 4:  to another question, she says, we talk about everything and then has no more
Speaker 4:  response. So I don't know how I'm supposed to come out of that. Yeah. Not
Speaker 4:  thinking that she didn't know this was a thing.
Speaker 6:  I came out of that thinking she was filibustering and trying to make fun
Speaker 6:  of Julia for asking the question at all. Like the way she looked
Speaker 6:  to the audience after she's like, did he say that? Or, and that's why
Speaker 6:  I wanna know like Neli, you were there.
Speaker 5:  She okay being in the room Linda, I don't know, I,
Speaker 5:  I don't know. I was in that room all day
Speaker 5:  and I would just say the com, the room was packed. You know,
Speaker 5:  a lot of things, if you ever go to a conference, like the composition of
Speaker 5:  the room changes over the day. 'cause people are like networking, they're
Speaker 5:  like doing it whatever. And like they're like doing work halls, whatever.
Speaker 5:  Like this was packed
Speaker 5:  and Linda got a lot of cheers, which
Speaker 6:  Like big cheers.
Speaker 5:  Linda came with an entourage
Speaker 4:  Like the, like the Apple employees you hear cheering at an Apple event. This
Speaker 4:  was like a small version of that. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It was, there was just, there was an element in there that was weird.
Speaker 5:  And I'll say this at the end, Julia got a standing
Speaker 5:  ovation. This is a real thing that happened at the end of code. Like
Speaker 6:  She deserved it.
Speaker 5:  The conference ends, Linda leaves Casey and I walked back on stage. I
Speaker 5:  literally said, holy shit. And then I said Julia Borson everyone.
Speaker 5:  And, and Julia got That's great. A standing ovation from that crowd. That's
Speaker 5:  awesome. So like, you know when I say the composition of the room was, it
Speaker 5:  was odd, but the people who were noisiest at the beginning were like
Speaker 5:  the Linda people. Yeah. And so I think she thought the room was a
Speaker 5:  lot warmer to her than it might have been. Been. She
Speaker 6:  Played to
Speaker 5:  The room a little lot on, she played to the room a lot because I think she
Speaker 5:  had the sense that the room was really was like on her side. So she kept
Speaker 5:  looking at the room is though everyone agreed with her that this was bullshit.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And that was not the case. And the one example of that, which
Speaker 5:  was absolutely the funniest thing that I've ever seen happen at
Speaker 5:  Code. And I've been to, I've been gonna this conference for a decade. She
Speaker 5:  said, who wouldn't want Elon Musk by their side running product?
Speaker 5:  And like there's just like, people just like burst into laugh. Did they start
Speaker 5:  raising their hands? Because it's a room full of product people. Like what
Speaker 5:  did I say at the beginning? What did I want code to be? I wanted the code
Speaker 5:  to be about product. Who did we invite? Who did we put on the stage? Who
Speaker 5:  did they bring? Product people? And they were like,
Speaker 5:  no. And Julia was like, raise your hand if, and like
Speaker 5:  every, I was like, I cannot believe like you
Speaker 5:  don't know, like you don't know This is a room full of product people.
Speaker 6:  That was a brutal moment.
Speaker 4:  Alright, that's enough of that.
Speaker 5:  I could talk about this by the way for the like maybe the rest of it.
Speaker 4:  I know, which is precisely why it's enough of that. Let's, this
Speaker 5:  Is why I was like, I need to be the guest, not the us.
Speaker 4:  Everybody should go, it's worth watching the whole interview. You're gonna
Speaker 4:  get three minutes in and your whole body is gonna start to feel itchy because
Speaker 4:  it is very uncomfortable.
Speaker 5:  Imagine being in the room.
Speaker 6:  It's like the first half have never been kissed, which is the most excruciating
Speaker 6:  movie.
Speaker 5:  And then just, just to make it about me for one second, very
Speaker 5:  important. Imagine being like, I have to go back out on the stage after.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Was holy shit a rehearsed line. Had you like stood backstage going,
Speaker 4:  holy shit, holy shit. Like yeah,
Speaker 6:  That's on the teleprompter. Actually,
Speaker 5:  Casey and I were just like holding hands like what are we gonna do?
Speaker 4:  That's great. But yeah, everybody, we'll put it in the show notes. You should
Speaker 4:  go watch it. Go listen to it. It's, it's really interesting. Let's just blow
Speaker 4:  through some of the actual like interesting product stuff that happened.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. To me the Getty AI thing was
Speaker 4:  one of the most interesting pieces of the whole show. Yeah. Do you wanna,
Speaker 4:  do you wanna just explain a little bit about that conversation and what we
Speaker 4:  got from Craig Peters? The, the Getty c e o? Yeah.
Speaker 5:  So. we had two conversations back to back that I really wanted to make sure
Speaker 5:  we had back to back. It was Microsoft C T o, Kevin Scott who is wonderful
Speaker 5:  and the c e o of Getty. Craig Peters who is a firecracker.
Speaker 5:  Right. But
Speaker 4:  You wouldn't think for the Getty c e o but like kudos.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. But he's great. He's a creative, like he ba he manages
Speaker 5:  thousands of photographers. Like once you like put that together, like oh,
Speaker 5:  you're like, oh, I get it. You know? So Getty is suing stability ai, which
Speaker 5:  makes stable diffusion and the, you know, the, the lawsuit is what you think.
Speaker 5:  It's whether training on copyrighted images is fair
Speaker 5:  use, stable diffusion is like some, I
Speaker 5:  don't, I don't think think it does this anymore, but like for a while would
Speaker 5:  produce the Getty watermark in AI generated images. And Getty is like, come
Speaker 5:  on. Right. So, you know, everyone thinks that stability is kind of a
Speaker 5:  chaotic company. They refuse to come on stager code. We'd invited them
Speaker 5:  to, you know, respond to Craig and they, they said no, it says a
Speaker 5:  lot. But you know, Craig's entire thesis was like you can build AI
Speaker 5:  tools that don't step on other people's copyrighted stuff. And in fact, fact
Speaker 5:  we have. And so, you know, they, they shut off their brand new product stuff
Speaker 5:  at code. They shut off their brand new AI image generator and we like had
Speaker 5:  fun using it on stage. But his argument was this industry
Speaker 5:  is stepping all over creatives and like what Getty makes is
Speaker 5:  important to history and we need to like protect it and
Speaker 5:  we need to build business models that protect it instead of just like Racing
Speaker 5:  headlong into devaluing it even further. And the reason I said I put
Speaker 5:  the interviews back to back is because my, Kevin Scott is an author,
Speaker 5:  he's an artist, he's a maker, he is a renaissance man. He's great. He can
Speaker 5:  talk about anything. Microsoft has a $10 billion
Speaker 5:  bet on it being fair use. Yeah. With OpenAI, right? Like
Speaker 5:  that's crazy. And so, you know, Kevin was like, a lot of people think this
Speaker 5:  is fair use. And I was like, not everyone and Then we brought out Craig,
Speaker 5:  which was really cool. So listen to those two conversations back to back.
Speaker 5:  They, you know, they're all gonna up the Decoder feed and they'll be on The,
Speaker 5:  Verge YouTube. But that was the dynamic that I really put in front of
Speaker 5:  everybody. Like the industry has not figured out this huge
Speaker 5:  problem at the center of ai. And we had, you know, we had Warner
Speaker 5:  Music, c e o Robert Kinsel on stage, he's a Former head of business at
Speaker 5:  YouTube. Like I'm not on the side of the music industry very
Speaker 5:  often. I'm not on the side of fig copyright very often. But you see this
Speaker 5:  dynamic and actually like shuffles the decks a little bit. And the gian
Speaker 5:  conversation in particular, I think really brought us to the
Speaker 5:  fore. 'cause they're making some of the technology too. They want to show
Speaker 5:  that you can make the technology in the right way.
Speaker 4:  That bit that he showed where he was basically like, we're in this race
Speaker 4:  with, you know, open AI and Anthropic and Google where everybody's trying
Speaker 4:  to do the biggest possible thing, right? Like everybody brags about like
Speaker 4:  the number of parameters in their model and how big the training set is.
Speaker 4:  And it's like everything is supposed to be this gigantic all purpose thing
Speaker 4:  for everybody, for everything forever. Like AI is just Windows now,
Speaker 4:  right? Like it's huge. And then I thought I, that was just why I thought
Speaker 4:  Craig and the Getty stuff is so interesting because like we can take this
Speaker 4:  smaller corpus of data that is better and we can actually make
Speaker 4:  it work just as well, but more successfully
Speaker 4:  for everyone involved. And I just think that's very cool.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And then somehow inside of that, there's one more piece, one more term
Speaker 5:  that's super interesting in there. And somehow we will
Speaker 5:  compensate the artists whose work is in the training data. And I
Speaker 5:  was like, how? And he is like, we just are making it up.
Speaker 4:  Right? Yeah. He was very honest about like, we only have half the answers.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. But he is like, right now we're basically doing it on popularity. Like
Speaker 5:  if, if you are, it's like spot the way Spotify works. Like this was
Speaker 5:  to weedsy to get into on the code stage. But the, the
Speaker 5:  answer is like, we'll look at the proportion of
Speaker 5:  images inside of the training data that people
Speaker 5:  call up more often in the wider world of Getty. And then when
Speaker 5:  people pay to generate images, we'll dole out fractions of a
Speaker 5:  penny based on that sort of like underlying ranking, which is like, it is
Speaker 5:  more like how Spotify works than anything. But it is not some
Speaker 5:  incredible complicated algorithm about what training pixels
Speaker 5:  were put. It's, it's more like what's popular. You get more money, you
Speaker 5:  know, like it's, and like they're, they need to refine that.
Speaker 4:  The other one, Alex, you and I watched Casey Bois together. What,
Speaker 4:  what did, did we get anything from Casey that, that we thought was interesting?
Speaker 4:  Casey Bois runs H B O is like a very important person. This happened
Speaker 4:  right after the end of the writer Strike So. we had like new information.
Speaker 4:  Peter Kafka interviewed him. They talked a little bit about that, a little
Speaker 4:  bit about some other stuff. Like what, what, what did we get from Casey that
Speaker 4:  you thought was interesting?
Speaker 6:  We got the true detective season four trailer, which looks, I'm just apparently
Speaker 6:  very excited. Yeah. Yeah. I think I was like texting you like, this is my
Speaker 6:  personality for the next four months. Yeah. Yeah. I think we just got his,
Speaker 6:  his reinforcement of David Slovs kind of way of thinking out there, right?
Speaker 6:  Like he was talking a lot about how the, the cable bundle was back
Speaker 6:  and it was gonna be on, on these streaming services and that
Speaker 6:  like, he felt that was he, that was good. And, and he wants
Speaker 6:  to see that more. And, and then they talked a lot about this new show Naked
Speaker 6:  Attraction that's on a p o Max just kept coming up, which was
Speaker 6:  like my, my sister-in-law had just texted me the night before about it and
Speaker 6:  I'd never heard about it. And I was like, yes, I know what he's talking about.
Speaker 6:  'cause I just Googled this and, and so he was kind of like
Speaker 6:  defending the way that they're choosing what they put on H B O and
Speaker 6:  what they, what they share as H B O versus Max versus Cartoon
Speaker 6:  Network versus all H G T V and all of these other channels that are
Speaker 6:  now part of, of the larger streaming ecosystem. And
Speaker 6:  yeah, it was, it was mainly just like reinforcement of David Al's kind of
Speaker 6:  way of thinking and that it was nice. Like, it was interesting to see that.
Speaker 6:  'cause you're kinda like, well how does, how does someone like Boise think
Speaker 6:  about it? And apparently very similarly,
Speaker 4:  I don't know, Neil, what did you, what did you take away from it?
Speaker 5:  That I think Casey Boise is maybe one of the most powerful people at
Speaker 5:  Warner Brothers Discovery. And he knows it and David Zla knows
Speaker 5:  it and you know, the, the stuff about H B O versus
Speaker 5:  Max, like, he was just very calm and comfortable with it. You know,
Speaker 5:  I I I saw Casey backstage and I was like, do you want me to ask you some
Speaker 5:  more questions about H B O Max versus Max? And he's like, Jesus Christ
Speaker 5:  man. But you know, his, his thesis,
Speaker 5:  his argument was that H B O by itself has never been a successful business
Speaker 5:  in the history of H B O. Even when you think about people paying for H B
Speaker 5:  O directly. He's like, people had a cable bundle and they would pay us
Speaker 5:  extra money for H B O and if we don't ride along with that cable
Speaker 5:  bundle, that has never been a successful business for us. Is that a
Speaker 5:  recon? Maybe, you know, like maybe, yeah. But it
Speaker 5:  is historically true and you know, there's a new owner at the company and
Speaker 5:  that is his thesis that's very much has Oslo. Things like what
Speaker 5:  people want is 90 day fiance and then sometimes they want intruder
Speaker 5:  detective. It's not the other way around. And that
Speaker 5:  is, I think probably Vergecast listeners don't feel that way.
Speaker 5:  But Ha have you ever been to America?
Speaker 6:  Like I think that's, I honestly I do think that's true,
Speaker 6:  right? Like, like most people are watching the reason you like H B O and
Speaker 6:  the reason you like those things is that like Sunday night you go watch H
Speaker 6:  B O but you were probably weren't watching H B O every single night of the
Speaker 6:  week when you were were watching TV channels. Yeah. I mean you could have
Speaker 6:  been, but like, that was a very small population of folks and they could
Speaker 6:  kind of be uns insufferable.
Speaker 5:  Right? What are the dominant TV like from the golden age of
Speaker 5:  television in the Bundle? It's, but it's a bunch of network TV series. It's
Speaker 5:  friends, it's the Office, right? Like, and there's still Dominant, which
Speaker 5:  is crazy. So yeah, I, you know, there there was that, he talked a lot about
Speaker 5:  H B O shows now appearing on Netflix again and he was like, look
Speaker 5:  in, you know, the brass ring used to be syndication and we need to go back
Speaker 5:  there. And we went through this weird period where everyone was trying to
Speaker 5:  build their own little monopoly and we've like, we've realized like that's
Speaker 5:  not the way. And I was like, I always knew that wasn't the way.
Speaker 6:  No, no one's told Netflix though, right?
Speaker 5:  Well I but that Netflix is a different business. It's the only one that's
Speaker 5:  successful, right? They, they fired like just cannon
Speaker 5:  blasts of venture capital money into building their moat. And everyone else
Speaker 5:  tried to do it and it like destroyed the industry along the way. Casey didn't
Speaker 5:  talk about the strike by the way, speaking of cost going up. And Peter asked
Speaker 5:  him like, is the resolution of this strike and maybe the SAG strike gonna
Speaker 5:  bring your costs up 'cause your labor costs are higher. And he was like,
Speaker 5:  no. Which I think if I was in the Writer's Guild or the Screen
Speaker 5:  Actor's Guild, I'd be like, yeah, we told you so. By the way, here's all
Speaker 5:  the disclosures are staff is unionized by the
Speaker 5:  WGA e Alex is in the WGA e we, Comcast is one
Speaker 5:  of our investors. Linda Yaccarino doesn't like me very much.
Speaker 4:  We made a Netflix show. We we made
Speaker 5:  A Netflix show. Yeah. I'm the EP of a Netflix show. Someone has asked this
Speaker 5:  many times. That show is not because it's documentary, it was not covered.
Speaker 5:  You what? It's what What do you want from me?
Speaker 4:  Neli so tight. I'm
Speaker 5:  Hosted a code conference. I'm so tired.
Speaker 6:  Alright,
Speaker 4:  Let's do, we're gonna, I wanna talk more about the rider strike. We're gonna
Speaker 4:  get to that in a little bit because it ended in some really interesting ways.
Speaker 4:  So we're gonna talk about that. Let's do two more just ultra fast
Speaker 4:  things about code and then get outta here. Yeah. First Neli, I am going to
Speaker 4:  give you 65 seconds and no longer to talk about the Monarch
Speaker 4:  tractor c e o that you had on stage. Ready Go.
Speaker 5:  The most important interview I did a code was with Pravin Piso, the C e O
Speaker 5:  of Monarch tractor. I opened that interview by saying the
Speaker 5:  entire human species is utterly dependent on tractors. And I
Speaker 5:  saw Jake, like our deaf owner, Jake, just start cracking. He is like, oh,
Speaker 5:  NE's on his bullshit again. It's true. It's
Speaker 5:  a fact. Pravin just like blew the crowd away by talking about his tractor.
Speaker 5:  So it's an ev tractor has a full sensor suite. They built it to be
Speaker 5:  ultra modular. All the, the sensor suite is in the roof of the tractor, which
Speaker 5:  is just a handful of bolts in a couple cables for power, power and
Speaker 5:  data. And he's like, that is what we're gonna upgrade. Like over time we'll
Speaker 5:  just sell you new roofs. Other people can have new roofs or, you know, they're
Speaker 5:  the open ecosystem compared to John Deere. They're partnered with Case is
Speaker 5:  making tractors using their technology. Go watch it. He's like, we're
Speaker 5:  we're the Android. Like John Deere's the iPhone close proprietary, hard to
Speaker 5:  service. We're gonna be the open eco ecosystem and the tractor's
Speaker 4:  Cool. Yeah. His line was, we're becoming the Android of agriculture, which
Speaker 4:  is just an unbelievably cool it love and vergie sentences.
Speaker 5:  It's, and I will tell you this, I've, I've talked a lot about the crowd,
Speaker 5:  crowd in this room. They loved him by the end of this, they were like, oh,
Speaker 5:  tractors are the shit. Like one person was like, I'm gonna buy a tractor
Speaker 5:  for my vineyard. Which is the code audience.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I, I did a, I did a conference one time and basically just
Speaker 4:  introduced a man and asked him, so three D printing houses, huh? And he talked
Speaker 4:  for like 20 uninterrupted minutes about all the cool things you can do when
Speaker 4:  you can three d print concrete houses. And it was the most excited room I've
Speaker 4:  ever been in. Like, people love this stuff. It's awesome. The world runs
Speaker 4:  on it. I agree.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Technology and products. I'm telling you it's the, that's, that's what
Speaker 5:  code's all about.
Speaker 4:  It's, it's the stuff. And then the other one was Artifact, Mike
Speaker 4:  Krieger, which I think I continue to think Artifact is interesting, but it's
Speaker 4:  like a little kind of tiny thing. But they just launched Twitter at code,
Speaker 4:  right? Like Mike Krieger was just like, we're doing Twitter.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. C co-founder and co-founder of
Speaker 5:  Instagram launches Instagram.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It's like, I don't know what you want me to say. Like, KRE Krieger's great.
Speaker 5:  He was literally coding, you know, artifacts a tiny company. He was literally
Speaker 5:  shipping code in our green room. That's awesome. And he was like, this is
Speaker 5:  so much better than being at the big company. So that was really fun.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Go look. It's Twitter, right? It's posts. The only, the only real difference
Speaker 5:  is you have to have a photo for some reason, which is a lot of Instagram
Speaker 5:  d n a coming through. But you know what, what, what Mike Krieger
Speaker 5:  has told me, what Kevin Strom has told me is they always launched Artifact
Speaker 5:  with the goal of being something much bigger with the goal of creating a
Speaker 5:  much bigger corpus of machine learning data and doing more interesting things
Speaker 5:  with it. And you can see they started with it's links on the
Speaker 5:  web. It's a recommendation engine for webpage to, you can share
Speaker 5:  links to now you can just share your own content and we will recommend that
Speaker 5:  to you. And they're building a, they're building sort of like an AI first
Speaker 5:  social network. It's cool. And like again,
Speaker 5:  what, what, what am I hammering home here? Yes, there's the chaos. There
Speaker 5:  is a lot of product conversation to code. Like an awful lot
Speaker 5:  of what products are we building? Why are we building them? What are the
Speaker 5:  dependencies on Nvidia, on GPUs, on
Speaker 5:  other stuff that we need to overcome in order to build products. And to me
Speaker 5:  Mike was like the, the pinnacle of that moment. 'cause he was literally building
Speaker 5:  the product in the green room before he walked out on stage. He was
Speaker 4:  Great. And then, okay, last one. You did not successfully
Speaker 4:  get RJs Care and the c e o of Rivian to talk shit about the cyber
Speaker 4:  truck, but I would say he made fairly clear that he thinks the cyber truck
Speaker 4:  is stupid. Would you agree with that assessment?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, you know, there's the code name of Decoder is Neli versus
Speaker 5:  media training. You know, it's like, can I fight you to a draw? And like,
Speaker 5:  sometimes I usually get to a draw. I think sometimes I win And
Speaker 5:  that's,
Speaker 4:  And then the sub CEO e o gets in trouble.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, exactly. Like sometimes I win too much,
Speaker 5:  honestly. But it's like fine. It's a game. And that's why CEOs come and do
Speaker 5:  it 'cause they're all type A and it's, it's, you know, it's a game that's
Speaker 5:  set up to, to be winnable. Like, not to be unfair, but you know, you know,
Speaker 5:  the questions are coming. And the reason I bring all that up is sometimes
Speaker 5:  I can see the media training and the most devastating answer you
Speaker 5:  can give inside of the media training is, well that's a
Speaker 5:  choice.
Speaker 4:  As as as allowable answers go. That is the most damning one.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Right. It's like, yeah, people are Freeda make that choice. We'll see what
Speaker 5:  the market decides. Like it's,
Speaker 4:  It's a real like bless their heart kind of response. Yeah, yeah, exactly.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Like if you know what that means, you're like
Speaker 5:  the one piece of news that's inside of there that was important. And I,
Speaker 5:  I hope sort of the EV community caught this, I asked him about the deal
Speaker 5:  terms to use the Tesla charger. 'cause Rivian is using N A CS
Speaker 5:  two and he said everyone thinks there's some like complicated data sharing
Speaker 5:  agreement. There's these conspiracy theories out there and there is not,
Speaker 5:  there is an agreement to use a charger and there's agreement to give us access
Speaker 5:  to their network and that's it. So there you go. I don't know what it's like
Speaker 5:  for everybody else, but he is like, like everyone else, we thought the charger
Speaker 5:  was better to use. The Biden administration did its
Speaker 5:  thing, it's like some tax scheme that requires them to basically open up
Speaker 5:  their network and then everyone rushed into use the charger and the network
Speaker 5:  because the conditions were there for us to go make a deal on not
Speaker 5:  honors terms.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, fair enough. It was good stuff. There's a ton of good stuff coming
Speaker 4:  out. We're gonna have a lot more, it'll be on the YouTube channel, it'll
Speaker 4:  be on podcasts all over the network. I
Speaker 5:  Did ask him about the, the single wiper. It's
Speaker 4:  A choice.
Speaker 6:  My death. Is that where he said, bless your heart.
Speaker 5:  No, that was, that was the second. It's a choice. I was like, do you think
Speaker 5:  this triangle's gonna destroy your business? And he was like, I don't know
Speaker 5:  man, don't no thank you. I was like, what about one big wiper?
Speaker 5:  And he was like, many people have faced say like it's,
Speaker 4:  You can have as many wipers as you want, you want. Alright, we need to take
Speaker 4:  a break and then we're gonna come back and Alex and I are gonna tell me lie
Speaker 4:  about everything else that happened this week. We'll be right
Speaker 4:  back.
Speaker 7:  Support for The Vergecast comes from Crucible Moments, a new podcast
Speaker 7:  from Sequoia Capital. Did you know that PayPal invented Capcha to
Speaker 7:  fight 10 million in monthly fraud that almost sank them? Or that
Speaker 7:  Airbnb was once nearly put out of business in Europe by a copycat
Speaker 7:  competitor that clone their website down to the Pixel. Crucible
Speaker 7:  Moments is a new show hosted by Sequoia's Ruloff Baha that
Speaker 7:  takes you inside the pivotal decisions that shape startups. Whether you
Speaker 7:  have your own startup or just wanna learn how iconic companies once navigated,
Speaker 7:  perilous crossroads, then you might want to give Crucible Moments a
Speaker 7:  listen. The show brings you inside decisions from companies like Airbnb,
Speaker 7:  PayPal 23 and me and Nvidia. Tune into
Speaker 7:  Sequoia's new podcast series to discover how some of the most
Speaker 7:  transformational companies of the modern era were built. Crucible Moments
Speaker 7:  is out now and available everywhere you get your podcasts end at
Speaker 7:  Crucible Moments dot com. Go listen to Crucible Moments
Speaker 7:  today.
Speaker 4:  All right, we're back. Let's get to the other news of the week.
Speaker 4:  Alex, I'm gonna give you the choice. Do you wanna do the writer strike first
Speaker 4:  or do you wanna do Meta Connect first? Ooh,
Speaker 6:  I kind of wanna do Meta Connect first. I think both are really important,
Speaker 6:  but I wanna talk about some gadgets.
Speaker 4:  All right, let's do Meta. Three big things from Meta Connect, big annual
Speaker 4:  hardware event, The Quest three headset, the new Smart
Speaker 4:  Glasses and the just weird slew
Speaker 4:  of Ai AI stuff. Yeah, let's start with the headset. Well,
Speaker 5:  You don't want to start with tpa. I'm not,
Speaker 4:  I'm not ready for T-pain. I need like a minute before we get to T-Pain and
Speaker 4:  Snoop Dogg and Dwayne Wade pretending to be not Dwayne Wade. And
Speaker 4:  I don't understand what any of that actually, you know what, let's do that
Speaker 4:  right now. I'm angry.
Speaker 5:  I knew it. I knew it. It's like, do you want Tom Brady in your house not
Speaker 5:  being Tom Brady?
Speaker 4:  I don't, yeah, Alex. Will you just, will you just explain what Meta is doing
Speaker 4:  with all these chatbots?
Speaker 6:  Well, they assume you don't have any friends and that you
Speaker 6:  need artificial intelligence to be chat like your friend.
Speaker 6:  Basically. It's a bunch of chatbots, but the chatbots are designed to look
Speaker 6:  and sound like famous people. So there's like a Snoop
Speaker 6:  Dog dungeon master that they, he
Speaker 6:  tried to demo on stage. It didn't work. That was kind of unfortunate.
Speaker 6:  And, and that's basically the gist of it, right? Like the, these chat bots
Speaker 6:  are meant to just replicate people and build
Speaker 6:  these, like enhance those pair of social relationships you already have with
Speaker 6:  celebrities. And I really, really, really, really encourage you
Speaker 6:  to make more friends.
Speaker 5:  Wait, wait, wait, wait. Let me, let me offer you the flip of, let me offer
Speaker 5:  you the flip of this. So I was reading Casey's newsletter last
Speaker 5:  night and he was writing about the new version of
Speaker 5:  chat c p T, which can actually speak to you. He can play these characters,
Speaker 5:  it's multimodal, whatever. And he had this example in here, which
Speaker 5:  I had not really considered, but he is like a teenager, a young
Speaker 5:  trans teenager wrote into hard fork and was
Speaker 5:  like, I get affirmations every day from G p T. Like, it's the thing that
Speaker 5:  I talk to on this, like, right. And I, and that's an earlier
Speaker 5:  version. So I, there's, yeah, and his whole newsletter is basically
Speaker 5:  like, we're on the cusp of this being, these relationships being realer
Speaker 5:  and like, there's all the Silicon Valley baggage, there's all the endless
Speaker 5:  conversation with the movie her, all that stuff is in there, but he's like,
Speaker 5:  there's something here that is worth paying attention to. And that kind of
Speaker 5:  unlocked my brain when I was reading it. I don't know that I wanna be talking
Speaker 5:  to t Payne about, you know, like, but there's something in
Speaker 5:  there. What
Speaker 4:  You just described is kind of the story of community on the internet since
Speaker 4:  the beginning of the internet, right? Like,
Speaker 5:  Actually, wait, I want to take this back. I wanna be talking to TPA now that
Speaker 5:  I've, I'm very tired, but I just want it to be
Speaker 5:  actual T-pain, T-pain rules. Like, I just, like, there's no, you should watch
Speaker 5:  this podcast. He's amazing.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, no, T-pain is great. But no, I think the, the question of
Speaker 4:  like, where is your community on the web is a really
Speaker 4:  interesting and important one and is one people have been talking about for
Speaker 4:  25 years, right? Like, you go back far enough and there were people who
Speaker 4:  were like, oh, these kids are talking to other people online that's bad.
Speaker 4:  And we've like come to realize that that's like you, those relationships
Speaker 4:  are real and you that stuff is real. And then it turns
Speaker 4:  again once it's an AI thing. And I think that
Speaker 4:  changes the calculus a little bit. But there are versions of that that are
Speaker 4:  good and valuable and useful. I just think this thing Meta is
Speaker 4:  trying to do, which is not like build tools
Speaker 4:  that are good and useful and sort of human, but like make a thing
Speaker 4:  that looks like Dwayne Wade that will like help
Speaker 4:  me. Or like Snoop Dogg can be the DMM for
Speaker 4:  my Dungeons and Dragons games. Or like random celebrities
Speaker 4:  will help me cook. Like that to me feels like the uncanny valley of
Speaker 4:  all of this. Where it's just like we're, yeah, we're not anywhere with that.
Speaker 4:  To me.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I think what left me kind of like cold on it. 'cause I do
Speaker 6:  think right now I'm trying to play Dungeons and Dragons for the very first
Speaker 6:  time ever. And apparently it is very hard to get a bunch of people coordinated
Speaker 6:  in a room. So like, apparently that Snoop Dogg thing is actually really,
Speaker 6:  really good if you play Dungeons and Dragons. That seems like a really compelling
Speaker 6:  thing. But it just felt a lot like when when Alexa
Speaker 6:  started doing the voices, it felt, it feels like, like it, they just hit
Speaker 6:  me that same way of like, this feels like the technology's not ready
Speaker 6:  yet, so we're having to put like a celebrity layer on top of it
Speaker 6:  to get you to engage.
Speaker 5:  Well this is like the Meta thing. It's like we launched Threads, here's a
Speaker 5:  bunch of celebrities and, and then Yeah. And they've been backing into the,
Speaker 5:  the func the real functionality that will make it successful or
Speaker 5:  not. I I think that's this too. Yeah. Right. It's what
Speaker 5:  you want is I wanna talk to Tom Brady. I don't think anyone's ready, let
Speaker 5:  alone Tom Brady for like, you can just talk to me whenever you want. Right.
Speaker 5:  And that's dangerous if you're a celebrity in a lot of ways. Like
Speaker 5:  whatever. But hey, come play a character and
Speaker 5:  give life to a character that you can talk to with
Speaker 5:  some personality act. I think that's very safe for, it's just playing a role,
Speaker 5:  right?
Speaker 6:  To meta's credit. Like there's a big, there's like big K-pop groups that
Speaker 6:  already do this where you can go talk to an AI and
Speaker 6:  it's, it's like programmed to kind of be like the, the the K-pop
Speaker 6:  star you like. So, so it's out there. This stuff exists
Speaker 6:  already.
Speaker 5:  K-pop is always on the bleeding edge of being really weird. Yeah, right.
Speaker 4:  Also Alex, if you just spoke Apop as AI pop into
Speaker 4:  existence, I'm gonna be furious with you.
Speaker 6:  AI pop. It's coming. Apop.
Speaker 5:  All right, go watch V We have it on our site. Yeah, it's in a quick post
Speaker 5:  you, it's on Yeah. TPAs Instagram or it's on T-Pain TikTok. Go watch
Speaker 5:  the video. It's very strange. But I do
Speaker 4:  Think the more interesting piece of the AI thing is the, is the Meta
Speaker 4:  AI chatbot that they're putting out and putting into basically all of their
Speaker 4:  messaging platforms. You'll be able to get it everywhere. You use Meta
Speaker 4:  products and it's essentially chat g p T, like they're just turning on chat
Speaker 4:  g p t inside of Meta products.
Speaker 5:  No, it's, it's chat. GT is opening eye. They've turned This is their own
Speaker 5:  model. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  But it's like functionally it's, it's the same like the, the goal is
Speaker 5:  They think it's better. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I don't know if it's
Speaker 4:  Better. I don't know if it's better either.
Speaker 6:  We've heard some people say it is, we've heard some people say it is a,
Speaker 6:  we'll just have to find out. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  Yeah, yeah. And they're big on Llama, which is their large language model.
Speaker 4:  Like there's the, this three headed triangle now. Like Amazon just made
Speaker 4:  this big investment in Anthropic. They're gonna do some really interesting
Speaker 4:  stuff over time. Microsoft and open AI are obviously together. Google is
Speaker 4:  doing its own thing and now Meta is doing its own thing and like this race
Speaker 4:  is getting real and really expensive and really high stakes for all four
Speaker 4:  of these companies really Fasts.
Speaker 6:  Really? Yeah. And they're doing art generation too. It's not just, it's not
Speaker 6:  just words like there's gonna be a bunch of stickers where you can just like
Speaker 6:  make something up and do that. And that I'm actually very excited about because
Speaker 6:  like the possibility for trolling my friends is extraordinarily
Speaker 6:  high when I can just make AI generate horrible art for
Speaker 6:  me.
Speaker 5:  Wait, can I say some like deeply diverge Cassie thing about that?
Speaker 6:  No.
Speaker 4:  What is a sticker?
Speaker 5:  What is a sticker? The reason that stickers and
Speaker 5:  memes and reaction gifs and all that stuff is
Speaker 5:  powerful is because they have shared meaning. Yep, yep. Right. So like you,
Speaker 5:  you're like, here's a gif, and like it means something and it carries a whole
Speaker 5:  layers and layers of meaning. When you share it with a friend in response
Speaker 5:  to something else, I'm gonna AI generate some stuff
Speaker 5:  for you. De novo, like over and over again, does not carry that
Speaker 5:  meaning. It's just you talking, it's just you being like, I made up words.
Speaker 6:  You say that, but if you make a horrible enough one, it can
Speaker 6:  be a beam.
Speaker 5:  No, it's true. It it's just like, I, I don't want to, there's a part of this
Speaker 5:  where it's like endlessly customizing everything actually
Speaker 5:  detracts from how we communicate. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Fractures. The fractures, the communication.
Speaker 5:  Well it's just like, it's at the dumbest
Speaker 5:  level. It's like now I have to explain all my jokes to you.
Speaker 5:  Like I made up a joke and I have to explain it to you instead of repeating
Speaker 5:  it or riffing on a thing that already exists is, I know, I know
Speaker 5:  we got some PhDs in our audience who are full of this information.
Speaker 5:  Our, our co-founder and friend Dieter bone deep into
Speaker 5:  semiotics. Like the, the meaning of meaning. This is it. It's like
Speaker 5:  right in there. It's like what if the AI is making up ways for
Speaker 5:  you to communicate that the person on the other end has no context for
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And, but like it, it's stickers like it,
Speaker 5:  it's fine. People aren't gonna use, that's what I'm trying to get at is like
Speaker 5:  if you don't, if you don't get to free ride on the history of meaning, like
Speaker 5:  the stickers are just silly stickers.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Yeah. I mean that's, there's a big giant like huge cultural question
Speaker 4:  in all of that. Right? This everything is becoming endlessly personalized
Speaker 4:  versus we need things that everyone understands in
Speaker 4:  order to communicate about them, which is why the office is so useful. I
Speaker 4:  realized the other day that like most of the screenshots in on my phone are
Speaker 4:  gifs from the office that I just use for infinite purposes. Yeah. All the
Speaker 4:  time. There's a why are you the way that you are a gif that I just use 50
Speaker 4:  times a day and people understand it, it's great. It's very helpful.
Speaker 5:  Do you know those people whose entire personalities as movie quotes? Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Like they're not gonna be out there generating stickers, you
Speaker 6:  Know? That's very true. They're a dying breed. 'cause we don't share that
Speaker 6:  cult, like everybody watches their own things now. So that shared culture
Speaker 6:  is is is dying down to Barbie movie, which is great Barbie movie. Wonderful.
Speaker 6:  But like fewer places of commonality.
Speaker 4:  You're saying people don't run around quoting Oppenheimer to each other all
Speaker 4:  day. Yeah. Why
Speaker 6:  Not? Not, it's not, what's up with that?
Speaker 5:  I'm become deaf. That's, I'm just gonna start sending that to
Speaker 5:  The Verge staff every day.
Speaker 4:  I love it. Alex tell me about The Quest three. Tell Neli
Speaker 4:  about The Quest three. We've been wondering about this thing. We kind of
Speaker 4:  knew what it was. Daylight.
Speaker 6:  It's cool.
Speaker 4:  What are we, what's going on? It's,
Speaker 5:  It looks bananas. Like I was looking at the photo of Addie wearing this thing
Speaker 5:  and I was like, I dunno,
Speaker 6:  I love it. Like we were talking about this in, in Slack the other day and
Speaker 6:  people were like, I hate it. It looks alien. And I'm like, that's exactly
Speaker 6:  why I love it because it looks kind of alien. It's got, it's got these three
Speaker 6:  like little ovals on the front and they look
Speaker 6:  kind of like the iPhone 10 camera module. So it looks like
Speaker 6:  they slapped three of those on there, which feels very like old fashioned
Speaker 6:  and kind of Oh, I've seen that before. But then somehow,
Speaker 5:  And this is, well this is in the service of room tracking of pass through.
Speaker 5:  It's
Speaker 6:  $500. It's got dual
Speaker 6:  2064 by 2208
Speaker 6:  pixels. So it's a much higher resolution than, than the previous one,
Speaker 6:  which was only 1832 by 1920. Like it's gonna be a little
Speaker 6:  sharper and it's got the, the second generation of the
Speaker 6:  Snapdragon XR two processor in it. And that's where a lot of the big stuff
Speaker 6:  changes. So I think like probably the most notable thing, and the thing that
Speaker 6:  that Addie talked about in her hands-on was that the graphics are
Speaker 6:  better on this thing. Like it's, it's, it's, it's things are sharper.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. The resolution's a little higher. Sean was very excited.
Speaker 5:  No one else has this frame of reference 'cause zero people bought a Quest
Speaker 5:  Pro, but I I have one. Is it better than The Quest Pro or worse than The
Speaker 5:  Quest Pro? 'cause Quest Pro is pretty good. Probably
Speaker 6:  About better
Speaker 5:  The software disaster where the hardware is,
Speaker 4:  It's Yeah. From a, from a pure like display
Speaker 4:  quality perspective, it's better than The Quest Pro. Really?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It's actually, it's the highest res thing they've
Speaker 4:  made including The Quest Pro. The, the ongoing existence of The Quest
Speaker 4:  Pro does not make any sense.
Speaker 5:  I So what we should note here is that Alex Heath interviewed
Speaker 5:  Zuckerberg on our site for in the Deco feed. He did. And I think he asked
Speaker 5:  me The Quest Pro and Zucker was like, I got it. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  It's like we just had a bunch around. We had to ship them. But no, it's very
Speaker 4:  clear that this is the one Yeah. That Meta would like to sell you. I mean,
Speaker 4:  Zuckerberg kept saying, and even Andrew Bosworth, the C T O afterwards kept
Speaker 4:  saying this is the first mainstream mixed reality headset.
Speaker 4:  Like that is their phrase. Right. And they're coming after Apple's Vision
Speaker 4:  Pro in a really big way. They made a bunch of jokes about how it doesn't
Speaker 4:  have a cable or a battery pack. Yeah. Which is honestly like a really good
Speaker 4:  burn of the Vision Pro. Yep. It's also not $3,500. So that's
Speaker 4:  good. But that is, that is the pitch that they're making. They're like,
Speaker 4:  this is the one, it's not finished. This is not where we're ultimately
Speaker 4:  headed. Ultimately where we're headed I think they think is, is these smart
Speaker 4:  Glasses, which we should also talk about. But this is the
Speaker 4:  one that is for regular humans now.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It's the end of this form factor. Right. Or like the best version of this
Speaker 5:  form factor you can get right now.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, exactly. And I think they continue to struggle to make the
Speaker 4:  case for why people would want this. Like a lot of what they talked about
Speaker 4:  was video games. They have more games, they have better games, there's stuff
Speaker 4:  to do, but then they occasionally just throw in, you
Speaker 4:  know, Meta Quest for business, but don't really
Speaker 4:  explain that. They're just like, you can have it if you want it for
Speaker 4:  business. That's, that's all we know about that. They talk a little
Speaker 4:  bit about it as an entertainment device, which I think is interesting. Like
Speaker 4:  they, they show the same screenshot that everybody shows, which is just like
Speaker 4:  you can watch, instead of watching one N B A game, you can watch seven
Speaker 4:  N b A games on virtual screens. Yeah. You And that is like extremely my
Speaker 4:  shit. But like I didn't get the sense that there is some sort of brand
Speaker 4:  new life changing use case for this. It just seems like between
Speaker 4:  pass through better screens and just sort of an overall
Speaker 4:  better experience of using the thing. That's
Speaker 5:  Great though. I just wanna be like going from the iPhone three gss, the iPhone
Speaker 5:  four and getting a red retina display is like great.
Speaker 4:  Oh, absolutely. Absolutely. And, and I've, a bunch of us got a demo of
Speaker 4:  this. I, mine was relatively short but I still got to play a couple of the
Speaker 4:  games and stuff. It is, I mean, leaps and bounds better
Speaker 4:  than The Quest two, like the, the pass through is is not perfect.
Speaker 4:  It's a little sort of, it's a little sort of Warpy like the floor
Speaker 4:  was moving a little bit, but
Speaker 6:  It's better than the Pro
Speaker 4:  Oh better than the Pro Way better than The Quest two, which is like black
Speaker 4:  and white and essentially doesn't actually work as pass through. Not as good
Speaker 4:  as the demo I got at the Vision of the Vision Pro. But that was super controlled.
Speaker 4:  Who knows what that'll be like in real life. But yeah, this is a
Speaker 4:  massive improvement over The Quest too. Whether it will make people who didn't
Speaker 4:  care about headsets, care about headsets to me is still the open question.
Speaker 4:  Right. Like that's what I don't know. But if you're a person who cares about
Speaker 4:  headsets gigantic upgrade,
Speaker 6:  I kind of think it didn't sell itself well enough. Like,
Speaker 6:  like talking to Addie, talking to you, talking to people who got to actually
Speaker 6:  try the thing was much more compelling than to me than watching the
Speaker 6:  actual keynote about the product.
Speaker 5:  I think this is gonna be true for every VR headset, including the Vision
Speaker 5:  Pro forever. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And well that's just very interesting to me 'cause Addie like told me about
Speaker 6:  it and she's like, oh yeah, the pastor is way, way, way better. And I was
Speaker 6:  like, oh dang, I kinda want it just for that. That sounds really cool. And
Speaker 6:  then I don't see any of that on stage and I'm like, well I'm glad
Speaker 6:  Addie told me.
Speaker 4:  It really is one of the great unsolved problems of VR is how to show
Speaker 4:  someone what you're seeing in VR in a way that looks at all
Speaker 4:  compelling. 'cause your options are either like show it on the two screens,
Speaker 4:  one's for each eye, which just doesn't make any sense to anybody. Or you
Speaker 4:  just show it like a like slightly low res television. It's like this doesn't
Speaker 4:  mean anything to anybody. Yeah. And I, I've been hearing this from people
Speaker 4:  in this space for like damn near a decade now that they're like, when we
Speaker 4:  put this on someone's head, they get it. Yeah. And until you
Speaker 4:  put it on someone's head, it is so hard to explain what it is
Speaker 4:  about it that works.
Speaker 5:  The only things I've ever seen do you know, there's people who play Beat
Speaker 5:  Saber and they feel entire green screen rooms. Yeah. And so like
Speaker 5:  they, they're doing like real life overlays. Yeah. They, everyone's just
Speaker 5:  gotta do that. That's, that's my feeling. But the problem is like so many
Speaker 5:  things are like sitting and using a computer like Quest for business is
Speaker 5:  like now you'll, you'll excel. It's like this
Speaker 5:  sucks. Yes.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Very large Excel
Speaker 6:  And the price doesn't, I think the big problem is the price doesn't help.
Speaker 6:  Like one of the reasons The Quest two was so compelling was you're like,
Speaker 6:  wow, I can get this for $300 when it was first announced. Right. And they've
Speaker 6:  now dropped that price back down to $300 after like a brief time of
Speaker 6:  increasing the price and so little, little
Speaker 6:  wave there. And that was really compelling. Like I went out and bought it
Speaker 6:  the day it was announced 'cause it was like that price is so low. I didn't
Speaker 6:  get the $300 one, I spent more money but I was still like, wow, I'm getting
Speaker 6:  such a deal. This is great. And then this one is still $500. That's the same
Speaker 6:  price as a PSS five or an Xbox. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  This is very hard to justify as an impulse purchase
Speaker 5:  at Christmas. The way that I think a lot of Quest twos got sold
Speaker 5:  is sort of like, what tech present? Am I buying the kids for Christmas?
Speaker 5:  Because it was like that, the lower number.
Speaker 6:  And I think that's gonna harm adoption 'cause 'cause of that fact that you
Speaker 6:  have to put it on, you have to try it or you have to know somebody who
Speaker 6:  has to really be compelled by it.
Speaker 5:  Or it actually, I, I think what makes it even harder is it's like
Speaker 5:  not a console generation, right? It's not PS four to PSS five. A lot of people
Speaker 5:  have Quest twos 'cause of what happened last Christmas and the Christmas
Speaker 5:  before it. Yeah. And it's like, oh that's just sitting on the shelf.
Speaker 4:  Although, I don't know, I think this one is gonna be a little bit tough because
Speaker 4:  I think the The Quest three is gonna make
Speaker 4:  The Quest four a console generation because what it's gonna do, like
Speaker 4:  everybody's gonna spend the next year building actually usable mixed reality
Speaker 4:  stuff because for the first time it's worth doing. Like the pass through
Speaker 4:  stuff is good enough and
Speaker 5:  The Vision Pro is there, right?
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And so we're, we're now gonna get to a point where there is an actual
Speaker 4:  generation of stuff to do that takes advantage of this tech. Whereas right
Speaker 4:  now it's like a lot of the reason for the mixed reality
Speaker 4:  is, and they even pitch it this way so that like I can find my
Speaker 4:  coffee cup or look at my phone without taking my headset off. Which
Speaker 4:  is useful. It's a bad reason to buy a product. And
Speaker 4:  so there just hasn't, they need the thing and that
Speaker 4:  will come and it can come now, which is really exciting. But I think it's
Speaker 4:  gonna make, it's gonna make the selling point for next year's model much
Speaker 4:  easier. But I don't know how much it does for like right now. Do
Speaker 6:  You think it'll be next year's model? Yeah. Or do you think they'll wait
Speaker 6:  a few years? That's the problem is I don't think they're, I think they're
Speaker 6:  still at console level, not at phone level in encouraging upgrade
Speaker 6:  cycles. And I think if they, that could be true. Release a new one next
Speaker 6:  year. It's just gonna be like, well why? Like at what point do
Speaker 6:  I actually invest in this very expensive thing that isn't always reliably
Speaker 6:  backwards compatible that is like growing each year by these
Speaker 6:  leaps and bounds. Shouldn't I just wait until next year? Shouldn't I just
Speaker 6:  wait until next year? Shouldn't I just wait for another price drop? Yeah.
Speaker 6:  But I think they need to be a little more thoughtful about how they're marketing
Speaker 6:  this thing and and pricing it. But I still also
Speaker 6:  kind of want one.
Speaker 4:  Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Yeah, that's about right. And I think that's like the best case scenario
Speaker 5:  for them.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. It is. Like Christmas, somebody gives me like a little Best Buy gift
Speaker 6:  card. I'm like, yeah,
Speaker 5:  Somebody wants to throw me 500 bucks, you know, maybe I'm not equest,
Speaker 6:  I'll spend it, spend it not on Legos.
Speaker 4:  It, it seems clear that what Meta did here was say
Speaker 4:  we have to stop building the best possible cheap thing and just
Speaker 4:  build a thing that's really good and then charge what we have to. I think
Speaker 4:  Apple went the same route to like the nth
Speaker 4:  degree, but Meta has been on this path and like Snap has
Speaker 4:  been doing this and others have been doing this where they're like, these
Speaker 4:  things have to be cheap. They have to be impulse buys. You have to be able
Speaker 4:  to buy 'em for Christmas and we're gonna make them as good as we can and
Speaker 4:  they'll get better and better over time. And that hasn't really worked because
Speaker 4:  it's still not possible to make a really good one for that price. I don't
Speaker 4:  have any reporting to back this up, but I would bet good money that
Speaker 4:  this hardware is not going to be earth shatteringly high margin for
Speaker 4:  Meta. These things are expensive to build and hard to
Speaker 4:  build. And I think Meta was smart to say
Speaker 4:  like, this is the bar for what quality is and we just have to charge what
Speaker 4:  it costs to build this and yeah, let that get cheaper over time
Speaker 4:  as opposed to like, hoping quality goes up over time because that I just
Speaker 4:  don't think has worked so far. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  It looks cool
Speaker 5:  Though. And this is, by the way, we should talk about the heath interview
Speaker 5:  with Zuck. Yeah. Zuck makes this point, right? Like making things smaller
Speaker 5:  and cheaper is actually very hard. And he, he, there's a,
Speaker 5:  we we can even watch the, we should go watch the whole thing. It's great.
Speaker 5:  But we have a TikTok app where he is like, people are impressed by the pyramids
Speaker 5:  but it's actually small things that are
Speaker 6:  More impressive.
Speaker 4:  The beginning of his history channel show.
Speaker 5:  One more thing I I wanna, I wanna bring up out of the heath interview. The
Speaker 5:  heath interview is great. Mark is super loose, super
Speaker 5:  relaxed, talks a lot about building products, actually he's relaxed about
Speaker 5:  two things. It's building products. He's like back in builder mode and he's
Speaker 5:  like, this is what's great. Like the last few years I've needed to be like
Speaker 5:  this First Amendment scholar, statesman person person. But like now I'm building
Speaker 5:  shit again. And he can tell how loose and then he is super loose when he
Speaker 5:  talks about beating people up
Speaker 6:  So loose.
Speaker 5:  Loves it, just loves hitting a guy. And that's like great. It's like this
Speaker 5:  is the most personality. But he loves like m M A as a sport, not just
Speaker 5:  like streak fight. Just be clear, I'm very
Speaker 5:  tired.
Speaker 6:  He's just out there punching people on the street.
Speaker 5:  But he like talks about it and he talks about how the skill and discipline
Speaker 5:  and they're like, you can see he's relaxed, like he's back in his zone as
Speaker 5:  opposed to Senator we sell ads, you know
Speaker 5:  like, and there's a lot of talking with The Quest three and
Speaker 5:  building that and what they've learned and all this stuff. There's a lot
Speaker 5:  talking about building Threads and how excited that's made him
Speaker 5:  and one more confirmation that they're definitely gonna decentralize and
Speaker 5:  federate Threads, which I think is really
Speaker 4:  Cool. Yeah. And he made the case you would hope he would make, which is that
Speaker 4:  like we think that the future of social, we have to give
Speaker 4:  people confidence that these things are going to be around. And it's like,
Speaker 4:  yes Mark, where have you been for 20 years?
Speaker 5:  Right? He's like, we've thought about doing a Facebook but Facebook is too
Speaker 5:  complicated so you have to do it from the beginning, which is like cool,
Speaker 5:  you know, and
Speaker 4:  True. Like I think that's a re like re-architecting Facebook for
Speaker 4:  activity pub is probably not possible. It's just,
Speaker 4:  yeah. Can
Speaker 6:  We talk about the coolest part of the Beta connect?
Speaker 4:  Was it how ripped Mark Zuckerberg was? I said it like three times as we were
Speaker 4:  sitting watching the live stream. Like I cannot believe how shredded this
Speaker 4:  dude is.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Like we, I think we were all just quietly slacking each other just
Speaker 6:  being like Yoel. Wow. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  It sucks Yoed It
Speaker 6:  Was the Glasses, the Glasses were something that I think hearing about
Speaker 6:  them, it was the opposite of The Quest three. Somebody would tell me about
Speaker 6:  The Quest three and I'd be like, oh that sounds really, really cool. But
Speaker 6:  I'd watch the demo and I'd be like, that's eh. And then this one I'd watch
Speaker 6:  the demo for the Glasses and be like, eh. And then they talk about the Glasses.
Speaker 6:  I was like, actually these, these sound cool. Like I want these Glasses
Speaker 4:  Convince me I have been back and forth on this a million times. Smart Glasses
Speaker 4:  to me are either a thing that everyone should have immediately or an objectively
Speaker 4:  stupid idea that just should not exist. And I genuinely go between them 10
Speaker 4:  times a day. Convince me they're cool. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  I I I do too. 'cause I have to wear Glasses and I don't wanna go
Speaker 6:  like get new lenses for these
Speaker 6:  $300 frames, which is probably the same price as most frames
Speaker 6:  anyway. Like that price isn't that different. But
Speaker 6:  they, they were good looking. And then the woman that did the presentation
Speaker 6:  for was like, had such good energy. Oh yeah. She was so
Speaker 6:  excited to be there and talk about these Glasses that I was
Speaker 6:  like, are they really awesome? Yeah, these seem
Speaker 6:  awesome. And I think it was like the camera, it was just like the,
Speaker 6:  the, the way the cameras work, the camera's much higher quality than it has
Speaker 6:  been previously. I don't think I, I can't think of a practical use case for
Speaker 6:  these Glasses. 'cause they, they've got the, they've got the audio in them,
Speaker 6:  so, so you'll be able to hear stuff and you'll be able to like
Speaker 6:  use your phone to ask it. You can ask it questions and the
Speaker 6:  the responses will pop up on your phone and that seems like kind of cool
Speaker 6:  and moving towards that mixed reality thing. And then it's got the, the
Speaker 6:  cameras that will, that will like stream to Threads and stream to, to
Speaker 6:  Instagram and do all of that. And that seems really, really cool. And I don't
Speaker 6:  think I actually wanna be that connected to other people. But at the same
Speaker 6:  time part of me was like, but don't I
Speaker 4:  So thi this is actually the exact, like, it was weird tension that I have
Speaker 4:  been feeling too. And Neil, I've been wondering all week about you because
Speaker 4:  I remember when you first had a kid,
Speaker 4:  one of the things that you did pretty quickly was buy a point and shoot camera
Speaker 4:  because you were like, I wanna take a lot of pictures, I wanna document a
Speaker 4:  lot of stuff, but I don't want to have my phone in front of my face all the
Speaker 4:  time. For lots of obvious reasons. And that is the exact use case
Speaker 4:  that all of these companies make for smart Glasses. Like there are
Speaker 4:  kids in the demo reel for every single one of these. Right? Always. Always.
Speaker 4:  'cause like you can have both hands, you can swing your kid around whatever,
Speaker 4:  but you, you are less, there's not so much of a thing between
Speaker 4:  you and especially not a thing that is otherwise trying to grab your attention.
Speaker 4:  Well there's
Speaker 5:  One thing between you and your kid, you're wearing
Speaker 5:  sunglasses.
Speaker 6:  You can get them in regular frame
Speaker 4:  Get with prescription lenses.
Speaker 5:  There's like, there's, there's one thing
Speaker 4:  You can get transition lenses. My dad wears transitions. They're
Speaker 4:  fine.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, your dad and like every fourth grader who just got their first pair
Speaker 5:  of Glasses, I was that child. That boy was me. It
Speaker 5:  was not cool. My friends, everyone, someone please go to fourth
Speaker 5:  grades across the country and tell these children
Speaker 4:  Wow. This is, this is Joey Slater that I will not tolerate. Sorry
Speaker 4:  dad.
Speaker 6:  I had an adult person try to help me to get transition
Speaker 6:  Glasses recently.
Speaker 5:  No, it's fine. Once you've like a achieved in life. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  It's
Speaker 5:  Okay. You can have transition lessons. I
Speaker 4:  See. Okay.
Speaker 6:  That's what that was. That was the case made to me. They're like, no, no,
Speaker 6:  you're, you're, you can do it now. You're an adult.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It's your children are at the house, you're married, you got a grandkid.
Speaker 5:  You're like, yeah, just take a load off bro. Just have sunglasses
Speaker 5:  ready to go when you're in fourth grade. It's not just
Speaker 5:  tell the children
Speaker 6:  They're just gray all the time. These little kids in gray
Speaker 6:  lenses.
Speaker 5:  It was so weird. 1980s in Wisconsin. Anyway, yes, this is the argument. The
Speaker 5:  problem is the camera's any good, but my RX 100 is a great camera.
Speaker 5:  That's why I bought it. My iPhone is a
Speaker 5:  extremely complicated philosophical quandary of a
Speaker 5:  camera. That's why I have it. This is like, I'll have it, I'll get my
Speaker 5:  hands back, but I'm gonna take shittier photos. Who doesn't love
Speaker 5:  12 megapixel single non H D R photos. People
Speaker 6:  Love it More than five megapixels, which was the previous one.
Speaker 5:  That's true. And that's true. I haven't seen the photos, but that's always,
Speaker 5:  to me it's like, you know, what's the the phrase the best camera's, the one
Speaker 5:  you have with you. I always have an amazing camera with me.
Speaker 6:  Your Glasses, right?
Speaker 5:  I i my Glasses my transition lenses. I know I always,
Speaker 5:  my phone's around, you know, and I, I bought a really nice
Speaker 5:  camera so I could divest myself of the phone. But I don't
Speaker 5:  think having a more convenient camera. I dunno,
Speaker 5:  maybe I haven't seen the photos. I haven't like used a thing again,
Speaker 5:  blind reacts to the, the right hand Glasses.
Speaker 5:  But you know, I, I don't know. Like it's, it's more technology and when
Speaker 5:  I was what David, to your point, I was after less.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And I think, I think to me like, it's very clear that Meta
Speaker 4:  does not see these smart Glasses as like the end point of smart
Speaker 4:  Glasses, right? Yeah. Like at the end of Connect Mark, Dr. Berg got up and
Speaker 4:  did the like almost sort of Steve Jobs impression of like, you
Speaker 4:  know, when he was like, it's a widescreen iPod, it's a phone, it's an internet
Speaker 4:  communicator. And he was like, he showed it, he was like, we have The Quest
Speaker 4:  three headset, we have all this AI communication
Speaker 4:  stuff and Then, we have smart Glasses. And the case he
Speaker 4:  made is that like the end state of this is that the first two things, The,
Speaker 4:  Quest and the AI stuff are going to end up in the Glasses,
Speaker 4:  right? Yeah. Like he's like, this is the form factor and we're gonna pull
Speaker 4:  this stuff into it over time. And I
Speaker 4:  don't know how long that's gonna take or if that's ever gonna happen, but
Speaker 4:  I believe them that that's the vision. And I think the question we've been
Speaker 4:  asking for a bunch of years now is like, is there anything interesting along
Speaker 4:  the way? Yeah. And to me, just purely from a personal
Speaker 4:  perspective, the cameras don't do anything for me. Partly because I think
Speaker 4:  the like real world creepiness factor is still really real.
Speaker 4:  And I don't, I don't know how to sort through that even. It's very high.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It's just like, even just like walking around, like if you just walk
Speaker 4:  around a city just holding up your phone, like you might be
Speaker 4:  taking a pic, you're gonna creep people out, right? It's like whether or
Speaker 4:  not you're actually doing anything, it feels bad. And so I have not sorted
Speaker 4:  through how to deal with that. But I do think the, the thing
Speaker 4:  I'm most excited to see about these Glasses is whether
Speaker 4:  the mic and headphones are good because it's
Speaker 4:  essentially they're trying to do this like personal audio speaker thing where
Speaker 4:  you can hear it but nobody else can. It has five mics in the Glasses, including
Speaker 4:  one on your nose that's supposed to do a better job of picking up your voice,
Speaker 4:  which makes sense. If that works. That's pretty
Speaker 4:  cool. I don't like being a person who wears
Speaker 4:  AirPods all the time. I would like to be a person who wears AirPods
Speaker 4:  less. And so if that's the kind of thing that I can use, like if
Speaker 4:  I'm out on a walk or whatever, that's compelling to
Speaker 4:  me. But also like it's whatever, it's 250 bucks am I gonna
Speaker 4:  buy, I don't wear Glasses anyway. If I already wore Glasses, I think I would
Speaker 4:  be slowly talking myself into this. But as somebody who doesn't otherwise
Speaker 4:  wear Glasses, that's a big leap.
Speaker 6:  I mean that, that's, that's why I'm like, ooh, I like, maybe I
Speaker 6:  should get a pair of these the next time I go get my prescription updated.
Speaker 4:  I mean a pair of wayfarers is like $165. You're not that far
Speaker 4:  away to add all this other stuff.
Speaker 5:  I, we're all learning an important lesson about the amount of margin containing
Speaker 4:  Yeah. A pair of wayfarers. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Maybe this is gonna drop, start dropping the prices of regular
Speaker 6:  Glasses.
Speaker 5:  I only buy $20 sunglasses 'cause I lose them. And I think I've, I just realized,
Speaker 5:  I came to my conclusion
Speaker 4:  Same. I bought one nice pair of sunglasses and I said, if I lose these
Speaker 4:  within a year, I'm never allowed to buy nice sunglasses again. I lost them
Speaker 4:  in three days. I don't, they're just gone.
Speaker 4:  And so now I buy, I buy $15 sunglasses like four times a year. It's
Speaker 4:  great.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I bought prescription sunglasses. I have had them 10 years.
Speaker 6:  The prescription's no longer accurate. Perfect. But I still have the Glasses.
Speaker 6:  Perfect. I probably shouldn't drive with them. It's fine.
Speaker 5:  I will just say this here. You know, everyone thinks this is a form factor.
Speaker 5:  Apple thinks this is a form factor. What the most compelling applications
Speaker 5:  that are being built in the space are all virtual reality applications.
Speaker 5:  Even Apple, right? When you look at their demos, it's like your court side
Speaker 5:  at the N B A or like there's a dinosaur eating you or whatever. They're all
Speaker 5:  VR applications. There are no compelling
Speaker 5:  mixed reality or AR applications yet because they
Speaker 6:  Haven't figured out the privacy
Speaker 5:  Well sure. But they, they just, they can't even demo. Even my demo, my
Speaker 5:  killer app. I will pay any amount of money for it. Right? Just show me people's
Speaker 5:  names. I was just at this conference, the amount of time I spent squinting
Speaker 5:  at people's badges, which is just really a weird thing to
Speaker 5:  do. By the way, if you're ever hosting a conference, make the names bigger
Speaker 5:  on the badges. That's my one note. And now that I'm a conference host, well
Speaker 5:  the font sizes next year are gonna be bananas. It's, it's out of
Speaker 5:  control. It's huge. Everyone's gonna carry around like yard
Speaker 5:  signs with their name on them. This is my killer app. This is the thing I
Speaker 5:  want the most faces and names. It incredibly difficult to do in a
Speaker 5:  privacy centric way. You might have to build a, a worldwide facial recognition
Speaker 5:  data, but all very hard. Even that, right? That that it's
Speaker 5:  not built because of those problems. But it's the killer app for ar. No one
Speaker 5:  can do it. All of the ones are building along the way are vr and that is
Speaker 5:  in conflict with our belief about what the form
Speaker 5:  factor will be. Because you have to block out the world in to
Speaker 5:  do VR Well, and a pair of Glasses does, does
Speaker 5:  not by definition does not do that. And I was having dinner with a
Speaker 5:  friend at the conference and they're like, oh yeah, but we'll just like do
Speaker 5:  the things on the sides. And I'm like, what kind of like
Speaker 5:  mad Max like bullshit. Are you trying to sell me right
Speaker 5:  now?
Speaker 6:  Good. No, you looked, just looked like you had cataract surgery.
Speaker 5:  No. That you're gonna look like will I am in a like an early two thousands
Speaker 5:  video? God, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Speaker 6:  No's a bad look. Don't do that.
Speaker 5:  So like, I'm just saying like all of the best applications that we're building
Speaker 5:  are VR applications and everyone thinks the form factor will, will
Speaker 5:  make those applications go away unless you solve this like block out the
Speaker 5:  world problem. And like, I don't, that's weird. There, there's a tension
Speaker 5:  there that I think, like you said, David, we're figuring out if there's anything
Speaker 5:  interesting along the way. The thing that's interesting to me along the way
Speaker 5:  is the absolute tension between what's, why you would put
Speaker 5:  a computer on your face and the form factor of whatever it wants that computer
Speaker 5:  to be
Speaker 4:  Or has to be at the right. We're very much in the like Yeah. You know,
Speaker 4:  1990s desktop tower PC thing where the only version of it
Speaker 4:  weighs a thousand pounds and has to live. Yeah. On your wood
Speaker 4:  office Max setup. Please keep sending us your old desk setups. We love them
Speaker 4:  so much.
Speaker 5:  We're gonna make a coffee table book. I want to be clear about this. This
Speaker 5:  is my goal. It's a coffee table book called Computer Rooms and Then. We're
Speaker 5:  gonna retire and we're gonna buy a boat and that book and that boat will
Speaker 5:  be called the Computer Room. And I've just been thinking about this
Speaker 5:  plan the whole time.
Speaker 4:  I love it. Alright, we need to take one more break and Then we're gonna come
Speaker 4:  back. We're gonna talk about the rider strike real quick and Then, we're
Speaker 4:  gonna do a little lightning round and Then, we're gonna get outta here. We'll
Speaker 4:  be right
Speaker 4:  back.
Speaker 6:  be reaching a conclusion. Everybody was starting to get kind of excited
Speaker 6:  about whatever contract was coming. Contract is
Speaker 6:  out now. The the Guild still has to vote on it. So both the
Speaker 6:  Writers Guild of America, east and West, both of them still have
Speaker 6:  to vote on it. Everybody's still reading over it. They released a Summary
Speaker 6:  Tuesday night and then they, the next day they release the
Speaker 6:  actual contract. So you can go and if you want to, you can go pour through
Speaker 6:  the whole thing. We, we have like a, a little Summary of it up on the
Speaker 6:  website as well. And there's a lot of big stuff in it. They got almost everything
Speaker 6:  they wanted as far as AI goes. So there's a lot of AI protections in
Speaker 6:  it. You're not gonna be able to go ask AI to
Speaker 6:  come up with a plot and then take that to a writer and make a writer write
Speaker 6:  it. And then you keep the, the rights to that story. You're not gonna be
Speaker 6:  able to do that. The, the writer will maintain the rights to the story 'cause
Speaker 6:  AI cannot, AI generated content cannot have rights according to
Speaker 6:  this contract, which is probably good. I think that was really
Speaker 6:  exciting. I know I spoke to a few, few writers who were really, really excited
Speaker 6:  about that part of it and excited to just have that protection to,
Speaker 6:  that helps maintain the status quo. And then the thing that's really gonna
Speaker 6:  change the status quo is the
Speaker 6:  data. There's now going to be data that the Writer's Guild is gonna
Speaker 6:  receive from these streamers like Netflix,
Speaker 6:  Amazon, all these people who have been super, super opaque about their data.
Speaker 6:  They're not gonna be able to be opaque with the Writer's Guild itself. A
Speaker 6:  lot of that data's not gonna come to the rest of us because it's,
Speaker 6:  you know, they still don't want everybody to know their numbers. But the
Speaker 6:  writer's GU will be able to release it in aggregate and the fact that the
Speaker 6:  numbers are even gonna be out there just changes things. Yeah. Like
Speaker 6:  it's a town. People talk, people are gonna know those numbers.
Speaker 4:  That seems like the bet. Right. I was listening to an interview with Adam
Speaker 4:  Conver, who's a, a writer who's on the negotiating committee for the the
Speaker 4:  Guild. And I forget who, who he was talking to. I wish I could cite the
Speaker 4:  podcast I was listening to, but he basically was like, if you
Speaker 4:  reporters want the number, maybe you should make a journalist's union and
Speaker 4:  go fight with studios. I don't care about you. I'm trying to get numbers
Speaker 4:  for my people. But then what he basically said is like, between,
Speaker 4:  between the numbers that are gonna get reported to the Guild and the fact
Speaker 4:  that this business is shifting towards advertising, like we're just gonna
Speaker 4:  start to know more. It's, they're just, the numbers are going to be reported
Speaker 4:  to more people. People talk. It's gonna start to be out there in much bigger
Speaker 4:  ways. And I think that's true, but it does seem like, like there there was
Speaker 4:  some rubric they invented for like total
Speaker 4:  hours watched of something. It's like we're we're still inventing the new
Speaker 4:  numbers of what all of these things mean. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  They're still new numbers, but I think because they're enshrined in
Speaker 6:  a contract, they'll probably start to stabilize a as the new
Speaker 6:  numbers. Right. We talked about that on the podcast earlier this week and
Speaker 6:  the numbers, they've always been fake. They've always been not real
Speaker 6:  and everybody just agreed, okay, these not real numbers are the ones we're
Speaker 6:  gonna use. And so now we have new numbers that are probably the most realistic
Speaker 6:  numbers we've had for, for streaming or, or broadcast
Speaker 6:  television, if I'm being honest. Like these, these are numbers that like
Speaker 6:  are very, very trackable, very understood.
Speaker 6:  And they're different. It's total hours of
Speaker 6:  something streamed I think is, is it? And that's like kind of goofy,
Speaker 6:  but it's it's a real number. You know it but it does mean that
Speaker 6:  like if 300 million people watch the first 15 minutes of
Speaker 6:  something, that could be the same as if one person
Speaker 6:  watches it 300 billion times. Yes. Which real, very real possibility
Speaker 6:  because there are some weirdos out there. I'm
Speaker 4:  One of them like Alex Cramps, Alex
Speaker 6:  Like me
Speaker 5:  Speaking of K-Pop fans, I have, I have an important piece of information.
Speaker 5:  Yes. So one of our sponsors at Code was Illuminate, which formerly
Speaker 5:  Nielsen scan scan, they do the billboard charts. So I was talking to 'em,
Speaker 5:  hanging out, it was really fun. They did a session and they were talking
Speaker 5:  about how they measure things. Did you know that at the platform level, if
Speaker 5:  you streams something more than 50 times in a day doesn't count
Speaker 5:  because really there's K-Pop fans. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  You just tap out at 50.
Speaker 5:  Yep. That's it. If you, if you're more than 50 times a day, they're like,
Speaker 5:  that's you didn't do it. You, that's not
Speaker 4:  Becausecause. You're either but do you get the 50?
Speaker 5:  I don't it, I that's proprietary
Speaker 5:  weirdness. Interesting. Right, but like if you talk to the people who measure
Speaker 5:  things Luminate, which makes the charts with
Speaker 5:  Billboard. Yeah. They're like, yep. There's, at the platform
Speaker 5:  level we like K-pop fans are like our
Speaker 5:  antagonists.
Speaker 4:  So everything you love you can only stream 49 times
Speaker 5:  A day. Yeah. And then, and then there's still some like
Speaker 5:  algorithmic renormalization and I think this is now
Speaker 5:  coming, this is my thesis, like all Yeah, whatever happens to the music industry
Speaker 5:  happens to everyone else five years later, this is now gonna come to
Speaker 5:  streaming television because if you're a writer or you
Speaker 5:  have a fandom and there's gonna be an aggregate number that everyone agrees
Speaker 5:  on, you're, you're necessarily gonna go try to game that number.
Speaker 6:  They, I mean the, the fans already do that. Like if they think there shows
Speaker 5:  Right. But there's no transparency. Right. Right.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, yeah. Right. Right now it was kind of like we're working because it
Speaker 6:  showed up in the Netflix top 10 or we're working because some, some company
Speaker 6:  did analysis and said,
Speaker 5:  And Void is showing up the Netflix top 10 not guarantee you a goddamn thing,
Speaker 5:  nothing canceled in the middle of the first
Speaker 5:  episode.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. But not only that, I mean the platforms also have, you know,
Speaker 4:  a hundred thumbs to put on the scale at any given time. Like the, the, what
Speaker 4:  Netflix chooses to show you in that big banner when you open the
Speaker 4:  app is very meaningful.
Speaker 5:  And the top 10 is like very localized. Like the here's the top 10 things
Speaker 5:  in your house, it's the show that you were the EP of and you're like, oh
Speaker 5:  this is
Speaker 6:  Right. It's always the shows that they've already canceled. It's like, Alex,
Speaker 6:  do you wanna watch this show? We just canceled. And I'm like, I do and I
Speaker 6:  hate you. So, so yeah. I like the this the what what this
Speaker 6:  contract, this contract is straight up historic though also because like,
Speaker 6:  there were a lot of big price increases in it, particularly around streaming.
Speaker 6:  Streaming is not lucrative if you're a writer just straight up before this,
Speaker 6:  it was not lucrative. You could barely make ends meet for the vast majority
Speaker 6:  of people. And the, the studios have gotten really good about gaming
Speaker 6:  the system that existed to pay as little as possible.
Speaker 6:  And this kind of ended a lot of that gaming. It's still gonna
Speaker 6:  happen. People are still gonna get screwed outta money that that is the nature
Speaker 6:  of business. But, but this is, this contract
Speaker 6:  really put some really strong guardrails in particularly around streaming.
Speaker 6:  Like they were, they were anticipating, I think it's like a 26%
Speaker 6:  increase in, in revenue for writers of
Speaker 6:  streaming films that make that have a budget of 30 million or
Speaker 6:  more. So all those really big Netflix, apple TV films and stuff
Speaker 6:  where previously they probably weren't getting a lot of money for that. They're
Speaker 6:  now gonna be be getting like at least a hundred thousand dollars and that's
Speaker 6:  nice. That, that seems nice to me. So, so yeah,
Speaker 6:  this was like very historic. SAG is still on
Speaker 6:  strike, but there's a lot of movement there. People were kind of
Speaker 6:  expecting this to be the way WGA goes. They get this really good
Speaker 6:  deal SAG is gonna get a lot of similar stuff because of that
Speaker 6:  deal and be able to close things. And if you were in the Director's Guild
Speaker 6:  of America, I don't know what to tell you. You guys decided on
Speaker 6:  your contract before everybody else went on strike. Well
Speaker 5:  I think they, they might have known that the writers were
Speaker 6:  Yeah, they do. They knew. And, and, and their contract is by
Speaker 6:  comparison not nearly as good. Ah,
Speaker 5:  They're directors.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, they're directors. They're fine. They got their producer credit. Like
Speaker 6:  they can just put themselves in as an actor or a writer. They'll find other
Speaker 6:  ways to make the money. Oh,
Speaker 5:  Every director now does a cameo.
Speaker 4:  It's
Speaker 6:  Gonna be great.
Speaker 5:  I will say the, the Casey on SIA code was like we're doing, we
Speaker 5:  held true detective because we wanted the, we wanted Jodi
Speaker 5:  Foster to be available to promote the show. We wanted people to be able to
Speaker 5:  talk about it and it's like, oh, the SAG deal isn't done. But they're very
Speaker 5:  confident that the writers deal is gonna give him the actors deal.
Speaker 5:  Yeah,
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Because so much of the debate is about the same stuff
Speaker 4:  and I think, I think it, it, it definitely seemed to be that it was likely
Speaker 4:  for the Gil to get the deal done first and then there's gonna be a lot of
Speaker 4:  copying and pasting from this deal to that deal. Yeah. Especially it seems
Speaker 4:  with the AI stuff. And I thought one of the most interesting parts of the
Speaker 4:  AI piece of this deal was essentially that they
Speaker 4:  punted on the question of training data. Like, can you use
Speaker 4:  our work to train AI
Speaker 4:  models that can make other screenplays
Speaker 6:  That there was a very specific reason for that. And that's because there's
Speaker 6:  so much like law laws that are potentially going to
Speaker 6:  in effect. So why hold onto this bargaining
Speaker 6:  chip when you know that California, this like, I think it was last week,
Speaker 6:  California said we're gonna look into regulating trading data and, and making
Speaker 6:  sure compensation happens and stuff.
Speaker 4:  I will bet you $10 right now that this deal gets renegotiated again before
Speaker 4:  anybody makes a law on that. Yeah. Right.
Speaker 5:  If you know that you're, you're operating in three year cycles, you're like,
Speaker 5:  eh, will
Speaker 4:  That, that's what I mean. Like I think you're right Alex, but I think, I
Speaker 4:  think everybody was just like, who the hell knows? Like, let's come back
Speaker 4:  and do this again in three years. If it gets weird, there's a line in here
Speaker 4:  that lets us yell at you. If it gets weird, that's good enough for now. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And I, I thought that was really smart on, on their part. Like, okay,
Speaker 6:  we're gonna kick this can down the road. Maybe something happens, maybe something
Speaker 6:  doesn't, we got three years to figure it out.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It's just, it's just a funny acknowledgement of like, no one really
Speaker 4:  knows anything. So like, let's just be cool for now and we'll
Speaker 4:  figure this out later. I thought that was like, that was just a funny place
Speaker 4:  for that to land. Alright, let's do a lightning
Speaker 4:  round. We are already very long, so let's just blow
Speaker 4:  through this, hit some more news and get out of here. I will go first
Speaker 4:  so you guys can come up with your own Neli. You can quickly read five
Speaker 4:  Days of The Verge and catch up and see where you are. Oh,
Speaker 5:  I know. I already picked mine. It's very obvious. No, no, that one's mine.
Speaker 5:  Alex Alex and I are fighting in the Google
Speaker 5:  Doc. There's like two
Speaker 5:  cursors, like furiously selecting lines in the Google Doc.
Speaker 4:  There's a lot happening right now. Mine is, there's this big shift
Speaker 4:  in the podcast world. I feel like we gotta talk about podcasts. On podcasts.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Google is killing Google Podcasts because it's all in on YouTube
Speaker 4:  music as the home of podcasts. I just like a random side
Speaker 4:  note is I hate the fact that there are apps called Amazon Music and YouTube
Speaker 4:  Music and they're podcast apps, like bad names everybody like
Speaker 4:  You, you screwed up. But anyway, Google podcast is going away because Google
Speaker 4:  can't stop killing its apps, but it's all in on YouTube as a
Speaker 4:  podcast platform. YouTube music has been like a sneaky place
Speaker 4:  of investment for YouTube for a long time now. And they're getting much louder
Speaker 4:  about like, we really think this is our subscription business going forward.
Speaker 4:  That's really interesting. Apple Podcasts is going the
Speaker 4:  other way. They're they're integrating a lot of stuff from outside of podcasts
Speaker 4:  into podcasts, including some of the like radio stuff that they've been
Speaker 4:  doing. Some of the different like meditation
Speaker 4:  stuff that they've been doing. There's just a lot of like audio around the
Speaker 4:  Apple ecosystem that's now all being pulled into Apple podcasts.
Speaker 4:  So while, while YouTube goes into YouTube, apple is pulling into
Speaker 4:  podcasts. And I thought that was very interesting. And also to everyone who
Speaker 4:  has asked what podcast apps should I use? The an there are lots of good
Speaker 4:  answers minus PocketCasts. It's a terrific app. It's been around
Speaker 4:  forever. Automatic owns it. The people who own WordPress, so they're not
Speaker 4:  gonna kill it randomly because they hate you. It's a good app.
Speaker 4:  PocketCasts,
Speaker 5:  I can't even mention podcasts without people telling me to use Overcast.
Speaker 5:  They just like show up outta the
Speaker 4:  Overcast is a great app. The only downside of Overcast is that it is, it's
Speaker 4:  pretty platform specific, but otherwise it is a terrific app. Let's see.
Speaker 4:  I feel like whichever one of you I call on right now gets to have this one.
Speaker 4:  No, I I
Speaker 6:  I I I picked another one. Let
Speaker 5:  Me go. Lemme go. Stay away. I'm not, I'm not gonna tell you that you stay
Speaker 5:  outta my chair. Like literally.
Speaker 4:  All right. s Neli, go. Alright.
Speaker 5:  I'm Logitech. It partnered with a company called Play Seat and they've made
Speaker 5:  it, they've made a Logitech branded Racing
Speaker 5:  chair. I'm really unhappy because I own the same
Speaker 5:  chair without the Logitech improvements. I own the plays seat challenge for
Speaker 5:  PlayStation VR and Grand Ismo vr. It's a great
Speaker 5:  chair Logitech by the way, if you just look at it. I own their Racing
Speaker 5:  wheel now. They're doing this chair. That company thinks there's a bigger
Speaker 5:  market in Racing Sims and they're just like going
Speaker 5:  after it. And I think they're right. They know,
Speaker 4:  They know it's coming. This thing folds up. Yeah. Like that's, I have not
Speaker 4:  bought one of these because No,
Speaker 5:  No, I have, again, I have the thing, it folds up. It's very good. It does.
Speaker 5:  Okay. The, yeah, it folds up and the the wheel stays attached and it's all
Speaker 5:  very compact and you get in a closet. It's just, you unfold it and you put
Speaker 5:  it in the center of your living room and you're like, I'm gonna use it again
Speaker 5:  tomorrow. You never fall. It's just like,
Speaker 4:  No, my problem is I have to buy this thing without my wife ever finding out
Speaker 4:  that I bought it. So I need it. I need to be able to get rid of it very quickly
Speaker 4:  at a moment's notice.
Speaker 5:  And there's nothing like furtively hiding a receipt that says the words play
Speaker 5:  seat on it from your wife.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. That's fun to explain on the, on the credit card statement. Wait, so
Speaker 4:  what did Logitech do that makes this cool and exciting?
Speaker 5:  So if you just look at some of the, you know, the little lashes a little
Speaker 5:  better, like they've made, they've made some quality of life
Speaker 5:  improvements because they're Logitech. So it's like I, it just, from
Speaker 5:  what I can tell, they've just made it slightly easier to like operate the
Speaker 5:  folding and the, you know, they, they've just like made it more ergonomic.
Speaker 5:  But I think it's mostly like the things that were red are now blue, you know,
Speaker 5:  but like Logitech is doing this 'cause they want to distribute the stuff,
Speaker 5:  but Placey doesn't have huge distribution. Right. They're actually a little
Speaker 5:  company logitech's, like Best Buy. So like I, I think they're,
Speaker 5:  they're taking it and they're putting it out in the channels because they
Speaker 5:  see a bigger market for this stuff. It
Speaker 6:  Folds down so little
Speaker 5:  Did p ss v r grander Ismo vr. We, we did this whole thing about
Speaker 5:  The Quest three. Yeah. And I am telling you the grand jury Ismo VR
Speaker 5:  on the pss VR two is one of the single most compelling things you
Speaker 5:  can do in vr. I believe it. Like even and I'm like a car nerd and I
Speaker 5:  love it and it's like fine. Like my friends, my family, I put
Speaker 5:  them in the thing and like they're in this silly little chair and they go
Speaker 5:  and they're like blown away.
Speaker 6:  You put a little fan in front of 'em, really get the immersion. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I stand right next to him going Broom Broom.
Speaker 6:  Just back the truck up. Roll coal on 'em.
Speaker 5:  We did, you know, we did a, we did a like a, you know, kids React video to
Speaker 5:  Project Star line at code, which is another thing that's impossible to show
Speaker 5:  people, but it's great. We should do it. We should do a video of people reacting
Speaker 5:  to, to grander mobile vr. 'cause it's super cool.
Speaker 4:  That's a good idea. I need to stop looking at this page else. I'm gonna buy
Speaker 4:  this thing. Alex, what's yours?
Speaker 6:  Same. I just wanna close the loop. We know where Amazon for
Speaker 6:  Amazon Hardware Chief David Lemp went. Oh yeah. And he's going to Blue Origin.
Speaker 6:  So he's gonna go build rockets. Just
Speaker 4:  Can't get enough. G f Bezos. That guy
Speaker 6:  Jeff just can't get enough of Jeff. So that was like we,
Speaker 6:  everybody, conversely they also finally confirmed that Panos per day is
Speaker 6:  definitely coming to Amazon. Yep. That is happening. So all of the stuff
Speaker 6:  that was up in the air, now we know where everybody is. Yeah. Dave's gonna
Speaker 6:  be over at Blue Origins, so probably
Speaker 5:  Dave's definitely gonna put Alexa in the rock. Alexa, take me to
Speaker 5:  space for two minutes. I need to float around a little
Speaker 5:  bit.
Speaker 6:  And, and Panos is definitely coming to Amazon,
Speaker 6:  so it's both happening. I, I've already emailed
Speaker 6:  Amazon repeatedly about e-readers as soon as it was announced.
Speaker 6:  I'm so sorry to Amazon pr. But yeah, let's see
Speaker 6:  it. Panos, let's see the, let's see. A really good Kindle.
Speaker 4:  As soon as the Panos News was announced, somebody just mentioned me on
Speaker 4:  Threads and just said the words Kindle fold question
Speaker 4:  mark. That's all I've been thinking about all week. Panos, do it.
Speaker 4:  It's coming. Give me my folding Kindle. I'm
Speaker 6:  Feeling it.
Speaker 4:  Alright, we have gone extremely long. We need to get outta here. Like I said,
Speaker 4:  there's a bunch of lawsuits now
Speaker 5:  Let's talk about Lindy Aina somewhere.
Speaker 4:  Neli Neil, I needs to go to bed. So, we gonna
Speaker 4:  go.
Speaker 5:  I'm back. By the way. Code's over. I am become
Speaker 5:  deaf. Welcome. The eye
Speaker 5:  of Sore on his back.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Everyone who asked for a Neli, I was, you're gonna, you're gonna ru
Speaker 4:  how much he is back now. Welcome to hell. But yeah,
Speaker 4:  like I said, there's gonna be, there's a bunch more trial stuff to come.
Speaker 4:  It sounds like Satya Nadella, the c e of Microsoft is gonna be testifying.
Speaker 4:  So, we didn't
Speaker 5:  Even talk about it. Wait, you were there in the room.
Speaker 4:  We're gonna talk about that next week. There's so much to talk about. It's
Speaker 4:  gonna be great. I'm excited about it. Satya Nadella is testifying on Monday.
Speaker 4:  We think. I'm gonna try and be in the courtroom for that. Lots more going
Speaker 4:  on there. We have the F T C suing Amazon. The F T X trial is starting next
Speaker 4:  week. There is like a lot still happening. There's a Google event coming
Speaker 4:  next week. We are not short of things to talk about. In
Speaker 4:  the meantime, we're gonna have a ton of code stuff going up over the next
Speaker 4:  few days.
Speaker 5:  Interview with A B C E O. Lisa. Sue is up now. She, she talked a lot about
Speaker 5:  competing with Vidia. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  That was a good one too. We should have mentioned that earlier. She was great
Speaker 4:  and very interesting about like the future of all of this
Speaker 4:  AI hardware stuff. That was a really interesting one.
Speaker 5:  Products I put products on stage at code. The bullshit was the bullshit,
Speaker 5:  but the products were real.
Speaker 4:  There you go. Alright, we are outta here. Everybody's gonna go just decompress
Speaker 4:  for a couple of days and then we'll be back next week. That's it. That's
Speaker 4:  Vergecast Rock and roll.
Speaker 5:  He took my
Speaker 5:  line.
Speaker 7:  And that's a wrap for Vergecast this week. We'd love to hear from you. Shoot
Speaker 7:  us an email at Vergecast at The Verge dot com. The Vergecast is a
Speaker 7:  production of The Verge and the Vox Media Podcast network. The show is produced
Speaker 7:  by me, Liam James, and our senior audio director, Andrew Marino.
Speaker 7:  Our editorial director is Brooke Miners. That's it. We'll see you next
Speaker 7:  week.